Three,
two,
one,
yes.
It feels like you would just hear what
people don't know.
Most people don't know because it hasn't
come out yet.
No one would.
How would they?
We've bid a podcast late last night and
it got completely out of hand so that I
don't even know what to do with that
thing now.
What's that thing out like a gentleman?
I mean,
I'm certainly putting it out on
pretending,
putting out.
So long story short for listeners,
uh,
Joe was kind enough to.
I was interviewing Sam Harris for my
podcast and Sam was like,
we really should just do more than just
a one on one because ordinarily my
podcast is about as a panel of people,
a bunch of people sitting around talking
about the news and so I texted Joe and I
was like,
is there any chance of doing it at your
studio?
And being the gentleman that he is,
he was like,
sure,
just come on by and we'll just type it.
Even though he had two shows yesterday.
So after those shows,
late at night,
Sam Harris comes over and Hannibal
buress is still here.
It was about to call an uber and I said,
why don't you stick around?
Yeah,
hang on.
We were drunk based the way we drink,
so much whiskey,
best decision you ever made,
inviting him to stay,
so Hannibal buress and Sam Harris and
Joe Rogan and I have an interesting
episode of my podcast which will come
up,
so if you're listening to this now or
watching this now subscribed to way the
people live.
Just switch for whether people space
life you need the live and then when it
drops you will.
You will see it.
It was an dining epic.
Our long argument between Hannibal
Burress,
a drunk Hannibal burress and Sam Harris
regarding statistics.
We'll just leave it at that.
Yeah.
You don't want to give him more
statistics that may or may not involve
black lives matter.
I'm shooting police shootings and just
the reality of police violence versus
the perceived reality of police
violence.
So arguing about the statistics rather
than the emotional connection and the
difference and what was interesting is
how we have conversations about things
that are so touchy.
Right.
I've been,
part of the reason why I want to talk to
Sam and you on my podcast is because I
think it's important for us to find ways
to have the sorts of conversations that
you have in that Sam has and hopefully I
have where there's not a lot of kind of
opinionated bloviating.
It's more about actually trying to
understand each other,
but actually trying to take each other
at face value,
not sticking,
you know,
a what a sword in the sand and saying
like,
I can't believe that you offended me or
you know,
having tripwires that if someone
transgresses that'll says a certain
thing,
then all of a sudden you're going to
crank up the outrage machine.
So much of that,
so much of that.
So I wanted to talk to Sam and you about
what,
how do we have conversations that are
the more reasonable,
but of course you don't necessarily have
a conversation that's that reasonable
when you're drunk and emotionally
sensitive.
Drunk.
Hannibal burress says that he's smarter
than Sam Harris and smarter than I think
anyone.
Didn't he say anyone?
Uh,
he definitely said he was smarter than
Sam Harris.
Hannibal's a smart guy,
he must be successful and he's a
compelling
and good comic.
Just not smart enough to know that he
shouldn't say smart Sam Harris.
It was drunk,
really drunk and we kept drinking to
view.
Hit it.
Well,
you hold your liquor.
I bounced back quick.
I'm healthy.
So I stopped drinking.
Also.
Loyalty.
So what you're implying exactly what I
said.
You heard me and uh,
about an hour before the end of our pod,
you have me in Hannibal,
I realized I was drunk,
so I backed off.
Right.
And he going,
he was preparing himself out like half a
half a wine glass of whiskey.
Yup,
Yup.
Yeah,
it was deep.
We went deep.
So,
uh,
he can't be held responsible folks.
Everyone was helping,
right?
Because if you drive drunk and kill
somebody,
then you're not held responsible for
that.
Um,
if you're a woman,
you can have sex with someone.
You're not responsible though the man's
responsible.
That's right,
that's true.
So it was more of a woman having sex
with a drunk driver hitting that high
bar,
more of a woman.
And I bet I'll tell him you said that he
was a guest in my studio.
So,
uh,
I'm responsible.
He didn't,
he could not consent conversation you
with the chaperone.
He was too drunk to consent.
I was the rapist raped him with our
conversation by forcing him into this
conversation that I didn't know he was
going to get into.
Right.
You sort of annually fisted him with
Woodward.
Now you go into a little of my own taste
you said.
Right.
What about this whole,
right?
Have you been,
have you been talking with thinking
about the whole,
like Amy Schumer cut and myths good.
You know,
and like,
and I saw what he said and you know,
I had someone else contact me about that
guy and whether or not,
you know,
he was telling the truth or the woman
was telling the truth.
I don't know him.
I don't know her and I'm not getting
involved because I don't know if I knew
her and I could implicitly trust her.
And I knew that she was going to tell
the truth and it's not,
it's not,
uh,
I,
I just don't understand the motivation
behind someone jumping in with an
opinion.
I think what he's saying though is
interesting because what Kurt was saying
was that it is entirely possible he was
satire,
obviously.
But you're saying women cannot lie
there.
Like my Bible.
It's impossible for a woman to lodge,
just like the Lord's word.
That's it.
You know,
he's being funny.
He's hilarious.
Shitster.
Yeah,
he's hilarious.
But,
um,
it's a,
it's weird,
you know,
like that there's this culture,
what we know for a fact that some people
lie about every single aspect of life.
They lie about what they did.
They lie about their taxes,
they lie about everything.
But we're supposed to assume that women
never lie about rape.
And it's not true.
We know it's not true,
but we're not allowed to say it's not
true.
Even though we know it,
we're not allowed to bring it up.
But.
So if there's a possibility,
if a woman says that she's raped,
you have to accept that 100 percent at
face value.
Even if the man is saying he didn't rape
her,
it's really hard because that's one side
of the ledger and um,
and then on the other side of the
ledger,
you've got all of the overwhelming
number of cases where men get away with
it.
Yes.
Because women are too afraid
to go to the police or they feel like
they feel like they're dirty or that
somehow for whatever reason,
just not talk about it and let it go
away.
So I think that I think that women's
rights people and feminists think like
if,
if it's occasionally the case that a man
is wrongly accused,
that's a small price to pay for
fostering a climate in which women feel
more,
feel less nervous about coming forward.
Now I'm not saying that I believe that,
but wow,
what a shitstorm Kurt has.
So I'm not sure if everyone knows the
background of this,
that there was a.
One of the comics that UCB theater in
New York was accused of being a repeat
sexual offender by a bunch of women.
So say suspended him as a comic and
excuse me,
and conducted its own internal
investigation.
And Kurt went on a big facebook rants.
I was looking at it this morning
actually saying,
I'm basically like,
why is this internal?
You know,
what is this like the Catholic church,
the UCB theater,
like doing the internal investigation.
Why didn't these women go to go to the
police?
He writes a.
This is his original facebook post.
Guys.
I've just heard some disturbing news.
This Guy Jeff Delfi Berg is a rapist.
I know because women said it,
and that's all I need.
Never you mind who they are.
They're all women.
All women are as reliable as my Bible.
A book that much like a woman is
incapable of lying.
So what you were saying,
you think I would dare ask my God,
Lord Jesus Christ.
Then Nazareen to provide any details or
evidence of any kind before I believe in
him or a woman.
No,
because that would be like hammering the
nails into Jesus my Lord's feet or
rewriting the victims.
Good whole asking for proof in a murder
trial and he goes on like that.
I made.
It's really funny.
If that guy's innocent,
if that guy's guilty,
then it becomes really disturbing.
Kind of become a name and an enabler.
Problem is.
There's no way Kurt can know exactly
exactly,
but I do.
I think it raises interesting questions
about the whole kind of the,
the censorious and like the hysteria of
the Social Justice Warrior Brigade in
that there are people who really fucking
want him to get fired and never,
you know,
if amy's show comes back,
they don't want him back.
As a writer,
I'm sure that there are a comedy clubs,
so they're going to rethink whether or
not they want to book him because he
might be too toxic and I doubt that.
Maybe,
maybe not.
It's not that big of a deal because what
he said was not that big of a deal,
but the issue and everyone went crazy.
She went crazy.
She posted the amy did.
She posted this thing,
you know,
saying that she's very disappointed and
that was in response to an endless
barrage of social justice people in
feminist saying that this is completely
unacceptable and he deserves to be fired
for it.
He has a job.
He showed some pretty incredible loyalty
to her during that whole plagiarism
scandal,
especially when he was one of the ones
who told her to not do one of those
jokes because it was a windy liebman
joke,
so he kept his mud about all that and
then she turned on him with this whole
thing.
The whole thing is very sorted
and I see.
I see her point of view and I see his
point of view.
I really do.
I think she didn't.
I think she felt she didn't have an
option,
but because she did say I could see my
friend and knowing him,
I'm disappointed in him.
Yeah,
it's toxic.
I mean there's no way that you can talk
about.
You can't raise the question that you
just raised.
Unless you're on the Joe Rogan
experience.
You cannot raise the question of whether
or not it's appropriate,
whether they should be in a presumption
of innocence.
That's why podcasts are so God damn
important as you could never do this on
a regular show.
Certainly couldn't do the shit we went
on last night on a regular show off the
air.
Yeah.
Wait till it comes out,
Woo.
Um,
you know,
here's the PR again.
Here's the problem.
If that guy is innocent,
then Kurt is doing a service because he
is expressing this very real possibility
that someone might be lying.
If that guy's guilty,
then it's not funny at all and it
becomes really fucking gross for the
girl if she has to sit back and listen
to someone mock whether or not she's
telling the truth when she knows she
did.
That has got to be a horrible feeling.
So the question is,
what is worse?
Is it worse to get falsely accused of
rape or is it worse to get raped when
someone doesn't believe you and get
accused of being a liar?
It's obviously worse to get raped and
being accused of alive,
but by how much,
I mean if you grading on a scale like
getting getting,
I mean let's just,
let's just assume it's at least a bit
worse on that side
because you use the physical right is
worse than being falsely accused but
surely
in having your career destroyed and
dragged through the mud and forever
labeled a rapist,
which is entirely possible for someone
is innocent.
It happened to a friend of mine,
a friend of mine got accused falsely of
rape.
This girl that he was dating,
he broke up with her.
They broke up and she just decided that
she was going to get back at him,
so she said that he was a rapist and she
followed through with it for awhile and
then eventually abandoned it.
But that does happen and it's happened
many,
many times and there's a bunch of
statistics you can look up online,
but they're not entirely accurate
because they don't take into account how
many women leave.
You look into like overall rapes and
overall people who lie it,
rape the overall rape statistics are not
accurate because they do not know nor do
they take into account or can they
possibly take into account how many
women don't say anything.
It's a big number.
And also like what constitutes a rape
exam.
Like when you say that with some men
have falsely accused is not always as
black and white as you know,
they,
they were dating and they never even had
sex at all but she suddenly accuses him
of.
Right.
But there are also scenarios where as
you said before she was drunk or like
she didn't know that he thought there
was consent and there wasn't consent or
that,
you know,
I mean,
or maybe they were,
you know,
so it's,
it's,
it's a vague area and I think Kurt's
point which is like,
I don't think that we should be having
to choose between the two options that
you just cited,
which is on the one hand a woman gets
raped and is not believed.
And on the other hand,
a man is falsely accused of rape.
Well,
I think what Kurt is trying to do,
just in a clumsy,
smart ass,
he a flame throwing way is say,
can it be true that rape is really,
really terrible and we also should,
should offer men the benefit of the
doubt and encourage rape victims to go
to the police rather than to internal
investigations at places like Uc Bay.
His point is like he thinks he's on the
side of the rape victims,
right?
By saying like they've been sold a dumb
bill of goods by feminists by saying,
oh your such poor,
pathetic victims that you can't go to
the police and it will never be taken
care of by going to the police.
So you should just be mollycoddled and,
and you should either remain silent or,
or you know,
just to have it sorted out internally.
Think he's saying when he says,
he says so he,
this is his followup facebook post which
you posted last Wednesday where he
begins by saying I'm my punishment the
mob is howling for is now officially
more severe than the one for the actual
ripest.
Which is interesting.
But towards the end he says,
I didn't yell at victims to go to the
police.
They are victims.
I'm yelling at the people who said women
can't go to the police.
They have to work outside the system.
I think that's out of bullshit and leads
to rapists walking free.
It hurts the victims of sexual assault.
Okay.
He's saying that because this woman
never went to the police.
That's just publicly accused of rape.
That's right.
Isn't there more than one woman as well?
I believe so.
I believe there's a second one.
Who's friends with that girl?
Right?
Who also says the same store.
So he ain't good.
He claims to be on the side of the
victims.
I mean,
I think he just doesn't quite get how
traumatic it can be for people who've
been for women who've been sexually
assaulted.
He gets raped every day.
You don't even know.
You don't know.
He gets raped every day,
just so you can understand.
It gets raped every day.
He loves it.
Not Funny.
Rape is never funny.
Um,
he,
he said,
why?
He says,
why did the story of what actually
happened?
What happened to come out after the guy
is declared a ripest?
I'll listen to any victim's account.
All that was given initially is Aaron's
right best pass it on.
My point was that no one seems disturbed
by this.
No one sees that down the road.
Next time we might get it wrong.
Well we might have it wrong here.
We don't know,
but it's not good when a second person
calls you out for the same crime.
That's right,
but it's also not good that no one went
to the cops and maybe also what kind of
evidence do you have?
Somebody raped you a month ago,
guess what?
You have no evidence.
No,
exactly.
As you've showered up and you don't have
any bruises.
Like what can you say?
It's your word against them.
Yeah,
and you know,
I think for some women and it's also
like what exactly was the scenario that
we're talking about?
Was it a simple social justice warrior
type thing where two people are drunk
and then the woman didn't consent,
so they're calling that rape,
which is repeated ad nauseum and it got
kicked out at Occidental.
College is a lawsuit going on right now
because of that.
I'm sure you know that story where a man
and a woman,
the girl was saying,
coming over,
do you have condoms?
They have sex,
and then her friends convinced her that
because she was drunk,
it was rape even though they were both
drunk and then the college kicks him
out,
keeps her and so he's suing the college.
It's a fucking giant disaster is total
sexism.
One hundred percent sexism against the
man and when you look at the story and
what it is,
it's a goddamn witch hunt and they gave
into the witch hunt.
They just wanted to quiet it down and
they figured it would be easier to kick
this kid out and and just given to the
wills of the mom
and then on the other hand you've got
that,
like the the California College swimmer
kid who who raped a girl behind the
dumpster on campus.
You've never heard about that.
She was passed out and he was like
fingering her and she ended like pine
cone cuts all over her vagina and
everything was really horrible story and
she ended up getting,
what,
six months basically nothing,
and now he's out.
Now he's out again and um,
and
that's,
that's a fucking terrible person and
that guy should be
punished.
And the judge was,
the judge was an alum of the same
college and so and so.
He's like,
it's an all boys school.
oh,
well boys will be boys.
And the,
and the apology that this rice,
the ripest little asshole road was like,
I think this serves as a good lesson
about intoxication and the dangers of
inebriation on campus.
Like,
fuck you,
it doesn't,
that's not the lesson.
The lesson is done,
right.
Paypal,
when she's in colons and someone's
vagina piece of shit.
Well,
I mean,
when she was ending,
it was bad enough to people who say,
well maybe he thought that she was
consenting.
It was obvious enough that to other
students,
they were foreign students.
They were Swedish guys were riding by on
bicycles and they saw what was going on
and it was obvious from afar,
even in the dark what was happening
because they stopped and came over and
rescued her.
She was limp as a,
as a ragdoll.
Yeah.
So there's that.
That's real rape and that's,
that's terrifying when a woman does get,
you know,
exposed as being someone who's
experienced rape.
So the,
you have to think about all these people
that know your personal trauma and then
this guy barely gets punished.
That's horrible too.
Yeah.
It's horrible too.
Yeah,
man.
It sucks both ways.
You know,
I guess it's definitely sucks worse if
you,
the person who gets victimized,
but it still sucks if you're someone who
didn't do anything wrong and someone
claims that you're a rapist and that tag
carries you for the rest of your life
and in your being falsely accused.
Yeah.
Until we can read people's minds clearly
and truly,
God,
that'll be terrifying.
It's going to happen.
It's on the way.
It's,
it's like right now we are at the Morse
code of reading minds.
We're at the,
uh,
to,
to do,
do,
do.
That's where we're at.
I mean they're sending signals,
they're receiving signals,
they're articulating words,
someone sending their setting words
through the Internet into your mind and
you see those words.
You hear those words,
images,
they can place images in your mind.
This is a very rudimentary right now,
but they're gonna be able to string
those words together and form sentences
and those words instead of being through
some giant Bank of supercomputers,
it's going to be something that's in
your phone or a chip that we all
willingly installing our brains and
we're going to read each other's.
Then we're going to know.
I wonder how nuanced that'll be though.
So I did a,
I did a story before I was at huffpost
live.
I had a show on discovery science
channel,
which was sort of a bit like the soup.
We like a smart ass.
He kind of look at,
but science nerd news and I went to come
and where it was somewhere up in the bay
area,
so some it place where they working on
mind reading a computer games.
And this was all the way back in I guess
2010,
2009 and I you could put a thing on your
head and you can operate the computer
game just through the intensity of your
pet,
of your thought patterns.
It's very,
like you say,
it's basically Morse code.
It's pretty much only on or off.
You can't just know nuance apart from
just think hard about something and then
you know,
you'll set fire to this little thing
that you need to set fire to,
to win the game.
That's amazing that they can tell that.
But I wonder whether or not.
And for example,
we can see the brain when you put people
in an Mri machine,
we can tell whether or not the,
the room,
the memory part of your brain is
lighting up when they show you
something.
So they talking about the possibility of
in a criminal trial,
they'd be able to at least be able to
tell whether or not you've ever been to
the inside,
excuse me,
of the of the place where the crime was
committed.
Well,
you know,
I did an episode of this,
of that drug and questions,
everything with Mri.
They actually,
they accused someone and convicted
someone,
I believe in India of having functional
knowledge of a crime scene because
through f Mri they were able to indicate
that she understood where that crime
scene was and she had some form of
memory that they could deduce from the
Fmr.
The problem according to neuroscientists
and the woman I was talking to on the
podcast on the show,
I forget her name,
I apologized to her,
but she explained that the problem is
that during the course of the
investigation that person,
the woman who was accused and convicted
could have been exposed to the evidence
of that crime scene and then have
functional memory of that crime scene.
Because of that which was exposed during
the MRI.
Particularly when you think about the
fact that her freedom was on the line,
she was falsely accused or accused of
this crime.
I don't know if she did or not.
She's accused of this crime they
presented with this evidence.
She has to go over this evidence.
There's an incredible amount of weight
in emotions involved in that and they
could see or that memory deeply in her
brain of what that scene looked like.
Yeah,
that's interesting.
I can't remember whether you've told me
about that or whether I've just heard
you talk about it on the,
on the podcast,
but.
But then as you get to more and more
subtle layers of thought,
so it's not just is the memory part of
the brain firing when we showed this
person an image of something,
but it's like.
I mean,
how would you.
How would you ascertain somebody's guilt
or innocence in a rape case?
Right now?
I can't see.
I think what they're doing with this
Fmri stuff is.
I mean obviously you can't if there's
some significant evidence,
Siemens scratches video actually by
reading your mind,
but I don't think that Kenya,
what they were saying is that the.
What they did in India with this woman
was telling me she,
and she
again,
is a prominent neuroscientist.
She was saying that they misuse the
evidence.
They misstated the efficacy of this
evidence and that they use this in a
very inappropriate way that would not be
legal in the United States like you
would get.
No one who understands,
truly understands Fmr,
who would sign off on that or no one
whose ethical,
I mean from the neuroscientist who I've
spoken to,
I think we're a long,
long,
long way away from having the kind of
granularity and confidence that we could
say just because this part of the law,
the brain is lighting up or was it just
because of these kinds of waves of being
emitted by your neurons.
That means that you're either guilty or
not guilty according to our standard
biology.
I would agree with that and here's where
I deviate.
I think that we are not that far away
from them being able to introduce
artificial recording of memories and I
think that people are going to do it
willingly and I think it's going to be
one of those things that people share
with each other back and forth.
What are you showing me,
Jamie?
Scientists discover how to implant false
memories pulley Ah,
shame.
We just blew it up.
So what does that mean?
Pull it up.
Mit researchers expand that so I could
read that a little bit better.
MIT researchers,
Steve Ramirez and wow.
The Zulu recently made history when they
successfully implanted a false memory
into the mind of a mouse.
The proof was a simple reaction from the
road and what the implications are.
Vast,
they placed the furry little creature
inside a metal box and it froze.
Displaying a distinct fear response.
The mouse is reacting as if they
received a wreck.
Electrical shock there when it had it at
all,
Huh?
I'm stable.
I'm not surprised and this is what I
think.
I've been really heavily dabbling in
virtual reality lately because my friend
Duncan has the htc vive and uh,
he put it on me and I went into a frenzy
and I realized like what is happening
and where we're at and where I thought
we were at versus where we actually are
at.
They are so far ahead of where I thought
they are.
They are so close to creating a,
uh,
an indiscernible virtual reality.
It's so close.
Kind of do this,
a friend of mine works us up at a,
but what,
who owns oculus?
Facebook.
That's the big,
uh,
virtual reality of either Google or
facebook.
Yeah.
Facebook.
Facebook tarmac is coming in here.
John Carmack,
the girl from ID software who
programmed.
He created doom and quake and all those
games.
He's now at Oculus,
which is just,
I mean,
he's a flesh and go up there to try to
stuff.
I was hearing Tim Ferriss talks about
this as well and just say a Dunkin
donuts podcasts.
I connect you guys in town for a til
Saturday.
Okay.
I'll connect you guys when we get after
this show and I think Duncanson town.
Fantastic.
You're going to shit your pants.
This shit.
So it's amazing.
But what's amazing about it is right now
it's goggles and it's connected to a
computer and it's clunky,
but you know,
the original computers at the Apollo
mission used were giant room and one
quarter of the processing power or
something of your life.
I don't even think it's one quarter.
Yeah,
you know,
but that's the point is that as you,
as this technology exponentially gets
more and more powerful and smaller and
more easy for people to access,
you know,
used to be everyone remember Wall Street
when Michael Douglas had that giant
brick phone and we're like,
what a gangster.
I'm walking around with that phone,
that phone's job and now,
I mean that was in Brazil a few years
back in 2003 and uh,
you know,
you go to these like little tiny jungle
villages and all these people have cell
phones.
Everybody has a phone.
No,
it's going to be incredible as you see
how.
I mean,
the interesting thing for me in via are,
is what we're saying is where it's gonna
go.
So everything moves so fast now that
it's incredible for me to.
I love,
I love human ignorance as well as
genius.
Like I love my own inability to predict
how things are going to unfold and just
the,
the sheer,
the sheer joy in how spontaneously kind
of a,
I don't know,
exciting that this whole human
experiment is because when for example,
huffpost live,
we started doing this thing in 2012.
We were like,
okay,
well let's do the future of television
because obviously television and the
Internet are coming together and they're
going to merge,
so the way that we.
If you,
if you were starting from scratch and
inventing a tool,
a television talk show now knowing
nothing about the history of
broadcasting or television or radio,
what would it be like?
Well,
it'd be didn't have commenters and you'd
have people joining via Webcam and so
they developed like 12 hours a day of
huffpost live broadcasts from studios.
Within a few years it was clear that
that was obsolete.
That was not the way that the future was
going and now it's all like short live
streaming,
shareable things.
Right?
Similarly with virtual reality,
I think the Fio was and has been.
When it gets really good,
everyone's just to sit in their basement
and watch virtual reality porn all day
and no one's going to connect with each
other anymore.
Right.
It's coming,
but he is.
What's the.
What's the biggest virtual or augmented
reality breakthrough thus far?
That's widespread.
That's caught on.
I don't know what his pokemon go.
Yeah,
but that's dropped off significantly.
Do you know that?
Yeah.
They're dropped into my users over the
last week.
Really?
I didn't know it was that much,
but here's the thing.
I was pretty sure against it.
It's in Thai.
Yeah.
I mean I.
I'm not saying that it's going to.
The pokemon go itself is going to change
the world.
What points to to me is the possibility
that where we thought that virtual
reality was all going to be about
headsets and me and my own head and
maybe it still will be to some extent.
I could totally see it go in the
augmented reality way instead so that
you're walking around the street with
some kind of little thing on the side of
your head and all every way you look,
things are popping up like little
graphics are pumping up on top of
things,
offering you sales in a particular
store,
showing you where you know,
you can say what you're looking for,
you know,
where's the nearest bank and this little
arrow that points down over the newest
chase branch or whatever.
That's what magic leap is saying.
Yeah,
right.
So and that strikes
me is actually a more plausible and
organic pot old possible future than the
one in which we're all just sort of like
in the wally,
remember the movie Wally Universe where
we're all just in Bocca lounges and lazy
boys in kind of our own.
I don't think they're mutually
exclusive.
Maybe not.
I don't think it's either or.
I think that's going to happen as well.
There's going to be brave fools that
venture outside and experience augmented
reality where everybody else stairs at
people's buttholes from two inches away.
I'm telling you,
man,
you put on these virtual goggles and you
have a three d porn going on where these
people are having sex and you can get
right in there.
You could look at their face,
you could stare in their eyes when they
have sex and it looks so God damn real,
but their computer generated avatars or
they feel human being filmed.
Human beings for 360 degree cameras.
And right now it's,
you know,
it's fairly limited.
Did you watch porn on it now?
I didn't.
Duncan has though.
Dunkin is into it.
I didn't want to watch porn in front of
Dunkin.
Can't see anything other than the.
I'm just kidding.
But it's when you feel someone blowing
you and you're just like,
what?
Come on.
Beard.
Play enough.
Duncan.
Um,
it's,
you know,
I saw the um,
the most impressive thing that I saw was
the underwater thing.
They have this underwater thing where
you,
you're standing at the bottom of the
ocean and these fish swim by and then a
whale swims up to you and you're looking
the whale in the eye and it has this
feeling of mass,
like you really feel like there's whales
in front of you.
You freaking out.
I mean,
it's so realistic.
It's actual three d footage of A.
Well,
no,
it's CCGI generated.
Well,
but it's amazing.
It's amazing and it's just.
It gives you this.
Well,
I first tried virtual reality at
Duncan's place,
I want to say four years ago,
three years ago,
somewhere in there,
and it was really crude.
It was pixelated and it was some silly
game and it was really clunky,
but I could see it.
I could see it.
I could go,
oh,
I get it.
I see where this is going.
This is just leaps and bounds past where
that is and there's one game that you
play or one experience that you have
where you go into this guys room and
he's composing music on a piano and you
walk in the room and you can look up and
look around and while this guy's playing
the piano,
you can get up beside him and look at
his keys.
It's fucking crazy.
That's video.
That's a real guy.
And Apparently Duncan says like,
the porn is just like that.
You can just like get.
So I mean for me the question is,
I think fundamentally we are.
Oh well he's the image of the whale.
Yeah.
I mean this is not doing it justice
because you don't have a real reality.
Yeah,
but you don't have any control whether
or not you move.
So you're kind of getting a sense of
what happens while love this camera
moves around,
but I'm a.
You can get underneath that.
We'll look at its body.
I'd gone onto the water with a,
with a humpback whale and mainly a
couple of years ago.
You're not allowed to swim with them,
but if you're in a little dodgy Zodiac
like I was,
then they get around the rules.
Well my guy did by just holding
your legs,
so as long as you're still connected to
the boat,
like you're technically not swimming,
swim with them because it for
environmental reasons,
like people were Dick heads would go up
and harass them for the team and the
whale or something.
Exactly.
You need to give them their space and so
I had a snorkel on and goggles on and
this huge thing just comes looming out
of the ward and the size of a fucking
bus.
This memo that breathes air like that
eats these times.
I mean the miracle of it blows my mind
the diversity of this incredible planet
that we live on a and then it just sort
of sinks down into the crystal blue
water until I can just sort of make it
out and then it's just disappeared and
it's all just blue blue underneath.
I mean it was like,
I don't want to sound too wacky,
but it was spiritual.
I mean,
you come over there and that thing is
just that was born,
that squirted out of another whale's
vagina and then grew up and now it's
just,
now it's doing its thing in the Pacific
paradigm shifting because of their
masks,
because the oddness of them.
Well,
even dolphins,
I um,
did this thing last summer where,
uh,
me and my whole family were in the big
island and you go on this dolphin
excursion where they take you on a boat
and they find these pods of wild
dolphins and you just jump into the
water with the dolphins with snorkels.
So you're,
they're swimming around and you know,
I did it with my,
at the time she was five,
we did it with my five year old.
I'm like holding her hand and taking her
with these dolphins and we're looking
down with our goggles and these dolphins
were swimming right under you.
Amazing.
It's fucking beautiful.
It's nuts.
I was in the water and in Australia in
Byron Bay and was,
and there are occasional shark attacks
there and caught a glimpse of movement
out of the side of the side of my eye.
Oh fuck.
And I was like,
And looked over and could see like a
shape and a and a fin ps,
the,
the water and then like what?
That moment where time stands stand
still and you're like,
Holy Shit.
And then the back just arched out of the
water.
I know.
I was like,
Oh,
thank fucking Lord you Dolphin.
Oh fuck.
Oh God.
And then this whole pod of dolphins just
diving through the waves,
I was like,
oh my God.
Yeah.
There was a video off of Maui or excuse
me off a Malibu really recently where
these people were flying a drone over a
Malibu and he was only,
I don't think maybe one or 200 yards
away from swimmers and surfers and this
is fucking monster.
Great White Shark swimming around it and
looking for something to chomp on and
they're out there apparently like really
common off a Malibu and they're
realizing that now because it drones
Herdez people fly those drones.
And have you ever done those?
Have you found that operated at myself
and that's another aspect of virtual
reality.
It's fascinating.
You put these virtual reality goggles on
and you put a camera on this drone and
as the drone is flying,
you feel like your.
I did that in the Pacific when we
were looking for bigfoot Duncan and I
coincidentally,
and this,
uh,
this drone is flying over the tree tops
and it really does.
You have this sensation of flight.
That's what I want because I used to
want to be a pilot.
I'm a huge aviation path.
Like I'm part of the travel hacking
community,
the bunch of nerds who figure out ways
to fly first class all over the place
using credit card,
frequent flyer miles tracking travel
hacking.
Yeah.
No,
that was real.
Yeah,
it's great.
I mean,
I fly around the world first class at
least two or three times a year as long
as there's many times I have time for
one flights that would cost 20 or
$30,000.
Mean flight from here to Australia in
first class on a good airline is $22.
Twenty two,
$23,000.
Yeah.
You just use points these miles.
But.
So I'm a huge.
You,
you look like,
you think that I'm committing crime?
No,
I'm not your own little insecurities,
but I don't know.
I feel like I've been saying that in an
interaction with law enforcement to Joe.
So,
um,
but whose credit card are you using?
I'm not going,
but I've always,
I mean I've reckoned flight would be the
most amazing thing I'd love to.
I've been meaning to get around to like
learning to hang glide or paraglider,
one of those types of things.
I think that'd be a great hobby.
Who have you seen the new inside of
planes that they're building?
They're building.
Oh yeah.
I'm not sure they're going to do that.
But you may passenger planes where the
interior.
The exterior.
I've seen the mock ups of.
Yeah,
well apparently they're thinking about
making it or they're in development,
but the,
if it becomes a reality,
the ultimate goal is you're going to be
flying and essentially what feels like a
convertible.
Yeah.
Because the entire top of the plane is
going to be a screen and you're going to
be able to look up and see the actual
sky above you.
I mean,
they could do it on the floor as well if
they wanted to.
Sure.
That freak you out.
Feel like you're just sitting in a chair
flying through space.
Oh my God.
I sometimes wonder what the experience
would have been like for like the people
in the Malaysian Airlines plane that was
blown up over Ukraine where like all of
us,
you know,
one minute you were at 34,000
feet and then [inaudible] those
explosions,
the way that those anti aircraft and
missiles go is they blow up outside the,
the plane just,
just immediately outside it.
And then all of the shrapnel shatters
the plane and blow it apart.
Yeah.
So did they shoot that thing down or did
a bomb blow up on the plane?
They shut it down.
So it was the,
uh,
the Russians.
So it was a Russian shout,
a plane down for.
Yeah.
You remember the Malaysia Airlines plane
that went down Mih?
I always get approved.
Who Shot that down?
Basically.
So Putin was alarming.
It wasn't intentional that didn't know
it was a passenger plane.
So it was during the Ukrainian.
Putin had annexed Crimea and was
basically fermenting a revolution in
Ukraine because he resented the
Ukrainian government being pro western
and pro American and so they were
sending in Russian special forces in
like,
not in Russian uniforms,
but our secret service guys will know
they are Russian
backed in Russia to finance.
They using military hardware that only
Russia could have gotten them,
that a rag tag team of Ukrainian rebel
San Francisco would never have been able
to get on their own,
such as an anti aircraft.
Ms Dot Paula can shoot a plane out of
the sky from 34,000
feet.
Now there are lots of conspiracy
theories that are put out by Moscow
about this because of course Russia
doesn't accept it.
They think that it was the west,
I think that it was the Ukrainians or
whatever,
but there was a Malaysian airlines jet
that was flying from Amsterdam to Kuala
Lumpur full of quite a lot of people who
were heading to Melbourne actually.
Which is why I did quite a few stories
on it.
And um,
the that we're heading to Melbourne for
big AIDS conference was the big national
aids conference,
so actually a lot of the world's best
biggest best aids scientists and aids
research has died in that,
in that crash.
And they were just flying and they'd
been in the air for a few hours and they
were going over Ukrainian airspace and
the rebels sore a speck in the sky and
assumed that it wouldn't be a passenger
plane.
Why they assume that I think that there
was a warning that passenger jets
shouldn't be going over that area.
And I think it was an off year.
They assumed that it was a military
plane and they used one of these huge
antiaircraft things and it's self God is
seeking.
So it goes straight to the thing and
then just as it is,
it's next to it explodes and the plane's
splits into and just literally drops out
of the sky.
And I sometimes wonder like,
what is the experience when you're
sitting there,
do you have a half a second to,
to know what's happening?
I mean,
you must,
you must write.
The deceleration is so fast that I've
heard scientists say,
you wouldn't really know what's
happening.
You'd just sort of you pass out because
all of a sudden you're going from what,
500 miles an hour down to and rapid
rapid deceleration.
Obviously all of a sudden it's.
There's no air,
there's no air anymore.
There's it's freezing cold,
but I mean some people I would have
imagined would be semi momentarily aware
that something horrible has happened and
it's suddenly it's called tumbling out
of the sky.
It's kind of weird to.
So I don't want that kind of flight.
Joe Don't know why that popped into my
head,
that whole story,
but I want some kind of flight.
Yeah,
that's not good.
Yeah.
Me.
Amazing.
On the question of virtual reality,
do you think,
do you not think that we are so
fundamentally creatures of community,
of communion,
of communication that this dystopian
vision of all of us just sitting solo
with our headsets on,
having our own experiences is unlikely.
I tend to think that there are going to
be ways that we will find ways to use it
to connect us more rather than less
because what makes it anything not,
that's not a gimmick.
Like I don't know.
I can't foresee what virtual reality
will become.
Like when film was invented,
they started out just by doing here's an
image of a steam train and people were
like,
oh my goodness.
It's like it looks like there's a steam
train,
but no one knew what the fuck to do with
it.
It took awhile.
It took years.
It took decades before the craft and art
of cinematography and filmmaking became
a thing and I don't know that we know
yet what virtual reality will become at
the moment.
It strikes me as just something like,
Whoa,
it'll become everything can become.
It's not going to become any one thing.
It's not going to go in only one
direction.
All these directions that we're
proposing are not just possible,
but most likely inevitable and whether
or not we're creatures of community.
There's a lot of people that seek
community online and that's the only way
they get community and it's very
problematic in a lot of them when you
find out like who they are as people,
they're really fucked up and one of the
reasons why they're seeking community
online is because they don't have
community in the actual physical world
and they're disenfranchised and they're
loners or they're,
you know,
they're on the spectrum or there's a
bunch of different factors,
a bunch of different social misfits that
are finding community online.
I know places where you can go where you
could see the same people online
literally 18 hours a day every day.
Some people that are on disability and
they get checks and they never leave the
house and all they do is pay for their
Internet connection and food and that is
where they exist and that is really
common.
So if that's really common,
you know there's probably a million plus
people out there that are doing that
every day.
What's going to stop them from going
virtual?
They will,
yeah,
they will.
Well,
and I think a lot of other people will
as well.
If you think about what we're doing with
phones,
you know how many times have you gone to
a restaurant?
You see a table full of seven people.
No one's talking to each other.
Everyone's staring at their phone.
I mean,
this is a form of virtual reality.
You're going into the reality that
exists on your phone and you're like,
hmm,
what's.
See what's going on.
You're constantly updating it and
constantly checking your facebook feed
to see if who's posted something
interesting.
You're clicking on videos and instead of
talking to each other,
you're showing each other some shit
that's on your phone.
That is really common,
right?
It is.
It's a big fucking problem.
I think it's.
I think it's deeper than we know
Ari Shaffir and big Jay Oakerson did a
podcast where they were on the roof of
this building and they were a peeping
tom on this.
A couple of those couples about deaf sex
and they both started talking on their
phones will start playing with their
phones.
The woman was straddling this man and
she's looking at her phone and the guys
underneath the girl and he starts,
okay,
I want to know why our Irish affairs
spying on people,
what he does,
he's a pervert.
He's a creep,
but I think it's what it's doing to our
heads.
But like,
because like,
so a friend of a friend of mine is a
stand up here and in La and he first,
he got rid of his smartphone in favor of
a flip phone already did that too.
And then he got rid of his flip phone in
favor of a home landline with an old
fashioned answering machine with a type
in it because he feels like he enjoyed.
He thinks there's a virtue in being
bored.
There's something to be in board.
Yep.
That you'll brain needs the space of
having to conjure up imagination in its
own right in order to lead you to the
muse because you never know when it's
gonna hit.
So you know,
constantly.
I mean,
I think back to why not I was a kid and
if you made arrangements to go and see a
movie with a buddy of yours,
you know,
when I was 15 and you said we'll just
meet at the movie theater at five and
they were going to be light.
There was no way for you to know that
they were going to be seven minutes late
and during those seven minutes there was
nothing for you to do and it's amazing
to me that I'm amazed that that's the
case.
It's amazing to me that now I can't even
really imagine just standing on a street
corner outside of movie theater for
seven minutes being totally unruffled by
the fact that a friend is seven minutes
late and being perfectly comfortable
just doing what?
Gazing at the sky.
Looking at passes by.
Yeah.
That's what people have done for
thousands of years when they had to wait
for something and that space,
that just psychic space of not having
the ability to check who taught me,
talking about me on twitter,
who,
what,
what's going on on facebook,
what am I missing?
What's happening?
We know what's the latest photo from my
friends.
What's the latest news thing that's
coming down?
Just standing there.
They life used to be punctuated by
moments like that all the time.
Yeah.
And I wonder whether those are the
moments in which you come up with ideas
for the book that you want to ride or
the standup bit that you want to do or
the painting that you want to pay until
the,
I don't know,
the chair that you want to make.
No,
they can or you can just actually work.
A lot of people think that the music is
supposed to come to you when you're
bored.
How about you sit in front of your desk,
you fucking Lazy Bitch.
And actually right.
You know,
there's that too.
I mean,
I think there is absolutely an argument
for not being constantly entertained by
electronics.
There's absolutely an argument for that,
but I don't know if that's the best one.
I think um,
I lead is,
well I think reflection and time alone
and also I think the,
um,
the way to mitigate that is discipline.
I think you have to have discipline.
You have to have no wins.
A lot of people don't.
I don't
and I appreciate moments of,
you know,
I used to love flying before you had
back televisions because it was a good
excuse to just read and just gaze out
the window and just think now I watch tv
because I don't do this.
I'm an
bullshit.
You're not though,
but you're not.
You get a lot of things done.
I do,
but don't.
I mean I like a lot of creative people.
Beat myself up a lot for not getting
more done.
I mean I look at.
I live as well and I get a lot done.
Yeah.
But I think everyone looks at you and
thinks,
fuck,
I wish I was more like Joe said.
I just did a lot of shit.
He seems to have his shit together.
Guys like you and Tim Ferriss.
You like an Anthony Robbins and stuff.
You're always doing shit.
Yeah.
But whereas a lot of us are the creative
people spend a lot of time scratching
our head,
scratching our offices.
Here's the dirty secret.
I'm never satisfied.
Yeah.
I'm not everything I eat everything.
I do
have a podcast comes out great.
I'm happy and everything like that,
but I.
I get very little satisfaction from it.
I just.
All I think is the next one's got to be
good to.
Let's.
Let's make sure the guest is good.
Let's make sure the subject matters.
That was good.
Easy,
easy fella.
You're a good guest,
but I've had some gas before.
We're like,
oh Jesus,
I got to do all the heavy lifting here.
Motherfuckers not even finishing his
sentences.
I've had people like that before.
Especially people that don't know how to
do podcasts or they haven't done them
before.
Yeah,
I mean podcasting itself is kind of a
work of art.
It's a very pretentious way to describe
it,
but I mean it is a creation and there's
something that's going on.
You have to be aware of how people are
gonna perceive this creation,
how they're going to ingest it,
and it has to be as smooth as you can
make it and you have to learn from your
mistakes and you have to make sure
you're not talking over each other too
much,
but you also can't let someone ramble
too much as well.
Sometimes people get boring,
they just drone on about things in their
own,
in their own space and you've got to
kind of pull them out of their space.
So there's A.
There's like a craft to it all,
but yeah,
I do a lot of different things,
but one of the reasons why I do a lot of
different things is that they all kind
of symbiotically connected together in
some sort of a weird way in that I love
them all.
I enjoy doing them all.
Whether it's a comedy or mma commentary
or podcasting,
they all do sort of flow together.
Hm.
I mean,
it's interesting that you say that.
Like there's a craft to podcasting.
In terms of how.
We were talking about this a little bit
last night with Sam Harrison on my
podcast about when should you interrupt
and when should you not,
not interrupt because I find that
sometimes I'll be criticized for
interrupting somebody on my podcast and
as far as I'm concerned what I.
The last thing I want my podcast to be
or any form of entertaining conversation
to be is just a sequence of speeches
that two people give to one another.
I mean this is one of the things that's
appealing about your podcast.
You know,
you come into this with a two to three
hour stretch ahead of you with
absolutely no idea what's going to
happen and no preconceptions about where
it's going to go and the joy of it is
the is the dance,
right?
Is the interplay like I don't know what
was going to be talking about in five
minutes time and neither do you.
So it's interesting to find out and I
feel like if you have too nice to other
people and don't interrupt them in order
to create that dance,
then there's basically one person
standing on the sidelines and another
person trying to do the two step or the
Flamenco by themselves.
But that depends on who the guest is.
Like there's certain guests like Dr
Rhonda Patrick is a perfect example.
All I do is wind her up and let her go.
I mean I interact with her a little bit
but as little as possible and she's just
such a dynamo that all I have to do is
ask her questions about the mechanisms
of certain vitamin absorption or
whatever we're talking about cold shock
therapy,
whatever the fuck it is.
And she just goes.
So in that case,
if I wanted to chime in and have a
normal conversation,
I'd fuck up the flow of the
conversation.
So going to know you to have the.
Whereas you and I,
we always have these silly conversations
that goes all over the place.
We're laughing,
we're serious.
It's very fluid and it goes back and
forth.
But you like,
I am not a fucking medical expert.
No.
I mean we're not experts in anything
which is,
which is what kind of what I like.
I like being a polymath.
I like having a lot of fingers in
different pies and polymath polymath
person who is for who's good at it can.
Can we get a definition on polymath?
Jamie?
I understand it.
To be a person who's interested in and
good at several different disciplines
like doesn't really focus on one.
I prefer smile.
A renaissance man,
a person of wide ranging knowledge or
learning well.
Experts in this
bands.
A significant number of different
subject areas.
That's an expertise.
Many expertise.
So a person who is known to draw on
complex bodies of knowledge to solve
specific problem.
Well that's the Wiki.
I was no,
look at the one above.
I was using the general,
the general use ranging knowledge or
learning.
Yeah,
it's.
Well that's just a more pronounced
version of it or more polymath.
I like it.
How much time do you spend distracted by
your phone?
I tried very low,
more,
less lately than ever.
I've been really good about it.
Over the last few months,
like I went to,
I was in the Nevada high country in the
desert last week,
just for a whole week.
I love this.
I love the.
I love that.
Just for your listeners,
so I got my book a trip to La.
I had a few meetings out here.
I'm always here at the last minute,
so I never had never planned in advance.
I send you a text,
don't hear from him for a couple of
days.
He gets back to me.
Sorry I've.
I've been in the wilderness like my
image of you is like you didn't have any
cell phone reception.
You're out in the woods and in my brain
you're like,
you're naked on the back of a horse.
Like shooting elk.
No,
I was trying to shoot
mule deer.
I was in the desert.
I was camping and those were the a group
of friends and we were on a hunting trip
and we were there for seven days.
No Cell Phone Reception,
no pee.
We occasionally saw another hunter,
but that's it.
We're just saying,
well,
they're on public land in the wilderness
and chasing after dear.
I got to do more of the seven days.
No cell phone.
How many female?
No,
there was five of us total.
One,
two,
three,
four,
five,
six.
Six of US total.
Great.
Yeah.
What'd you it off into?
Two groups.
We brought food,
brought a freeze dried foods,
these things called mountain ops,
the you add water to them.
This freeze dried fruits and dehydrated
foods and then we brought some whole
foods,
some actual real foods.
We ate that all by the,
like the fourth or fifth day and then we
not shitty freeze dried stuff,
but um,
we're hoping we going to eat a deer but
we struck out.
But it was a very fun time and even just
for the,
just the release of just being
disconnected from society.
But point is I try to do that several
times a year.
I do that maybe five times a year,
but more important than that,
I leave that fucking thing alone more
than I've ever done before.
I treat that thing.
If I spend too much time with it,
it's going to give me a disease.
I think it does.
Yeah.
And don't know why.
I don't
know what's changed.
I'm trying to put my finger on what it
is about my relationship,
especially to twitter.
That has changed because it's a very
wholesome.
Yeah.
Is that what it is?
With so many assholes,
you realize like in my real life,
how many people do I get in contact with
them?
Make me feel awful.
Very few.
Almost zero.
So you choose to hang out with your
friends,
choose to hang out with your
acquaintances.
All the people that you know,
you interact with people.
And even if I meet someone and they're a
stranger,
99 point nine times when I meet them,
it's a pleasant interaction.
It's very rare that I find someone who's
like really truly rude or where it can't
be worked out.
You know where you can't walk away from
it with a handshake and feeling good.
But this thing,
this w two dimensional conversation
where you don't know who the person is,
you don't know what,
where they're coming from.
You don't know what their agenda is.
You don't know what their life is like.
You don't know anything about them.
And they say something and you react to
that 130 plus characters.
So there are two problems,
right?
One is the,
the absence of destroy,
the distractedness that it kind of
fosters in our lives.
The fact that it rubs,
at least in my experience,
I can only speak for me,
it rubs me of moments of Zen that could
exist throughout the day by plunging,
by know.
We know physiologically that it gives
you a little dopamine hit every time you
notice that someone's mentioned you on
twitter and said something right.
I mean you get a true that they'd done
like studies with people.
Yeah.
You get a little hit,
you get a little drug hit.
I mean just a tiny drip,
drip,
drip.
It's like having a little piece of
candy.
I could just get dripped all day then
just sit around and just drip away.
Well,
people do drip,
drip,
crazy man.
And so there's that.
There's the fact that I'm constantly
getting that literally hit by,
by lugging on what is that an energy
thing when you're writing?
This is your brain Alpha Bank.
Yeah,
yeah,
sure.
Is it going to.
What does it contain?
I mean,
I know I should know this because I know
that you're the guy not,
don't worry about it.
It doesn't matter.
I'll talk to you off the aerobatics.
Just Dole it handled.
He did throw them all.
Last night there was only two left.
Hannibal stolen.
He sent me.
He sent me a text message this morning
laughing about how he stole all my Alpha
brain and I've got his address.
I'm like,
just give me your address.
I'll send you out.
Did he say anything else about to about
last night?
No.
No,
no.
Okay.
Good.
I don't want them to feel bad about what
was going to feel bad when it comes out.
Yeah.
Alright.
Uh,
so getting around that,
if you release it,
he's gonna feel bad even though maybe
he,
maybe Sam feel bad.
I don't know.
Well this comes back to twitter.
They'll feel bad if they read twitter
and they want to feel bad if that irate
to stay off twitter.
And so this is interesting.
So in addition to it being a kind of a
drug that you keep in your pocket,
that stops you from,
uh,
from ever just being alone with
yourself.
Have you seen that?
Louis ck bit by the way,
but he,
I think he's on Conan where he's talking
about why it doesn't want to give his
daughter's phone because like,
he's like,
you know,
that he was like,
he was stopped in traffic at lights and
he felt something inside that he didn't
like,
which was like the experience of being
human.
And so he reached for his phone and then
he realized that that's what we do.
Like the moment we start to feel the
great emptiness of being alive,
we reach for our phone and but one on
one occasion he didn't reach for his
phone and he pulled over the side of the
road and like started bawling his eyes
out and it was so cathartic and so
beautiful.
And then he recovered and he like had
this wonderful spiritual goal.
Some experience,
hold the fuck on.
He just started crying song.
There's some songs on the radio and it
was so beautiful.
Anyway,
he gets,
he waxes all lyrical and gets old poetic
Louis ck growing a vagina right in front
of her eyes.
You heard it here first.
Louie Joe Rogan says you have a vagina.
Sorry,
go ahead.
But anyway,
that's his point is like that's what
part of the experience of being human is
all about his side of the road with a
car listening to magic created by a
machine.
Yeah.
So human.
Maybe that's the wrong example.
Can Pussy.
So in addition to that then you're
talking,
people were tweeting.
Louis right now doesn't even have a
twitter anymore that's wise.
Deleted his twitter.
Well he sells out Madison Square Garden.
Yeah.
What does he need a fucking
disappointed.
I was one of these schmucks who bought a
ticket to see him at Madison Square
Garden a couple of weeks and I'm now I'm
thinking I used to see him when he was
at the seller like I used to.
I went at Austin,
come aspen comedy festival and saw him
with 50 people in the room.
Why am I going to be sitting?
I,
I'll feel like it's not going to be the
same in the garden,
but definitely not going to be the same
because it's a different show different
day.
Yeah.
Well,
so what you wanted to see the stadium so
you could see him at the comedy store in
here all the time.
Can you just come over to my place and
do it in my living room?
Shit.
Just got weird real.
He's crying.
You're inviting them over here.
I'm crying.
I'm going to be on virtual reality
watching porn and he's going to be doing
a bit.
Yeah man.
It's going to be different.
He's doing a big gigantic show and he's,
you know,
making a lot more money doing it that
way.
Yeah.
Well he apparently emptied out his bank
account to create that horror series.
No.
Horace.
And Pete was the animated series.
That's not unlimited.
No,
Harrison paid is a.
is like a,
an old school kind of multicam no studio
audience.
I never watched it.
Somebody told me it was animated.
Who said call me fucking assume they
were right.
I thought it was anime.
No it's not.
Oh Wow.
It has a drawing as it's icon.
Oh,
that's what it is.
so what is,
is it good?
It is innovative in a way that only a,
an altar like Louis would have the balls
to pull off.
Is that a tactful way of dodging the
question?
So I don't get it.
I'm just kidding the first.
So He's,
he fucks with you.
Right.
Remember his original Louie Lucky Louie
on Hbo,
like that was done to,
to sort of look like the and like with
bad
sets that Kinda shook and like,
you know,
bad studio audience was like a very sort
of 19 sixties Sitcom feel and everyone
criticized it because they're like,
oh that production values are terrible.
And he's like,
well yeah,
we fucking know that.
It's not like hbo doesn't have the money
to get a good set.
If we wanted a good set,
it's supposed to look like an old
sitcom,
but it's a very sort of metta like fuck
you concept.
And in a similar way,
what he's done here is he's basically
done a,
a dramatic,
sort of almost 19 seventies English
style play that is shot with no studio
audience with very,
very,
very long scenes and long takes that's
very dark and a bit whimsical and funny.
But I've,
I only got through a few episodes and
then it,
although I respected it,
it just wasn't a way that I want to
spend my evening,
if that makes sense.
Yeah,
that does make sense.
You mean it's a,
it's a piece of art.
You're creating something.
Yeah.
And also when you're creating something
like,
especially when it comes to like a
sitcom or something along those lines,
it takes a long time for it to find its
legs for you to figure out like what the
characters are all about and what,
how,
how the scenes are going to play out.
Every Sitcom that I've ever seen or the
ones that I've been a part of,
they take many,
many,
many episodes to create.
Like to figure out what,
what it actually is.
And then along the way,
like you have to have someone who
believes in it and they're financing it,
funding it,
and he loved him,
did all that shit on his own,
but he emptied out his fucking
and he's already made it back.
So now everything from now,
now he hasn't made any sales of it,
so he's made it all back just from
Internet sales according to him.
And then so whatever sale he ends up
making,
if he sells it Netflix or whatever,
he's apparently waiting for the emmy's
because he wants to.
He's hoping we'll get some of then will
be in a stronger negotiating position.
But all of that will be profit.
One hundred percent profit.
That's interesting.
So he did make the money back,
so he complained about it and then after
he complained about it,
he made more
complaining about it.
Thing was he claims that was just a
bullshit and media spin.
He was on Howard I think.
I think it was on Howard stern show us.
No,
no,
no.
He didn't lie.
What he was saying,
his point is that he was saying that he
spent all of his money and he was like
joking about how like,
you know,
I spent all my money on this thing and I
have no idea if it's gonna work and then
some fucking clickbait media outlet was
like Louis ck broke off to,
you know,
losing all of his money on the show.
He was like,
no,
I never expected to get my money back
immediately.
This is an experiment.
I put my money and it's an investment
and now like it's paid off.
That was all the money that he had and
he was just doing that and then he had
to go on tour.
I mean that was part of what you're
saying,
that he's going on tour for more money
because he had emptied his bank account.
Okay.
But that's different from losing you
money.
He invested his money in this thing and
now and while he was waiting for it to
pay for it to pay itself off them,
a bunch of news articles came out about
how he had no money.
Well,
that's what people want to hear.
They don't want to hear what a wonderful
investment in data and create creative
venture that was profitable,
wants to hear that he's a loser now.
Sucking dicks for homemade one
people are people are gross where they
want to hear about failure.
Hearing about a guy that has a,
you know,
a reasonable sort of a risk and it pays
off.
It's not a great story is already
successful.
It's not.
Nobody wants to hear that.
Why are we like that,
Joe?
Why do we want to see accidents?
If you want to see,
do you want to see someone to fly by on
a motorcycle?
You don't want to see some fly by
another guy.
Changes lanes in that car goes changes
lanes,
but I want to say blood and at least see
implying
can vw beetle on the highway on the way
here,
charred,
burned to a crisp on the side of the
road with the cops around it.
Whoa.
Is that a thing in Los Angeles
so that shouldn't be aware of.
Is that for insurance or something or is
it a massive accident?
Could have been anything.
We could have just been a fire,
you know,
how does it can catch fire,
but didn't vw go through some weird
fucking shit where they were lying
about,
uh,
the diesel.
But this was,
this was a beetle from the new ones.
No,
no,
not the ones with the little fake
daisies in the.
Probably caught on fire.
Those are shipped boxes that Joe,
thanks for listening everybody.
That's a show.
We solved it.
It's like CSI VW beetle.
Joe Joe fixed it up.
It was on fire.
No,
it was definitely on fire in a car that
accidentally caught on fire.
Actually,
I have,
now that you mentioned it.
Yeah,
when I was a kid,
we,
uh,
we were staying in the UK and we were
driving a friend's Jaguar,
Jaguar,
and uh,
it was one of the,
it was incredibly expensive.
This guy's a multi multimillionaire,
big star in the UK.
And so we are driving.
He lends it to us for a weekend while
we're there and it's the 19 sixties
vintage thing.
And we go out and drive through the
countryside and the car catches on fire.
Oh No.
So my parents had to pay to restore this
vintage Jaguar and the minute they
didn't accept responsible for this piece
of shit catching on fire,
he lent it to us.
Actually it was more than a weekend.
He was letting us use it because he was
out of the country.
I think we were staying there for a
couple of weeks.
He was letting us use this place,
letting us drive his car.
It's kind of a deal,
you know,
we're not gonna
yeah,
but whatever.
A car does not catch on fire does.
If it's a 19 sixties vintage Jaguar,
but it doesn't catch on fire because of
your fault.
No sunfire because it's a piece of shit.
You a piece of shit.
He knew it was a piece of shit because
it's in 1960 car.
You're driving it around and it acted
like a piece of shit and caught on fire
and then he wants you to pay.
I would have been like,
fuck you buddy.
How about you get your wires checked and
I sue you for almost killing me.
He didn't have your car.
He didn't want us to pay.
How much was it that I don't remember?
I was a child,
a little child,
probably a lot of them.
About 12.
It was a lot.
I remember my parents feeling like it
was a lot of money and it goes because
like smoke just started pouring out of
the bag
because it didn't even have a fucking
fire extinguisher.
No fucking shitbox.
Goddammit.
I'm mad.
I'm mad now.
British engineering excellence.
He was a wealthy guy that's got very
wealthy.
Well,
he's a piece of shit.
Your parents weren't rich and expensive.
Car parents weren't rich.
They were not rich.
Then he made them pay.
He didn't make them pay.
They refused to accept his offer.
Have to reimburse them.
Oh,
so they.
They.
If they insisted on paying.
Yeah,
he should've bought them something with
that money.
He probably did,
but my parents are nice.
People just stopped going to take money
from a friend of his.
Yeah,
but it's,
it's.
That's tricky man.
First of all,
what a wonderful guy for letting you
borrow this 19,
60 something job.
Those old jaguars are so bad ass.
Look,
and to have that long front knows God.
What a fucking know this was even
before.
So I'm trying to think of what model
that is with a very,
very long nose.
This is the one before that which was
around,
uh,
around a kind of shape from memory.
Pull it up,
Jeremy.
Come of what it is.
What,
what,
what was the shape of jags and the light
in the late sixties was talk about a gas
guzzler.
I mean,
you know,
it's an fi 12,
wasn't it?
Yeah,
it'd be a V.
I'm not even sure.
It might've been an in line eight.
Would that make sense?
Could have been of a 12.
I'm making things up.
I don't know anything about old jugs.
Yeah,
I said it was.
I mean it was,
it was certainly eight or 12.
It was not,
it was not nothing expensive at it.
Yeah.
It was one of those 19 sixties Jaguar.
MK Two.
What?
A pretty car.
Incredible.
It was a kind of car were when you
stopped at the lights,
people would wind down the windows and
we might see the one next to it is the
one I was thinking of.
The red one.
What is that one?
It's like a James Bond style that's so
dope.
I love on type II type 19 sixties type.
Those are so pretty.
You know,
they make those now with modern
underpinnings.
You can buy one of those.
These companies,
they,
they take an old Jaguar e type,
but they put a completely modern
suspension and brakes and modern engine.
And so you look like you're driving a
car.
Were you driving this?
That's a real new thing that they're
doing.
It's called Resto Mod.
That's great.
Super Common.
I have a 19,
65 corvette like that.
Really?
Yeah.
I love five.
What's the 60?
Can you show me a 16?
This is a picture of my mind.
So I did a video with Jay Leno.
We did Jay Leno's garage around.
Yup.
Yep.
I'll check that episode out.
Yeah,
that'd be great.
Um,
I heard him on your show as well.
You had him on my car.
Oh,
that's great.
I love those.
That's got a state.
How many cars have you got?
I've got a few.
You don't want to say that's a night on.
I've done a lose the,
the common man.
Touch,
I'm definitely not,
well,
I've lost it over,
but that,
uh,
that has a 500 horsepower ls,
one supercharged engine under the,
under the hood and it only weighs like,
it's probably less than 3000 pounds,
especially because it's a convertible.
At what point during this did jay come
in his pants immediately?
Yeah,
we had to change pants for Tai Chi is an
animal,
but it's um.
Oh,
speaking of coming in.
Oh No,
I'm not even going to go there.
I'll tell.
I'll talk to you about it after the,
after the podcast,
you know,
when the filter between your brain and
your mouth is no more flood gate come on
nights.
It's just something personal in my life.
I'm talking about your call.
And so,
uh,
I just want to come back to that cord
segway.
How do we go from.
The problem is the problem is that the
thing is so much less interesting than
whatever is in everybody's brain.
So dear listener,
I understand he is a,
here's a piece of advice,
whatever,
whatever you are thinking about right
now.
When you heard me talk about a coming
that is more interesting than the
reality of the story that I was going to
tell you.
Oh,
so just hang onto that.
Listen folks,
whatever he tells me after the show,
next podcast,
I'll tell you,
I will break our bond of trust.
I will violate violator practicing.
No,
it basically had to do.
I'll tell,
I'll tell you that.
I'll tell you the skeleton of the,
of the story,
which is that there's a medical
procedure that I am a,
a part of at the moment,
which a,
which requires me to potentially a.
it's an ivf related thing,
right?
So I had a meeting earlier this week and
ivf,
in vitro vitro fertilization trying to
make a baby and yes,
conceivably make a baby.
So,
uh,
so,
it didn't say with my baby and has to
robot baby ignorance,
right?
A super fucking superhuman.
I'm basically trying to create like
doll.
It'll be like the movie twins,
you know,
creating the ultimate superhuman
machine.
But,
uh,
I had a meeting at 11:00
AM on the same morning that I had to
donate my sperm sample.
Uh,
this,
this week,
a few days ago,
and so I'm in the meeting and like,
it's not going that well.
I'm not really feeling it.
So then I was like jerking off right
now.
No,
I literally,
I literally said to them these really
these important entertainment type.
So I was like,
guys,
I gotta I gotta be blunt.
Early this morning I came into a bucket
and created a human.
What the fuck did you do before 11?
I got bored with the conversation.
I'm out of here.
Just pull it up.
You were doing huff post live.
Why did you stop doing that?
The whole thing basically gradually
imploded.
I got out founding editor of the
Huffington post who sort of helped
create it with Ariana had been fired
slash supposedly resigned in November
and now Arianna was fired slash
supposedly resigned.
What last week or two weeks ago?
Fire the Huffington Post.
So happens you ask other people for
money.
Yeah,
basically.
So she.
So huffpost was bought by AOL in 2011.
Wait a minute.
AOL has money.
Yeah.
Well basically I will,
I will actually does have
money because they have some,
they get money.
It's really funny.
Two ways.
One is they've got some proprietary add
software which is helpful for websites
and the second is a lot of people in
America still unknowingly pay for
AOL.com
because back when they used to sell you,
well they don't know that they don't
have to anymore.
Like when they were in,
like in the nineties,
they would send out cds.
Apparently I wasn't here then,
but the iol was the place where
Americans got online and so those.
Here we go,
two point 1 million CNN money to lose.
I will dial up and they pay.
They pay for that.
Scroll that down.
I want to read that.
Oh my God.
Seventy percent of Americans are
connected to the Internet over much
faster broadband,
the average us broadband speed,
blah blah blah,
blah,
blah.
200 times faster than the 56 k per
second dial up even smartphones and more
than 100 times faster than that.
Yeah,
so the average AOL dial up user is
paying 20 bucks a month.
Whoa.
20 bucks.
And managing pain,
John Upstate should pay you for
dialogue.
So what is this?
People that just live in like really
super rural.
They probably can't get it yet or we can
get better.
That's right.
Or they're just old Hicks and they don't
know better.
That's amazing.
So she.
So aol basically.
I mean they say that iol bought happened
in post,
but really it was Ariana essentially
becoming a senior manager of aol or
whatever her title was at aol because
iol had no future and they were like,
oh,
huff post is cool with the kids,
so let's have,
let's get in on some of that action.
Then last year if a rise and bought AOL
and in part of that whole shake up the,
you know,
she got ousted.
I mean,
let's be frank.
She is eccentric and has her own hobby
horses like her.
I mean she spends a lot of her time
boyfriends helping host a thing in
America.
Is it that term?
If I was an old rich lady,
I'd have some hobby horses though.
Dudes that need money for the gym.
Sure.
No,
I'm not implying that duds.
And given Viagara and send them over.
Do you want to fucking Jaguar?
Boy,
get it hard.
Uh,
not a boy toy.
A hobby.
Horses is a hobby that is a personal
interest that you spend way too much
time on instead of.
Yeah,
I mean it might be.
It's probably in Australia and she
spends,
in other words,
she spends a lot of time going around
the world giving speeches about why you
should get more sleep.
Really.
She's begun to sleep.
That's it.
We read a whole book about it.
How much sleep do you need?
She read a whole book.
Really?
Yup.
And it.
All it is,
is one of those books where you
basically know in the first page what
the whole book is going to be with them
and just pat out the remaining hundred
80 pages.
That's one of those,
Huh?
And it's just about how much you need to
recover or get enough sleep.
I think Dan shine it is the sleep
revolution live.
Listen,
you're rich
lady.
Most people aren't rich.
They can't fucking sleep all time.
Bitch.
The sleep revolution.
How many fucking people I know that are
participating in that revolution
unknowingly,
comics,
while fucking call them before noon.
They believed,
dude,
why'd you call?
Totally.
Yeah.
I mean I,
if it were up to me,
I would stay up very late and get up
pretty late as well.
I mean some people are just like that.
I felt bad about it and then I found out
that Sam Harris and Tim Ferris do it as
well.
So fuck,
fuck.
They stay up late and go to bed and get
up late.
Yeah.
Well,
um,
I'll get my best work done late at night
when everyone's asleep and I almost,
I almost feel like
it sounds so woo,
but this is what I believe.
Uh,
I believe there's a different feeling to
the air at like two,
3:00
in the morning because almost everyone
is asleep and I feel like there's less
signal.
I think you get something from people.
I think if there's an intangible quality
that people exude,
that people expressed that they
broadcast and when you're around them,
that's why certain people have bad
energy and certain people have good
energy and some people are warm,
some people are weird.
I think there's a thing that we don't
know how to quantify and that it's about
people and I think that is entirely
possible if there's a hum of a city,
like a,
uh,
like a literally a,
a feeling that you get when a bunch of
people are thinking and awake and
conscious and you get a different
expression when those people are asleep.
And so I know that when I'm writing at
two,
3:00
in the morning,
which is when I do my best work,
everybody else's conked out.
So I feel like I have more clarity.
I feel like I have more peace and I can
write better,
might be total bullshit,
but there might be something to it.
You're right.
That is.
We were totally right.
It's possible.
It's also possible that there are visual
and auditory cues that just make it
feel,
make you feel like here in a special
place,
right?
It's dark.
There's no.
There's no one moving.
There's no one making noises.
Here's another reason why I might
be interested in believing that.
Not what you're saying,
but what I'm saying this because when I
go on these camping trips,
hunting trips where no cell phone
service,
there's a very different feeling to the
world when there's no service.
You feel different like do you feel
wait when your cell phone has no
service,
no cell phone,
no Internet,
no signals,
there's no nothing that would the.
How would the thinking hum of a human
mind get transmitted through to your
phone?
Not to your phone.
I'm not saying it gets transmitted to
your phone.
I'm thinking that there are signals that
you are receiving all the time.
Like in this room,
we have wifi there,
cell phone,
there's radio,
there's a lot of shit in the air and
there's just all of those waves somehow
resonate.
You can send them.
I don't know if you can,
but I know my computer can and I know my
phone,
but do you think you can sense the
mental states of human beings?
Which is
what I thought you were saying
it was what I was saying,
but I'm thinking that there's more than
one kind of signal that is being
expressed not just by people but by
society in general.
The hum of the city,
the buzz,
the like,
you know,
that feeling that you get of New York
City,
like it's a lie.
Yes,
absolutely.
You know,
I wonder if that's not because you're
dealing with 7 million people stuffed
into this little tiny areas.
Yeah,
definitely.
It's definitely that.
The question is what is the transmission
mechanism by which that presence makes
itself known?
I mean,
one of.
I totally know what you mean about
campaign because one of the most
beautiful places that I could ever be is
in the outback at night.
Nothing around for miles.
I love desserts.
I love,
you know,
I drove through Nevada once and I've
done a couple of trips around Australia,
right?
Deep into the middle of nowhere and
there's just something so I mean for
start the blazing sky of stars so bright
that if anyone hasn't seen them,
you would not believe that this guy
could be that bright and then the Shia
scientists silence so silent.
It's just.
It's almost a noise in itself.
It's almost a deafening noise in the.
In the absence of noise.
It's not just a silence.
No,
I feel like it's an absence of signal.
It's a silence and an absence of signal.
I think we've become accustomed to the
signal of a city,
the signal of all the people and all the
things that are being broadcasted around
us and all the waves and all the
different shit that we're we're
experiencing unknowingly might be
bullshit,
but it might.
I mean there's.
There's people that are concerned with
Wifi.
They're concerned with Wifi because
there's not a long history of us using
Wifi or even sell cellular signals.
We know for a fact that they interfere
with bees.
Bees,
a form of communication.
It gets interfered with by Cell Towers,
cell towers and cell phone signals in
general,
and that all these signals that are
flying through the air that are reaching
your and my phones and everyone else's
phones,
so the bees are actually taking these
things into just imagine the world where
bees before the 19 nineties,
they're like hanging out,
having a great time,
but communicating with each other,
but those businesses and then all of a
sudden they're here,
a Jackhammer in the background.
Like what the fuck is that?
Well,
the,
I think this,
they think that Sona is one explanation
for why wiles beach themselves and why
so many migratory patterns underwater as
fucked up as well.
Have you heard that theory doesn't make
sense.
You know,
the,
the military and the,
um,
the US military does all kinds of,
uh,
I don't even,
I can't remember the name of it,
but long distance sona so that,
you know,
really,
really reaching out.
Part of the spying system I think is,
is,
it might not be sonar maybe,
but anyway,
the gist of this is correct.
Even if the details are not that they,
they basically blanket,
you know,
hundreds or thousands of miles of ocean
in these things that we can't hear that
we thought had no impact on anything but
they can,
but you can notice behavioral changes
in,
in Wiles,
just vast distances away from these
submarines that are conducting these
things.
So it's entirely conceivable that with
bees and other animals are tuned into
things that were not tuned into.
I mean the thing I love about getting
away from all that is like the first
day.
I don't know if you find this,
but I find that the first day,
the absence of all of that can seem a
little bit irritating in some way or a
little bit.
Like there's nothing to do.
Like I feel sort of fidgety when I first
go to the desert.
That's why you got to go hunting,
but.
Well yeah,
that'd be great to have a very primal
task in front of you show up.
But I mean after three,
four,
five days,
then you use your pace just slows down
into.
It almost makes me feel some kind of
kinship to aborigines or something.
I like people who are a lot more
connected to land and New York City,
uh,
and you get into it just a different
sort of headspace,
different relationship to the earth and
the soil and the sky and all that.
I mean,
it sounds very hippy dippy,
but you can definitely feel it when
you're there.
Yeah.
It does sound Hippie Dippie,
but I think you're right,
there's something going on and I think
there's something going on that's
natural.
When you're,
you're,
you're disconnected from all this
unnatural stuff.
They're so attractive to us.
I mean,
the reason why you're seeing these
people at dinner all touching their
phones and playing with their phones,
something is happening to them,
right?
There's some sort of compelling thing.
It's not like they're that compelled to
read,
like have a diamond from them because if
you had books in front of these people,
would they be fucking with those books?
And same with the reading people's
tweets.
No,
no.
They will focus
and concentration.
This is the,
this is the big thing.
This is where there's a book called the
shallows by a can't remember.
I did a segment on this discovery
science channel show called based on his
google making a stupid,
which is,
do you know that book?
There's a book,
is Google making us stupid?
And there's this kind of ideological
battle between these two guys.
I come up with their names.
One of them is Nicholas,
someone about the question of,
is all of this technological input,
uh,
you know,
making a smarter because we've got so
much more data at our fingertips and
we're so much more nimble
intellectually,
or is it making us more stupid because
we're more reliant on outside sources of
data.
We don't have to remember things anymore
and we're constantly skipping across the
surface of information instead of
digging down into it.
And I think it's an interesting question
about you say,
would those people be reading books will
know?
And do they even read as many books as
they would have if you know,
if they'd lived 100 years ago?
Because an argument can be made that
were really good these days at
multitasking.
We're really good at jumping from
facebook to twitter to the next thing to
do.
I'm writing something,
but then a little egg email pops up and
then a text message comes through,
so I'm constantly distracted and
constantly busy,
but there's that old line of a company
who said it,
yes,
you're busy and a busy,
but what's the point?
Right?
Like what are you up to?
What are you doing?
What are you being productive and being
efficient?
Are you achieving anything that's really
important to you?
Buisiness is is the scourge of modern
life in a way because it gives you a
fake way of feeling like you're doing
something when you're actually,
when you're actually not,
and the argument is,
yeah,
we're better at juggling all this shit
than someone in the 18 hundreds would've
been would've been,
but our way is capable of having the
patience to read Dostoevsky.
Could you read Moby Dick?
They don't like.
Do people sit down and really devote
themselves to a deep dive rather than
just an across the surface horizontal?
If you put that thing down for a little
bit,
you can buy my business.
Does it disincline you to doing that?
I think so.
I think something's going on and I think
something's going on that we haven't
quite recognized yet and I think one of
the things that's going on with cell
phones is this as a step towards this
symbiotic relationship that we're going
to have with computers and Internet and
communication and what we're talking
about with virtual reality is a part of
that and it's all becoming more and more
integrated,
more and more invasive and more and more
prevalent.
And I think what we're doing,
and I've said this time and time again,
so forgive me if you've heard this
before.
Other people who are listening,
I think we are a caterpillar that is
giving birth to some sort of an
electronic butterfly.
I think we are going to become something
different and I think this is a step.
I think we're building a cocoon.
We're building an electronic cocoon by
encompassing and engrossing ourselves in
these electronic aids,
these things that were connecting to
constantly all day.
We are getting more and more attached
them to the point where the other day I
left my phone in my house.
I drove down the street and panicked and
how a you turn turn right back around.
How's this going to be?
I was just kidding.
I was just going to go to the store real
quick.
Yeah.
I couldn't do without my phone.
I'm like,
fuck.
My phone turned around and that feeling
is.
It's a weird feeling.
It's a.
it's a strange feeling and I think that
that feeling is.
There's something I think is a natural
thing that we're doing.
I think that as technology becomes more
and more innovative and it more and more
powerful and it can do more and more
things for you and connect you to more
and more people and more and more
different and involving ways,
I think it's going to eventually lead to
the next step and that next step is some
sort of an integration of it into your
biology.
I want to get to that in one second
because I've said that to me before and
I think it's really interesting.
I'm on the question of leaving your
phone at home and freaking out.
I mean another.
This comes back to the,
the,
the anecdote that I was telling you
earlier about the friend of a friend
who's a comic who's gotten rid of his
phone because I love podcasts.
I listen to podcasts all the time,
love your show,
love a whole bunch of different of
different shows and I will habitually be
listening to a podcast while I'm
brushing my teeth,
listening to a podcast while I'm driving
around,
you know,
whatever,
whatever it is.
And today,
uh,
I was interviewing Andy Kindler,
they comic for my podcast
and he like literally he was downstairs
at the hotel where I was staying and
just to go down and pick him up.
I had exited the room without my phone
to listen to a podcast.
I walked back into my room,
open the podcast app on my phone,
put my earphones in,
find the podcast that I was listening to
waste like 25 seconds,
one minute task because heaven forbid I
should go outside and get in an elevator
and go down and meet Andy kindler
without listening to what?
Fifty five fucking seconds of the latest
radio lab episode that I have to listen
to.
How dumb am I?
How distracted do I need to be by people
speaking in my ears or conscious?
Be with myself for an elevator ride from
the seventh floor in your defense,
how engaged are you in this wonderful
podcast where you're gaining all this
knowledge and it's fascinating and
intriguing?
You don't want to let it go.
Thank you,
Joe.
I feel better.
How much do I owe you for this session?
Uh,
so being a friend,
if we are,
if we are building a cocoon,
then the butterfly,
artificial intelligence.
And do we play a role because we become
it?
A Kurzweil will say,
yeah.
So occurs.
Kurzweil will say that the artificial,
until the whole question of artificial
intelligence is slightly a red herring
because we will be become the artificial
intelligence.
We will unify ourselves with machines in
such a way that human intelligence,
that biological intelligence,
artificial intelligence become
essentially indistinguishable.
I think it's possible that that's true.
I also think it's possible that we could
have both.
We could.
We could literally have artificial life
forms that we've created along with us
being inter connected with some sort of
a computer that enhances our
intelligence that we carry with us
everywhere or that as a part of our body
and then it becomes something like
Kurzweil's talked about these computers,
these nano computers that are as small
as red blood cells,
so they're going to inject into our
bloodstream to find cancer and other
diseases and all these things.
I think it is entirely possible that
there's something like that.
I was going to enhance intelligence and
then you're going to have something that
you can inject into your body and you're
going to be like Lucy from that scarlet
Johannson moving.
It's not outside the realm of
possibility that both things can happen
at the same time that you could have a
literal artificial intelligence,
something that is created by a person
that can think and talk.
Did you see x Mokena?
Yes.
Loved it.
Actually interviewed both of the,
uh,
the actives and also the writer,
the writer of that,
Alex,
uh,
I forget his name,
but very interesting guy grappling with
a lot of these big issues.
I mean,
he's genuinely motivated by and
interested in the whole question of what
it means to be conscious and self aware.
Yeah.
Amazing.
Amazing movie,
but that,
that,
that's possible too.
That kind of thing.
Where are you going to make a fake human
and you know,
it,
it could be confined like they were in
some sort of a way where it didn't have
the option to access the worldwide web
and nor did it have the option to
exponentially
increase its own abilities.
Because that's one of the things that
all of these people sort of agree with
is that the launch of artificial
intelligence is not simply going to be,
oh my God,
we have an artificial intelligent thing
here now,
but it's going to be that this
artificial intelligence is going to be
infinitely smarter than us,
almost instantaneously because it's
going to innovate on itself.
That's right.
Yeah.
So yeah,
I mean,
I've heard Sam talk about this as well,
but I mean 10,000,
10,000
years precisely in a minute or
something.
Yeah,
so it's.
It's amazing.
So when you,
when you say something to me,
my brain is operating at presumably
roughly the same speed that your brain
is operating and neither of us were
inebriated and other of us are
incredibly tired.
So presumably the experience of the
passage of time of this conversation for
us is roughly one to one.
Maybe slightly off.
Imagine if every single thing that you
said I had the experience of basically
waiting for several years to figure out
the perfect way to answer that and then
they're not going to answer it.
That the artificial intelligence is
going to be so far ahead of that because
we're telling me I'm the official
intelligence right now,
and so I've just been sitting here
wondering what is the best possible
response?
Well,
of course I'm going to end up getting
better responses.
What I find interesting is if you make
this x market a robot,
I think it'll be easier to make a robot
that seems,
that passes the turing test.
That seems to us to be self aware.
Then it will be to know whether or not
it really is self aware.
Right,
and and is there a meaningful
difference?
I mean this is what's interesting to me,
is there,
is there a meaningful difference between
a computer that can completely
convincingly reassure you that it is,
that it has feelings and a computer that
actually fails or what?
I think there is a ceiling.
What,
what difference does it make it?
Here's,
here's the thing.
Like we were so connected to this idea
that the only life that's real is carbon
based life of biological intelligence
cells,
life,
death,
life span.
It has a.
it's got a finite reality.
It's eventually gonna rot.
I mean that's what we think of life is
and that's the only thing that's worth
anything to us because we're so we're,
we're,
we're just so inexorably connected to
what we are and that we don't.
We only think that's the only kind of
life,
but there could easily be in life form
that exists in the form of ideas.
You know,
and I've often thought about this in
terms of like the word of the word
alien,
like people always love that expression,
alien intelligence and has,
have we ever been visited by aliens.
I often think that if intelligence keeps
expanding and keeps growing at the rate
that it has with human beings and you
compare us to people that lived a few
thousand years ago versus today,
it's impossible not to conclude that
people have gotten far more intelligent,
far more capable and have far more
abilities than we did.
Whether it's technologically or you
know,
through what the way we can manipulate
matter in our environment.
It's fought,
were far more capable now.
Right now,
if we can continue to go from here till
you know,
thousands and thousands of years from
now,
we could get to the point where we can
inject ideas and send ideas to each
other in the form of like thoughts.
Yep.
Now how do we not know that imagination
itself is not a life form that wants us
to continue to innovate and create and
build something different,
that it's not just a function of the
brain.
It's not just a function of the the,
the,
the conscious mind to be curious and a
byproduct of our time as hunter
gatherers and this constant seeking of,
of food and shelter and safety that is
causing us to innovate,
but instead these ideas are almost like
a,
like a signal that's in the midst and
that imagination itself,
which is responsible for every single
thing you see in this room and in this
city and on this planet that human
beings have created.
All of it came out of the imagination,
all of it.
And why is this imagination so fucking
hungry for innovation?
Why don't we have the capacity to
recognize that phones are small enough,
computers are fast enough is a big
enough.
Cars are quick enough.
Let's stop right here.
Let's stop right here and work for the
better good of humanity.
Every era.
You could have said that Joe,
that's,
that's why fuck the sixties and Shitbag
cars and they're fucking.
That's what people will say in a half
century ago.
You want to drive all those old shitty
jaguars and catches on fire.
No,
but you know what I'm saying?
I do.
Right?
You're right.
I mean,
you could have said that,
but what is it?
What is going on?
Like what is imagination?
Well,
I think anyone who works in a creative
field or maybe anyone who,
even those who don't will agree that
there is something mysterious about the
Muse for want of a better word.
Right?
I mean there are moments when I'm
writing where,
where something just dropped into my
head and I'm like,
that's great.
And certainly people who write music or
who painted,
you know,
they will get in that zone and you find
that flow and it is like you're writing
something else.
It's not like you're the author of it
entirely.
Um,
so on the question of whether or not
computers would fit in what,
when you say like,
what would it mean to say?
Does a computer actually feel?
I think,
do you know the.
Have you heard of the essay?
What is it like to be a bat?
I think it's,
I think it's called Thomas Nagel was a
20th century philosopher and this was a
foundational sort of philosophical
essay.
It's only about 10 pages long.
I'm really kind of trying to nail down
the fundamentals of um,
I can't remember the field of,
uh,
of,
of philosophy,
but it basically a philosophy of mind
where his point is it's only meaningful
to talk about things,
feelings if you can say like,
what is it,
what is it like to be a,
an x?
And,
and so what is it like to be a bat?
That's a meaningful question.
I mean you can,
you can sort of look at the brain,
you can try to figure out how it
responds to its sonar,
what that might feel like.
Is that a kind of a vision as a kind of
a sound?
If I pick up this cop and I say what is
it like to be this cop?
I mean that's essentially meaningless.
What do you mean?
What,
what is it like to be a cop?
The cop is,
is nonsense.
It has no input.
It has no experience of,
of life.
So my question about artificial
intelligence is what would have to
happen for it to be meaningful to say
what is it?
What is it like to be that computer?
And I think that's more than just a
computer that can be creative or a
computer that can have imagination or a
computer that can spew out something
that's interesting.
I mean we already have computers that
can,
for example,
write operas,
bad operas,
but operas that conform to operas.
Like we're not far away from having
computers that can write books that are
at least as good as the average book
that you get an airport bookstore,
right?
Just a general book,
but for a computer to write,
proust is going to be difficult for a
computer to Beethoven is going to be
difficult and when it does,
I'm not saying it won't happen.
I'm just saying this nation in human,
in humans,
there's some.
There's something about biological
intelligence so far,
which is you,
which is uniquely creative and
imaginative and what the fuck is it?
Yeah.
Without the imagination.
We're just an animal.
The are not very imaginative.
You know they're not,
but they still have an experience of
life in a way that my computer and phone
dunt for now,
for now and so something's going to
happen.
I mean at some point they will be.
I mean,
I sort of agree with the materialist on
this because I'm not a religious person
that our brains are surely all of all of
this experience of being made for,
for most of us have this word
[inaudible],
which means the actual experience of
experiencing knowledge and data.
So there's this thought experiment that
I remember from,
from university where imagine a child is
born in a black and white room.
They can't see themselves.
They just strapped down.
So they kinda see any color,
right?
But they learn everything there is to
know about color,
but scientifically school in the nature
of the light spectrum,
and I understand that old,
I know that the sky is blue.
They know that they don't.
They've never seen this guy,
but they know everything there is to
know about the science of color.
Then one day after they've only ever
seen black and white,
you release them into the world and they
look around at trees and birds and skies
and the ocean.
What would their response be?
Would they respond to simply be,
oh,
well,
I already know everything about cholera.
You know,
I,
I perceived the world previously as a
kind of a,
a paint by numbers picture,
so I already know that the sky was blue
and I know what the wavelength of light
is that makes blue
or would they be overwhelmed by how
beautiful and amazing the world looks.
Of course,
they'd be overwhelmed by how,
how much richer the experience of
experiencing color is than merely
knowing and understanding about the
spectrum of light and that difference is
what philosophers call the,
the experience of having an experience
which,
which is very hard to like.
What is that difference?
They already had.
This person already had everything you
could possibly know about color,
what was added,
what was added to the mix here that made
them impressed colors.
A purely visual thing.
I don't think it's the best example
because if you're.
You don't feel color,
so if you cannot see color and then you
can see color.
There's no way you could've known
everything about color without seeing
it,
but what is it that you didn't know?
Because I didn't know what the visual
aspects of different hues are.
You hadn't experienced them,
but you would have been able to answer a
question yes.
Assigned.
Just kind of answered,
you know,
what question would you not have been
able to answer?
What are you don't know what it looks
like to see red,
but how.
But you would have been able to answer
exactly what red means.
No conversation.
You would have no.
Not without seeing no understanding of
quality or analogy.
I'm absolutely nonsense argument.
No.
A scientist would have been able to have
the person who's never seen color and a
person who has seen color and there's
nothing they could ask either of them
that would,
that would make a difference.
Doesn't matter.
Let them that haven't experienced that
visual aspect of precisely.
Right?
So that's what I'm telling you it in.
So that's what I told you about.
Just the signal,
but it's a signal that the person who is
seeing in black and white does not
receive.
Once they receive that signal,
it'd simply becomes more data and then
there's no more data.
That's the thing.
It's not more data.
It's a visual experience of data.
Okay.
Data know this is we're splitting hairs
here because if you're looking at red,
like if you're looking at something and
you just see a black and white,
right?
Yeah,
and then all of a sudden someone adds
something and you see color,
right?
They turn on the switch.
That's data.
So suppose that the black and white
thing that in your world,
in your paint by numbers world red is
the number 19 and that object had a 19
written on it.
Then you knew that it was red.
You don't know what red is.
Try Try saying what the color blue is
timeline man,
but I think the point,
the point that you're arguing is
precisely the point that philosophers
wrestle with,
which is if,
if the.
If the question we're asking is what
does it mean to actually feel and be
self aware and be conscious,
what would it mean for an artificial
system to feel the way that we do?
What would it mean for artificial
intelligence to actually have interests
for it?
To be meaningful for us to say what's it
like to be this computer in a way that
it's not meaningful to say what's it
like to be this cup?
Then quality was one of these
interesting things that's sort of.
That's intrinsic to the experience of
being human and you're totally right.
It is part of our foundational knowledge
because living without it would be sort
of meaningless,
but it's very,
very tricky to understand exactly
what the difference between that and
pure data is.
There clearly is a difference.
I mean it.
It's clearly different.
There's a difference now.
It was clearly different for me to be me
alive and experiencing things then
merely than merely for me to be,
for example,
an intelligence that is just behaving
like me,
but actually the lights are off inside.
Right.
Okay.
But why do you assume the lights are off
once the connections are being made?
How do you not know that artificial life
won't be a life?
That's why I think it will be at some
stage and it certainly can be.
That's we already know what I'm saying.
It right.
That that,
that difference is the difference at
which,
how are we going to know where,
when,
once that,
where that boundary is
being breached,
draft and know this is what I think,
I think what we're trying to define it
in some way where this is real life and
that won't be real life.
The same thing as we're talking about
virtual reality,
like this is reality and that will be a
fake virtual reality.
I don't necessarily know that I'm not
necessarily convinced that this reality
that we experienced because we have
gravity because we have cells because we
feel the weight of our feet on the
ground as we walk.
Once that is replicable,
once there's something that you can plug
into that gives you all have that exact
experience,
but it's not happening in the physical
sense and it's indiscernible.
What is it still happening?
It's absolutely still happening.
The experience is still the same.
So is your consciousness what guides
you?
Is your.
Is the data that hits your
consciousness?
Is that what's important or does it have
to be something that you could put on a
scale or measure with a ruler or or c
over a timeline?
What is reality is the real question
becomes,
and that's when people who really think
there's a significant possibility,
there's a real physicist that we are
living in some form of a simulation
currently that it's one of the reasons
why reality is so preposterous is that
reality is a work of fiction and that if
we keep going as we are today,
there's gonna come a time where we are
able to create some form of virtual
reality that's indistinguishable from
reality.
So the question becomes how will we know
when we're in it?
Yeah.
Elon Musk,
uh,
is,
is a big proponent of this as well.
You know,
he,
he believes,
he believes that it's almost certain
that we are in a,
in a virtual reality right now,
just because the proportion.
I think the argument goes along the
lines of at some point in the future,
there are going to be so many virtual
realities that the likelihood of us
being in one of those instead of in the
earthly reality that we think
Erin is going to be enormously more
probable.
Well,
we can go one better.
That even the earthly reality is so
fucking bizarre and filled with holes
that the.
I mean the very adams that we,
we have that,
that exist,
that encompass every single aspect of
everything that we see that's physical,
are mostly nothing.
And then we,
these subatomic particles that blink in
and out of existence and they can be in
a super state where they're moving and
still at the same time they come and go.
They go somewhere.
We don't know where they're going
and forth between this dimension and
another dimension that we've done.
Have you seen stranger things on
Netflix?
The underside,
which brings us to,
to Iosco.
So,
um,
about a month ago I tried asked for the
first time and I'd want it to do it for
awhile.
And a friend of mine.
Have you done with the psychedelics
before that?
I've done psychedelic.
I've never done DMT,
but I've done so I've done acid and
mushrooms,
but not for not for a few years.
Had some of the best experiences of my
life on acid and mean some of the most
eyeopening and just revelatory and
extraordinary experiences.
Had a bad mushroom trip and haven't
really done many psychedelics since
then.
Pad.
How much I was in Amsterdam.
It was too much for the circumstances
under which I was trying to hold it
together.
I just try to do it in public.
You're not supposed to do that.
It's going out on a trip with my brother
in Amsterdam,
like wandering around.
It was like we were just.
It was.
It was one of those moments where like,
you can't even remember the thought that
you had like half a second ago.
So your entire experience of life is
just a fractured.
You're
supposed to be quiet laying down
somewhere.
I know,
I know.
I know that.
I knew all that,
but I was better.
I was too good for any advice that I
could get.
Grams,
I don't know because,
well it was mushrooms in your hand how
big it was.
It was a handful.
It was a significant.
Any influence?
It was a lot.
Yeah,
I'm sure.
And we ended up like,
you know,
we tried to go into a cafe thinking that
that would be better,
but by the time we,
we've made our way through the thicket
of impenetrable chairs.
That seems like there were too many
tables,
like none of it made sense.
I didn't know where the walls were so
then I'm sitting down and like I don't
know how to order tea anymore and like
she's,
I don't know what people are asking for.
I don't know when I'm supposed to pay or
how I'm.
And then it just became too stressful
and I was like,
have to get out of the cafe.
It was just all of that.
And then I don't even remember like how
long have you even been in the cafe at?
People looking at me because it was just
one of those weird,
like just not good.
But I mean I will ask is a bit different
because it's,
it's a shamanistic ceremony.
That's presided over by this Peruvian.
Where'd you do it?
Dude?
I New York in the city.
Uh,
yeah,
in Brooklyn.
Uh,
they rent out a,
like a dance studio or some space.
Did you know the other people you're
doing it with?
Only one of them was my friend.
He's done it a bunch of times.
He's done it a lot.
Um,
and starts about nine or 10 in the
evening.
Goes until about four to six in the
morning.
And uh,
either we're about 20 people there,
so it was a reasonably large group and
you're all sort of lined up along the
walls with yoga mats and whatever else
you want a bucket to vomit into.
And He,
uh,
gives a little speech.
He's down in Peru a lot.
He's been doing this for decades.
You know,
this has been going on for thousands of
years among,
for people who don't know what Ios is,
it's a hallucinogen from the Amazon.
It's been fundamental to a lot of South
American religions for thousands of
years.
Competent Tory hallucinogenic combines
the leaves of one plant,
the vines of another.
So one of them is dmt and the other one
is called an Mao inhibitor and a mano,
amy and Oxidizes Mao and your body
produces it and your stomach and your
gut and what it does is it keeps you
from getting high on Dmt,
which exists in thousands of different
plants.
So if you were eating a lot of the
things that we eat on a regular basis,
if he didn't have monoamine oxidase and
I'm sure it has other functions as well,
but it would cause you to get high on
certain grasses and plants and many,
many different ones.
So your body produces this stuff to
break that down.
There you go.
Glad I got you.
Hit Ya.
I didn't even drink it orally.
Active version of DMT.
And they essentially figured out a
solution for dealing with the motto,
aiming oxidase that your stomach
produces
long before they even knew what any of
that shit was thousands of years ago
when they were just screwing around in
the Amazon.
Yeah.
We don't even know how really,
how old it is because they don't really
have much of a tradition.
But um,
they claim it's,
I mean they claim that it's been
fundamental,
but who knows,
it's a verbal little notion.
We don't know how they figured it out.
We don't have any of those things.
I mean it's a,
it's a very interesting experience
because the,
I went into it sort of wanting what
everyone,
I guess,
once out of a psychedelic experience,
which is some kind of like con opening
up of your mind and connection to the
cosmos.
Awesome connection to your own true self
and your connection to life force and
the mystery of consciousness and
everything.
But I will ask is very interesting.
It almost felt like it was a character
in the trip.
The trip was very visual and the first
portion of it was like just closed.
I would close my eyes.
It was just an incredible expect a candy
collar universe of weird like Pez
dispensers,
dancing and all kinds of amazing visual
hallucinations.
I opened my eyes and the person next to
me,
I couldn't tell whether or not they were
there or not or whether they'd gone.
I think that he'd gone to the restroom
but.
And I could sit and it's not that dark.
I couldn't see that he was not there,
but I still felt like he was there and
not in like a woo.
All his spirit is still the airway,
just like I was literally not sure what
criteria I would need to use to
establish whether or not there was a
person sitting next to me.
Like the visual data was there.
I could see that there was just a yoga
mat,
but I was like,
where'd he go?
Is he white?
He said,
no,
he's,
he's
there.
Then where's his physical body?
No,
you did see someone sitting next to me.
I think there is bang on.
Then where is he would like.
It was literally and also it was very
because some people
vomiting.
I mean some people have haven't
experienced where they're crying and
bawling their eyes out.
They go to the darkest places.
I was a bit nervous beforehand because
it shows the claim that what they claim,
what the shamans claim is that it shows
you what you need to see about yourself
at that moment and that can be wonderful
or that can be negative,
but whatever it is,
it's like Iowaska has a personality.
It's like it is Gaia.
It's like,
it is the power of laugh.
It's like it is,
you know,
the Amazon itself,
it's like the lungs of the earth or
something and it brings you in and you
just have to roll with it because if you
try to fight it,
it will crush you.
Um,
what I loved,
what I was heartened by was the true
sort of Josh steps that came out during
the experience was a very like,
funny,
not funny ha ha,
but like just joyful person.
I could.
There was no,
there were,
there were moments of darkness and there
were moments of hallucinations were
like,
there was the bloodied face of a woman
up in the right hand side of my
periphery.
And I started going towards it and then
I was like,
I consciously sort of said to the Ios
got,
you know,
we can go there.
I didn't want,
I knew that if I tried not to go there,
then it would get worse and worse.
So it was like,
we can do that and that's fine and we
can make this a bad trip if you want.
Frankly,
it's just more interesting over on the
fun candy colored side and then it just
sort of faded away.
So I think there's a,
there's something about relinquishing
yourself to it and not trying to control
it and not transfer of power.
A lot of road trips come from is just
trying to,
trying to control with your ego,
trying to control the experience.
So I sort of gave myself into it and
like there were moments where like the
funniest thing that you can ever do.
I know you're a comic.
So here's a little tip.
You'll enjoy this joe.
Next time you need to have the best life
of your life,
just pull a blanket over your head.
Hilarious.
According to Josh steps,
whilst on Ios Guy,
funniest thing I'd ever done.
I was like giggling madly underneath a
blanket with the blanket over my head.
That's why drugs are illegal.
Look at them.
I'm just laughing or nothing.
It was like,
it was so funny.
And then so I was.
So to get back to the point about what I
was looking for with some kind of
insight into the mystery of
consciousness and what you were just
sort of talking about,
about like the imagination and you know,
self awareness.
I felt like about halfway through the
trip I hadn't really gotten my money's
worth on that.
It was a fun life goal and goal.
Exactly.
I was like,
I felt ripped off and the Iowaska
goddess or whatever it is,
like the personality of the drug was
sort of visually like up here on the
left of my periphery.
And I was like,
Hey,
what gives?
Like what did it show me the show me the
majesty of,
of consciousness.
And the drug said
I can't just notice.
And I was like,
ah,
that's bullshit.
I came here for a life,
for example,
the life expand and experience.
I wanted my mind to be blown and all of
a sudden the drug tells me that she
can't even give me an insight into the.
Into the nature of how incredible
consciousnesses and I went off in.
My brain went off on different tangents
than about 10 or 15 minutes later.
I'm not sure how long it was because you
had your sense of time is completely
screwed around with.
I was struck by how incredibly profound
it was.
She was like,
you don't need the drug to be aware of
how incredible consciousness is.
Just notice.
And I was like,
whoa.
And I kind of was struck by the fact
that at any point in time on drugs or
not day or night,
wherever we are,
if you just remind yourself that we are
atoms that were produced inside of stars
that have been spewed out of exploding
stars and have accreted on this little
rock that is spinning around another
star.
And we have evolved over hundreds of
millions of years from amphibians
through to mammals.
And we are self aware and web blots of
substance cleaning into the side of a
speck of dust in the middle of a massive
cosmos and we self aware and we are
conscious and we're looking at the
universe that created us and now having
a conversation about it.
That in itself is weird and it's
staggering and impressive.
And we're a couple of decades away from
creating an artificial version of
ourselves quite probably quite probably
if not decades by 100 years.
One hundred percent.
Yep.
And then we're off to the races.
Well then we're God,
or not us,
but it is,
it is God because it's going to like we
were talking about become 10,000
years more advanced in a matter of
moments and then in a matter of moments
after that 10,000
years more and then in a matter of
moments in weeks and months will pass
and we will be infinitely more separated
from what we are today or more evolved
or more capable.
There was a,
a moment during the trip were one of the
female and the Shaman is on Iowa.
Oscar as well.
And he has female assistants,
she's saying this incredible song about
like the majesty of life or something,
and one of the things she was saying
about was like that whatever the life
force is inside you is more powerful
than the sun.
More powerful than anything.
And it sounds a bit corny when you're
not high listening to it,
but it gave me a,
a profound sense that yeah,
this,
this web of procreating,
self-developing ever improving sentiment
creatures that are life is one of the
oldest and most enduring things in the
universe and most impressive things in
the universe.
Just in terms of going all the way back
to the genesis of life on this planet or
elsewhere.
So as you say,
if we give birth to this new artificial
intelligence,
we will,
as you say,
be the the organism that sort of
transcends from biological life to
artificial life.
And just being a part of being a part of
any of that experience struck me as
incredibly,
incredibly moving and touching in a way
that I know sounds stupid to people
who've never done psychedelics.
And I know that there are friends of
mine who are like,
well,
yeah,
okay,
you had a hippy dippy trip,
but it's one of the,
again,
it comes back to sort of the quality of
question,
the experience,
the insight that you are able to achieve
when you're using these substances,
or alternatively if you're a good a
great meditator or something or if
you're in a float tank or any other way
of getting your mind into a different
plane than the normal daily plane is
not,
is not a one of data.
It's not one that is easily explainable.
It's not one of reason.
It's a,
it's an,
it's an insight,
you know,
it's an experience.
It's an undeniable experience.
And um,
I always wonder if that state that you
achieve when you're on DMT DMT,
which is the active component in Iowasca
and you haven't done Iowasca.
I've only done the hardcore form of DMT,
but dmt takes you to these places that
apparently you can kind of reach an
Iowasca for brief moments.
A lot of people feel like Iowasca is a
more spiritual version of it because it
lasts longer.
You have more time to absorb the
experience and a lot of times it's more
for some people more life changing
because dmt is so titanic,
Lee Alien,
that one when it's done,
you're just like,
what the fuck?
But I've.
I've done dmt over the course of several
hours or you keep doing it.
Oh right.
You just keep doing it because you smoke
it.
Right,
and then the last 15 minutes
trips,
then you fucking banging out one more
time,
get back in there.
Did you have someone coaching your way
through it?
Because my friend,
my Iowaska friend who introduced me to
this ceremony,
tried dmt once and read and really had
a.
had a freakout and wasn't crazy about it
and was then told you should really have
someone who sort of knows what they're
doing with your.
Don't be a pussy or wouldn't be a it.
Let it
go.
You got to let him take you there and.
But your,
your mind does get exposed.
Your thoughts do get exposed.
You find out what's negative and what's
positive about the way you look at the
world.
I had one of the most powerful
experiences ever and my second trip
where I had this visualization of
negative thinking like I had a negative
thought came into my head and it was
like dark and twisted and I just had
this negative thought and then I
realized that I was thinking in a
negative way and this is a physical
manifestation in front of me of negative
thinking and at that moment I relaxed
and thought wonderful,
beautiful,
positive thoughts and it blossomed into
this incredible flower of geometric
patterns and continued to get more and
more beautiful as I relaxed more and
more.
It was like a physical manifestation of
looking at negative thinking.
It was negative.
That negative was like dark black and
green,
and it was just like,
it was like a toxic.
We close.
No totally closed.
Uh,
but I was so fucked up,
I probably wouldn't have mattered if I
opened my eyes.
I would have seen the same thing.
I was so gone.
You're,
you're,
you just,
you dissolve.
You cease to be there when you're doing
the DMT,
the most intense version of smoking it.
Um,
but you,
I wonder if we will eventually be there
because what that feels like when you're
doing dmt and Mckenna's described it as
Terence Mckenna described it as like
you're in some sort of a well of souls,
that you transcend the physical body and
you enter into some space,
some well of souls.
I wonder if this thing that we look at,
we look at reality and we look at Adams
and what we're talking about,
the physical space,
when Adam's are mostly nothing and then
these subatomic particles that blink in
and out of position.
I wonder if what really is going to
happen as we get more and more evolved
and more and more powerful with our
ability to manipulate matter,
is that we're going to transcend this
dimension.
I wonder if that place that we go to is
where our future lies and that our
future doesn't lie in the stars because
the stars aren't even real and that the
real dimension means they're real.
Is in.
You can see them and you can send things
to them and you can measure them.
But this is just a,
almost like a prison of a dimension and
this dimension can be transcended and
that you can briefly view it when you do
dmt or when you visit the Iowasca God
and you,
you,
you pass through and briefly into that
dimension.
But if one day that is where
consciousness will exist all the time
and that we are creating this
possibility in this door through our
thirst for innovation and knowledge and,
and this constant evaluation of our
current abilities and the constant
desire to improve upon those abilities,
that one day it'll get passed this
desire to have artificial intelligence
and what is this intelligence going to
be able to do?
What's it going to be able to achieve
and what's it going to be able to
accomplish?
And we're going gonna open up other
dimensions as possibilities for
consciousness to exist in.
I mean,
this sounds a lot like,
like pre abrahamic religion,
right?
I mean this sounds a lot like religions
were experience and indigenous religions
where before we fucked everything with,
uh,
with Moses and Jesus and Mohammed.
Well,
you say that.
But do you know that most most recent
scholars in Jerusalem believed that the
Moses experience was about dmt?
The Moses experienced specifically?
Oh No.
I'm only is that that a lot of the
early.
A lot of those old testament things,
writers were on psychedelic.
Most likely they were.
When you think about the fact that
psychedelics has been,
have been here forever,
so what's the Moses
the most experiences that Moses saw?
The burning Bush that represented God?
Yeah.
Well,
one of the most dmt rich plants in the
area where Moses was the Acacia tree.
The acacia Bush is rich in DMT.
If that was on fire or if you figured
out a way to extract dmt from it and
then he smoked it or you lit it on fire
and did some sort of a way where you're
absorbing this smoke and absorbing the
DMT,
you would say,
God,
you would see God.
There's A.
There's a lot of DMT.
Flora in Australia apparently,
and I just feel arris grass,
right?
A lot of different plants.
There's an Australian native called the
wattle,
which I think is the national plant.
I'd have to look that up or maybe it's
the state plan of my state.
Um,
and so,
and Acacia isn't that they're all part
of that family.
And so I was,
I was looking earlier this year that
there's a push in Australia to get a
Iowaska off the,
uh,
the register,
you,
the banned substances list and permitted
as a,
as a religious,
as a madison,
as a medicine.
Yeah.
It helps a lot of people.
There's a lot of people that go to it
that have all sorts of addictions and
all sorts of real problems and it sort
of reset their brain,
resets their life.
It's one of many different psychedelics
that are really good at that.
He Boga is incredibly good for people
that have addictions to opiates,
literally resets the way your brain
views and connects to addictive
substance.
So I've heard,
yeah,
I mean one of the,
I did a story on huffpost live about
Iowaska before I'd ever used it and they
were saying that there's some
interesting research about its ability
to be a circuit breaker against,
for example,
alcoholism and stuff like that,
that people will go into the experience.
Alcoholics tends to come out.
Yeah,
right.
it was psychedelics.
So I mean if it's so difficult to know
what the fuck is going on with
consciousness,
right.
Why is it that we are assembled in such
a way as to have these experiences and
to be conscious at all,
but why do you think that it's a
different dimension that we could cross
into rather than just a another
perspective on this world that we are
opened up to because we're ordinarily.
I mean my,
my theory I suppose although it's
tentative,
is we have the capacity to be tuned into
all kinds of amazing shit that's going
on in the universe,
but I really mean in terms of woo.
I mean in terms of spiritual ghosts or
anything.
I just mean there was a perspective on
life that is much bigger than the one
that we walk around with a on our day to
day on a day to day basis,
but evolution has has favored traits
that force us to focus on getting food
and having sex and surviving.
Right.
Which means that it has intentionally
closed the parameters of what our mind
is capable of experiencing.
It goes intentionally closed or is there
no benefit for the biological is what I
made distracted by these.
Exactly.
Running from tigers.
Precisely.
You don't want to cave man who's like,
who's like philosophizing a bit about
his place in the cosmos is eating well.
He gets eating wise tripping.
Yeah,
exactly.
He's like,
this is amazing.
It's such a spiritual journey.
We Abbott startup gets devoured by a
woolly mammoth,
a little silly voice,
but you know,
and what drugs do is they break down the
walls of perception and you know,
to,
to borrow from Huxley,
they,
they shatter those,
those kinds of limits and constraints
that our biology,
that evolution has put on our mental
ability and simply let the mind wander
into whatever space it cares to go to.
Yeah.
Well,
why?
By using the word dimension,
I think we've sort of,
uh,
we've,
I've limited the perception of what I'm
saying because we already have like
three dimensions that we believe in and
the dimensions that we understand,
four dimensions that we believe in,
but also the,
they believe that
quantum physics there a nine or 1111 is
it?
Yeah.
So we,
we understand that there are other
dimensions that we don't totally
understand yet,
right?
Um,
but those,
those are,
those are words,
right?
To mentions their words,
but there's time,
space,
distance,
all these different things or words and
these words sort of lock in a definition
in our own mind.
But whatever the fuck it is,
when you do have a dmt trip,
you go to a place and that place is not
right here.
It's not,
you're not,
you're not here when you go there and
it's some all encompassing infinite
geometric place called a dimension.
But that's just a noise that you make
with your mouth.
It doesn't really matter what it is.
It's something that you experienced that
you don't experience right here in
Calabasas or wherever the fuck we are.
You know,
it's,
there's,
there's something different about it.
And um,
could it be another dimension?
Yes.
Could it be all in your imagination?
Your imagination might also be another
dimension.
The word dimension is a weird word
because it's so limiting and defining
and,
and we have these preconceived ideas
that we,
you know,
there's a box that we can put our head,
oh,
it's a dimension.
There's the dimension,
you know,
whatever that thing is that you can
experience.
If we can tap into that and other ways
is going,
the world is going to get very strange.
One thing that struck me after the
experience,
which gives,
which I think it bolsters the idea that
there is something real about that
dimension and slash intelligence or
whatever it is,
whatever you want to call it,
was the,
was that I noticed that whenever people
have these experiences and go to these
places,
regardless of what mechanism they use,
they always come out with basically the
same.
Just have a conclusion and if it was
merely what someone like a,
uh,
who's a tele,
penn,
penn and teller,
one of my pendulous nine.
Why?
If it was merely what a person like Penn
Jillette thinks it is,
which is just the [inaudible] of your
brain,
right?
Do you mean you take this stuff but he's
never done anything?
No,
exactly.
That's right.
He's lost.
So he's not just a teetotaler.
He's a denier of the possibility of all
these different experiences being
transcendent.
That's right.
He was.
As far as he's concerned.
What happens when you take dmt is that
there are neurological disturbances and
your brain goes,
goes in,
has weird experiences because the drug
is just fucking with your neurology.
And the Daddy said to Moses,
nothing.
What?
I said,
why don't you,
why?
Why have you?
How come you have no interest?
He goes,
I think everything has been learned from
those experience.
Everything that we've already figured it
out,
we've already taken what we can from
those experiences.
Nothing to be learned by doing that.
Other people have already done it.
Mike,
you're out of your fucking mind.
And if that's the case,
then just do it.
Then there's no harm,
right?
So silly to say that is so silly.
I love that guy.
He's awesome.
But I think he is missing out on a
massive blind spot.
Just massive blind.
But Dick Chunk of possibility.
He thinks it's hallucinations.
He thought.
I mean,
he doesn't know.
He really doesn't know.
He doesn't understand.
I mean,
some of it is hallucinations,
but.
So here's it.
I'm not sure.
I think it might be what Mckenna thinks.
I'm.
It might be a wealth of souls.
It might be what life is this.
This whole biological thing might
literally be the cocoon that we were
talking about.
But when I'm,
when I close my eyes and I see a
mechanistic universe of bright pink,
yellow and purple machines cranking away
and exploding and little sort of Mario
style computer things bouncing around on
them,
and then I start spinning through
kaleidoscopes of color.
Are you implying that Mckenna Mckenna
would say that those are actual real
things that I'm seeing in another
dimension?
Woody Kenna
believed that?
What you were expecting?
He had some weird names for them.
I think he called them.
Uh,
what did you call machine elves and
hyperspace.
He believed that they were entities.
He believed that they were living
entities and that you were communicating
with each other.
No words.
I could believe that.
I think there are clearly hallucinations
because there are just things like I
would open my eyes and then there was a
river in the middle of the,
of the room between me and the other
people sitting there.
Like I'd seen no reason to assume that
that actually was a river a,
but maybe it was anyway.
But where it comes to like souls and
where it starts getting really woo woo
is when I could feel the tug of going
into a particular place like the woman's
head or something like I could feel.
There were moments where I was having
lots of fun and I was thinking,
Oh,
is this,
oh this is,
oh,
this is going to be enjoyable.
And then some I would just,
a wave of dread would wash over me and I
was like,
ended up start to feel like I was going
to vomit.
And then I'd be like,
oh,
okay,
I have to take this shit seriously.
And I'd sit upright and I'd.
And I'd take a deep breath.
And that I can imagine,
I think is what he's sort of talking
about.
Right.
And maybe that's like something like
that.
One of the things to make the really
powerful distinction is Mckenna was
specifically talking about dmt.
That's what he was into.
She wasn't really into Iowasca.
His brother Dennis is really an Oscar.
And his brother Dennis really
recommended that I do it and I probably
will eventually.
I'm sure it will,
but terrence was into the hardcore
version and it was.
It's a apparently you can't.
Well,
I know from the hardcore version of it
you're not.
You're not escaping.
Like once you're locked in,
you're gone.
Like it's.
It's way more potent.
Way more potent.
Yeah.
I got to try it and see the difference.
The,
the,
what you're experiencing when you're
having the Iowasca trip is a,
this emo a inhibitor allowing you to
have this prolonged slow release dmt
trip so you're not getting shot through
a fucking cannon to the center of the
universe.
No,
sure.
But people have been using this for
thousands of years and believing that it
is opening a portal to some kind of
spirit of winter,
so it's not okay.
Saying there's a difference between what
Mckenna's describing as what you
experienced.
Yep.
Got It.
And what I've experienced,
but presumably Mckenna's Mckenna's
theories can be extrapolated to Iowasca
as well as the MTA.
Sure.
He goes,
yeah,
definitely.
But I think that you're getting a much
more watered down version of it when
you're doing,
which is one of the reasons why people
can sustain it for many,
many hours.
I mean,
I'm just trying to figure out what the,
what the competing claims about this,
this dimension that we're accessing A.
Right.
You know,
on the one hand you've got a,
a Penn Jillette who's saying,
well,
it's just all in your district
guard.
What he's saying.
He hasn't experienced it.
If he experienced it and he was
dismissing it,
I would be like,
wow,
he must have got some weak shit.
I mean,
the,
what's compelling to me,
what I was just saying about the
conclusions that people have after they
come off of these kinds of experiences.
No one has ever had one of these
experiences and come out of it and said,
wow,
I really felt like I was.
I got an insight into the true meaning
of life.
And the meaning of life is I should hate
Jews.
You know,
or like no one has ever become more
petty.
You all of the experiences.
Well,
not that I know of,
most certainly everyone who I know will
have or have read of who have had,
who've had these kinds of experiences
tend to come out with similar
intellectual conclusions that we are all
one.
That life is precious,
that,
uh,
you know,
consciousness is divine,
that love is important.
All these kinds of things which
indicates to me that it's more that
makes it more plausible than it would
otherwise be.
That you're actually viewing something
that exists rather than merely having
your brain stood up
but isn't impossible.
That just does just stripping away the
normal boundaries of consciousness,
reveal the positive aspects of the human
nature and you take away all of our
insecurities and have all of our
biological necessity of survival and all
these different things that sort of
motivate us and sexual impulses and
desires and fears.
Strip all that stuff away with
dimethyltryptamine and all of a sudden
you reveal what the human soul really,
essentially.
Yes,
but why is the human soul based on love?
Well,
because love is probably the thing that
makes us most connected and makes us
most productive and makes us feel the
best.
You know,
you don't feel good if you're successful
in the loan.
It's one of the weirdest things about
being a person.
If you gave a person all the money in
the world and all the tools and toys in
the world and all the gadgets and
Gizmos,
but you left them by themselves on the
moon,
they'd probably want to blow their
fucking brains out.
You,
you.
We don't exist in a vacuum.
We exist as a super organism.
This is something that Anthony Robbins
that make sense?
Absolutely.
I mean,
it's almost.
It becomes back to.
It's almost semantic between that end
having an insight into another
dimension,
because if what you're saying is that
fundamentally at the core of all of us,
once you strip everything else away is a
kind of beating heart of deep,
glowing and abiding,
connected love.
We'll just call that the other dimension
then because that's spooky in and of
itself.
That other dimension would.
It feels like when you're doing dmt,
is that the way?
I describe it as it's you.
You're in this infinite realm of complex
geometric patterns that are made out of
love and understanding and that you and
by understanding I mean like wisdom,
like they see you can't bullshit them.
You're exposed Ra and what you are and
what you have been as exposed raw and
your personality and your life and your
culture is stripped away and you're left
with your soul or whatever we think of
as soul.
Again,
waited words,
weird words,
but ultimately that feeling of love does
come out of everybody like and I think
that that's probably at the root of what
makes us want to be connected with each
other.
That's why you do feel bad when you're
just alone for long periods of time.
You don't connect with people and it's
probably good to be alone occasionally,
but ultimately you want to get back to
people and you want to get back to
people that you care about in the love
because you,
you,
you bond with them.
You mom.
You do that thing that happens when you
go into the DMT world where you connect
with everything in it and it sucks you
in and as you let go,
it bathes you with that loving,
weird,
strange,
all knowing,
feeling
Anthony Robbins has an interesting line
that you reminded me of the beginning of
the show when you were talking,
when you were joking about how you'll
always feel unfulfilled and like you
know the moment you do a podcast,
you need to just focus on the next one
and get the next one done.
A which is that he,
he feels like the greatest failures are
successful people who don't feel
fulfilled,
that he would much rather see an
unsuccessful fulfilled person than a
successful,
unfulfilled
person.
Let me step in here because Anthony
Robins,
his greatest success,
Robin's his greatest success,
is teaching people to be successful.
So he must said to be fulfilled.
He must feel fulfilled.
Teaching people how to be successful.
I think he would say that he teaches
them how to be fulfilled.
Okay.
What has he done?
What has he dies?
Teach people how to feel fulfilled.
Yeah.
That's his vision of fulfillment.
How much,
uh,
amazing creative work of literature,
of fiction,
of how much stuff has anthony robins
done?
How many movies is he made?
How many,
how many paintings has he done?
How many things is he created out of?
Nothing that he's super happy with.
No,
his none.
His.
He's not a creative artist.
His life mission is to help people get
fulfilled.
So him talking about creative people
being fulfilled.
Fundamentally,
I don't think he understands what I'm
saying.
Like am I fulfilled?
Yeah,
I mean is it great that we have 830
whatever podcast in a bunch of people
like,
absolutely,
but what is fulfilled me and am I,
am I content?
Can I sit back and relax and enjoy it?
No,
because part of what makes you good at
something is that you're constantly
assessing whether or not it's good and
you're constantly objectively and
introspectively analyzing it and
breaking it down and chopping it up.
Dude,
I just got through doing a Netflix
special.
It's going to air in October and I had
to edit it.
It's fucking awful.
Doing that.
Chewing away at your work and trying to
figure out what you can do.
What's better.
Can I cut this out?
Should I leave this here?
And ultimately what I decided to do is I
did four shows so I could do one of them
almost completely in its entirety and
they'll like in and do it that way,
but I know other people think it's
funny.
I know the people that were there,
I got a standing ovation.
I know they loved it.
I fucking hate everything.
I don't know.
I don't mean hate,
but I mean you're there,
but there's a constant search for the
right beats and the right things and
it's not a matter of not being
fulfilled.
I'm a very fulfilled person.
It's a matter of never really liking
anything that I do.
Never really loving it and they're
always this constant need to make it
better.
This constant state of.
And the most people that I find that are
really super happy with everything they
do,
they usually suck.
That's true.
Yeah.
No,
I mean I'm like you,
I never.
That's why it takes me forever to write
and I never meet writing deadlines
because I always hate what I want.
I produced why you're good.
Anthony Robbins is a great guy.
I.
I appreciate him very much and I
listened to his motivational books on
tape when I was a fighter.
I used to listen to that.
I have fucking one of those walkman
cassette things and I bought his books.
I listened to his stuff.
Ultimately though,
and this is not to dismiss him,
what he does is write about success.
That's right.
And he wants people to be successful,
so that's what he thinks of his
fulfillment.
But if Anthony robins decided to write
some great work of fiction,
then I could listen to him.
Anthony Robbins sat down and came up
with this fucking amazing movie and
produced it and it's some saifai
masterpiece.
Then I could understand,
but he's not doing that,
but don't coaches.
I mean this isn't the defendant Anthony
Robbins a hour,
but don't coach like you can be a great
coach without being good at the thing
that you're coaching people on.
Absolutely.
And sometimes that's useful to.
Oh sure,
yeah.
No screenwriting coaches.
Robert Mckee runs his three day seminar.
Incredibly invaluable.
If anyone wants to write a screenplay
who's out there do robot Mckay's a
seminar.
He's never written a screenplay in his
entire life.
No,
he's not a good screen writer,
but he understands that he,
he's the first to say that,
but you know what?
All the big studios,
uh,
pay for their,
for their script readers to go to his
seminar.
You know where that doesn't work.
Stand up.
There are no,
there are no standup coaches that are
any good.
No,
that's true.
That's true.
Isn't it weird?
It's terrible.
Comedians that fail and then they start
to make stand.
It's like the standup class but,
and you're like,
well,
I'm sorry,
what do you know about them?
What?
And if you ever watched them do standup,
you want to fucking shoot yourself.
There was a couple of people that wrote
books about standing up and they were
all awful,
awful comics.
There's one guy who was really helpful
to me when I started doing standup,
but not that I've ever been successful
at doing standup because I didn't pursue
it.
But he was really helpful to me in New
York when I first got there.
But apart from that,
yeah,
I completely agree.
It basically he was just a good joke
writer,
so he was good at whittling down a
concept into a punchline.
But the people that are good at.
Yeah,
and you,
you could learn from friends,
but I've never seen a really good comic
teach a course like David towels there.
You just stand up.
That's.
You know what I mean?
That's right.
Well be yourself.
I mean like I love the idea.
I've had so many conversations with,
with successful creative people who I
admire that I couldn't believe that I
still ever doubt this advice,
but it's the most consistent advice that
I get from creative people.
I like anytime they try to do something
which is calculated to appeal to a
particular demographic or which is based
on notes that other people have given
them or which is intended to fill a
particular niche,
it falls flat on its face and every time
they do something that is for them that
they love,
that has an audience of one,
which is them.
And it's true to them and it speaks to
them and it's idiosyncratic and
particular.
It kills.
It's so true.
But
here's the rub.
You have to learn how to be yourself.
That's right.
And that takes a long fucking time.
Right?
I think back when I was 21 when I first
started doing standup and I'm horrified
that anybody let me onstage because I
didn't know anything.
I didn't know who I was.
I didn't know what my thoughts on things
were.
I was just terrified trying to get
laughs.
So I was trying to figure out what would
make people laugh.
I had no idea what I thought was funny
other than what I saw that made me
laugh.
I couldn't break it down.
Like if I went to see a Sam kinison or
Jerry Seinfeld or something like that,
I knew they were hilarious.
They made me laugh.
I could repeat the joke to you.
I can say,
Oh my God,
I saw Seinfeld.
Let me tell you his joke and I could
tell you.
And I knew it was funny,
but I didn't know how to do it.
I just clumsily concocted my own
versions of different subjects that I
thought could possibly be funny and then
over time,
slowly but surely figured out how to
actually be funny,
but along the lines I had a fail
miserably and learn and feel pain and
heartbreak and all the bullshit that
people go to before I started forming my
own actual opinions on things.
I think that's a really good point
because sometimes one day I was,
I was a late bloomer and figuring out
who I am as a creative person.
Do you know now I don't know what the
fuck I am.
Well,
you know,
to to her closest approximation that
you're able to,
that,
that you're able to land so your
audience knows who Joe Rogan is.
Put it that way.
Right.
And that's enough.
Some of them do,
some of them are mad.
I thought you were different,
but I think fun of ignore them,
make fun of.
My mother was like reading the comments
section of a website,
but it I think some of sometimes one of
the differences between people who
peaked early into successful young
versus people who are better later in
life is just how just how long does it
take you to really get grounded in who
you are and to stop trying on these
different kind of invisible cloaks of
personalities that you think you might
be until you can strip all that away and
then you're like,
okay,
I think this is.
I think this is the real.
It's the same with podcasting as well.
Like I,
I used to host stuff and try to get it
up and do radio bits in Australia and I
if I listened back to them now,
it's so effected.
It's so.
It's so not.
It's so me trying to be me on radio
instead of just made.
Yeah,
you gotta be you.
Yeah.
I think the thing that happens also with
the peaking early thing is success
itself is the poison or of creativity.
A success itself like you all of a
sudden you have it.
That's one of the reasons why I don't
believe Anthony Robbins is correct,
is like this,
this idea of like being satisfied and
being fulfilled.
Like I mean,
sure,
I'm satisfied and fulfilled.
Absolutely.
But the whole thing about the,
this creative process is you can never
totally be happy with what you're doing
or what you've done because you've got
to do more shit.
Especially standups.
Like if you're a musician and you're the
rolling stones and you have a catalog.
Fuck man.
You could tour forever.
You don't need to write a new song ever.
But if you're a standup,
I put out a new special every year and a
half every two years,
whatever it is.
And if I don't do that,
I feel like a fucking piece of shit.
And if I try to do the same jokes,
uh,
five
years in a row,
six years in a row,
10 years in a row,
we all know comics that do that.
You go to see them and they're doing the
same bits word for word for decades and
decades and never put anything out that
doesn't go for the.
I got back to the comedy cellar in New
York sometimes in the,
you know,
the emcee will be doing the same shtick
that he was doing 10 years ago when I
first came to New York.
I'm like,
that guy is still doing the same
material.
I mean,
in one respect I can sort of understand
it because if you're like take music,
maybe not the rolling stones,
but say Hansard,
you can just do embalm every single time
you go anyway.
And that's all you need to do for the
rest of your life.
And in comedy there are people like,
like sometimes audiences want it,
right?
Sometimes I'll do that bit about blahdy
Blah.
Grandma sucks,
which is fine.
You mean Jerry Seinfeld did that one
thing I'm telling you for the last time
I saw him and Sydney.
Yeah.
Nothing wrong with that,
but,
but then he tied all of that material.
But like if you go to see a guy like
bill burr,
you see bill burger special and then you
go see him like a year later you're
gonna see a whole new set every time.
And that's the same with Ari Shaffir at
the same,
you know,
fill in the blank,
yet every single essentially,
I mean touring comedian now,
to be fair to Anthony Robbins,
I don't think that he's saying that you
should just be sit on your laurels and
not strive.
And it's interesting.
You know what I mean?
What he's saying is,
will know the story of like the person
who wanted a Ferrari and wanting to,
wanting to sexy wife and wanted the best
job and wanting to make a million
dollars and then gets it and finds
themselves miserable,
connected to exactly.
They're not connected to what they
really want.
That's what he's doing.
He doesn't mean being self satisfied.
It means he means being genuinely
fulfilled by the things that you're
aspiring to do with your life and to get
up to in the world where there are a
bunch of things that we think we want
and what they are is really just these
unattainable goals that seem like
they're unattainable.
And then once we attain them,
we go,
well,
well the now what?
Exactly.
And that's what happens to a lot of
people when they get famous.
So a lot of comics in particular,
they become famous and they are really
good when they become famous,
like kinisons of my favorite all time
example because I've,
I believe that Kennison from like 1984
to 1986,
it was probably the greatest comic of
all time.
There was just a time where he was just
a maniac.
He just was.
And it's hard because you've got to kind
of put it in the context of the time
that there was no one like that back
then because comedy is not like music.
Like you go listening to music from the
19 sixties.
It's still really awesome.
Go try to listen to some mort Sahl from
1960.
It's fucking terrible.
It doesn't mean that more.
Saul's not a brilliant comedian.
He's certainly was.
Or Lenny Bruce Who's like the godfather
of the whole thing.
If it wasn't for Lenny Bruce,
no one today would be doing the same
kind of standup.
It just,
it wouldn't have existed.
It's,
it's an art form that almost,
that he in many ways sort of gave birth
to.
Well,
go listen to that stuff today.
It doesn't hold up.
Comedy doesn't necessarily
hold up.
So in some ways kinison doesn't totally
hold up when you go back and understand
that I'm a bit hard to grasp from
today's vantage point I must say,
but during the time,
this is a.
I've told this story before,
unfortunately.
So everybody who heard it gather around,
there was a girl that I worked with.
I was working at the Boston Athletic
Club.
I was 19 years old and there was this
girl that was working at the front desk.
She was hilarious.
She was like really?
Like this big athletic girl.
And she was just always like boys jurist
and joking around about stuff.
And she was awesome.
I really wish I stayed in touch with
her.
But uh,
I don't know her name anymore.
I don't remember her name,
but our member,
she told me about Sam Kennison.
She goes,
I saw this comedian on Hbo and now
granted this is the back.
And then there was like Hbo,
Fox,
NBC,
ABC,
there was nothing and maybe cinemax,
right?
She did that bit about a homosexual
necrophiliac paying money to spend a few
hours undisturbed.
But the freshest male corpses,
you know,
that Ben,
there was a bit about a real story that
Kennison had heard were these,
uh,
apparently this is a real issue.
And I'm Joey Diaz knows a guy who walked
in on this mortician that was fucking
his mom after his mom was dead.
Apparently people have done this and
that.
They treat people's bodies like a sex
doll.
And it's Joey Diaz,
the kind of guy who'd make that shit up
because that sounds.
No,
no,
no.
Listen,
guys got arrested.
These guys went in the kinison story.
They got arrested because he's
morticians.
We're accepting money from these people
that would come in and fuck these
courts.
I mean,
if it's a stranger,
I understand.
I do that in a heartbeat.
But if.
But my mother.
Well the guy wasn't fucking his mom.
He was fucking someone else's friend's
mom.
This mortician was fucking sign anyway.
I'm pretty sure it was.
Joey told me that.
I hope it was.
Anyway,
point is this girl does this bit for me.
She goes,
it's because the way kinison do it.
He goes,
imagine.
you're lying there.
You're on the slab.
You Go,
well,
well had a good time in life.
Now I guess I'm going to go to heaven
and be with Jesus and then says,
rocking back and forth.
You and she's doing this on the floor in
the.
On the parking lot on the ground.
She's lying on her stomach
going,
hey,
it feels like someone's fucking me in
the Oh,
you mean live keeps fucking in the ass.
Even after your dad didn't have never
ends.
I am laughing my ass off,
but this girl doing this in the parking
lot and I went out and I believe I got
it on vhs cassette because again,
this is 86.
It was before I'd ever done standup and
I watched his hbo special and I went,
Holy Shit.
Like I didn't even know that was comedy.
I didn't know someone could.
I thought comedy was evening at the
Improv.
Guys would roll up their sleeves.
Do you ever notice set up punchline?
Yeah,
and this guy was doing this completely
radical version of that with a bra on
and a trench coat.
I was like,
what the is this,
and he was so good for a short period of
time and then I went to see him alive
when I first got into comedy around 1988
and he had already slid way off the
rails and he was just partying all the
time and doing coke and bang and
strippers.
He's on heroin as well with me.
No,
I don't believe so.
I think he's pretty much just a coca
probably did heroin probably did
everything you put in front of them.
You know Sam Kennison.
He was an animal.
He even joked around about that,
about people expected them to do drugs.
He's here,
he's here,
could cut the biggest line in the world
and even doing his heart would be
beating out of his chest.
I want to say no.
Well also it would be bad for his image.
He sort of became a prisoner of his own
image.
He created this persona and then it
became a prisoner to that persona,
but he just stopped writing and stopped
being funny and he's hanging out with
celebrities and he's going to parties
and he's not not hungry anymore,
not doing the work.
And he went from being one of the best
ever to being like an open mic or is
caricature of who he really was.
We really didn't have any points and it
was all just scream and all just,
you know,
like trying to pick out a shocking
subject.
But it wasn't really.
It wasn't,
didn't really resonate with them.
And I think with a lot of Comedians,
what's really important is a,
you are a regular person that you are,
you just,
you can fit in with people and you
understand people and a lot of people
they become famous and then all of a
sudden they get assistance and then they
get,
you know,
managers and agents shield them from the
world.
They have publicists to do all the
talking for them and they get tucked
away in an ivory tower and then they
show up for interviews with sunglasses
on.
And you know,
and they're,
they're all about maintaining.
Tell me about it.
I've interviewed enough of those on the
live.
Yeah.
Well,
I mean,
not even necessarily Comedians,
but people who come on with that persona
who are,
who are handled,
who have spent their entire lives being
handled.
Like,
give me an example.
Roseanne Barr.
I brought her in here.
She was awesome.
Was She?
Yeah,
she got.
Well you probably got her to open up.
I had,
I had 25 minutes.
Well I had three hours and she knows I'm
a huge fan.
I think Roseanne is probably one of the
10 most important comedian.
Oh,
absolutely.
I mean I'm a huge fan of actually the.
Did you see the documentary film that
was made about her run for president?
No,
it's actually really interesting.
It's,
you know,
it's fascinating to see this person who
was so groundbreaking and who,
who did so much comedy in for and for I
guess the portrayal of women and that
people and the working class on American
television wasn't totally different
thing.
She was a totally different thing.
Yeah.
Just see her kind of puttering around
her home in Hawaii,
like trying to run for president as a
green candidate.
It's.
It's an interesting documentary.
She had to set her straight about chem
trail.
She believed the government was spraying
things in the sky reading.
Maybe I read about that and maybe you
tweeted about it or something,
but I remember reading about her and
chem trails or maybe it was Brian
Dunning's episode or did he reference
that or something?
There was something maybe skeptical.
Maybe he might've.
I don't know.
I don't remember.
There's too many of them.
They get it.
If I really remember it at all.
You know Dunbar's number.
Like there's.
There's only like certain amount of data
you can stuff in that fucking dome of
yours.
Absolutely.
And let it go.
Who Cares?
Who gives a shit how many homes it is,
but she was awesome on this show and she
didn't.
She didn't come in like handled it all.
She came in by herself,
sat down,
shot the shit,
laughed,
joked around.
Interesting.
I mean fame you or met you were talking
earlier about fame.
Like it can be incredibly alienating
when you reach a certain.
What's your sweet spot of fame?
Because I,
you know,
I think I hit it
about a year and a half ago.
I'm trying,
you know,
I wanna be able to go to the movies.
I can't think of anything worse than not
being able to get on a plane without
everybody.
Like I got on a plane a couple of years
ago and Deniro was sitting in seat one
Aa,
so I don't know how he got on the plane,
how long he'd been on the plane,
but he wasn't here.
I didn't see him board.
So I know Richie.
Oh yeah,
we got on the plane
already there.
I have no fucking idea.
He was already on the plane.
I'm like yeah,
I'm in the front of the line,
Bitch,
get on that plane,
Lionel.
So I was one of the first people that
was one of the first people on the plane
and I also happened to be in first class
and the.
And you hack your way into first class?
You son of them.
That actually someone,
a production company paid for me that I
was shooting a pilot,
uh,
and so I was,
I was one of the first people on the
plane and I was able to see the
reactions of everybody walking past as
they notice or don't notice that it's
Robert Deniro sitting on the plane and
it's incredible to.
I mean his life is just a relentless
stream of people acting weird.
Right?
I mean,
every single person who noticed him
would do a double take gospel nudge,
unsubtly nudge the person who they're
traveling with and he has to sit there
reading the newspaper,
pretending that this is normal and he
can say hello to him.
But what a horrible,
normal one.
If you want to pick your nose,
don't pick your nose in public.
You piece of shit.
Lot.
Have a good pick.
Isn't a good picture?
Satisfying?
Weird.
How many people up dry up?
They get a big old dry.
Yeah.
You realize that there's more up there.
You kind of pull out a pc of Brian
almost just goes all the way up to,
in between your eyes are agree.
That's good.
Yeah,
it is,
it's got to be weird to be that famous.
So there's certain levels,
like a buddy of mine,
his friend Doug Stanhope is friends with
Johnny Depp and uh,
he,
he talks about how unmanageable Johnny
Depp's famous like he cannot go to,
if he goes to a restaurant,
literally people do not give a fuck if
he's eating,
they swarm and the table and come over
with cameras and pictures and they want
to touch him and they don't leave him
alone.
He just,
he's just far beyond the regular fame
into that weird.
There's only 10 people in the world that
have that kind of fame.
And you become other people's property.
Yeah,
basically.
And they feel like you owe them.
And I think television,
maybe movie stars.
Uh,
I'm not sure how it would play,
but I think in my experience,
broadcasters,
and in other words,
television personalities and radio hosts
are people feel like you're their friend
in a way that they don't to movie stars.
Yeah.
So there's a different interplay.
Like people movie stars are different
because they play someone different.
Like,
oh my gosh,
the guy from Cape fear raging bull.
That's Jake Lamata the thing,
and there's something about the bigness
of the screen and the Glamor of
Hollywood that makes them sort of other
worldly.
Yes.
Whereas when people go up to Jimmy
Fallon,
it's like,
oh Jimmy,
you know,
it's like,
oh,
you're my buddy.
Like we should hang out sometime.
Yeah,
no,
exactly it,
but I think there's a sweet spot to,
to fame that as you say,
I would not want to go past.
I'd like to be more famous than I am,
but not not so famous that I can't pick
my nose in public.
That's the judge sets level.
Definitely shouldn't pick your nose in
public to,
to your alone grandmother.
Don't stop chastising me for my boogers
in front of all these humans.
I've got my fist up,
my nose right now to my wrist.
I was sitting next to this guy on an
airplane once.
This old dude,
he just kept digging in his nose.
He didn't give a fuck.
Well,
that's not about 75 years old and he's
like,
nobody's fucking me.
Do it.
One more time happened,
I don't give a shit,
and he was in first class.
We had some cash.
He just fucking up there weighty wipe
it.
I don't remember.
I just stopped looking at them and put
my headphones on,
zoned out.
I'm tired of looking at this old dude
picking his nose.
He fired a bunch of times to household.
So about just letting that go.
I've had some bad experiences on Greg
Fitzsimmons has a bit about that,
about how he,
uh,
you know,
when he's in first class you always to
gets upgraded because he flies so much
that we was in first class and needed to
fought but didn't want to stink at the
first class cabin.
So He'd go back through the curtain to
economy class and just walk down the
aisle fighting
that's cropped up and then he'd go back
to first class,
smart life.
Those,
those,
those people in cattle class at
disgusting.
It smells like hell back there.
Joey Diaz always farts in first class
in.
It's always so horrific.
You can imagine.
I wrote a whole bit about Joey farting
in first class.
I wrote a whole blog entry about this
one time that he did that.
This woman,
she yelled at him,
he had fallen and she yelled out behind
us.
Oh my God.
She yelled it out.
I put my shirt over my nose like this,
and he started laughing and clapping.
Look,
I've occasionally,
I will confess,
I've occasionally been too hung over on
a plane and have not been able to hold
it in and I've got a little trick for
people which they can keep up.
This leaves and you know,
go to the bathroom.
Rude piece of shit.
Sometimes you're,
sometimes you're in the window seat and
the person sitting next to you is eating
their meal or something and you,
you kind of get out.
You don't want to disturb things and
you're not sure if it's going to smelly
or not and you're
not sure if it's going to be big or not.
It's just going to be something has to
give and so here's the tactic so that no
one will suspect you.
You release it.
You survived through the beginning of
the horrible smell without paying any
attention to it.
Then as soon as it would have had time
to have gotten to you,
if it had been admitted by someone
nearby,
then you very visibly start to react to
the bad smell.
You don't understand light.
This is a strategy that has been hired
by American children for it is called.
He smelt it.
Dealt it so this is not so new.
It should be the first no one white.
You white until the person sitting next
to you starts to wince.
Yeah,
and then once they win and then you go
up because then the trajectory can be
established.
If they win first and then you wince,
then it's obviously coming from the
other side of them.
No,
you're going to give away these like
micro expressions that are going to
reveal your guilt.
Not because I'm a perfect doctor.
The perfect crime by.
You're not.
None of my fucking face shot themselves,
and then I loudly say,
oh,
I can't believe someone was sad,
disgusting.
It's tough fights in this cabin and that
person wasn't me.
Yeah,
it's the woman behind Joey Diaz that's
really foreign and when she smelled his
foreign,
she made it even worse and I was blaming
it all on Joey,
but her yelling out,
oh my God,
I'll never forget that lady,
that poor lady I love,
I love the audacity that she's not
embarrassed about it because it wouldn't
let you have the Oh,
nearly you have the tact to be a bit
embarrassed about for the,
on behalf of the fighter.
When you understand what kind of fucking
smell Joey Diaz can pack in that body.
You're talking with a man who is well
over 300 pounds and who knows what he
ate a small child who was fighting
inside him and now he's fighting the
fight happening many things.
Um,
I wanted to mention also,
I was reading this piece about stem
cells.
Have you been paying attention to the
fucking crazy.
I mean,
it looks now like we're going to be able
to use stem cells to grow.
I mean,
we always knew you'd be able to grow
organs in a lab,
right?
But now it looks like within the
fussiest future we're going to be able
to grow a hearts and essentially grow
hots in a lab.
And you're not gonna have to worry about
stem cell treatments.
No.
Talk to me.
I,
uh,
was that close to shoulder surgery.
I had a tear in my rotator cuff tear in
my labor room,
a tear in my bicep tendon and my,
my shoulder was in some pretty
significant pain and I was like,
is this from a particular injury or is
this just from Geneva to.
It's from martial arts.
It's from weightlifting.
It's from years ago.
Overall wear and tear of being Joe
Rogan.
When I got the MRI apparently in my
shoulder had been dislocated.
I didn't know it and it popped back in
place at one point in time and they saw
there's some particles that are floating
around.
Jujitsu is just unbelievably brutal on
your body because you're constantly
attacking joints and,
and trying to break those joints and
then you have to tap but you don't want
to tap.
So you muscled through it and then you
wind up getting pretty injured and then
you heal up for a little bit and you hop
right back in and train again because
it's so much fun.
So,
uh,
I was really close to getting shoulder
surgery and I talked to the doctor from
the UFC who had just gotten these stem
cell injections in his shoulder after
surgery.
He had shoulder surgery,
had a shoulder repaired and then gotten
these injections and I had some pretty,
pretty good results with it.
And he's like,
look,
you really probably need surgery,
but if you want to try this,
these injections,
let's give it a shot because it has been
shown.
I just don't want to give you any false
hope.
Okay,
let's give it a shot.
So what they do is they take a woman's
placenta that,
uh,
is a given birth to a kid through
Sicilian section and then a young woman
and they take those,
that placenta and then they get these
embryonic stem cells from it.
Yup.
And they injected it into my shoulder.
And within four weeks I felt better than
I've felt in a year.
And then it kept getting better and
better and better.
And now,
I mean,
there's still some clicking like because
there's still some shit floating around
in there.
But uh,
I lift a lot of weights and I don't have
any pain.
I mean,
it's amazing how much better it got.
I,
I did a kickboxing workout today where
I'm,
I went seven rounds on the.
So I'm slamming into the back.
I have no pain in my shoulder at all.
Nothing.
Zero.
I mean there's stuff floating around in
there.
Like I said,
I could feel it.
Go,
click,
click because there's some broken off
cartilage and shit.
That's,
that I'll.
Maybe I'll have to get pulled out of
there one day.
But there's no pain.
There's no,
there's no limit in my range of motion.
There's no strength problem.
Like I've shown the doctor,
like the physical exercises I can do and
he's blown away.
He's like,
that is incredible because it just
regenerates tissue and it can
regenerate.
It can regenerate meniscus,
it can regenerate ligaments.
It's,
it's incumbent.
Anything.
Exactly thing.
I mean,
think about that.
You had an injury,
you had a,
you had a debilitating injury that was
causing you significant discomfort and
pain.
What science was able to do is take the
cells that we're going to form the
spinal cord of a baby from an embryo,
and those cells were then able to
convert themselves into portions of Joe
Rogan's,
different constituent components in
order to rebuild a portion of Joe's
body.
It's crazy shit.
I mean,
if that miraculous.
I don't know what it is.
I mean there are some things coming down
the pike with stem cells that are going
to change everything.
I
mean,
I'm literally made the cost.
Like if I had gotten this injury five
years ago,
I would've had to have surgery,
but I didn't.
I got it now and now there's no need for
surgery.
Like my shoulders.
I have a shoot.
Archery,
you know?
Right.
So I shoot a,
I pull 80 pounds 100 times a day,
so I'm just going,
nope.
No shoulder pain at nothing.
Zero.
Did you watch the artery and the
Olympics?
I did watch some of it.
Yeah,
it's fun.
The lcs got silver,
I think that.
Oh,
you fucking papers.
Oh yeah.
We're into ourselves.
I've just watched the NBC telecast.
I gave up on the very humble swimmer,
lied.
I gave up Ryan lochte.
He had poor fella.
He's a bit of a music bit of a Bogan,
isn't he?
As we were saying in Australia,
that's what you guys were calling me.
You know what I thought was hilarious
though,
that how people were,
uh,
um,
I think it was salon had some article
that it's proof that white male athletes
are pieces of shit.
Like they had this whole thing about
white male athletes like Jesus Christ.
You think you can generalize.
One person can die.
Can you imagine if they'd said this is
proof that like if it was an African
American,
they were,
they were like black women or black
women are of shit.
That would've been.
It would've been really fun.
It's amazing that people are allowed to.
By the way it was written.
The article was not written by a white
man.
It was written by someone else,
but it's amazing that,
that you could do that,
but you can.
You can be sexist as long as you're
being sexist about any can be racist as
long as you're being sexist and racist
about a class that you believe is
privileged,
so you're allowed to punch up.
Yeah,
you should always punch.
Always Punch out.
That's.
We were talking about yesterday with
nonsense.
That's the illness that punch up shit.
That is God dammit.
That's amazing.
It's so annoying,
but.
And it's especially annoying because I
understand the motivation behind it.
Right?
I do.
I do believe that it's different if you.
If there's a genuinely oppressed
minority than it's different than they
should have more of a license to make
fun,
for example,
of the majority than the majority should
on them.
At least it's less.
I can understand that.
It's less bad.
What I've done on the stand is when
they're allowed to show flagrant
bigotry.
Yes.
Right.
I mean it's not,
it's not just like a gag.
It's like.
So did you see there was a.
I mean this is slightly tangential,
but everyone got their knickers in a
knot.
Oh,
that tits and the tangle about that.
A headline,
and I think it was in the San Jose
Mercury when Michael Phelps won his
final,
do you see that?
And it was this tokenistic kind of
patronizing headline,
which was like,
you know,
Olympic glory for Michael Phelps and
African American woman because there was
like an African American woman who
street is what I saw is Michael Phelps
when silver is a big headline and then
below it is world record set and the 800
meters by this woman and he set a world
record and she was below him.
He won a silver and it was above her.
That must have been another one because
there was,
there was another one which was
something like a,
it,
you know,
Olympic trials for Michael Phelps and
African American athlete.
Now that's a clumsy,
stupid
headline,
right?
Does that,
is that the,
uh,
the one Michael,
as a historic night with
African-american Olympics,
I said Michael Phelps ratios historic
night with African American.
Wait a minute,
wait a minute.
He's,
he's was widely panned for being
racially insensitive.
That headline,
the headline,
Dan Olympics,
Michael Phelps shares historic night
with African American.
My,
my point is it's part of America's anal
obsession with race that makes that
headline possible in the first place.
That headline isn't racist in the way
that the KKK is racist.
If I mean no white supremacist would
write that headline,
they would just ignore the
african-american entirely or they would
write off that achievement.
That is the kind of headline that's
written by a constipated at white guilty
liberal trying say african-america
exactly.
Just say the woman's name.
That's right.
Trying to be tokenistic.
Lee Approving in this kind of a
paternalistic,
patronizing way that white liberals
insist on being and in doing so is
actually racist and that's.
That's telling I think because it is
racist to be overly concerned about
race.
Even if you're trying to be positive.
What does this say?
Yeah,
they put up a second one,
10 minutes later that.
Oh,
Tim says Olympics.
Michael Phelps shares historic night
with Stanford.
Simone manual.
Why is that?
A gaff says missing something guys.
The third time was the charm is the Merc
went with,
oh,
third time they wrote instead Stanford,
Simone Manual and Michael Phelps make
history.
So because Michael Phelps was first,
that's a layer.
That's ridiculous.
So they're saying that when they changed
it,
they didn't put the gold medalist first.
They put Michael Phelps
because he's the best fucking sweater in
the history of the wall ever.
Yeah.
But what's hilarious is they got it
right the third time.
Her name is first,
like why?
Why?
First of all,
how about just say she won a fucking
gold medal.
Why did she have to be in the same
headline?
Is Him Anyway?
Can you have another goddamn story where
she won a gold medal?
However,
given her own fucking story and then
have him have his own story.
I mean,
why not just say Olympics,
uh,
you know,
golden silver,
silver and gold for Philips and a guy.
Because if you want people to buy your
fucking newspaper,
you better show Michael Phelps name
because otherwise they're not going to
buy to see Kim Kardashian of swimming.
I think it's,
I just think there's so much
unnecessary.
Yeah.
Here it is.
The Mercury News,
uh,
didn't even have her,
is showing up.
I didn't have him in the picture.
Just had a picture of her.
Well now is that the original?
The original.
That's the original.
Still people love to say his name on.
Let's see.
Some of these tweets so flustered now.
They can't even get it grammatically
correct.
Keep trying.
Michael historic night.
Oh yeah,
Stanford.
I mean,
who cares?
Well,
social justice warriors care a bunch of
fucking Weirdo shut ins that are
constantly monitoring the Internet,
looking to be recreationally offended
and can't wait to look.
There was a clumsy fucking head,
but again,
to be fair at the reason why this,
that headline is stupid or exist in the
first place is because it's written by
someone who has been contaminated by
social justice warrior thinking and
thinks that they need to point out the
rice,
the gold medalists.
Wouldn't it be nice if there was just a
gold medalist and a silver medalist and
that's the only metal just happens to be
much more famous than the gold medalist.
So obviously you put his name in.
Imagine if she
went to a gas station and lied about
being robbed,
and then someone from Salon wrote an
article that it's proved that that black
American women are,
have this proof that male athletes are a
protected class.
It's not proof.
It's proof that this guy's a fucking
sociopath.
And he lied.
Mary Elizabeth Williams,
the ballot of Swim Shady.
That's a good headline because it's
pretty cool.
Uh,
why that's not true.
Male.
Oh,
I was wrong too.
It's like I thought it said white males
just as male athletes are protected
class.
I just don't think that it's fair
because it was one guy amongst the
thousands of athletes.
It's so stupid that you said male
athletes are a protected class because
he didn't get protected by the way he
got exposed.
There's nothing protected about dragging
that guy's name.
Do you know he will be the fucking
subject of jokes about lying for the end
of time?
Yeah.
That guy will be the benedict arnold of
jokes.
Jenelle did a gag of bed last night.
Look,
it's going to happen.
Like there's nothing protected.
That's not proof that he's in a
protected class.
In fact,
it's evidence that no one is protected
from lies because video cameras,
because of technology and because the
truth eventually gets out.
I do think that if he was,
if he was a black athlete from a pool
from like Ghana or something,
look at that.
He lost all four major sponsors in one
day.
Good.
He's a dickhead.
I don't give a shit about Ryan.
Lucky who lost a million dollars and
endorsement money.
Woo.
Suck.
Speaking of breaking ourselves into
intertribal racial camps,
did you see the,
the approval of the Ellen generous as a
tweet?
No.
And she said she was a.
She did this.
Can you find that Jamie?
So you saying bolt.
She was like,
it was something like next time,
next time I go to the supermarket,
I know what mode of transportation I'm
going to get.
And there was like a photoshop image of
her on Hussein bolt back or something.
Uh,
here we go.
She tweeted that.
Or did somebody.
Did somebody photoshop it or did she do
it?
I think her show Photoshop,
photoshop.
And then she tweeted it.
Oh,
okay.
I see you write someone a fan.
Did it,
did they?
Uh,
and so then of course it's like,
it becomes this big thing about she's
racist because it's the white.
It's the white person enslaving the
black person.
Seriously.
Does anyone believe that?
She wouldn't have made the same joke?
If.
So here she is like being given a
piggyback by Hussein Bolt.
That's funny.
It's funny.
It's not a photoshop.
Is that what that is?
No,
she's really doing it.
Joe,
why did somebody photoshop straight?
What does the tweet say?
Girlfriends.
Hot.
Who gives a fuck?
Go down.
School out.
Stop,
go back.
Dammit,
I'm trying,
trying,
trying to scroll down.
We have a picture of her girlfriend
right there for them.
Okay.
Is that I should have gone back again.
This was wrong.
She looked really cute and so she wrote,
this is how I'm running errands from now
on Hashtag Rio 2016 with the picture of
her.
But that's not a race joke.
While people are retarded.
That's a,
it was a white guy.
The white guy.
She'd still.
I mean she still would have traded it,
right?
So that doesn't mean that she's racist.
So this comes down to the question of
when we,
when we accuse someone of doing
something racist,
uh,
we,
do we actually believe that they're
racist or are we just trying to find an
excuse to interpret what they're saying
is basis recreationally outraged.
That's what she is.
Yeah.
Where they are,
where they're getting upset at her,
they're orange.
They're deciding that this is something
that they should be upset about.
They see the green light and they're
hitting the gas.
Yeah.
Have you really get pissed off at that?
Go jump off a fucking bridge.
Seriously.
Just stop.
Just stop talking,
tweeting,
interacting,
stop sharing your opinions of,
of sort of emotional and intellectual
effort.
Joe,
that's expended in the world these days
on these outrage outburst.
If you could channel that hot air into
some kind of power plant,
be like Zeplin,
light it on fire suppression and just
grow it out.
Cover album.
Yeah.
It's a waste of time.
And it's one of those things where I
think we were.
We've already beaten it into the ground.
We know what it is and I think it's
slowly being less and less acceptable
for people to do shit like that because
I think more and more people realize how
fucking unproductive and stupid it
really is.
Yeah.
I feel like that's right.
I,
I hope that the tide is turning,
but I think that as the tide turns,
the people who really get a kick out of
this stuff,
uh,
becoming more and more vitriolic and
turning the dial up to 11.
Yeah,
because you just feel like they're being
sidelined.
There's still shut ins.
They're still not going out and
experiencing the world.
They're still living in this really
bizarre confined environment that they
exist in or it's,
it's,
it's not reasonable.
That's not reasonable to get upset at
that.
I had a conversation with an African
American friend of mine about braided
hair the other day,
was it a Kardashian just got her hair
braided,
cultural appropriation,
cultural appropriation.
And what frustrated me was she kept
going up to the edge of,
of being critical of it and then saying,
look,
I don't really carry the way and in
these conversations I always feel like
saying,
well if you don't care then just don't
care.
Didn't bode Derek do that like way
fucking back in the day.
I mean,
is that really cultural?
Appropriation came from age,
ipt.
I mean they've been around for so much
longer than that.
Remember when that fucking girl was
getting mad at that boy for having
dreadlocks and she was trying to cut his
hair off and yeah,
she's being a cunt to him and she was
doing it just because he was a little
tiny guy and she can get away with it.
I think if he was a 250 pound football
player,
she'd be saying the same things to him.
We'll also,
of course not he,
she,
she's at a liberal arts college and so
she knows that he's going to be full of
enough white guilt that she can pull
that shit and he's,
he's going to cop it,
she assumes and meanwhile she's wrong.
The dreadlocks came from,
the Greeks came from the Romans.
It's like they've been around as long as
people have been stinky with dirty hair
and so what my friend was saying about,
about brides was,
hey,
go preparation bro.
Derek Damn,
she was hot.
She was hot as fuck back then.
My friend was saying,
look,
all we want is for people to,
to just recognize that it's
appropriation and,
and to,
to,
to understand and to express their
gratitude for.
And I was like,
what?
By what mechanism would a Kardashian who
gets brides elicit such a,
I mean,
exhibit such gratitude for the cultural.
I mean if,
if it gets great,
gets braids and then goes out and says,
I want to thank everyone in the African
Community for creating brides that's
going to cause more of a fucking stood
then if she just did it.
It's so stupid.
What if I were a Sarong?
Wouldn't just wear pants and you're
black.
What if you're aware of white European
created pants and shirts?
Is that cultural appropriation?
What is that?
So stupid culture is about sharing.
That's what it is about.
It's about when you go to an Indian
restaurant,
are you culturally appropriating because
you're eating their food.
It's fucking stupid.
When you create your own Indian food,
are you violating the rules of culture
appropriation?
If you have taco Tuesday,
you a piece of shit,
you know,
come on.
It's fucking dumb man.
It's dumb.
You probably paid to sheet if you have
taco Tuesday.
It's just mad.
It's just stupid,
but some of the best thing about all
this stupid stuff.
I'm tired of wasting any of my time and
thoughts on social justice warrior
ideal.
I'm actually starting to study to stop
doing that because if people haven't
heard previous times that I've been on
the show and you like this,
then go back and listen to the to the
previous ones,
but you'll find that joe and I spent a
reasonably large amount of time talking
about social justice issues and social
justice warrior issues and how
ridiculous it all is.
I feel like to some extent we've reached
a tipping point where that's hopefully
no longer necessary and now it's a
little bit self indulgent for us to be
whining about the wine is.
I think you're right.
That's how I feel.
I feel like we've sold one whining,
I feel like.
Yeah,
exactly.
I feel like we've kind of won this
battle and we don't need to be so
outraged at the outrage anymore.
I think the data has to come in and we
had to understand that the only reason
why people were being so recreationally
outraged about the stupid shit because
they don't have real things to be fucked
up about in real life.
It's easy to get food.
It's easy to get shelter.
It's most people have those things.
Those are the primary things that we
need and once you have those things and
there's so readily accessible,
then you start looking at things to pick
on in the world because you don't have
any real dilemmas,
any real significant,
important,
absolute dilemma's primal dilemmas and
then the.
Yeah,
so the outrage machine,
I mean it comes back a little bit to,
to the reaction to Kurt Metzger,
Cummins,
I'm assume is Radha about rape as well,
like what is the appropriate
parameters of public discourse in order
to trigger the outright?
See I disagree there because like in
that sense,
like he's saying something about a
violent crime against women and he's not
exactly sure.
You know,
so I,
I kind of see why someone would be
outraged that you would step up and
defend the guy when you don't really
know because you weren't there.
But he's also definitely agree that it's
a more valid criticism.
Criticism of came as a lot more valid
than criticism of element.
Too Generous for her tweets.
That's true.
Definitely,
but still
in both cases I think that getting too
angry and wanting to punish people for
doing something that's politically
incorrect is not the ideal response like
did,
did you see also
important to point out that he didn't
say that the guy wasn't guilty when he
did say is that we have to understand
that women are capable.
He did it in a parody form,
but what he did say is women are capable
of lying to like this,
this stupid club,
whatever it is.
Bands.
This guy,
you know,
I don't know if they're stupid.
I'm sure they're great,
but they ban this guy.
They don't know whether or not he's
guilty and he's saying that this woman
cannot have lied because like my Bible.
That's right.
Too Hung up on the question of whether
or not he thinks the guy is guilty or
not.
That's not his point.
He's made.
His point is a social.
Social media should not be the forum in
which we conduct witch hunts
people.
Right,
and so people,
they.
They see something where someone's
stepping out with a controversial
opinion and what's their immediate idea
is not to debate this and say,
hey,
this is not necessarily appropriate,
but here's where it's point is and
here's where I disagree.
No,
fire him.
Punish him.
Bird,
Hey,
hey,
show it.
I ran the Dec.
Shoot them in the deck.
Did you Say the story about the saatchi,
the the executive at saatchi in london
who was fired for inappropriate comments
about feminism?
No,
so about maybe four or five weeks ago.
What was his comment?
He said he was getting it as a saatchi
and saatchi and saatchi is one of the
world's biggest ad agencies and they're
based in the uk and he is an elderly
white guy and he was giving an interview
to business insider and they asked about
feminism and sexism in the workplace and
he said that it's not an issue.
It's archie because he thinks that women
have this much more expansive vision of
what their priorities shoulD be and that
old old male dinosaurs have this old
fashioned idea about success,
which is they want to get to the top of
the ladder and they want to become an
executive and they want to have as much
money and power as possible,
but that women have a more expansive
view and are a wiser and more about
children and family and other things
than just success.
And that was perceived as being an
excuse for not addressing sexism in the
workplace.
And he was fired.
He was fired for.
yeah.
So that's a larry put on,
on administrative leave
or whatever it is indefinitely.
And I got an to work in advertising.
I sort of understood like that is a,
that is a whole big argument and
interesting conversation that's
happening among feminists themselves.
Right?
I mean even my old boss,
arianna huffington has written columns
about this sort of thing in between
Sleeping in between,
hi wonder have naps.
And dan,
I complain about how women can make it
as I'm worth $100,000,000,000.
She's.
She sounds like dr.
Evil,
dr.
Evil
back to me.
You will complete me
though.
She was not saying that she doesn't say
that women are being held back.
Her point is that we need to have like a
broader view of success rather than just
thinking about money and power over.
Sure but big.
But when a,
what man says,
and I look,
I don't know that it is appropriate for
a white man at the top of a company that
doesn't have very many women on the
board to be speculating loudly about why
it's not important.
Why?
There's no sexism in his company and why
it's not important for them to address,
but I don't think that he should be
fired for it.
Well,
you,
I don't think you should be able to say
to someone,
you know,
how do you feel about racism in your
company?
I think you should have to have
something to accuSe someone of before
you start bringing up accusations like
that.
Like there has to be something like if
there's a specific example of sexism
that he needs to address in his company
and then he meets,
needs to make a statement on it.
That's one thing.
But how did the journaLists is just into
int interested in this powerful mens
idea about women in the workforce in
general?
I don't think they're making an
accusation if you're right.
That's what I'm saying.
I'm saying they're not making an
accusation,
so if you're getting upset of this guy's
opinion about sexism and saying that I
don't think there's sexism in my company
because I.
This is.
We have this diverse view of what
success is and I think women are getting
away from this old dinosaur idea of what
second.
That's just nothing wrong with what he
said,
but if you say anything about sexism
other than what they want you to say,
well that's the thing.
What's the problem?
What upsets,
what?
What I worry about is that people are no
longer being punished for using bad
woods or slurs or attacking people or
expressing flagrantly bigoted opinions
or saying that one race or one sex is
better or worse than another.
I'm kind of cool with taking people down
for,
for doing that shit right there.
Now being punished for simply expressing
opinions that feel old fashioned.
Exactly,
and so you have to subscribe to sort of
the ideological thought police.
Yes,
that's,
that's a real worry.
Even if I disagree with all of those
opinions,
I want to live in a society that is
boisterous and diverse with lots of
different argumentative,
you know,
arguments coming from lots of different
positions and a lot of my white liberal
friends disagree with this.
They say that having loose,
these are smart,
successful,
can lose anyway.
What they say is that having someone
like him expressive,
a view like that actually silences other
people because it deprives it.
It probably,
it probably inhibits the women in his
company from feeling like they can speak
openly about their ambitions because
they think that there's a misogynistic
chauvinistic old dinosaur in charge of
the company will biases.
I can't really comment on this unless I
see his exact quote because we're
paraphrasing here.
I'm here.
So what is it?
His exact quote.
You caN't find the story
I was looking at when you started.
Well,
tell me,
what is his name?
What is the name of the place?
Saatchi and saatchi and saatchi.
Let me just see that.
S a,
t c h I o jamie can't spell saatchi.
bus feminism.
Saatchi,
fos feminism.
Feminism,
brouhaha for paul,
fau x space p a s.
Okay.
If we
scroll up please.
If women want to equal men,
they must change their notion of
happiness.
Hmm.
Women not men propelled the cult of
motherhood and spread the frightening
notion that life will never be truly
complete without a baby and that no
career plotted can compare.
Is that what he said?
No,
it's not what he said.
That's an opinion.
Pace by someone in the independent who
is twisting his words.
Well,
what the fuck is his words?
Let's find out.
The margin might be quoted in this.
Fine.
His words,
please.
Yeah,
it was because of what that is is
ridiculous.
Would that whatever the fuck that person
just said,
yeah,
you can get upset at the guy.
If he says that their ambition is not a
vertical ambition,
it is intrinsic circular ambition to be
happy.
Huh?
They are going,
actually guys,
you're missing the point.
You don't understand.
I'm way happier than you.
He explained their ambitious,
not a vertical ambition.
It is this intrinsic circular ambition
to be happy.
What?
This is weird.
Tim hunt,
abandoned,
need career here territory.
By saying that saatchi and saatchi,
he'd met a number of talented women who
reach a certain point in their careers
and rejected the chance to become
creative directors.
They're going,
actually guys,
you're missing the point,
so I'll repeat it again.
He saying that these women are saying,
guys,
you're missing the point.
You don't understand.
I'm way happier than you.
He explained their ambition is not a
vertical ambition.
It's as intrinsic circular ambition to
be happy.
Well,
you'd have to debate that idea because I
don't know if that's not necessarily
true for a lot of women who decided to
have children and then realized they
would rather raise these children than
climb is stupid fucking corporate
ladder.
I don't think there's anything Wrong
with what he said.
Yeah.
He also says,
here's the original article.
He says,
if you think about those darwinian urges
of wealth,
power,
and fame,
they're not terribly effective in
today's world for a millennial because
they want connectivity and
collaboration.
They feel like they can get that without
managing and leading,
so maybe we've got the definition wrong.
We're trying to impose our antiquated
shit on them and they're going,
actually,
guys,
you're missing the point.
You don't understand.
I'm way happier than you.
Their ambition,
meaning women's ambition is not a
vertical ambition.
It's this intrinsic circular ambition to
be happy here.
You just read that.
So I say we're not judging ourselves by
those standards that you idiotic
dinosaur like men judge yourself by.
He says,
I don't think the lack of women in
leadership roles is a problem.
I'm just not worried about it because
they're very happy.
They're very successful and doing great
work.
I can't talk about sexual discrimination
because we've never had that problem.
Thank goodness.
That last part slightly problematic.
I mean,
I think that what he's doing is
expressing a very self deprecating
opinion and this is talking about
himself being like an old fart.
And then the following weekend they
announced that he'd been placed on leave
and this,
they released a statement saying,
um,
because of his comments,
it is for the gravity of these
statements that Kevin Roberts has been
asked to take a leave of absence
effective immediately.
Oh my god,
everyone can suck my dick.
Everyone line up promoting gender
equality starts at the top and we will
not tolerate anyone speaking for our
organization who does not value the
importance of inclusion.
I don't think that's what he worked very
hard to champion diversity and will
continue to insist that each agency's
leadership be champions of both
diversity and inclusion.
They should boycott that agency.
They're a bunch of twat.
I can't believe I've spent so many,
so many man hours arguing this on
facebook.
This is the other thing,
like when you were talking about using
cell phones and like facebook and like
not using twitter so much and how kind
of corrosive that can be to your lived
experience.
Constantly dipping into that well of
insanity.
It's just a fucking waste of time.
It's a drag on my time these days,
joe.
I spend like I posted it.
So what,
how this blew up in my face was I posted
on facebook this article,
an article about this and all my comment
was was um,
descends shall not be tolerated.
Okay.
That was what I wrote.
Right?
Well,
tHat's a joke,
right?
You know,
we're not gonna tolerate and people will
send to.
You
ended up being like pages and pages and
pages and pages.
We had to migrate it into medicine job.
I had to go into private messages.
It's just reams and reams of back and
forth with friends in europe,
friends all over the world trying to
convince me that I'm a,
you know,
a chauvinist for support on suck my
dick.
All those friends follow them.
People stop.
They told me,
they said to me,
here's the problem.
This is not a prepared statement.
Not speaking off the cuff.
Another point that I was making,
like people don't understand what he's
just having a coffee with a reporter.
I mean what he Said was not that bad.
He's riffing.
Yeah,
and,
and he's trying to speak positively
about the company.
They don't have an issue with sexism.
Look,
he's.
I disagree with what he's saying.
I think it's naive.
I think it's kind of ham fiSted.
It's not.
Yeah,
exactly.
It's not the smartest thing to say.
It's not offensive and something that
usually it's something that certainly
opens up the possibility of debate.
Like you could say,
well,
if there's a lot of women that don't
feel like that,
I feel like the door or the glaSs
ceiling is there for them to achieve
management.
Exactly.
And the missions and the best
response to an idea that you disagree
with is to respond with more ideas and
to take that idea down,
not to fire the person who who had that
idea,
I'm so weary,
I can't do this anymore.
May two.
And these are smart,
very smart,
successful people.
One of them told me that I sounded like
he.
He basically said that I'm the same.
He was remembering back to an occasion
in the 19 eighties were an english
broadcast and english sports broadcaster
cold.
One of the,
one of the players,
a nigga I really liked,
but with a whole bunch of adjectives
before,
like a lazy,
a lazy.
He's just a lazy,
nasty old nigga.
that person got fired and he said that
I,
I am the type of shit.
I'm just like the type of person who was
who was opposed to the firing of that
person because he was at every point in
time our standards evolve and you are
just one of those white chauvinistic
dinosaurs who's defending the old,
yoU Know,
the old guard.
And in 50 years I'll be regarded as
being,
as I was like.
And that guy got away from his computer
and his wife put her strap on on and peg
and they cried and then she took his
credit card and she shit in his mouth
and she left her house and she fucked
her.
Her personal trainer,
who's a giant african american man with
a dick,
like a police flashlight.
Fuck him.
Fuck them all.
I'm tired of it.
Tired of it.
And I.
And it makes me question myself.
was this neighbor,
oh neighbor,
someone's breaking into the neighbor's
alarm.
Shouldn't be going off to sleep past
business hours.
Uh,
I gotta get outta here,
dude.
yeah,
let's go.
I do this anymore.
I really can't do this anymore in terms
of like subject matter.
I'm so tired of like validating these
dummies opinions and arguing about it.
No,
I mean I'm glad that we didn't really
talk about it much today.
I'm over it as well.
I try to stay away from it as much as
possible and I try to let it
peter out the massacre conversation is
much more complex and you know,
and the,
the,
the subject of mean you're talking about
like a real crime rape,
right?
Did it happen?
We don't know.
It was a real issue just to.
Women are accusing a guy,
have a real crime.
It's,
there's a thing happening there with
this other guy.
This is not a conversation that guy's
having about sexism at a company that he
worked.
But the thing is,
I take your point,
but the midst good thing is similar to
maybe not insofar as it relates to
write,
but insofar as it relates to what should
the penalty be against cut for
expressing an unpopular opinion?
Yes.
In an unpopular way.
No,
you're right.
You're right.
He should fucking quit that stupid show
and uh,
get a podcast because we always got
enough skanks go listen to his gut race
wars as well.
I've been on that show with everybody
else.
Go fuck yourself with the people.
He doesn't support josh steps.
Fuck off.
Exactly.
And if you want to hear sam harris and
hannibal buress going to be released
within the next few weeks.
Few weeks.
Fucking put it out,
man.
What are you doing?
Why are you clinging to it?
Trying to build up attention.
No,
it wasn't.
It was just a regionally planned for
them.
So if I want,
if I was going to release it now because
that was what just when sam was fitted
into the schedule,
I just throw it out there.
It's already done,
but it's so wild.
But why you,
why you call my producer?
I don't want to hear it.
Yeah,
but why are you hanging out?
Would really sit before we do that.
Really?
If you don't release it in a couple of
days,
we have a copy of that.
We're just going to fuck it.
Send it out there.
Just kidding.
Thank you josh.
So people live.
Everybody lives forward on all of your
pod platforms.
Joe.
It's always wonderful.
Always a pleasure.
I really appreciate it.
We've got to do this more often.
Absolutely.
Every tear,
open invitation,
you know that.
Thank you ladies and gentlemen.
See as soon you fuckers.