Here we go,
four,
three,
two,
one.
Boom.
First of all,
before we get started,
I want to say I love your reviews.
You are my favorite.
You,
you have the.
Well you and Lou.
I love Lou too,
but you,
you,
you're so good at covering all the bases
of whether it's cell phones or any kind
of weird technology that's coming out
and you just,
you just nail it.
You just,
you're so.
You're my go to guy man.
Well,
thank you.
That's quite an intro.
I appreciate that.
I really want to tell it like whenever a
new cell phones out,
like I saw that you walked in with the
red,
but that's your,
that's not your daily driver.
No,
I thought you would like this.
This is,
I mean every phone now is glass on glass
and everything,
you know?
Uh,
but this,
this red hydrogen one has a lot of weird
stuff about it.
Uh,
it's first of all,
it's about twice as big as it has to be,
but it's from red,
which is a camera company.
Why all these buttons everywhere.
So really good grip buttons.
This is just a grip,
this grip,
you can probably drop it from 45 feet
and it'll be fine.
Throw it across the room,
but the weird part is it's made by red,
so red is a camera company there.
They used their cameras.
I love their cameras,
but then they come out with this,
which is a function.
It's kind of weird,
but there is a screen.
Yeah,
it's my foot actually.
So that's next to the.
The iphone eight plus,
which is already a huge phone.
What is this metal thing on the back?
That brass looking.
So it's got these pins and it's supposed
to next year support modules that will
connect to it.
So potentially Vr,
better camera,
bigger battery,
a Vr,
whatever.
Read,
decide to support or make will attach to
it,
but it's also Kinda may or may not
happen for awhile.
Yeah,
because Jamie ordered one.
When did you order one?
Paid for it last.
I don't know.
Right when I went on sale last August,
maybe vaporware,
mine.
My official ingest ship.
That's a prototype.
This is the prototype you have here?
Yes,
seven.
I've worked with red for.
I've seen a lot of the process since
I've gotten like eight software updates
and this is not final,
but like gets a pretty good idea.
Yeah.
What do you think about it so far?
So I surprisingly get a lot of people
like new camera companies or new
companies come up and make a phone and
it's just not right in a lot of ways.
They kind of took a lot of notes and
they went and minimal with the software.
I like that about it.
I was expecting the camera to be
amazing.
It's they don't use.
They don't make this sensor so the
camera is not amazing yet,
but I think the modules,
we'll make this what it is.
I think the phone by itself is not
really $1,300
phone,
but it's support for upcoming things
that they're planning.
I think we'll make it good.
Is it a problem when a company tries to
get into the cell phone business and
you're competing with Samsung,
apple,
you know,
hard way.
There's just so many companies that are
so advanced for you to be read who's
essentially a camera manufacturer that
make video cameras.
Yeah.
Really high end for people that
know a really high end hd video cameras
and a lot of movies are shot on them.
Films,
all kinds of things.
You need to videos.
Yeah.
Oh,
you do all your youtube videos with it.
Yeah.
Is it really that good for you?
I mean,
is it worth having a read?
It's a large camera,
right?
It's heavy.
Yeah.
It started off not that great.
And then I got used to it and then they
got better.
So that was probably like five years ago
that I first started with a red,
a red scarlet.
This four k five k cameron.
Yeah.
It's kind of a pain,
but the workflow has gotten better.
They've worked with smaller teams,
like individual creators even to get the
cameras now smaller it does more in a
smaller body.
So it's gotten a lot easier to use a red
for a small team.
Whereas like,
yeah,
five years ago they were making a read
for a movie shoot with 15 people using.
Yeah.
So how much do they weigh?
No.
Uh,
I couldn't tell you a weight,
I'd say probably between six and 10
pounds at all.
Yeah,
because you,
it's completely modular.
You rig it up to be what you want.
So like you get that out the box,
which is just the brain we're looking at
for people who are just listening,
it says Red Dragon on the side.
Why is it called silver?
Red Dragon.
And you got some names.
It's pretty clutch looking.
It looks like a,
it looks really like a computer,
like.
So that's what,
that's what you're looking at is just
the computer and the sensor and that
side piece right there is the SSD
reader.
Everything else,
all those pins you see on the top and on
the side,
that's where you connect what you want
to make it the rig.
So if you're doing this eight years ago
you would attach a viewfinder,
you'd attach a couple monitors for
director as you would attach a controls
more.
Yeah,
all the follow focus on the Lens.
Obviously the mount,
all this stuff has to attached to it.
But for just me and my use,
I'd use it more kind of like what you
might see in another image,
which is just a monitor and SSD,
a controller and a lens and that does
everything.
So is the idea
eventually that this phone is going to
be able to do everything that that does.
So that I think if you asked read,
they would say yes,
but they aren't there yet,
obviously.
How could they released something and
not have an amazing camera on?
Yeah,
that seems crazy that,
that I think is what I think a lot of
people were super hyped about because
obviously red's good with not just the,
they make the silicon for the camera,
but they're good at color science and
autofocus and all these different things
that cameras should be good at.
Uh,
so when they come out with a phone that
has a camera on it,
you just kind of expect it to be
amazing.
So when it's not the best,
I firmly believe this is the best
camera.
Then you have the Google Pixel three.
Yeah.
Is the best camera in a phone?
Are you a Google Pixel fanboy?
I this point,
I'm a fan,
I'm a fan of the camera,
which has turned me into a fan of the,
the rest of the phone.
Just the camera alone.
It's an unusual cameron that it only has
one.
One camera.
Yes.
Yeah.
There's one camera where everybody else
is going with multiple cameras.
Three for Google's doing everything with
software.
Yes.
And I liked that about it.
Now is that the xl cxl it seems,
it doesn't seem that big.
It's kind of not that insane.
I think everyone's,
everyone's into the notch obviously,
which is a little different from what
you might see in a,
an iphone or a Huawei phone or
something.
Um,
but the software is very googly.
The screen is much better than last
year.
It's glass of wireless charging.
It's got all these things.
The last year's phone didn't have,
but the camera is absolutely what makes
that phone good.
It's really that much better.
It is that much better.
What is so good about it?
Uh,
it's like you said,
it's the software.
So what Google does with HDR and
essentially their image processing is a
big part of why it's good.
You can put the same sensor in glass and
another smartphone with way weaker
software and it wouldn't look as good.
Um,
but what they do with that,
that image processing APP,
it's a rolling buffer of images.
So you can take a,
it's like instant shutter.
So as soon as you press the shutter,
it's instant shutter a,
you freeze the motion.
The dynamic range is great.
The detail is great and it's photos are
amazing.
I was amazed of the low light photos.
Yeah,
there was stunning because I had seen
before that was the Walway,
the mate Rs,
I guess it was.
There's been a couple really good night
modes in while we phones.
Yeah.
But this seemed even better than that
and it didn't seem distorted.
It seemed like you realized it was at
night,
but you could see all the detail.
Yeah,
it's hard.
It's just never going to look as good as
daytime.
But,
uh,
there's,
I haven't,
I don't have the update yet,
but there's going to be an update to the
pixel that has night site or another
night mode that does the same thing,
which is taking a bunch of exposures and
long exposures and use a stabilization
and hopefully get some much brighter
image that looks way better than what
would be different from the update in,
in,
in comparison to what it does now.
So right now if you just take a photo at
night,
it'll just try to noise,
reduce all.
Like when you take a photo at night,
there's a lot of grain,
you're pumping the ISO all the way up
and when you clean all that noise out
you are,
it's kind of like airbrushing the image
and it's going to be softer.
So if you do a lot of noise reduction,
you lose all your detail.
It's really soft.
So low light photos just aren't as good.
But if you can take a longer exposure
with better stabilization,
you can not crank the ISO as high,
not introduced as much noise.
And then at the end of the day,
have a more detailed,
better looking photo.
So that's the theory behind a lot of
these night modes.
How do they do the all in software?
A lot of calibration,
a lot of knowing exactly how good the
optical image stabilization is in the
Lens.
And then electronic stabilization as
well.
A lot of algorithms knowing what part of
the photo is moving versus what isn't.
So there's a lot of computational
photography is what it's called a
happening on the chip that makes it that
good.
It's just fascinating that Google is the
only one who's doing this with one
camera as opposed to everyone else.
Like my iphone has several cameras.
I have a uh,
a note nine,
which I really like.
And one of the other things about Google
does not have a lot of Ram.
Now I've found that actually kind of a,
an interesting week point about this
phone and I haven't even.
I've reviewed it and it was kind of
skeptical about it's only only four gigs
of Ram,
which is like a couple of years ago.
Wow.
Four weeks or I'm at a phone.
That's amazing.
It's amazing,
but a lot of phones coming out and has
six,
eight gigs of Ram.
Who has the most right now?
A phone,
just a gaming phone.
Just came out with 10 gigs of Ram or the
razor phone or a different.
Now another one,
I don't even remember the name,
but then there's also an apo.
Find x with 10 gigs of Ram,
but do you need that?
No,
you don't.
You don't need.
What would.
What would be the benefit of having 10
gigs of Ram?
Like what software would run?
Basically the advantage to having more
ram is keeping apps open and running in
the background longer,
so if you have your camera and your
twitter and your instagram and your web
browser and all that,
a lot of high,
maybe a couple of games all running at
the same time and then you multitask and
switch between them on a phone with less
ram.
You'll find that you'll switch from the
game to the browser and you go back to
the browser and it reloads everything
because it completely garbage.
That from the memory.
After awhile,
because it was trying to save space,
so on the phone with four gigs of Ram,
this happened a couple of times where
I'd be listening to music and I'd open
the camera and take a few photos and
then the music or the podcasts or
whatever would just stop and it killed
that APP in the background with only
four gigs of Ram.
I'm not doing that crazy things with
multitasking.
Just two things running just to.
I think it might've been a bug because
the camera uses a lot of memory and for
whatever reason it just picks the other
big memory app and kills it.
It's not very repeatable.
I've had it happen to me since I landed
yesterday,
like a couple of times,
but it I think a phone with six or eight
gigs of Ram though.
The last phone I was using for awhile
was the one plus six has eight gigs of
Ram and I never happened to me.
Every time I multitask and go back five,
10 apps to go and open it,
it was right where I left off.
Is the Google Pixel three your favorite
phone or is it just your favorite film?
Because of the camera.
It is my favorite phone period and it
also has the best camera.
And is it your favorite film because it
has pure Google because you have the
android,
it's the latest android which is Kinda
hard to find and then you get obviously
this pure google experience in this
amazing camera and a great display and
my priority is in a phone or pretty much
along those lines.
I need a great camera and then I want a
great display.
I want good software and then the rest
kind of follows.
And you want pure Google,
right?
You don't want to be operating under the
Samsung Skin.
I don't mind.
I don't mind a skin if it's good.
Uh,
there's a lot of skins,
like one plus has oxygen less and it's a
skin.
Technically it's close to pure google,
but it's missing a lot of the pixel
features but it's fine.
It's smooth.
It's great.
Is One plus running the latest android?
No,
no.
Who is,
it's a central phone.
So one plus I think just got the android
p update essential,
just got the android update and then
everyone else is on like one version ago
or older.
And why?
Why is that a pain the ass for them?
Why can't it be universal?
I have a bunch of theories on why they
don't update their software as quickly
as they probably could.
I think a lot of it in the US,
especially as youth carriers,
when you have to get a.
You want to push a software update to a
phone on verizon for example.
Not only do you have to like rewrite the
software and optimized and everything,
but then you have to submit it for like
certification from verizon.
Verizon has to push that update.
That whole introduction of the third
party through the carrier is a huge pain
in the ass.
And then on top of that,
I know a lot of people who when they get
a software update,
like actively avoid installing it,
they just don't want change in their
phone.
So at the end of the day,
like they put all that money and work
into making a software update and half
the people never install it or don't
care.
Then they just figured they might as
well not put the money there.
So a lot of teams are.
A lot of manufacturers just don't.
They don't.
They,
they support the phone for a year or two
and then that's it.
But for folks like you,
for the power users,
that's big.
That's a big thing.
Having the latest and greatest.
Definitely.
Yeah.
That's why I'm a fan of phones that keep
the skin light and update quickly,
which is what you'll find with pixel and
essential in oxygen license,
stuff like that.
And that's really it.
Like Samsung takes a long time to get to
it.
Yeah.
Was Great.
As Samsung phones are,
they definitely are not first to get new
software.
They're trying to do it quicker
apparently what I've been reading,
but I guess there is.
There's a bunch of issues always
bottleneck.
Now when,
when you compare phones,
like do you have a checklist of things
that you have like on a computer or is
it just all off the top of your head?
Like do you,
do you have like a rating system that
you use?
A personal rating system?
I don't have a rating.
I do have a,
like a,
like a checklist of things that I
definitely pay attention to every time
that I must go through screens,
displays and battery life,
how good the camera is and things like
that.
But I'd never come to like a rating out
of whatever.
I used to do that a long time ago,
but I stopped because I just,
it's kind of like a neverending.
You'll never,
you'll never get a 10 out of 10
basically because if you ever give
something a 10 out of 10,
the next one's going to be better.
Right.
So how do you,
how do you put that on the scale?
So I just don't turn up for October
2018,
I guess he,
ah,
you'd be like this is the best phone.
Like I said,
if that say this is the best phone right
now,
then maybe that's not a 10 out of 10,
but it's like the best you can get,
but that,
that line just keeps moving so I don't
give things numbers but see for me those
are the things you said that would be a
pain in the ass that your music would
shut off because you're using the
camera.
That's kind of big.
That's a pain.
Yes.
Yeah,
that it's not a 10 out of 10 because of.
I think the memory is a problem.
Yeah,
the notches bothering some people.
It doesn't bother me anymore.
It just kind of blends in.
I don't really look at the notch.
So have you gone into the developer
settings and fuck now?
Removal of the notch.
I tried it.
It wasn't that big a deal.
It just makes a big black
bar over the top.
Exactly.
And you just lose the screen you paid
extra for that seems silly.
Yeah.
I don't mind it on the iphone.
I mostly,
mostly I use the excess Max.
This one right here,
but I'm so sour on apple because of what
they did with the batteries.
Yeah.
That was such a dirty thing to me
because everybody had always suspected.
Like my friend Brian was always like,
dude,
I'm telling you when the new phones come
out,
your old phone starts moving slower.
My Dad's a conspiracy.
That's all horse shit.
Like your phone's just old bro.
But then when I found out that it was
real,
I was like,
you assholes and problem.
And the problem was the way they didn't
tell people like they could have just
avoided the whole whatever pr we want,
whatever you wanna call it by just
telling people,
look,
this is what we do on your phones.
Getting older.
We need to preserve either the CPU or
the battery,
so we need to either voltage down the
CPU or save your battery,
pick one and give us a choice.
They didn't tell us until people started
suspecting things and they had to make a
statement and then another kind of dirty
and like hidden by it.
Yeah.
I think it's a trick to try to get you
to buy new phones.
I don't.
There was no way they didn't think about
that.
Of course,
there's no chance that.
Yeah.
Why else would they do it that way?
Why would.
Why wouldn't they just let the battery
be slower or they let the CPB slower and
the best part is they give you the
choice now,
but if you never look for it,
you'll never find it and they definitely
still default to saving your battery by
under clocking a chip.
So your phone will still slow down if
you don't know where to find that
option.
So as soon as a new phones come out,
basically no motherfucker,
it's just dirty.
It seems pretty dirty yet because it's
the thing that everybody always
suspected.
Oh,
everybody was suspected.
There was some sort of engineered
obsolescence and they're due.
They're doing this on purpose to get you
to keep buying the newest,
latest and greatest.
But I wanted to like go now apple.
Apple wouldn't do that.
I mean,
your friends,
hey,
paint this picture that's really up
upright and like we want you to have the
best experience as long as possible,
which involves not replacing your
battery,
which means we'll just slow down your
phone just a little bit so that it's,
it,
it lasts longer in the battery.
Can keep up,
make sense on paper,
but on paper.
Well it's,
there's a lot of things about apple that
I really like a really love the,
the OSTP.
I really love it.
I mean it's,
it's just so much better than windows,
but their keyboard sucks so bad on their
laptop.
It's just all the laptop.
Yeah.
Cliquey,
it just doesn't,
it doesn't feel good.
There's the sketch,
shallow travel.
There's all these issues with.
I switched to a Lenovo and went with a
thinkpad just for,
for standup.
I have to write a lot and I found out
that I wrote way slower,
like maybe 10 words per minute slower.
Like it's,
it's a real issue because it's like you
make a lot more mistakes with those
little shallow clicky things.
Yeah.
And with the Lenovo you have um,
a much.
You have much more travel.
It's much easier to touch type.
It just feels better for me.
But that bums
me out.
It's like,
why can't they get that?
Right?
Like you,
you're making these things for creative
people,
right?
That's your whole thing.
So I think different,
you know,
that's another thing I kinda got like,
it's again,
like what apple tries to portray
themself as versus what you're actually
experiencing.
If you never listen to apple and you get
the new laptop,
you're like,
wow,
let's keyboards worse sex,
why is this keyboard so shallow and
mushy a,
and then you're supposed to listen to
apple.
And they're like,
well,
we made it quieter.
We made it thinner.
So the laptop's thinner now.
Uh,
and they'll,
they'll give you all these reasons why
they did what they did.
And there's supposed to go,
oh,
okay,
yeah,
that actually makes sense.
Maybe this is better,
but your experience often says the
opposite.
So that's why people like to not listen
to what apple says and just evaluate it
without listening to that.
Particularly for writers,
for someone who writes and you write on
a regular basis,
you want a comfortable keyboard and you
know,
I've,
I've constantly searched for the best
keyboard and right now I think it's
probably the thinkpad,
but I've heard great things about the
razor,
the razor pro,
which is the really large gaming one,
it has a mechanical keyboard for the
first time ever on a laptop and that's
supposed to be really good.
I have tried the blade and I have tried.
What I'm using right now is the surface,
the Microsoft surface laptop too and
that's got a pretty good at keyboard.
Yeah,
it's travels a lot.
It's backlit.
And then the actual laptop part itself
is not metal.
It's got like Al Conterra like you might
see inside a car,
like a soft touch on the laptop in my
backpack.
Yeah.
So I'll go grab that.
It's kind of Falcon Tara.
Yeah.
Like fake Suede.
Yeah,
like what you seem to.
That's the craziest Shit I've ever heard
in my life now.
Can Tara?
Yeah,
I'm the razor.
Pull up that razer blade pro too.
If you get a chance,
we'll look at the surface first because
he's going to go grab that.
But the razer blade pro,
it's also an enormous laptop and it has
the.
Yeah,
that's it right there.
The razer blade pro is so big and wide
that it actually has the mouse on the
side,
like a track pad.
This is it.
Huh?
So that's the surface laptop too.
Oh Wow.
How weird.
And a keyboard.
It's pretty good.
It's like a polished Alcantara Ooh,
that feels good.
Yeah.
The question though,
whenever you ecm material is like if I'm
putting my palms on that all the time,
how long will that last?
Will it start to thin out and look kind
of worn after awhile or will it stay
looking like that?
I hope it does.
And also the whole laptop is matte
black,
which is,
I think that looks dope,
but that's also usually a fingerprint
magnet we carry around like a matte
black thing.
You get like all this is grease on it or
whatever carrying it.
So that's a challenge for that laptop,
but I love it.
Well,
the other thing about
the difference between the keyboard on
this versus the keyboard on,
what I have is I have the Lenovo Carbon
[inaudible] [inaudible] and what I
really like about this is that
there's,
they're not flat.
They have like a little bit of a,
like a dip to them.
So your fingers sort of a little bit.
Yeah,
there's a little bit of A.
that's smart.
I wish more so like you kind of.
It's easier.
Oh yeah.
It's easier to touch type when you have
like the spot.
Yeah.
Why don't people figure that out?
I think all of it is just,
you get used to it like a,
there's a,
there's a google tablet that came out
recently with a $200 keyboard accessory
that has circular quays and slightly
concave,
but like typing on it was fine and like
they claim like,
oh yeah,
once you get used to it,
like the surface area of the key being
circular makes it easier to type faster
after awhile.
Huh?
I don't know if I buy that yet,
but maybe if you were a secretary and
you really,
you're really used to the circular.
It looks like a typewriter when you just
look at it.
We want to pull that thing up.
That would be the google.
Oh,
what do they call it?
Something Tab.
It came out like the same time.
The pixel three and they're naming is
weird with them,
but it has a.
yeah,
basically a surface like,
like $200 keyboard,
magnet accessory.
You can prop it up at any angle and it
goes from a tablet to a laptop with this
keyboard dock.
Huh.
And then it's a,
it's kind of interesting.
But the circular quay is.
I found weird that Alcan.
Tara on the hand rest feels amazing.
Yeah,
that's really nice.
I was going to get used to that.
I,
I've been using a Mac book pro for so
long.
Like I,
the contrast is like I was really used
to like having metal and metal feels
premium and good.
It's like it's not going to wear down.
Um,
but I,
I like this a lot.
Well,
what metal doesn't feel good?
Those on your hands when you're sitting
on it for a long time?
Just.
Yeah,
they kinda got where?
Like they wrap the material around to
the sides.
Mac Book Pros.
Literally sharp.
Cut to kind of.
You put your hands on the edge for too
long.
When Nova was carbon fiber.
Nice.
So this whole thing is a.
it's not cheap though.
No,
it's not cheap in comparison to a Mac
laptop though.
It's true.
It is.
And there's way more options.
That's the other thing with a Mac.
You get like a 13 inch,
you get a 15 inch,
you gotta touch bar or you get nothing
yet.
What's a matter of Jamie Pixel slate?
I just had it there.
The picture changed.
Oh these motherfuckers,
that's what it's called though.
Pixel sleep.
Oh there it is now.
So those are the key.
Circular quays and that sort of connects
to the tablet.
It's a great accessory like the magnet
on the back,
like I don't know if you've seen a
surface tablet with the little
kickstand.
You kind of have like a couple notches
where you can adjust it.
And I think the new version has infinite
adjustment,
but this is the same thing,
like there's a magnet in the back of the
surface or the pixel slate.
I've lets you adjust the tablet to any
angle.
Watch videos type.
Apple's the only company that makes
keyboards that I know that had it better
in like 2012 than they do in 2018.
If you get a 2012 macbook you.
Oh,
this is kind of better.
There's more travel.
Yeah.
You might think it's like an upgrade if
they want backwards.
Yeah.
That's.
I agree.
Goofy.
Kind of agree.
I don't know how they did that.
Yeah.
Well there's so design oriented.
I mean everything looks stellar.
That's what it is.
Apple has been a,
not a victim of their own desire to make
great design,
but they often very often make
compromises sometimes to the detriment
of how good a product can be to make it
look better.
Classic example was the Mac pro,
the little circular trashcan looking Mac
pro that came out.
Yeah,
he 12 or something like that.
They kept.
They made all these promises.
It's this sleek modern workstation,
it's going to have the xeon chips and
big gps and I loved it,
uh,
but it only had one fan for a six slash
$7,000
workstation and they constantly
overheated and would throttle and
eventually it was a nightmare for them.
Wasn't that something that was going on
with the latest laptops with the latest
Mac book pro?
Yeah.
Same thing,
same thing.
They made the,
the I nine,
the core I nine.
They put in this
super thin laptop.
They made this laptop so finn and I kept
the fan speed so low because it's got to
be quiet.
So they,
they just throttled the CPU down so it
wouldn't get so hot that they had to
kick up the fans that high.
So the actual performance,
even though the CPU is more powerful,
was not as good as the last model.
Right.
Which was to make it look good.
Exactly.
So yeah,
apple's been a victim of their own,
like desire to make things so beautiful
and then they got fucked by Walway
because while we came along with the
mate book and the mate book pro is
really a better version of the Mac book
and into it.
Yeah,
he nailed it.
There's no bezels the way that Webcam
pops up from the found interesting.
I don't know how it angles up your
nostril.
Exactly.
It's like on
the table level of wherever you're
sitting and looking up at you.
That's very odd.
But yeah,
there's,
there's a lot of great things about
that.
But
pull that thing up mate book pro while
we.
But meanwhile it's probably spying on
you all day long.
Sending information to the Chinese
government.
Yeah.
Always reputations and also hot.
Found some spy chip and their cell
phone.
Oh,
you're talking about the uh,
well there's a couple things that just
happened with,
with chips in hardware.
There's another thing about a Bloomberg
report.
Did you see that?
Yeah.
It was a the chips that came from all
these,
this,
this server company or this company that
makes the chips that sells to all these
big companies like apple and and major
major companies and now everyone's
compromised and after was like,
nope,
not true.
Definitely not true.
Don't say the chorus,
not us.
Yeah.
No 100 percent.
Not Us,
but like,
yeah.
That's a really weird story.
Look at this map.
Book blue.
The bezels
almost nonexistent.
So your challenge or just website if
you're.
If you're just laptop rather than if
you're wowway and you make that now you
have to convince people to switch from
the Mac books that they love to,
that just on looks alone they could
probably do it,
but then there's all the other features
like,
well it doesn't run Mac os 10.
Do I have a message?
Right.
Do I have all these other things that I
like about my Mac?
This huge touchpad?
Well,
it does have a huge touchpad yes,
but I say to this day still,
apple has the best laptop touch pad.
The multitouch stuff with a battery life
supposed to be excellent as well.
Right,
yeah.
How have I given that chart?
That chart was perfect because that's
like all these x's for that.
Yes.
We have great design.
We have better ports.
You only have USBC on a little Mac book
pro.
We have full size USB,
we have all this stuff will give audio
to the Mac book pro.
It's got bigger speakers,
whatever,
but we have a better battery life.
We have all this better lower price,
all of the steps and you still have to
reconcile with what people love about
their macbook pros,
which is Mac is 10.
Well there's that,
but there's also people love having an
apple product net too.
They do love that.
Yeah.
Like if someone.
If you could put an apple logo and a
wowway I wonder how many make itself.
Probably a little bit of the shit out of
him.
Yeah.
Well you know some comic has a joke
about texting a girl and the text
message comes back and green and go damn
shit.
For true felt.
People have.
People want I message like if you're.
If you're messaging someone and you find
out it won't send an imessage will only
send a text message like a Weirdo.
He's,
they have a flip phone,
like so weird eighth person.
I've been on the other side of that,
like I carry an iphone,
but I don't.
I text people on my android phone so
I've never been on the uh,
judging side.
But I,
I wonder about that everyday.
Like really what does it matter?
Like I text you with a green bubble,
which apple decided,
first of all,
to differentiate I message versus text
message,
which is hilarious.
Um,
what,
who cares?
What does it matter?
Does look better it,
I'm sure they decided to.
They I'm sure in a software update they
tweaked that green to make it look extra
harsh.
They figured out,
they figured out with pool tables a long
time ago.
Like pool tables,
the cloth generally is green,
right?
But when they started playing in
professional tournament's,
they realized that blue cloth is
actually easier on the eyes and you
could differentiate,
differentiate the edges better.
So a lot of really high end professional
matches are played on blue cloth now.
It's like a light blue sky blue cloth.
Yeah,
I've seen.
And that's I guess because of the way
your eyes work,
like something about primary colors and
the cones and you're more contrast and
suited to blue.
Something like that.
I don't know about the way.
The way white contrast with green is not
quite as pleasing as white contrasting
with blue,
but it could be the apple fucking with
you with the green to give you some
vomit.
Green.
Making some brand color next year.
Yeah.
The color of the APP is green.
What would they make it?
Blue.
I messaged the APP.
That button you press to open it as
green.
It's a green though.
Why not make it blue?
That's really true.
Yeah.
What the fuck?
That's very good point.
Jamie.
Why did they do that?
It's still.
Why would it be green when you're
sending blue messages?
Apple.
We'd dorks.
Steve jobs is dead.
You guys are fucked.
You don't know what you're doing.
But the mate book,
other than that,
it's supposed to have a better keyboard.
It's supposed to have a keyboard that's
probably similar to that surface book
and it's supposed to have better battery
life.
Bacillus,
yeah.
Bezel.
This touch screen,
touch screen,
higher resolution,
but you got to deal with windows 10,
which is a little bit of a pain in the
ass.
I gotTa admit it's like the updates are
almost daily.
There's something going on with firmware
or something going on with this or that
or I've gotten used to it mostly though
because most of what I do on my laptop
is pretty web based,
so I'm just living in chrome or safari
or whatever,
so it's not a big deal.
But then yet once I have to go out and
I'm gonna go in light room and do some
photo work and then like suddenly I'm
digging through files and I'm in windows
and it's.
Then you start to feel like you're
different.
Yeah.
When you first time you have to update a
driver.
Like what is it?
Nineteen 96.
The fuck is going on here.
I'm updating drivers.
I try to get away that it's just their
clothes though.
Like it's way better than it was five
years ago,
five years ago you would look at
windows,
you'd be like,
this is some archaic.
Pixilated came from Vista to Windows
seven to windows,
10 vista was kind of that nightmare.
And then they kinda have worked upwards
since I started with windows 95.
I used to make my own computers back in
my hardcore video gaming days.
Nice to go to fry's electronics and get
motherboards and box and fans.
And I started that online so I never
went to a physical computer store to buy
parts,
but I would have to do the whole like
cross cross referencing what's
compatible with what online and then put
together a whole list and then just buy
it and then nine boxes show up and like
hopefully they all work.
Yeah.
But yeah,
it was the same experience.
Yeah.
And sli,
video cards and connecting them with
that cable and mess up in Brooklyn.
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
But fixing it makes you feel like you
did something.
Well there's something going on when
you're like the jumpers for the
motherboard and you're moving stuff
around.
And it was cool.
Yeah.
And then once you actually gone online
with a computer,
you made yourself like this.
Something about this.
And I met her when you used to be able
to do that with apple.
You used to be able to buy clones?
Yeah,
I mean my.
So I way back in the day,
still in high school I had a Dell xps
like 7:30,
I think it was called is huge desktop
where again you could like take this cpu
cooler out,
put a new one and it was modular fully.
And then apple also made this huge
desktop,
this power mac or I don't know what it
was called at the time,
but it was again massive.
You could take the graphics card out,
put a new one in,
you can take the ram out,
take the CPU out.
But it was like this,
this weird system where like they were
on like decks and you had to like take
this big
metal slot out and then do the Cpu there
and then put it back in.
It was really satisfying to like change
the hardware and like yeah I did that.
And they put it up and it's like,
that's exactly right.
Now it's got eight gigs around the other
side.
Especially.
I don't know.
I think it's a man thing to men like
changing carburetor,
mechanical field.
Yeah.
That's probably a lot to do with it too.
Yeah,
that's it.
One generation after that because that
whole that it had like basically like
elevator levels to it,
like the top level and on the bottom
level and on the hard drives and the
power supply and the top,
like all that stuff.
And he can mess with that.
If you go over someone's house and they
have that now you're like,
what the fuck is wrong with you?
But that's the thing about that was the
most accessible modular desktop apple
ever ever made.
And now they're making this promise
again.
Like,
all right,
we listened,
we know that little trash can.
Mac Pro was not good thermally or design
wise for anyone.
So we're going to make a modular
professional desktop Mac pro.
Again,
that's what they said and it's going to
be next year sometime and I keep
picturing that.
I picture them going back to the roots
of like a real bonafide desktop because
right now the most powerful imac or Mac
you can get is the imac pro and you
can't even update the ram and the Imac
pro.
Really?
You can't update anything about Macra.
Yeah.
What you buys,
which you get,
if you buy a $7,000
imac pro,
you will have that spec forever.
Apple doesn't want you opening anything
in that thing,
so when they say,
yeah,
we're going to make a modular updatable
real well-designed apple desktop,
I'm like,
I really hope they're doing that.
Like exactly because that's.
I love that.
Do they have regular towers anymore or.
No?
Everything's an Imac.
They had that,
that little trashcan and then the Mac
mini,
which is the longest since they've ever
updated it.
I'm hoping they update it at the event
this month,
but the Mac mini is the only other tower
they made and that Scott Laptop
internals,
so not really a true desktop,
so everything is.
Is that just because of technology's
advanced to the point where you can kind
of fit everything in the big screen of
an Imac basically?
Yeah.
I mean the Imac,
they have those desktop internals in it,
but uh,
yeah,
like,
you're,
you're still going to be restrained by
like how closed off that spaces,
how many fans I can fit in there.
Um,
so if they really want to do like a true
desktop,
they got to open it up and make it huge,
which is not very like apple.
So it's gonna be interesting to see what
they do.
Yeah.
Um,
um,
what is your,
what year is your laptop over there?
That's an older one,
right?
Is the last one before they added the
track bar.
The last one that glows 20 slash 15.
Does yours have a dip at all?
To the keys?
Very,
very small,
but that's all you need.
All you need is a very small dip about
flat.
As soon as they went with flat,
they fucked up.
There's a company that refurbishes
17 inch Mac books,
the big one,
the Mac daddy these a laptop would
refurbish it and put a,
like a modern CPU in it.
They put a,
a big um,
SSD drive,
a one terabyte or two terabyte SSD
drive.
So you deal with the solid state drive
so it's instantly fires up.
Much more ram.
Much more everything.
Yeah.
That's what they call a desktop
replacement laptop.
Yeah.
I was into that for awhile.
That was like one of my.
That's actually how I started my channel
was I bought a 17 inch laptop now.
I was trying to figure out which one
strikes the balance of where I want to
be with taking it off the dock once in
awhile and walking around the house
maybe,
but like planting it back here and it's
my desktop.
It's a 17 inch screen.
That was where I started with HP.
If you're at the airport and you have
like a canceled flight,
you could get a workout in just like
lifting.
Nothing will probably have you go side
to side.
That's the other thing that I was on the
plane with this.
This is like a 12 inch screen and every
time the guy in front of me lean back,
he just smacked my laptop to like move
it.
You really need like a 12 inch,
a nine inch screen probably to get away
with what?
That's 12 inches.
Can you flip that around as a 12 or 13
inch screen?
But it's like a taller three two aspect
ratio.
So it's not like,
like the smaller,
a 16 by nine screen would be underneath
like where that guy was hitting my
screen.
So most of the bezels seems like it's on
the bottom.
Uh,
yeah.
Yeah.
So your,
your chat at the bottom here.
I mean it's pretty,
pretty good size basil,
but like I'm still hoping for like
vesselis laptops.
What,
have you ever thought about going with
the Walway?
Uh,
not really.
Mostly because I switched laptops so
infrequently that I was just like,
if it's not massively better than the
Mac book pro,
I don't really feel the need to switch.
This came on my radar in the last like
two weeks and I decided to try it and
it's been like worth the shot.
Like I'm really into it,
I'm probably going to switch back to the
Mac book pro in a little while.
Once I started to run up against things
like this doesn't have USBC,
which is sad.
That's weird though that eventually
that's going to bite me and when I do
I'm going to want to switch back,
but it's got
a new Microsoft laptop that doesn't
have.
USBC.
Doesn't really make a lot of sense.
It doesn't at all why they do that.
I have no idea.
I want to ask.
It's a great laptop.
It doesn't have the charger.
Is this weird like it's not like magsafe
but it's this slot charger thing where
it like goes in and out easily but also
doesn't have a card reader also doesn't
have like a lot of things that I kind of
hoped to laptop would have.
So yeah.
This thing is everything.
This thing is regular USB USBC.
This has one size Usb port headphone
Jack and what it looks like
just as Htmi bias does not have that.
I'm a big fan of this thing and then
they make a.
They make a 15 inch version of it as
well.
This is the,
I guess
I don't know how big that is.
So what do you do?
Like mostly on the laptop because I know
he writing,
writing and then getting online.
Just online bullshit.
But yeah,
no software really.
I'm not really running anything other
than writing programs.
Microsoft word which is native,
right?
Yeah,
yeah.
I mean you could probably get away with
any number of laps,
similar laptops just like.
So at that point you basically pick the
design you like best and if it has the
ports you need then you're good.
But if you find yourself,
like if I'm a I like to do photo editing
a lot and so basically I have to have
some way to read memory cards.
Mac book pro doesn't,
it just has a lot of USBC ports so I
just have that dongle plugged into Usb
card reader and then I'm good.
This one I'll have to get a USB card
reader also for it and then get light
room and then I'm good.
You'll have to get a regular USB card
readers,
which is five years ago,
less common.
It's still easy to find,
but like it's Kinda Dorky.
Eventually it will be like 20 slash 20
and I'm like,
I don't want this in 20.
20.
Yeah.
That raise your pro.
The razer blade pro that we were talking
about.
What's interesting about that is it has
a track pad on the righthand side,
like a mouse because the mouse is on the
right and then it has this enormous
keyboard and a mechanical keyboard,
which I'm a really big fan of.
I like those clicky.
True,
true desktop replacement.
Yeah.
Look at that thing.
Isn't an acid.
Plus look at all the cool colors.
I have the 15 inch with the RGB.
They love their rgb.
I still,
that's your razor thing because they
have a phone now.
I don't know if you know the,
the razor phone to has rgb,
glowing backlight.
It's hilarious.
But it's,
that's,
that's their own aesthetic.
But um,
what is rgb stand for?
Just red,
green,
blue.
I like the fact that you can cycle
between colors or whatever at any time.
Uh,
is almost almost pointless,
like it's technically a backlight which
is useful,
but other than that you're just Kinda,
you know,
get into the Gamer aesthetic,
which is pretty fun.
Yeah.
It's,
well,
it's,
it's a fantastic thing if you're into
games like that thing literally you can
play high end games at very high frame
rates and you know,
I don't know what kind of battery life
it has.
Probably not that great.
It's a four k what's so much juice in so
much screen and that's.
So that's a four k laptop with a desktop
gpu in it,
size of four k model versus a full hd
mode model.
And I think the fourK has a lower Max
frame rate if I'm not.
So what is the difference in full hd
model?
So I think the full hd model is a higher
100,
20 hertz,
10 80 p or probably 60 hertz,
four k.
So if you're gaming you'll probably go
with the 10 80 p,
but then you get your higher frame rates
and you'll enjoy games better on that.
But if your photo editing than you'll
probably go with the four k and you get
that desktop power or video editing for
example.
But,
uh,
I don't think the battery life would be
very long on a four k laptop.
It's hard to imagine.
It's so big.
Yeah.
Like finding
out what it says in terms of the battery
life.
But like if you just playing a game and
you're not plugged in,
you're kind of far.
Yeah.
If you're that,
if you're that guy,
you're walking around with the power
cable all the time.
Yeah.
One hundred percent.
You're walking to a new room plugging it
in and then setting up there.
Yeah.
Which is better than a desktop
technically,
but yeah,
you're walking around with the power all
the time.
Yeah.
Better than the desktop technically.
But is it as powerful as a desktop?
Like if you get a gaming desktop almost.
I think their goal is to get as close to
a desktop as they reasonably can and
then give you the ability to take it
places quickly.
What does it say about the,
uh,
oh,
you fucking motherfucker disable every
website ever.
Everybody's popups.
Ugh,
so gross.
What could this world we live in now?
Why?
Why do I want notifications from your
website?
So a great jeff the other day.
Am I saying that right,
Jeff?
Uh,
of like every website where like you go
on to this,
you don't even get to the content.
It's just three hours,
52 minutes.
Battery life movie tests for just
watching a movie that's still 100
percent.
You Watch a movie and then it's dead.
That's hilariously low.
Yeah.
Because if you watch a movie on a Mac
book pro,
like you got plenty of juice left,
the movie's over.
You might be able to watch three or four
movies.
The battery 99.
What?
Our battery.
That's actually huge battery,
but still.
Yeah,
that's one of the things that I liked
about,
not this model of Lenovo,
but some of the pads have a swappable
battery that you could swap wild.
That's a while it's on.
Yeah.
Oh,
what?
Yes.
Oh yeah.
I used to be able to do that.
Yeah,
that's definitely a barrier.
There's an internal battery and there's
an external battery,
so you pop out the external,
but which is a big thick band plugged
in.
You want to get the full Jamey that goes
like 25 fucking hours and if you pop
that sucker out you could do it while
this is still running yet and it doesn't
shut off.
Pop the new one in hot swapping?
Yeah.
Hot swap that.
I haven't had a laptop with that since
like,
like uh,
seven years ago probably.
It's been a long time.
Yeah,
well I think thinkpads are mostly
business oriented.
I mean that's really mostly what people
are using them for.
Yeah.
But it's,
you know,
there's,
there's that balance of like,
what are you looking for?
Like are you looking for something that
can do everything?
Are you looking for something that's
just.
I mean most people for a lot of people
you could really get by with one of
those Google chromebooks that doesn't
have much storage at all.
That's where I'll probably end up
getting my parents into a lot.
Like if your parents or grandparents
don't really need much of a computer,
but all they need to do really is email
someone,
maybe go to a website or to watch it
online movie.
You just need a web browser.
So like a chromebook is great.
Yes.
So much is in the cloud.
Yeah.
You know what I mean?
So many people keep their photos in the
cloud,
they keep it as long as you have an
internet connection,
you're good,
you're good.
But in terms of like local storage,
yeah,
that's,
that's probably one of the things about,
especially when I was talking about this
phone,
not only does it only have four gigs of
Ram,
it also only has 64 gigs of storage.
That's it.
Uh,
there's a 64 and a one slash 28 and
there's a lot of phones now that have
like 2:50,
six,
five,
12 and then expandable storage via micro
SD.
And the reasoning google is giving,
which I actually subscribed to you is
everything just goes through the cloud.
Like the only thing I keep offline is my
spotify library and podcasts.
So my whole spotify,
whatever is like 30 gigs and then
whatever podcast,
I have a couple more gigs.
I don't need a 512 gig phone for
everything.
I usually keep offline.
I have a couple of big apps but not
really.
Uh,
and,
and all the photos I take get uploaded
automatically to google photos in full
resolution and I never really have to
keep all of them locally.
So every photo I've ever taken in full
resolution is on my phone,
even though I only have 128 gigs of
storage
now when you use the Google version of
like whatever I photo is,
I photo uploads everything to the cloud.
It's really simple when you get a new
phone,
everything loads up to it.
Does the same thing happened?
Same thing.
Google just as good.
Yeah.
And you can use it on an iphone,
which is.
You don't have to.
But yeah,
real photos.
I have google photos on my iphone,
so every time I take great photos on
this phone they're on my iphone.
Oh,
that is actually not having the APP is
pretty useful.
That's nice.
Yeah.
And I know there's a thing that's one of
the things that people really love about
iphones is that airdrop feature.
That's very nice.
That's one of the best apple only
features.
Yeah.
But don't they have an android?
There's an android dropped to now I know
that because I've used it to send things
from my Samsung phone to my apple phone.
Um,
possibly.
So there's,
it's not like a first party thing.
So NFC is useful when I want to send
something between two android phones
that NFC.
But this is something I recently,
I wasn't really using airdrop until
recently.
And then I was like,
oh wait,
I do have a Mac and an iphone.
I can just transfer transfer files back
and forth.
And I,
we started doing that in the office a
lot,
which we,
we have a bunch of MACs and iphones in
the office.
So we started like passing files back
and forth.
And then one day I was trying to do it
on my android phone.
I was like,
wow,
this is like a bummer.
I have to go into like dropbox and
upload it and then download it.
And it was just this couple extra steps
were a pain and it made me really
appreciate how good airdrop is,
but
they're just pretty good.
That was really good at making things
super simple.
Yeah.
Like you don't,
you don't ever really have to update
things and until the ostp updates and
it's pretty rare.
Yeah.
Everything works really good.
You don't really even worry about
viruses or anything like that.
Yeah,
there's a lot they do.
That's really excellent.
Yeah.
But I feel like the running on the
momentum of Steve Jobs,
maniacal vision.
Yeah.
There's been a lot of apples changed or
apple is not the same sense since no
more.
Steve,
which is true obviously.
Uh,
but they're also like their momentum,
like how can you not like,
they're insane.
They,
they're a trillion dollar company now.
They continue to make iphones that look
the same that they did nine years ago.
Like why not,
you know?
And if people keep buying them,
of course they'll probably never have a
reason to change.
It's just a different kind of company
now.
Before.
I mean he was like Jen generally
regarded as an asshole,
like just a crazy.
Yeah.
Whip,
cracking.
Micromanaging.
Yeah.
Just just a nut.
Like there's that famous thing of him
trying to use.
I forget what the device was,
but it wasn't used.
It wasn't working during one stage.
Yeah.
I remember that live and he threw it.
Yeah,
he was like did.
It was casual,
but it was hilarious.
It was like there was anger to it though
because someone definitely got fired.
Like within minutes of that happening.
Yeah.
And that's happened on stage.
Like things mess up on stage like yeah,
it's going to happen.
For a couple of years ago there was a,
an apple event or s I'm pretty sure
Steve was on stage trying to get
something to work like in a demo and if
you've ever been or seen like an apple
event,
like the entire audience or half of it,
half of the audience is just people
typing like blogging,
like exactly what's going on.
So they're all connected to the
Internet.
They're live blogging.
Yeah.
So Steve is like,
get me one that works.
Look at his face.
This is the thing like back that up a
little bit and give me some volume like
this.
You're gonna.
Take that,
turn it on.
Got It.
Well let's see if we can turn it on.
There's an anger.
Yeah.
Well you know,
he was like,
Yo,
my speech after the show,
he was definitely doing the.
Yeah.
So there's another event where like
something wasn't working and he's like,
I need everyone in this room to turn
your wifi off so that this will work.
Everyone.
I need everyone to stop blogging,
close your laptops,
get off the Wifi and then this will
work.
And it was kind of like a,
a couple minutes of like,
ha,
that's funny.
Maybe is he serious?
And like slowly like everyone did close
out.
He's like,
Eh,
everyone,
everyone get off the Wifi,
everyone close your computers right now
and this is going to work.
And it was the issue.
I don't remember exactly it was.
It was.
Must have been some wireless related
getting something to load or work.
But that was pretty hilarious to me.
I feel like if you want things to
operate at the speed of apple when he
was alive,
you kind of have to be a fucking crazy
asshole.
Yeah.
You have to have that next level.
First of all,
I need a vision of what you wanted to be
and then you need to be insane enough to
try to get people to do that.
Well,
he also was according to.
Is this it right here?
Yeah.
Oh,
safari demo.
Yeah.
I don't know what's going on.
It's a four minute.
But this is.
Yeah.
So is failing to load.
So everyone's using the local Wifi.
Wifi is just getting tagged.
He isn't.
Wifi is getting crushed.
So instead of verizon atnt
okay.
Yeah,
yeah.
You're just having Wifi issues that are
confronting moment where he said it.
We're actually unwind by here.
So at 20 minutes later Jesus.
Point number six.
So yeah,
running around like crazy.
We figured out why.
I'm like Damn,
little crashed.
Why did it become more of a 575 base
stations operating in this room?
We can't deal with that either.
I've got some really great that I'd like
to show you so we can turn off all the
stuff and see the demos or we give up
and I don't show you the demo.
Would you want to see?
I'm thinking of hoping
he'll just try again and then I'll have
to turn it off.
Yeah.
Some of these things too by the way.
So all you need to turn off,
turn off every notebook.
I'd like them to put them down on the
floor and all you look around and want
you to help me see each other.
Look at the end.
The whole crowd.
Is everyone.
The only reason they're there is to live
blog.
Yeah.
And put them on the floor please.
All right.
One last tweet because
he was telling me to turn the Wifi off.
Thirty minutes.
Hey Johnny facetime.
That's another thing.
Like
facetime is another proprietary thing
that apple has.
It's really excellent and it's built
into the contacts.
It works perfectly.
Yeah.
Just everyone with an iphone.
You can do it with them.
Just Papao.
I was like,
that's a massive vat and I message,
or like two of the biggest reasons
people refused to even try an android
phone,
so I'm like,
all right,
well clearly google's mission should be
to get it message on Android,
right?
Like that should be like a.
An apple will never let that happen.
They know that they can hold people
hostage on Ios as long as they want.
If they can't get the message anywhere
else and takes time and things like
that.
I imessage,
facetime,
airdrop,
walled garden.
Yup.
Wonderful.
Walled Garden made a video about this
whole ecosystem.
It's A.
It's real.
It's a real major advantage.
Yeah,
it really is.
And they've got that nailed.
They really do try to make their own
versions of these things too.
Well,
just like they tried to do google plus
and everybody was like,
yeah,
good luck with it.
I have a friend who was an executive at
Google.
It was hilarious.
She was always telling me how great
google pluses might.
That shit's dead in the water thing is
google plus Google plus even though only
like nine people used it.
It was great.
I'm sure was really good,
like all the things that they let you do
that I wish facebook would let us do
like sharing with certain groups of
people and like all these different
things with circles.
It was kind of a shit show with like how
they did it,
but it's good.
Like it was good anyway,
so it's going to die now and that's kind
of sad.
It is killing Ya.
Yeah.
They have this whole security breach
thing,
uh,
which is also a weird story.
But then eventually they're like,
you know what,
we're shutting it down.
Yeah.
I want to call my friend up and go,
ha ha,
I told you so it's going to be,
it's going to be finally no more google
plus.
But like Google keeps trying to do this.
They keep calling it like a universal
message service.
Everyone's like,
oh,
I messaged for Android,
you're going to make your own great.
And then make a aloe duo hangouts.
Men like they have all these half
halfway there.
Things that kind of tie into android and
are sort of like facetime and imessage
but not really a.
and it's just not well done and it's not
convincing anyone.
Now I know there's been some third party
attempts to figure out how to put our
message on android phones that you can
get like some sort of an app that allow
you to use our message is probably
really clunky and 40.
Yeah.
I haven't tried that.
I haven't either.
I imagine it's horrible.
I have the note nine,
like I said,
and I was thinking about switching over
to it and I was like,
oh I'll use this pen.
I never use a pen once.
Yeah,
that's,
that's the thing.
I as a reviewer,
I'm always trying to figure out what is
a real genuine use it everyday feature
that's worth paying extra for.
And what is a cool demo feature that'll
get you to brag about the phone and show
your friends but you'll never use it.
And I've always been split on the s pen.
Is that a thing people really use all
the time?
And I've been like kind of somewhat
convinced.
There's people who like,
yeah,
I use the s pen every day.
I take notes on my phone,
I use that APP and I'm like,
I try,
I try.
I had this little point where I was
like,
yeah,
I'm going to do lock screen notes every
time I want to remember something,
I'm going to write it down and I just
never got into it.
So like I'm usually pretty good about
like dividing things into buckets of
like,
yes,
this is something we will use and is
worth paying.
This is dumb,
but it's really cool to demo and it will
just sell people and they never use it
again.
Those two buckets are very clear.
The yes pencil has been in the middle
from the lock screen things weird too
because it doesn't work that smooth.
The lock screen known better.
Yeah,
it's a little clunky and then you don't
just get it right there.
It saves it to notes.
So you have to go to and you have to go
to the notes APP.
Yeah.
Well,
what my thought was,
I'm going to use this and I'm going to
put my set list on my phone and that
where anytime I go to the lock screen,
the note setlist would be there.
I'll just be able to scroll through
my set list when I go on stage.
Yeah.
But it doesn't work there.
No,
I've got to go to the notes.
Well what is this then?
Yeah.
Yeah,
so it's just kind of weird halfway
there,
but I want to talk to someone who's
like,
yeah,
I buy the note every year because I got
to have the pen.
Like I got this.
I think.
Well,
one thing that is kind of cool about it
that I've never used once but kind of
cool about it is the fact that you can
use that pen as a remote control.
That's definitely a take photographs
firmly in the second bucket of like
great demo.
Yeah.
Look,
I'm halfway across the room taking a
selfie.
That's cool,
right?
Yeah.
Then you'll never use it,
never use it.
And then also using it as a remote
control for music and for video you can
map it to all kinds of crazy thing.
It's actually a really well thought out
feature.
It gets Bluetooth and the s pen has its
own battery now.
So you put the battery in the phone and
it charges the stylists very quickly in
a couple of seconds you get like half of
the battery.
Like it's really well thought out.
Yeah.
But am I ever going to use.
Probably not.
Yeah.
The battery is huge too.
It's got a 4,000
milliamp battery as opposed to the
Iphone,
which is what?
30.
Even the big ones,
like at 31 and $3,200.
Is that that little?
Yeah.
But I mean like iphone.
So I've never needed that.
The number on paper to be big to be well
optimized because it's software
software,
but they've done tests where they did
benchmark tests between the note and the
iphone x.
What does it matter to tennis 10.
Ask Max.
Yeah.
I'm.
It's not the.
The,
the note crushes it.
Yeah.
No,
Samsung's getting better with
optimization too,
which is awesome.
That they crush it.
They,
they used to be kind of scared of
batteries in the notes.
I wonder why so that they finally gotten
better at that and they're,
they're doing really well.
It's amazing that they bounced back from
that at all because we'll fucking died
in A.
I don't think anyone died.
Well,
some one guy,
I don't know what happened to him,
but there was a famous guy who was a
tech guy who died because his battery
exploded in his house,
caught on fire and he died in the fire.
Really?
I don't know what phone he was using
though.
He was some,
some,
I don't think it was the note crypto
currency guy not follow the note pretty
closely because that was.
I had a couple of them just because like
I was in the middle of reviewing it and
using it.
I carried when everyday starts getting
banned,
starts getting caught on fire.
You can't fly with it.
Like I followed that all very closely
and all of you.
The cases of cause,
it started off with not only where the
note seven starting to explode,
but they started recalling them and
sending people replacements and then the
replacements started to explode.
At that point I was like,
this is amazing.
I need to follow very closely.
Uh,
had a,
a blackberry and a y way and they don't
know which one exploded.
Probably walway assassination.
I never.
It has a weird,
actually wasn't ceo cradle fund ceo now,
just written Hassan song and it caught
his whole house on fire.
Yeah.
He died after smartphones,
pulling catches fire in his bedroom.
That is really extreme.
Yeah.
Where to go.
They can't mess around.
So like
one that's when your phone starts
exploding and you're Samsung,
like you have to get,
you have to fix that.
There was a famous video of the guy who
parked his car in the driveway and put
his phone in the charger and left it
there.
And he came outside to his car bursting
into flames.
His whole car was on fire.
Oh my God.
That's horrible.
Especially in a gas car with literal
flammable liquids in.
Luckily it wasn't in his garage.
She was in his driveway.
That is net fuck.
Yeah.
It's amazing.
They've bounced back from that though,
because they really have.
Yeah,
they're actually,
that's been impressive at their
reputation.
So like in the reviewer community of
like,
I watch it all my friends videos about
the note when it came out,
we stopped making explosion jokes.
This year I noticed that the galaxy note
seven had all the explosion jokes.
No eight came out,
all the explosion jokes last year it
exploded guys.
So what have they done this year?
It's better now.
We're on no nine and I think we're kinda
over it two years.
That's how long it takes.
That's today though.
I mean the short cycle of news today.
It's like things come and go so quickly,
but I wonder if that would've happened
to an iphone.
What kind of nightmare that would have
been.
I also think there's probably no way it
would have happened to an iphone.
Like you would think.
There's no way what happened to Samsung,
but somehow it did.
But like there's this whole process of
like getting a battery supplier for your
phone and then trusting their quality
testing and then using that supplier for
your manufacturing and all that.
Um,
and I don't know how different that
process is for Samsung versus other
manufacturers like apple,
but it just seems like apple would never
let that sort of oversight slip bright.
Hm.
I wonder,
but if it did,
how crazy would that have been?
Samsung comes out with new phones way
quicker,
right?
They,
so they come out with phones more often,
but they update their lineups at the
same rate,
like once a year for note and also once
a year for galaxy s.
But since they're six months apart,
it looks like they made four new phones.
So we're going to get a new phone.
Every April galaxy has 10 will come out
in April and they'll get galaxy note in
September.
Was like,
well it's only six months.
Well that's part of a different lineup.
So like galaxy s is every year.
Galaxy notice every year they have all
these other lineups.
So they didn't make a lot more phones
for sure.
And Are they still doing the sport
because they had that sport model
active?
Uh,
I think they are still.
It's not nearly as special seeming to
them as it used to be.
They used to really like put a separate
commercials for it.
And they have like all this hype.
I remember like Galaxy s seven active
was a big deal.
I don't even know if there is a galaxy s
nine active,
I don't believe there is.
It might not be.
It was a rumor that it was coming out
and then it was going to be completely
waterproof and shock resistant.
It was going to have a rubberized case.
Right.
And it was going to have an enormous
battery life that didn't.
They haven't released it.
The nine was going to have the same size
battery as the note nine,
but the regular size nine screen.
So 4,000
million amp
battery.
But in the s nine screen.
Right.
Which would have been massive.
Yeah.
I mean that's just.
That would have been incredible.
I guess people just don't buy it as
much.
Yeah.
I don't think people knew about it.
I think it's one of those deals.
I love battery life.
I'm always scared that my phone's going
to run out of battery.
I know it's ridiculous because it very
rarely does,
but I'm always like,
fuck,
what if it runs out of battery?
Yeah.
When I hear about like the iphone's
battery not being so good.
I like,
I've heard that the,
the x s regular has better battery life
and the excess Max because Max has the
larger screen.
I think the,
I think they're about the same.
I think that standby time on the tennis
Max is better because of the bigger
battery.
But when you do use your screen a lot,
they kind of diminished down to the same
number I think.
And um,
the iphone 10 are,
which I've just started using,
seems to have a battery battery life
than both of them.
And this is the less expensive $750 ips
lcd version of the iphone 10.
Yeah.
The color is and all that.
Now,
how much of a factor is that in everyday
use?
Do you notice the difference?
The battery life?
Yeah.
No,
the,
the image quality not being as good with
the different screen.
Yeah,
that's the only factor,
right?
Of the internal components of same.
They are the same as one gig of Ram
weirdly,
but yeah,
all the rest of the internals of what is
a standard one half six,
so four gigs of Ram on every iphone
still and then three gigs in the 10 are.
And then also one camera instead of two.
And then an aluminum rail on the side.
I call it a rail,
but the outside's aluminum instead of
stainless steel.
So the iphone's got the shiny stainless
steel outside.
Uh,
the.
Yeah,
the screen is still pretty decent.
I know everyone likes to trash on it
because it's only eight,
20 8:00
PM,
7:20
p screen roughly.
This is the bar the are.
Um,
but like using it or just looking at it,
it looks fine.
And like an apple iphone eight.
Yeah,
exactly.
It's the same pixel density as an iphone
eight,
which was fine for most people.
So if you get too caught up on the
number,
which is not the typical iphone 10,
our buyer,
then it's gonna.
Look bad,
but if you just look at the screen and
use it,
which is most people walking in a store
and just say,
hey,
this looks fine and it's $250 cheaper.
I think I'll just get this one.
That's why I think the 10 hours is going
to be a great seller for Apple.
Yeah.
It sounds like,
you know when you switch to those
battery pack cases,
that's now you have a brick in your
pocket.
That's huge.
Yeah.
That's a big phone already too.
So a six point one inch screen on that
10 hour and then this big battery on the
back yet it's just going to be massive.
Yeah.
I don't know.
I mean I haven't seen any excess Max
with a case that has a battery in it,
but shoes I wouldn't even try finger
pocket anymore,
but it's great if you go on a trip
somewhere and you.
You might be in some Janky plays.
It doesn't have.
Yeah.
Power like a travel version
of your setup.
Yeah.
It's a big old brick case.
Well not a case person.
Yeah.
You don't have any cases onto cases you,
but you switched phones so often.
Even if you drop them.
That's what people say.
Papa Sim card out.
I still take good care of my phones.
People are like,
Oh,
you get a new phone every two weeks you
might be right,
but I still take really good care of my
phones.
I actually did kind of getting out of my
car,
the slid out of my pocket,
which is kind of a nightmare and it took
one bounce before I like sort of half
caught it.
So I got these little scratch on the
corner.
That's google phone,
Google phone,
but it's fine.
So I always questioned people that don't
have cases.
I'm like,
Oh,
you're one of those people.
My friend Andrew Santino,
he doesn't put a case on anything and I.
He didn't have like a good.
He was a more a design person who's
like,
look how beautiful this case in this.
That's part of it.
But Neil degrasse Tyson had a really
interesting perspective.
He said he takes his case and he flips
it around in his hand constantly and he
said,
if you go to like watch like cadets when
they're learning how to handle guns,
they're spinning their gun around and
catching it goes,
why do you think they're doing that?
They're doing that so that they're
always able to catch their gun no matter
what.
They have the suit.
He takes his phone and he flips it
around his hand like a cadet.
That's awesome.
Guess my phone and he showed me.
He was like flipping in between his
fingers,
like,
oh,
I like seat,
but that's him.
He's got this next level thought process
behind everything.
That's fair.
Not having a case.
That means he's not a case person.
He's always got his phone.
Yeah,
that's fine.
I actually like your case,
this case,
which is a clear case and the reason why
I like it is because it's more grippy in
your hand.
It just.
There's more to it.
I found a slippery.
I phones are these slippery as phones,
their.
The way they're shaped,
they have the stainless steel and then
they kind of just melt into this orb
shape and it's by far the most common
like slide out of my pocket phone is the
iphone.
This phone was never slid out of my
pocket obviously.
And the one plus.
Yeah.
You said that that was your favorite
phone before the Google Pixel three?
Yup.
Why do you like the Pixel three better
than that phone?
Because I've heard great things about
the one plus.
I love the one plus still and I would
have no problem using it today,
but this camera is so much better than
every other phone.
Yeah.
Now is that because you took a lot of
photos for youtube and blogging and that
kind of thing?
Yeah,
just social.
I tweet a lot of photos.
I instagram a lot of photos and I just
much better.
Yeah,
that's much better than the one plus,
which is already a $600 phone and is the
one plus what?
I mean.
The,
the galaxy note nine was supposed to
have a very good cameras.
Well,
I can't tell the difference.
I'm not good enough.
You most people won't until you put them
next to each other and then you kind of
go,
oh,
interesting.
There's a much like when you put an
iphone photo next to a pixel,
photo,
iphones have matory
great cameras.
Pixels have notoriously great cameras.
You might be totally fine with either
one,
but if you put them next to each other,
you will notice massive differences
between the cradles.
Yeah.
So did you notice comparisons that are
online that we could pull up right now?
Um,
my last one,
I compare it a pixel to,
to iphone 10 to one plus five t,
two,
two other phones.
I did it like a five camera blind test.
And what I did was I put the five photos
next to each other but didn't tell you
which one is which ne B,
c,
d or e.
and you go down the list and I have like
seven,
eight,
nine photos in a row,
a,
b,
c,
d,
or e,
pick your favorite one.
A lot of people went with b.
A lot of people went with D and they
didn't know which one.
It was not the end I revealed which one
was which,
and a lot of people were surprised by
which one they picked.
Oh,
I picked the pixel over the iphone every
time.
Really interesting.
Uh,
and a lot of times when you put them
side by side,
you'll notice like iphones like to boost
the shadows a lot more so that they're
much more immediately lit.
Yeah.
This is that side.
So like if a,
b,
c,
D and e,
which one do I like better?
And I already can tell immediately which
ones the pixel.
And you might not because Iraq,
I remember Pixel two had cooler colors
and more contrast than any other one.
And this is a backpack.
Yeah.
So another thing about these is it helps
to see it in a high resolution because
the difference in detail and sharpness
between them is another thing I paid
attention to.
Which ones he,
I want to say that was the one plus,
but I forget now.
I'm pretty sure be as the pixel because
this backpack is starting to look a
little bit blue and that was a big
characteristic of the pixel two from
last year and that was a big issue with
the screen as well.
Right to the Pixel xl?
Yeah.
Look at this contrast like you see like
all these are like pretty good,
but when you see B and you see how much
more contrast that has and you look at a
and how much it's lifted.
The shadows.
Yeah.
He's got.
He's got a pretty even tone and is also
the one plus.
I don't remember what it is.
I'd have to go back to the video,
switched them around one every time.
It was the same as the same every time.
B is the same every time.
I know I'm already pretty sure that B is
the pixel.
Go to a,
go to the top left one with the selfie.
So again,
like that gray sweatshirt,
it starting to look at blue and be right
in.
He become much higher,
brighter.
Those shadows are like my black hair.
It looks kind of gray at that point in
that one.
So there's a lot of things you don't
notice until you put them side by side.
But so nitpicky,
they all look so good.
They all look pretty much like the same.
So you never see your little parallel
syrup?
Yes.
See is a little bit tighter.
So I'm gonna go see as the iphone
because the iphone has,
has a,
a little bit of a tighter selfie camera.
A lot of android phones have a wider
angle selfie camera because you can fit
more people in them.
But apple's always told me they go with
a tighter angle because there's less
distortion and they want it to feel more
natural.
You just take a picture of yourself and
you look great.
Here we go.
Iphone X.
Okay.
So you know it too in hassle.
But I did add a real camera into the.
Into the mix.
Can I wrote was preferred good?
Yeah,
I hope so.
It's $10,000.
That was a real camera.
Better look.
Pretty good film or is that a or?
It's a photo.
So it's a.
it's a medium format.
Fifty Megapixel Hasselblad,
[inaudible].
It's a crazy camera.
Iphone x was pretty God damn good right
there.
It does,
but there's just a little bit more to
the Pixel to pixel.
Two has.
So this is a portrait mode comparison.
So I remember I was trying to test like
the blurry background versus an actual
good camera.
And whenever you look at these portrait
mode photos,
what they're doing is they're sort of
trying to outline the subject,
keep it sharp and then blur the
background artificially and year after
year they've gotten better at this
because the fall off between the blur
isn't just like a cut out in real life.
You get sort of like a gradient of how
much blur you have.
So Pixel two has typically the sharpest
cut out and the best like separation
between the background where the iphone
kind of just takes the face,
keeps the face sharp and then sort of
has a more natural fall off.
So your body might not be at infocus uh,
and note eight as it's just not as good.
Yeah.
And that image,
that's a really,
that in that one you really see how good
the pixel two is.
Yeah.
Like that.
And so it takes all three.
Got Better at that actually.
Yeah.
So.
And now you can change.
Something note was doing last year.
You can change how blur the background
is.
So an iphone 10 s now pixel three,
note nine,
all of them.
You can change how blurry the background
is.
Now I noticed you have an apple watch on
though.
I do that Smart Watch and the game,
which is I'm a is by a lot by a lot.
By Lot.
Yeah.
That's why I'm an iphone person really
because of the watch.
I carry two phones all the time.
An android phone of choice and an iphone
of choice.
So my android phone of choice is my
pixel.
That's the main number.
The main phone I usually use a and my
iphone of choice of carry because
there's still things that I.
iphones do better and I always carry
whatever the best iphone is.
A lot of things.
It's media related.
It's like whenever I'm airdropping,
like when I'm publishing a video on the
go,
like I have the thumbnail from airdrop
on this phone,
but just things like snapchat and
Instagram,
instagram stories and instagram live a
lot of apps with camera stuff or better
optimized on the iphone than they are on
any android phone because they're built
for iphone.
So I carry an iphone and the best smart
watch is the Apple Watch stories for.
So I wear an apple watch series for
[inaudible].
It's good.
It's really good.
But you don't get text messages on your
Apple Watch them now?
I don't,
but I,
I do.
Uh,
yeah,
kind of.
I would love to be able to use a
smartwatch and this good with my android
phone A.
I still haven't found one that good,
but I'm mainly.
I'm using this for fitness tracking now,
which is kind of entertaining.
Just like keeping track of workouts and
calories and standing hours and all this
stuff.
It does,
it's pretty cool.
Yeah.
This
talking to you before the show,
but the sober October fitness challenge,
we're doing this the first time I've
ever worn a heart monitor.
And then the scene,
actual scores,
yeah,
there's a real crazy motivating factor
of seeing an actual number.
The game of gamifying of fitness is
really entertaining to me and that's
what's kept me like,
I've usually don't wear a smart watch
for very long,
but I think it's been about a month and
I just keep like.
So there's a feature now where you can
challenge people to a one week long
challenge to whoever burns the most
calories and it has the most points or
whatever it was like a point system.
Right.
And that gamification of fitness has
been,
I think,
pretty special.
It's been pretty good.
Well this contest has been really crazy
with me and my friends.
So what are you trying to do?
We,
if the winter is going to get a belt,
like a wwe style belt.
Nice.
It says intergalactic sober October
champion and it has like
marijuana leaf with the line through it
and a bottle of booze,
the line through it.
And uh,
you were these things.
It's a,
it's called a mile zone and it,
it works with an APP.
It works pretty good and it,
it registers your amount of your heart
rate,
the amount of calories you burn and it
gives you a point system.
And the point system is,
I don't know what it,
what they call it's m e P eps.
I don't know what it stands for,
but this is the amount of points over
the month is what everyone's shooting
for.
Right.
And so today were at October the 23rd,
so we have eight days to go and I have
worked out more in these 23 days than I
have in the last six months and I'm not
exaggerating.
Yeah,
I put in five and a half hours
yesterday.
Hard.
I got more than 900 points.
Then after the podcast I said fuck it,
we're going to go for another hundred
and I worked out and I've got another
100 points.
Put in another hour.
It's maniacal because you,
you actually see the number and because
I could see the number,
I could see all my friends' numbers and
I'm way ahead.
So I'm what I'm.
I'm just keep telling them that I'm
twisting the blade because I'm so far
ahead.
Like right now,
I am 1500 points away from everybody
else.
All births trying to work out again,
that Slob.
So when you see somebody catching up,
you're like,
well I better hit the gym.
Exactly.
Yeah.
And so I'm,
I'm planning on staying so far ahead
that they must die in order to beat me
and
the iphone or the Apple Watch when you
have people connected with the fitness
part of it,
it will literally notify me when one of
my friends has finished a workout and
tell me like how good there were,
how many points they just got as they
finish it.
Like you,
you hit the finish button and you know,
everyone's getting a notification like
that's interesting.
So I'm going to put in the extra four or
five miles on the bike.
So they get that notification that I did
that and that really does work
work.
Yeah.
I mean there's no doubt about it.
Just having that external motivating
factor and then seeing a number.
There's something about like with this,
with the meps,
mtps,
whatever the fuck that stands for,
find out what that stands for.
I don't even know what that stands
and I don't know how the Apple Watch
measures points either.
I think there's a.
because it's measuring.
I mean there's a lot of sensors in this
thing,
so not only as a heart rate monitor,
there's an accelerometer and a gyroscope
so it knows when you're standing,
knows when you're moving quickly and I.
It basically just comes up with a points
number at the end of the day and I.
Every time I fly I just don't get any
points because I just sit there.
Right.
But yeah,
there's like a live counter constantly
going of like you and your friends and
you got to have the highest number.
So out of all the stuff that you do
during my zone effort points,
that's what it is.
That's the maps points.
But here's the thing about that maps
points and we were trying to figure out
why it does.
It gives you the same amount of points
for 80 percent of your Max heart rate as
it does for 90.
So like the first day I said I'm just
going to sprint and try to bury these
guys.
So I put them in 90 percent for 35
minutes.
I was like,
they can't do that.
I'm just going to do some shit they
can't do,
but it doesn't give you any more points
for 90 percent.
Ninety percent gives the exact amount of
points is 80 percent.
So it's there on proprietary.
See those two?
They're fibers piece of shit.
So uh,
it's so dumb.
So I think the reason why they did that
as to keep people from killing
themselves,
that's what I think,
which makes just get somewhere in the 80
to 90 range that Bert is always in the
two and three fat bird never gets in
yellow.
That slob,
he just modeling around,
waddling around with blue and green.
Mostly gray gets a lot of gray.
He'll get gray for hours,
just waddling complaining,
thinking about vodka,
dreaming about food.
He's going to watch this and hit the gym
immediately on the gym.
The Gym right now,
he's at the gym right now trying to
catch up.
So always playing catch up.
Yeah.
The thing you gotta stay,
you gotta stay ahead like yeah,
when you fall behind in the distance,
you got to think of them as wolves
barking in the distance,
chasing it like no fucking way.
You're not eating me bitch wolves 10
miles away and not going to get you,
but wolves a hundred yards away they
they're going to get now they're going
to kiss you.
You gotTa,
you gotTa.
Keep the distance 10 miles away too far.
Ten miles that you want to hear.
Okay.
You don't want to.
You want to be at least just slob.
He said he's going to double everything.
I do.
Look at fat face.
That's not even possible.
I brought my dog up here to fuck you.
Yeah,
baby.
It's all so broken.
Stop this before I throw up the dog.
He's so far behind.
It's impossible to win,
but that's the point.
The point is to keep the.
To keep the boot on his neck.
Yeah.
This is.
This only does seven day challenges,
so you basically like you get,
you start it and they accept then
accounts for the next
seven days,
all your cumulative points.
Well that would be good.
Then you just do for and they can just
keep going.
Yeah,
yeah.
Over.
Yeah.
That's.
I like the challenge aspect of it.
It's really mean.
All jokes aside,
it's been really fun with my friends.
Poor Tommy Buns,
way behind what was going on.
Thomson [inaudible] way behind.
He's like 1800 points behind me.
Warn them up as he like saving for a
couple of days.
Might be,
might be sandbagged.
Then just comes full strength all day.
You saw you store them up in,
you're in this device and then you sync
so you can pretend that you're not doing
any work.
It could sand bag.
Yes.
No one knows.
Then the last day,
like you son of a bitch shows online.
He's 10,000
points ahead.
Oh,
just a real issue.
So the key is just keep the work rate at
an almost impossible level.
So like yesterday,
like I said,
I worked out five and a half hours and
then another hour and today I've already
put in two hours and put in two hours at
7:00
this morning.
So I tell her it doesn't have any.
The thing is I'm putting two hours in at
yellow,
I'm hitting 80 percent for two hours.
Fat Burn out,
they're waddling around with his dog
pretending he's working hard,
making videos.
That's,
he's got like gray and a little bit of
blue.
He maybe green who agree and then he
takes a break.
Cries and his numbers are low.
They're lower than mine.
That's a fact.
I worked out more yesterday,
last night and this morning.
Then he has an a whole day.
He knows my problem when I,
I play Frisbee,
so I take the watch off when I played
because it's a risk thing.
I'm constantly mutating.
Play like Frisbee disc.
Ultimate Frisbee.
Yeah.
So I take it off every time I play and I
know that's thousands of points that I'm
missing out on.
What is disc golf versus ultimate
Frisbee disc golf is what it sounds
like.
There is,
you play nine or 18 holes and you're
throwing in,
walking up or you throwing a Frisbee and
look at you.
They're gonna.
Get an Air Sun.
So ultimate Frisbee is different.
Ultimate Frisbee you can think of as
kind of like football slash basketball,
throwing that Frisbee with the left and
the right hand.
Yes.
Mostly one end.
Sometimes you throw a little offhand.
Why don't you switch the sucker to the
lefthand?
Uh,
it's,
I don't know,
there's something about wearing
something on my wrist of like throwing
and catching and it's just not.
You're so serious about it.
You're willing to lose points.
Yeah.
I,
if I really had to wear it for a week to
get really playing competitive here.
Yeah.
So this is all,
I'm pretty sure this is all pro
highlights,
but you guys are pro.
There's professional ultimate Frisbee
now and you're playing professionally
and I'm playing professional.
Ultimate Frisbee.
Whoa.
This actually looks really fun.
Yeah,
there's a lot of.
Is that you?
Two Thousand Sixteen Eastern Conference.
Defensive Player of the year.
I was a baby.
Mark has gone again.
Some would you have big hands?
I probably helps in this sport.
Right.
Definitely.
This is a fun play.
Look at this.
I want.
Oh,
snatch that guy that I just roofed,
scored like 15 points against the
psychologist called,
which is a lot.
I just roof to roof to roof.
Is that an ultimate Frisbee?
There's all kinds of uh,
there's,
yeah,
there's a term for a common one is you
skyride someone but roofed I like
because it's a disc and it's above his
head.
Well,
whenever you asked somebody what does
that,
when you lost someone like Randy Moss.
Oh,
but wearing muscle went out for football
and his chest is out.
Your like at your head level.
That's what someone looks like.
But there's other words for it.
So you might reach someone.
I can't believe you're doing this
without your,
your sensor on because you're so serious
about it.
Somebody.
Yeah.
You're losing so many points.
Wow.
Do you do any strength and conditioning
to prepare for this?
Yeah.
So the season is a couple of months
long.
So yes I am.
We're in the off season now.
This season just ended,
so we're just basically rebuilding.
I lose 15 pounds during the season,
so I'm putting that up
back on.
Then you get to like try out season in
like February or March.
Uh,
and then you just start.
Yeah,
getting a throws back,
getting your cardio back and starting to
work into it.
And then the season starts.
I would think that like leg strength and
explosive power,
like doing box jumps and things along
those lines would be huge for you.
Yes.
Uh,
so there's different,
like sort of like basketball or
football.
There's different sort of types of
players.
Uh,
you can sort of diff.
There's so many things to explain with
Frisbee.
There's a throwers and catchers you
might call them,
so handlers and receivers a lot of
shorter,
faster.
People who aren't as explosive but are
really,
really quick.
Our,
our handlers now go around the squirrel
around and they'll have awesome strength
and they'll be able to throw it
anywhere,
but they won't necessarily go downfield
and try to go score on someone because
they're not as tall or as explosive.
Meanwhile,
a lot of cutters are receivers are.
You can think of sort of like a wide
receiver in football,
they're going down field in there,
the athletes going and making plays in
the air and they're hard to guard down
field,
but they're not necessarily scrolling
around throwing a lot.
They're mostly just catching,
dumping it off to another thrower and
then going for some more yards again.
So if you watch a game unfold,
it's very fluid.
You constantly switched between offense
and defense,
like basketball,
you're scoring and an end zone and then
the points over and then you pull again
to start.
But as the points going on,
you kind of notice like certain players
are mostly doing certain things,
like mostly throwing,
mostly getting the disc back.
Other people are mostly going downfield,
threatening deep.
There's a lot of terminology you get
involved in this.
Uh,
the high school I went to,
Columbia high school invented this sport
in 1968.
Had a very competitive team for the
years that I was there and I made a lot
of friends on the team playing.
I played for the JV team for the first
two years and then I played for the
Varsity team my second two years,
so it was pretty serious program and we
played against other high schools around
the country.
We traveled,
we flew play against.
We had rivals in Massachusetts and
Connecticut and all these other schools,
and then we had the big eastern
championship at the end of the high
school season.
That was,
that's what we all played for it.
We won 11 straight state championships
the two years that I played.
That's incredible.
Yeah.
I did not know that.
This was even a thing.
They dealt as a rich history to it.
Yeah,
the tea.
Yeah.
50th anniversary this year.
That is so crazy.
I would've never guessed.
You said one was ultimate frisbee
invented.
I would say like a couple months ago.
Yeah.
Well it's so the pro league just is less
than 10 years old,
so there's always been this sort of
club.
You think of clubs,
soccer,
like area teams.
There's always been that.
So I've played for the New Jersey Garden
State Club team for much longer than I
played for any proteins and that's
generally what players take the most
seriously.
The club championships were this past
weekend,
the New York area team beat the San
Francisco area team to win nationals.
Like that's generally what people care
the most about,
but it's not very spectator friendly.
So what we've sort of created is the Adl
is the American ultimate disc league.
It's a pro version of Frisbee.
It's mainly the same sport but a little
bigger field,
uh,
and a little bit faster play just
because they've shortened the stoppages
and they have referees and everything
now and there is selling tickets and
selling merchant and jerseys and like
broadcasting games and they have a pro
championship at the end of the year.
So that's,
that's been like a whole new thing for
frisbee players to pay attention to.
And I've,
I've played for a protein as well as
past couple years and it's been pretty
fun.
Well I bought it because,
I mean just watching that clip was
really exciting.
Yeah,
it looks fun and you guys aren't getting
any brain damage.
That's a big deal.
It's about the same level of contact is
basketball I would say.
Perfect.
So you're not like throwing elbows or
anything like that.
There are false so you got to be careful
about where you're throwing your body
around,
but you're not going to happen because
people are running at each other,
but.
Exactly.
You're not worried about tackles.
Everything.
Stopped football or Lacrosse,
which I tried Lacrosse.
That was not for me.
Ridiculous people hitting each other
with sticks.
Yeah,
fuck all that.
It was a lot.
Do you mess around with Vr at all?
Yes,
a little bit.
I have A.
I have an htc vive and that's been the
most common use of Vr.
We have a vibe in the studio and the two
games that come to mind the most are
called super hot.
Don't know if you've played that.
No.
And beat Saber.
I try to play,
but my kids dominate this.
The vr thing.
Yeah,
they come in here and like get outta
here.
They pushed me away and there's a lot of
those.
There's a lot of fun stuff,
so I like so,
so super high is a fun one.
It's a shooting game,
strategy game type of thing.
Um,
so,
so the way supra you're getting,
you're in Vr so you're wearing this
thing and it's a bunch of stick figures
trying to kill you and they're running
downstairs,
running around corners,
shooting at you,
trying to kill you,
but time only moves when you move.
So if you hold still you can look around
and like see in the headset where people
are and sort of evaluate like okay I
can,
I can pick up this object and hurt
somebody with it.
This is it right here.
Yeah.
This is very crude looking video.
Yeah,
it's super basic.
Again,
stick figures trying to kill you,
but it's like a strategy game in that
you sort of have to evaluate where
you're at and not look around too much
and then as soon as you start to move
and throw things,
everyone else is trying to kill you
also.
Huh?
And so you can sort of dodge bullets as
they come around because you don't move
when you see them flying through the
air.
There's a lot of cool stuff to this
game.
So I got really into it.
I didn't get to this level,
which is probably.
Yeah,
you got to dodge all the bullets flying
at you.
Turn around,
throw something at him.
There's a boxing game.
Well there's several boxing games,
but in vr that are really good.
Wow.
And there they give you a workout
because there's a guy in front of you
and he's throwing punches and you're
bobbing and weaving like full speed
punching at him.
Yeah.
And they look good like it looks like,
like,
like you're in the ring and the guy's
looking at Jews mean mugging in throws
punches your way.
And when you get hit you see a flash of
white.
I want to try that now.
Yeah,
it's really fun.
But I think with the,
with the haptic feedback suit,
especially if you could put something
there it is right here,
the new one.
This is.
Oh this is a new one to create video
casts.
On your mouth.
Oh,
rock new rocky movie.
Or they can block.
Yeah,
follow up damaging kind of expose
protocol.
You could hear rocky's,
you're chairing this look at this,
but when you're doing it,
like we did it out here in the hallway.
My feet were hurting because I was
moving and shifting left and right and
throwing punches and bouncing off my
toes and after it was over to my fucking
feet are exhausted and you're doing the
drills and everything more so than it
would be if I was actually sparring.
Huh?
Because it was actually sparring.
I don't think I would.
I don't think it would throw as many
punches in such a quick succession.
You'd be more worried about getting hit
back and actually getting punched,
but when you're doing.
It's really interesting.
Wow.
Yeah,
that's I got to know,
is that Adrian?
There's also the uh,
is this the eight htc vive to it says,
yeah,
this just came out for all of them.
Okay.
Yeah.
The other one,
the other one's called beat Saber and
it's a.
You can think of it as like guitar hero,
but you're holding a light saber.
My kids love that.
I've gone past you.
I love that.
And things are flying at you and you're
hitting them.
Yeah.
That,
that is a really well done.
Yeah.
There's a bunch of really well done once
there's a,
there's a great one that you're in a
castle and you have a,
like an old school bone Arrow and then
disease almost like South Park.
Look at monsters.
Yeah.
And they're like,
it's still kind of cartoony.
But like if the graphics are crisp
enough that you like,
feel like you're a cartoon character in
a way.
Yeah,
it's good.
it's really cool.
And you know,
like there's actual physics to the
Arrow,
like when you shoot it certainly like
you have to lift your arm up to get the
arc of the Arrow.
Correct.
A hit it things.
Yeah.
Yeah,
yeah.
That's good.
I so I,
I think about vr a lot just because as a
video maker you're making content for
the platform that people view it on and
we started to get this little creeping
up of like three 60 video is getting
really good and like interesting
applications of of three 60 video and
it's still kind of early and I don't
really know if it's gonna take off or
it's,
it was just this medium steppingstone
format to what might be a more immersive
thing or maybe just ar is going to be
way better.
I don't know yet,
but I pay a lot of attention to it just
because it's,
it's new.
Ar is fascinating as well.
I mean we,
we,
we discussed,
what was it,
magic leap.
Is that what it was?
The Microsoft one know that that's the
other one.
Hollow Lens is Microsoft and then
magically it does its own thing.
I haven't tried either actually yet.
And which one was the one where the
Ballerina was dancing in your hand?
Magic leap,
but which one is that?
The one that people are saying is kind
of vaporware,
sort of,
sort of.
I would imagine that that screen on that
phone would have some sort of similar
technologies like light field
technology.
Talk about that.
Doing weird stuff with your eyes.
This is weird.
So this phone has a,
what are they calling it?
I'm not going to remember what they're
calling it.
Oh,
is there?
I need Wifi for it actually.
Uh,
it's got a three d screen at glasses
list.
3D,
uh,
and you,
you basically,
it has a three d screening.
You look at media on it and it's
supposed to sort of pop out at the top.
That doesn't have to be lowercase a
lowercase.
No,
no,
it doesn't.
One is it,
this is um,
t ballon.
Yeah.
Yeah,
that's it.
Uh,
but basically it's about,
it can look like that,
but you can't have things actually
popping out above the screen.
So things on the screen will look three
d,
but anything like outside of the screen
won't.
It's kind of hard to explain.
Wow.
And so this is for video games or for
other things as well.
So at this point what they're trying to
do is have a media like photos and
videos pop out,
pop out,
so not just games,
they're going to have games as well,
but they have shared with me a couple of
media files that are like a good use of
the three d and I'm curious what you
think of them because they're definitely
like a stretch but it's hollow me
Holler,
holographic is the word they use but
it's,
it's hard to explain and it's kind of
trippy,
oh
do this is weird.
And there's,
there's different like,
so there's a movie trailer version of it
where there's like things coming towards
you and I think that's maybe the best
use of it.
I've seen
it's impossible to show on camera.
I've tried many different times this,
this will never show up on camera.
This is odd.
Yeah,
they're an issue or like people have to
make stuff for this.
So.
So any content you have to shoot for,
for view,
they call it four of you
or they can take existing content and
convert it to four view,
but that's a little less successful
usually.
So it's really strange,
but the cameras on the back,
they have two cameras on the back and
you can shoot for a view with the
cameras on the hydrogen.
It's crazy.
Well,
what,
what I'm looking at right now is a
topographic maps.
Yeah.
Wow.
Amazing man.
So there's,
it's,
it's hard to
tell again,
like I try to separate things into
buckets of this is something you're
going to use everyday and love or this
is a total gimmick that you'll never use
again.
And I met,
I started with it in the bucket of this
is kind of like a gimmick,
but they've put so much effort into
making it good and all these different
conversion techniques in.
Let me see if I can find a clip,
but they've been constantly changing the
algorithms and adjusting it and updating
it to look better that it's starting to
convince me that it might be worth
paying attention to for more than just
the first two seconds.
This is amazing.
Do you think you would like use it all
the time?
No,
never use it.
It's still amazing.
It's still pretty cool.
Right?
It's very cool.
But how much better is it than regular
video that,
that end?
How long can you like look at it before
your eyes start to tweak?
A little bit.
Um,
I'm already going,
but it looks good.
It definitely looks really good.
It looks cool.
It's kind of interesting.
Yeah.
But
so you can take,
you can take photos and videos with the
camera on the phone that are in this
three d and that's maybe the best use of
it because then you can see like what's
actually in the room around you.
The way it would just show up and like a
direct translation.
Yeah.
How much of an impact does it have on
storage size?
Uh,
not much.
I mean there's still video files and
they're like big four k videos,
but they're not necessarily through
faces big or anything like that.
It looks cool but,
but then use the video looks pretty cool
too.
When you go into the view finder and you
go from two d to three d,
then he can take photos and videos of
things
in that format.
So he,
oh this
is weird man.
Take.
If you take a capture and then look at
it and you kind of like move the phone
around a little bit.
It's Kinda like Shimmery in a weird way,
but kind of three d sort of.
This is very odd.
It's very hard to explain.
Yeah.
You'd have to look at this through this
thing.
Like you'd would never be able to show
this to someone in a video.
Yeah,
exactly.
Look,
I'm looking at these plastic sell little
figurines and as I move forward and
backward,
you really get a sense of three d.
yeah,
that's pretty bad ass.
So I gotta figure out how to show it in
the video of like,
you can't.
I just have to describe it to use my
words.
God,
that's amazing.
Yeah.
And that's.
Well,
it's probably coming.
That's probably common.
It's probably going to be something
we're all gonna have to deal with.
Yeah.
I'm interested.
Uh,
if you ask,
read that tell you,
yeah,
this is the future.
Everything's going to be like this.
I'm like,
you got it.
I think you have to say that at this
three d movies were a big deal.
Get those stupid glasses and yeah,
I mean,
so they're claiming is like,
yes,
this is what's it's genuinely good.
Like you can use it in portrait and
landscape glasses.
Let's three d,
it's usually only one way or the other
because of polarization.
So this is a lenticular technology.
I don't know exactly how it works,
but you can use it in portrait or
landscape.
You can play games with it and things
will react in depth of space on,
in the game.
Well,
the first video that you showed me is
really interesting too,
because it's essentially like a
topographic map.
Yeah.
So it's like Sarah,
you're paying attention to depth.
Yeah.
You're looking at the layers of the
mountain and the hillside.
So it was kind of weirder,
like seeing these little figurines and
moving toward them in real life.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
That's what I think is a,
that's the best way to calibrate tier.
I like what it's doing around,
if you just look at like a video of it,
you're like,
all right,
it looks three d like it's coming at me.
And they had a couple,
uh,
like a movie trailer type of thing where
like again,
like it was mostly shot for this format
and things would like kind of go past
you and the speakers are also really
good.
So they have this sort of a three d
conversion technique for audio as well
where it sort of goes behind you.
But yeah,
it's definitely interesting.
Yeah.
Um,
did you mess around with Google glasses
when they first came out?
It did,
yeah.
What did you think?
Okay,
this is,
this is going to be something I guess I
probably did.
I,
it was a glass was weird.
It was ahead of its time but also like
not really.
Like I,
I,
I had it,
I was in college also,
so it was like I can't wear it to class
or like walk around.
I guess I could walk around hoboken with
it,
but the whole idea of an augmented
reality,
this little screen that I could just
check the weather and then look back
down or check my texts and look back
down and was like,
oh,
that could be cool.
But also if you look at someone wearing
google glass,
it's like,
that guy's wearing google glass,
you can't,
can't get around it where people would
get angry at people for wearing it
because it had a camera and filming me.
What are you doing?
Yeah.
So that was another thing is I tried,
uh,
I won't even say the name,
but like another,
like much newer version of that where
again,
it was like a,
a small projection to a prism that
would,
you could see,
but no one else could and it would fit
into something that looked more like
regular glasses.
So it had a battery,
it had everything but it didn't have a
camera and you still had a screen that
you could look up into the corner too.
And I was like,
well,
I wonder if you'll notice the difference
between regular glasses.
And I went down and I met the guys who
were showing it to me in the lobby and
immediately I was like,
that guy's wearing it.
I can see it.
I could see a little light in his eye.
I can see like the extra thick glasses.
So it was like,
it's,
it's an interesting concept and I don't
know where it goes from here if it has
to be glasses based or if we'll
eventually have some sort of a chip in
her eye or what the deal is,
what the next move is.
But it's a cool concept.
Yeah.
It's one of those things that sort of,
it's kind of been flirting with for the
longest time people thought virtual
reality was going to be.
I mean there was virtual reality
concepts 20 years ago and people thought
virtual reality was going to be the
future and then it,
it took a long time for the hardware to
catch up.
I think augmented reality has a more
promising immediate future just because
it's more useful.
Um,
but virtual reality has like the
immersion factor going for it.
The problem is you have to make a whole,
you have to make a whole world.
So augmented reality is just like some
layer on top of your current world.
So you get like a little screen or
whatever,
or you look at one particular thing and
it looks different from real life.
That's easier to build for virtual
reality,
you have to build the whole world that
you step into it.
That's like a much,
much a deeper layer of immersion,
which is great to step into but also
hard to make.
So that's the difference.
I think I'm more into ar at the moment.
Well I think ar in the sense of having
all the functions of your phone in front
of you in the air when you call upon
them.
Yeah.
Kind of like a movie.
Like a,
like one,
someone in a movie or like iron man even
like they just out like as a sheet of
like buttons in front of them and like
close it only they could see that maybe
that's the future and have some,
Hey Siri type,
you know,
hopefully not demand series.
Terrible.
Serious.
Not that good.
It works for some things.
It's okay if something.
Siri Google assistants better though.
Yes.
Yeah.
Uh,
yeah.
See that?
Well there's the.
Have you tried bixby thing?
Excuse even worse.
Bixby.
It was pretty bad.
Yeah.
But bixby does a few things.
Okay.
Like a checks.
Flights.
Okay.
Me has like bixby.
I think is hilarious because it shows
how good it can be and then it isn't
good like it.
It has a couple of things that it can
definitely do better than any other
assistant,
like what it can dig in locally on
Samsung phones and like do strings of
commands.
You can say,
Hey,
Spi,
open my settings APP,
turn my brightness halfway down and turn
my wifi off and it'll do all of that.
And Siri and Google assistant won't do
that.
But if you say,
hey,
big speed,
how tall is like the Statue of Liberty?
It might not do it like it's a really
bad at a lot of basic things.
So yeah,
Google Assistant I think is the most
complete and useful.
I genuinely use it all the time.
Syria mostly triggered by accident and
then I wonder if it's better and it
isn't what's offensive.
The bixby has a button.
Yeah,
I hate that.
Come on.
Why?
And you can remap an unreal mappable
Dick speed button that you accidentally
press all the time.
Yeah,
lower left hand corner.
Like what is this thing that.
It's pretty bad.
Yeah.
The iphone Siri button gets pressed a
lot,
but what I really like about the pixels
of squeeze.
Yeah,
you can turn it off.
Do you use it,
like just squeeze it?
Actually the assistant?
Yeah.
Once in a while.
I mostly use the hey google trigger
which is mapped to my voice,
so see it turns on now that I said it.
Oh Wow.
But I started using the squeeze a little
more so I don't have to yell and I can
just squeeze it and say a commander
question.
Mostly question now,
do you use any of the home feature
things like do you use Alexa or the
Google home or.
A first thing I got into my home was
google home,
so now I have a google home home.
If I had Alexa first thing I probably
would have had an Alexa home with things
that worked with Alexa,
but they genuinely like usually work
with each other.
Do your lights,
work with it.
And also what I have is I have a nest
thermostat and I have a nest security
camera and I think that's it.
And I had smart lights but I stopped
using them so it's mostly just the nest
stuff and I can ask what the temperature
is upstairs and then say hey,
change the temperature to this and then
it'll do it.
So I don't have to run out and find the
thermostat and change it myself.
I remember hearing that,
um,
Bill Gates had some pin that you would
put on when you entered into his home
and when you go into certain rooms,
if you had a pin on it would recognize,
oh it's bill.
Bill likes the temperature at this
level.
He likes this art on the wall.
So he had have lcd screens that would
display different images.
That's almost too much modularity.
Like I,
I kinda,
I like it a general state of like things
are the same unless I want them to
change.
Like that would be kind of weird.
Like every time you leave the room the
art changes behind you when you walked
back in and it changes back and you
leave again.
It's kind of a lot.
Uh,
but yeah,
like just like a couple things,
like I have the Google home app where
I'll like,
yeah,
changes the temperature once in awhile
or a you get,
there's this thing I've considered
getting the ring doorbell.
Yeah.
Which has a camera,
but I don't really use the doorbell that
much.
It's mostly packages get delivered to
work instead of home.
Yeah,
that's about it.
Yeah.
The Alexa and the Google home,
they're like,
what the big concern that people have is
it's listening to you all the time.
Like there was a store that I read
about,
there was a murder investigation and
that they were trying to get the records
of Amazon Alexa Wild,
you know,
this murder investigation was going on
because they think they could have like
listened to the conversation and then
people are like,
wait a minute,
this fucking thing.
Just listening all the time.
Well it is,
but it's not,
don't worry about it.
It'll help you.
Yeah.
If you get murdered dee,
you don't want anybody to get away with
it.
Do you?
True.
Yeah,
that is a lot.
Yet it's got to listen like.
So the whole privacy thing,
I have honestly have to think about that
a lot.
Mike.
My compromise in my own head personally
is I don't have privacy and I know it so
I might as well get something back for
it,
which is convenience.
So like if,
if I'm going to have like this Google
assistant on my phone,
I already have a gps and Wifi and all
these sensors in my phone,
I might as well like Google of course
they know where I am so I might as well
get something for it.
So maybe I'll get like shortcuts to like
where I need to go,
you know,
where my work is just gimme a shortcut
to traffic to work.
Like that's what's weird and says you'll
be home in 12 minutes.
Like pitch.
How do you know where I lived?
Yeah,
exactly.
How do you know when I'm home?
But if you're going to know that,
which I know you are because you're
google,
then give me something back.
Right.
And you know,
restaurants near me.
Like how do you know where I am?
You're watching me all the time.
You're constantly basically.
So it knows like I have a couple of like
preferences that seem like pretty minor,
like what sports teams do you like?
What sports do you enjoy watching or
like what sort of topics do you enjoy?
And if you open my google assistant it
will tell you like here's the score of
the game you were about to check the
score to here's the traffic.
I have a flight later.
What is going to do and I know it's
going to do this is it's going to tell
me when it's time to leave based on
traffic,
based on my location to arrive to my
flight 90 minutes before the scheduled
departure.
It's going to tell me when to leave
because it knows where I am.
It knows where the airport I'm leaving
from is it knows my flight,
my flight time and it knows I need to
get to the airport in 90 minutes before
the flight.
Does Google own ways now?
Uh,
they either own ways or bought.
I think that yeah,
I think they bought waste.
So when you get something through Google
maps,
it does kind of the same thing that
weighs does,
right?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
They use data from which people who live
in these neighborhoods were ways is now
rerouting.
You heard about.
They are furious about that and I'm away
his person.
So like,
I know you're very familiar with the
rerouting and it's pretty hilarious.
It's hilarious.
People had these sleepy little
communities and now it's like it's
traffic streams of cars going through
their neighborhood is great though.
Yeah,
it is great.
It is great.
I mean it's,
it's amazing how well it predicts your
time arrival to and the whole like
notifying you when there's construction
or police or something.
Yeah.
No,
it's excellent.
The car's broken down the right lane,
you know,
shift to the left.
You're going to get around it.
Yep.
I'm,
I'm fascinated by all these advances and
where they're taking us.
And uh,
I spent a lot of time thinking about it.
I spend a lot of time thinking about
what the future or what
the future holds and where all this
stuff is going.
And I never,
I never would have imagined 20 years ago
that we would be all addicted to our
phones and one of the big issues would
be like one of the new features in the
iphone shows you how much screen time
you have and because when we're doing
this fitness challenge,
your screen is on all the time because
you're looking at your screen because it
shows you the score that you're scaling.
So it's like your screen usage this
month is up 900 percent.
Like oh no,
that's not good at counting this month
obviously because of that.
But there's something to addiction to
phones and addiction to technology and
the fact that it's so a part of our life
that I.
I can only imagine it's going to get
more and more immersive and we're going
to become more and more symbiotic with
all this electronics mean you're wearing
a watch that Paula tile and new things
all the time and you have three phones
with you.
Yeah,
I.
on one hand,
I know that it's gotten a,
at least recently,
a little more in the spotlight.
Like Google just added the same thing.
It digital wellbeing feature which tells
you how much screen time you've had in
certain apps and we'll let you restrict
your usage of instagram by a certain
number of minutes,
whatever.
As soon the same thing.
They both introduced that within six
months of each other,
which is kind of fascinating.
But on the other hand I think I think in
my own head that I am not addicted yet.
I still unplug every weekend to play
ultimate and then I plugged back in on
Monday.
When you say you unplugged,
meaning you don't check your email,
check your texts?
No,
I mean I,
I,
if I get texts I get them but like as
far as that mean.
So like I have my stuff with me but like
when I go,
when we go play a tournament that's like
you'll have like five games in a day.
So I'd get up at like 7:30.
You go to the fields,
you put your bag down,
you warm up,
you play a game,
you play a game and you'd done about
like four or 5:00
PM.
Wow.
All Day,
no phone activity.
Yes.
That's amazing.
You're not wearing your watch.
Yeah.
I'm missing out on a lot of points.
I'd be whooping some people in this
competition thing,
but I'm clearly not.
Um,
so yeah,
like all day and then we'll have a team
dinner and then shower,
sleep,
wake up the next day,
day two of the tournament.
Sunday you need instead of that risk
drop,
you needed like a forearm strap that's
like on out of
the way.
Yeah,
like on like one of those tennis fan
things.
I know I have a couple of friends at
that play ultimate with that on like
under their jersey,
but like the watch is the points.
Like I don't know if the watch,
if I put it up here,
we'll still measure my heart rate and
all that stuff the same,
but my zone thinks thinks to a
compression shirt and I know you can
sync them eyes on thing to your watch.
The Apple Watch it that way.
I don't know if you could.
I'm pretty sure you.
What do you mean it syncs to a
compression to compression shirt that
has those little sensors sinks,
but through their.
But
yeah,
I almost bought it,
but he snapped the thing into the
compression for all,
for women in a shirt.
For my God,
I got to get a Bra.
I'm,
I want to get one of those days because
the mind's getting super sweaty,
man.
This thing is losing a lot of.
It's less density.
It's so gross to instincts that you can
wash it,
wash it in water and these led drivers.
So I thought it was electronic,
uh,
isn't going to stink.
Just like,
oh,
just the fabric part.
Oh,
I just assumed that because all this
stuff is like you have to voltage
sensors.
It's just the sensors or making some
sort of a contact with these buttons
which makes a contact with your.
Don't wash the sensor.
Plastic metal.
So don't watch this,
but the rest of it,
it has to go through these pads to get
to your skin.
I don't want it to be shitty.
Yeah,
get this straight then.
Okay.
How many get the shirt?
But yeah,
it's not,
almost,
not quite yet.
It's not too late overnight that four
days.
Yeah.
Um,
augmented reality,
uh,
you know,
I know that there is a,
there's talk about a contact lens that
was being in development that was going
to be some sort of a lens that's going
to allow you to do like a lot of
minority report type shit in front of.
I think tech is tech as I know it is too
far from that to make that work just
because you need like a contact lens you
think of is just like this clear thing.
Maybe some circuits on it or whatever.
But like you need a battery,
right?
And then you need,
unless it operates off your body I
guess,
but then you still need some smartwatch
that operates off the heat of your body
is.
I mean I don't know how direct,
like even if you do operate off of some
other power,
says you need to get that power source
to connect to the electronics to make it
work,
which still takes some space.
I don't know how much but see,
I don't know.
It seems kind of far out,
it's a,
it's a cool idea,
but it also seems really,
really difficult to put a contact lens
directly in front of your retina and be
able to focus on it and there's a bunch
of questions I have about it.
I don't know how reasonable or realistic
it is.
My real fear is that they're going to
invent a better eye for blind people and
when they do like,
look how amazing this is.
We've given blind people the ability to
see,
again,
optical zoom,
but now they also have all these other
features that you don't have with your
regularized.
Let us keep those bad boys out and put
some fucking.
Some robot eyes,
binocular eyes.
I'm a little worried about that.
Realistically worried about that.
It came.
It came from.
We were watching this video once where
there was a guy who got his arm and his
leg bit off by sharks.
He got attacked by a shark when you're
surfing.
So yeah,
this carbon fiber hand that totally
articulate,
it's like a real hand and he's standing
there with his.
From his knee down was an artificial leg
and he was walking around and moving
like a regular person.
I was like,
look at this guy.
This is an incredible.
I'm like,
he's kind of a bionic guy because his
hand was moving around.
He could shake your hand and he seemed
so normal.
I'm like,
what if it gets like many,
many generations better than this where
it has like Luke skywalker when he got
his hand chopped off by Darth Vader,
remember we got that robot hand and
history.
There's people working on this every
day.
So I kind of figure we're headed in that
direction where like,
what's this Jamie?
So I just googled something at not out
yet.
It's because this is called Macula,
which is a Ar Lens that you were with a
sunglasses.
So in and together they make an air
station
glasses,
a lens as a contact,
and then sunglasses
picture that they,
uh,
that's what they say they got.
So yeah.
What is the Macula?
Sorry,
I have a lens here and then go over top.
What do about a creepy dude?
Wow.
What a picture.
It's not out yet,
it's just this,
you can invest in it.
So it's more like how magic leap was
about a year,
year and a half ago.
Like I'm not invested in anything that
uses guys are covered.
Boy,
what's up with his face?
Man?
It's a fucking robot,
man.
He's an alien.
He looks like the guy from men in black.
Remember when the alien put the skin on.
Remember?
That's what he looks like here.
Something wrong with the left side of
his face,
man.
He's wearing someone's skin.
That's a weird system.
So a lens in a contact.
So the battery might be in the glass and
the glasses and it's working and I don't
know how it's connected,
but.
Hmm.
Wow.
Well we.
This is.
Who knows what this is.
Here's the other thing.
I don't need the information that fast,
that bad.
I'm okay with a one second delay of
picking up my phone and checking it
instead of [inaudible] like,
what are you getting with?
You saw the note.
The examples were like incoming call,
the weather,
your emails,
things like that.
Like information you can already get in
two seconds by just.
Yep.
I have an incoming call.
I have an email.
I have a text like that pretty quick,
pretty quick.
And I've,
I've said this before where someone has
asked me like,
are we at like the final form of
smartphones?
Like where are they going to go?
Are we going to get bigger?
I'm going to get smaller.
Are they going to be implanted in you?
I think smartphones are at like pretty
much their final form.
We're going to keep evolving the insides
of smartphones to be better.
They're going to get faster,
they're going to get more and more
transparent,
whatever.
They'll get like more interesting
looking,
but I think it's always going to be a
thing I pick up and use and then put it
back down.
I think that's where we're at for a
while.
Um,
w what are your thoughts on Samsung's
foldable screens
that I am very curious about because
again,
sounds awesome,
but why do I fold it?
Why?
What am I doing with it and how big is
it going to get yet?
Am I so like maybe so we had this a
while ago when we started first getting
this big phones,
they were like,
oh you could have a really big phone,
like a tablet,
but then you fold it in half and it's a
phone size now,
but like I might as well just have a
phone and a tablet unless I don't know
if I need both to remember the Samsung.
What was that giant thing that they had
that was bigger than a note a while.
They have small tablets but they had a,
it was a phone.
Oh,
the galaxy mega.
Yeah,
they have like the weird thing is like
that I think was like a six and a half
inch screen and that's where we're at
now.
Was it really?
Yeah,
it was massive compared to what we had
also in the market,
which was like five inch screens.
I never saw one in the wild.
I reviewed one.
Yeah,
it was,
it was way bigger than any other phone
out,
but I'm pretty sure if I looked back
that was like a six and a half inch
screen.
It was less than seven inch.
I think that's the sweet spot.
Seven inch screen tablet,
six inch screen phone and I think yeah,
this is a six point two inch screen.
This is a six point five.
Six point five inch screen.
So what's that?
It was six point three.
So that's bigger than the galaxy mega.
That's crazy.
Look at that thing.
Endless entertainment mega for x zoom.
But that thing's still had the forehead
and the bezels on the Chin and bad.
Really in comparison to that horrible
iphone eight.
It's Kinda the same galaxy mega 16
gigabytes.
Woo Baby.
Wow.
Look at that thing.
That's so weird.
I wonder what year that was.
That was like,
no,
don't tell me.
That was probably college.
So like 2014,
20.
Pulled that thing out.
You were a pimp.
Like what are you doing with touch and
shine as movies all the time?
Battery life.
Forty four minutes.
That was a fun time.
Yeah,
it's crazy when you connect your phone
to your car.
Here's the other one that just happened.
The,
this tiny palm phone.
Uh,
I don't know if you've seen this.
So it's like a super small phone
accessory to your normal phone,
so it does almost everything your normal
phone does,
but it's way smaller.
It has like a half of the.
It says congratulations.
You've launched the stupidest product of
the year.
If it's a phone accessory to your phone,
they could have just made a small phone.
That would have been fine.
But then they made this,
this whole thing.
We're like,
oh,
but it has to connect to your other
phone and then it uses the same phone
number but it works sometimes.
And steph curry is our ambassador and I
don't know anymore why someone would
want to get that.
So how close does it have to be your
regular phone?
Uh,
I think it has its own data or
something.
I Dunno.
It's Kinda like an apple watch.
Like it's an accessory to your phone
that kind of is the same form factor as
a phone.
You put it in your pocket,
you like go to the gym and you just
bring that instead of bringing the main
phone or you just go on a hike and you
just don't want to bring your whole
setup so you just bring the little
be in the meeting with whatever cokehead
came up with that idea.
I don't know.
I can't think of any other really great
reasons to have it.
Well I think the iphone,
the apple watch sort of has it nailed
right.
You get your notifications,
but if it's excessive or that you enjoy
it even though you're not even using it
for a lot of the features I'm using for
the fitness aspect.
And what else do you use on it?
Whether or.
Yeah,
so like it's,
I have the four g version,
I get the weather and also it has the
ability to make calls.
I do,
but I never do.
We never do.
Like if I wanted to call a restaurant
and see what kind of,
you know,
hours they have,
I could say hey siri and make a call.
But yeah.
Yeah.
Now is there nothing commensurate in the
Google world?
I mean there's other smartwatches.
There is technically A.
Samsung also makes their own,
but they have a galaxy smartwatch that
has like a kind of a cool spinning
thing.
Yeah.
Galaxy Watch.
It's probably the best android
compatible smartwatch.
Huawei has a kind of a cool one too.
Right?
So why we did this thing that I thought
was is the good try.
It was a good try.
It was a smartwatch that has a digital
screen but then had a mechanical hand
like so that it looked like a normal
watch on the screen is not on.
The problem with that is when you go to
look at like your notifications or
whatever you get the hands are blocking
the screen.
So they didn't really think too hard
about.
I mean they,
they got to that point and they're like,
oh you know what we'll do,
we'll have this button where you press
it and then the hands like move out the
way and then the screen,
the notification will like move to the
side so you can read it.
It was.
They tried,
they really tried.
They tried to be different.
I respect the hell out of that.
Good try wowway.
But no.
Now do people,
do companies ever come to you and say,
hey man,
you're really good at reviewing these
things?
Um,
are we [inaudible] up here?
Uh,
Kinda sorta red came to me before this
existed in it's in this form a and it
wasn't a prototype phase and they were
still pretty far along,
but it was kinda like,
should we do this?
Should we put this here?
Should we keep the headphone Jack?
I was,
I was giving them sort of,
yeah,
they kept the headphone Jack.
Little things like that.
Um,
but for the most part,
I think what a lot of people don't
understand about product development is
it happens many,
many,
many months before you ever see the,
the products show up.
So I don't know if you remember,
like all the leaks about the pixel xl,
all of them guarantee six months before
the iphone came out.
It was done.
Like they knew that that's what it was.
Gonna more than I think any phone that I
can recall.
Yeah.
So that's the same as the iphone,
like they've been working on the
whatever the next iphone is,
they've been working on that iphone and
it's probably going to be like a couple
more months and then they're like
finalizing design and things like that.
And so when you start to see phones come
out like around like September and
October and they start to all kind of
resemble each other and then another one
comes out and it looks the same.
It's not like they saw the phone in
early October and they were like let's
copy that.
And then they made the next phone two
weeks later they've been working on this
forever.
So like when the whole,
like the whole notch thing was people
were like,
oh I hope Google's trolling us.
Then that's not really the notch.
And they're going to have this phone
with no notch.
Now it's,
they've been working on this for a long
time.
This is what they planned.
What is that one phone where the back
slides up for the selfie camera.
So there's two,
I think what you're thinking of Apo
fine.
10.
Yeah,
that's a pretty.
I like the idea,
it's pretty cool,
but I'm like,
man,
how long is that thing gonna work?
That's the question.
So phones are no chips in there.
Yeah,
any little bit of breeze motors?
Yeah.
Phones are solid state for the most part
for good reason.
You don't want a lot of moving parts in
a phone that you're like running around
with A.
There's another one called the Vivo
Apex.
A.
No,
it's another vivo phone.
Basically.
Nex is what it's called and it has just
the selfie camera pop up.
Testing that one too and that's another
thing.
It's like,
well what if a grain of sand gets in
there?
Like is it toasts?
Immediately,
drop that soccer on the beefy,
drop it while it's open.
Is that over by evo next?
Yes.
Any excess or next?
I don't know if I'm supposed to say next
or whatever,
but that's a.
it's an interesting.
It looks cool because now look,
you have the fingerprint reader under
the glass.
You have all the way to the bottom of
the screen and then all the way to the
top is the screen and then you just have
the selfie camera.
It looks amazing.
Awesome.
Yeah.
No,
no bezels at all.
Yeah.
Or basically no.
Bezels pretty much tiny chin at the
bottom.
So that's the idea is like we're in this
sort of a race to get to a Bezel this
phone.
Um,
and I guess that's the closest we can
get right now.
It's just having a little mechanical
thing pop out.
I think what we want is a,
the stuff to be behind the glass.
Yeah.
A camera behind the glass.
But then how would you see the image?
Yeah,
so I think if,
based on what I know about the physics
of the technology you need,
you need an oled display and you need
the camera to be behind the oled display
and then when you light up the camera
you need like a little black circle
where those pixels are off so that they
can shine through.
I don't know if this is all making
sense.
I think you're still going to always
have some sort of a black circle in the
front of the phone somewhere.
It's fascinating about iphone versus
android is that there's so much more
room for possibility with android
because you have so many different
manufacturers that are competing in that
marketplace.
They're trying to find some sort of a
way to shine and that was where the
wall.
Wait,
was it the mate rs
with like the Porsche Design version
where I thought that was a really
interesting film because it was stupid
expensive,
but it had a gigantic battery and had an
incredible 20 megapixel camera.
Great night photos.
Low light photos.
Yeah.
They,
they,
they really tried to do like,
you know,
Porsche designed does a lot of different
things.
They do sunglasses.
Yeah.
Ballpoint pens.
They do all kinds of weird stuff and
really has nothing to do with the car,
but what they've really.
They design.
They came up with something really high
end and they showed there's some sort of
a market for that.
Is that it right there?
Yeah,
that's it again.
Phone now they did with the mate 20.
They did the same thing,
it's a great looking fun,
but it's a again,
when you look at like how much you have
to pay versus what extra you're getting.
You might as well just get the mate 20
pro and not worry about the science.
People want that Porsche design.
Then just to go look at me.
I'm a baller.
They made a bitch fade.
They did the same like Porsche does that
Lamborghini does that.
A Ferrari does that?
Tesla does that.
There is a,
a Lamborghini addition.
Apo fine 10.
Yeah.
Like carbon fiber and phone though.
You got to put it on the car and it
looks dope on the car.
Of course.
That's a dope looking phone period.
Did you mess with that phone at all?
Uh,
I,
I mess with the May 20 but not the
porsche design one,
but it comes down to like using the
phone itself is going to be pretty much
the same.
Like once you get past like the design,
which is a little bit different,
you open up the phone and the software
is you'd get a cool couple wallpapers
but like it's the same phone and on the
inside a little more storage maybe,
but basically the same thing.
But I just,
I find it fascinating that they've
decided to go that far out into the high
end,
deep end.
Yeah.
I guess you have to differentiate
yourself at $20,000,
right?
Yeah.
Starts at $2,000.
So I guess as hype as you want to get
about it,
like are you going to go pay $2,000
for that?
Probably not.
But then when the note nine came out,
it kind of took a lot of the window.
They're sales battery was the same size
cameras for fairly similar big ass
screen.
And the other thing about phones is we
got all these phones that are a thousand
dollars now and it's made it so easy to
just bump up the price of your phone and
not have anyone blink an eye.
I've been thinking about that a lot.
We have the iphone 10 starts at a
thousand dollars,
right?
So then the iphone 10 art came out and I
think they could have priced it anywhere
from 6:50
to 8:50
and they just nestle it right in there
at 7:15
and you're like,
oh,
that's way cheaper.
So then this phone comes out Pixel Pixel
and Pixel xl.
You probably don't remember what the
Pixel to cost,
but the pixel three starts at seven 99,
which seems like that's pretty
reasonable,
right in that range.
That's a hundred $50 more expensive than
last year.
Why?
Like what's so much better about pixel
three then pixel to that.
It's a dollar is more.
The market is just lifted everything
plus $200 so that a thousand dollars as
a high end now.
And I think that's what's convinced.
Companies like Wowway,
like if we want to compete with apple
and really make what seems and looks
like a premium phone,
we have to charge $1,200
so that people know it's better than the
iphone.
If we charge $800,
they're not gonna think it's better than
the iphone.
We have to charge more than apple
charging to prove that we have more in
our phone,
but plus is interesting because they're
really reasonable,
but their specs are very high.
I liked them.
They,
they've had a good history of like they
usually listen to what people seem to
want and a phone and they're also good
at like picking high end numbers that
look great on paper and usually
translate pretty well to using the
phone.
Uh,
but they always cut out.
They cut as many corners as they can to
get the price as low as they can.
Their phone.
Last year it was about 550 bucks,
right.
All glass,
but no wireless charging.
But it's glass.
We have dual cameras.
You hardly ever use a second camera,
but it's still cameras.
Uh,
eight gigs of Ram snapdragon 8:45.
A lot of phones have the same specs now
these days.
But like they've gotten pretty good at
like going the opposite direction.
Like we're not going to charge a
thousand bucks.
We're going to make a that same phone.
Trust us,
it's the same,
but for way less money,
that's,
that's a much more popular direction to
go.
As far as sales,
no.
They've done the same strategy for the
newest one plus.
Yep.
And they're coming out with a new one
this month.
Oh,
one plus 16.
They.
They keep the headphone Jack so far.
So far.
Jack is a weird one.
Right?
It's like,
how is Samsung going to hold onto that
sucker?
Samsung's been very popular for keeping
the headphone Jack and not having a
notch.
They're like the last ones to have a
headphone Jack and no notch.
Well,
I'm a big fan of the way the note nine
looks when I'm using it.
That's a beautiful device.
It feels net premium and the hand.
Yeah.
What do you think is wrong with it?
With no nine?
Yeah.
My biggest problem with note nine is the
front facing camera and the software and
the software is not even that bad.
It's just,
it's gotten slow for me quickly.
A lot of times,
like I've been using note nine.
I also don't think it's the prettiest
software.
I really like Samsung screens,
so I know they can make good looking
stuff,
but I think if they made A.
I don't know if you remember Google play
addition when they used to do that,
if they made a Google play edition
galaxy note nine,
I would instantly by that phone that
would be sick because I love Google's
like software being cleaner and looking
a little better.
If you look at Samsung software,
it looks kind of cartoony a lot of
times.
Very colorful.
Not a problem,
but it's just not my favorite.
I know some people have figured out a
way to use the google launcher on other
phones,
so they other phones look like a pixel.
Yeah,
you can.
You can go.
You can only go so far back like you
can.
You can use the Google launcher and you
can use an icon packed use google icons,
but still you're going to have your
settings pull down.
It's still gonna look like Samsung.
You're going to have in the apps,
like the settings app is still going to
look like the Samsung settings app.
You're still gonna have three email apps
and three messaging apps and all this
stuff.
Samsung on his does,
but yeah,
the messaging apps are weird.
Do you want this one to beard to fault
and like.
I don't know what that is.
Yeah,
I just that one.
I just want to use one and not have a
message.
Plus.
Yeah,
like why is it better if you use a
verizon Samsung note,
I think you end up with three messaging
apps like verizon messages of rise in
Messenger and then there's the message
plus on this Google's messenger and it's
just a lot and then there's hangouts and
then how do I even get in touch with so
on anymore.
It's a lot.
I'm wondering if there's ever going to
be a time where something happens
technologically where the walled garden
of apple sort of dissolves and
everything becomes accessible.
Apple will fight till they die to let
that wall that they will never let that
go down.
That's.
That's like one of their biggest,
most prideful accomplishment is building
that wall.
I mean,
they really have nailed it now other
than brand loyalty and other than the
prestige of having an apple product,
which is all very high.
Yeah.
That walled garden,
that's where it's at.
Have you ever tried to leave an iphone?
I did like that's a thing.
Yeah.
Okay.
It was a fucking nightmare.
Yep.
I,
I couldn't get text messages and very
calm.
And here's the thing.
I even called up apple and I said,
I want you to remove me from your
message.
Yeah.
From your.
I'm,
I gave them my email address.
I gave them a phone number,
the whole deal and they will why I go
because I went with a pixel phone and it
was like a pause.
Like I just ate a baby.
It's a different phone.
You Fox.
I'm trying to find a different phone.
Will let me out,
let me out.
So then I call my friend.
I go,
hey man,
send me a text.
Send me a text.
I sent that shit.
Nothing.
Now I'm going to send you a text.
Nothing,
nothing.
I'll go,
okay,
I'm going to shut it off.
Turn it back on.
Nothing,
you have to start with a new phone
number.
The Wall.
Yeah.
You have to literally start with a new
number.
You have to start from scratch and then
people get that green mess.
The reason why I don't make my main
phone number and I found it because I
know I'm like lowering myself into the
garden.
Like I can use an iphone,
but that will probably never be my main
sim.
I have two sims.
My main number,
the one everyone has an android phone.
I think it'll stay that way as long as
that's the way
I feel like you in your particular
profession as a and you're a reviewer of
all these things.
I think you kind of have to do that
because otherwise you'd be in this weird
position of
not being able to leave.
That was the thing.
Okay.
So there is a video,
Lou data.
Actually we keep saying Lulu from unbox
therapy,
clarify.
Um,
which was like,
it was.
We all went to ces in January,
all in vegas every year in January.
And we just went around the room and
just went,
what phone do you use?
I saw that,
which is what phone is in your pocket
right now?
Take it out,
show us with fung,
use iphone after iphone after iphone.
And there was a couple of pixels in
there,
but every time you ask an iphone person
like,
so why?
And I felt and they're like,
man,
I'm message facetime.
Like that ecosystem is real.
You Louis seemed angry about being more
people weren't using pixels.
Well,
there was a whole thing about,
uh,
just whatever phone.
There's a lot of people who do a
sponsored videos where they'll talk
about a phone as if they use it,
but they don't.
And that was one of the things that at
ces specifically that we kind of had a
laugh with at our studio because you
would think like if you watched
everyone's videos,
like,
oh,
everyone's using a wowway.
Everyone.
I guess while we had a big budget for
ces and they just paid a bunch of people
to make mate 10 pro videos at ces.
So if you,
if you went into watching a video,
like what phone is in everyone's pocket,
I think you would just assume everyone's
got away mate.
Ten pro and nobody did,
which is really funny.
That's dirty.
And then the other thing is about wally.
I hate trashing while away,
but I also kind of left trashing wildly,
uh,
is they have a lot of money to pay
celebrities to tweet ads for awhile way
basically Gaga being one of them.
Right.
And you heard this story,
uh,
so she's tweeted a bunch of wally ads
and I noticed that while she's a brand
ambassador for awhile way tweeting ads,
but how much he loves her Huawei phone.
If you look in the details of the tweet,
it's always via twitter for iphone and
it's like whatever.
She can use an iphone.
I don't care,
but I thought it was funny so I just
tweeted it,
it blew up.
And uh,
I had walway reached out to me like,
how did you find this?
How did you know,
where did you,
is this a mistake?
Like,
could this be a pr?
has this ever malfunction?
I'm like,
no,
this is,
that's how twitter works.
Like you can see the data.
It's clearly an iphone.
And I thought that was Larry.
Larry.
That's my screenshot.
And so,
uh,
not only did Gaga Dope Bloch Gal Godot,
the fucking wonder woman lady.
Yeah.
Wonder woman,
wonder woman,
you fucking fake from an iphone.
It's just funny because look at the
picture.
She blocked you.
Not only did she blocked me,
but way since then has tweeted all they
deleted like her latest tweets and
repost them from an android phone and
she's tweeted from android phone ever
since.
I'll give her respect for that.
They probably told you lose all that
cash.
There's no way she's tweeting.
Like she has a team.
I get it.
But like whoever was on her team
tweeting from an iphone,
like the fact that she blocked you,
those,
those hilarious.
It's gross.
I thought it was.
Do anything.
No,
I didn't.
I think,
well I tagged her in and she probably
was just getting barraged by like people
going,
well you're using an APP like an iphone.
Like why I'm I think event.
It was like a year later she unblocked
me.
It was really funny.
She unblocked me.
Thanks.
That's great.
Well,
I really love her as wonder woman.
And my friend Patty is actually
directing that movie director.
The first one she's directing the second
one too.
So she says,
gals,
a great gal.
Tell Gal I said,
hi Gal.
It's okay.
You got busted.
That's all going to happen.
You're not alone.
You're a 100 percent.
Not a lot.
That happened recently.
Um,
razor the company who made that a razor
phone tweeted their official
announcement tweet of the razor phone to
from an iphone.
How they speakers were excellent in the
first one there.
Even better or they're better than the
second one.
Yeah.
And the better.
The second one has ip 68 or 67?
[inaudible] 67.
I'm pretty sure it's water resistant up
to 30 minutes.
One meter,
something like that.
You can splash it.
I wouldn't go under water with a splash
it,
but 68 is pretty,
pretty damn good.
Yeah.
Sixty eight is the new iphone at 68 is
also the note.
Yes.
Both are 68.
Ten Rs.
Sixty seven.
P three,
pixel three is 68.
I think also.
But the weird thing about Ip
certification is it's just as far as I
know,
the way it works is you just submit the
phone for a certain test and if it
passes then you get to say it's
certified.
And the only difference between Ip 67
and [inaudible] 68 is ip.
60 seven is technically certified for 30
minutes.
One meter an IP 68 is certified for 30
minutes,
one point five meters and the meter.
So sometimes it's two meters,
sometimes it's a little more,
but it's basically just a measurement of
water pressure.
Like if you.
There's different half a meter.
I mean water's heavy but like it didn't
seem that significant to me,
but it's basically just water pressure.
So he splashed the phone a little
harder.
Is it going to break versus an ip?
60 eight phone.
I don't know,
just seems safe to Ip 68 every time,
but it must be a big enough difference
that some of them do it.
Yeah.
Interesting.
Well listen man,
I'm glad we finally get a chance to do
this.
It's really cool.
A lot of fun.
Giant fan of your videos and I really
did.
I mean,
like I said at the beginning,
I really do go you immediately.
I think you do a fantastic job.
You cover all the bases,
you do a great job.
Awesome.
Keep it up that for sure.
Um,
give people the address of your youtube
channel,
your twitter,
instagram,
all that jazz.
It will always be the same five letters.
Mkb Hd.
So youtube.com/Mkbhd.
What does that stand for?
MKB is my initials.
Phd for high definition.
Oh,
alright.
There you go.
Mk be hd on everything.
Everything.
All right.
Thanks brother.
I appreciate it.
No problem.
Bye.
Everybody.