Ladies and Gentlemen,
please welcome Dan Harris and Jeff
Warren.
I don't know why it started off that
way.
Just felt weird.
It was weird to start starting
aesthetics as always,
very odd.
Uh,
welcome.
Welcome Jeffrey.
Nice to meet you.
Thank you.
Dan.
First tank experience.
We didn't talk too much about it.
No,
he just got out of the sensory
deprivation tank.
I don't even know if that's a word.
Dragoon it is a word.
Um,
uh,
you know,
we should tell people how you did it.
You basically taunted me on text,
which was awesome.
It was called hot,
but you were saying that you were scared
of being in there.
Might be scared.
There's nothing to be scared of.
It's just water.
Yeah.
But it's not just water because you're
in this enclosed space.
You can't see anything or hear anything
weird or is in your mind though.
Well that is absolutely correct.
I just happened to have a mind that is
really good at panicking and I've
demonstrated that time and again to
myself and others.
So I was a little wary that you call me
a chicken and I was like,
well,
fuck,
now I have to do this thing.
Uh,
so I did it.
Not without trepidation,
but it was really interesting,
really interesting.
I know you spent so much time exploring
your consciousness and meditating and
just being in your head that I felt like
this is something that you really should
be exposed to you.
You're absolutely right.
And I appreciate it.
I really do.
It was,
it was,
what I realized is I think I need to do
more of it because the brief discussion
we had,
I know we want it to not fully explore
it until we got on the,
on the Pod,
a brief discussion we had afterwards.
One of the things you said is that it's
good to kind of explore your boundaries
when it comes to fear.
This is something actually that my
meditation teacher has said to me before
and it made me realize I think I need to
get in there and start pushing it a
little bit in this,
um,
in the tank,
uh,
because it will help me in lots of areas
of my life because when you don't test
those boundaries,
your life becomes smaller and smaller
and that happens to people with panic.
It will,
it happens.
Just people in general.
And I think it's one of the reasons why
people fall into panic is because they
don't have enough experience with
stressful situations to the point where
they could just relax and just let it
happen.
And that that's one of the things that
I.
One of the reasons why I think martial
arts training is very good for people,
not just for the self defense aspect of
it,
but for the aspect of just dealing with
stressful situations on a regular basis
to the point where you're very
comfortable with them and then you
realize that the consequences of this is
it's not really as bad as you think it
is.
Like most people are terrified a
physical confrontation,
but when you have physical confrontation
on a regular basis,
especially through my favorite,
which is Jujitsu training,
because there's no striking so you don't
get hit in the head,
you're not worried about brain damage or
any of that stuff.
It's just basically grappling.
But that through continual
process of testing yourself and stress
and regular life stresses sort of become
diminished.
I think it's really important.
You know,
I do some of this in my life,
been live news presentation is stressful
and I do that a lot of.
I've covered many war zones,
which is much more stressful,
very stressful.
Um,
but I think there are areas in my life
where I've closed off because of
claustrophobia in particular.
I need Mris for sir.
I jacked up my,
both of my shoulders and my knee and I
haven't been able to deal with them
because I just won't get in a scanner.
Jeff and I were down at actually at
vanderbilt where they wanted to take a
look in my brain in a scanner while I
meditated.
I couldn't do it.
That was a great opportunity.
It's really expensive to get a
neuroscience is to look at your brain
while you meditate.
And I wasn't able to do it because I'm
afraid.
Uh,
and so I think
afraid of it seems like there's no
physical fear,
right?
It's not like there's a dog in the room
that's going to bite you.
Right?
So why not just force yourself to
go through it?
Well,
have you ever expand?
Have you ever had a panic attack?
No.
So it panic attack is,
you know,
we evolved for this fight or flight
instinct where your brain,
you know,
when you're faced with a saber tooth
tiger or whatever with the brain floods
with adrenaline and it is overwhelming.
I made,
it overwhelms all reason.
And you,
uh,
either fight or flight,
in this case,
it's flight a flea and you,
you're,
you can't control your body in many
ways.
And uh,
because I've had so many panic attacks,
I'm primarily the ones that people know
about or the one in particular was on
television on Good Morning America in
2004.
When your brain learns how to do this,
it gets really good at it.
And,
uh,
there's no,
you can't hurl yourself into the,
um,
at least I can't hurl myself into the
Lotus position and meditated away.
It is overwhelming.
And so I can't tell myself a story
about,
hey,
I'm not in physical danger because the
body,
the brain is just
what you're saying is very interesting
about getting really good at it.
There's a term in archery called target
panic and it happens to people.
It happens to target archers.
It happens to bowhunters.
And there's a thing that happens where
you literally can't keep the pin on the
target.
Your,
your brain won't let you and no one
understands,
like the people that are having it while
it's happening,
they don't understand that like,
I can't believe I can't do this,
but your brain gets so used to freaking
out in this moment that literally you no
longer have control and you just,
you try to make the shot go off as quick
as you can.
You'll miss by feet and you just,
you can't.
You understand it.
Like I practice everyday,
like how is this happening?
But if there's this weird overwhelming
sensation of adrenaline and fear and
nerves and the chaos of the moment and
you just slam the trigger and the Arrow
goes flying nowhere near the target and
it's really,
really common to the point where people
seek psychologists and sports trainers
and there's always different methods
that they use to try to keep in,
in a controlled loop system of,
of thought process to try to handle
this.
Probably like you said,
athletic trainers would probably the,
the fighting it and then getting into
your head about it.
It's probably the same as when you get
in a slump in baseball,
you know,
it's,
you're just locked up in yourself and it
takes a long time to get over it.
That is,
you know,
in the tank.
I was thinking a lot about how that has
been just a huge recurring theme in my
life where the ego steps in the thinking
mind,
the mind that won't surrender to what is
actually happening right now comes in.
I get locked up and can't do what I want
to do.
One of the things jeff and I have talked
a lot about in our time together is
dancing as an I can't do it,
can't do it isn't the right way to say
it,
but I've struggled for a long time with
dropping myself consciousness enough so
that I can dance in a way that,
uh,
you know,
I have a three year old around the house
and we'd like to dance.
And even around him I get a little in my
own head about it and I think all of
these things are related.
They must,
they have to be.
It completely makes sense,
but it doesn't make sense to me that you
can't get your brain examined when you
spend so much time examining your brain.
Yeah.
So what's different is,
is this it
interesting time to talk about like the
difference between the brain and the
mind.
So I'm looking at my mind,
um,
and uh,
you know,
the,
the idea of,
first of all,
just because I spend,
I spent the last nine years looking
closely at my mind doesn't mean that
I've conquered all my neuroses and I
don't know that that's on offer.
I think it's a gradual process,
you pointed to something important about
testing those limits and I think
meditation can be really helpful and
testing those limits and I was
meditating most of the time that I was
in the tank and that allowed me bringing
that kind of focused attention to what
was happening,
allow me not to get carried away with
the waves of fear that came in and I was
able to let them pass without hopping
out an embarrassing myself.
Um,
but I don't know that I can magically.
I think it's going to be a process
before I can get in an MRI is.
But what I'm trying to say in a long
way.
Well,
if you have damaged shoulders when you
kind of have to.
I do,
I do.
Do you know you don't,
but you don't even know what's wrong.
I think it's Bursitis,
but I need to get a diagnosis before I
can figure out whether I got to get
surgery or cortisone shot or whatever it
is.
Full range of motion.
Can you put your arms over your head?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
You should try hanging.
Have you ever looked into hang the
southern,
it's just something else crazy.
You're trying to get music from your
shoulders,
a dangerous dude to hang onto a bar and
having your weight.
It's
really important for the shoulder joint
and it's something that very few people
do on a regular basis.
I don't do it on a regular basis.
Most people don't.
And even people that work out don't.
And you're constantly compressing your
shoulder,
compressing and with poor posture,
compressing it with stress,
exercise and your shoulder needs to
expand.
And it also needs this sensation of
hanging your body weight from your
hands.
It's tremendous.
Rear shoulder impingements.
And there's some doctors.
There's one doctor in particular that
explored this.
See if you could find that guy's name,
um,
who stopped doing most shoulder
surgeries and started putting people on
hanging therapy where he just tells
them,
you know,
at the beginning,
just have a bar that's not quite above
your head.
So they could just sort of relax your
knees and you know,
if you can't carry all of your weight in
your hands,
just carry a good percentage of your
weight in your hands.
And try to relax your shoulders and it
releases impingements,
it's stretches that joint out.
The idea is that we came from tree
swinging primates and then as tree swing
primates,
we're constantly doing that and that's
what the shoulder joint is meant to do.
It's meant to articulate in that way we,
you grabbed something swinging and then
not having this full range of motion and
not using it on a regular basis.
Here's this guy's book,
I'm Dr John Kirsch,
John M Kirsch and um,
he came up with this many years ago when
he realized that one of the things that
was messing people up was just they
just,
their joints weren't being put through
the full range of motion.
And that by hanging you could release a
tremendous amount of pain and a
discomfort that a lot of people are
facing.
That makes a ton of sense.
So it seems to me that you guys are
actually saying talking about the same
thing when you're talking about the mind
and you're talking about the body and
talking about impingement and you're
talking about where your mind is
limited.
I think it's the same exact dynamic
actually that's of what's going on.
Like how would you define what an
impingement is in the body?
A blockade,
you know,
like I say,
lack of range of motion,
um,
poor exercise habits.
There's a variety of factors,
ignoring potential injuries and then
restricting your motion to the point
where everything's sort of tightens up.
Muscle tissue in particular.
Um,
joint tissue like around the shoulders
and any,
anytime where you're dealing with range
of motion issues,
you have to stretch and you're,
most people very rarely stretched their
shoulders.
It's just something that we don't do.
And also most people very rarely
strengthened their shoulders.
And I think,
uh,
it's,
it's a very complex joint mean you look
at the way your shoulders articulate.
There's not like there's not anything in
your body that can do this sort of
things and the range of motion that your
shoulders exhibit while carrying weight.
So you think about all the different
things.
Carrying your kid,
picking up a briefcase,
you doing a lot of weird motions with
your shoulders and occasionally develop
little tears.
Those tears.
I started out superficial.
They get larger,
you injure them more,
you're playing,
you don't warm up,
something pops,
you ignore it,
it hurts you for years.
There's a lot of things that we do to
our bodies that would just.
It just compiles and you never handle
it.
You never deal with it.
You don't get that Mri,
you don't get therapy and it just gets
worse and worse to the point where
seeing a lot of people get shoulder
replacements,
so the exact same thing is true.
Everything you just said is true for the
mind.
It's exactly the same.
It's conditioning.
It's repeating the same pattern over and
over.
Having some kind of involuntary response
that gets a little bit deeper,
a little bit deeper,
a little bit deeper each time and it's
like your.
Your mind is the mental body and it has
habits and it develops bad habits and it
develops limited range of motions,
what it can do,
and so we ended up in this really narrow
situation inevitably because we ended up
with a particular set of conditioning
and it starts to limit us.
So you use practices just like a used
physical practices to open up your range
of motion to work through impingements
to have more flexibility.
You do the same for,
you know,
with meditation or with other kind of
mental practices.
I think it's literally the same thing
and you and that there's just this sort
of a isometric nature between the mind
and body.
It's the same kind of stuff.
It completely makes sense and that was
what we were talking about before the
podcast when we're in the hallway about
just dealing with stressful situations
in the tank.
Like if there's a weird freak out that
happens,
like how do you handle it?
Like what,
what do you do?
And I was saying that the more stressful
situations that I experienced,
the more understand what they are and
the more I can relax,
but it's also like a matter of
constantly being exposed to these
stressful situations where there's not a
long break in between doing standup or a
long break in between martial arts
training where to the point where
anxiety can build up and then once you
get into it,
it's almost an.
It's an unusual situation instead of a
usual one.
That's probably why I probably need to
get in the tank reasonably soon.
Yeah,
so say more.
If you don't,
this is your shot,
but if you don't mind,
would you say more about that because
you,
you're able to get in the tank,
not only regularly,
but you'll,
you'll dose yourself with some stuff to
get an attack.
Well,
the,
the thing about stressful situations is
a,
you're always trying to,
once you get comfortable,
you are trying to push them and make
them more stressful.
And this most district,
most stressful way to experience the
tank is either edibles or mushrooms.
Those are the two for me.
Mushroom?
Yeah.
Wow.
Well it's just,
it's basically mushrooms without any of
the distractions of your body and also
distilled.
It's a pure culture.
Yeah.
Pure culture.
Mushrooms and.
But,
but animals can be just as potent in
their edible marijuana is.
You know the difference.
Most people aren't aware that it's a
completely different psychoactive
substance when it's.
When you eat it because it's processed
by your liver and your body produces
something called 11 hydroxy metabolite.
That's four to five times more
psychoactive than thc and it's not
psychoactive in the smoking version.
It's very different.
That's why a lot of people when they eat
brownies so strong.
Yeah.
I'm sure there was a famous nine slash
11 case where uh,
uh,
there's an audio recording of these cops
that took some pop from some kids and
made pot brownies of it and then ate it
and then called the police and called
nine slash 11 on themselves because they
thought they were dying.
But it is one of the greatest audio
recordings of all time,
I think of dying.
I think time is really.
So please send help.
Oh my God.
That's awesome.
What do you do in those moments?
Like do you have,
is that.
I'm just interested because you've had,
from what I can tell,
quite a bit of experience with
psychedelics and also isolation tanks.
What's the right term for sensory
deprivation?
Sensory deprivation tanks.
So what do you do when the little lamp
in your head starts telling you like the
world's ending or slow?
Just let it go.
You have to just relax.
I mean,
I've been there 100 times,
more,
many more than a hundred times really,
but were you really nervous?
Really scared,
but what compounds it is trying to
control it.
What compounds it is trying to wrestle
the moment away from this experience and
just taking control of it and try to
sober yourself up.
No,
fuck this.
I'm going to.
I'm going to,
you know,
I gotta I gotta get getting control of
the situation and the freak out is
really what compounded.
That's where the,
that's the root of all,
you know,
air quotes,
bad trips come from is this desire to
control failure.
Just surrender.
You've got to surrender.
You've got to relax and resistance.
Yeah,
nothing's gonna happen to you.
You're going to be fine.
You're going to feel really crazy and
you're going to that.
It brings up memories from years ago
from weird conversations you might've
had where you acted poorly or weird
choices that you might've made decades
ago or you know,
things that crossed your mind a couple
of days ago that you're embarrassed
about.
There's all these different things
that'll come out that will just your,
your,
your brain,
your mind,
your consciousness wants to explore
these because it feels that you
neglected them or that you put them on
the back burner or the you didn't give
them enough attention.
He didn't give them the attention that
they deserve,
so they're festering and bouncing around
the inside of your mind and I find that
edibles in particular,
it's a very self exploratory experience
and your brain desperately wants to
point out all these areas that it feels
that you might've neglected and that's
terrifying for people and he just
started really freaking out.
Then not to mention the concept of
mortality.
You start thinking about your children's
life and your life and you know,
you get freaked out in there.
Why would you want to do that?
Because I think exploring those things
makes regular life more,
uh,
it makes it more palatable.
It makes it more relaxed.
It makes me,
it gives me a perspective.
It's almost like having a near death
experience on a regular basis.
Well,
you get out of a near death experience
and one of the things that people say is
even if it's a near death experience,
like from a a severe illness or an
injury,
you have a perspective enhancement from
that and you come out of it feeling
like,
well,
I kind of have a new version of life
now.
I understand life now because I
understand the full spectrum.
Before I was operating in this very
comfortable spectrum of everything being
safe and now I realized like,
no,
it doesn't have to be.
Say there can be terrible things where
everything can go wrong,
so appreciate this with much more zeal,
like much more lust for life if
it sounds like what we do in meditation.
Oh my God did.
I was just thinking that.
It sounds like a meditation retreat.
I think they're all connected.
These questions.
Yeah.
You're not even taking.
You don't.
You don't need to ingest anything for
all that stuff to start coming up.
In fact,
there's a kind of classic.
There's a classic progression in a
retreat or an even in a city.
You could say there are these terrains
you move through where first year just
trying to get going and then you're kind
of having all these breakthroughs and
insights and then you can get into this
really challenging stage where it's like
you can't meditate.
All your dark stuff is coming up.
Sometimes I think of it as like,
um,
you're exfoliating the brain.
You know,
you just externally eight exfoliate and
a send.
You hit an air pocket of some old school
shit like your old shame and your rage
and your childish petulance and,
and it all comes bubbling up and you're
inside this atmosphere and then from
inside that atmosphere you're seeing
everything through that filter.
You're now seeing how everything sucks
and your life's a catastrophe or
whatever and that's.
And just like you were saying about the
body and about the psychedelics and
about the tank,
you got to learn to be okay with your
own uncomfortableness.
You've got to learn to be okay to sit
inside this discomfort and say actually
to welcome it,
to say,
well,
this is just part of what's going on
with me right now.
And if you can do that without
resistance,
like you were saying,
without fighting with,
with it,
then it can actually work its way out.
And then you can get into this really
beautiful stage of a practice where
it's,
you know,
the equanimity stage they call it,
where it's just,
you're really open and available to
things.
You're super present.
It's not exotic,
you're not in some peak experience where
you're,
you know,
melting in oneness and have an energy
shooting up your spine.
But neither are you in one of these,
you know,
low experiences,
you're just in the,
it's like the beautiful ordinary,
you know,
and those,
those are the.
And you go round and round and those
cycles.
And then from actually that beautiful
ordinary place that you can have these
breakthroughs.
And that's the kind of classic place
where people have these shifts,
you know,
they like a no self experience
or a pretty interesting.
The phenomenology of it is really cool.
Like there's people described very
specific kinds of things happening that
drop them into this next level of our
next progression of insight.
You could say,
and I don't want to overstate my
meditative capacities,
but,
um,
I had a,
I would say probably like a Jv version
of what you're describing a last month,
just a few weeks ago,
I was on a 10 day silent meditation
retreat and I could see as you described
this,
this progression,
I could see in hindsight that that was
what I went through.
So as your mind starts to settle and you
get more concentrated,
there are fireworks.
You know,
you did the,
you get a lot of sensations in your body
that feel really good.
You're seeing things behind your eyes.
Um,
uh,
just the mind releases a lot of dopamine
and Serotonin in response to the reduced
chatter that can happen when you're more
focused on what's happening right now as
opposed to caught up being caught up in
the,
in,
you know,
our egoic chatter.
And I,
at one point though,
uh,
I,
I hit a stage that's sometimes referred
to as life review where I,
I just,
all the things I'm most ashamed of just
started.
I couldn't avoid him.
I couldn't sleep and it was all just
right there.
I was just thinking about them and then
I started questioning the whole practice
and what am I doing here is just a waste
of time.
And I had a conversation with my teacher
who was a brilliant individual.
I mean you could argue,
um,
some have argued and I would agree,
one of the greatest living meditation
teachers,
his name is Joseph Goldstein and he's
not a,
he doesn't walk around in robes or
anything like that.
He's a Jewish guy from the catskills and
he's in his seventies and he would,
I was staying and he in a cabin and he
would pop in and see me in this cabin
every once in a while because it was
right near his house.
And He,
one day I was kind of complaining a lot
about
the futility of my practice and he said,
surrender.
They said,
you got to surrender.
You've got to just stop.
Just stop getting in your head about are
you doing it right?
And all that stuff.
Just let the practice do its thing.
As Jeff sometimes talks about it,
it's like lead time in nature,
do it's work.
Just trust that the practices we've been
doing this for Millennia,
human beings,
it was a reason for that.
Just do the practice and stop worrying
about it.
And the next set I had was this kind of
equanimity thing that you're talking
about.
Where I could see was two hours long.
I could see everything coming up.
All of my urges,
desires,
thoughts,
physical sensations,
things I was hearing,
things I was seeing was I was very
focused.
But at this point it's all just coming
at me and I'm not reaching for it.
I don't not pushing it away.
The unpleasant stuff.
I'm not trying to push it away.
I'm not trying to grasp onto the
pleasant and it's just.
And it's,
um,
it's like this incredible video game,
right?
Uh,
where you can't.
I sometimes describe meditation.
It's like a video game where you can't
move forward if you want to move
forward.
It's the anti video games and once you
stop wanting,
once you just surrender into this thing
where you're just nonjudgmentally
observing,
whatever comes up in your mind,
whether it's fear,
whether it's planning,
lunch,
whatever it is,
who you just,
you can start to move forward and then
the ego comes in and tells you you are
the best meditator ever do.
And then you fall for that for a minute.
But then you stop falling for that.
Anyway,
at the end of the,
I looked down at my watch and for two
hours had passed.
And,
but then I was fully in the zone of
like,
oh,
this is the end of my next book.
I,
uh,
this is,
I'm enlightened.
This is the best thing ever.
And I've,
I then a couple of hours later start to
realize that I had been telling myself a
story about how amazing I was and how
they should put a plaque up in that
room.
This is where the,
the best meditation sit ever happened.
And,
uh,
the next meditation I went to,
the next time I tried to meditate,
it was as if I'd never meditated before.
And I just like,
I didn't know what I was doing anymore
and it all collapsed.
Wow,
there's so much there.
Um,
there's an experience that you have in
the tank where you,
you try to let go and you let go and
relax and then you realize,
no,
you just,
there's one layer of relaxation.
Totally.
But they're stacked on top of each
other.
There's infinite layers.
And as you get deeper and deeper into
these layers of relaxation,
you hit another layer and you go,
okay,
now this is relaxing.
And then,
you know,
there's way more than this,
there's way more to this.
And the more you think about the fact
that,
oh,
now I'm on a new level,
relaxation will now you're not.
Now you're probably two or three levels
above where you were before you
addressed it.
That's the one you were talking to him.
It just seemed like the layers of the
onion and just you have to peel those
layers and you're blowing my mind.
This is all the shit that I always talk
about.
It's exactly you're describing.
Exactly.
It's the layers of the onion.
You,
it's like you,
you're,
you're holding this fist and you don't
even realize you're holding this fist.
You're walking around going,
yeah,
everything's fine,
but you're holding this fist and then
you realize you're holding on so tight
and the need first.
You don't even know how to open.
The fist has been closed the whole time.
At some point without.
You have to.
The way you open it is not trying to
open it.
You have to just be so okay with the
fact that you had this tight fist here
and eventually it just opens up itself
and then you think you're free.
And I think if I'd describe it as like
walk in the onion,
you know,
it's like you're walking on top of the
annuity and unique.
It's imagined the planet is an onion.
You're walking and you're turning the
onion as you walk and you got the huge
open air all around you that the
university feel like you're free,
but very slowly you're sinking into the
onion is a layer of tension,
is kind of appearing or coagulation.
That starts to kind of coagulate in your
experience and eventually realized that
there's this layer of tension here and
you're not free.
You're inside this thing.
Then you have to figure out how to
exfoliate that or let that go and it
just keeps going on because it's turtles
all the way down.
It's like it's onion layer after onion
layer and every time you get into a new
place of freedom,
the fact and the act of living is
creating more coagulation.
It's creating more just natural
frictions and things that are coming up
so it's not just that you're going
through.
So the the progress of insight,
the progress that they call purification
in Buddhism is a.
is a process of kind of working through
your conditioning but also
simultaneously learning to work through
the new conditioning that's accreting by
virtue of just being a human being and
that's,
that's the game.
And that's why a lot of people say there
is no end to it.
You don't get to some final liberation
because just the act of living is
creating its own blind spots.
You know?
So you've got different people in
different camps who argue different
things about what real freedom looks
like,
but that,
that to me seems the most realistic,
you know,
at least it's the one that at that fits
with my experience and it describes
exactly how you describe it and you
know,
the two are,
they really line up.
I think most of us are operating on
momentum and I think you,
you learn things as a child and those
become,
you know,
whatever your personality is,
the way with whatever thought process
you sort of have carved into your mind
like the grooves and patterns that you
normally find yourself thinking in.
And I equate it to a lot to martial arts
training.
Like I,
I used to teach martial arts for a
living.
One of the things that I've found
incredibly difficult was to reteach
people.
It was way easier to teach a person with
no training than it was to reteach
someone with poor training.
So when someone has poor training,
they have these paths carved in their
movements and their thought process and
when they're in a situation they fall
back on those patterns.
And it's extremely difficult to get
people out of that and learned to do
things correctly.
But if you can teach them how to do
things correctly from the beginning,
then they naturally grow.
Like this is the stressful situation.
Here comes the problem.
Here's the issue.
What's the technique?
Now you know it and it's locked into
your brain.
You know the right pathway,
whether as like don't go to the
technique you've been using all your
life.
Now use a new technique and and remember
to manage that situation under pressure.
I think that's how most of us are
handling our lives.
We're handling our lives with poor
techniques and poor management skills
and and these pads that are carved in
that or infant tile and that are
essentially like the the remanence and
the echoes of when you were a teenager
or even younger than that,
and then maybe your parents and the
learned behavior that you see watching
them and maybe they weren't so good at
managing life either,
but these patterns are carved into your
brain and you find comfort in them
because you know where they're going to
slide right into them.
And then as an adult,
you start trying to remap your
consciousness and remap patterns,
and in doing that it's very difficult to
sort of re think how you think.
I mean,
I think what you're pointing to here is
close to the,
what has become,
for me,
the animating insight of my whole side
hustle as a meditation proponent,
which is that the mind is trainable.
Now we are you,
you describe,
I think very accurately the ruts in
which many of us find ourselves or don't
even know we're in.
But the good news is that there are ways
to retrain the mind week.
And I didn't know that until my late
thirties when I started reading books
about Buddhism and all the things we
want the most calm,
patience,
compassion,
generosity,
happiness,
whatever that means.
These are,
these aren't factory settings,
non negotiable factory settings.
These are skills that can be trained
that you can take responsibility for
just the way you take responsibility for
your body in the gym.
And there are lots of ways to train
them.
We,
you know,
Jeff and I obviously talk a lot about
meditation,
but,
uh,
you're,
you've talked about other ways to do it
as well from martial arts too,
and there's now been a lot of,
there's a growing body of research about
psychedelics as well.
I,
uh,
it was obvious to me from being in the
isolation from the sensory deprivation
tank that,
that is a training too.
There are lots of ways to get at it,
but the fundamental good news is you
aren't stuck with the patterns that are
making you miserable.
Yeah,
you're not,
you're definitely not stuck.
And,
um,
I think that all of these things are
related and I think that even running,
even a exercise,
yoga in particular,
all these things that are difficult when
you do these difficult things,
you're stressing your mind or I should
say,
don't be stressing your mind,
exercising your mind and exercising your
body's ability to manage intense
situations like yoga poses a very
intense,
especially hot yoga.
It's hard.
It's very difficult to very testing and
in doing so you,
you lessen the stress of regular life.
Exactly.
You're,
you're,
you're tied up in a reef knot,
you know,
you can be economists with this
ridiculous pose where you're shaking
with exertion than how much more
economists can you be.
How much more present and open can you
be in your life.
It's the same thing.
Do you think most people
bill how to translate what they're
learning in something like.
So for me that was what broke through
about meditation was it was so obvious
how to translate what I was learning
with my eyes closed to my life.
Whereas all the other things,
you know,
I've been,
I had been running since I was in my
teens and,
and while I,
it,
it's absolutely good at staving off
depression,
which I've dealt with for a long time
and,
uh,
and making me feel just generally fit.
Uh,
I don't know that I was explicitly
taking the lessons of running or any of
the other things that many people do
that they sometimes refer to as their
quote unquote meditation now.
And applying it to my life.
The way was against so obvious.
Well,
it seemed like the obvious aspects of
meditation are conscious.
Like you're,
you're looking for these solutions,
whereas with running,
you might be getting them without being
conscious of them or at least getting
some of the benefits of it without being
conscious,
but those benefits would certainly be
enhanced with a different perspective
going into the running,
like going into the running with the
thought process of testing your
consciousness to endure this a very
difficult thing in front of you like
hill running in particular.
Um,
there's,
there's something about anything that's
like very uniquely physically stressful
like that which requires the mind to
stay the course.
And in doing so,
especially in the other end,
once you come out of it,
there's this great feeling of euphoria
and peace and it's not just a physical
release of energy,
but it's also an understanding that the
brain has exercised the demons that are
responsible for the anxiety while you're
overcoming this stressful
and the limits you told yourself were
there.
It's funny,
you know,
my,
my wife and I've been doing a lot of
soul cycle,
which I know my wife does it too,
but you don't,
you don't do it with her.
But I,
I have other shit to do because I'm a
better,
I'm a better husband and Joe Rogan,
uh,
so although in my,
she's,
she's out in the green room right now
raging against me because she's,
she's angry because that I'm not at soul
cycle right now that I haven't said what
I'm about to say,
which is that I'm the one who got her
into it,
so,
so in her defense.
So,
but they are often giving these,
the teachers are often giving these
really sort of affirmations from the
front of the room.
And uh,
my traditional approach to those is to
completely ignore them as incredibly and
irretrievably annoying.
And however,
what they're saying is what you're
saying,
what they're saying is pedal through
your resistance,
your telling yourself a story that you
can't turn the knob up to the right
right now,
the resistance knob to the right right
now,
and stay on the beat and sprint and do
all the Greek.
You're telling yourself a story.
You can't do it,
but you actually can do it.
Try it.
Try it to get over the limiting stories
you're telling yourself.
And in fact,
yesterday morning when we did soul
cycle,
that guy at the end said something I
normally would have ignored,
which was next time somebody proposes
something to you that you tell yourself
you don't want to do,
do it.
Hence the sensory deprivation tank.
Direct link to what he said to my being
willing to do it.
So there's some there,
there.
Yeah.
There's something about things like soul
cycle,
even if the right.
Even if the motivational speech rings
true,
you want to like,
fuck,
this
is the problem with spiritual teachers,
right?
It's a problem with somebody who's,
or anybody who walks around that it has
the answer.
And that's.
And it's an.
And often the answer can be this sort of
pollyanna ish,
a Disney channel thing that may,
maybe it probably is true on some way,
but it's just the delivery of that kind
of certainty.
That's so annoying.
I
say that my,
my,
uh,
you know,
there are millions of meditation books.
The only thing new about the books that
I write is that I add the word fuck a
lot.
And,
and,
and that is a,
uh,
just a new way to talk about this stuff
because our tendency,
or at least guys like us,
I think where people like us,
men and women like us,
is to some people when you hear,
when you hear this kind of affirmation
uttered,
you reflectively rejected,
which is again normal,
but if you can just say it to people and
fresh language,
it's the reason why these things are
cliched,
is because they're true and they become
cliche through sort of mindless
repetition.
But if you can find new ways to
articulate them,
they can land.
I think also whether it's your book on
meditation or anybody,
just life experiences that they're,
they're writing down.
We gather information from other
people's life experiences in a very
unique way.
And that's one of the reasons why people
really enjoy autobiographies.
It's one of the reasons why people
really enjoy,
just truly reflective introspective
thinking because we,
we can pick out little gems in our self.
So even though you might be talking in
your meditation book about things that
other people have talked about in
meditation books,
you're talking about it from your unique
personal experience and when someone
reads that or here's you say it,
you get something tangible out of that.
Well,
we,
we talk a lot about,
um,
so my favorite comedian of all time,
other than Joe Rogan is Dave Chappelle.
And you,
uh,
you came on my radar screen because you
were on a show,
uh,
the Chappelle show back in the and the
fear factor bit he did years and years
ago,
which was one of the funniest things
I've ever seen a and Chappelle in one of
the seasons.
Jeff and I were talking about this last
night as a matter of fact,
talked about,
um,
how he was doing one of these outtake
episodes.
I can't remember which season was in
because they only did two and a half.
He was doing an outtake episode and at
the beginning he did a riff about how
back in the day African American
communities never got the good part of
the pig to eat.
The white people.
Got the good parts of the pig,
so,
uh,
the African Americans had to figure out
how to make good food out of snout and
that's he said what this episode is
going to be,
we're going to take the snout and we're
going to make good stuff out of it.
And my approach to writing books about
meditation is the snout is the good
stuff.
The embarrassing shit that happens to
you when you were,
when you're meditating is the good
stuff.
It is what will allow people to see what
the practice does for you.
So I take the worst,
most embarrassing stuff that happens and
talk about it because that is gives you
a front row seat at what training the
mind actually looks like.
And if you can't have a sense of humor
about how crazy you are,
you are truly fucked.
I think that those uncomfortable moments
are so important for other people to
hear about it.
Yes,
yes,
absolutely.
We need to know we're not alone.
Yes.
All our madness.
What was it like on the set when you
were working with Dave Chappelle?
It was great.
Well,
I've known Dan for a long time.
I was actually on the very first episode
we by chance I was walking through New
York and I saw dave and this was before
the show had.
Even Beth.
I didn't even know it existed,
but I rented a Bobcat Goldthwait who's
there and I'm like,
what's up man?
What are you guys do?
And he's like,
he goes,
oh,
hey joe,
we're doing a TV sketch man,
you want to be in on it?
And I go,
I only have like 20 minutes.
I'm on my way to a meeting.
He goes,
here he goes,
we're handing out Britain's for New York
boobs,
and he,
I had a box,
so it's me and him walking through
Manhattan and he's got this crazy fake
mustache on and he's like,
you've got the best New York boobs,
and he would give someone like a ribbon
for heaven,
New York boobs.
And it was really silly but fun.
And so I was like,
well,
Dave's got a show.
And then turns out it's the greatest
sketch show in the history of the world.
And a year later he calls me up again
and asked me to do this thing for.
They wanted to do a fear factor sketch
with tyrone Brigham's.
Yeah.
So that's me and him.
A fresh faced Joe Rogan and Dave
Chappelle.
The.
Yeah.
Well this is.
What year is it?
Three.
Four.
Yeah.
I think it's before that.
Is it.
I want to say it's 2002 maybe.
Yeah.
Because,
uh,
I wasn't even doing the mantra back then
and I was doing that in 2003.
So I think it's 2002.
The fear factor bit is one of my
favorite season two,
if I recall.
I think so,
yeah.
And is really one of the,
at one of the funniest bits in a show
that is,
I would argue perhaps the greatest
television show of all time.
I think it's the greatest sketch comedy
show of all time.
Something bigger.
It's hard to say that though,
because if you boiled down a lot of the
all time great shows,
like in living color or some of the
other ones,
boy,
they had so many seasons.
If you boiled them down to two seasons,
maybe there will be some,
but he's got some sketches that worst
just groundbreaking,
like the black white supremacist who was
blind.
Yeah.
What about.
I was watching last night because jeff
and I were talking about Chicago last
night,
so on the car ride home from this event
we did together,
I was watching black Bush,
which was another I think unbelievably,
which released season two where he plays
George w dot Bush,
his version of Georgia and all the
rationales for going into the war in
Iraq and it's unbelievably funny.
Yeah,
he's a genius.
He's a real comedy genius,
but also a guy who's.
You wouldn't get it if you just sort of
see him do standup,
but he's deeply introspective,
like very intensely.
Well thought out.
You know he's not.
He's not a surface guy by any stretch of
the imagination.
I love them.
I really do.
I keep thinking that show's going to
come back at some point.
I'm sure
his is.
Netflix specials are better.
I've seen him unfucked with in.
Unless Netflix let them do a Chappelle
show where they just left him alone.
Then it will be genius,
but that was the problem in season three
set.
I know it was.
He was.
They were telling him what to say.
They were telling them there is so much
money involved that they were trying to
get him to slightly watered down his
content in order to make it more
palatable for advertisers.
They were asking him,
does not say the n word.
There was a lot of behind the scenes
nonsense that I dealt with the exact
same administration and comedy central,
so I'm well aware of how silly they were
about certain things.
They had these corporate ideas and this
was also right around the same time
Janet Jackson's nipple popped out there
in the street ball,
which fucking oddly enough,
changed everything.
People started freaking out about
content because of a nipple.
Yeah,
it was.
It was very.
It was a very weird time for television
and in their defense what they do is
they're producers.
They're not.
They're not creative people.
They're executives and they didn't know
how to handle how to keep it funny and
keep it free and loose,
but also figuring out a way to make it
fit into what their corporate structure
is of what's acceptable and not
acceptable for advertising.
So it was just a clusterfuck of control
and neediness and too many cooks in the
kitchen and people's ego where there's a
lot of people that just want it to
affect the show just so that they can
put their greasy fingerprints on it and
that's a really common thing with
television that that ego aspect of,
you know,
these different people who are high up
on the food chain in the executive world
wanting to put their stamp on a show and
then talking openly about putting their
stamp.
Well,
that was my idea.
I thought it was really important.
We get dave out there like that and it
for him.
He was like,
fuck this,
I'm going to Africa for a couple months
and I'm just going to come back and
quit.
And everybody was like,
whoa.
But that's who David is.
I mean,
that's,
that's.
There's not a lot of people that walk
away from $50,
million dollars,
but he's one of them.
He's just like,
I don't need to do this.
I could.
I could do something else.
I just do stand up,
and he in fact we even weirder,
he didn't do standup for a long time and
when he did it,
he did it for free.
He would just show up places like he
would show up places with a speaker and
plug it into a microphone and a park in
Seattle and just start doing standup.
There was a lot of stories about like
people would just gather around hundreds
of people and he would just be doing
standup for these random people and they
were like,
what's going on?
How does a guy get to be like that?
Just be yourself.
That's who he is.
But was that you think,
is that something.
I mean because that sounds to me like
somebody who had a practice or something
or like or an inner compass that was
smoked a lot of weed that maybe that was
part of it.
He smokes weed all day.
I mean if you watch this new netflix
specially smoking a vape pen through the
entire special to the point where I
watched it in like 40 minutes of the
special.
I started getting anxiety.
I'm like,
how high are you right now,
man?
When you said you might,
will you hide your Netflix?
But yeah.
Yeah,
because you said at the beginning you
were baked and I was like,
is that a bit or is it.
No,
I was high but I didn't keep getting
high through this special.
Like Dave keeps hitting that vape pen
and I don't know how strong that vape
pen is,
but he's like seven,
eight,
nine,
10 hits deep in 40 minutes in.
I'm like,
Yo,
this kid gets super slippery.
Yeah.
He just kept pulling out this vape pen.
I mean it was literally with him through
the entire set in his hand.
That's increasing the degree of
difficulty to this that I would not want
to explore.
That's what an isolation tank.
Yeah,
exactly.
That's a.
But it also,
it's freeing in a way because you're so
comfortable that experience of like
giving into the,
to the marijuana,
like giving into the,
the,
the thc where you just sort of like
float away on it and don't question it.
Yeah.
But as you were high backstage getting
ready to do your netflix special and I
would imagine that's a pretty stressful
environment because they're taping this
thing.
It's going to be your special.
It's a big deal.
Did you not have a moment of like,
Holy Shit I shouldn't have,
I shouldn't have smoked?
No,
no,
no.
It's fun.
It's just like,
this is like an incredibly privileged
position.
I find myself in like this whole thing
is amazing.
So crazy wild ride.
So I'm about to do the wildest part of
the wild ride film a Netflix special and
uh,
just,
just joy,
just taking it all in and then going.
This is so like,
all the hard work is done.
The materials in place,
the writing has been done,
the rehearsals been done,
has been hundreds and hundreds of sets.
Everything's tightened up and all the
notes are in place.
And I've run it 100 times.
And by the time you saw the film,
the Netflix special,
it was mostly the fourth show of for
taping.
So I've already taped three taping so
I've already got it in the can.
So there's.
Most of the pressure is off so it's just
like a regular show on.
Okay.
Yeah.
So it's just just happiness.
Just let it,
let it happen.
Now you seem happy while watching it.
It was fun.
Yeah,
it's a good time.
But it's one of those weird things where
you know,
stand up,
live standup is,
is weird itself because you know you're
dealing with all these factors,
the people's consciousness.
You're,
you're trying to manage your material as
well as bring them in and make sure that
your timing is right and everything is
smooth.
And then on top of that there's the
filming aspect of it.
Like this will be locked in and recorded
forever.
Like this is,
this is going to go online and then
people will have copies of it and then
it will be.
This is,
this is your material,
this is your thought process.
Do you have this iron down?
Do you have this edited and parsed and
sectioned and have you thoroughly
examined?
Have you used
the correct economy of words?
Have you.
Have you boiled it down into the best
possible version of itself?
So funny with standup because you watch
it as a as A.
Because I've never done standup.
You watch it as a consumer.
It looks casual,
it looks off the cuff,
it has enormous amount of work that goes
into it,
but it's both casual and off the cuff
and incredibly well thought out and
rehearsed and it has to be both of those
things but don't you have to.
So you prepare like crazy,
you know you got that,
but then when you're actually there,
isn't there a certain amount of having
to let go and try and be actually
responsive to what's happening in the
audience to a.
That must be the skill.
It's like you do the preparation so you
can almost let go of.
Yeah,
this both,
you know,
like you have to be prepared but you
also have to be loose and you have to be
completely engrossed in what you're
talking about,
but also in the moment.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
It's tricky,
but the bottom line is when it's done
it's worth it.
Like all the weirdness of like when you
get it done or something like triggered.
When it was done,
I finished it.
I was like,
I did it.
Like this is what I wanted to do.
Like I wanted to,
I wanted to accurately represent a real
live standup comedy set that feels like
any other set that you could catch me in
San Francisco on a Saturday night.
And so it was that.
So it's all worth it.
Yeah,
it felt like that.
Yeah.
So then I waited about a year,
then I start doing it again and now I'm
in the process.
A couple more months I'll do it again
now.
It sounds a lot like actually the
experience of teaching you're teaching
meditation sort of like because you got
to be,
you kind of got to know you have to have
experienced and sort of know your stuff,
but the other hand you actually got to
be super open to exactly what's coming
up and what someone's describing or
what's happening and you've got to be.
And so if you.
If you try to bear down too hard on
that,
then you're just going to be repeating
your own shit back again.
So can you be a.
had that total openness to actually see
what it is that someone is saying and
not have not have your.
Put your projections on it,
but you have to have also done your
homework in a way and it's just having
that balance and then there's that
really this beautiful thing where you're
kind of.
You get into flow when you're kind of in
the zone and it just like you hardly
even know the words are coming out or
responses happening and it's not.
It's not remotely deliberate at all,
but it's the right thing in that moment
or the right thing that someone needed
to hear or you needed to hear and it
feels incredible.
It feels like it feels effortless,
but it's the effortlessness that comes
out of preparedness.
Previous effort.
Yeah.
You have to have both.
You can't just wing it,
right?
You have to be prepared,
but you also have to be able to just be
flexible in the moment and to be able to
ride the.
It comes back to the word that we
started with his surrender.
Yeah,
and I noticed this a lot because I do a
lot of traveling around and giving
speeches and I'm always about meditation
and I'll have my little shtick that I
do,
but then I will open it up for questions
and actually the same thing is true for
when I'm live on good morning America.
You know where I have to.
If I'm in my head,
if I'm thinking about what I should say
or how things should go,
I make the worst mistakes.
If I can get myself to surrender and
just be there.
I've been playing with that a little bit
even in the course of this discussion,
uh,
as a big podcast.
Don't screw it up.
Say that.
Don't say that they'll do the dumb thing
that,
you know,
whatever,
blah,
blah.
Actually,
if I can just like,
let all of that chatter go away,
play itself out.
Then you have a better conversation.
Then you say the thing that you couldn't
have planned.
Yeah,
that is the art of the podcast is the
art of conversation in general is to get
out of your own way and to be able to
also at the same time find the right
words,
articulate the right thoughts,
figuring out the right way to the piece,
the sentences together.
So it's both entertaining and engaging
but also rings true and there's not a,
an,
a,
an air of bullshit to it or a ego to it
or you know,
because people can.
There's a unique thing about a
conversation,
especially with people interacting with
each other that people they tune in to
like.
And I tune into it like if I listen to
certain conversations with people that I
find awkward and I'm like,
well,
what is uncomfortable about this?
What is this weird?
And see it.
A lot of times it boils down to like one
person trying to be too much in control.
Absolutely that.
Yeah.
Or yeah,
personally I'm usually that person.
Yeah,
everybody is.
And you can tell when you're hanging out
with that person because it's like
there's this grippiness or,
or when I have that,
it's like your study,
fearful usually word and you're,
you're trying to hold onto the narrative
and it just creates this unnatural nus.
Yeah.
And then everyone's got a little bit,
it feels a little bit weird and then
someone's trying to overcompensate with
someone over here and it just wrecks the
whole flow of it.
You know,
when I first started reading a little
bit about that
Zen Buddhism,
which one of the flavors of.
They talk a lot about spontaneity.
Yeah.
And it didn't quite zen bounced.
I didn't quite get that,
but this is what we're talking about
actually.
If they also use this word freshness,
that if you can get rid of the stale
planned canned stuff and just touch in
on what's happening right now,
which is fresh,
uh,
than the spontaneity arises.
Can I?
There's um,
uh,
so I got a teacher,
this Guy Shin Zen young,
who I think is the,
the fucking bomb.
You've got to get them on.
This is amazing.
He is incredible.
He is truly amazing.
He's a super nerd consciousness and he
is really articulate about the dynamics
and he's trained a lot within the zen
tradition but also in kind of old school
theravada like the more strict sue's
name,
s h I,
z e and Canadian,
sorry,
z e and Shin Zen young.
And he actually likes Ms Dot Martial
Arts and he guides people while watching
mixed martial arts in his undershirt.
And he's the,
he's the wicked too.
Yeah,
I,
I can fully that.
Yeah.
So
he,
uh,
but he talks a lot about something
called the zen bounce because he's,
he's interested in how,
like,
how,
you know,
how do these different practices from
different traditions work?
Like how do they,
what is the way in which they for you or
they reduce your suffering and and
because they can look so different on
paper or actually inexperienced,
so you might have one kind of meditation
tradition.
It's all about just sitting with your
eyes closed,
not moving all about that kind of
stoicism and then you when you do move,
it's very slow and deliberate and you
got to be mindful and all that stuff,
but then you have other traditions like
within a certain kinds of schools where
you're actually.
If you it's frenetic.
It's like go,
go,
go all the time.
You're moving fast.
You're like unwrapping your shit and you
put your shit back together and you're
eating your food in a particular kind of
way and you got to get to this thing
over here and you gotta get this thing
over here and then you got to sit next
to stop on a dime.
And what they're doing is they're
deliberately shaking things up there.
Deliberately creating all this agitated
and energy to teach you how to ride the
energy to teach you how to be calm
enough in the center that you can add
that energy turns into spontaneity,
turns into creativity,
turns into genuine being available in
the moment.
This as opposed to being stuck in some
way.
That's what's getting trained.
And when you see these guys from those
monasteries are from those traditions
who are really,
who practice a lot,
they've got this bouncy available,
turn on a dime,
do this,
you know,
it's like they're just available to
what's going on because they've trained
that quality in their experience.
It's gotten out of their own way.
They've gotten out of their own way.
I mean,
and they would,
I mean Shin Zahn when you talked to how
he is,
he,
you know,
I've had like hundreds of hours of
discussions where I'll call him up,
I'll be like.
And He,
the best thing about him is he'll answer
the phone if he's ready to talk,
he's ready to serve,
you know,
whatever you got going on.
I'll be like a column in the morning,
Shins in.
So what's going on right now?
What's your experience of consciousness?
And he basically describes,
you know,
it's like he's just there and it's like
he's sort of part of this upwelling of
the world and it's all kind of vibrating
up through him.
He has no center,
you know,
he asked him where his center.
He experiences the center of himself.
Sometimes it's over here,
sometimes it's over on the right and
he's just like,
yeah,
it's just,
it's all reality.
Just this free flow of reality that he's
just responding to now and then.
And then he'll tell me this is the shit
that would blow my mind.
Cause you're like,
okay,
that sounds awesome.
But he's like,
no,
there's challenges for him.
The challenge is,
is taking condition seriously,
taking condition seriously.
He has to convince himself that went to,
you know,
that the stakes are high enough that he
should work on this thing or that.
Yeah,
I guess I should go to the way that bus.
You know,
it's like,
I mean he will because his instincts
kick in,
but it's like he's so in the uncondition
that,
you know,
he,
his danger is just becoming one of those
dudes sitting on a mountain and not
doing anything but the world is fucked
and it needs people like him who can
help us out.
So he,
he,
and he's very inspired to,
to,
to try to do his best to be a great
meditation teacher.
But that's his battle.
He's no longer so most practitioners,
their battle is trying to get to taste
that more unconditioned quality,
the spontaneous,
that free the yourself as just a
process.
Uh,
his,
the other direction.
He's gone so far into that now he's
trying to remember what it was like to
be a human being.
He's more like a cosmic rock,
like there's the vibrating into infinity
all the time,
which is great for stress but not so
great for maybe other things.
Very interesting.
Yeah.
So he's just been doing this for so long
that she is very high level of.
He's another Jewish guy from this case,
from Los Angeles.
He was born in the forties or fifties,
Eisenhower,
America,
and he basically was way into Japan,
Japanese culture,
learn Japanese as a teenager.
I went to Japanese school and then went
to Japan when he was like 19 or 20 and
decided he wanted to study these.
Uh,
some of the Zen practitioners eventually
got in with a,
uh,
what's called the Japanese have Adrianna
school.
So it's sort of a particular school of
Buddhism.
Started training with them and then that
was never finished.
He was getting a phd program.
Do hardcore stuff like that.
You have an ice baths and things like
that?
Yeah,
yeah.
I mean,
so it's all what we're talking about,
building up resilience building and back
when emily,
can you sit in these seriously?
I mean they do the in Japan they do the
thing called,
he'll talk about this.
The marathon monks were basically these
guys sit for like no joke for days on
end days not going to the bathroom,
not moving,
not eating,
not drinking water.
I mean,
it's hard to imagine how it would even
be possible,
but apparently it's a televised event on
in Japan.
Like they do these long walks and then
they do these sets and these guys,
it's all about what shinzen would say.
It's about recycling the reaction,
so it's all about your hub,
these responses in your body,
you're feeling uncomfortable,
you're feeling hungry,
you're feeling this stuff,
but if you can bring enough equity and
openness to those sensations,
then they just.
And I had this happen to me thousands of
times meditating or the sensation just
boils off.
It just goes from being pain in your
need to just vibrating,
feels like maggots squirming and then it
just wouldn't,
it just.
And it's all about how,
how completely present can you be.
You can metabolize anything stuck and
guess what?
You can metabolize stuck physical stuff
too.
So if you put your attention on a knot
in the back of your,
you know,
in the back of your shoulder or
something.
I've had to experience in meditation
where I'm just feeling this tension in
my body and I just hold my attention
there long enough and this sort of,
oh,
in this open way,
not trying to make a change.
Just curious about it.
Looking at it.
I've had the experience of knots,
like desolving were like an actual
impingement or a physical thing that
seemed to change.
Now that's really weird because then you
realize,
wow,
look the mind,
the mind and body,
it's all part of one process,
you know,
and at part of what was keeping that
tension,
there wasn't just the problem in the
muscle.
There was some part of me that was
keeping it there.
There was some way in which I was
holding onto it a little bit,
like holding my breath a bit,
you know,
or like when you said about releasing
layers of tension and you sit down on a
meditation cushion and you think you're
relaxed and you realize you're actually
kind of uptight and you're like,
and then you let go of that and then you
and you said a little bit more than you
realize there's another layer of tension
and you can just let go and let go and
let go.
And it just seems to go on and on and
on.
And it's like,
that can be.
I mean there's some.
I know another teacher only teaches is
lying down.
She teaches people,
Reggie Ray,
go to a Dota,
go to his meditation,
resets.
You just,
you're laying on the ground.
You're not doing anything.
You could fall asleep,
doesn't matter for a month.
He just laying on the ground and he's
teaching you how to actually land on the
ground.
You could spend a week,
two weeks learning how to actually lay
on the ground.
You think you're laying on the ground
where you're still a little bit tense.
You're still a little bit holding
yourself up in some way and it's like
you're just letting go of those layers
and letting go of those layers until
you're just like a pool.
It's funny because everyone,
we all know that we need conscious
awareness.
We need the to be here and present,
but also that thinking of conscious
awareness and the control that we try to
enact on our environment and all the
different ways that the ego forces us to
think and pushes us and nudges us.
He really is about getting out of your
own way.
In a lot of ways,
like it's a paradox to because the only
way to truly surrender to reality is to
not fucking care.
It's absolutely true,
but,
and that's what's going to free you up
to be the most effective in your caring.
You cannot get around that head fuck
because it is.
Absolutely.
That is absolutely true.
You know,
so we would,
I mean this is the thing that people
really struggle with because a lot of
people here will hear everything you
just said and you know,
and all this stuff about Shinzen,
you know,
not caring and think,
okay,
if I meditate,
well I'm going to be ineffective.
I'm not going to be able to do it.
But that's what I'm saying is the
paradox.
It's like the person who's most
effective as the person who gives up
needing to be effective.
It's like you because that's how you
free up all the energy.
It's like if you're trying to control
everything all the time,
you're going to be really limited in
what you can actually do.
If you just let go and let things be as
they are,
you're kind of like,
it's like you're conserving all this
deep,
deep well of energy that's there and
then when you really do need to make a
move because it does fucking matter,
then you've got the energy to act and
you act in a way that's probably more
effective because it's less distorted,
so it's just skillful use of energy and
that's actually,
that's what I've learned from practice
and even from getting older because I'm
46 now and I don't have the energy I
used to have.
It's like choosing your battles and
didn't seem like now I'm like,
that seems really tiring.
I'm not going to do that.
I'm going to actually just sit here and
chill and relax so I'll have the energy
to do what I need to do when I need to
do it.
That's kind of that maturity is sort of,
I think a big part of the.
The meditative like learning.
Well,
so it's so interesting what you're
talking about as well as it relates to
like how when you're on good morning
America,
like just sort of figuring out a way to
just be in the moment and guide the
conversation,
but don't think too much about what
you're saying,
but say the
right things and have poignant things
and good questions and being able to
engage but not being too conscious of
how it sounds or what you're trying to
achieve by your words or the image that
you're trying to portray.
It's,
it's.
There's so many parallels that would
exist in standup comedy of that exist in
podcasting.
They exist in martial arts like when
you're doing martial arts.
That's a big part of being able to train
effectively is to focus almost entirely
on the movements themselves.
To have them trained into a way where
there a pathway that you can almost
observe like you.
You're the observer and a passenger.
As much as you're the driver of the
experience that it's all just sort of
taking place and when you start tweaking
and freaking out about it,
that's when everything tightens up and
that's when you start to run into all
these real issues with training.
Well,
that's why I find basic.
You know,
we've talked a lot about.
Jeff has talked as he always does,
very beautifully about deep end of the
pool,
you know,
mysticism and highly attained
meditators,
but the,
the,
the nuts and bolts,
basic application of beginners,
mindfulness meditation,
which Jeff and I talk about is what
allows you to get out of your own way.
Because saying to people,
Hey,
get out of your own way.
Get Out of your head is a very
frustrating thing to hear because you're
like,
how the hell do I do so?
But the basic,
the basic move of,
of what?
Of of beginner meditation,
which is to sit with your eyes closed.
Bring your full attention to the feeling
of your breath coming in and going out,
and then as soon as you try to do this,
your mind is going to go bonkers.
You're going to start thinking about,
you know,
what's for lunch,
where do I need a haircut,
where did dribbles run wild,
blah,
and the whole game is just to notice
when you've become distracted in a
nonjudgmental,
friendly way.
Oh yeah,
that's anger.
That's random thoughts,
whatever.
Let it go.
Go back to the breath over and over and
over ad Infinitum,
and that basic bicep curl for your brain
allows you to have a less hostile
relationship to your inner chaos,
allows you to see it clearly,
and that is the mechanism by which all
have for me,
at least by which all of the things
we're talking about here.
You're not freaking out on live
television being able to survive in a
sensory deprivation tank when you think
Joe Rogan my judge you for freaking out
and jumping out all that stuff.
It allows you to see the chatter arise.
This basic move that we're doing in
meditation,
which is just sitting back and allowing
all of this stuff to come up without
trying to grab it or push it away,
can help you in the things that we're
talking about here.
Martial arts,
standup comedy,
all of the things.
So,
uh,
can I just say something about what,
where it turned a corner for me when I
was practicing because I was terrible
meditator.
Um,
and it was,
it was understanding the actual skills
that we're.
And that's
the thing I think that links all what
we're talking about here.
When you talk about martial arts,
when you talk about being a broadcaster
and you talked about comedy,
talk about practice.
It's like there are particular kinds of
mind body skills that we're training and
those skills are actually.
They have names.
There's a feeling of that that's
happening that you can experience when
you're training that muscle group.
And that was when I started
understanding things that way because
the Shin Zen because he talks about it
that way,
but Buddhism talks about it that way.
What the factors of awakening that
you're building up concentration,
which is your capacity just to pay
attention to what you want to pay
attention to.
It's like a commitment.
Your mind wanders,
you bring it back.
That's one skill.
You're building up clarity,
which is your ability to be clear and
make the sermons,
but what's happening in your experience,
what's happening in a social experience?
Is this the right time to say this
thing?
What's happening inside me,
like what am I really feeling and versus
how my acting,
you know like so dialing up that
resolution dial and building up
equanimity,
which is just the can actually not fight
with my experience as it's unfolding.
Can I have this centeredness in the
middle of what's going on?
Whether I'm doing martial arts,
whether I'm doing comedy,
whether I'm doing meditation,
the beauty of meditation practices,
it makes explicit what those skills are
in a simple situation with your eyes
closed.
You can notice when you're being
concentrated,
when you're being clear,
when you're being honest with you,
being friendly,
which is another good skill,
like you notice when that's happening
and because you notice when it's
happening,
you can start to notice how to apply it
in every other area of your life,
so that's all it is.
All practices is about being explicit
and deliberate about what qualities of
existence of being that you want to
train in your life and then you just try
to apply it everywhere,
and so that's why you can get people who
are.
I see them as basically meditation
masters on a comedy stage or people who
are basically meditation masters in the
sports arena or in the,
in a,
in a cage match or whatever it is.
They're applying the same principles.
So all these are paths that can bring
you into more of a,
a more presence in your life.
And the problem comes when people
started saying,
no,
but my path was a good path.
Oh yeah,
but I teach meditation.
That's more fundamental,
or no,
no,
but I do a body practice.
This is more fundamental.
It's like it's about the skills.
Those are what's fundamental.
Yeah.
And the more you can concentrate on
that,
the more you'll enjoy this weird
experience.
The mystery of this.
It's this weird experience that doesn't
have an owner's manual.
Yes.
Do it.
That's one of the things that's always
freaked me out about the mind and the
body.
It's like you have this incredible
vehicle and this amazing resource that's
sort of operating this vehicle and no
one,
no one gets a manual and you're taught
how to handle it by people that don't
know what the fuck they're doing,
whether it's teachers in school or
whether it's the kids that you grow up
with or maybe even perhaps your parents
or sports coaches.
You get shitty operating advice.
They're grinding the gears and banging
into trees and no one knows how to
handle this
thing.
Correct.
Particularly in our culture.
You know,
I mean,
one of the points that Sam Harris mutual
friend of ours,
great podcasts are great writer,
has made in his book waking up,
which was one of his many books,
but I think my favorite is that,
you know,
in the West we've developed an
intellectual and scientific culture that
is really robust and as changed the
world and is in unquestionably valuable,
but in the east they actually were
working on the owner's manual for the
mind for Millennia.
You know,
you got to Buddha statues in here 2,600
years ago,
this guy,
if he even existed or what do we don't
we don't know,
but this culture of Buddhism and before
that the Hindus were working on how do
you operate this mind?
What is this mind?
And uh,
I think the beautiful thing we're
watching now globally,
this trend is the meeting of these two
things and jeff is one of the people is
most excited about.
This is partly why we're such good
friends.
The meeting of this western scientific
rational culture and this eastern
exploration of the mind.
But birla I want to just call you on
something like I think,
I think that's absolutely true,
but I also think these,
the,
these,
this understanding,
this way of thinking about it is there
in the West as well,
that it's like the east is made it
explicit in very particular ways.
But even within humanistic traditions,
if you look at like the,
some of the Greek philosophers who are,
a lot of them are really mystics.
If you look within the abrahamic
traditions,
there are,
these understandings are there as well.
And they're describing it in similar
ways and like you hang out with some bad
ass Catholic priest who spent his entire
life like in poor neighborhoods,
helping people out and like totally
being present and working on service and
at the way in which that human being has
learned how to survive and is learn how
to flourish and learn how to be present
for his community or her community.
It's a lot of the same skills and did
not.
There's obviously shadowy aspects
everywhere too.
But you know,
these are human universals.
That's right.
And there's a book,
there's just to being a bad ass priest.
There's a book called Tattoos on the
heart,
which was written by the guy who wrote,
ran homeboy industries here in la.
And He,
as far as I know,
doesn't have any meditation practice,
but he talks about it.
This is a bit of a sappy word,
but compassion,
you know,
at actually giving a shit about other
human beings about whom very few other
people give a shit.
And his whole life is the organizing
principle is taken care of.
These gang members,
uh,
who's,
who have had,
who've been discarded by their family's,
grown up with parents who were in
prostitution or drugs or whatever and
had no shot and this guy,
his whole life has given them a shot and
if that's not a living this stuff out,
then I don't know what it is.
Why do we think compassion is the sappy
word?
I'm just wondering because I know that
it's so common to have those responses.
Like what does that do you think
problem with that we were talking with
soul cycle before,
you know,
when they,
it's the presentation,
you know,
when you eat it,
it's through repetition.
It loses its meaning and then sometimes
you get the sense,
I get the sense at least they would.
The people who were saying this to me
have no idea what it is they're saying
or why.
Yeah.
The Co op,
they're clunky now.
They're just a signaling their tribal
allegiance to a Unicorns or something.
By just repeating these phrases are
really embodying what they mean or
something.
Right.
Like the people that say that,
I'm not religious,
but I'm spiritual.
Yeah.
Right.
And they say that you let go Christ.
On the other hand,
I hear that I just hear somebody who's
trying to connect these principles and
doesn't want to necessarily identify
with some of these structured forms of
religion that,
that are,
that all these fucking problems.
Sometimes it's that and sometimes it's
just weird people that are just making
noises with their face because they want
you to think a certain way about that.
Making noises with your face.
But now thing that people do where
they're just really just saying noises
that they,
they hear other people say and they're
not connected to them and you feel
they're not connected to them.
So you just kind of waiting it out.
So it's hypocrisy.
The hypocrisy that makes you want to
puke because it's a disconnect between
what's real,
which.
Because you know it's real because you
can feel their body language and then
what they're saying,
which is the opposite.
But even when it's real.
I mean,
this was my problem when I first started
getting into meditation.
Even when it's real,
there's an earnestness,
there's a lack of sense.
If there's a sadness,
a saccharin about the presentation of
these really fresh,
amazing,
invigorating ideas that,
that I,
I,
this is why I wanted to write a book
with you because you talk about these
things in ways they got me interested as
opposed to sometimes the preciousness,
it's precious and I had this beautiful
little box that I'm going to unfold for
you and it's like,
and it's so holy and perfect and it's
just like this whole thing around just
makes me want to fucking vomit as soon
as they get anywhere near it.
Yeah.
It's like certain yoga teachers can say
the exact same thing and it's calming
and when they say no a you say it back
you totally.
Exactly.
And then the other ones say,
I like,
will you please shut the fuck up buddy?
So I have a,
I have a trainer that I work with,
this bad ass woman named jade.
Jade Alexis,
who was a former j dot j dot Alexis,
former golden gloves boxer.
And she's just,
I,
I would take spin classes from her,
not like just straight up spinning
classes.
You would just get in your face.
Turn up your resistance dial for you
while you're in the middle of a sprint
is just a total bad ass and so I started
working with her one on one.
She is the first person who got me to do
yoga because when she says not mistake,
I'll say it right back to her.
Yeah.
I used to take yoga from this guy from
South Africa.
He was amazing and he would say all the
things that you would hate most coming
out of insincere people,
but you knew he really believed it and
he also was one of the rare guys and
I've ran into a few people that do this,
that run a donation only yoga class,
which was fascinating for because I
would watch these
people pull in in a Mercedes and not
donate and take classes for free and
leave and I'm like,
this is amazing.
It's amazing to watch like how many
people take advantage of that and it's
amazing that the concept of it is the
purest expression of yoga.
You can get totally like give what you
can.
I'm not gonna charge you anything.
I'm not.
That's not what this is about,
this is about the yoga itself and if
people contribute enough,
I can continue to do this and we could
pay the rent and he managed to keep the
place open that way because he was so
good and it was so real.
Many meditation teachers operate this
way,
many of them.
That's how the CCO nation owning.
Yeah,
it's great if it could work,
right.
It's.
That's how kind of it should be.
Yeah.
We have A.
I have a group in Toronto called the
consciousness explorers club that my
friend James and I started like eight
years ago or something and we try to do
that principle and the idea is that
every week we get together and we
explored it and practices and we
explore.
Then we do a part two so we might,
which is like a social practice or
interactive or body practice and the
whole thinking is basically like we want
it to be kind of one stop shopping.
That whoever you are,
whatever your background and how much
money you have,
you can come once a week to this place
and it will cost you nothing.
If you have no money,
it'll cost you.
The sliding scale is 10 to 20.
If you have money,
you'll get the absolute best of what we
can do with guest teachers.
You know,
every Monday is a different set of
programming and that's.
And that's what we'll do and we'll do
that as much as we can for you and it's
like.
And then you can go home and do go back
to your life and if you need referrals
for more help there potentially there,
but this idea that once a week anywhere
in any community in the world,
you can just go to a place where you
could get the best and it's affordable.
There's no reason that can't happen
because there are so many skilled
practitioners out there and teachers and
facilitators and different modalities
and it's just exploding across the board
like psychotherapies,
exploding meditations exploding like
body therapy based therapies are
exploding like insights about a house,
sports,
how sports work,
how the mind body works,
exploding.
So there's all this diet stuff,
movement stuff,
all this expertise out there and it just
needs to way.
We wanted to create a framework where we
could start to channel some of that
expertise,
you know,
get together and have an adventure,
explore what this particular modality
has to say and then and then do it all
in communities.
You get that community support.
Yeah.
Well I think that's good with
everything.
I think having these shared
differences and sort of relating,
what are the hiccups that you found
along the way?
What are the pitfalls?
How have you overcome those?
There's,
there's great value to that.
Whether it's in meditation or we use
that in comedy a lot.
There's a lot of like one of the great
things about communities like the comedy
stores that we get together and talk
about the pitfalls like yeah,
I'm in the middle of the set and I'm on
the,
on some of them in my own head and then
I'm realizing this bit's kind of clunky
and I'm trying to get out of it and
like,
ah,
what do you do?
Like a group therapy for sure.
Yeah.
There's a lot of that.
Like one of the things that's really
interesting about standup in general
today as opposed to in the past,
is that the consciousness of it is sort
of shifted.
In the past,
it used to be a very solitary pursuit
and everybody was sort of fighting in a
scarcity mindset.
There was a famine thinking mindset that
there's only a certain amount of slots
on sitcoms.
There's a certain amount of host jobs
for late night talk shows and there's
only certain amount of jobs are comics,
certain amount of clubs to work at.
Well now there's so many clubs to work
at so many theaters on top of the clubs.
There's all these internet places where
you can do podcasts and there's so many
different avenues that comics don't feel
this famine mindset anymore and it's
much more of an open and supportive
community.
Do you think that in part is driven by
the fact that there are more women in
comedy as well and they they,
they can sometimes bring a little more
civilized approach?
No,
I think that's true that they do do that
in a lot of ways,
but no,
that's not what it is.
I think it's a lack of scarcity,
it's structural and it's also more
people who have meditated,
who have explored their consciousness,
who,
who are aware of the pitfalls of the ego
entering into comedy and then more
people sort of fostering that idea of
community through.
Yeah,
I was surprised there.
I know a reasonable amount of comedians
and some of them have come on my podcast
today to talk about how meditation helps
them in what they do.
Millennials in particular,
it's great.
Yeah.
Really good.
Very funny and very nice guy.
You kind of realized that the comic,
the comic is kind of like the canary in
the coal mine because the comedians are
really sensitive,
right?
I mean that's kind of part of what it
means to be a comedian is to be
sensitive to noticing cues and
subtleties and things in the culture
that other people overlook,
so it's not okay.
Because what I hear you saying is it's
almost like some of the most,
like,
I hate this word,
but evolved or mature people out there.
Professionals in the world are creative
people in the world or people in that
comedy community because they had that
sensitivity and they've had to learn how
to work together in some way.
I mean,
it's an interesting.
Maybe they're like,
there's something we could learn from
that population,
you know,
if we look around and saying who can we
learn from?
Is there something in Comedians and the
way they're doing things that other
people can learn from and what and what
is it?
Can we distill those lessons,
you know?
Well,
I think a lot of,
a lot of
ways it's an exploration of the mind,
you know,
and I think comedy is an exploration of
the mind,
not just in your own mind but also in
how do you relay those thoughts to other
people and the most efficient way
possible.
And a lot of that has to do with how
much have you managed your own mind and
your own ability to communicate and
meditation can greatly assist you in
that regard.
Do you do any meditation?
Yeah,
I meditate.
What's your practice like?
Well,
I do a bunch of different things.
One,
I do a lot of yoga,
breathing exercises and do them by
myself were essentially just completely
concentrating on the breath,
just breathing in and breathing out and
forcing out all the thoughts and
allowing them to come in and then
allowing them to leave and I like to do
that also inside the tank,
like one of the things that I really
like to do is get myself into a position
where I've settled in the tank and then
just completely concentrate on my breath
and just just concentrate entirely on
the breathing in and breathing out and
get it into this almost like hypnotic
cycle of breathing in and breathing out.
And it's the same thing.
There's going to be all these different
thoughts.
Like a,
you know,
I'm itchy.
I should scratch my nose.
And I'm like,
uh,
maybe I should cut this down to an hour
instead of two hours like I planned or
you know,
I really need to go running instead of
going to yoga tomorrow,
maybe I should switch.
You got to let those go.
They come in,
they come out and just the breathing
being this consistent thing that I can
always go back to concentrating on.
Yeah,
I mean that is,
that's it you just described.
I do a practice almost exactly like
that.
It actually enhances the tank.
Well,
it's interesting.
I was just going to say that I was
trying to figure out what I was noticing
my breath,
like what am I noticing here?
Um,
I might actually feeling the breath or
might just hearing the breath come in
through the nose and just identifying
that was actually a little bit
interesting.
It actually boosted my level of
attention to the breath when I decided
to go in that direction.
Yeah,
it's,
it's both.
I mean,
you're hearing it,
you're feeling it,
but it's just the act of it,
you know,
the thing that doing it,
they're doing it and they're like this
sort of like hypnotic in and out thing
that happens when you have no sensory
input whatsoever.
You're not feeling your feet on the
ground.
You feel weightless.
You're not hearing anything and not
seeing anything.
It's just a particularly effective
environment for exploring your.
There's an expression sometimes this
feeling of our inexperience of being
breezed,
so it's like you're not.
You're no longer doing the breathing.
The breathing is just happening.
It's like you're being breathed by a
giant cosmic lung.
It's like that,
that you know,
that feeling that you're talking about
letting go try to do that in the tank
and it's just like you.
You just let go of any sense of that.
There's a dewar and it just that you
just start to taste yourself as this
process,
this thing that's just happening,
you know in a bird is passing outside.
Clouds are passing and someone's walking
across the street talking on their phone
and you're being breathed and it's all
just one system that's just happening.
It's also interesting too,
when I'm in the tank,
I lose the sense of what is up and
what's down here.
Like you lose like what?
When you're lying there and you're
floating,
you kind of lose this.
Everything seems like all over the
place,
but in the thought of relaxing and
letting go,
it's always going down.
It's always like a deeper thing.
It's always like settling in more,
settling more.
It always seems to go towards back,
like you're
just sinking in deeper and deeper and
deeper.
It's one of the only times we have a
sensation of a very particular direction
that you're going in.
I found that direction,
listening of it that initially was quite
scary for me that I was aware it,
but my moving or is this inner ear
stuff,
you know,
like it was just flying.
But,
but I,
I didn't experience that as a soaring.
I experienced it as more terrifying.
Do we,
do we do we have footage of Dan Klein
the inside of the tank?
It's a practice,
man.
I,
I see the value.
I mean,
another thing that actually kind of
reminds me of my last meditation retreat
where we're talking about physical
discomfort.
My teacher and I and because I was
experiencing a lot of physical pain from
long sitting for a long time,
pain comes up and I was asking,
you know,
is it okay for me to quit at some point
just because it's pains too intense?
And He.
Joseph was arguing,
you know,
I think you want to test your limits on
this.
Obviously at some point you're going to
get up,
but you want to,
we're,
we're gradually increasing the amount
that we can stand and that to me seems
very similar to the value that I can
perceive of getting back in the sensory
deprivation tank of being able to be
with that fear a little bit more,
test the limit a little bit more
consistently so that I'm a so that my
world isn't getting smaller.
People echo that same sentiment when it
comes to psychedelics.
Right?
That was the next test for belonging,
very interested.
There's a lot of,
as you know,
there's been a growing body of research
into the salutary effects of
psychedelics and a lot of it's being
done at Nyu on cancer cancer patients
who have anxiety,
but there's also some specific work
being done at Johns Hopkins on
meditators and uh,
and psilocybin.
What kind of effect to psilocybin have
on meditators and in Kenya in a way,
show them directionally where you want
to be moving in your meditative
practice.
And I've had a longstanding desire to
get into this study,
my shrink and my wife strongly argue
that I shouldn't.
Somebody with my kind of brain chemistry
who had,
has to go on and perform under pressure
when the red light's on,
on TV.
Probably not a great idea to dose myself
with psychedelics,
but this is something that I've been
wrestling with.
What are you worried about?
What that looks like?
What do you think is gonna happen is
right back to the.
My worries in the tank.
And Timmy,
I was thinking a lot about psychedelics
and I've had,
you know,
when I was a kid and,
and would smoke weed,
I would have panic attacks.
And I think it's about the desire for
control of the ego.
The thinking mind moves is,
and it's,
it's like a vampire confronted with
garlic,
you know,
it's just my ego's spoiling and can't
handle the lack of control.
And it's not just the entity energy
of those experiences that's so intense
where you just have no control over it,
but it's also,
it just blows apart your worldview.
Like you had this idea that you think,
oh,
you think you know what's really going
on,
and then you have one of those
experiences and it just shows you that
you don't anything well
and you are there,
you think you are,
you that there's some solid you there
and that that is called into question
fundamentally.
Yeah,
but it's humbling to be shown that all
your,
your ideas about how you think things
are just that you know,
that it's just like that you don't know.
Fuck all.
And that has been,
that's my experience from doing,
doing that stuff.
It's like I just shows me that I'm just,
you know what?
Just sit back to sit back and,
and let nature do what nature's going to
do.
Can you say sit back dude,
when there's no dude there,
when that's what you're starting to see
and you get exploded.
So it basically you're going to.
It's a win win situation.
Either you win because you're able to
stay super aquinas with a greater and
greater intensity of what you're
experiencing under a trip or you win
because you don't stay economists.
You fight with it and you get ripped to
shreds and in that humbling moment you
that isn't itself is deeply consoling
and healing both.
I think it's like both sides of that are
are positive.
It's like a net positive gain on both
sides of that.
That's how I legitimated you know,
when I'm getting ripped apart.
Yeah.
Getting ripped apart.
Yeah,
it does.
See you see what I'm worried about.
Yeah,
that's what I'm worried about.
Yeah.
I think it was just relax.
It'll be fun.
Yeah,
I know,
but that's one of those things like get
it onto your.
When people say relaxed or get out of
your own way for somebody as tightly
wound as me,
it's a frustrating thing to hear because
it's hard for me to have
racial gotta resist that clench.
Resist the clench.
Just let it go.
Sometimes you do get ripped apart.
Yeah.
Oh you.
Most of the time if you do it right,
heroes dose.
So that's part of the thing about it
though,
is you're supposed to thing heroes does.
Terence Mckenna?
Yeah.
I got five dried grams.
That was seven to seven if you're
interested,
but five dried grams is the recommended
threshold.
Yeah.
That's a different kind of emotional
experience.
Yeah.
Um,
I think it's one of those things where
if you test yourself slowly but surely
in those waters,
you'll get more and more accustomed to
the feeling of relaxation and letting go
and that treat it like it's a shamonic
experience.
Like it's a very deep intensive search
to the very meaning of your existence
and don't,
don't think of it as like,
oh my God,
I'm about to do drugs.
Right.
But
there's.
They're not dissimilar in the way that
when you don't know up from down when
you have no sensation of your body
anymore.
That is exposing the fundamental,
the fundamental fact that Jeff has.
Jeff has used as this description over
and over I think quite beautifully
throughout this discussion,
which is that we aren't as solid as we
think.
We are.
In fact,
a process and the dude,
you're trying to console the dude.
It's okay that dude or do that.
There's no there,
there and that I could see myself going
in that direction in the tank that's
inexorably where it takes you and that
is where psychedelics take you.
And again,
I'm in,
I have,
I'm in this weird position because I'm
deeply interested in that experience and
I've tasted in my own meditation for
sure.
So scared.
Yeah,
I mean this is where meditation goes.
If we're seeing that your,
that the you,
that you've been defending and
protecting since sentience actually
doesn't exist is I think ultimately very
liberating really is the true
liberation.
But seeing it initially as a,
as a,
um,
as a newbie is it tears apart as Jeff
says,
your worldview,
the world,
our worldview is based on us at the
center.
It's a death experience.
Yes,
exactly.
So it seems to me it's like you want to
learn how to swim,
but you really only interested in calf
high water because if you,
if you really want to learn how to swim,
what happens is they take you out on a
jet ski to the middle of the ocean.
They go jump off,
dude,
you're,
you're now in the center of the ocean
and that's the psychedelic trip.
The psychedelic trip is you are fucking
swimming,
right?
There's no if,
ands,
or buts.
You must keep going or you're going to
drown.
I think there are different approaches
based on different people because I
think you're exactly right that I want
to swim,
but my tendency is to stick to the CAF
high water,
but you're from what I know about you
having spent a little bit of time with
you and just follow following you,
you're kind of a baller,
like you're ready to go out on the jet
ski and jump in or do all this crazy
stuff that traditionally.
I mean,
I have done some crazy things that we
discussed,
but traditionally I'm more cautious and
I think for somebody with my kind of
brain chemistry,
somebody whose brain is very good at
panicking,
I think there's a more step wise
approach,
which is what I'm intrigued by,
which is what we're,
we keep discussing,
which is test those limits time and
again,
keep testing them.
Don't,
don't let up.
For example,
for example,
uh,
my shrink,
the one who got me to stop doing drugs
after I had a panic attack on television
and helped me,
you know,
Kinda straighten myself out.
I had a panic attack or the beginnings
of a panic attack on a subway.
I'm about five years ago.
And it was,
for me,
it was devastating because I was like,
this is such a setback.
Um,
I'm right back at stage one.
I'm and my world is gonna get smaller
again.
So I went to go see him kind of on an
emergent basis and he laid out a plan,
which is not his original idea.
This is actually the way you treat these
things called exposure therapy where he
said,
okay,
here for the next 10 days I want you to
go stand on the subway platform every
day just for a couple of minutes.
And then for the 10 days after that,
I want you to get on a subway or a car
and then get off before the door closes,
five,
five to 10 days.
And then after that I want you to get on
and go one.
And basically he got me back on the
subway because I was able to gradually
get through.
I'm not Joe Rogan from my.
I would never be able to host a show
called fear factor the way you did with
that,
unless it was a completely different
show where you know,
you're not getting in a tank full of
torrential is on the first day,
you know,
I have to do in a step wise progression
because that's the way my brain is
wired.
Absolutely.
To me that there's going to be different
ways for folks to do it.
They're definitely as did you,
were you exposed to a lot of difficulty
when you were young?
Did you have to overcome physical
adversity?
Did you participate in any one on one
sport
or anything like that?
I think the problem was just the
opposite,
that I had two incredibly loving former
hippie parents.
I was a bit of a spoiled kid and Jeff
and I have talked about this,
that,
uh,
to the extent that I experienced anger
or frustration.
Oh,
sorry.
It's because I'm not getting what I
want.
Yeah.
But I did do some competitive sports.
I just wasn't very good at it.
So do you guys have you guys heard of
somatic experiencing?
So sematic experiencing.
It's the super interesting a way of
addressing trauma that is starting to
get really influential in the body work
community and psychotherapists and
psychiatrists and psychologists are
starting to look at it and there's a
bunch of good papers out about it,
but basically the thesis,
it comes from being really a guy named
Peter Levine who spent a lot of time
looking at animal behavior.
And what he noticed is that when animal
goes into a fight or flight situation,
um,
they.
So you're a gazelle and all of a sudden
there's the tiger and then you go,
you just exploded to action.
So there's this explosive release of
energy running or fighting,
whatever it is afterwards,
they'll often go into this shaking
effect where they'll start trembling.
I'm unconsciously or they can't control
it.
It's like,
and what they think is that it's like
discharging all the excess energy and
then they go back to homeostasis.
And so his theory is that what happens
with human beings is because we have
these giant frontal lobes that we get
shocks to our nervous system,
um,
and we can't discharge the energy.
We can't fucking punch your boss in the
face or we can't run or whatever.
And just the same as when we were kids,
we just swallow it up.
We swallowed up and the,
and that trapped energy,
the nervous system starts to become our
neurotic habits.
It becomes chronic anxiety,
becomes a panic attacks.
It becomes chronic aggression or
irritability.
Also,
chronic freeze responses get stuck in
there too,
which is sort of like chronic,
not their illness or someone who sort a
little bit dreamy.
And so somatic experiencing is a whole
way of working with it.
We're basically,
it's sort of like exposure therapy,
but it wouldn't,
it's not,
it's not the same.
It's like it's all in the,
uh,
it's very meditative.
It's like you're working with somebody
and they,
and they go,
okay,
why are you coming to the awardee feel
comfortable sitting?
It's like,
oh,
I,
I feel a couple of sitting over here.
Why did you sit there?
Well,
I kinda like had my back to the wall.
what is it about having your back to the
wall that makes you feel more
comfortable?
I just feel this and it's like,
well then what's the opposite?
What's the discomfortable thing?
And then you and you notice,
well,
what it would feel like to be
uncomfortable there and you basically
find a spot in your experience and your
consciousness which is very centered and
comfortable and then you find that the
problem and you try to simultaneously
notice both at the same time and
basically all the trapped energy of the
neurotic place starts to drain out that
making sense.
I'm trying to make it visually vivid or
visual,
but that's how you work with this stuff.
So you can start to drain out these
patterns of like chronic fear.
These paddocks of,
of chronic fight.
You do it,
uh,
by noticing how that pattern is in your
body connecting to it.
And then it can kinda empty out.
It's so interesting because it also
just,
it,
it blows the lid off trauma.
It says trauma is going to be different
for every person.
All traumas is just shock to the nervous
system.
It's not just about surviving a
terrorist attack or you know,
all this horrible stuff.
It's like someone might do something to
Dan in the,
in the smallest way when he's a two year
old,
that wasn't any big deal,
but it completely freaked him out.
It basically shocked his nervous system
so intensely that now there's that
pattern of shock that's in there that
still lives in there.
And what happens?
It just grows and grows and grows and
because if you don't release that
energy,
it just just keeps causing havoc in the
system.
That's the thinking of somatic
experiencing.
It's.
And I've been working with somebody and
I had a.
I mean,
just to give him,
to make it real.
I had a,
I've had a lot of injuries in my life,
like broken neck and broke,
busted shoulder and different things
from just being a jackass.
But one time I got hit by this truck,
I was on my bike and it blew up my
shoulder,
hit the ground.
And then uh,
the,
uh,
back of the truck hit me and he has sent
me spinning.
Um,
and so one time I was in there working
with the somatic experiencing lady and
she's like,
what direction do you want to look in?
I'm like,
ah,
I kind of felt like,
look in this way if you don't,
you don't feel like looking that way.
And I'm like,
no,
it doesn't really.
I don't really want to turn my head this
way.
I don't really want it.
And I realized that that's always there.
I kinda don't want to look this way.
And she's like,
well,
what,
what happens when you look this way?
And I,
it was like,
I started looking this way and was
harder do and suddenly I remembered the
impact of this truck from when I was 17
years old on this side of my body and I
could feel that the impact was still in
my body and she got me to work to turn
my head.
And like she got me to connect to that,
to that.
So I'm thinking of that memory and I'm
feeling that memory in my body and she
gets me to work through that turning my
head and the act of doing that was like
all of a sudden
I felt all this new freedom in this
pattern and I have now not had that
issue as much.
And that's just to give you an example
of how you would work in that mode.
Isn't that.
Isn't that cool?
I mean,
I find that to unbelievably.
I do too.
That is interesting.
Listening to your story about your life,
about the lack of difficulty.
It sort of reinforces my ideas about
martial arts and that it's not about
learning how to be a great fighter
learning on the beat people up.
It's learning how to battle your own
internal demons and,
and confront insecurities and fears and
to do it on a regular basis frees up a
lot of the mental landscape.
It allows you to just be more relaxed
about a lot of different approaches to
life and this,
this tension and control that we have is
a lot of time just pointless.
And it's highlighted by martial arts
training.
Yeah,
I think it's almost always pointless.
Yeah.
Although you know,
the thing is you look at a good fighter,
just like if you look at a good dancer,
there's definitely a sense in which
they're just flowing and they're
responding,
but then when they need to be tensed,
boom,
they got it.
It's like they got that power behind
them.
It's like if you were dancing,
for example,
any.
All you did was just flatty flow.
You would have,
there'd be no form to it.
It's like you need the pulling in,
you need that.
So it's about the.
It's about the intelligent use of
tension,
you know,
knowing when to be soft and then when to
be having those two sides.
Yeah,
but what I'm talking about,
those,
the management of stressful physically
difficult things on a regular basis
frees the mind.
Now just the,
the,
the getting comfortable with conflict
and when in the absence of conflict,
then you look to try to restrict and
control everything and then every little
affront to that,
any little questioning and challenging
of your control over things can cause
anxiety because you're uncomfortable
with this idea of surrender,
of relax hoagland.
Totally.
Whether it's in psychedelics or whether
it's meditation or all these things.
There's some relationships.
Yeah,
and stand up comedy,
communicating,
podcast hosting.
Good Morning America.
I mean there's so many parallels because
a lot of it is in managing the mind and
just being able to,
again,
get out of your own way.
I agree.
Yeah.
Oh,
we got that shit sorted out
tomorrow.
It'll pop up again in your cost while
you got to keep doing it.
It's like,
Hey,
these uses,
these books are all saying the same
thing again and again and again,
but you still need to read it because
you forget.
Yeah.
And it gets a little bit easier all the
time.
You know,
managing the mind gets a little easier
in part of it.
You could chalk up to maturity and life
experience,
but it's also just this continual
practice of paying attention to what's
going on inside your head.
Exactly right.
Jeff doesn't like my analogy that I'm
about to use because he thinks it's
slightly aggressive and he's right,
but it's,
it's mostly meant for comic effect,
but it's like when you have a dog who
takes a shit on the rug,
you kinda.
Sometimes you've got to put their snout
and shit and that is what we're doing in
meditation and in all of these
practices.
Seeing over and over again how crazy we
are,
how the fear arises,
how the anger arises,
how the discontent with whatever's
happening right now arises and not
getting owned by it.
And,
and that's why these practices so useful
and why you got to stick with them.
You don't get just fixed,
you know,
it doesn't work.
That was nothing
like that.
No.
I mean,
there are a lot of people
blood.
They're selling them.
Yeah.
Something real.
What's the most annoying aspect of that
to you guys?
Please go to the power of positive
thinking.
Oh,
well,
you know,
we were talking about that yesterday
where people were talking about
President Oprah and I reminded everyone
about Oprah and the secret.
I'm like,
do you know how many fucking people ruin
their lives because they thought all
they had to do was have a vision board
and think positive and this is going to
be the key to happiness.
Yeah.
I think it's.
It's one of the most pernicious ideas
that's ever been sort of released into
our culture and it even predates the
secret because there's.
There's a book called the power of
positive thinking.
There's another book called think and
grow rich.
I don't want people to go buy these
books because I don't think.
See that the idea that you can solve all
your problems through the power of
positive thinking is so easily
disproved.
Just engaged in the following thought
experiment.
Anybody who's born right now in a
refugee camp,
were they thinking incorrectly in Utero
in 2010 when the.
When the earthquake hit Puerto Prince,
Haiti,
it was everybody in town thinking
incorrectly.
Did they bring that upon themselves?
Of course not.
Of course not,
and yet we're telling all these people
that if you make a good vision board,
you can carry your cancer or you don't
have to go to the doctor.
All this.
It is demonstrably false and recklessly
dangerous
and most of the people that have had
success with the power of positive
thinking,
they attributed to that,
but you're not talking to any of the
people that thought the exact same way
and failed.
You're only talking to the successful
people.
The the sampling is so biased.
The only people who've had all their
problems solved through the power of
positive thinking or the people writing
those fucking books and selling all the
copies and if by the way,
if it was that easy,
they're all new.
One book.
Yeah,
well,
I would say writing books.
I keep saying,
come back to this next seminar in this
freezing cold room with your credit
card,
but I will say the one part of it that
they idea that you can have an intention
that having a clear intention of
something about how you want to be or
something that you want to have happen,
that that can be helpful.
I think that's common sense,
the difference between having a positive
attitude.
Yeah,
absolutely beneficial.
Yes.
Absolutely.
Do you guys have you heard,
um,
you know,
William James,
the great kind of psych psychologist,
a mystic,
he was a mystic.
He had this really cool,
um,
he talked about,
uh,
I think it was called first born versus
twice born or one sport once born and
twice born.
And it was a fundamental way in which
you distinguished people who had,
who have maybe had a spiritual outlook
in life.
And he said the ones born people were.
People were just naturally,
they're the kind of the positive
thinkers.
The kind of like everything is perfect.
Everything is awesome.
This rose colored view of reality and
really not able to kind of see suffering
and everything,
that kind of a thing,
and we all Kinda know people like that.
It kind of the classic,
a naive spiritual person,
uh,
but he was really interested in the,
what he called twice born and that's
what he was.
And I feel like that's,
that's certainly how I identify which is
somebody who can come into a kind of
perspective,
like a mystical or spiritual perspective
but has to but only did it via having to
look hard at the reality of suffering at
the reality of evil,
of fucked up shit in the world like
that.
You can't wave away the world's unfair
distribution of wealth and hardship and
that you had to come to that.
You had to come to your view through a
honest reckoning with the crappy stuff
about being a human being and the crappy
stuff that's out there and that you
couldn't not look at it and that you
could do that.
Like tolstoy was the famous example.
Then you kind of could be reborn into a,
a perspective that was wide enough to
include the full bittersweet and that.
And so I think that's what I think to
the,
to the,
to the twice born,
the first born outlook is kind of
repellent because it seems like it's not
looking at the truth of all the very
real challenges that are going out
there.
It's like you could just be in,
you'd go to your yoga class and heat
your,
your perfect raw food and be in your
perfect bubble.
But,
but meanwhile the world is just
contracted in pain.
And to really be a kind of true,
expansive humanist is to kind of look at
all that and to still find your way into
thinking that life is worth living.
You know,
there's a mystery there.
And um,
um,
yeah,
I'm trying.
I guess you have to recognize that there
are these horrible things in the world,
but concentrating on them fully in an
only is not going to benefit you in
form.
That's also true.
It's like there are amazing things to
this life and the more you concentrate
on them,
the more you'll recognize them,
the more you'll sort of baskin right?
The amazing experience that we're all
going through this right now,
and so what you're describing as
elements of positive thinking,
that's the good side.
That's totally legit.
That positivity,
positive attitude as opposed to positive
thinking,
which is loaded up with this idea of
like sort of mental control of the
external world and that I think is
dangerous,
but I think Joe's describing is
gratitude.
Yes,
absolutely.
Absolutely.
That's,
that's so important.
But it's important to parse this out.
What part of this is healthy and good
and what part of this is destructive?
Yes,
I agree.
Right,
and what part of it you could parse out
from what you would call the law of
attraction,
which is not a law,
so I was not.
I mean that's another part of the
problem too.
Like the Wu is written in the title like
it's not a law,
it's just that's not what it is.
So you calling it the law of attraction,
let's be know you're full of shit that
was law made by Zeus.
See that episode of Hercules.
There's something that's undeniably
important about positive thinking,
having a positive attitude and being
enthusiastic and having energy and
focusing on the good and focusing your
goals and focus on what you're trying to
achieve,
but the idea that that in and of itself
is all you need,
that that it's,
it's uniquely powerful and then it can
literally bring you your future and then
all these people that say that,
that this is what they used,
like you know,
you might have been successful and that
might be your underlying thought
process,
but there is a wider series of factors.
There's a big spectrum of things that
had to happen for you to be successful,
including luck,
including the great fortune of being
born in America and privilege.
Yeah,
there's so many different places.
You could be so many different life
experiences.
You've could have had horrific parental
situations in an household,
situations you could have been born
into.
You're extremely lucky.
Look at the case of James Arthur Ray.
I covered it extensively for ABC news
that the,
he was one of the gurus in the secret,
in the DVD of the secret.
He was one of the guys talking about how
the universe is like Aladdin's lamp and
he held a sweat lodge ceremony in
Sedona,
Arizona,
which several people died and he went to
prison.
So how well was the law of attraction
work for him?
Yeah,
maybe it did work.
He put in a bunch of bullshit and got
some.
Yeah.
They also found in his hotel room a lot
of like a hgh and testosterone and stuff
like that.
So he definitely wasn't as buff just
through the power of positive things
and he was trying to do what would the
sweat lodge like,
what was the.
I like,
look,
the sweat lodge is a beautiful ceremony
from,
for native Americans,
people too hot or too hot and they
overheated and their electrolyte balance
got crazy or something and how to people
dying or something like that.
You know,
it was awhile ago so I can't remember,
but I think it was two people.
The problem with a lot of those people
too is that what they do is they,
they put together like some sort of a
program where maybe it's a book,
maybe it's a a guideline you're supposed
to follow.
Then they start teaching seminars in it
and they start putting it into practice
and leading all these people with this
stuff and that it becomes who they are,
like who they are is like a guru who
they are as a spiritual person and
people come to them that the dynamic
they have people come to them,
what should I do?
And the universe provides bounty.
Oh,
and everybody claps and goes along with
it and they live in this sort of bubble.
Yeah.
And it just,
it gets really odd with those folks.
Yeah.
I mean that was why.
I mean I was,
I had been assigned a years and years
ago to cover faith and spirituality for
ABC news even though I'm an agnostic and
I ended up covering a lot of these new
age gurus and that was why I ended up.
My first book I wrote was called 10
percent happier because I was trying to
counter program against the Sea of
bullshit that is America is
$11,000,000,000 a year self help
industry because I was watching what
this was doing to people's lives.
It's so far.
We've been talking about that a lot
lately.
There's so many people that are trying
to get in this on sort of the open level
when you see it on Instagram,
like there's a lot of people like
promoting these inspirational little
posts and they'll have these little
inspirational videos like you know,
what you got to do today is go out there
and embrace life and just go after your
goals and like.
And there's so many people that are
trying to give people this fuel and give
people this and they might not
necessarily really even be in practice
with that themselves.
Yeah,
it's A.
I liked the open.
I like your analogy about the open mic.
That is what it's like.
It's like they're trying it out.
They're learning how to be an Anthony
Robbins.
Tony Robbins.
It's funny.
I have a friend who was living in France
and they came back to Canada and he'd
been in Paris,
live in there for like 10 years or
something and so he's walking around the
streets of Toronto and he said it was
the same when he was anywhere in North
America and he kept feeling like there
was something wrong,
but he couldn't put his finger on it.
It was like,
what is wrong?
Something wrong,
and then he realized that everyone was
actually having the same conversation
all the time over and over again,
which was everything's gonna be all
right.
Adam is going to be all right.
Everyone's going to be all right.
It was just this constant pepe
cheerleading from everywhere.
Whereas in France it's just like,
things are fucked that is fucked.
No,
you are shit.
And that's what it's like being in
France know.
It's like at least they're honest,
but that has its downsides,
downside,
but I mean there's also a realism where
people are just gonna,
like call it out as it is.
We're here.
There's such A.
There's a tendency to just to Kinda.
There can be this kind of Pollyanna ish.
Everything is fine.
Everything is fine because people don't
really want to look at what's under,
what's lurking underneath,
you know,
well,
everything's fine right now in this
moment,
right?
Most of the time.
Now we've got pro most of the time in,
but can we talk about the mystical
mystery underbelly weirdness,
show off this idea that everything is
fine in the moment,
this exact moment right now,
like so in practice,
this is something Shin Zen taught me
that the more you.
It's almost like the present moment is
on a continuum and that didn't sound
make any sense,
but it's like you can be present and you
need to be more present and more and
more and you can start to get a feeling
for that.
For practice of just the absolute.
Now it's like you're getting closer and
closer to the absolute now with ever
actually getting there,
which I know just sounds like a bunch of
gobbly goop,
but the feeling on the inside,
it's just this.
Everything is.
It's like the silence,
this presence.
It's like this sacredness,
you know,
the no bullshit kind of sacredness
that.
What is that,
you know,
that to me is like I wrote about
consciousness for a long time before I
started realizing that there's this
thing here and how do you talk about,
how do you write about it in a way it
doesn't sound ridiculous,
you know,
and yet it is the most important thing.
It is the most,
uh,
it orients you to be able to come into
that understanding.
Yeah.
How do we talk about it?
You know,
the mystics have always said you can't
talk about it.
It's inevitable,
but it's true as an experience.
But where is it?
Bears talked about intelligently,
where are you going to read about that
in the New Yorker magazine or,
or whatever.
You know,
it's like,
it's either talked about in this
Disneyland way or it's not talked about
at all.
It's like we got to try to talk about,
we got to try to,
or at least remember not taco about come
to find practices,
you know,
but honor that it's real and you know
that that's something I'm really
interested in and I'm trying to learn
how to do it.
Now.
Let me ask you this.
As an outsider,
if someone is coming to this with zero
meditation experience,
no,
no thought whatsoever about pursuing
this and they're listening to you say
these things like,
okay,
what's in it for me?
What do I get out of that?
What do I get?
If I can get to this,
what do I get?
What's what's in there?
It seems like you're just alive.
Yeah,
like this doesn't seem like anything
changes.
Well,
I think that is what you get.
You get your life,
you get your life back.
Most of the time you're not in your
life.
You're freaking out about your life.
You're in your head thinking about this,
this or that happened,
or you're responding to situations.
What you get is the capacity to be
sitting here in the middle of all this
and be an appreciate the richness and
the fullness of it because that's the
thing.
It has,
it has a quality of a,
of fulfillment in it,
has a quality of like nothing needs to
be any different.
So there's a peacefulness and a beauty
or something or even when things are
objective,
even when things are shitty and his
bittersweetness so you know,
this poignancy to things,
it's like you get exactly your life,
just more of it.
And that's why,
you know,
Shinzen used to say it's like,
it's like you lived,
it's like it,
you get to live 10 times deeper or va
one time to two times deeper or three
times or four times the more you
practice,
it's like,
it's the same surface,
but it's the depth dimension that's
getting like richer and fuller,
broader.
Um,
and,
and so then it gives you the capacity to
also to appreciate more and more what's
going on because most of the time we
walk around like,
ah,
this is the stuff I like looking at.
But I don't like this stuff over here,
I don't want to feel these things are,
I don't want to see these things.
So we're like,
we're kind of,
you know,
we're,
it's like we live.
The analogy I use is like,
we're born into a mansion,
but room by room we're like,
nope,
can't go in there.
Can't go in there.
That's my ex girlfriend.
Or that's my relationship with my
parents.
Or Oh,
that's this limitation of this
limitation.
At some point we're just sitting there
under the stairs.
Everything is fine.
I think it's fine.
Yeah.
I've really enjoyed my life.
Were hiding in the dark under the
stairs.
Go.
So you want to.
It's about reclaiming the mansion,
you know,
it's like,
can you be,
like you said exactly,
can you be free in more and more
situations and can you begin to
appreciate the,
uh,
the beauty of even these difficult
situations and that way your whole life
just kinda can open up to you.
That's what the practice is about.
Other way of thinking about it and is,
and this is a bit of a new age trope,
so it's a little annoying.
But it's like what I said before that
cliches become cliches for a reason and
the reason is their true generally all
you get ever because right now,
everything you've experienced in your
whole life happened to you right now and
everything you ever will experience will
always happen to you right now.
Non Negotiable.
We live most of our lives.
However,
in a autopilot of in a fog of rumination
and projection,
and we're not paying any attention to
the only thing we ever get.
Meditation,
digging more deeply into the present
moment is giving you your life back
now.
How do you address?
Because what we're talking about is
managing the mind and increasing
happiness by 10 percent or more.
Hopefully.
How do you address psych meds?
Because a lot of people that are going
down this road have already gone down
the pharmaceutical road and might be
inextricably connected to it.
Some sort of a way they might be on anti
anxiety medication,
be on antidepressants.
Like how do you address that?
Jay?
I think I can speak for both of us and
that we are maximalists that when it
comes to wellbeing,
it's important.
You got to surround the ball,
you got to use every Arrow in the
quiver,
and uh,
just because we're in the meditation
doesn't mean we're not into all the
other scientifically proven ways of
dealing with your mental health.
You know,
I often say that we,
as a culture,
we spent so much time working on our
bodies,
on our stock portfolio is on our cars
and no time on the one filter through
which we experience everything and
that's our minds.
And so if you have clinically diagnosed
anxiety or depression,
which again,
we need to be talking about more openly
because there's so much stigma around
it.
I've dealt with both since I was a kid.
If you have that,
you should avail yourself of every
possible remedy and if your doctor
recommends a that you take psych meds,
then you should investigate it.
If it works for you,
then stay on a meditation is just
another thing you can also use along
with exercise,
getting enough sleep,
having positive relationships,
having a healthy diet.
All the other no brainers with Jeff and
I are saying is in the Pantheon of no
brainers,
meditation needs to be included.
Yeah.
I think,
I think with the meds thing,
um,
sometimes meds can get you to the
baseline of uh,
then then you can meditate,
you know,
and it's almost like a,
I mean,
I know too many people whose lives have
been including people I know really,
really well really,
really helped by these meds.
I know other people have had super hard
time with it,
but some of them at the same boat and
some of them it's like,
it gets you to a place where it's almost
like the meds can help by time for your
own system to work itself out.
And so you get to a place where you're
like,
I have a lot of trouble with crazy
energy surges up and down.
Like,
and like a manic phase.
Yeah.
Like I get,
I get hypomanic and then I get like
disparate and then hyper hypo manic.
I actually just got a diagnosis,
uh,
two weeks ago that I probably have a
mild form of bipolar is 46 years old.
I'm finally learning,
but it's not a surprise.
I kind of knew how do they,
how do they diagnose that?
So,
uh,
so it was an interview,
so it's an hour long.
This case was like an hour and a half or
an hour long interview or a guy just
really took my history,
like how I've been challenged.
I have add big time add that's,
that's been diagnosed multiple times but
just because the way my attention works,
but he basically really asked me lots of
questions about how about my history and
when things started to get into the more
surges and,
and they've been getting worse the past.
And this is entering [inaudible].
I meditated a ton but,
and,
and there was a period of the meditation
was super,
super working really well and
stabilizing everything.
And then there was a period where the
meditation felt like it wasn't working
as well and all this energy,
it's like that trauma stuff I was
talking about.
All that stuff started to come up.
So I go more into these ups and downs
and I found that the practice would
help.
It would help me from feeding the
spikes,
but it wasn't I a,
it hasn't been totally addressing it.
Now.
I haven't actually started any meds or
done any lithium metal.
I'm thinking maybe I would try that
because I want to understand what folks
go through.
Um,
but basically he just asks a lot of
questions.
There's,
you know,
I guess he,
they have a diagnostic criteria around a
set of like,
does that seem to make sense for what we
know about it and because they've seen
all these patients,
they've got all these ideas and it's so
new.
I don't even know what to do with the
information.
In fact,
I'm kind of can't believe I'm talking
about it because it seems a bit
premature,
but I'm,
you know,
the way I think about it as I would
consider doing meds because I just want
to be able to get to a place where I
could then let my body heal itself,
help itself out,
figure itself out,
and the meds might buy me time to do
that.
Then they and the meditation can be part
of that as well and that's just a messy
human reality of it.
But you,
you seem like you've got your shit
together.
So like what is it exactly that's
bothering you so much?
You'd actually be considering
medication?
Well,
it's try writing a book with them.
Yeah.
So I'm like fine.
Six days a week and then one day a week.
So there's the,
there's the potential stuff.
Just being overexcited about things in
my getting pulled in every direction.
That's not really a problem so much
anymore.
Like I've learned to the problems.
There were more like you disappoint
people,
you feel like you can't get your shit
together,
you know,
you're just,
you're just so scattered that can happen
and,
and that back and upgrade its own
challenges,
but the energy ones are more
fundamental.
It's like,
I'll wake up in the morning,
you know,
it might be once every week or two and
all of a sudden I can feel my heart
pounding and I could feel like this
incredible energy in my hands and my
body and I just,
I'm in this hypo manic state and I,
and I,
and it feels good.
I don't even realize it,
but I'm going around,
I'm talking,
I'm excited about stuff and I'm just
jacked up on this,
like a,
on this energy and it's um,
and what comes up must go down.
So I usually like it.
But then what will happen is I realized
they know that I've been,
I've exaggerated like,
oh,
I've gone into something that I had been
too aggressive of a situation or have
been exaggerating some situation where I
got grind grandiose about something and
I feel super embarrassed that I was in
this sort of like high and in a way
that.
And I,
and I didn't have my shit together at
all.
And then I ended up in the downswing,
which is the,
the catastrophizing,
the like,
uh,
the despair sometimes.
Like,
you know,
I said Lenny lose like that thing about
being in the center that was talking
about when it's there,
it's so true and it's so there and all
of a sudden I'm not there at all.
I don't feel anything.
There's,
I feel like there's no meaning to
anything and I am just in this
desolation thing and that last for a few
hours or like a day or something and
then I'll pop out and I'm fine and I
know that once a week or once every
week,
two weeks or something,
I'm going to go into that cycle.
Now I've done my whole life without
having.
I've tried to manage it entirely with
meditation,
with exercise,
with diet and I may just continue to
keep doing that.
Have you gotten better at it?
I have got well so I have gotten better
at managing it.
Absolutely no question.
I've gotten way better at not believing
in it when I'm in a high and not
believing when I'm in the down.
I don't want to interrupt you,
but the thought process,
like what?
When it kicks in,
What are you aware of it?
So yeah,
it starts as well.
I am because I start this energy in the
body,
so I feel the vibrating this.
I'm like,
okay,
that's the first my early warning sign
and then it gets bigger and bigger,
but the thing is it's addictive because
you do you mind on your heart rate?
While this is how I know,
but I can feel the fucking heart
sometimes is going like a Jackhammer and
other times the heart it cools out,
but that it's like the.
I mean the power is still there,
the feeling of.
And that's that feeling of power which
is very workout when that hits.
That's too.
That is what I do.
I hit a punching bag and it's the best.
So I.
This has been the best thing in the
world for me is been hitting a punching
bag and it's men meditation can't do
shit when I'm in that place.
Right.
But punching bag,
I feel calm and centered afterwards.
So that is the main intervention of what
I'm doing.
I may never go the med route.
I think I can handle it like I've been
doing it until now,
but what makes me want to do it is I
want to know what other people have to
deal with.
Like I want to know what is like to be
on those things and what and so I can
help those people maximally and say,
this is what I can tell you about what
meditation can do and this is what I can
tell you about what it can't do.
This is what I can tell you about how
physical practice can help,
but how they might not be able to help.
This is what I can say about how meds
have helped and it,
but if I can have good experience with
those different things and talk to lots
of other people who've done it,
then I can triangulate it on helping
people almost in a,
in a more effective way.
So when you get these surges,
you get this energy surge,
you exercise,
you hit the bag,
you feel great.
Yeah.
Does that even everything out?
I usually take it can discharge the
energy.
Then why on earth would you be thinking
about?
Well,
that seems insane because then as a very
organic solution to this problem,
but I don't know that it'll always will
work with the punching bag.
So it's working right now.
Right?
It hasn't perfectly worked every time.
What's,
what's.
When you say it hasn't.
Sometimes I go and I hit the bags and
afterwards the energy's still in me.
It may not have the same edge,
but it's still.
I can still feel it.
And when you say energy is really
interesting to someone who doesn't get
the surges I want,
I'm just trying to like,
um.
Do you feel like you're on caffeine?
Do you feel like a speed speed?
It feels like a nowhere.
So you wake up and you're on speed.
I'm on speed and it's like.
And there's nothing I did externally.
Nothing happened.
I didn't take anything.
I didn't do anything all of a sudden.
So this is the things.
There are corresponding thought process
that goes with this.
Is there a zest for life is fucking.
Life is awesome to me.
It's,
I want to go kick some ass.
It's pure exuberance.
That sounds great.
It is great.
But that's the problem of it.
It's great.
So you feed it so you're like,
you want more of it,
so you just,
it's like.
So basically it's like this.
It's also not always great for the
people around.
It's not always great for the people
around.
You were like this,
right?
We have our ups and downs.
This is like from foom foom and the more
you feed the up,
the higher you go,
but that means that the bigger you have
the fall.
So like that's what I've learned is that
when I,
when I feed the grandiosity of the
energy that exuberance,
like I'm super fun to be with at parties
for sure.
Like I'll do crazy shit.
That's usually when I've had all my
injuries,
my various breaks because I've been on
one of these crazy high.
So that's another reason not to do it.
But inevitably there's gonna be a part
where it's going to crash.
So.
So now my whole job is from being a
meditation teacher is I feel the energy
start to come up and I back off.
So it's like I let it just come through
me,
I try to let it just come up like a wave
and just and I and I and it's really
uncomfortable being in that vibrating
energy and not acting on it,
not saying some stupid shit or not like
being more whatever,
not acting on it and keeping it going.
I have to kind of let it.
So I just try to keep myself calm and
centered and I try to let it just feed
itself fruit now with the punching bag
or with the biking and with these things
that really can help with that process.
So I do think I might be on the verge of
it.
Maybe I won't do that,
you know,
maybe I won't,
but I don't know because it's.
The thing is dude,
it's fucking hard being at tufts to
anyone who is bipolar or be those ups
and downs.
It's hard to be in that.
It's exhausting every week.
It's like you don't,
you wake up,
you don't know who you're going to be
this week.
Who am I going to be today?
Or what?
Or if you're in a down place,
like now you've made all these plans
with somebody,
then you got to cancel the plans,
but you,
you're talking,
you were saying this is a slightly
bipolar situation for you.
This is so it's not.
I think the bipolar,
I'm not sure.
One of them,
there's bipolar one,
bipolar two.
One is more extreme like real mania
where you go and fucking buy 50 couches
and like,
hey honey,
I bought 50 couches.
We're going to put couches all over the
neighborhood.
You know,
like your classic Manic episode.
It doesn't go for me.
I never had that happen.
I just have the,
the Hypomania.
So like the lots of the energy.
But I don't go into total craziness.
And biologically what is the process
like?
What is actually happening to you that's
causing this?
I don't know.
Um,
there's no,
they don't understand that.
I mean,
so this is new for me.
I'm just,
I just found out two weeks.
So I haven't really done the research on
the brain science yet.
They do say there's a brain signature
just like there is for add,
for bipolar,
there's a particular signature of what,
uh,
of what it looks like.
It has some kind of dampening of the
frontal activity.
So probably a lot of activation in maybe
the Amygdala or something.
I don't know.
Uh,
all I know is from the inside,
it really feels different.
It feels like a,
um,
I mean it's,
I mean,
I'm sure people can relate.
Like when you've had a coffee and you've
got that vibrating energy or,
or you have or feeling super confident
about yourself,
but it's almost like your confidence
goes too far.
You're a little bit like overconfident,
you know,
you're,
you're delusional,
delusional.
It's a.
and then that.
And that actually happens in meditation
to that stage,
the upstage of meditation than to be
called the arising and passing.
You can get to a stage where suddenly
you really feel like you get it.
You.
Oh yeah,
I understand.
It's like what Dan said.
Yeah,
they're gonna put a fucking plaque here
on the wall.
I'm the best meditator on the planet.
Like because you got,
you're just,
all the energy is coming through you.
And then inevitably there was the crash.
So actually that is why I didn't get
diagnosed for so long.
I thought it was just meditation and
that it was,
I was just noticing the cycles because
of my meditation and it was really just
add.
And it wasn't until it started just to
become.
I started to see,
okay,
there is a real pattern here.
Like I need to just talk to somebody and
get some other perspectives on this.
I just might make it worth.
It's worth pointing out that it's highly
unusual and very courageous for somebody
in juxtaposition.
It's,
it's highly unusual for anybody to talk
about having mental difficulties at all
in our culture.
Unfortunately,
we need more people who are willing to
say,
you know,
I deal with anxiety,
depression,
bipolar,
um,
add.
But for somebody who's a meditation
teacher to do it because as jeff has
said that the traditional understanding
of meditation teacher is someone who's
got their shit together on every level.
For somebody who's a meditation teacher
to deal to come out and say,
yeah,
I have these challenges.
He's incredibly brave and also really
important because I think and,
and,
and working with Jeff on writing this
book,
one of the things you know,
there were times when the patterns that
he's describing were very annoying to me
to deal with as his coauthor,
but over time it actually,
I,
I started to see that he was wrestling
with this stuff and in many ways it felt
like a meditation teacher.
It was obvious to me that he is a
meditation teacher with Imposter
Syndrome and now I think he gets in,
I think you can hear it and what he's
saying,
that actually these challenges make them
a better teacher.
That he's more in touch with the things
that we're all dealing with and
sometimes on,
on an exponentially higher level of
degree of difficulty and that therefore
he better at getting under the hood and
helping other people with their mental
challenge.
Yeah.
Like so in many ways like what you were
experiencing for your own profession is
almost a gift.
It's why I say,
yeah,
because you have this unique opportunity
to explore your own consciousness in a
very challenging way and also to be
completely honest about it,
which is very,
very beneficial to not just your
students,
but a lot of the people that are
listening to this right now,
it's now,
it's now it's living inside the snout
because you get.
It's more.
It just makes everything more dramatic
so you can see the dynamics because it's
so frigging dramatic and you.
You're then able to see the more subtle
way it plays out for everyone because
the stuff I'm talking about,
it's just the human condition hand.
Everyone's got [inaudible] is struggling
with a version of this.
It may not be to that extreme thing,
but they but they got it or they have an
orthogonal challenge over here.
It's something a little bit different,
so you're.
You're continually training your
compassion for how hard it can be in
life,
but you're also learning very
practically how to work with the
dynamics of that stuff.
Is the downside of that,
the reaction to the upside or is there a
corresponding physical feeling?
I think of it as like a rope,
like you're,
you know,
you got things like this,
it's just physics will come.
It's just what comes up must come down
and mine is a bit unusual in that it's,
I'm more up,
I don't have a ton of.
I don't stay down long.
Sounds great.
So that's why it took so long to get
diagnosed.
But then.
But trust me that being up all is
deranged too,
you know,
it's like you're,
I,
I go back sometimes I had an experience
where I just was trying to fix up my
website,
look back at an old talk I did and like
that I was videos in this big room and
I'm like,
Holy Shit.
I was so manic,
you know,
I just thought I was crazy because it's
like,
what the fuck was I doing about the
memos you sent me when we're in the
book?
So say some credit.
What was the,
what was so crazy about the males?
So,
um,
you know,
I mean,
do you want to explain it?
Okay.
So we will be,
this is a book we wrote is for
beginners.
I wanted it to be really simple and know
we were doing it on a crazy deadline.
So we did a road trip across the country
in January 2017,
so not long ago.
And at the end of the road trip we,
we recorded all of it.
We got the transcripts back and we had
to hand the book in in June.
That set me up on a schedule where I had
to write a chapter a week,
which is insane because I have an anchor
to shows at ABC and I have a wife and a
child and it will be insane even if I
didn't have that.
And so my job was to write the
narrative,
the overarching structure of the book
and Jeff was going to write the
meditation instructions that got
inserted in.
And all I wanted from him was to give me
some basic fucking meditation
instructions.
I did not want an exit Jesus on,
on like the pawnee shots,
you know,
like I didn't need him to go through and
explain to me like the whole Pali Canon
from Buddhism or the,
you know,
do his version of the Bhagavad Gita.
But he would send me these memos with
his grandiose,
he'd be on a medic upswing,
but he would have these ideas about how
he was going to explain meditation as
it's never been explained before as a
series of exfoliation of the mind,
blah,
blah.
17 page,
17 pages of life of like tightly,
you know,
because like you get the energy comes up
and he gets super excited.
Now I'm just pumped and want to talk
about all these little kind of like a
complicated bits and put it all together
and create this really elaborate
scaffolding and a metaphor to describe
exactly how the mind works.
And,
and that's why,
you know,
that's why I had,
that's why I didn't get the book done
before I was working on with Dan.
I spent 10 years working on this book
about enlightenment,
about the,
about the progress of insight and
meditation.
And I just kept getting more and more
complicated and more because I kept.
I would kind of simplify it and get.
It'd be very sane.
I have it all understood.
And then I would suddenly go one of
those episodes
and it would,
I would explode it all and like
elaborate whole new dimensions of stuff
and it was like I would never get
anything done,
you know,
and,
and I want to say in your defense that
the memo,
because I've gone back and read the
memos,
they're great.
It's just not what I needed while
writing a very simple book on a deadline
and I would get these memos,
I look,
I don't know what to do with this and,
and so that actually you're putting
your.
So that is the reason why the ops are
challenging because when you're in an
up,
you're not really seeing the world as it
is.
Like this is a person who needs a very
particular thing.
If you're just centered,
you know that you respond with that,
but you're in your own story about
something and that is the part that's so
pernicious or are dangerous about,
about the ops and you know,
and so that.
And that happened in the process.
We're going to book,
but then we got to sort it out.
But yeah,
of course,
I know there's something about,
um,
being on an upswing like that and in
this kind of,
for everybody,
it's not just jeff and we're picking on
Jeff here,
but when we,
any of us is on an upswing or any of us
has just caught in any mental state.
Your,
your,
your capacity for empathy and compassion
goes way down because you're stuck in
your own story.
And uh,
the name of the game here at the end of
the day,
not withstanding by already stated,
misgivings about words like compassion.
That is where the rubber hits the road
because you can talk about performance
that is important.
But I think the real measuring stick for
how well you've trained your mind is,
are you an asshole?
Yeah,
that's huge,
right?
Like,
how well are you interacting with other
people?
That is the money.
Do you care enough about other people to
actually see who they are?
Yes.
To see the character in their face,
the,
you know,
what,
what they're really telling you.
Can you actually get out of your.
You just get out of your own bullshit
and see what's going on in front of you.
That's the name of the game.
Right,
and in the most awkward conversation did
you ever have or when people were just
talking at you?
Exactly.
Did Not even taking you into
consideration.
Yes.
Why would you even talk to that person
anyway?
You're not.
They're not.
They're just talking to themselves,
but you got to.
For me,
it's about what this journey is often
about.
Journey is another word that I don't
really like,
but what this exploration is all about.
Adventure,
whatever you want to call it.
As I see sometimes I'm that guy,
I'm that guy.
I'm not really listening,
and you got to see that.
You have to see that stuff in yourself
instead of just complaining about it in
others in order to really get to the,
to the good stuff,
which is actually then learning how to
listen and it's also like we're talking
about.
It's very important for people to hear
because everybody's that guy sometimes.
Exactly.
We may not want to admit it,
and many of us liked to spend a lot of
time complaining about how everybody
else is a Schmuck,
but you got to see that stuff.
It gets back to the snout,
man.
You got to see that stuff,
uh,
because actually that's the good stuff.
It's actually,
there can be a real pleasure,
truly a pleasure in seeing it.
There's a great expression from this
eminent spiritual teacher named Rom Dasa
lives in Hawaii for your.
Many of your listeners may have heard of
him.
He talks about how meditation doesn't
conquer your neuroses.
It makes you a connoisseur of your
neuroses.
You're like a Somali,
a,
of your own insanity.
And there's a real pleasure every time
you see a anger come up,
uh,
or your own selfishness come up.
Oh,
I see you.
I see that there's a real pleasure in
that because then in the scene you're
then not owned,
but you're not in it.
You're not in it.
That's playing the game well,
and that's what this game is.
Now,
for the uninitiated,
all this is very hard to absorb.
They're sitting back and listening this
long conversation and trying to put all
these pieces together.
What's the best first step to take
actually try meditation is the is the
best step to take and here's the thing
to know.
This doesn't require a ton of time.
I often point out to people that have
five to 10 minute a day habit is a great
habit.
I've spent.
Everybody wants to know what's the least
amount of meditation I can do and get
the advertise benefits of meditation.
All this stuff we've been talking about
in high minded terms,
but there are some easier to comprehend
benefits from meditation,
lower blood pressure,
boosted immune system,
literally rewiring key parts of the
brain that has to do with focus and
things like that.
People want to know what's the least I
can do to get that good stuff.
I spent.
We haven't cracked that by we.
I mean the scientific community that
studies meditation.
I'm actually part of it,
but uh,
I know a lot of these men and women,
they haven't figured out exactly what it
is,
what's the minimum dose,
but I've asked them,
you know,
it's five to 10 minutes,
probably enough in the general consensus
is probably enough to derive many of
these benefits.
But so that's the good news.
But I think the even better news is if
five to 10 minutes sounds like too much
for you,
one minute most days,
one minute daily ish,
is really enough to see what you need to
see.
What you need to see is that you're
fucking crazy.
You need to see it over and over again.
This is the schnauzer getting his snout
put in,
in the poop.
You need to have that happen to you over
and over again.
Why?
Because every time you see that,
every time you sit,
try to focus on your breath.
See that you've become distracted in
that moment.
That's the moment when most people think
I've failed at meditation is actually
the victory and when you see how crazy
you are,
when you've become distracted and learn
how to start again and again and again.
Every time you see that you've become
distracted.
That's a win and it when have really
towering consequences because then you
see that you don't have to be owned by
all that craziness.
You can recognize it.
You could nip it in its tracks.
Another thing that I think that people
should take into consideration about
this talk of this meditation and trying
to manage the mind is that one of the
big issues and struggles that we faced
with today is addiction to social media.
It's a giant and it is the exact
opposite of meditation.
It is this constant like clicking and
being distracted and just getting all
this weird input from stuff and it's
not.
I enjoy social media on occasion,
but you got to recognize that this is
something that can overwhelm your
consciousness
and I'm not going to present myself as
holier than thou and this because I to
enjoy it and sometimes I take it too
far.
There's no question about it.
I'll get lost in social media where
meditation is useful is because again,
what your training is self awareness.
You're just training to see your own
stuff clearly so that it doesn't own you
met in the course of meditation it
because if you have some meditation
under the belt when you're so deep in a
twitter whole that you're,
uh,
you know,
spent three hours on the thing.
Maybe meditation can kick in at some
point and say,
oh,
my stomach is bubbling,
my head is aching.
I haven't eaten.
I'm not ignoring my children.
And you can pull yourself out of the
spiral and you just get better and
better at doing that.
I don't think perfection is on offer.
I don't know that all of us are gonna
live like Shin Zen young,
where the university is just bubbling up
through us all the time.
When we're not enemies,
I'm editing for 50 years.
Okay,
so great.
That's nice to have those aspirational
figures out there.
It's also great to have masters out
there who can get in and help us with
our meditation practice for most of us
at a level of five to 10 minutes a day
or one minute a day or one minute.
Most days.
It's just that you're going to become
marginally less of a schmuck and that's
really valuable and it does not have to
be complicated.
Sit down for five minutes.
Do it for 10 minutes.
Notice your breath.
Then we get distracted to come back.
Notice what got you distracted.
That's it.
You do that.
You'll find your own way into these
insights.
You know you will start to learn how it
works and this is take the time to do
that and you don't even have to do it in
a sitting practice.
You could do it,
you know when you're exercising or
something.
It's just harder to do it when there's
more going on.
I mean normally we lead with that,
but since you're a beautiful Weirdo,
you took us into all sorts of.
Weird spaces and that's where we went
first and Jeff is in my view,
one of the best people in the world at
talking about meditation at the deep
end,
but normally we lead with what we just
discussed,
but you know,
such is life.
Well,
I think that this is an important aspect
of it to focus on that social media use
and this addiction that we have is
literally the exact opposite of this
mindfulness and meditation and really
concentrating on being completely free
of all these,
these devices and things that you're
distracting yourself.
Thing to think.
It's like living is making habits.
What habits are reinforcing you are what
you repeatedly do you.
So if you are just completely.
If you're training your attention to be
fragmented,
it's gonna only get more fragmented
because of the things just keep
changing.
They get deeper and deeper and deeper.
So at some point you need to start
training a different set
of circuits.
You know,
it's just about that.
It's about what you're going to train
and what you're not going to train.
Most of us don't think of life that way.
We land in life and you just start doing
stuff,
but the things you're doing are the
things that are going to become your
inevitable conditioning and that's a
very sobering thought,
but it's also liberating thought because
it shows you that if you can start to do
the stuff that's better for you,
better for your brain,
your body,
then you can start to reverse that stuff
as well.
Right.
Amen.
To what you just hadn't.
Just to amplify your point about this,
the mindless use of social media being
the opposite of meditation.
I actually think there's.
It's interesting.
I think the proliferation of
communication technology is in part why
meditation has become so in vogue
because people know on some level
whether they can,
whether they can articulate it or not,
it's something's wrong.
We are.
This is really interesting woman minutia
Zomorodi who has a podcast called note
to self and it's about all about our
relationship with technology and I was
talking to her recently.
She said,
we're conducting this massive science
experiment with these devices and we
don't know what the outcome's going to
be,
but it's happening globally and people
have a sense that something's off.
And that I think is why meditation has
become such a.
But you know,
actually I think what I think is really
interesting is if you guys heard of the
slow technology movement,
um,
there's a few different ideas around
this slow design or the basic idea is
that right now the interfaces that we
use,
these flat screens,
these,
uh,
and all the notifications,
the buzzing,
the flickers that's kind of blowing our
attention apart,
but that it's true.
So it's training the brain and the mind
and a particular kind of way.
But in the exact same spirit,
if you were to start to design these
interfaces in a way that according to
basic mental health principles,
you might be able to create a more
positive habits.
So it's just starting to think like
actually how could we design our to our
devices?
Our interfaces are technology in a way
that's promoting a more happiness,
more connection,
more of all the good stuff.
And that's a good question.
People are just starting to ask and I
think it's really,
really cool to like think,
think about things in that way that
it's.
It could be an opportunity,
there could be an opportunity with these
with the technologies to do something
really awesome.
So it's not like it's,
it's because they're neutral in a way.
It's just a tool.
It's how you use it.
The
tool and the way in which the tools
designed for allegation is that actually
many of these devices and platforms have
been designed specifically to me,
but that's not neutral.
They're like they're salty potato chips.
You can't stop eating.
Yeah,
I'm a but I will just put in one plug.
But while we're waiting for slow
technology to come to fruition,
there are ways that it's on us as users
to use these things wisely.
One thing I would say is as somebody who
does use twitter and instagram is a,
there's a great tweet from this guy,
Ian Bremmer who,
who's a big thinker about current
affairs.
His.
I think his pin tweet is something like
a.
If you're only following people you
agree with,
you're doing it wrong and I think
there's a way in which actually are
social media use in,
in,
in that we create these cocoons bubbles,
ideological echo chambers were only
following people who give us visceral,
satisfying,
ideological red meat.
If in fact you can use these platforms
and podcasts to listen to people with
whom you disagree and maybe you
communicate with them.
Then actually that is a thoughtful and
wise use of this technology and may
solve some.
What I would argue is the biggest
problem this country is facing right
now,
which is toxic,
tribalism.
Toxic tribalism is a really good way of
putting it.
That's like your.
Everyone's just stuck in their own
facebook feeds.
It's basically the facebook feed is your
reality.
Yeah,
but you can use facebook to connect with
your neighbors,
you know,
disagree with you,
and to actually be able to hear their
arguments in a way that isn't blindly
reactive.
It's about doing the rounds of the
community.
Can you actually go out there and do the
rounds of the video and check out some
different perspectives?
Yeah,
absolutely.
I think that's very important.
I do that a lot.
I,
I follow a lot of people that don't
agree with and I also try to talk to a
lot of people that don't agree with.
I think that's also important to and to
have some sort of common ground where
you can explore the ideas themselves and
not look at the person who presents the
ideas as your enemy.
That's a real problem today in this
country.
Obviously.
I agree.
We've never been more divided in terms
of right left and the ideologies and
especially when you have such a divisive
president.
I mean you have this,
this person at the very top of the heap
who literally chastises people and mocks
them on twitter.
I mean you have a,
a mocking insulting president.
It's fucked up.
Who uses social media and there's a
trickle down from that.
Unquestionably.
There's people that look to the guy who
was at the top of the food chain as
being the one who we should model
ourselves after in some way,
shape or form.
And so the idea that people are leaning
in that direction now where they weren't
for eight years,
it's weird.
It's a weird time for interaction and
debating ideas.
Yeah.
Well,
it's also,
again,
one of the negative things with social
media is that thing of just like the
whole trolling thing,
you could just say whatever you want
because you don't actually have a real
human being right in front.
You can't see them.
They're hurting either hurt.
So people are just this unbridled
reactivity that just creates more
activities into my own twitter feed
snowballs and people saying things to me
that they.
I doubt they would ever say to my face,
yeah,
yeah.
I mean that's what we do.
That's what people do.
And that's one of the things that's so
bizarre about the lack of social cues.
You're not standing in front of someone.
There's no consequences.
It's,
it's communication in incredibly
unnatural and unrealistic way.
All our lives.
The time that we were monkeys coming out
of trees are in exchanges,
have been face to face until very
recently.
Yes.
And again,
I know we're flogging the meditation
thing and I don't want to present it as
a panacea because it's not and nor is it
the only approach to increasing the
sanity quotion in our society,
which badly needs to happen,
but again,
I do think that meditation,
mindfulness,
that sort of self awareness that's
generated through meditation can play a
positive role in this,
the aforementioned toxic tribalism
because if you're so caught up in your
own story,
you can't,
as we've discussed,
have the kind of empathy that is needed
to understand people who have different
views and meditation is a way among
other techniques to kind of just reduce
how seriously,
how personally you're taking your own
inner chaos.
And I think that can be very useful
right now.
Do I think everybody in the world's are
automatically gonna hurl themselves into
the Lotus position?
No,
but I think each individual can take a
personal responsibility for making
things less crazy.
I agree with you 100 percent.
I think that's a good way to wrap this
up.
Yeah.
Well good.
Thank you very much.
Thank [inaudible] else.
You know,
any.
Anything else to add before we wrap
this?
Thank you for putting me in the tank.
I really appreciate that.
There's an expression of gratitude is
the expectation of future favors,
so
I expect to be back in that tank anytime
you let me know when you're in town.
We'll hook it up and by the way,
there's hundreds of tank centers all
over the country.
I know.
I'm sure you're in New York,
right?
So they.
I'm sure they have them.
I know they have them in New York.
They have them all over California now,
so they're everywhere.
All of the states.
So find them.
Thank you guys for the book to people.
The title meditation for Fidgety
skeptics.
There you go.
That's it.
Bye everybody.
Three hours.
Mm.