Experience.
Louis is here from unbox therapy,
sweating our beautiful new
equipment that doesn't work.
Especially our new fucking
super awesome HD set up.
We were supposed to be live in HD by now,
but someone fucked us.
They sold us this fucking Sony HD box
that's supposed to work great with
Ustream.
Doesn't fucking work at all with Ustream.
Not only is it not work with you steam,
it's never been proven
to work with Ustream.
Use Dreams.
Never got one from them to
test it lies and propaganda.
At least.
At least it's pretty looking though.
It looks dope as fuck.
So we'll probably wind up going with a
tri caster cause this fucking sack of
shit isn't working correctly.
And we're watching,
um,
that we,
we talked about zero before the podcast
started that has anything to do with
tech.
Everything was about sexual allegations,
sexual assault allegations,
whether or not someone should be rioting,
whether or not these fucking idiots that
are closing down the one on one freeway
in La to protest something
that happened in another state.
It's crazy times.
The yellow is that about
all these crazy white,
it's all white people that
are protesting like in,
do you,
have you seen New York City
in New York City as well?
Oh yeah.
They won't show it on the news
because it's like everyone's like,
it's all white people.
It's all these like wow.
Emo,
white people,
social justice warriors demanding justice.
I Dunno.
It's rampant.
Everybody's,
everybody's trying to latch on it to
express themselves through this high
profile situation.
Well,
I think that there's no doubt there can
be no doubt that there's a real issue
with police brutality.
There can be no doubt.
There's many instances,
and this is not the best one.
You know,
Jamie was talking about it before the
podcast that the 12 year old boy who was
shot in Cleveland with a fake gun,
a toy gun,
like seconds after the cops arrive.
That is way scarier to me.
That kid that was shot in a
Walmart who had a toy gun,
that is way scarier to me.
You know?
Then even asking questions,
talking,
trying to find out what's going on,
they're just shooting.
Yeah.
It's funny.
It's a funny thing about which news
stories prevail and become the mainstream
ones they need to be.
This is sort of perfect and appealing
package that people want to share and talk
about and sort of that
drives conversation.
They the,
the really like obviously
terrible ones that nobody has,
you know,
like it's hard to have an opinion about
that other than that's terrible when
when it comes to like a
kid shot with a toy gun
versus the other one.
The other situation in a Michael Brown.
Yeah,
the Michael Brown situation where
for some reason they're appear,
you know,
there,
there's,
there's these defined sides
on that and that thing.
There's very little gray
area for discussion.
It's like pick your team.
We were talking about
this before the show,
but I was watching on Twitter,
a white rapper and a black guy arguing
and the black guy was on the side of the
cop that shot the kid,
the,
and you know,
it wasn't an asshole,
wasn't a Republican.
He was saying,
look,
the reality is this guy had robbed a store
just before then had been involved in
a bunch of criminal type behaviors.
And there's witnesses saying
that he charged the cop,
like you don't know what happened.
And the,
the white rapper was arguing
with him and he was saying,
you are blind to the facts in
your desire to be down and,
you know,
which had to hurt the white rapper.
Right.
You know,
black I accuses you of fucking posing,
but there's,
I mean,
that's,
but that's what's happening
in the street right now,
isn't it?
I mean,
it's the same thing.
It's that it's,
uh,
it's appealing for people to latch onto
a cause in order to help try to identify
themselves.
Yeah.
You know,
to get something out of it,
to get some kind of very
good way of defining it.
Yeah.
To get some kind of a,
I dunno,
like they like this,
this kind of a wind can be a success for
them that they can express themselves
through,
uh,
these kinds of issues.
But obviously it's not about,
it's not just about a cop shooting a guy.
Right.
It's like in this particular case,
it appears to me that it's part of a
much bigger issue in specifically that
area.
Uh,
and,
and probably the way of life.
They're like,
is it really,
you need to be a certain kind of
person to just jump on a riot train,
right?
Like,
oh,
wicked,
perfect,
let's burn down more shit.
Right?
Yeah.
And I mean,
sometimes it will be,
it's not necessarily just race.
Sometimes it will be a
certain set of circumstances,
like a sports team loses and people
go crazy and start smashing cars and
whatever,
and it,
it's somehow attracts
other people to that,
to that,
uh,
agenda.
I remember,
uh,
in Toronto during,
I think it was the g 20 summit when
it was like the first time ever,
people had like smashed when I
was living downtown at the time.
And I had a,
I had my first kid will and he was little.
And I remember sitting at home inside
and knowing that people were out there
smashing windows going like,
how in God's name are
these people justifying it?
How,
how do they believe for a moment that
smashing his Starbucks is what's going to
change anything.
It's such a weird way to
try and get what you want.
Is it,
is it any,
it's not even a Po.
I Dunno.
It seems to me like the equivalent
of kicking and screaming as an adult.
Oh,
it's,
it's even worse.
It's so idiotic.
There was a Twitter post today that I
read where this guy was standing in front
of a BMW in
Oakland,
California,
which by the way is nowhere fucking near
Ferguson and the windows were smashed
and it said,
fuck corporations,
corporations.
Let me tell you something.
You dumb cunt.
You wrote that on a phone that
was made by a fucking corporation.
You piece of Shit fucking dunce and you
broadcast the damn picture via another
corporation that allowed you to even have
the voice to reach the people that you
ended up reaching with it.
And what has BMW done
besides make awesome cars?
What have they done this so terrible
besides making fantastically engineered
automobiles that you couldn't
possibly come up with yourself?
Yeah,
I don't,
I don't know specifically,
but I think it is very strange that
people pick and choose which corporations
are there for them and
which ones are against them.
Because ultimately this entire economic
ecosystem is what allows everyone to
survive and what allows anyone
to have any kind of wellbeing.
It's not perfect.
Everybody knows that.
But when you burned down and
Mcdonald's in your neighborhood,
you're taking away jobs from the
people that actually need them.
You know what I mean?
Like,
or the Walmart or whatever,
whatever it was at the destruction
that's happening over there.
It's like by,
by force,
you want to throw a Tantrum,
but at the same time the consequence
is bigger than you personally.
It's a,
there are,
I'm sure plenty of upstanding citizens
who just wanted to go back to work.
And this corporation that
you're angry with is actually,
uh,
something that people rely on in
the case of this BMW dealership.
I mean,
you're talking about such
an unrelated institution.
Yes.
So unrelated Starbucks.
There's people that were guarding
Starbucks and we're freaking out.
Fuck Starbucks.
You know,
what about the people?
What about the people?
People pay for that stuff.
You know that Starbucks is a franchise,
like someone owns it.
They had an air earned money,
save it,
get a bank loan,
go out of their way,
hire employees,
put together a business model.
I mean Jesus fucking Christ,
this childlike view of the world,
and this is not exonerating police,
this is not,
and I feel for the police because I think
their job is almost impossible to be a
cop and a crime ridden
area is almost impossible.
There's almost nothing you can do to
stem the tide unless you could go back in
time and somehow or another,
not even the parents of the children
who grew up to be criminals,
but the parents of the parents that the
children that grubs were criminals and
somehow reach them,
somehow educate them or provide them
with some sort of counseling or some,
some factor that's going to change
the way they view the world and view
community and view each
other and give them
opportunity.
Give them some sort of a way to
not be involved in a life of crime,
not be involved in these horrible cyclical
repeating relationships that seem to
occur in these terrible areas.
So many factors and,
and in many cases,
the areas themselves
reinforce the behavior,
uh,
through various means.
Like I used to watch the first
48 have you ever seen that show?
And you get to see how like immediately
after a crime takes place what the cops
are working with,
uh,
as far as the,
the evidence,
but also,
uh,
the witnesses and trying to get anybody
to say anything about what happened,
but kind of like a super core,
fundamental level.
If you don't want to tell the police that,
you know,
who killed somebody,
is that really any different
than participating?
Like then being a part of it,
it's so weird to me that that's considered
to be an acceptable thing amongst
that community right there.
The no snitching thing
and no snitching thing.
It's like,
hmm.
That to me just sounds like you're afraid.
That to me just sounds like the actual
power within that group doesn't lie
within,
uh,
the police or authority or whoever,
but it lies somewhere else.
But you're somehow justifying
it to yourself by saying,
oh,
I really am participating
because I chose not to snitch.
Well,
if you live in that community though,
and you did snitch,
the consequences would be dire.
I mean,
it's not something that's like an easy
thing to stand up for if you're living in
a crime ridden.
Sure.
But then you also shouldn't
expect anything to change.
Boy,
that's,
it's weird to put the ownness on the,
the,
the people that are poor and
they're living in these areas.
I see.
I don't,
I,
it's not,
it's not completely that way.
Obviously there are things that could,
could happen surrounding that
world that could help it out,
but ultimately to get
yourself up out of there,
it has,
doesn't it have to be,
I mean,
who can really walk into that community
who's not a part of it and change and
change something.
It's not like,
it's not like you're wanted there,
you know?
It's not like when the police go in there,
they're treated in a certain way
because maybe the life they lead is so
different than that of
the individuals in that,
in that lifestyle themselves,
you know,
well also that US versus them
mentality gets some printed.
It gets cemented in,
in terms of sports teams.
So imagine how crazy it gets when you're
dealing with crime ridden neighborhoods
and police.
It's so hard to break free of.
I worked as a security guard for a very
short period of time when I was a kid
and um,
it was a place called great woods.
Uh,
it's like a concert
place in Massachusetts.
And one of the things that I remember
really clearly is realizing that we had
all developed this us versus
them mentality at the,
there was these crazy drunk concert
goers who would cause trouble and do all
kinds of crazy shit.
And then there was us and we had
developed as very clear us versus them
mentality that I saw people,
I saw people act on this against
people that weren't a problem,
you know,
and I remember watching it,
kind of step back from it,
but a part of it as well because
I'm wearing a security outfit.
I'm going,
okay,
we're doing like cop shit.
This is like what cops do.
Yeah.
And then I was thinking like,
man,
I wonder if that's just like what happens.
And you know that Stanford study
that they did where they took,
uh,
they,
they did like a prison study where they
put people in jail and they made one
group become security guards
and one group become prisoners.
I believe it was Stanford wasn't Stanford.
Um,
but they,
they had to call it off.
Like they had to cut it short
because the people that were,
the guards had been so shitty to the
fucking people that were the prisoners.
They were like,
well,
this is like inherent human
behavior or something like that.
It's almost like there's a pattern that
people slide into that unless they're
really consciously aware of not doing it.
Yeah.
The Stanford prison experiment.
Wow.
Yeah.
And it was a really eye opening to a
lot of people that is power is a very
corrupting thing.
Right.
Especially that kind of ultimate power.
Like someone's in jail or you have a gun,
you can shoot them and you're allowed to.
Yeah.
It's a,
it's a,
it's an unfortunate thing that that's
the only way to govern ourselves that
we're forced to to do
so at the end of a gun,
like,
yeah.
Right.
You hope that that,
that doesn't have,
have to have to happen frequently,
but ultimately that's part of what's
holding this whole damn thing together.
You know,
I drive down the highway
to get here and he's like,
Jesus,
everybody is in their lane.
All of these different mechanisms at play
to keep order to keep things happening
and as smooth sort of way.
And yeah,
there's crazy shit going on elsewhere,
but we've also done one hell of a job
of having the vast majority of people
comply.
Yes.
Based on the system.
That's something that people overlook
when they think about chaos and mom
society,
like God is so safe and organized in
comparison to the number of people.
Yes.
I was in Mexico City reasonably
right for the UFC first time.
Yeah.
Wow.
And Mexico City is first of all,
everybody thinks like,
oh my God,
you don't get kidnapped on the God.
He didn't get shot.
First of all,
they are the nicest people.
Mexicans in Mexico City are so friendly,
they're so nice.
But their version of order and our
version of order are very different there.
You know what,
stop lights,
optional gridlock.
You know how we have grid lock?
Occasionally someone fucks up and they
get stuck in an intersection when the
light changes and everybody beeps at them.
In Mexico there is only gridlock,
like there's no getting out of it.
The lights change
and it's just bumper to
bumper in both directions.
And I saw people that were trying to
merge and they would just pull in,
they would just pull in front of
everybody and you're talking about six,
seven lanes and these people
just pull into the lane and,
and people would just sort of stop
and some people wouldn't stop them.
They didn't have to pull forward.
And it was fucking crazy and it,
and I'm laughing,
I'm talking to the guy that
was driving and I was like,
is this normal?
And he's like,
ah,
these none,
no.
This way in America,
In America,
when it's a red light,
people actually stop.
It's amazing.
It is amazing how well
trained we actually are.
I mean a light comes up
and everyone complies.
The odd,
it's a,
it's a very minor outlier that actually
disobeys that even though it's a fairly
simple thing and most of the time
no one's probably going to die.
But we,
it's just,
it seems like when you're
relatively well taken care of,
it's so much easier to
just fucking comply.
Yes.
And when you,
when everything's okay,
when your belly is full and you
know your children are safe,
the minute that you take away
the necessities all it's like,
yeah,
let's go.
There's a thin veneer.
Yes.
Oh they days and you get like these
crazy people like Zombie apocalypse type
people.
Like it's all gonna crumble.
But truthfully speaking,
how much would it take?
You know,
I mean it's not like you need a complete
collapse of the infrastructure to get
people panicking.
I remember that big
blackout on the East Coast,
uh,
a few years back where it knocked gas
stations out and knocked most people's
houses out and you know,
people were running their air conditioners
too much and that the panic was real
there.
People were like,
people had to talk to each other,
a one to one and be like,
you know which piece,
which pizza place still has food?
Which ovens are running off propane?
Like it was dipping quick
and I was like a week,
my friend Tommy was in Connecticut
when that big snow storm hit and he was
telling me how they had a drive
hours just to use a cell phone.
It'll drive like two hours
to find a cell phone service.
You had to find food like we went,
he was saying that we went to,
he,
you know he and his girl had went to
Dunkin donuts for food and there was a
giant line outside of Dunkin donuts
cause it was the only place to that end.
Exactly.
Putting your body exactly.
Any calories.
That's what happened at,
that's exactly what happened in my
area when it originally happened is
essentially you had like one pizza place
feeding the entire community until the,
until they ran out.
And,
but it really exposes the
fact that we have such,
this kind of gets into
the world of technology,
but like basic skills like sort
of just being a human skills,
survival skills week.
Yeah.
In general,
in general.
Oh across society.
If we were forced to rely on our
own beans to deal with like a B,
c Jesus,
take,
take away the cell phone on its own.
I mean,
I'm not,
I'm uh,
we were talking about doing a video
like 24 hours without technology.
Like maybe we'll get a map and
we'll have a set of challenges.
Like,
try not to use your phone,
but having,
being,
you know,
thinking about that as
I was on my way out.
I mean,
I'm on Google maps,
I'm analyzing traffic.
I'm rerouting based on accidents.
Right.
It's like take that away.
And how much more ineffective am
I at participating in all of that?
Yeah.
I have a friend who doesn't
use the navigation systems.
He still uses maps.
Wow.
I looked in his car like,
what?
Where's your navigation system?
And he goes out the old paper,
Matt,
when he's an author too.
I mean,
he's,
um,
he's a wealthy guy and he goes,
I just don't,
I don't want to deal with it.
I go,
we want to do with what
the things are awesome.
Like,
what the fuck are you talking about?
Like you,
you don't want to be a part of the new
information that's coming your way.
That tells you how to be more convenient,
more,
more efficient.
You can get around this accident.
Don't you want to know it's there?
Like why would you,
so what do you think that's about wanting
to be like living in the fucking past,
this longing for nostalgia.
Like you know he wants to fucking fall
smoke signals to find the village.
I don't understand it.
It's funny that anybody who's
nostalgic like that or avoiding change,
they only want to go back so far.
They don't want,
they don't want to go the caveman style.
It's like it's just a,
everyone picks a point in their life.
Even now I have friends who have
picked that point like they're done.
This is as far as they're
going with technology and like,
you know,
you're showing them a smartwatch
or whatever it might be in,
or even even,
not that like it could be a piece
of software or social media,
like they're on team Facebook,
but Twitter's too much or something.
It's funny how at some point people
flip the switch and they're like,
this is as far as I'm
going with this damn thing.
Yeah.
There's that weird thing that people do.
Uh,
you know,
you have kids and I have kids who
I've talked to many people at,
man,
I wouldn't want to bring
kids up today in this world.
I'm like,
what are you talking about?
People brought up kids when they were
woolly mammoths when they're fucking saber
tooth tigers and like one,
one in a hundred infants survive.
What are you talking about?
This is like the best
time to have a kid ever.
You know,
they have amazing doctors.
Yeah,
you were.
You really have very little to worry about
and the kid has so many advantages of
themselves from a learning perspective.
I am amazed.
I have a five and a three year old at how,
you know,
the unfiltered,
maybe unfiltered is a bad word because
I don't want them going everywhere that
they want to go online maybe.
Right,
right.
Yet.
But the idea that they're in control of
the information that they participate
in,
it's like a huge deal to me,
that they're not just flipping on the
TV and sitting through whatever is
programmed for them.
Instead they have the freedom to select
whatever it is that's interesting to
them.
And I know that in my life,
when I started to really
identify the things that I liked,
it was when I really started to progress
in what I was capable of personally.
That's the essence of
education,
at least the best kind when you have a
basic kind of draw to a particular topic
and then you get there
and then you retain it.
That's,
I mean that's really the whole package.
And uh,
I don't know,
you know,
if we talked about education
the last time I was on here,
but I mean,
I remember growing up and not giving
a shit about a particular topic.
And then all of a sudden when
the Internet was amazing,
I find myself hours deep into a
particular article or I'm on Wikipedia.
It's like,
what am I doing right?
What am I doing?
The old me would have
thought that I was an idiot.
You know,
like,
dude,
get out and do something cool.
Why are you,
but it's amazing how the context shifts
the entire conversation when you're
doing it for yourself.
When you're driving your own car,
ship,
whatever.
All of a sudden things become enticing
and interesting that when there was like
a dictator pointing down saying,
this is the curriculum,
it just wasn't the same way.
It's also the enthusiasm of whoever's
telling you about the subject too.
Right.
There's some people that
can talk to you about like,
I knew the grass.
Tyson is my favorite example because
he's so passionate about space and about
astrophysics and when he's
talking about these things,
it becomes fascinating.
Yeah.
Whereas you can watch a lecture that's
given by someone who's just has no
interest in the subject,
or excuse me,
no interest in teaching this subject.
They're just,
they're just relaying information.
They're just getting through it and they
think that all they have to do is plow
through it without any charisma,
without any,
that's what I was going to,
I was going to use the exact same word,
is I think charisma is not something
that's abundant amongst people.
It's a very special thing that some have,
some don't.
And it's like,
it's not a prerequisite
for becoming a teacher.
It's not like,
wait,
let's evaluate their charisma.
Right.
No,
it's,
it's a,
uh,
an institutional kind of
approach to how do you pump out,
you know,
how do you factory farm teachers,
right.
And,
and so it's unfortunately
not a very difficult thing.
Well,
I don't,
I don't want to go that far.
I mean,
it,
it does take work to become a teacher,
but it's not like,
it's not like you're,
you're prequalifying them to be
entertaining or do you do a good job of,
of the things that lock a
person's eyeballs onto you.
And so there's the,
the ratio of teachers that are charismatic
versus ones that ended up there is,
I don't know that you're ever
going to be able to fix that.
No,
I don't know.
I don't know if you are either.
It's like trying to find charismatic
people to explain any subject to you.
Charismatic people that,
you know,
our managers have an office
arithmetic people that you know,
talk to you at a hospital about
what happened to your kid.
You know what I mean?
It's just like the charisma or none that,
I didn't even know that's the word.
But genuine enthusiasm,
passion,
passion is so contagious.
When something happens in the world,
uh,
and you,
you,
you can,
you can have two options.
One is just the facts
laid out to you in a very
bland,
monotone way.
And the other one is someone who's
extremely passionate about the subject.
Two talks about it with
like great emotion and,
and,
and understands the significance of the
information and how you are going to
react to it and has this understanding
of the interpersonal reaction or
relationship that's so huge to,
to taking in the information,
to absorbing it.
I think that the enemy of that
is the idea of curriculum.
The idea that there is a,
a very direct and concrete way of learning
something like you have this list of
things at,
by the end of this course,
this person's going to know
this and that and that,
and they're going to be tested on it.
If I was at,
uh,
a teacher or a charismatic
person or whatever,
it's like,
I don't,
I don't want to just be your puppet,
your robot up there following the
set of guidelines that you set forth.
They have very little freedom in what
they can bring into that conversation
against what's been approved by whatever
body is responsible for producing that,
that information.
And you know,
and oftentimes it's like the same guy
who's standing up there as the guy who's,
who's selling you the textbook.
And there's like this weird,
this weird kind of thing baked into
it where it's not where it's about do.
It's like the path of least resistance.
It's about not ruffling any feathers.
It's about just getting from a to B to c
without really having a strong point of
view.
But isn't it also about like you have
to have the basic building blocks.
Yes.
And then from there you have to or you
should find something that you're truly
interested in and then pick a career.
But at what point,
at what point do you think that an
individual has the basic building block?
Right?
Where does it happen?
Because my opinion it
happens far too late.
I don't think we were encouraged at a
young age to really hyper focus on the
things that are interesting to us.
Yeah,
I think you've got a good point there
because I think that kids that do find
something that they really enjoy early,
they have an an awesome headstart in like,
like they have hope as to like
what they would like to do,
I guess.
You know what I mean?
Like if you talked to someone who is
really involved in pick a field computer
programming,
they want to be a game developer and
they're 14 years old and they already
started coding and they're
doing something like,
well this kid is on a path.
Whereas you know,
some people are 20 and they're ne'er do
wells and they're just fucking laying
around eating chips and then
trying to find their path.
And I just got to find something
I'm really interested in.
Meanwhile,
as 14 year old brother is reading coding
magazines and already like reading,
you know,
reading about John Carmack and how you
started off in software and you know,
he's like,
he's on a path,
you know,
and getting on a path can give you so
much energy and momentum and it makes it
so exciting.
And
an argument would be that would be that,
well maybe that's not really where
their head was going to be at.
Maybe you closed some door and that's,
that's like the fear,
right?
That's what the,
that's what like parents are
thinking and the kids themselves,
that they need to have this vast array
of subject matter that they're proficient
in because God forbid they end up wanting
to do something they're not prepared
for.
But that's like,
that's like a weird way of
looking at it in my opinion.
I think some people,
I think everybody at some point in their
lives has a particular skill that's
worth exploring,
but oftentimes he doesn't
fit into the window of,
of what will be acceptable at that time.
Right.
And also your parents sometimes discourage
you from that if it seems like it's a
tricky subject or it's
difficult to succeed in it.
Like my parents were not into
me being a comedian at hall.
Right.
You know,
when I told my mom was
going to be a comedian,
she was like,
you're not even funny.
And I was like,
Oh shit.
Oh mom,
fucking brutal.
You want to know something though?
Think about the alternative
of your mom saying,
oh perfect,
you're the funniest guy I've ever heard.
Like,
I know guys like that too where their
moms or their biggest fans and it hasn't
done very,
they're very much about them.
That's a good point.
Like sometimes it's better if
they present you with a challenge.
Like I'll show you,
you know,
like you,
if you get too much encouragement or
a distorted version of your actual
skillset,
that can be bad too.
Jamie,
something's going on in my throat,
man.
Come on and make some tea.
We have tea,
tea back there
fighting off something but not like
a cold or something in my throat.
Like I feel physically good but I'm going
a lot and I know that shit is annoying
as fuck to you folks out there.
I think we were a reading
before we got going.
Is that dude from CBC that was
facing sexual assault charges.
How do you say his name?
John Gomez.
Meshy that is a weird subject
and a hard subject for me.
I have three daughters.
And when I read about dudes beaten up,
women especially,
um,
this guy who's like this
really left wing progressive,
sweet voice guy who would do interviews
and talk to people like this,
pretty much the idea that that guy
was beating women up and you know,
and doing it under the guise,
I mean,
who the fuck knows what the reality is?
But the allegations are that he
was doing it under the guise of,
um,
fantasy or sexual fun.
I mean,
what would you call it?
Bondage.
Yeah,
that's what it is.
And it's funny because I remember
when that craziness was going on,
when 50 shades of grey came out,
it's like everybody on the subway
train had a copy and I didn't,
obviously I didn't,
but it blew up.
And I remember thinking like,
this is the first time that bondage s
and m has really permeated pop culture,
like in a big way.
And the movie is coming out soon too.
And I know that he went so far as to
reference 50 shades of grey in his
argument.
Meaning that in some way he
felt that that enabled him,
uh,
some leeway.
Yeah.
Right.
It's,
that's,
that was a really weird
thing to me is like the,
the acceptability of that way of doing
things like between what somebody wants
to do and doesn't want to do.
I mean,
when you're engaging
with somebody sexually,
how do you,
if all of a sudden,
culturally you have this huge book
that x number of women reads or read,
sorry,
how much more likely are
they to put up with that?
Even if it's not,
you know what I'm saying?
What I'm trying to get at?
Yeah.
I D is that book about beating
them up a 50 shades of grey?
I Dunno.
I,
I don't,
I think it's just mostly just rough
sex and bondage tying up a whipping,
that kind of shit.
But I think he did.
I think it exposed a world of
sexual fantasy that wasn't,
I mean,
that shit was so mainstream.
Yeah.
You know,
I think for the average
soccer mom or whatever,
it wasn't in,
in their lexicon,
pre 50 shades of gray.
Now I'm not,
I'm not blaming the book or whatever.
I mean,
people are going to do
what they're gonna do.
And this guy was obviously behaving
that way long before based on the
accusations long before
that book even came out.
But,
uh,
it seems to me that he,
his point is that,
or at least his defense is
that this was simply rough sex.
Right?
Right.
And that was working for him for a
bit because the initial accusations,
as far as I know,
were sexual partners.
He had had girlfriends,
right.
But then these other accusations started
coming out about girls who wouldn't
participate,
who are just getting,
showing up and getting beat
up and being asked to leave.
And there was no sexual element at all.
So it,
you know,
it appears that the guy has some kind of,
uh,
issue.
Uh,
I don't know why it's so disturbing to me,
but what,
what gets me is these guys that
are like these really sweet like,
like,
like soft-spoken,
like you know,
you,
you just picture him cuddling.
You couldn't even picture him fucking,
you know what I mean?
Like I couldn't picture that guy with
stuffing a girl in the corner of a couch
fucking hammering away.
I wouldn't think of him being doing
anything going down in that way.
In that way.
You almost see them as more of a
Predator like the printer because psycho
fucking Ted Bundy type sociopath.
Well there's something about someone
who is like really like projects,
an image and the image is like
the like the Cosby situation.
Perfect example projects.
This image of this wholesome,
super squeaky clean family man who doesn't
swear admonishes of the comedians for
swearing using bad words,
talking about sex gets really angry.
Them calls them up.
The famous Eddie Murphy bit where Bill
Cosby calls him up and tells him to stop
swearing and then he calls up Richard
Pryor and Richard Pryor tells him did,
did people laugh?
Did you get paid?
Tell bill to have a coke and
a smile and shut the fuck up.
Classic.
Right.
Well you do.
And when the guy and Richard
Pryor who's just fucking,
everything's on the table,
man,
everything's on the table and scold.
Yeah.
Light himself on fire.
Comfortable to know
where you stand with it.
Yeah,
that's my dog.
yeah,
yeah man.
If you're willing to go that far on that,
then you're probably not hiding anything.
There's nothing scarier
than somebody hiding shit.
Exactly when you think about it.
But the interesting thing about the Cosby
situation is that it's the accusations
or date rape,
which to me is,
well I don't,
wouldn't even say date rape.
I would say rape and I would say,
well the war,
the worst kind of race,
sorry,
I was referring just to the drug.
Right?
Like it wasn't date rape
in the sense that like uh,
he,
you know,
he was on a date or whatever.
Like he held him down like he
did the difference in that.
I'm not saying it's any different in,
it's not any more excusable
or anything like that.
I know.
All,
I'm all I'm saying is that,
uh,
trying to prosecute that,
oh,
your,
your point is the,
what's the woman,
what's the story?
What's the,
the,
the accusation.
I was,
I was completely cognizant.
I woke up in somebody else's clothes,
like I read her,
her account,
the original,
uh,
accuser who nobody was listening to at
least for the first few years after the
accusation.
Uh,
I woke up in his apartment,
don't know how I got there
and I was wearing his clothing
and I was throwing up.
That's the accusation,
right?
Right.
Well,
what a woman has to do,
well,
I shouldn't say I shouldn't
put it on the woman,
but the only way to prove is
to immediately get a drug test,
uh,
call the cops.
And you know,
I mean,
but a lot of women in those scenarios
are fucking terrified and scared.
And not only that you're dealing
with like way back into the 60s.
And there was,
you know,
like what kind of drug tests
were even available back then?
We,
what could they test for?
How could they please?
So the drug itself and that
happening to people was so new.
Right.
I don't even know that somebody would,
we would realize the steps
necessary and maybe he had the gun.
But imagine you're that.
What was,
she was like 18 at the time.
You're her and you're,
you want to make an accusation against
bill fucking Cosby and nobody wants to
listen to nobody.
I mean,
he's a giant superstar.
he was a superstar in the 60s I believe
his first TV show us in 65 I think I
spy.
I mean,
he was an Emmy award winner
a lot before I was born.
Crazy.
You know,
and that,
the thing that kills
me though is that like,
like this Ghomeshi guy,
he was this like sweet guy.
Like you,
you,
you saw him as this,
you know the father figure on
the Huxtables and he had this,
you can never imagine that guy dropping
Queloz into a chick's drank and just,
it's so fucked up and it's almost more
fucked up than if the allegations are
like,
let's pick a guy like old dirty bastard.
You know what I mean?
Rest,
rest in
peace.
But if old dirty bastard
did something awful,
you would go,
well let's,
you know,
like I was shocked because you know
where you stand with old dirty.
Yeah,
right,
right.
You meet old dirty or
like I already get it man.
You know,
and not to say that he was a rapist,
but yeah,
it's,
there is something creepy about,
uh,
you know the whole Ted Bundy character,
how old dirty bastard is probably
less likely to do that too,
which is more fucked up.
Right.
He was probably a guy who just like,
because women knew what you mean.
Look at his gold grill.
You knew what the fuck because the
creepiest people are the best actors.
Right,
right.
The creepiest people or the guy who
talked to you on the radio like this and
then get you alone and you fucking
cotton punch in the face like,
whoa.
You imagine and up.
Especially if you're a woman and you're
into those like emo dudes and you see
him and you're like,
oh,
this guy is sweet,
he's going to cuddle and I'll be able to
get really close to him before we have
sex.
Know he's punching you in the head,
stuff in your head under a pillow
and tried to suffocate you itself.
It must be such a mind fuck to be
in that scenario after the fact.
You know,
to find yourself there and be like,
wow,
that was not expected.
STANDUP citizen,
we're assuming he did this by the way.
I mean we don't to be careful.
He's tried to sue the CBC,
but he did.
He dropped,
dropped it.
Well,
if you drop it,
I mean if you're suing and you're in the
middle of the stuff he's charged now.
He's charged now as of
a couple of days ago.
So yeah,
I mean he's not,
he's not convicted yet,
but there are a number of accusations
on the table and that's gonna that can't
bode well for him.
Yeah.
Oh,
who the fuck knows what actually
happened in that particular case?
But what just drives me up the wall is
that someone's capable of doing that.
It's,
it's,
it goes back and is sort
of a very loose way.
It goes back to what we're
talking about with Ferguson.
It's like our real issue when
it comes to any kind of a crime,
any kind of a horrible scenario,
is what turns a person into the
type of person that can do that.
What turns what turns a
person into the type of kid.
But whatever Michael Brown did,
we know he robbed a store.
We know there's a photo of him
grabbing some guy by the neck.
He's a giant guy.
We know that.
He did that.
Oh,
so what could you have done that
when you were 18 I couldn't have,
I wasn't a violent person.
I was violent and it's right
in the sense of us fighting.
But you had an outlet.
But yeah,
my outlet,
I mean I was never,
I never,
I hadn't,
I haven't even gotten into a
scuffle since I was in high school.
Like I've had z maybe
one time I'm fear factor,
but the one time I fear factor.
I didn't even hurt the guy.
I just grabbed him.
I didn't do anything to him.
I just,
I thought he was gonna
hit me the question.
Yeah.
The question is what
makes a person like that?
How much of it is nature nurture,
so almost it's huge
chunk of it is nurture,
right?
Huge chunk,
but nature and nurture are
combined because of epic,
epic genetics and there's
learned behavior there.
There's,
there's tendencies that a child,
if they're in the womb of a mother who
was under extreme stress and duress,
a woman who's,
it lives in a horrible neighborhood
of deals with violence in the home.
A woman who's being beaten
while she's pregnant,
that child will have a higher
propensity for violence like this is,
there's all these studies that have
proven this are being done to prove this
you,
everyone's on equal.
If your parents are super sweet and in
love with each other and super supportive
and you grew up and you're in the womb
of that mom and then there's this kid
who's mom is getting beat up by the dad
who is a junkie who comes home every
three days and it's just chaos
and violence and fear and crying.
You're a D,
you're growing up a different person.
So if you're in that circumstance and
you're part of a greater group of people
who have also had that
same experience coming up,
are you really,
do you really have the
capacity to understand how
your actions are affecting the
entire picture?
That's a great question.
That's the real question,
right?
That's the real question.
The real question is isn't whether or
not that cop shot that guy in in a just
way.
The real question is how?
How do we stop a kid
like that from being kid?
Like how do we stop an
angry young man from,
from developing into a criminal?
How do you intervene?
Is it possible to intervene?
Is it possible to
intervene with counseling?
Is it possible to intervene with education
or is there some sort of a medical
pharmaceutical alternative
that's on the horizon?
I mean,
who the fuck knows what,
what,
what turns someone into what's,
well,
you know,
fill in the blank.
There's a million instances
all across the country,
every day of people committing
violent crimes and it's,
and it,
and,
and to be fair,
it's not just this,
this part of the populous.
It's not just somebody who came up,
uh,
without very much,
well,
that's why this Ghomeshi
guys kind of fuss.
I mean,
or I remember the kid in Santa Barbara,
the rich kid,
yes.
Who had had it out for women or whatever.
I read,
read some stuff for regarding
him when that happened.
So yeah,
it can happen anywhere,
but it's obvious that violence among
particular communities is vastly more,
uh,
consistent.
Yeah.
Impoverished communities.
It's just more stress,
more stress,
more violence,
more poverty.
Did you hear this hope that they found
that Mcdonald's is spending significantly
more money advertising important
neighborhoods recently?
Yeah,
they did a study.
They're like,
I don't even remember
what the percentage was.
I hate quoting things that
I don't have the data on.
Maybe Jamie can look it up.
Yeah,
Jamie could.
Um,
but yeah,
that maybe runs even deeper than this.
Right?
As you,
I mean,
you know the like how does,
how does nutrition play into it?
Right.
And that's a good point.
You know what I mean?
Sugar is a big part of
the Diet of poor people.
I mean not just sugar but
sugar in refined form,
whether whether it's candy or soda,
but also in terms of like
breads and carbohydrates.
It's all like an alcohol
upon those things.
Meat Processing,
the sugar.
If you,
uh,
if you're a poor family and you
can go to Mcdonald's and get a,
you know,
a bunch of meals for five bucks
a piece and it's weird how,
how many things are stacked against you.
It's just weird like that the fund,
the building blocks of human life
like vegetables or whatever are,
are,
are not accessible to you.
At least not,
not in the same way as those
other ready made meals.
Like,
cause you've got to cook them.
You got to,
the investment isn't just the
amount of money that it costs.
Cause I've seen those responses like well
you know they could buy vegetables and
this and that,
but when you're working two jobs and
you're a single parent and whatever else
that the energy invested in actually
turning that vege those vegetables into
something your kids actually want.
Is this it right here?
Yeah.
This is the disturbing ways that fast
food chains disproportionately target
black kids,
specifically McDonald's.
But it's a lot of Papa John's
Popeye's and Mcdonald's in there.
Sorry,
I may have accused him.
Well they,
they go where they can
make the most money.
I mean it's like a magnet
attracts metal filings.
Well how do you feel about that?
Is this,
is this acceptable?
Well,
sorry to put you on the spot.
Here's the thing.
In an ideal society,
like if you Louis would like a big Mac,
you should be able to buy a big Mac.
I completely agree.
No,
that a big Mac is shit.
You know,
it's not good for you.
But if you have to choose between going
down the street to whole foods and
getting a nice salad that's super healthy,
nutrient dense or a big Mac,
and you choose as an
adult to go get a big Mac,
that's one thing.
But the,
there's a big difference between
that and children and you know,
and,
and people that aren't educated
or people that are poor,
I don't think that Mcdonald's or
burger king has a responsibility.
Should they be able to
advertise to miners?
Two miners,
she's,
this show will do whatever they
want as long as it's legal.
I mean,
look,
if you want to serve
your kid a cheeseburger,
it should that be illegal.
If your kid,
okay,
your five year old says,
Daddy,
I want a cheeseburger.
Like,
all right,
well let's go in there
and get a cheeseburger.
Is that it?
Should that be okay?
And if that's okay.
Why?
I mean,
if it's okay to go to an ice cream store,
if it's okay to go to Baskin Robbins
and get your kid in ice cream Sundae,
which pretty much everybody
does every now and again.
But here's the,
here's what I'm getting at is that the,
the developing mind is very susceptible,
at least traditionally has
been susceptible to this to
advertising's ability to,
to bypass the,
the,
the defense mechanisms
that an adult brain has.
Right?
I know you want to sell me something,
right?
I know that big Mac
looks fucking delicious.
I'm going to come by it.
Right,
right,
right.
But
maybe the like longterm embedding them,
embedding themselves in the psyche of
people at a young enough age is somehow
affecting their decision making
far later into their lives.
That is not just a simple discussion of,
you know,
an advertisement tomorrow and,
and free choice tomorrow.
Like how free are we actually
when it comes to thinking,
right?
Yeah.
Well
it's very,
it's a very complicated and
complex situation because
what is okay for one group
is not okay for another,
what is okay for adults discerning
adults who are educated and aware.
If you want to go get a snickers bar,
you should be able to.
But if,
if that is all that's available in your
community and you are young and starving
and you don't have much money,
then that's a real issue because like
this kid needs nutrition and they're not
getting it from a
snickers bar or a big Mac.
And it would be interesting to,
to,
to attempt to investigate the consequences
of that from a mental perspective.
Like is it possible to have a fully
developed mind living off snickers is not
and I don't think so.
Even if it's whether or
not it's fully developed,
it's not going to be optimized.
No,
that's for sure.
and the effects of that at at,
at a young age,
so it's,
it's not,
it's not like it's an old thing
from a human history perspective,
like the food that would
have been available,
it may have been available more to
the rich people than the poor people.
But you're talking about
roughly the same stuff,
right?
It comes out of the ground or are you
or you kill a cow and whatever you got
what you got.
No.
Well,
I think what we really need
with communities really
need is community gardens
and you know,
it would also foster a massive sense of
community if you had community gardens
where like say if you live on a block,
all you would need is one lot.
Okay.
You know,
you have a hundred homes on a block,
one of them one lot with v feed.
Literally a hundred homes.
You would just have to grow it correctly,
you know,
stagger the food and
have everyone do shifts.
If you have a hundred
families doing shifts in this,
you know,
one half acre a lot,
I mean a half acre is a lot of
land as far as like growing food.
If you have access to water
and seeds and all these,
the,
you know,
the proper soil to for growing food,
you could do an amazing
thing with an area.
When I was a kid,
my parents were involved in,
um,
my stepdad was going to school,
he was a computer programmer and he went
back to school to become an architect.
And when he changed careers,
he,
when he was going to school,
he was involved at one point in time
with some project at his university where
they were,
um,
they had like a communal garden sort of
a thing and everyone had to do like a
shift.
And I remember this very clearly because
I went with him one day and I got
attacked by a goat.
Fucking conti.
Goats jumped after me and they
had livestock at Guardian.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
They were,
they were milking goats and uh,
it was a part of,
I don't,
I was about maybe eight at the time,
maybe seven or eight.
So I do not remember the exact extent
of their duties are what everything but
what everything was for.
But I remember there was all
sorts of different vegetables.
They were growing and then
they had some livestock,
I think they were using.
Goat's milk is particularly nutritious.
Yeah.
Very easy to digest as well.
And it's an issue with babies.
A lot of babies have a real
hard time with cow milk.
My daughter did.
It should a really hard
time drinking cow milk.
But goat's milk is super easy
to digest for whatever reason.
I don't know nutritionally
bubs or whatever.
But that idea,
that concept of a communal garden,
I mean first of all it could bring the
community together and amazing way,
you know where everybody's sort of working
towards some sort of a universal goal
and two,
it could provide people with food that
either don't need money to pay for if
they can just,
you know,
if everybody has a shift that
they have to do like hey,
it's your shift to lay down
manure or your shift to pick up,
you know,
the crops and document them.
And if you have like,
you know,
a log book that everybody
has to sign in and you know,
today we picked 18 squash,
we put them here,
you know,
let everybody know,
send the word out.
Squash is available to families,
come and get some squash.
You know,
the Kale is grown to the point.
We could pick it that that's all possible
and not like economically prohibitive.
And it would probably save a
lot of people a lot of money.
I think that makes a lot of sense.
Most definitely.
But I think for me it's like you won,
you wonder how much time plays into it,
right?
Because when you like what comes with
money and wellbeing and growing up in a
good community and whatever is his time,
free time,
which is what allows not only uh,
you know,
things like that to exist,
but also the ideas,
you know,
like the,
the,
the free format of
communication and ideas.
When you subtract time from
people when they are getting paid,
uh,
you know,
a fraction of whatever they get paid
per person is getting paid per hour or
whatever.
It's there or you know,
red lining there,
their cape,
their capacity,
the,
the age old work smarter,
not harder type scenario.
But it's like if,
uh,
if time is not abundant,
it's hard to imagine that people would
find a w what could find a way to
participate in something like [inaudible]
is a guy named Ron Finley who's got
a Ted talk on this very subject,
right?
He calls himself a guerrilla gardener.
Wow.
Yeah.
He's got a Ted talk about guerrilla
gardening and south central La and it's
really interesting.
Yeah.
And he has,
um,
these,
these gardens that he
set up and like medians,
like growing food
in all these places that
where nothing was growing,
but like weeds before only gets young
kids involved in growing this food.
And he's talking,
you know,
this ted talk,
it's really interesting because he's,
he's talking about how little it costs
and how healthy it is and how good it is
for you.
Yeah.
You know,
it's,
it's a really to get him on here,
man.
I got him.
He's um,
yeah,
I mean he sounds like a bad if he has a,
yeah.
I wonder if he has a Twitter foe.
I'm sure he was at Twitter.
It's funny though that if this stuff
is really as accessible as it seems,
it is like ground Sun rain,
right.
Why the hell does it cost
what it costs at whole foods?
What's that about?
Yeah.
What is that about?
I mean,
I,
when I got here and I was at the whole
foods in Venice and Jesus Christ,
that place is buzzing.
It's a scene,
man.
It's,
it's like,
it's like you're,
you're,
you're in some wacky
nutritional nightclub.
They kind of like a little wine bar and
if people are sitting there talking,
sipping on expensive wines,
you know,
buying the most expensive
products you possibly can.
It's very,
it's like a rite of passage.
It's like nutrition is a rite of passage
as a place even more expensive called
Erewhon who were been an Erewhon.
No,
that's a new one
to the next level.
Do they have a dress code?
No,
but whole foods is better though because
whole foods has like a real butcher
shop.
Like whole foods.
You can get like a fat rice and steak.
Yeah,
I saw that.
Like good meat that,
I mean they even had smoked brisket.
Like they're smoking it right
there in the supermarket cheese.
There's a whole food in boulder
that is like a God damn restaurant.
I mean they have all sorts of,
or they have a pizza oven?
Yeah,
I have.
They make sandwiches.
They have all sorts of stuff.
The one in Venice had
the wood pizza oven too.
I tried it.
It was bad ass pizza.
Like I'm not taking
anything away from them.
Better food for more people is awesome.
Expensive though.
That's what I'm saying.
So it's hard,
but price wise it's like,
and I'm not trying to uh,
be prejudice or anything,
but that is a type of
person that's in there.
You know what I mean?
I love how you said that.
I'm not trying to be prejudice.
Um,
I it is prejudice Twitter page called yes,
you're racist.
Oh,
okay.
And uh,
I was tweeting it the other day because
it was a during the day of the riots,
it was a great time to go to,
yes,
you're racist.
And they would find like
racist tweets and put them up.
And the guy who runs the page was
saying that that was the worst day ever.
Worst than Trayvon Martin or
worse than any other that day.
Well,
there was so much,
so much racist bullshit being tweeted.
Wow.
I mean,
I believe it.
I've been in the youtube comments before.
It's,
it seems like there'll be a way to,
to mitigate a lot of the issues.
And this also,
it's,
it's also difficult to get
people to fucking eat that shit.
Like they want eat cheeseburgers.
Right.
You know,
it's not as simple as a,
do you want some more coffee man?
Who wants to make small clubs?
I would love some more.
This is fantastic coffee.
I'm just,
it's,
it's starting to sink in.
I'm getting fired up now.
We got plumbing,
caveman coffee.
Right.
Perfect.
Um,
it's,
it's hard to get people to choose
a salad over a fucking ice cream,
but I feel like it is prevailing.
[inaudible] I mean,
I don't know about when
you were a kid or whatever,
but nobody was saying
Mcdonald's is bad for you.
Right.
Nobody was saying
cigarettes are bad for you.
At some point in time,
you know,
at some point in time,
doctors were prescribing things.
Did you ever see that j Edgar
Hoover film know Capria Oh no,
I never saw it.
It's a good movie.
And one of the things in the movie was
Leonardo Dicaprio or j Edgar Hoover's mom
telling Leonardo Dicaprio that he should,
you know,
smoke the cigarettes that the doctor
prescribed to make him heartier,
you know,
to make him more really
prescribing cigarettes to
make you like refer stronger.
No.
Yay.
Yes.
Doctors prescribed cigarettes.
Yeah.
Well,
you know,
before the,
before the vibrator
doctors would give yes.
Hysteria,
right?
Yes,
yes.
Hysterical hysteria being
connected to hysterectomy the,
and you had to define me.
That's signed a way to
log it into the book.
That's medical book.
Yeah.
It's like the connection hysteria
and hysterectomy like that.
That's where the word comes from wildly.
And these women,
I mean I'm doing a butcher
job of the definition of it,
but these women would go to the
doctor and the doctor would,
uh,
just finger blast though.
That's the doctor would tell,
you know,
I mean with a cigarette in his mouth and
then the origins of the word hysteria.
Yeah,
right.
Probably right.
Yeah.
It's,
it's,
it's wild how much things can
change in a short period of time.
Yeah.
And it's an,
it's an accelerating thing as well.
Uh,
but I think we're,
you know,
we'll look back on this time and say,
I can't believe we did that the same way
we're looking back on 40 years ago or
30 years ago and saying,
I can't,
I can't believe we did that.
So,
uh,
there's definitely a movement
into the direction of,
uh,
getting back to the food thing into a
direction of a more fulfilling diet.
Yeah.
Hysteria.
The describes unmanageable
emotional excess.
The fear that can be centered on a body
part or most commonly on an imagined
problem with that body part.
Disease is a common complaint.
Uh,
see also body dysmorphic disorder
and heal what I was reading or,
no,
sorry,
listening to a podcast,
uh,
I think it was radio lab or I dunno,
something like that.
And they were talking about using a
woman using a pms as a defense in a court
case.
Oh yeah.
For,
uh,
for punching or hitting
her kid or something,
something like that.
And,
and how the implications of
that on the legal system,
whether or not,
uh,
whether or not you're psychologically
there when you're experiencing that
hormonal imbalance that comes
with that time of the month.
Yeah.
Well people have used sugar
as defense for murder.
Like yeah.
Some guy use Twinkies eating Kate
to make Twinkies and went crazy.
I believe that was in northern California.
Yeah,
female hysteria.
That's the the thing.
I was looking for a once common
medical diagnosis exclusively in women,
which today no longer recognized by
medical authorities as a medical disorder.
It's diagnosis and treatment where routine
for many hundreds of years in western
Europe and one of the
things they would do,
they would blast water on a woman's pussy.
There's,
there's a photo,
if you go to the Wikipedia for the,
look at that cannon fire hose,
there's blast and note how her
legs are together and down.
Meanwhile she'd be like grabbing the
back of her knees yet outta here.
It would just be flooding.
Look at that wedding chair that doesn't
look like it's ready for that kind of
force.
I know it should be like some sort of a
captain's chair like a captain Kirk had
in the enterprise that's going
to tip over and they will like.
You see how the doctors keeping his
distance ways he's firing that from a fair
distance.
The physician in 1859 claimed at a
quarter of all women suffer from hysteria.
One physician cataloged 75
pages of possible symptoms
of hysteria and called the
list incomplete.
Almost any Aleman could fit the diagnosis.
Physicians thought that the stresses
associated with modern life cause civilize
women to be both more susceptible to
nervous disorders and to FAU to develop
faulty reproductive tracks.
What they just fucking gas back then.
It's really amazing when you go back
just you know a couple hundred years and
you look at like the connections
they had to disorders and diseases.
They just guessed they were so off.
Yeah,
they didn't know what the
fuck they were talking about.
It's false.
It's not true.
Oh is that Snopes?
But didn't some guy actually use
something like sugar as a defense?
Sugar as a defense.
I'm sure some hot shot
lawyer has attempted to use.
What does he say?
Anything to say?
It never happened.
Uh,
recently resigned.
tweak your defenses over common.
They recognized term.
It says he got off with
voluntary manslaughter.
Defense argued the refined sugar and
is junk food made them depressed it
mentally incapable of premeditated murder.
Well,
no,
this,
listen,
this was an actual defense and he tried
to use his defense was that he suffered
diminished capacity as
a result of depression.
His change in die from healthy food to
Twinkies and other sugary food was said
to be a symptom of depression.
So contrary to popular belief,
his attorneys did not argue that
Twinkies were the cause of the actions,
but at the consumption was symptomatic
of an underlying depression.
So it was like confusing.
So like he's deep,
he's depressed.
Look,
heats all these 20,
you must be depressed,
depressed,
and that's why he killed somebody.
It wasn't that the Twinkies were
causing him to kill some money.
The Twinkies,
we're just a consequence
of his depression.
Twinkies.
Apparently we were never mentioned
the courtroom during the trial,
nor the defense ever claim that white
was on a sugar rush and committed the
murders as a result,
however one report,
his use of the term twinkie
defense caught on and stuck.
That's people in a nutshell and that's me.
I'm perpetrating it.
Fucking keeping the
ignorant chain rolling.
It's funny how stuff like that works,
you know?
I mean essentially a lot of
that is going on in Ferguson.
Like someone gets an idea and
then like my hands are up,
don't shoot.
Like they're pretending that
this kid said my hands are up.
Don't shoot.
It's like people keep saying hands up,
don't shoot,
hands up,
don't shoot.
And then it's a better story.
Witnesses that made testimony,
the indictment there were saying that
he rushed the cop and then he said,
you know you too much
of a pussy to shoot me.
Who the fuck knows what really happened?
It's just,
that's not the sexy story.
Exactly.
Cops need to wear fucking cameras,
you know?
And a couple cops have argued
with me about this online.
Really?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Saying that they don't think they should.
Yeah.
They were saying like,
you know,
do you have much more to
go with calls but fuck off.
How much is it go pro fuck off.
You can get one for 150 bucks.
Jesus Christ,
you got fucking so much money is
being a four K GoPro right now.
So much money's being
invested in the war on drugs.
invested in Afghanistan.
I rack and just feeling
the fucking blanks.
Corn subsidies,
I mean Jesus Christ,
the amount of money that's being,
do you ever watch king corn?
The amount of money that's being invested
in making sure that Mcdonald's still
has fucking corn syrup.
There's a lot of money going around folks.
And the idea that someone
who carries a fucking gun,
that it's not a good idea
to put a camera on them.
Right?
For all sorts of reasons.
Look,
if that kid was saying on camera,
you're too much of a pussy to shoot me
and Juan and towards that cop and the cop
shot him,
we're good.
We're done.
This whole thing is done.
So right now we're dealing with a lot
of speculation and we have a bunch of
people that are walking down the
street and mass closing down freeways.
Say yelling out,
hands up,
don't shoot.
What's the cost of that now?
How the fuck do we even know that?
That was sad,
like what are you doing?
And like that black guy that are on
Twitter was saying to the white rapper,
you are blind to the facts
in your attempt to be down.
And there's a lot of that going on.
There's a lot of track people.
They want the narrative,
they want the narrative,
they want it to fit in with
their idea of you know,
what,
what is just or what is exciting
or what's really going on.
The other thing about the camera too is
it's not just about what would have been
captured,
it's about what might not have happened.
Well,
there's a I p I tweeted a story or a
tweeted a study rather about California
that said that when they made cops
where cameras that numbers of complaints
against cops,
the numbers of violent incidents and,
and,
and abuse dropped dramatically.
When people are accountable,
they don't fuck up on both sides.
Both sides on both sides.
If you are,
if you're somebody who's committing
a crime or not or whatever,
you understand the
consequences of that camera.
Yes.
That what you're about to say and do.
There's a record of it and the cop
knows he can't get away with anything.
Both parties.
Now you know what they should do if
they find a cop tampered would fucking
camera,
they should put him in jail for 20 years
and find a cod or erased footage or
that purposely,
if they can prove that a cop
purposely fuck with a camera,
there should be a high consequence.
Know what though?
There's a way around
that you could have it,
uh,
uploading streaming in real time.
Yeah.
You know,
like,
have you heard it?
Do you have one of those drop
cams or have you heard of them?
You got to have heard of them.
Yeah.
So like set them up in five minutes.
They're like this big,
they connect to the wifi
network and then boom,
you're,
you're streaming probably would be if
you were in a place that was remote,
you know,
if you were in the Maine
Woods or something like that,
if you know ry fucking
game warden or something,
abusive cops could get away
with it if there was no signal,
but right.
I mean if you had some sort of
a fail safe mechanism where the,
the data is being backed
up by a Bluetooth,
you know,
to the hard drive of the patrol car,
or some sort of a signal that reaches
the hard drive of the patrol car and it
can't be tampered with.
Right.
That doesn't seem to me to be
outside of the realm of possibility.
That would be great for everybody.
Great for the cops and
fantastic for civilians.
I mean,
I,
I guarantee you that alone would cut
back on police abuse dramatically.
Would you per,
so you get pulled over for speeding,
right.
You want the cop coming
up in recording that?
Yes.
Really?
Sure.
Okay.
Why not?
I don't know.
Some,
there is some kind,
there is a,
uh,
a feeling that being recording
recorded as a negative thing,
like the whole,
you know,
NSA type thing.
But maybe it's different because
you know you're being recorded.
Yeah.
You know,
you're being recorded and you being
recorded because you violated a law.
Okay.
Let's say you didn't go well then you say,
I didn't violate the law,
right?
Whatever you say it on camera.
Right.
So some people would have a
hard time asserting themselves,
which would be an issue cause socially
some people a bit more awkward.
That can be an issue.
But I think that if someone comes up to
you and talks to you about a crime and
you know you're being recorded,
I mean it's gotta be a
lot of transparency there.
Like if you were speeding and they have
the evidence and they have all the data,
I mean that's all the only thing that
would be a problem as people wouldn't be
able to get off for being cute or having
a crying story or a girl with big tits.
Yeah.
Well and what percentage of traffic
infractions you do actually end up getting
convicted for the whole,
the whole thing.
Like there's no leniency there.
And the amount of blow jobs at
college receive would dramatically,
that's the real reason,
right?
I know a cop,
well I don't know a cop rather,
I know a girl who got pulled
over by a cop and the cop said,
look,
it might be some other way
we can take care of this.
And she was like,
what the fuck are you talking about?
The cop went back to his car,
wrote her a ticket and
fucking centered on her way.
You know,
like he was been going on for
as long as it's been cops.
I'm sure he's floating it out there.
Oh look,
my zippers on done.
Oh,
your mouth is right there.
Yeah,
I mean it's been done.
It's not like the first,
I mean,
how many times it has a girl offered.
He's probably,
a lot of girls are offered that.
I don't know.
I'm sure.
You know.
The thing is though,
human beings cameras.
Why I was watching this
thing the other night,
um,
and maybe you've heard of
it called surveillance man.
No,
you heard of this.
He recently got all these
shit pulled off youtube.
Uh,
but this guy goes around
and just records people.
Regular people walks up to you,
records you and puts it online and,
and whatever.
He edits it together
and puts it on Youtube.
Well that's Kinda fucked up.
Take this very fucked up.
That's it's,
it's very fucked up.
Is he a creep?
I wouldn't know who.
We know who the guy is.
No idea.
So he doesn't put himself on that ever.
Fuck that guy.
So he walks up to people and gets,
uh,
various responses.
Some people,
like he walks up to chew,
all this stuff got pulled off youtube,
but it's on live leak now.
He walks up to two Mormons,
the ones that go door to door
and they're super polite.
They're like,
whoa.
oh,
you're recording.
And it's whatever.
Like they have a nice
conversation and they walk off.
But then other people,
they're trying to knock them out.
But I think it's so,
it's so interesting how the camera in
and of itself almost has this social view
of,
of like,
like a weapon in a way.
It's like you're pointing that thing at
me because you're attempting to take,
the person's not doing anything
wrong by pointing the thing.
No,
no,
no.
I mean the person that's getting recorded,
you're not doing anything wrong.
Why does it make us feel so uncomfortable?
You're opening up a door for a bunch of
other people to enter into your life.
If you take a guy like
I take a camera on you.
Yeah,
I don't know you,
I find you,
I take a camera and you know,
and I put it on a youtube channel that
has a million subscribers like yours.
Does he,
let's say the person doesn't know
that when they're being recorded.
Okay.
Dot.
Right?
Like if you're out in the street,
probably doesn't count for you because
somebody might know who you are and what
in that case.
But if you're a regular everyday person
and someone walks up to you with their
smartphone and they're just
a few feet away from you,
recording you that like
that's what he's doing.
He's not announcing that
it's going to be on youtube,
but people's reactions are intense.
Yeah.
Shouldn't be into his phone.
It's still is fun.
Kick him in the Dick.
Fuck that.
But maybe he wins.
He wins that way.
He wins the how's he win?
Cause I stole his phone.
No,
because that's a way,
because that's a way better
clip if you don't get it,
if you don't get that phone,
oh,
I'll get his phone.
Let me get his phone.
Well,
whatever you may,
you may be more gifted than others who
fail in his clips to get it from him.
Is he like a sprinter while he's,
he,
he starts to get what he,
he moves away at the right time.
This guy's crazy.
He interrupts like,
uh,
he,
there are cases where he walks behind the
cash register at Mcdonald's and starts
recording people that are like
making burgers and they're just like,
what the fuck?
Or in certain cases it's
like he know he walks,
he walks into like a um,
a card game that's going on private
card game and he's recording it.
Like he takes risks to,
to get that footage.
But I agree with you,
fuck that guy.
But at the same time I think it sort of
unveils something about humanity and how
we're not completely ready
for a fully recorded future.
We're not completely ready,
but I feel like it's kind of inevitable.
I think there's almost
nothing to stop it from.
I mean if you look at
where things are going,
you look at what was our access to
information just a hundred years ago.
What is,
what is our access to information going
to be like a hundred years from now,
fully streaming everything
fully streaming.
Now I'm,
I'm a big believer in that we're going
to be sharing our lives that our lives
going to be like,
like,
you know,
I can go to your Facebook and look at
your pictures and I think there's going to
be a time where you're going to be able
to read my fucking thoughts because my
thoughts are going to be recorded on a
hard drive and HD or my instead of my
thoughts,
whether my life,
what I see,
you know,
the experiences that I have.
And then from there it's probably going
to be even more complex and complicated.
There's going to be some
sort of a mechanism for a
re-introducing emotions into
an outside observer.
Like I could find out whether or not
you cried when you went to the movies.
I'll watch a movie
through your perspective.
I mean,
that might be a channel that you go to.
Let's watch movies with Louis.
Yes.
You know,
and like,
Oh my God,
Avatar 16 just made me cry.
And I'm like,
oh,
he's crying like you were,
you know,
like you see it through your eyes.
I could like see what you like
to masturbate too and how,
what,
what excites you.
But that's all it totally inevitable.
But if you asked anybody to
flip that switch tomorrow,
it's like you're not going
to be on the front lines.
I don't know about all.
Oh,
you would,
you're ready to broadcast 24 seven.
I don't,
not me,
but I think a lot of
people would jump right?
The phone.
You have people on Youtube
who almost do that.
They upload a Vlog every day.
Let's say.
I like how you said that Vlog Vlog.
I usually call it v log.
Oh,
okay.
Vlog.
Well,
because it was pulled from blog.
Right.
But uh,
and I,
I sit there and I look
at that and I'm like,
damn,
I am so happy that that's not me.
That's not what I have to do.
Well,
you,
you're a content based guy.
You're,
you're doing videos at unbox therapy
based on your review of particular items,
objects,
things.
Yeah.
So people are tuning in,
not,
I mean partially for a
glimpse into my life,
but not,
I'm not expected to create content
out of my experiences 24 seven right.
Whereas like I feel like a bloggers
in this and this kind of space,
not everybody,
but some where they're trying to turn,
I'm going to be not
even consciously trying,
but once you broadcast everything you do,
how can it not become a performance?
How can it not be what you mean?
Yeah.
Well that was hunters Thompson a argument
when they were filming him way back
when he was doing
one of his early documentaries
and they did on him.
He was saying that you're,
you know,
you're not going to really get it.
Like that camera that you're putting on
me changes the interaction 100% exactly.
And that's what I was trying
to get at with the whole,
the whole thing before about
the cop carrying the camera
or the surveillance guy
or whatever is like,
are you you when a camera's on?
Yeah.
Well eventually you are potentially
your you when the camera's on,
what does that mean?
I'm you now hear me now?
No,
I'm mean now.
You mean now when the camera's on?
Are you?
Yes,
like this camera on me as deep man.
But I do,
I do this so often.
I know in a podcast,
like if you and I were
having this conversation,
the only difference would be I wouldn't
be feeling these fucking things on my
ears.
Yeah.
I mean it may be,
but here's a bigger,
quite personal information.
Here's a bigger question.
Are you the same?
Me Too.
Everybody not to people that I don't
know if they might have like ulterior
motives or they might be
creepers or there might be weird,
like there's people about certain things.
Sometimes you're sitting in that
chair and I'm sure I don't remember.
One doesn't come to mind,
but the guy across from you,
you're not.
You know what I mean?
There's not a connection.
Like it could be a,
I don't know if you,
maybe not if you disagree with that,
but you must have had conflict before
in this environment changed the you that
you were most certainly me.
But you also would have,
I mean any conflict outside
of this environment.
If you had conflict with someone and you
want to trademark it would change who
you were and how you interacted with them.
You would be more guarded.
You'd be like,
Oh,
this guy's a creep.
Yeah.
See The you the,
this is like deep shit.
But like,
but no,
but seriously,
I don't know that you can be the
same person around everybody.
Yeah.
I think I know we all,
I think we all do some kind of editing.
Right?
Well and not only that,
I mean,
isn't that kind of what
being a human being is?
We are,
part of what we are is we are who we
become when we're around other people.
Yes.
One of the reasons why we like
being around certain people,
they make us better.
Yes.
Interesting.
And it made me agree with that.
They make you more fun or they make you
more kind or they make us where we're
not totally autonomous,
we're just not.
No,
not,
we're not completely individuals.
We are individuals interacting with under
individuals and those ingredients of
these other individuals provide,
they change who we are.
That's it's important not to
hang around with negative p.
Yes,
I had a friend who's a nice guy,
but fucking dude was like,
he,
he always was involved
in drama and bullshit.
And when I was around him,
like I remember thinking
like this fucking guy,
like everything in his
life is always a mess.
And when I'm around him I become a mess.
Like when I'm around him,
I'm arguing with him and
when I'm not around him,
everything is calm and his life remain.
Koi.
I stopped hanging around with them
really slick way back in the day,
but I stopped hanging around with him
and his life just became more and more
chaotic in mind.
Became peaceful because of it,
because I eliminated this one,
like super problematic dude from my life.
But I have other people that I hang
around with them and it's always fun.
Yeah.
You know,
I hang around with them.
It's always laughs and joking.
It's always a good time and you
feel better when you're around them.
You become a better person.
I think we collectively,
at least sometimes for me,
like we underestimate the
importance of this stimulus.
Yeah.
The people that are around us,
the things that we
surround ourselves with.
Like Facebook recently did
something controversial.
Um,
I don't know how recently,
but they started auto playing videos
as you scroll through and you know that
the,
some of the shit that's out
there you don't want to see.
Yeah.
Right.
Yeah,
I know.
I definitely don't,
I don't play sucks in general.
It sucks in general.
But I guess what I'm getting at more
with this one is it's like the Internet
opens up this door to
see as much as you want,
right.
And to,
to use your eyeballs.
You get in a metaphorical sense as
like the vein to insert the drug.
And so I don't,
I don't know that we are collectively
aware of the fucking heavy duty
consequences of that,
that the web,
the web giving us everything is,
that's the best thing about the web.
But it's also the worst thing about
the web in that you're changed forever.
You watch a guy's head get chopped off,
you're different.
It's true.
There's no,
there's no going back.
You've seen it.
You know what that looks like.
I mean,
up until I was in my twenties I didn't
know what it looked like when the guy got
his head sought off by a buck knife.
You know it's right.
Then you see it and you go,
oh Jesus Christ.
And I remember I can still to this day
remember I think the first time I ever
saw like faces of death,
same and to this day I was
way too young to see that.
Yeah,
I would just remember like the
weird like tightening of your body.
Like the,
the intent me ask you this.
Do you wish that you hadn't seen it?
No.
I'm fine now.
Well,
I mean I've seen them now.
It doesn't make me a worse person.
Just it is what it is.
I know what it is now.
No,
it's like you don't go out of
your way to watch more of it.
No,
I do not.
I avoid it.
These recent ones with these journalists
that would be headed by the isis guys.
I.
W I avoided all of them because you need,
the objective of those guys
is to attract your eyeballs.
I don't need to experience that.
I know what it looks like.
I know what's going on.
I don't need to express,
but I do know I did watch one cause
I couldn't believe it was on fucking
youtube.
Somebody sent me a link to it on Twitter,
something about isis and I was like,
what?
So I clicked on it thinking,
this is a youtube link.
This is not going to be anything serious.
It was a full on execution.
Them cutting their heads off.
Both Youtube and Twitter are having
difficulty keeping it down because of the
speed at which it's being
replicated in re uploaded.
These guys from a social media perspective
are fairly educated that you hear the
guy's voice,
he's got an English accent.
It's like these are not
who we think they are.
Right?
Right.
We think of them as being an uneducated
savages are unaware who were living in
caves.
That's when that,
and that was the narrative for so long.
Yeah,
that that's what that was about.
But it's interesting how people subtract
themselves from the overall equation
like,
and by that I mean that by watching it,
you're a perpetuating it sort of,
yeah.
Being away.
Yeah,
because the entire objective from an Roi,
this sounds gross to say it this way,
but from an Roi perspective,
Roi,
return on investment from a
return on investment perspective,
Isis has mad legs via one dude.
What's the cost?
The one dude,
right.
That's the scary part is that the Internet
has allowed for the proliferation of
a piece of content,
an idea,
something that all of us collectively
recognize as negative but can't keep our
fucking eyes off.
Whether it was something that someone
tweeted [inaudible] who's a part of Isis.
We was talking about how everybody gets
crazy when one person's body part gets
removed.
But meanwhile a hundred
people get blown to bits.
Yeah.
By a robot.
There you go.
No one says a word.
It's hard to argue with that.
I mean,
I'm not supporting isis,
but it's hard to argue with that logic.
Like we have some weird
ways of looking at loss.
Somebody tweeted me the other day,
um,
that there was an objective to kill 40
people and they wound up killing 1,417
people in their attempt
to kill these 40 people.
Like that's a lot of fucking
murder for no reason.
I mean that those other
people that collateral damage,
those people have families,
those people have lives.
Those people had friends,
those people had lovers.
All on these were gone.
So long as those people on TV speak a
different language and wear a different
outfit and look different than us.
Buya Bulia choose.
Let's do it.
Yeah.
And the all that is affecting
us all that's changing us.
Just like having negative
people in our life.
Just like communicating
with shitty people.
Just like being in a bad neighborhood,
all that is your reality.
You are a combination of your reality
and your take on that reality.
This membrane here like is not nearly as
strong from a structural perspective as
we like to believe it is.
Yeah,
no shit.
Right.
That's what I was saying with the,
with the fast food thing in,
in uh,
targeting black people in black
neighborhoods and kids and this and that.
It's like the informational world.
We just don't view it like
torpedoes or heroin or whatever,
but the consequences are very similar.
Like when you let shit in,
it changes you.
Like we both just said emotionally,
how is it you can watch this thing
that you know already happened,
right?
Like how I can't change
what happened there.
Right.
When when a guy gets his head chopped off,
there's literally nothing
that I can do about it.
So it might as well be
fiction at this point.
It might as well be
Hollywood at this point,
but it's not,
I watch it and I know the difference
and I can't steer clear of it.
I can't escape that high.
Yeah.
You can't escape that input.
I mean,
we are essentially a product of our input.
Yes.
Our interactions,
our input and how we,
how we process all of it.
That's,
that's what we are,
that's what makes a person,
a person.
That's why people that have lived color
for lives are so interesting is because
they have so much input.
There's so much variety in their input.
Right?
Yeah.
And when we all become connected and
some sort of a weird hive mind way.
Yeah.
Is it,
is everybody more fucked up than we think?
There's a lot more fucked
up shit than we think.
Yeah.
I think we based a lot of our
ideas of reality on media.
Yup.
On,
when I say media,
I mean like fictional
depictions of pain songs.
Coldplay songs.
Yeah.
And there's a lot of women to think
dudes are like the guy who Coldplay song
don't,
please don't.
I have a whole like tangent on Rom coms
about how like what's a Romcom romantic
comedy,
how no self respecting dude
should ever take his girlfriend,
wife to any of those movies.
Those move,
that's fucking terrorism right there.
Give me an example,
Jennifer Aniston movies
when she was like a cop,
that shit,
every fucking time it's selling one thing.
The grass being greener always Amy,
you're the fucking,
you're the current lawn.
You know what I mean?
You're in a current fucking
line and you're taking your,
you're taking like,
it's crazy to think that,
oh,
we're just going to enjoy it and we're
going to laugh and whatever this and
that.
There is no Romcom.
There is no,
no,
none of that structure
without the triangle.
The Love Triangle and the love triangle
opens the door to the third party.
See,
we don't work that way dudes.
For the most part,
we're like stimulated by
other shit as you know.
But on that side of the fence,
it's all imagination.
It's all like,
yeah,
the fucking pool boy or the
the delivery man or whoever.
Someone's always going to treat
you better or whatever it is.
And as you know,
anytime you're in a,
in a,
in a relationship,
you learn really quickly that,
I think we talked about
this last time about,
you know,
the,
the honeymoon phase and how things change
and that's just part of growing and,
and whatever.
But in those movies it's never about that.
It's never about,
oh look,
they've been together forever
and they still fucking doing it.
Right.
It's always some prettier
dude has to come along.
[inaudible] you're a fucking idiot if
you're taking your wife to that shit.
Okay.
What should you take her
to I planet of the Apes,
Dystopia fucking version of reality
where gorillas become sentient and they
start getting machine guns and shooting
white people may mean that what we need.
No,
maybe not that.
I don't know.
I don't know either.
I don't know how to solve that shit,
but all I gotta say
he's don't participate,
but what have you enjoyed them?
No,
you don't.
No.
It's not a chance.
It's fucking impossible.
Ryan Gosling movies,
no way.
Drive maybe,
which I haven't seen and
tells him 21 jump street one.
Who's the Guy Tatum?
That guy,
that handsome bastard.
What about him?
Fuck 'em all man woe.
I take it back chatting.
I didn't mean it.
You gotta do what you gotta do.
And if you know,
if I look like that,
I'd probably do the same goddamn thing.
But truthfully,
like it's,
it's,
it's weird how much we turn our lives
into the stories that we want them to be.
Well,
we've definitely pretend
we definitely pretend.
And the,
the,
the other issue is that when that's
a part of the input of reality,
your drawer you're dealing
with like faulty data,
you're dealing with
like fictional accounts,
rive reality,
the fucking glitch.
A bunch of writers sat down.
They were in a room,
they worked for weeks lines.
That would sound absolutely
ridiculous in the real world.
Music plays when the guy delivers some,
his head is 60 feet tall.
He's on a giant fucking screen.
The perfect words,
his features are perfectly symmetrical.
Everything is wonderful.
So Dreamy.
Yeah,
I mean look,
think about like what
they can do in movies.
Now Look,
how about the movie 300 those guys
didn't even really look like that.
Like,
I remember when I saw that dude,
Gerard,
whatever the fuck his name is,
Butler.
Yeah.
In real life.
And I was like,
oh,
look at this fucking flabby because
I couldn't handle that movie.
Really?
No.
Why is that?
It was too far beyond the realm
of what I was willing to accept.
I feel the same way about
a lot of Zombie Shit.
You know,
I was watching,
I was like sorta off the
walking dead for a while.
I watched the first season and then,
you know,
I dunno,
it got old for me because of
the zombies stopped being as,
as they were early
on.
Right.
If they're all slow and shit now.
Yeah.
You know,
and it's like,
well fuck,
I don't know.
I want the zone.
I want a dangerous zone.
You want a 28 days later,
Zombie love 28 days later.
If I need to be afraid of something
like second nature for them,
you know,
to,
to kill them now.
But anyway,
I'm watching that shit and it's like,
oh,
the girls look fucking awesome.
They got makeup,
they got makeup.
They're,
they're,
they're prepped up.
I want to see the Real Zombie movie.
People look like shit.
Well fuck it.
All of Hollywood needs to
tone down the appearance.
I that my suspension of disbelief in my
enjoyment of all of Hollywood is being
hindered by the fact that they can't
put normal looking people in stuff.
I was watching the Jurassic
Park trailer this morning.
Looks Wild.
It looks wild,
but at the same time I'm
thinking shit's hitting the fan,
this and that and the
fucking eyeliners perfect.
The bugs you.
It bugs the shit out of me.
How can anyone get excited about that
as a film maker like you at all costs?
Want this person to suspend disbelief
and pretend they were there for a minute?
Well,
beautiful women sell movies.
God beautiful people.
So movies,
I don't agree with that.
You come in the walking dead.
No one grows a fucking beard.
Hell yeah.
You know?
Hell,
you grew a beard,
Rick.
That's it.
He's the only one everybody
else has shaved out loud.
It doesn't make for a good billboard.
Does that what else?
No one's growing.
No one's like hairs growing
all fucked up and scraggly.
Their hair stays the
same length for years.
Same thing as the makeup.
They make certain concessions
to be more glossy.
Well,
if you paying attention
to this recent season,
there's a woman in the recent season
that always has fucking lipstick on and
there you perfectly,
perfectly like clean and press suit.
This is fucking ridiculous.
What self respecting person can
accept that in their content?
Come on.
If you watch movies from
back in the day before,
shit got all glossy.
You had people that looked
like regular people,
they'd be cast leading role.
Teeth weren't perfect.
Like who?
Give me an example.
I don't know if you watch old Scorsese
movies like mean streets and shit like
that.
People had big noses,
you know,
I mean,
you don't even need a specific exam,
watch anything from 30 years ago.
And it's like wow.
Either,
but that fucks with people's perception
of what now actually is and what they
need to do to participate
in that whole thing.
Uh,
from an appearance standpoint,
it's like a,
when you put so much emphasis
on the superficial stuff,
everything else like gene Hackman,
right?
Yeah.
That's a bad motherfucker.
That motherfucker right there.
There you go.
There's many examples of it,
George.
See Scott.
There you go.
You know who came to mind when
I originally thought of an ugly,
like right now,
trying to think of a straight up ugly
and no offense to this individual,
but a straight up ugly leading
man Gerard Depardieu right.
But that's kind of like have
French thing and gone though.
He's gone.
He disappeared,
he vanished and he left a France.
He doesn't even live in France anymore.
Gerardi Pardot because of this country.
Didn't want to pay.
He drinks like six bottles of wine.
It's a stick of butter every time
the lights you see he's winning.
That's fine.
I'm cool with that.
But as far as like that,
that uh,
penetrated my force
field for content wise,
uh,
when Steve Buscemi got the leading
role on a boardwalk empire,
right.
I was like,
see you guys famous though.
If you break through,
if you find a way through it,
that's what I need.
That's what I'm saying,
but try and find another
dude from an like,
he looks like a creepy dude.
Right.
He gives he,
and I'm sure he knows this because he
gets cast in those roles all the time,
so I'm not breaking any news here,
but for him to have the ability to sort
of be the face of an entire piece of
like,
uh,
the people are better looking on
even the Zombie Shit right now.
The walking dead.
Even then he was in the gangster.
They could have cast
somebody better looking,
but they chose him.
He looks like a real guy
that I would encounter.
Yeah.
There are a lot of beautiful people
and then fucking walking dead show.
That's what I'm saying.
The the pretty girl that
has the Asian boyfriend,
she just,
she never gets scraggly looking.
She was,
looks well fed her outfits like eyesight,
this outfit.
You've got to remember I came,
I was watching the first season.
Now I'm just starting again right now.
I'm looking at her outfits.
I mean,
it looks like that could
be in a magazine right now.
You know,
that's sort of like dirty,
like look like a,
she went hiking.
Yeah,
yeah,
exactly.
Like the sock goes above
the boot just a little bit.
You know,
it's like,
it's way too thought out.
I want to see fucking mayhem.
Well,
that's the thing about 28 days later
as opposed to like a television show,
28 days later was fucking dark.
And the monsters,
the zombies,
they were so much more terrifying.
100%.
It was a much more realistic scenario,
much closer.
And I was having this
Zombie discussion with,
uh,
with some people that I was watching
with and we were trying to think about
realistic,
Realistic Zombie movies
and we couldn't even,
besides 28 days later,
and it doesn't even make sense to say
realistic because there are no zombies.
But I mean,
closer to our interpretation
of what that might look like.
Well,
if we considered the different
diseases that exist in nature,
the does the different
parasites to takeover bodies,
the different,
I mean there are some incredible parasite
host relationships in nature that are
absolutely real.
Yeah.
You know,
uh,
back to another podcast I
was listening to about this,
the patient zero for for aids
and well yeah that was radio lab.
Yeah.
I listen to that well and it made
the leap from like a perfect storm.
Well,
the crazy thing is that it
happened in the early 19 hundreds,
right?
It happened.
They use the cut a hunter scenario,
so at the hunter killed a chimp and the
chimp had killed two different forms of
monkey in each one of those monkeys
had a different amine deficiency virus.
That's right.
And viruses combined
and made the jump to a person.
Yup.
They were basically required the both
of them to be able to replicate in a
fashion that was,
that they were capable because the
immune system is actually fairly
sophisticated in both apes
and us that we'll find,
find these kinds of
issues and wipe them out.
But this combination of the two of them
had all the necessary information to
build this super virus.
But,
uh,
I,
when I was listening to that,
I was like,
man,
any first of all,
why the fuck are people
killing and eating apes?
That's a bad move.
They've always been doing that.
I know it's happened forever.
No,
but you say it's a bad mood,
but when you're starving,
wow,
they'll kill and eat anything.
Right.
I Dunno if you're GE so that genetically
similar consuming that tissue
that's like,
they think it's problematic.
Yeah,
sure.
But I mean,
you know that chimps,
regular consume monkeys,
it's a huge part of their diet.
They do.
Well that's fucking crazy.
It's so crazy.
They prefer the organs.
So they eat the organs first,
which means they're eating the monkey,
the alive,
right?
Like they grab the monkeys and
they eat them organs first.
There's a crazy fucking video of
these chimps and they set up this very
sophisticated hunting strategy where
they have chimps that are like running
forward that are like pushing these
monkeys towards these other champions.
And then they come in from the sides too.
And the capture and the trees and
they have this chimp grabbing,
this monkey is called [inaudible] monkey
and the monkey screw marine and the
chimp is eating.
I'm from the hips first,
just chill alive and the monkey just
screaming and the look in his face,
it's so human like and so is the chimp.
It's really hard to watch.
But that's the harsh
reality of of the jungle.
You know?
There's just,
and people live there too and
they've always been shooting monkeys.
Yeah,
he's a new,
listen,
that radio lab,
I know that there's a new virus that
made a jump from a gorilla to a person,
a guy who shot and killed
a gorilla and has this,
there's a new like patient
zero that they were discussing.
Like if you wanted to find a patient zero.
There's a guy that's infected with an
immune deficiency virus that came directly
from a gorilla.
Hmm.
What does that tell us about us though?
I not us.
It's them.
I know,
but it really freaked me out when I first,
when I first saw or heard about that.
I remember vividly when I,
when I first found out about chimps
killing other chimps are killing other a
monkey monkeys.
Things that were really
similar to them to,
to eat for food,
whatever,
like that animal developed
as a carnivore or a omnivore.
Right?
Chimps.
Yeah.
Like what,
what,
what is it,
where,
where along the lines did they
start eating other animals?
Just vegetate forever.
Yeah.
I mean probably with chimps probably
from the moment they became,
I mean,
the
idea of being that animals,
I think the current theory is there
was climate change and that um,
some form of primates experimented
with different food sources.
That's why some primates
are still primary,
primarily vegetarians,
but the more intelligent ones were
the ones that started experimentally.
Yeah.
Because they had to to for two reasons.
It's,
it's also one of the theories that is
bandied about when they tried to figure
out why human brains develop so quickly.
Like the human brain size doubled
over a period of 2 million years,
which is apparently like the greatest
mystery in the entire fossil record
according to some biologist.
And one of the things they attributed to
might be the switch and diet or from a
strictly prep,
not just protein but resources.
Because in changing from a
strictly plant based diet,
your digestive system had to work less
hard because it wasn't processing as much
cellulose and there was more,
more resources available to think
about how to get these monkeys in,
eat them or how to get these bugs or how
to find these rodents or whatever the
fuck they were eating and killing.
And then also the more intelligent
animals were more effective.
So the more the animals
that were more clever,
they'd figured out how to use tools
if figured out hunting strategies.
Those are the ones that were
more effective in eating meat.
And it was sort of a combination
like a perfect storm,
like having less resources to deal with
processing the cellulose and the plant
fiber.
And so you're the,
the internal organs actually changed
and altered over the period of time.
And in having less resources
necessary to digest this plant matter,
the uh,
animal had more resources
to grow its brain.
Wow.
Yeah,
I saw a lot of weird shit that's,
it has to take place for many,
many years to develop development
and so on and so forth.
But yeah,
I just,
I don't know for me when to see them
in that kind of environment to see how
savage they could become and to know
that that's our closest relative.
Like when everybody ever,
anybody talks about us sort
of transcending our apelike
past and becoming far
more intelligent and not fucking
killing each other anymore.
You,
you,
if you look to your closest
relative relative their violence,
hell,
that's true.
But isn't there like a spectrum
when you think about like,
okay,
there's the people that live in the jungle
that eat bushmeat bushmeat being the,
you know,
they'll eat anything,
they'll eat chimps.
Gorillas is those people that
are eating that bushmeat.
But then there's also people here in
America that are primarily vegetarian and
they're concerned with their impact,
their carbon footprint,
and they're concerned
with animal cruelty that,
you know,
they use only if they have,
if they do eat meat,
it's organically sourced the free
range chickens for their eggs.
It's like a more,
more of a movement towards kindness then
for sure than the monkeys and chimps
that are living that
hard scrabbled jungle.
Oh,
there's no doubt that
were gentler than that.
And we're moving more towards
it being gentle in general.
So I mean that's,
that's the spectrum,
right?
Isn't that the spectrum?
The people that are in the jungle still,
they're the ones that are
still eating the monkeys.
Right.
Very few people go on hunting
trips to go get monkeys,
but that's but dope.
But that shit's been a source of,
uh,
some of the world's most intense diseases.
Sure.
AIDS,
Ebola,
whatever,
whatever it is.
Also prions,
they carry,
if you eat chimp brains,
they carry very similar prions to the
prions that like you get from like mad cow
disease.
Yeah.
So it's like,
I dunno,
aids where does it,
they were able to find patient zero,
but like where does it actually come from?
You know what I mean?
Almost like nature's way of making the
most savage amongst us evolve because it
kills them off force.
Forced evolution.
You think about what AIDS is.
I mean,
people would say you aids
is God punishing the Queens,
right?
Well,
maybe not,
but maybe it's nature's way of punishing
people that eat similar animals to what
they are.
Yeah.
And eating intelligent animals that are
closely related to you in some strange
way is how you develop those diseases.
And one of the big ones is mad cow
disease comes from people forcing fucking
cows to eat them.
How brains,
humans in New Guinea especially,
uh,
cannibals in New Guinea have been
observed having the exact same symptoms.
It's called Jacob's Creutzfeldt disease
and it comes from being a fucking
cannibal.
Yeah.
It's like nature's trying to get rid
of the people so fucking stupid that
they're eating people so crazy,
so crazy that genetically speaking that
those alterations can take place through
particular activity.
Yeah.
You know,
it's almost like it's set up,
it's like nature set up
for you to figure it out.
If you look at today,
don't eat each other
in in this day and age,
what what we're dealing with in the
age of information and the amount of
resource that we have today is the highest
level of information that's ever been
available to human beings.
As far as we,
yes,
100% access to information that's ever
been available and in this day and age,
people are generally
moving towards a kinder,
gentler way of living life.
Yes.
You know,
I'm a hunter and I take a lot of
shit from some people that have these
idealistic views of animals online,
but I understand where
they're coming from.
My,
my take on it is if
you understood animals,
you would understand that the death
by a hunter is probably the cleanest,
easiest,
safe as death in any of these animals
could go through and these animals are
going to die no matter what.
You would also understand that the amount
of protein that you can get from one
deer or elk or one moose like that one
animal dies and you could feed a family
for a year.
I mean,
you shoot a moose,
you could feed a family
for a fucking year.
That's real.
I just shot a 900 pound Moose.
I have 400 pounds of meat coming.
That's 401 pounds at work.
I was wanting to ask you that.
So you shoot the Moose,
there's the meat,
like how does it,
you can't obviously hop on an
airplane when I'm having it shipped,
I'm having,
it's very expensive.
It must be frozen the whole way.
It has to be frozen.
So it's an,
and it's very difficult times.
People just take some of it
back and they lead to the,
to the guide.
Like I have a friend,
my friend John is a guide up
in Alberta and he eats meat,
Moose meat all year round
because people give it to him,
but he also gives it to his neighbors.
He gives them,
they never buy meat from the store.
They eat everything that
they shoot or their clients.
Shoot.
He's an outfitter.
So he takes people to these
hunting environments and you know,
they have massive amounts of meat that
come from these animals and the animals
die like that.
You know,
you shoot an animal with a gun,
boom.
They follow up.
They didn't even know people are there.
Then all of a sudden they're dead.
What does it take to take a moose down?
Big Rifle?
Yeah.
Seven millimeter Remington,
ultra mag.
Boom.
Where do you hit him?
The lungs is the best double lung
because you want to eat the heart.
You don't want to waste any of the organs.
The hearts are delicious.
Yeah.
Wow.
You want to eat?
I'll show you photos.
You want to eat the heart.
The heart is delicious.
Delivers Trisha's to very nutritious.
She don't want to ruin any
of the internal organs.
Some people don't eat Oregon's.
I like him.
I think they're really good
for you and they taste good,
especially if you prepare them right.
You always watch on those nature shows
where like the lions will go for the
Oregon's first.
You're very nutritious.
The liver,
especially the liver
dictates what wolf is.
The alpha male.
The alpha male gets to
eat the liver first.
Really?
Yeah.
When?
When wolves take out an animal is there
was a guy who lived with wolves and he
had this a weird fucking set up in this
nature preserve where he was pretending
to be the Alpha male.
And one of the ways he showed dominance
is he would have a kill that they would
place and he would put a liver inside of
it and he would pull the liver out and
eat it in front of these wolves
and he would let them eat.
That was how he established himself.
And that's some gangster shit right there.
Very gangster and very crazy because
this guy wound up having to leave because
he had to go and leave the preserve to
help this local farmer who was getting
his,
his animals are getting killed by wolves.
So he had a scare them off.
So they set up all these speakers and
put these wolf sounds and what they
basically tried to do was
pretend that a larger,
much larger,
much scarier pack had moved in.
And so they push these other wolves off
and he was gone for like a couple of
months,
I believe.
Well when he came back,
the wolves no longer
accepted him as the Alpha,
so he had to beg for his position in
the pack and the wolves were snarling,
Adam and the new alpha
was going to kill him,
and so this guy was in dire danger and
he was whimpering and cowering and he had
to completely bow down and submit to
this animal that was previously allowing
him to be the Alpha crazy.
But this,
this wolf in the absence of the Alpha,
this wolf had taken over.
That's that hierarchy,
that social hierarchy that exists
within a pack that's got to be,
that's is that exclusive
to wolves.
First of all,
know exists in chimps exams as laws
exists a lot of Alpha male and credit.
Predatory animals,
not even just predatory.
I mean,
gorillas aren't predatory at all.
Gorillas,
Vegetarians,
right?
Having a female fight each other.
Yeah.
When you look at a gorilla's teeth,
those are for defense.
Those are,
those are for fighting,
right?
They don't eat anything but vegetables.
How do they become the biggest crazy,
what was that AP we're talking
about on on some other pod condo.
Ape Bondo.
A,
the Bili or Bondo ape.
It's a,
it's an enormous chimpanzee
but not as big as the gorilla.
No,
not quite interesting,
but really big nests on
the ground like a gorilla.
But there's very few photos,
very few,
uh,
like videos of them.
They have skulls though.
They know it's a complete subspecies
of that chimpanzee that actually has a
crest on its forehead.
Like a gorilla does.
Like a gorilla has like,
you know,
like almost like a Mohawk crest down
the center of his head and the enormous
biting muscles.
Hmm.
Yeah.
That's interesting.
When like you have the long term
development of specific traits as an
identifier.
Like your body is reacting to the social
environment in a physical way if give
it given enough time.
What kind of makes sense?
If you think about the variety of humans?
I mean they're finding,
they're always finding
new species of humans.
Like they found this new human that lived
in Russia is recently as 40,000 years
ago.
Complete subspecies.
Like,
you know,
there's Neanderthal,
there's homosapien and there's that.
The hobbit person,
they found the Flores.
That fucking thing was
alive 12,000 years ago.
Wild 12,000 years ago,
there was a three foot tall monkey person.
Look at the variety,
just if people that exist right now,
just that you remember on a previous
podcast you were talking about,
uh,
that MMA fighter,
the transgender MMA fighter.
And then you also said like
African American females
have the same bone density
as an untrained males,
like a it Ma men who don't,
if you lift weights,
man who lift weights about
a higher bone density,
alright,
then men who don't live weights,
right?
African American females have a very
similar bone density to white males who
don't lift weights.
That's crazy.
Crazy.
And so then you would assume that African
American males have even bonded us
even thick and even higher bone density.
Yeah.
Bringing up the,
bringing up the question of like,
because there's the argument in that
particular case was that she has a
strategic advantage,
right?
We're not just our physical city.
There's mechanical advantage shores,
the hip size of the hand,
size of the jaw.
The ability to absorb
punishments different varies.
But the also the argument
can be made across the board.
I mean there are some men that are way
more feminine and if they transitioned to
a transgender woman,
they would be way closer
to a biological woman.
Then if say like Mark Hunt
transition to being a female,
I mean that's a tough,
you know,
take
Brock Lesnar and turn them into a
transgender person like you gotta fucking
tough sell.
It's a very problematic when whenever
you're dealing with changing nature and
trying to balance things out.
Yes.
That's the argument against
testosterone replacement therapy.
Testosterone replacement therapy was
erroneous Lee aloud and then they realize
like,
well,
what the fuck are we doing?
We're allowing guys,
essentially it takes steroids.
The idea being that
some people were unfair,
it was an unfair disadvantage because
they didn't have as much testosterone so
you allow them to take it.
But then guys were taking like
fucking alien levels of testosterone.
I mean,
they,
they had one guy test at the average
person has between 300 and 600 like for a
really young healthy man,
milligrams to Nanogram,
whatever the fuck does,
but whatever the,
the,
the measurement is,
but this guy had 1,475 they,
you know,
and he was on the testosterone
place and you're like,
okay,
you fuck,
you know,
like ruin it for everybody
just ruined it for every,
you're juicing,
you're taking steroids.
And that's,
you know,
it's like some people have
naturally high levels.
Yeah.
But there's also some people that have
naturally low levels and the argument is
some people are more athletically
inclined and there's some people that are
just,
they're just whatever they do,
they're going to have this
ectomorphic like Pudgy,
buttery.
So for a long period of time,
presumably fighters were
fighting with testosterone.
No problem.
We'll,
they wasn't even,
it wasn't a thing that was restricted.
Right.
And adding it,
it was always restrict.
Totally.
It was,
yes.
Always.
Yes.
Well before they were being tested.
This is,
this is primarily speculations,
but based on a lot of evidence from
fighters from first account firsthand
accounts of guys who actually did this,
a giant percentage of MMA fighters
in the early days were on steroids.
A giant percentage,
like a huge percentage.
90 something crazy.
Yeah.
Okay.
Let's say even if it's 60,
that's crazy.
You know?
Um,
and then they started doing urine tests
and urine tests are essentially an
intelligence test.
All you have to do is cycle off.
By the time you weigh in on,
you know,
fight day and or after your fight
and as long as you've cycled off,
you have all the benefits of taking
testosterone or whatever the fuck you're
taking and none of it
shows up in the urine test.
Then,
um,
people get caught even during
urine tests and they're like,
oh,
okay,
well you fucking dummies.
You have made us want to
look deeper into this thing.
And then they started doing random
tests on people and then they started
catching a lot of people.
And then they said,
okay,
well we need to do is do really
heavy duty comprehensive blood test.
And that's what the UFC has
started doing fairly recently.
The problem is they're really expensive.
They're doing that to comply with what?
Not with anything.
No one's asking them to do it.
They're doing it because they want to
clean up the sport because the sport is a
huge image issue.
And also from a safety perspective,
a person who is on testosterone,
say if you and another guy who were of
the same age or the same body type your
same weight and you decide to fight,
but you're,
your opponent is taking all sorts
of performance enhancing drugs,
it's conceivably possible and very
likely that he'll be able to hit you more
than you'll be able to hit him.
He'll have more endurance,
he'll be able to do more damage to you.
Not always.
There's a lot of people that have
been on steroids that have lost.
So even though they had
an unfair advantage,
they didn't have the skill
level of their opponents.
So they've lost.
So here's a question for you
then in in that scenario,
what if both are on testosterone?
Yeah.
But then you're requiring people
essentially to compete at a fair level,
you're acquiring them to take something
that's going to fuck up their endocrine
system.
Because if you take testosterone,
you don't need it.
If you're a person and like you know your,
your ball gets shot off in the war,
you know,
and you know you're not producing it.
I mean that was pretty specific.
I don't know why I said that.
Okay.
You know,
for whatever reason and you,
um,
you are allowed to take a hormone,
that's one thing.
But if you're a person like you who's
young and healthy and you just choose to
do it to give yourself an advantage and
then you force your opponent to do it,
to give him an advice,
you know,
he has to do it in order
to keep up with you.
The issue is his body doesn't
need like extra testosterone.
He's adding it to it.
So your body is confused.
Even though it's a performance
enhancing substance,
your body is confused as to
why the levels are so high.
So your body stops producing
natural endogenous testosterone.
That becomes a problem.
And that's how they got around these
tests for the longest time because they
said my client needs testosterone.
Why look at his blood tests and the
blood tests showed a very low level of
testosterone would they didn't show is
the reason why it was low is cause he was
taking extra testosterone and it forces
endocrine system to freak out and be
consistent with the guy
who's getting 1,475 is I go,
we don't need to make
fucking testosterone.
We got plenty.
Yeah.
But see the argument being,
obviously I've heard it
mostly applied to baseball.
It if it seems like
baseball was the big issue,
they had guys in the courtroom room,
whatever it was.
And then there was this
counter argument which,
which was like,
well don't you want to see home runs?
See,
but that's different in MMA.
MMA is you're dealing with a sport that's
primary objective is to damage your
opponent.
Right.
And if you can give someone that lets
them damaged their opponent better,
more efficiently,
you're essentially allowing
them to create a crime.
I mean this,
that's been the argument
by people who are clean.
No athletes who don't take it like you're,
you're,
it's like assault.
Like what you're doing is like you're
hitting them more than you should be able
to.
You were cheating and cheating.
You're causing damage to your opponent
and you should be perhaps responsible for
that damage that you
caused to your opponent.
Wow.
Do you agree with that?
Yeah,
it's,
it's a very good argument.
So I mean,
a logical argument,
it's like many things in life.
Like the transgender argument,
it's not a gray,
it's not a black and white issue.
Yeah.
You know,
I've always said that I'm in
favor of men fighting women.
If the woman wants a fight,
a man,
I'm going to fit.
If I'm in favor of people riding bowls,
I'm in favor of people.
You know,
you want to wrestle a bear.
OOPS,
I'm not stopping you.
If you're a grown adult with a functional
mind and you understand the risks and
that you want to do whatever
the fuck you want to do,
you want to do it,
you go right ahead.
I don't have any problem with it,
but there's a,
you know,
you're at a disadvantage.
If a woman wants to fight a man,
there's no doubt about it.
She's at a physical disadvantage.
Doesn't mean that a
woman can't beat a man.
It is possible.
There's most certainly possible that a
woman who's highly skilled could beat a
man that's the same size as her,
but it's also possible she
get knocked the fuck out.
You know?
That's possible too.
And there was a woman named Lucy,
a Riker who's a famous MMA fighter,
or do you watch it to rather?
What'd you watch it?
I've watched everything,
Dude.
I can't say I wouldn't really,
I watch everything you would watch.
Let's say Rhonda Rousey fight a man.
Yes,
I would most certainly want killed and
actual dude from the same weight class.
I don't think she would fare well.
But if she wanted to do it and
it was going to be on television,
I'll probably watch it.
I'm going to be honest.
Wow.
Yeah.
I mean it's,
what am I going to do?
I'm not watching it.
I don't know.
I'm just saying courage it.
And she called me up and said,
hey,
what should I do?
I'd say,
don't do it.
I agree with you that it would be a tough,
a tough one for her.
Right.
So because of that,
I feel like I can already predict the
outcome and I wouldn't want to see that.
Maybe,
maybe she arm bars a fuck that dude.
Right.
That's possible too.
But it's a dangerous,
maybe we'll think about the
early UFC like Royce Gracie,
fuck chemo for instance.
Kimo was far stronger,
far larger,
far more powerful.
And his ability to deliver
strikes and hoist was,
but I always got him,
he's fucking had a war.
He duked it out.
But his greater skill level prevailed.
And that was the essence of what the UFC,
what made the UFC so special.
It was completely unfair.
He had one,
you know,
quote unquote professional fighters to
the word professional is a very loose
term,
something technique.
I mean chemo most certainly eventually
became a legit professional fighter,
no doubt about it.
But back in the day,
he was a martial artist who
is competing in the UFC.
He was like 200 fucking 60 pounds and
hoists was one 75 I mean Kimo was jacked.
I need just chat.
He came in carrying a fucking
giant wooden cross on his back.
I mean the whole thing was craziness.
So without a doubt he had
physical advantages over hoists,
but hoists his skill level
allowed him to prevail.
Right.
So if that's legal,
why wouldn't it be legal for Rhonda to
fight a man who has her same weight?
Well,
I guess I guess there's a
difference between legal.
Obviously I don't think
it should be illegal,
but I guess I've just part personally
I feel like I could fairly fairly
accurately predict the,
and then not want to see that outcome.
It all depends on skill level.
So like,
let's take,
let's take a,
for instance,
let's take a middle of the road MMA
fighter fights at 155 pounds and make him
fight Cain Velasquez.
He's going to get fucking steamrolled.
But let's take Hixon Gracie when he was
in his prime and make him fight a guy
who's the same size as cane,
but does know what the fuck he's doing.
He did that before it,
when Hickson was like 19.
He fought this Guy Zulu,
who's just enormous fucking super muscular
dude that Hixon fought in Brazil and
Hixon beat his ass twice.
He got his back and strangle them.
Right.
He weathered the storm,
had this fucking giant guy smashing
them and jumping all over him,
but he eventually used a
skill level to defeat them.
So it's skill level is relative.
It's a huge issue in the contest.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Physical got to have the combination.
Right.
For sure.
I guess I just,
it's,
it's interesting because they put,
I was looking at the,
uh,
what does it pound for pound thing and
they put Ronda Rousey on the pound on the
pound for pound thing.
What does she fight at?
One 35 yes.
Yeah.
And so,
you know,
I don't know that sad.
I guess that's what stood out to me.
Like it doesn't even,
I don't know.
To me it didn't make sense.
Well women's MMA,
she's number one.
Oh,
I know.
Hands Down for sure.
But she was in the list with the dude.
Yeah.
Let's see.
That's tricky.
It's tricky.
I mean it's very subjective.
The pound for pound list is
very subjective in my opinion.
Is Mighty Mouse Johnson's the best?
He fights at one 25 when I look at
like technically what he's able to do.
Right.
I don't,
I don't think there's anybody like
him in MMA does everything perfect.
But a lot of people don't think of him
as number one because he fights it 125
pounds.
He's a small guy and you know,
they look at like John
Jones who's also elite.
I mean so good.
But he's two oh five so you think of John
Jones being the number one guy because
he's knocking guys out.
Just submitting guys.
But Demetrius is doing things perfectly.
Like if you've scaled up Demetrius,
oh my God,
if you make Demetrius,
if he can move the way he
moves and he'd be 250 pounds.
Yeah,
it'd be the greatest fighter
the world has ever known.
Right.
But some of it's relevant relative too,
right?
Because he,
is he facing the same competition?
No,
he's not.
And he's also not facing the
same amount of dangerous.
The amount of people that get knocked
out in the flyweight division is
relatively small in
comparison to the night now,
number of people that get knocked out in
the heavyweight division holding onto a
few extra brain cells,
there's a point of diminishing returns
and it comes to the ability to deliver
power.
When you think about like what a 250
pound man can deliver and how much 250
pound man can take.
Yes.
As opposed to what 125 pound man can
deliver and what 125 pound man can take.
It's like at the heavyweight man,
when guys land big shots,
even the best guys go down.
Even Cain,
Cain got clipped by one punch by junior
dos Santos and his legs went out and he
went unconscious.
Yeah,
at least briefly.
That's just the reality
of heavyweight fights.
It's one of the reasons why
heavyweights are so exciting.
That's cause they can end a fight with
one punch and that can happen at two oh
five and that can happen in one 78 it's
even happened at one 25 I mean to meet
Trish Johnson knocked out.
Joseph Benevidez is one
of the best in the world,
period.
In any way.
Class with one punch.
He just caught him perfect
and knocked him out.
The whole,
the whole knockout thing
like it seems like there's,
it seems like UFC has changed a lot.
Right?
In what way?
Well I don't know.
I feel like I watched
a card the other night.
I think it was the most finishes in the
history of cards cause I was Sydney.
Australia.
Yeah.
That happens.
That happens some sometimes.
I don't know.
I don't have,
the statistics are,
are more finishes happening
in general right now?
Well,
they're,
they're rewarded for finishing,
so people are encouraged to get
performance of the night bonuses.
Very financially beneficial to them.
But you'll also have a card where
every fight goes a decision.
You know,
you also have a card where
every fight goes to submission,
which is much rare but can happen.
Yeah,
I guess it's just hidden boilies yeah,
I guess it's just like,
it almost feels like a guy's career is
tied into his ability to knock out maybe
more so than being well rounded fighter.
Well,
like guys who are exciting get,
we'll get more fights than
guys who may be more skilled.
I don't know about all that.
I mean it kind of,
but ultimately the cream rises to the top,
the best guy to hold the full package.
The best guys.
When,
I mean,
yeah,
like say like say a guy like Rory
Mcdonald who was on the podcast yesterday.
Oh,
role.
Roy is not a guy who
had chases a knockout,
but he's knocked a bunch of guys out.
But he's just super skilled and
technical and he's undeniable.
I mean,
he's one of the top contenders
and eventually he's going
to get a shot at the,
but I heard him on an MMA podcast and
even he said that his most recent knockout
was what he needed to
cement the title shot.
What was a big win too?
He fought Terex Hafeni who's a former
Strikeforce welterweight champion and
destroyed him.
Beat his ass.
So it was a definitive,
exciting Vic.
That's what I mean.
That's what I mean is it's a,
it's a better story.
Travels farther.
What sells,
you know,
it's a lot of it.
And what sells.
Like there's so many
guys in that division,
Matt Brown,
Robbie Lawler,
Hector Lombard,
and these guys are fucking ferocious,
has so many ferocious
guys in that division.
It's,
you got to sell yourself.
So you would say you climb the ladder
faster if you're knocking guys out.
Well,
if you're exciting,
but you could be submissions.
You know,
Damien Maia climbed the ladder
fast by submitting people.
It's,
it really depends entirely on what the
routed and it also like who you beat.
You know,
if she'd go in there and you
beat a guy who's not that good,
but you knock them out,
that's not as impressive as if you go in
there and you knock out Anderson Silva.
It's just that Mcgregor deserves the hype.
Everybody deserves what they get.
So yes,
everybody deserves what they get.
Whether or not he's the best in the world,
that's to be determined,
but he gets people excited.
That's a big part of
what the sport is about.
When we were talking earlier
about charisma and teachers,
like teachers having the ability to
be excited about the subject matter,
and it makes people drawn
to them well in MMA,
the ability to get people excited
about watching you fight is,
it's an aspect of fighting.
It's,
it's,
it's a,
it's a variable and you know
to say that Connor doesn't get,
why do you let them talk then?
How about we never left fighters talk,
you know,
how about we never do
post fight interviews.
You're obviously a part of the integrated
package of you want to follow a guy,
you want to know who he is.
And then there's some guys like
John Jones is a perfect example.
Jon Jones a spectacularly talented,
but people don't like him for some reason.
And I've speculated that some of it
might be racism because he's this young
cocky black guy.
But there's a lot of people that
disagree with me and they say no.
Like they think he's fake.
They think his personality
sucks or they think that,
you know,
he does too many stupid shit,
stupid things that are contrary to this
Christian image that he's trying to
sell.
And there's a lot of variables.
But the reality is Conor McGregor puts
more asses in seats than the number one
pound for pound fighter in the world.
And that's fucking crazy.
Yup.
John Jones is being fucking everybody,
man.
He beat Ryan Bader.
He put on my treated,
the automic,
cheated asleep.
He beat a gust of sin and the fucking
unbelievable war of attrition.
He,
I mean,
he's beating everybody.
They put in front of me,
submitted Vito Belfort.
You can go on and on and on.
His list of accomplishments
have been spectacular.
Conor knocked out Dustin Pour,
Yay,
that's his best fight.
You know,
knock on Diego Brandao could fighters,
but they're not,
there's not Josie,
although he's not destroying Josie,
although in the first round.
So it's like what?
What is it about here that if it moves
too far in that direction that it becomes
more of a show in less of a contest?
No,
because there's always a
guy like Cain Velasquez.
Cain Velasquez doesn't talk much.
Beats everybody's ass.
Right?
That's how you beat your rate at a time.
Yeah.
If Conor Mcgregor,
you know,
wasn't skilled,
he wouldn't be getting as much hype.
Part of what is hyped about him is that
he's the perfect combination of things.
He's an intelligent trash talker who's
also highly skilled and his results have
been pretty God damn oppressive.
Whereas Cain Cain is huge
just because he's awesome.
I mean,
do you even,
no one can even recall one thing that
he said that's been like captivating,
but when he beats your ass for five
rounds is fucking unbelievable storm of
punches.
And kicks and knees and take downs
in this never ending gas tank.
That's what makes Kayne special.
What makes him special is his
fucking skill level period.
End of this cut.
Same with Mark Hunt.
No one's getting all fired up about
hunts personality and interviews.
You know me feels awkward on camera,
but man,
when he fucking launches a
left hook and shatters dudes,
jaws and sends him flying,
that's what people get
excited about works too.
I guess it's just,
I guess it's just interesting that how
the whole social social media structure
has in every facet increased is the
importance of how of your public behavior.
Once like once upon a time athletes that
was just not even something they had to
consider.
Right.
You know,
and now you're not just
training at the gym,
you're training with the PR person who's
trying to help you get the most out of
every tweet.
What's also the difference between a
person like who the person actually is and
their public persona,
right?
That's eroded,
You get to know who they really are.
Like,
if you've,
if someone makes some like
really offensive or really
ignorant tweets and they
put all like it,
you go,
oh well that guy has these thoughts.
You know,
like the guy from orange is the new black,
what is his name?
Jason Silva.
Is that his name?
The guy from,
Oh Silverman.
Silverman.
Yeah.
Like I read this article saying that he
was ruining the show for them because
his tweets are so stupid.
And uh,
I was reading as to love that headline.
They are really dumb.
His tweets are don't.
Wow.
They really,
they are really dumb.
His tweets.
But it's family.
In what way?
Like she says stupid shit.
It's like wow,
you can pull them up.
But no,
I just think the offending
people very bright.
Wow.
They're,
they're goofy.
Alright.
Ignorant kind of tweets.
Okay.
I mean maybe he's not,
maybe it's just not put
a lot of effort into it.
You know,
sometimes people tweet shit and they just
write it down and expect it to be like
scrutinized.
And there's that possibility too,
you know?
Or maybe he's not aware of how goofy
142 they ask him to stop tweeting.
I don't know.
Oh,
I know there was a guy in ESPN that
actually there was a store that I tweeted
the other day that he got suspended off
Twitter because he was arguing about
evolution,
arguing for evolution with
some other baseball player.
And Espn denied that that was
the reason why he got removed.
But what at little fuck
else could it have been?
He was arguing with his former
athlete who was like nuts.
No believes the earth.
10,000 years old,
one of those motherfuckers.
Right.
And he got suspended.
Like the fact that ESPN can suspend
you from Twitter and ESPN says it has
nothing to do with that.
When you tell us what the fuck it out
do it because none of the shit that he
said is offensive.
Right.
He was talking with no swears,
no insults.
Talking about science and how important
science was talking about transitionary
fossils,
talking about the reality of evolution.
This is the evidence.
And they suspended him from Twitter.
So what else would cause them
to suspend him from Twitter?
What the fuck could you do outside of
tweeting that would cause you to be
suspended from Twitter?
And how the fuck does ESPN
suspended guy from Twitter,
not,
not uh,
a part of their marketing plan?
Well,
you know,
they're saying that they own you,
they own your thoughts,
they own your ability to express yourself.
Yes.
Do you,
there is a connection between the
sports fan in religion though.
How many thank God's coming out after a
fighter wins or someone wins the super
bowl or maybe,
but this guy was pretty clear about who's
wasn't saying that there was no god.
Oh he wasn't saying he was,
it wasn't anti religion,
Bollywood pro sign those,
those that disagree with the concept
of evolution or whoever it was he was
arguing with,
that's still a large percentage of the
public if that's really what they're
going for.
It obviously,
I mean obviously you're not,
yeah you are,
but shabby God damn at Espn,
right?
He's just fucking Christ.
I mean that's just like how many times
does it have to be explained over and
over and over?
How many biologists have to come on board?
How many times does evolution
have to be explained?
I don't know that they need to believe it.
I think that they're just more worried
about satisfying the audience and
audience.
A segment of the audience that they
might have walked out fuck ever.
It's just so depressing that a sports
network could actually have issue with a
guy who's talking about,
I agree with you and beyond that,
it's his Twitter account.
Exactly.
Yeah,
but it's not,
oh,
you if you,
I mean it is,
but if you work for ESPN
is not your Twitter,
you're their bitch.
You're their bitch.
And that's,
that's a common thing they tweet for
people that are on television shows.
When I was doing a show,
they asked me,
they wanted to take over my social media.
They'll fuck adding.
Yes they did.
And I told him to go fuck themselves.
Like,
are you out of your fucking
mind even asks you that.
I won't say no.
No,
not a name,
but like a company that I was working for,
a network that I was working
for that wanted to take over my,
they wanted a tweet for me and I said,
you can go fuck.
You can't tweet for me if you,
if you read a tweet is the only time the
tweets not from me is when it's an auto
upload,
a youtube video where
it says just uploaded,
blah,
blah.
That's not coming from my
fingers on the keyboard,
but it's coming directly from someone
who works for me who's only tweeting
something through a automatic top blue.
There's a little checkbox that says,
yes,
tweak this.
Yeah,
exactly.
And just to let everyone,
the other videos are getting uploaded.
It's not opinions,
it's not facts.
It's not interesting articles or
stories that I find fascinating.
It exposes though,
it exposes the whole a deficiency
of that traditional medium,
how they can just sort of dangle it.
You know what I mean?
How compliance is such a huge part of it.
Will you know what
happened with Joan Rivers,
right?
Oh Shit.
The endorsement after she was dead.
Yes,
it was an iPhone endorsement.
That's crazy.
Like what the fuck is daddy at all about?
Very,
very creepy.
Disgusting.
I saw that come up.
So that's one of those things are bad.
You don't realize,
you don't realize bad look,
choose or that I,
you know,
there's a thing called UFC fight
pass that allows you to watch fights.
I love it too.
And I was using it.
I'm like,
man,
five past fucking awesome.
I love this thing.
And I tweeted it because it was,
and people will use shill how
much they pay you for that.
Like zero,
zero.
Right.
You can't like anything.
Well,
I can't look anything as UFC related.
Yeah,
sure.
Yes.
Which is,
which is weird.
What's good?
This looks good.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Because people are
there checking up there.
They're there,
they're questioning things.
They're not just accepting
things for face value.
They're assuming that some fuckery is
around and even though they're wrong in
some circumstances,
I liked the fact that
there's some fantasy.
It's a bad investment for you.
For me personally,
yes.
No,
not really.
Cause I can talk about it.
No.
Oh No,
no,
no.
I'm not,
it's a bad investment for you.
What did I,
what did I mean to say by that?
Like you can,
you can go out there and talk
about something that you like.
Right.
But the second that somebody can point
out that maybe you were influenced in
some way than they have,
they have a case,
right?
And,
but if you allow,
if you allow that to happen,
right?
If you allow them to respond,
like do you respond back to them?
No.
No,
but on here maybe.
Yeah.
I mean,
I'm saying it right now on Twitter.
If I did that all day,
that's the people that I'd be responding
to and that would make people gravitate
towards criticizing me so
that I would respond to them.
I mean,
that's the trolling trap,
right?
Yeah.
They criticize you.
So they get you to try to
react to them and they go,
hi,
you reacted.
I won.
I mean,
that's what it is.
A game.
Well,
it's,
and there's legitimate
criticism that's interesting.
You know that like you gotta
take into consideration.
There's people that have a perspective
that maybe even if you don't agree with,
you could see their point of view and
maybe adjust with what you are projecting
so that you're more clear with your
original intention where your or your,
your actual intention.
There's people that get things wrong.
They,
you know,
and that's how small a fucking,
especially when it comes to Twitter,
it's 140 characters and it's,
it's typing,
you're missing inflection.
He's a social cues.
Yeah.
There's so much that's missing context.
There's so much that's missing.
It's such an,
that's one of the issues
that I have with blogs.
Like you can write a bunch of
really harsh shit in a blog,
but while you're typing things out,
like a conversation is a real
way to communicate things.
And when you're typing things you can,
you know,
you're,
you're missing all sorts of social
cues and contexts you're missing.
Who is that person that's writing that?
I want to see your fucking stupid face
when you're writing this or when you're
saying this.
I want to see someone challenge you on
it and see what your response to the
challenges.
So I know who you are as a human and I
know whether or not to take your ideas
into consideration.
So then what's the consequence of people
communicating less this way and more
through their thumbs?
A lot of confusion for sure.
There's there's,
and also the ability for individuals to
draw the conclusions that reinforce what
they already think.
Yes.
Which is a problem.
It's definitely a problem and it allows
people to have careers that are social
retards,
allows them to express themselves in this
really distorted way and basing it on
their preconceived notions what this
person is and this is the result I would
like to draw.
So I will write a,
you know,
fucking thousand words on this.
Yes.
The Internet has allowed for individuals
to hide in a way that they were never
capable of before.
You just get around a group of like
minded individuals and jerk each other off
all day long and your gold.
Yes.
While there's a really interesting article
that I was reading about this guy who
was a part of this like skeptic community
and he disagreed with these other
people in the skeptic community and
this woman who's in this community had
written some blog criticizing him and
he said that he was going to be at this
certain conference who would love to
discuss it with her and she wrote,
do not approach me at this conference.
You're not say.
And he was like,
well you wrote 14 different
blogs mentioning me and I
can't even say hi to you.
And then another man said,
I am also going to be this conference
and if you come near me and talk to me,
I will have the conference
organizers are inherited called.
But it's like you're a vote,
you're a social retard
and you're admitting your
social retard because you're
willing to communicate about this person.
You willing to,
you know,
call them out or you know,
a fucking publicly shame them or whatever
you trying to do with your written
words.
But it's as far as like
actually communicating like
human beings were naturally
doing before the Internet.
You don't want any part of that,
right?
Like you want to be
able to criticize them,
but knock community,
you want to have more control over the
discourse than you should be allowed.
But you also want to define reality.
You don't want reality to find,
you don't want that person to
be in front of you and going,
I never said that.
Like,
that's not what I mean.
You know,
What you're doing is reinforcing your
own narrative by distorting reality,
social anxiety,
uh,
high school all over again and I mean
that's what they're trying to avoid.
They're trying to avoid confrontation
by creating confrontation in,
in a literal way and in
a way where you know,
in,
in a written word way and insulated way.
That's why then they put it on a blog.
Just the choir.
Anybody who disagrees.
Banham.
Anybody disagrees in the comment section,
Ban them and create this fucking
echo chamber and it's so unhealthy.
And that's,
I mean,
that's a lot of
progressive thinking today.
They'll call it progressive,
but it's like so closed off to
any alternative points of view,
you know,
I mean,
progressive,
conservative conservatism,
right?
It's like,
it's like a religion in a lot of ways.
In a lot of ways.
It's restrictive,
alternative and also very unkind.
You know,
one of the things about like
a lot of progressive culture,
today's is call out mentality.
And this,
you know,
there's no ability to,
uh,
shame.
I got something coming up,
uh,
video that I'm doing for charity,
this holiday season.
It's for UNICEF.
I don't know if I'm
allowed to talk about it,
but whatever.
I already,
I already did a,
and they approach me and they're like,
listen,
you know,
this time of year you're going to be
showing off all the latest and greatest
cool stuff people to buy.
Uh,
would you
be willing to unbox our survival box?
They have a survival box,
which is like fundamental things that can
help people survive in shitty parts of
the world anyway,
and immediately asked her,
I said Yes to do it.
I thought,
oh fuck,
as UNICEF fucked anybody over.
Like what did I just open myself up to?
Because there's this concern
that like through association,
even if my intentions were the best,
that to the right person,
I may have just added just the right
amount of fuel for them to build an
identity around my decision.
That's so true,
right?
You have to be really careful when you
attach yourself to anyone in sanction.
Very,
very careful.
Then now I'm reading the Wikipedia in
UNICEF and it turns out that they collect,
uh,
in terms of revenue,
like,
like billions,
like they're huge.
But on the positive side,
a way to evaluate a charity is to see
how much money actually makes it to the
people that you're supposed to be helping
as opposed to like the administration,
like the salaries of the
people that work there.
And 92% gets out to people.
That's incredible.
Which is pretty good.
So it's incredible.
I mean,
that's probably the best I've ever heard.
Is it?
Yeah.
I don't think I've ever recall.
I don't recall anybody getting that much.
I've,
I've heard of horrible scenario where
zero or like 80% and 80% goes to
administrative costs and that's a common,
that's fairly common.
And they'll say,
well,
there's no other way,
you know,
there's no other way around it.
There's,
there's some pretty big
obscenity charities out there.
Yeah.
If you Google the percentage of
money that actually goes to charity,
there's some pretty harrowing numbers
when we've talked about on the podcast
have already listed all the railings.
Yeah.
Some of them are just disgusting.
This is a lot of fake fucking
charities and people get involved.
And I'm like,
do you remember when,
why clef John was running for
fucking president of Haiti?
No.
Yeah,
this is like,
that's like one of the big criticisms
was that how much of the money was going
like that he was trying
to generate for his,
um,
campaigns trying well,
he was trying to,
uh,
benefit Haiti after Haiti to
get hit by that big earthquake.
And there they found out that like a
very small percentage of the money was
actually going to elite illegal.
I don't know man.
I don't think there's actually
like a league goal number.
So you can start a charity
for a particular cause.
Have no interest in servicing that cause
keep all the money for yourself and
call it salary.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Like that's a huge fucking problem,
right?
Yes,
it should be,
but I think you can get
away with some shit man.
Apparently.
Yeah.
That seems to be,
that seems to be the case.
Yeah.
Quake gains little why club can
be found at hip hop artists.
Uh,
when was this quake in Haiti?
Little can be found of a hip hop
artist charity and there's um,
he was claiming that he and
dirty crucifixion after the
earthquake when he faced
questions about his charities financial
record and the ability to handle what
eventually amounted to
$16 million in donations.
That's so dark,
man.
Hmm.
Yeah.
I don't know like how
much actually went where,
what obviously,
I don't know.
He could be swindled by some dude that
he was attached to who ended up misusing
the funds.
And yeah,
it's possible.
But somebody in that chain of
command is a dark human being.
This is what it says.
The forensic audit audit examined
$3 million of the charities,
uh,
2005 to 2009 expenses and found (250)
600-0580 in illegitimate benefits to Mr
John and other,
a Yaley board and staff members as well
as improper or potentially improper
transactions.
These included $24,000 from Mr. Jones
show first services and $30,000 for a
private jet that transported Lindsay
Lohan from New Jersey to a benefit in
Chicago that raised only 66,000.
So 50% of the money that the benefit
raised went to Lindsay Lohan's jet.
Yeah,
I dunno.
The audit considered it appropriate
though for the charity to pay Mr John
$100,000 to perform at a fundraiser in
Monaco because that was his market rate.
So he did a fundraiser and during
the fundraiser that he organized,
he got $100,000 he had himself paid
$100,000 for a fucking fundraiser.
Well,
I'd like to be clear about
this upcoming units at video.
They did offer me money
to do it and I said,
hell no.
How about that?
It also found acceptable Yaley I guess.
What is the name of the benefit to spend
$125,114 on travel and other matters
related to a 60 minutes report on why
clefs mission to help the people of Haiti
and his personal success story.
So what's the fallout for this?
People think he's a piece of shit.
He's probably,
yeah,
I didn't even know about it.
Yeah.
I don't know.
I don't know man.
It's like if,
if he generates all this money and
more money goes to the charity,
then would have gone to the
charity without him doing it.
Is that a benefit?
Is that an inappropriate thing?
It's,
I don't know.
Think him getting paid a hundred grand,
do a fucking show when he's doing a chair.
I mean,
I've done fundraisers.
You know what?
I get paid zero.
I thought for 10 the whole idea,
every time I've done a fundraiser,
I've gotten paid zero months.
Yes,
he got a hundred grand doing a fundraiser.
That alone is fucking bullshit.
Yeah,
that's bullshit.
But that plays up the whole thing we were
talking about earlier about how people
want to attach themselves to something
and because that it's easy to prey on
those individuals.
I'm doing a charity,
I helped the poor.
Don't you want a piece of that?
Doesn't your,
that doesn't your psyche require that,
that great feeling that
comes through donation?
Definitely.
But the problem is with things like this,
I think people are fools if they don't
know that that's going to get out.
Oh,
you mean in his case you have to be a
fool to not know that someone's going to
find out you spent 30 grand on a fucking
private jet and fly Lindsay Lohan to do
a benefit.
Like how,
what?
What?
Lindsay Lohan.
Oh,
I'm confused.
You know you're not flying
Nelson Mandela somewhere.
All right.
Like what?
What kind of an impact is Lindsay Lohan,
a young pretty actress girl going to
have on your fucking charity for Haiti?
Right.
You're telling me that that money
wouldn't have been better spent on Haiti
itself?
Like that seems crazy.
Yeah.
I,
this is one of the benefits of the
distribution of information and things
opening up is like once upon a time if
some charities asking you for money and
you have,
you literally,
there's no way to even look for that
information or to to figure out where that
money's going.
So it's going to be,
it's obviously harder now to to hide
those operations because in his case,
yeah.
Could you imagine what it would have
been like just decades ago just to,
to audit an organization.
It's a charitable organization.
How many charitable or
charitable organizations over
the years it had been total
frauds just bilking money
from people cashed too.
Is there a standard number?
I mean do you have to have
a certain percentage that
is like I dedicated towards
the charity mean to me personally,
just from like a logic perspective.
If it,
it would seem it would have to be half.
No.
Am I,
am I crazy?
Does that seem reasonable?
Yeah.
Well even that,
I mean,
the think a UNICEF,
UNICEF is fucking Brockton with 98%.
90 to 90%.
That's amazing.
Crazy thing is though I still did the
math on it and they're so huge that that
remaining 8% is still a big number.
The worst.
Uh,
there's a thing on
America's worst charities.
America's 50 worst charities.
Raykin nearly 1 billion for corporate
fundraising is very fitting this time of
year because these,
these vultures,
these vampires,
they're out right now.
This is when they're coming after you.
Above the law.
America's worst charities.
This kid's wish network,
uh,
millions of dollars.
They only give a set of 3 cents
on the dollar to helping kids.
That's the children's wish foundation.
Which network?
Oh,
okay.
They're like a rip off of the 2010.
They hired the crisis management woman.
I'm not going to give her name,
but that did the BP spill
for disgusting.
It's just,
you know,
there's so many vultures out there and
then so many people that they want to
make a lot of money being
involved in charities,
they're like,
ah,
you know,
I'm a CEO of a charity.
I should be making what a
CEO of a corporation we make.
Well that's like,
that's counterintuitive.
That's,
that goes against what everybody
thinks of when they think of charities.
I think of you doing it for charity,
like you're doing it.
This is like you're doing it to help.
How do you feel about charity in general?
So it's a great thing if it's real,
it's a great thing.
If it's a real,
I mean much of it could be a
problem to write too much charity.
In what way?
Well,
I don't know.
Everyone always talks about like aid going
to Africa and then war lords and shit
taking control of it and it only helping
them maintain their grip of on of power
and yeah,
that's kind of a different conversation.
I know it's not,
yeah,
like real charity is like Red Cross.
Like would people need
blankets and there's just some
sort of a disaster in that
come in.
They get food and they set up a,
you know,
a food kitchen for folks that
you mean like check charity here?
Yeah.
Local charity charity that you can audit.
Mm,
I see what you're saying.
Charity where you know it's going to be
like if you watch like a soup kitchen
line,
like okay,
that's real.
Like there's these people.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I want to contribute to that.
If you're sending money to,
you know,
fill in the blank some country
sending money to the Congo.
Well yeah,
the UNICEF one is to help people
there in Africa and that's the,
that's the weird part of it.
Okay.
So it's 92% is going to those people,
but how much of it actually goes?
Exactly.
People suck.
And that's,
I think that's the conclusion that we
could probably draw somewhere on the east.
Like whether it's from
Ferguson or this fucking CV,
CBC guy that's beating
chicks up or bill Cosby,
Julian people and raping them.
We have focused on a lot of negativity.
This podcast,
I feel like we could,
we could have done better.
Where's the optimism?
It's too late.
There's also the thing that
when you're aware of negativity,
it kind of,
when you expose it,
it makes it much more difficult for
that negativity prosper in the future.
I suppose you're correct about that.
Right,
so maybe in that case our
negativity was actually positivity.
I would like to look at it that way.
Seems convenient.
I would like to say that we did some good,
we had some,
some discussions.
We highlighted some gray areas.
It's true.
They need to be highlighted.
Yeah.
You need to be aware.
Well,
it's also what we're doing
is by doing a podcast,
by talking about stuff and by examining
these ideas as open a mind so we can,
you're,
you're exchanging information and that
information gets people to think about
these things and changes the perceptions
and the future of what these things
are.
You know,
like we didn't know that there was a
radio guy that likes beating the fuck out
of checks.
We didn't know until
that information got out.
That guy was a big time radio guy
in Canada for a long time until the
information got out that he was beating
people up or be on women up showing that
in that case he could,
you know,
the argument is that that
information getting us,
uh,
getting,
getting out and then us talking about it
is going to get to people who may have
sure being like him.
Right.
And maybe they would deter
them from doing the same thing,
I dunno.
Right.
And there's,
there's,
there's a certain amount
of positivity and justice.
Yes.
You know,
when someone's doing what
bill Cosby allegedly did,
drugging women,
what do you think will
happen with Bill Cosby?
That's a good question.
With this,
this guy,
this John,
whatever the fuck his name is,
Kashi going,
getting arrested,
going to jail.
Yeah.
I find it hard to believe that someone's
not gonna file charges against bill
Cosby.
Yup.
And it's just gathering steam.
Right?
Well,
it's just a matter of how
much evidence they have.
How much ice or the
issue right now is the,
there is a restriction.
What is it?
The Statute of limitation?
Yeah.
Oh,
the age that the crime was
more than 25 years ago,
right?
Am I right about that?
25 I don't know what the number is.
That's tricky.
When you're dealing with
a guy that's that old too,
like he probably doesn't fuck anymore.
You see?
Right.
I mean it has to take the agro,
rape,
whatever.
He'd go way out of his way to rape me.
You mean he's got the,
he's got the ingredient.
He's got the ingrained,
he's taking the right vitamins probably.
Did you see the Associated Press thing?
Yes.
That little clip there was that evil.
Ooh,
scary.
The way he responded to it,
it was like,
we don't discuss these things and
I was relying on your integrity.
Is that evil?
Pure evil.
There's a lot going on there,
man.
First of all,
it's this elite royalty attitude.
he gave them the royal.
We do not respond like that's amazing,
right?
I'm talking to you,
man.
That's it.
That's a sociopath.
We means we means that he
views himself as a character,
right?
Isn't that what that means?
What does it mean?
We means there's more than one of him.
Yeah.
What does that mean?
We the organization known as Bill
Cosby artist known as bill Cosby.
Yes.
Representative of the artist,
the real version and the persona.
He's in weeding.
There's two versions.
I have a team behind me.
We do not yet respond and
he kept saying integrity.
In this weird world,
I'll rely on your integrity and I
relied on your integrity to not really,
data always kills me.
What I always think about whenever I
see any shit like that is how would I
respond had I not done it right.
Exactly.
And I always think I'd say,
listen,
get the fuck off my case.
Half speed didn't do it these days.
I feel like I'd be on
that stand or whatever.
Yes.
And I would not stop saying
that this was not me.
Exactly,
but yet you never see that.
Exactly.
Why the fuck do you never
see that they're guilty?
Probably.
I mean if you have to speculate,
honestly,
I'm just guessing.
But if I had to guess when,
look,
if someone came to you and said,
Louis,
I know that what you were doing is you
were a duck taping duties and fucking
their mouth.
What?
After you drug them,
you'd be like,
no,
I wife,
I didn't rape anybody in the mouth.
You can't just can't.
You can't fake that Reno.
No,
no.
The minute it starts to be labored
and it starts to be contrived,
you have to immediately say
what's the need for the show.
Exactly.
And there's also,
there's such a large number
of people that he harmed.
It's not like,
which one Cosby really?
Yeah,
there's like 17 women now.
17 oh yeah.
Oh Wow.
I not caught up on him.
17 yeah.
Yeah.
There's a lot.
Wow.
There's a lot of,
and more apparently are coming forth.
We'll do,
you know what they're saying is
he was doing this for decades.
Yeah.
He had a system.
I have three fucking donors to,
and even if I didn't have a mom,
you know,
you've had no daughters.
I love a lot of women.
You know,
I love a lot of humans
that happened in a female.
The idea that someone can do that and
that one of the people that I care about
and love could somehow or another,
how would you react?
I don't want to say,
you know,
it would be finding out where he was,
if I knew where he was physically,
if I knew where he was physically.
And he did that to one of my daughters.
Yes.
I probably be doing some jail time.
He would be in some sort of a
full body cast at a young age.
I saw the movie a time to kill.
I don't know if you've seen it.
Which,
who's in the Matthew mcconaughey?
It's before he started doing romcoms.
Yeah.
And sold his soul to the devil.
He was in the aids movie.
Um,
yeah.
He's,
he know now.
He's a bad ass.
He was mad Mike or Magic Mike.
Oh,
you're going back to
take a Channing Tatum.
No,
wasn't he in it to Macada
he was in there toe.
Maybe magic white.
I don't expose myself
to that kind of thing.
But then he,
but he recently did.
True detective,
which did you watch?
True detectives.
Right.
Wow,
that's fucking great.
That's the next level.
But anyway,
I saw a time to kill it.
A young enough age that you had
a drastic impact on my life,
which the premise of that movie,
Samuel Jackson,
do you remember this?
Yeah.
You remember the premise?
Barely.
Oh,
okay.
So early on,
um,
uh,
early nineties,
or black girl gets raped
by a bunch of hillbillies.
Did they kill her?
Yes.
Or they might,
they killed her.
They damaged irreparably.
She would never have kids
were raped her that badly.
And as you might've been
eight or nine in the movie,
I can't remember.
And,
uh,
and the,
the father,
uh,
murders,
murders of the dudes who
did it and he kills him.
Right.
And,
uh,
mcconaughey's character.
The lawyer is arguing that that was just,
Yup.
Yeah.
Well,
remember that guy that,
um,
there was a martial arts instructor
that molested his kid and the guy got
arrested and they were taking the guy,
the cops were taking the guy,
um,
through an airport or something like that,
and the guy jumped out.
You shot him in the head?
Yes.
And got off.
Got Off.
Yes.
I do recall that there's,
you know what man?
I mean there's certain shit that can't do
what any part of you though,
worry.
This is a very difficult question.
Would any part of you worry that the
story you were getting from your daughter
would be untrue if 17 other
people said the same story?
Time to die.
It's time to break Cosby's arms.
Both of them.
Wow.
And he places,
well,
there's 17 people.
I think if I,
if that was my daughter,
I would be so consumed with anger.
I don't know if I'd be
able to contain myself,
I would have to actively keep from being
anywhere near him because if I fucked
up,
and I mean there's something about
victimizing people that's horrific.
I know something about victimizing a
woman that's particularly horrific and,
and victimize a woman by drugging her
and then doing what you want to do with
her body,
like taking away their humanity.
They become like,
they become something that you use
like a fucking human fleshlight.
If they're out cold,
you draw them and then you,
you fucked them.
And like who?
I mean,
the real question is right.
Like the only thing worse you could do
is beat them up or worse you could do is
like physically hurt them.
Irreparably does the only thing worse,
like when you take away someone's
ability to decide what they do with their
body,
take away like a part of
what makes him a human being.
It's nuts.
Drugging them Cosby.
If that's real.
I mean,
obviously we're saying,
yea,
I agree,
but,
but you said yourself,
it's when it gets to 17,
he's not up for discussion.
Yeah.
And we,
you know what,
you're not talking about a
guy who cheated on his taxes.
You're not talking about a guy who,
uh,
I mean,
even awful things like drunk driving,
he said,
you know,
like a repeat drunk driver.
Yeah.
Fuck man.
You know,
it's horrible.
But there's something
particularly horrible about
a big powerful man who drugs
women.
It's terrifying.
And it's also confusing to
people because they're like,
God,
he's so famous.
He didn't even have what's,
what's the deal here?
What's he,
you know,
why does he wouldn't,
he could have done it the right
way and had incredible success.
Right.
Use the man.
Well it's also,
I think it fits that narrative that
like what is rape would it really is,
is not sex power.
Yeah.
Power.
And that's,
that also goes along
with that whole we shit,
you know?
Yup.
I mean the we shit is,
we do not respond to in you window I
would assume that you had to integrity and
I was relying upon your integrity.
Like what?
Integrity.
It's creepy man.
And the guy who's interviewing them is
like really intimidated and there's like
this weird moment.
Yep.
Why is that?
Because he's not famous and you know,
it's bill Cosby and your
round them and you're not,
maybe maybe it doesn't have a lot
of experience and to lose your job,
maybe.
No,
probably what,
what the concept of what the fallout
would be for asking that question.
Well,
what would you do in that situation if
you were the guy who was interviewing
him?
What'd you push it?
Which my me or like who are you?
You're you right now and you have some,
for some reason they give you a camera
and they let you interview bill Cosby.
Holy Fuck.
And he wants to talk about as NBC Sitcoms,
anytime somebody you get the feeling
that somebody is deceiving you,
uh,
you,
I mean me personally,
I can't help but not give into that.
I can't help it not give into it.
You mean to the deception?
Yeah.
Like I watch,
like I talked earlier about
watching help not give into it,
giving given to it in the
sense that challenge it.
Okay.
Yeah.
Uh,
I've talked earlier,
but watching the first 48,
like my favorite part
is the interrogation.
It's like,
it's creepy.
It's the,
the,
the glimpse into the,
into the mind for a moment
of how the mind prepares to,
to defend itself from anything.
The mind prepares due to self
preservation to say shit and do shit.
That makes no sense.
That mean they're tripping over the
excuses in an attempt to save their own
asses,
saying things that they
don't even believe.
Well,
that's why it's got to be particularly
frustrating if you're innocent.
And a cop is like,
look,
I know you killed her.
You killed your wife.
Right?
What the fuck man,
that's right.
Imagine being in that situation.
The same thing happens like we said
earlier about what would your response be.
It happens in those rooms,
in those interrogation rooms where you
get an immediate vibe as a viewer and I'm
sure that the cops being experienced
are the exact same way that a true date,
a true creepy fucking skilled murderer
is obviously the worst because of how how
great of an actor they are,
how great,
how great of a job they can do at exposing
all the flaws in how you interpret
them,
how they can preemptively figure out
what your questions are going to be in
already have the answers and someone
who is really planned out deception.
That's right.
Deep,
deep and advance and is used to doing
on a regular basis that there is no
antidote for that.
The only antidote for that
is them eventually wanting
to get caught so that they
could say a smee.
It's always been me.
So then they can be on the front fucking
page as the only point at which it
comes out because,
but then you also realize watching
that show that those guys,
those guys are the shit
that dreams are made of.
Like there's one every fuck,
I dunno how long,
true,
pure evil.
But the vast majority of them
are not skilled in that arena.
The vast majority of them are like,
fuck,
I don't know how this happened.
You know,
they,
and,
and they'll try the defense,
their defense in that state.
But it's stumbly and it's,
and it's so obvious that
they're just attempting to,
you know,
to spin,
spin
a web and then so the cops can figure
out which path they need to take,
uh,
to,
but it's very,
very weird watching it because I,
at times,
I feel like a sociopath watching it.
Brett Dunkin calls it murder porn.
I completely agree.
I completely agree with him
because I watched it and I go,
uh,
you know,
I know all the right answers.
I'm skilled enough now.
That's weird,
right?
You can educate yourself
watching first 48 that's right.
Do you think?
Here's a real question.
Yeah.
Do you think that as we get access to
more information about each other and
access to each other's thoughts,
like literally the,
the,
the calm,
the point in time where 10 years from now
and we can record our memories and our
thoughts on some sort of a hard
drive and have it be exchange,
whether it's 10 or 50 or a hundred,
whatever it is,
will we get to a point
where we eliminate evil?
Is that possible?
Is it possible to get to a point
where we eliminate things like murder,
rape,
crimes against people?
Why would an openness a
effect that consequences
either is 100% consequences to
your action?
The only time you come
still completely in,
in incomplete surveillance.
Yeah.
There's no opportunity to do
it without getting caught.
Yeah.
Uh,
what do you think about pedophiles
out a vinyl scare the shit out of me,
obviously because I have kids,
but buckets because I'm,
because I watched that,
uh,
Louis thorough thing he did on pedophiles.
They don't have a choice.
Some of them,
some of them don't know.
I think,
uh,
do you know a disproportionate
amount of lefthanded
Jesus,
disproportionate amount of
pedophiles are lefthanded.
There's a,
there was an article in New York Times
that was arguing for pedophilia being a
mental disorder that can be isolated and,
and,
and viewed that you can,
you can actually figure
out what went wrong,
what genes went wrong with what,
you know,
what genes,
the final scene in that movie,
uh,
maybe not the final,
but near the end in his documentary.
So he called a movie is the guy that
he's been going around with the uh,
he basically his guide,
the guy who's running the facility
for the dudes who are responsible for
pedophilia and whatever
other sexual offenses.
And he finally gets around to asking
him the question because he has a little
bit of an idea of the history
of how he ended up in all this.
And his reason for molesting
or raping his two boys
was that his wife wasn't putting out Whoa,
fuck Christ.
His wife wasn't putting out and the,
that he was going to
get back at her.
Oh God.
Was to take it out on their two kids.
Oh,
I've heard of people doing that in
terms of killing their kids to Yup.
To get back at their wife.
They've killed their kids.
Yup.
Yeah.
There's some fucked up humans,
man.
You know,
but
particular case,
the creepiest part about all of it was
that the guy seemed way too normal.
He seemed throughout the entire,
uh,
documentary.
He was like the most
relatable one of all of them.
You know,
he was,
he essentially was,
was driving,
driving him around.
He was the one explaining,
he's almost the narrator
of the entire thing,
with the exception of Louie himself.
And uh,
it's almost like the dude,
uh,
you know,
you have your traditional
mindset of like what,
what a pedophile is.
Like.
Maybe they were molested themselves or
they can't help it or whatever.
But in this guy's case,
it just seemed like a fucking psycho.
Well,
I think when we think about what,
what entails,
like what,
what ingredients are involved
and creating a human being,
there's so many variables,
so many situations that come up.
So much information that gets passed
from birth to whatever crime is committed
from birth to shooting up a school.
There is so much going on,
there's so much data and it's so
difficult to discern like what is it that
causes someone to become a murderer
and what is it that becomes,
that causes someone to choose a life of
crime or to become a rapist or to do,
to do anything that harms what,
what,
where does it go and how can that
be prevented and just becoming you.
Okay.
Becoming a nice guy,
becoming who you are.
Like think about all the fucking variables
that are involved and becoming you
and what could have gone wrong.
All sorts of things along the way.
What drugs could you
have been introduced to?
How many times could you have
been dropped in your head?
What things could've gone wrong that have,
but how do this,
hey,
can you completely off?
How did this Guy Soak in just and
state and how did he fake it so long?
Is he facing
or is he broken?
Does he,
is he lacking empathy?
Is he missing some sort of a social,
he was broken the whole time.
He had people fooled for years.
He had enough time to
be normal enough to not,
uh,
exercise those thoughts he was having,
I guess if we want to make the
argument that he was always like that,
but in his particular case,
the thing that affected me
more than any of that was that,
oh fuck.
I feel like this guy just snapped.
I feel like this guy wasn't broken.
Not Possible though.
Think about you.
What,
what could your wife possibly do to
get you to fuck your kids police?
You know what I'm saying?
It's not possible.
I something wrong along the way.
Maybe it's some sort of a inability
to recognize his own actions and non
introspective quality to his life.
A block that he put up early on in life.
Yes.
There's,
you're,
you're completely correct in the sense
that there's probably more to it,
but I think the scariest
thing to the regular person is
he's too regular.
Yeah.
That's theory.
I don't even know the guy.
And you're describing them to me.
I didn't watch the whole document.
I went on a Louie thorough,
um,
marathon,
which is on my just very easy to
do because he's fucking awesome.
He's really awesome.
He's a really interesting
guy to talk to you too.
So I watched the Fred Phelps won and
I watched the African hunting one.
I watched the whole series of them,
so I didn't watch the whole one.
So I don't know that dude.
I can't,
I don't know if I would
even recommend to watch it,
but just because of that.
It's really,
it's,
it's intense man.
Yeah.
I mean,
what goes into creating a you,
what I mean when I say you,
I mean everybody who's listening think
about all the things I think all the time
about what made me me,
you know,
the,
the idea of determinism,
the idea of the,
all the variables,
your genetics,
your environment,
your,
the input,
your life experiences,
your successes,
your failures,
your locks,
you're zigging when you should've zagged.
You're hitting the brakes and a
meteor lands in front of your car.
I mean,
there's so many fucking things
that happen in your life.
And one thing that goes awful
early can send you down a bad road,
which could send you to another awful
thing which could send you down a bad
road.
It's like a,
it's like you know,
many dimensions playing
out in front of you,
like the,
the potential,
the potential outcome of every single
event and the effect of that an impact.
And it makes you really
question everything.
Our existence as a whole,
that the possibilities of that,
you know,
what also makes you wonder,
is it possible to ever completely
socially engineered the human race?
Is it possible that we could get our shit
together 100% and have no evil and no
crime and no rape,
no murder and all done.
We're done.
We're good.
We're all utopia now we're,
I'll just come by ya and hugging each
other and smiling to our neighbors because
the whole world's our neighborhood now.
I think we are so addicted to conflict
that will find a way to fuck it up.
But are we,
are we always going to be,
this is the question.
Are we the same thing today?
That will be will be a million years from
now or are we just like those monkeys
that came down out of the trees instead
of experimenting with new food sources
and started eating meat and we'll
find other people to do it for us.
We'll find other things to do it for
us a million years from now do isn't
impossible that we can evolve past this.
Like we have evolved,
at least in this room.
Yeah.
We have gotten to a point
where I'm not worried about I,
we could all go to sleep
together in this room.
I'm not worried about it either.
If you guys hit me in
the head with a rock,
you know what I mean?
But if we were living in the Congo,
that
could be an issue.
If we were living in the
Congo a million years ago,
that could be an issue.
I suppose for me,
what I fear more than the
people around me is the,
and their decisions is the
proliferation of negativity in general.
Ryan,
why the fuck does this terrible
shit spread like wildfire?
Why is the news the news?
We all,
we all still want it.
We just don't want to
participate in a physical way,
but don't you think like this,
this riot things going on,
this closing of highways
all across the country.
The good in that of course is that
there are so many people that regardless
whether or not the
narrative fix the facts,
what they want to do is they want to
stand up for inequality and even if it's
not actually inequality
they want to stand up for,
and it most certainly is in some way
because this guy who no matter what,
whether what Arbill
things he actually did do,
he didn't grow up in your neighborhood.
He didn't grow up in my neighborhood.
I got a fucking pretty sweet life.
I had skated through the difficulties
that I had only made me a better person.
Here I am in 2014 with no fucking
criminal record and it never hurt anybody.
Everything's fine.
Cool.
You know what I mean?
This guy for you,
thank you very much.
This guy didn't,
he didn't,
his scenario was vastly
different than yours in mind.
So whatever played out that allowed
him to get in front of that cop,
I think what people are standing up
for is not just police brutality.
They're standing up for this recognition
that there is inequality in the world
to be addressed.
Of course,
that's one of the poorest
areas in the country.
Yeah,
it's fucked.
Yeah.
I was looking at like crime statistics
the other day and like adjusted for
population that is a fucking war zone
way there without this police shooting.
You know what I mean?
It's ultra poor and I know that the reason
people are attaching themselves to it
is inequality and it's unfortunate I
guess that it takes this particular set of
circumstances to have that conversation.
But uh,
ultimately you can't really have a healthy
society when there's the nat level,
that disproportion between
people who have stuff in people.
But you also can't have a society
that's 300 fucking 50 million people in
general.
I mean,
how,
how are you going to
organize 350 million people?
It's,
it's amazing that it works at all.
To be honest.
A poor community.
Anywhere where the crime is low.
It's a great question.
I think,
I don't know how much of it is about being
poor in general and how much of it is
subjective.
Like if being poor in America means being
poor relative to the richest people on
the planet,
right.
That's a different ball game and
being poor in India I have no,
maybe not because now there's
rich people there too,
but being poor in an environment
where everyone's poor,
you really pour,
do you know what the 1% of the world is?
You know what the number is that
you have to make to be in the,
in the global one,
top 1%.
It's way lower than people think,
right?
Yeah.
What would you think it would be?
I feel like I'm cheating because
you may have mentioned it before.
Okay,
go ahead.
Was it something like
40,000 or 35 34 35 yeah.
Anything more than $34,000 and you are
in the top 1% of the world privilege.
Enormous,
enormous privilege in this country.
You know,
enormous privilege.
That's an,
that seems like,
like,
Whoa,
like that.
Strengthen the borders,
increase the military.
It's impossible to overcome that number.
Like I hear where they were dealing with,
I thought we're going to fix the world,
but,
uh,
listen,
I'm 47,
I'll see a whole lot of time to do this.
So let's just fucking live in a
gated community and get a gun that's,
you know,
that's you d,
How do you psychologically deal with that?
Um,
the idea of privilege.
What can you do?
I mean,
it's real.
It's real as it gets.
It's,
there's no doubt about it.
There's some or feeling guilty about it.
Can't feel guilty about where you are.
I mean,
I would feel guilty if I
victimize somebody can't
feel guilty about being born
lucky.
Wow.
If you can,
I mean,
can you feel guilty
about being born lucky?
I don't.
I feel bad for people
who aren't born like,
right.
I see what you're saying.
It's a little different.
But look,
Bill Cosby,
if he did it should feel guilty.
Yes.
What I'm saying.
You shouldn't feel guilty that you are,
you know,
not a woman that's being raped.
Shit.
Do you know what I'm saying?
Yeah.
I don't,
I'm,
guilt might not be the right word,
but uh,
there are days where I feel lucky.
Right.
You know,
if you're lucky every day.
Yeah.
So what's the,
what's the,
what's the other end of that?
You know,
I,
maybe guilt is not the right word,
but there are people who wake up
everyday and feel shitty Bryant.
And so I guess I don't feel guilty,
but I don't feel great that knowing that
the vast majority of the planet isn't,
but then again,
what the fuck is happiness really?
Well,
then the other thing is how
much money is it relative?
Like how much money does the vast
majority of the planet need to live their
lifestyle?
When you're talking about poverty,
are they well fed and happy?
Because,
yeah,
I know it's one of the
things about Mexico,
like they were happy.
It was like one of the happiest
countries on the planet apparent wow.
It with all the drug lords and
all the consequences of that.
That's what most people don't get happy.
Those people are really unhappy.
The people that have to
deal with the drug lords,
it's always,
it seems to always be a
question of contrast really.
It's like,
uh,
I always come up,
I come out here to La and,
and,
and I'm amazed at how every
single day is exactly the same.
Like from a weather perspective.
Oh yeah.
Like I left the apocalypse back
home to come here and it's like,
it could be July,
in November and this new July.
Yeah.
There's no time.
The only thing I will say is it
gets dark incredibly quickly.
Especially being by the beach.
It's like in 20 minutes because we're
trying to shoot videos and stuff.
Like,
Whoa,
where did the Sun Go?
But um,
that's because of the stupid
daylight savings nonsense,
whatever it is.
But by,
by regardless,
it's like,
it's always a question of contrast.
It's like the good is
better relative to the bad.
Right,
right.
It's a,
you,
you need the bad to have the good,
you need to,
sad to have to happy.
That's the idea of being a human being.
Yeah.
The question is,
will we ever evolve and grow to the
point where that is not necessary.
And would the universal blind
in that aided by technology,
would that be the facilitator
of that new mindset?
So in that scenario,
is there a motion?
That's a good question.
There can't be,
that might not be,
it might not be sex.
I've always said that about
robots or about a rather aliens.
When you look at aliens or do they have,
they have no muscle.
They have no sex organs.
Big heads,
no rounds.
Like maybe it mean maybe they've found
a replacement that's better than sex.
Yeah.
The real alien is just the
brain hooked up to something.
Right.
It's not even,
there's no physicality at all.
Right.
Well maybe that's what it is.
Maybe it's just some sort of artificial
intelligence that it gets downloaded
into a body and the only thing that's
necessary is it the body has fingers that
can articulate and move in a certain way.
Yeah.
Matrix type shit.
I saw an article making the rounds on
my Twitter about how people are getting,
um,
neck problems from their smartphones.
Oh yeah.
Looking down,
looking down and the uh,
how posture and the weight of the head,
the amount that the cervical spine has
to hold up beyond what it was designed to
do and the like drastic number
of consequences because of that.
Oh yeah.
Uh,
and it really makes you wonder like the
sedentary lifestyle that everybody works
on a computer.
Like who the fuck what profession
doesn't require a computer?
Smart phone number,
Jack.
All right,
so lumberjack,
you're safe.
But the vast majority,
especially in the expanding sectors are
required to interface in a weird way
with a monitor and in
a posture that is not,
is not a,
our bodies weren't designed for.
So that's why we started
using these chairs.
Ash,
road depot,
cherish.
I still feel like didn't fix me at all
because I've been doing this the last
time that is better than the slump.
Like you're leaning forward
and supporting yourself.
Like your elbows on the table is bad in
other thing they do is they have these
chair or these tables rather that you
stand and they stand with standing desks.
I have,
I have one.
A motorized one.
Yeah.
We just got one,
Ergo depot.com they send us these chairs,
right?
They sent us the desk.
They might be the same
guys who sent me the desk.
I'm not 100% sure.
Is it a Jarvis Jarvis task?
No,
I don't think mine is called a vert desk.
Do these chairs and the shit.
I was using this other
one that's Sally chair,
but it hurt my balls and really?
Yeah it was,
it's like it's split down the middle.
I think my ball was still hurt from that.
It's not good,
but this one's much better.
But even with all the equipment and
stuff for us to like adjust our into
working,
still not natural and,
and it seems to be continuing
to progress in that direction.
So you have to wonder.
It could,
it,
could there be a physical,
uh,
what's the opposite of evolution?
Devolving devolving could be physical
devolvement and then if you extrapolate
that and push it way out,
then it all all of a sudden becomes the,
the,
the body is a,
is a problem.
Like the body is just in the way,
or this could be an
immediate intermediate step.
Yeah.
In some new technology that doesn't
require you to be at a desk or look at a
phone.
Oh,
I have some sort of,
so we can protect the physique
or whether you're your frame now,
just your,
your own,
your body itself.
Yeah.
Sitting is the new smoking,
is that what they say?
You haven't heard that?
No.
Yeah,
that's what they say.
I can hear.
I can imagine them saying that.
Did we're out of time.
Oh really?
We did three hours.
Just rock goodbye every time.
Every time.
Dude.
Like that.
Awesome.
Unbox therapy on Twitter,
unbox therapy on youtube.
Louis,
you're the shit.
Thank you my friend.
Always good to talk to you and sit down.
Get a new perspective.
Unbox therapy.
You fucks.
Go follow him.
Enjoy your life and a don't rape anybody.
See you soon.
Bye.
Later.
Negative.