Well,
you know,
alcoholics anonymous was created by a
guy who was in the LSD.
Yeah.
Bill W
baller.
Jamie,
I'm going to show you through your
sweater and saw bad sweater sweatshirt
you're wearing.
It's very cool.
But this is a,
this is a symptom of everything is
wrong.
Miss,
go ahead.
Are we all in yet?
Yeah,
we're on,
it's got fake short sleeves.
It's got fake short sleeves,
over long sleeves.
So the,
the short sleeves or sewed in?
Not so it's not attached.
How has it worked then?
This,
the short sleeves,
it comes apart.
This sleep part not attached at all.
It's separate.
So it's two pieces.
Yeah.
I didn't know that when I bought it
either.
But when you pull the sleeve up,
what happens?
Nothing can come off.
Oh it goes all the way over the top.
Oh,
I see.
Like a separate hood.
So do you where the two of them together
are?
They I just saw it on,
I just bought it.
There's a whole rocky thing that this
company did it a whole bunch of pieces
and I was like,
oh that's Kinda cool.
So I'm Sylvester Stallone is slated to
come on the podcast.
You will wear that correct.
And He's here please.
Okay.
All right.
So is that,
but that the upper shirt is just laid
over the tops,
shorts,
long sleeve shirt.
So you could wear one without the other.
Like you could wear the short sleeve
one.
Oh,
okay.
It's just two sweatshirts,
you know.
But it's the training montage.
Oh,
it comes,
it comes as a,
as a team.
Is it heavy or is it light?
It is not light at all.
I'm starting to sweat right now and let
me shut this door.
But that'll make you stronger if you got
a heavy shirt.
I think that's the idea.
So,
uh,
we are here and if uh,
some shit goes down,
I may have to bolt from the podcast
because a,
there's mandatory evacuations all around
here.
Really?
Yeah.
What does it mean to live all in Ventura
County?
There's all these mandatory of bees.
Honey bees.
Is it really?
Yeah,
they're making too much.
Honey,
what is it?
Let's have mudslides.
Oh Wow.
I didn't know that.
I had to pull off loss at one time.
They a bunch of bs on there.
What really huge hives,
man.
Wow.
You see,
you know a lot of homeless people and
they don't do anything,
but when be show up they fucking get to
do and shit.
You know?
That's one thing I noticed quickly.
Yeah.
Isn't it an interesting,
how'd they get motivated by bees?
Bees will motivate anybody,
you know,
you're not all cracked out once the
bee's show up,
dude,
I watched bees communicate with each
other once I was on the set of fear
factor and we covered these people with
bs and then a neighboring colony,
a colony that actually lived there.
Local colony came and were like,
what are you guys doing here?
And the bees all flew up in the sky
together and sorted it out in the sky.
Really?
It was wild.
We had,
the guy told us like the beekeeper,
he's like,
everybody's got to stand down.
We've got to back up,
get out of the area.
And was like,
what?
So yeah,
they have to communicate.
I thought he was joking.
Let them do it,
Huh?
Yeah.
It's like they have to talk it out.
I'm like,
whoa.
They talk.
Wow,
what are they going to say?
There's something
going on with them that we,
you know,
we just kind of subtly,
we sort of get what they do.
Yeah.
They're kinda like little,
little kind of liaisons it seems like.
Like I wonder from the future we'll know
that like certain animals can like,
you know,
take messages around for us and like if
you told an animal something that could
go tell,
you know,
like a wonderful start using animals
more because animals are,
we don't use them that much.
I mean there sitting around most of the
time.
Right.
I've read something about,
they were trying to encode information
in DNA.
We could ask Mike Tyson about his
pigeons.
Yeah.
I think that's different though.
Carrier Pigeons,
pigeons.
Just to carry for a long distances.
How about game of thrones?
Duesberg for,
yeah,
for sure.
But whatever,
for whatever reason it makes more sense
with birds.
Yeah.
Right.
Like a bird seems like you should be
able to train it a little bit.
Oh,
Berg,
you could train some birds.
I think some birds I think would do
their own thing.
Then I'll ask you this.
If you had an important message,
would you just send one raven?
That's what I hadn't never got you.
How about you send a flock of these
mother fuckers?
What are you crazy live that God damn
thing gets eaten?
What if an Eagle Jackson one along the
way,
the fate of your kingdom is at hand,
sir.
Yeah.
You can't put that on the back of one
bird did.
I would send a bird.
Nobody would expect,
you know,
like a little warbler or something or in
nightingale.
Oh,
that's a good move.
Yeah.
You gotta send a bird that nobody wants
to shoot though.
Shoot.
Birds will al too,
dude.
We had al two Thanksgiving's ago.
We had two hours at my sister's house.
Yeah,
I saw one last night actually.
Did you?
Yeah.
It was pretty,
no,
not last night before last.
It was pretty fucking cool.
I pulled into the driveway and an owl
took off.
It was big too.
It's gross.
I think owls,
the meet the uh oh you ate them,
you saying?
Yeah.
But you guys eight hours.
Yeah,
that's legal.
He's probably shouldn't say that on the
podcast.
Well,
I didn't have a lot.
I used to have a joke about it and I
didn't have a lot.
Man.
I have no job.
They got even spit it out and I'm not
even joking.
Yeah.
Clinton,
when you smoked that weed and they had
to,
they didn't have all the things.
They don't have a lot of meat on him.
I fucking know.
Like owls.
They're predators.
They're important.
That's why you don't have rats
everywhere.
Yeah.
But I'd rather,
you know,
they're,
I think they're violent and they're
dirty and they get this.
Alice,
whoever did their pr,
you notice everybody thinks they're
smart and they can read and they're
like,
yeah,
they had a good pr.
Yeah.
Right.
Look at that.
We only got one up,
Jim,
but see how much little meat is on him.
You think there's more?
Look at,
he's kidding.
He's kidding folks.
He's not eating owls.
The one in the middle,
it looks like it's from another planet,
you know?
Yeah.
And that's what,
that's what it really looks like.
That's what it looks like.
Fluff.
That's a little bit a little alien
raptor creature.
I was like a crab.
It looks like a crab.
I was driving home on one,
was flying above me on the road and
dropped a rabbit.
He had got a rabbit and jacked it.
It's flying with the rabbit and as he
was flying,
just decided
like maybe decided the car was too close
to him or it was too loud or something
like that.
I just dropped that rabbits at fuck it
and I stopped the car and to check it
out.
I was like,
whoa.
That's flirt and really it sounds like
flirting.
LFL drops a rabbit at your feet.
A bitch.
It's ready to fuck.
Probably.
Yeah,
like an offering.
Look,
that guy for you more.
With that came maybe
predators.
Men.
They,
we never thought of him growing up as
predators.
Yeah,
that's all they told us.
They were wise.
They had that,
that Monica like fucking like Budd
Friedman.
You'd need the Improv.
I remember that.
I'll like that.
Planter's peanut,
but Friedman from evening at the Improv.
His whole deal was yet I loved evening.
At the Improv when I was a kid.
Oh Man.
That was like one of the reasons why I
got into standup comedy.
I still watch these TV shows.
They had syndicated TV shows that they
would do,
you know,
vh one had one mtv at the half hour
comedy hour.
And what time did it come on it?
I don't remember man.
I don't remember.
That was bud,
but it was probably the last night.
He looks like that planters nut.
But Daniel,
one of the owners,
uh,
he sold it eventually and Chitchatting,
cashed out about from Brian Friedman in
the left corner.
That's a different dude.
Yeah.
Interesting.
A lot of freedoms out there.
Um,
but anyway,
Bud ran,
uh,
he was the host of evening at the Improv
and he would come out with that monocle.
Go back to that Monica picture again,
lower left.
Bam.
That was him.
See Google Budd Friedman evening at the
Improv.
That's widget.
Okay.
Yeah.
Nice guy.
Real,
real nice guy.
And Yeah,
he was real nice guy.
Always,
always a sweetheart to me.
Always very,
very friendly.
He was a very gregarious guy and he um,
uh,
basically he was one of the original
owners of the evening of the Improv and
evening at the Improv.
I don't know.
I don't know the full history of the
Improv.
I probably should,
but I think I want to say it started out
in New York.
Yeah.
Cause I know there were wars,
there were ones everywhere at one point
in time.
They had one in Boston for a little bit
and Improv.
Yeah.
They had one in Boston and then they
changed it to a different name.
I started hell's kitchen and 1963.
Yeah.
So that was probably one of the original
standup comedy clubs.
Probably one of the top two or three.
Do you have a favorite like a club when
you were like doing clubs more?
Do you have like a favorite one?
I was just happy to get on stage back
then,
you know.
I mean I had favorite ones like nick's
comedy stop was always a favorite in
Boston.
Right.
Stitches but stitches moved a couple of
times.
Stitches moved twice.
What about any of the funny bones or did
you go to any of those places?
Yeah,
well,
but the,
for the Boston club,
the comedy connection was the big one
and now that's the Wilbur theater.
It's really weird because it used to be
the smallest club in town.
Everybody wanted to work at,
it was like a hundred Ooh,
I want to say they get stuff,
maybe 150 people in there,
but I mean he'd stuffed,
I mean this room,
this,
this ceiling was low,
you know,
I mean I'm five,
eight and I remember I could,
I'm pretty sure I could touch the
ceiling.
So this shit is low.
So if you were like,
Oh and Smith or you know,
so and tall it along on,
yeah,
that's a big ass stage for you.
Like big people would look real weird on
that stage,
but the laughs would be so contained.
It was so low.
Ceiling and tight.
I love that.
Great.
I saw Hicks there for the first time.
First Time I ever saw him was there.
I was like,
whoa.
He was doing this bit about Jimi Hendrix
meeting a tiffany at the mall.
Tiffany the arm sanger here.
Cause she was real popular then.
Yeah.
Oh that song I'm making you just be a
wreck.
I remember being on the school bus so
fucking wrecked bro.
Dude,
I remember that Shit Bro.
Did I love being erect and I was young
man.
Now it's whatever.
I have to do something now.
What are you,
you know what does my Dick need me to
do?
Right?
It's like eat now.
So
I'll tell you this.
If you want to feed a family of four,
you can't just have one hour.
I will say that though.
Well if you look at what it looks like
without the feathers,
it looks like saying fucking demon.
You know it's a real bait and switch.
I feel like that's when the gods hidden
agenda.
So I was talking to someone about
peacocks about this and I started
talking about it on stage that like
peacocks are pretty,
but if you took their feathers off,
you'd want kill it with a hammer.
Like what is that thing?
Fuck is that.
He wouldn't let that thing anywhere near
your kids.
Look,
peacocks have their feathers on you.
Let your kids get right close to him.
Oh yeah,
but beautiful.
No feathers.
Dark skin like charcoal covered scary
and the little nubs all over it.
I'll look.
Hey,
fuck.
Look at that.
It looks like lane murderer.
It looks like a little twink out on the
town.
A little creepy murder.
A little bit.
Probably a little gray and pink
murderer.
Who is that what?
It looks like?
What?
Whoa.
Is that a real,
I'm like duck face.
I don't know.
Yeah,
that's a duck,
bro.
It says peacock.
That is something else that a minute
think they'll go back up to the peacock
picture.
They have a different head.
Go back to that peacock picture that you
just had.
Oh my God.
That's a totally different head.
Like the beak shape different.
That's the problem with the Internet.
Yeah,
you can't,
it's so hard to tell.
That's a duck son.
Who is is a duck.
Maybe it's on that page or something
like that.
Well,
it says right there,
it said feathers ripped from live birds.
Didn't ripping the feathers off.
Peak car hits a nice guy.
What was he like?
Did you meet him?
Meet him?
I met him like hi,
like hey,
so I was,
I wasn't open.
Miker oh yeah.
Oh,
he ain't going to talk to me.
Yeah.
It's like,
you know,
I say hi to everybody.
I run into like door guys.
I always try to say hi to everybody
because I remember what it was like when
I was an open miker and seeing these
guys where I couldn't even talk,
couldn't even imagine that we were the
same thing.
Couldn't talk to them.
You know what I mean?
Like the big Comedians,
you mean?
Fuck yeah,
like Bill Hicks would come into town.
I didn't want to say hi to him.
It'd be super annoying.
Right.
Cause then what do you back it up with?
That was always my thing.
I was so stupid back then too,
and I'm pretty dumb now,
but it was really dumb back then.
Yeah,
there was no way I had anything to say
to that dude.
And you think there was a time of your
life,
you are the dumbest that you'd ever
been?
Probably a couple of weeks ago.
Let me know.
I don't know Matt,
but I definitely have more data to work
with now,
but I've forgotten a lot of shit too.
But like you think there's generally a
time in people's lives when they,
what they should know kind of.
And the,
there's like a kind of like a middle
ground where maybe it doesn't.
Well for sure when I was in my early
twenties for sure when I was in my
twenties like deep into my,
you know,
it took me into my thirties to f kind of
fucking shit.
Shake my head loose and figure out what
the fuck I was doing.
Yeah.
Do your 20 bro,
when you think about twenties right?
No direction.
No idea whether or not this comedy thing
was going to work out.
I'm like,
what am I doing?
I'm telling jokes.
Jesus Christ and yeah,
and then telling people when you go back
home and they've never seen you,
they've never heard of you.
They think you're gay.
Like they're like,
you keep flying home,
you don't have any money and you're not
bringing a girl home.
You have.
Yeah.
You're hiding from Samsung,
you know,
just come out.
I remember my Stepdad is yelling at me
in the yard one time told you to come
out.
Yeah.
I was like,
I'm not fucking gay,
Bro.
Like I'm just not flying some girl home
that I just met,
you know?
Just approved to catch it.
Catch it.
A lie.
Yeah.
He thought maybe he was going to leave a
a yeah.
Like a going to set a trap.
Yeah.
It's going to set a trap.
Setting the trap.
Yeah.
He's like a slick boxer.
I said,
boy,
what the fuck?
That's one of the reasons why young boys
would always accuse each other being
gay,
because it's so hard to prove.
You're not,
yeah,
so hard.
But someone says you're gay.
Like you take that off me.
It's crazy.
The worst has gotta be if someone says
you gay and you are,
but you don't want to know.
Yeah,
that'd be sick.
Yeah.
You changed your clothes.
The next day he'd come dressed like an a
mafi outfit or something like something
to totally take them hot off the trail.
You know,
you just wish you could say you were,
you know,
you wish you could tell you were.
I think now you can.
I think it,
I think still can a lot of places.
It is.
I mean,
I would love to think that everybody's
like the people that are around us where
they literally don't give a fuck if
you're Justin Martindale or look,
our language is funny and after that
it's cool to be around.
Those are the things that are most
valuable in our world.
Funny and cool to be around.
Those two things.
Someone's funny and cool to be around.
We don't give a fuck if you're a guy,
a girl,
trans,
gay,
funny ghost.
Cool.
The bureau.
You can be heroes.
Yeah.
Do you think this goes to the comedy
store?
I,
I don't know.
I have some friends that are,
the other day I was trying to give them
the whole tour and tell them how it used
to be Ciro's nightclub bugs and them
downstairs to own it.
I didn't take them all the way,
but I showed them,
you know you go through the back room of
the main room.
Did that used to be like their hide out
and shit?
I told,
I told them about all the ghost stories
that had been filmed there,
but I don't believe it.
I don't think it's real.
Well I think I'm surprised we don't have
more ghosts to animals.
You know what I think,
I think it's you.
This is what I think for real.
I think when you,
I think you can probably tune in to
something that happened in a place.
That's what I think.
And I think if you trip yourself out,
you could see things that aren't really
there.
And I think that it is entirely
possible.
The ghosts aren't real,
but that you seeing a ghost is real.
But I think that you can get your body
into like such a frenzied,
terrified state.
And if you are open to the idea that the
ghost is a real thing,
your mind can fuck with you.
Like the ghetto boys,
your mind's playing tricks on you and
me.
Yeah,
that's what I think.
I think legitimately.
And I also think that if you hit the
right frequency,
I bet you get hold up like a,
just a ghost of a memory of someone
getting killed in a place or something
horrible happening.
Just a ghost of a memory.
Oh,
I think that's next.
That's one of the next things you're
gonna be able to do,
like a gang sign in the air,
a special gang sign and then a fucking,
the truth is going to pop out right in
front of you.
Like I think we're going to start to
learn like Harry Potter type shit or
like maybe a song.
What if the cer a certain like playing
of us lyrics or our notes in a row would
reveal like the past right in front of
you.
Like I wonder if there's some Ma,
you know,
magic little warp poles or something.
Well,
we'll think about what music does.
Do music literally changes the way your
body feels like a drug.
Like if you were a kid,
okay.
And you heard that rocky song
[inaudible] you could run faster,
you would get more fired up.
You'd be able to do more pushups,
Chin ups,
Stepdad.
Don't say it.
Do it yet,
but you will probably a lot of dudes
probably.
But the point is you would for sure get
energy from that.
Like a drug.
Yeah,
cause that was a cup of coffee.
You'd be like,
Woo,
this coffee coffee's good.
Right?
You hear that song
put up that video the other day.
Oh yeah,
that got video that I repost it.
Vibration sand.
Yeah.
If you look deep into this topic of
vibrations and symbols that come out and
like what we're talking about,
it's kind of difficult card.
Yeah.
I posted it on my instagram.
I re posted it because it's really
fascinating.
It seems like it's just a mat that's
charged yet being vibrated.
So let's explain what's happening for
the people that you just listen,
I'm going to play this video cause
they're probably get taken down.
It's got a lot of views.
There's lots of different versions of
this online.
It says amazing,
amazing,
amazing resonance experiment.
So they put some,
Sam,
is it Sam?
This is probably salt.
Okay.
They put some sort of powdered stuff,
sand or salt onto a black mat that's
charged and then they send certain hurts
through it.
This one's 3,835 hertz.
And then it makes a different patterns
on the,
look at this 3,975 like every time they
changed the hertz,
it has a different penalty that 4,049
look at this pattern.
So these hurts are waiting.
It's unbelievable.
Uh,
you can take these numbers and these can
also be,
um,
notes that you're seeing on a piano or
you used to hearing her singing.
So these can also be recreated and other
ways in are probably happening.
And to us that's how like maybe one of
those,
uh,
ear warmer here,
like Victoria,
you're in the back of your neck,
vibrators
like that.
What if a certain hertz just spelled
your like your grandparents name?
Well,
what's interesting is that each one of
them are different geometric patterns.
They're these beautiful patterns.
They're gorgeous.
And as you change the hurts,
the patterns morph immediately.
Yeah.
And,
but the thing is they're kind of
fractal,
like not fractal,
but they seem to be,
uh,
what's the word?
Equal on both sides that this is what
I'm looking for.
Parallel.
No,
no,
I think you are,
you're on the right topic.
If the numbers a little more a round,
like a round number of these are not
specific hurts.
Like if you do a specific yeah,
different than identical.
But anyway,
they're both sides are exactly the same
and it's separated in this one.
They're not,
it's not separated in a half.
It's,
it's,
it's all like the circle is a center and
it all goes out from there.
But they're different every time.
But they're all even like see it lifts,
the only thing that's keeping it from
being perfect is that they run out of
sand and it looks like the power is
centered around the center part where
the wires are connected to.
So that's the most potent.
But so that can beautiful.
So that may like if you think about that
like in a shake,
maybe if there's a certain hertz going
through the air like in space,
then it would form like a solar system
against one better.
The feeling that you get from like
rocky,
right.
The feeling that you get from that song,
not the duck,
that things going through your badass.
Yeah.
It literally could be like a little drug
look.
Think about why people like music so
much.
Cause that musician is your drug dealer.
Yeah.
Okay.
You hear like some old Elton John,
like you're in your car and Saturday
night comes on your fucking goosebumps.
If you haven't heard that song in a long
time and you don't expect it.
Oh fuck yeah.
JSC had friend that would make you want
to,
you know that's a good song too,
but that vibe is good.
This was done with my,
like I was saying with musical notes.
Wow.
On water.
We're looking at the thing,
it says the Saima
scope.
Is that how you say that c.
Y m a scope uses a high definition
camera to monitor the effects of an
individual.
Sounds particular vibrations on purified
water revealing for the first time.
What piano notes look like.
There are people out there so much
smarter than you and me.
Oh yeah.
Oh God.
It's,
it's amazing that we're considered the
same thing.
You know what?
Smart people,
really smart people.
They're going to have someone like Shawn
Carolyn,
the physicist and he has to break down
particle physics and shit to you.
You like,
is it hard?
It doesn't even get in,
does he?
I I can repeat what he said.
Yeah,
don't the fuck it means like when people
start talking about quantum quantum
things and quantum theory and quantum
particles as danger.
Dude,
I don't get,
I don't trust that kind of stuff.
A lot of it.
Well,
how about,
you know what superposition is,
is the ultimate what the fuck we're a
particle can be in a state of motion and
be still at the same time.
I like,
well good luck with that.
Good luck.
This magic world that you've created.
Crazy scientist that I don't understand.
Yeah.
I would rather do something more chill
than that.
What the fuck?
Something can stay now.
Sign up like or go for a run or
something being rather than study that
are rather than be that particle.
Oh,
rather than study that and be,
yeah,
I it like,
I just think,
but don't you want someone to know cause
don't,
you'd benefit from cell phones.
Well what about the,
the th th th such few people know that
if they all want it to lie to us,
then they could,
they would have to be conspiracy.
Now you starting to sound like some
other people.
I know.
Let's go get some tin foil.
But
while I didn't know that,
that,
so that's funny that,
that your body would do that.
The reason why they would never do that
is because scientists whole deal is
figuring out shit that other scientists
didn't figure out.
That's like the best thing they can do.
The best thing is scientists can do is a
real honest to goodness breakthrough.
Would you have sex with a scientist,
you think?
Yeah,
like a movie scientists.
Like she keeps the glasses on.
Yeah.
They're always blonde in the movies
right now.
Sometimes a dark black hair too.
Stereos.
I bet they're clean too.
If you fuck a scientist yet,
I bet they have a clean apartment maybe,
but maybe not.
Maybe their fucking brain is like that
chalkboard with all the squiggly alien
mathematics are high.
That's Cherry la getting tattooed.
It's a bunch of dirty math tattooed or
on their posts.
I was reading this there,
but I was reading this thing about
Richard Fineman.
You knew who fineman was fine was a
scientist.
He was a physicist and a,
there was an article about him,
like was fineman and abuser,
but,
um,
it was,
it was talking about Richard Fineman and
how,
you know,
he used to,
he just,
his wife said he's just do nothing but
calculations all day.
And then he wanted to play the bongos
and he didn't want anybody to bother
him.
But like,
he had a quote from one of his,
uh,
one of his books and it's crazy reading
it.
It's like,
uh,
I just,
but see if he could find it because it's
a really,
it's a crazy quote calling women
bitches.
And I'm like,
what?
Like that there were that,
that,
you know,
I just,
uh,
I don't want to paraphrase it because I
was like,
I don't want to,
I don't,
I,
I can't deal with these bitches around
here.
So I think he was a funny guy,
right?
Is what I think it's hard.
It's hard when you see things in text
because you think,
okay,
maybe he's like a really mean terrible
person.
See,
I adopted the attitude that those bar
girls were all bitches,
that they aren't worth anything and that
they're all in the,
all they're in there for is for to get
you to buy him a drink and they're not
going to give you a God damn thing.
I'm not going to be a gentleman to such
worthless bitches and so on.
He writes,
see,
but I feel like,
and so on when someone says,
and so on,
that implies that this is taken out of
context in my mind is I want to know
what does that mean and so on.
That means to me,
what I'm getting out of this,
if I,
if I was going to guess is that he goes
on,
he elaborates,
he might say,
this is how I felt back then and
obviously I changed my mind.
I mean he could have been 18 when you're
talking about this or 16.
I don't know what the fuck is this is
about.
But he also could be very funny because
he was apparently a very funny guy.
So his,
the title of his book is surely you're
joking Mr Fiman.
Aww,
that's nice then.
But if it,
so like if one,
if someone said that,
but I dumped it,
all these bar girls are bitches and say
said it funny.
Could you see those,
those same,
I thought they had all these balls
bitches,
but it's all different depending upon
how old he is too.
Or it could be that,
that's really how he was.
And maybe he got married,
maybe got in trouble,
his wife and he had to say this.
You know,
I don't think that's it.
I think he's talking about when he was
younger,
but it's,
um,
I could see that though.
Do.
You're at the bar if you don't like
we're loud music and all the girls are
just drinking with a bunch of,
I'll be like,
oh,
these girls are a bunch of bitches.
Probably.
Yeah,
but that's a lazy way.
If it is a lazy way thing and it just
makes it,
it's you can judge and you can control
the scenario.
Yeah.
Thing is,
look,
if you go into a room and 10 girls are
in there and seven of them are fucking
super annoying and you say these bitches
are all annoying,
you're being super rude to those three
that aren't and there might be some
decent girls,
but that's why it's weird.
It's like it's weird to hear like high
level famous scientists probably.
I think in the article they were saying
the second fee.
Yeah.
Beyond uh,
beyond Einstein.
He's the second famous most famous
physicist.
Especially a scientist.
Because you think a scientist would know
that there's a couple of these bitches
could be variables.
I'm thinking this might have been a
quote from him when he was young.
Yeah.
That's crazy.
Then I think that he said that or him
criticizing himself when he was young,
but I don't know.
I'm just guessing.
I was hoping that it would be that bad.
It's crazy to read that.
Do it a lot.
Sometimes I miss being young man.
Don't you miss it sometimes?
Well no and yes.
Like it looks like fun to have no
responsibility and to be 22 and be
backpacking around the world are doing
something silly and not having a place
where you have to go or a bunch of
bills.
But on the other hand,
I feel so fucking ridiculously lucky
that I get to be a comedian.
Like I don't want to try to do this
again.
Yeah.
Why would I try to do this when I'm
doing this?
Like,
but yeah,
but to go back out of Smith's,
being young and like member a nat man,
we took a nap and you were young and
could last.
He fucking getting care could last for
three days.
Yes.
But I think one of the secrets to
happiness is to never look back at any
point in your life and wish you were
back there because a,
it's not possible.
Right,
and B,
if you didn't go through that,
you wouldn't be you.
If you would go back now and be 22 again
and broke and fucked up with all the
information you have now,
he'd be like,
shit,
y'all don't know.
I had a fucking Netflix special.
You guys don't know how I was killing it
out there.
I decided to start over like an asshole.
Now here I am.
Yeah,
I'm young,
but I'm broke.
I can't even afford vitamins.
What the fuck?
I don't want to be.
That guy gets a birthing.
Joe Wants.
It's a good,
I work out hard,
man.
I got to take care of my body.
You're right.
Feed it the right food.
I can't afford a ramen noodle and eating
ramen noodles everyday.
I'm going to get started breaking
joints.
Yeah,
whenever was tear muscles and shit.
Then you're going to be now let me
fucking catching squirrels in my yard.
That's when it gets bad.
I'm not sure what to do when y'all done
either.
I missed my body being young dude and
like,
how old are you?
I'm 38 shut your mouth.
You're fine.
You just got to work out.
Yeah.
He didn't work out.
Huh?
I just started getting back into it.
Yeah.
That's all it is.
Doing some yoga and I want to go travel
Brazilian Jiu Jitsu.
Downtown's slow down with that.
You carry yourself in shape first.
Yeah.
That's what I'm realizing my,
yeah,
my advice because you're trying to
explode and get out of things that look,
don't listen to me.
You can start Jujitsu and be in terrible
shape and get in shape through Jujitsu.
You can.
Yeah,
absolutely.
But if I was going to advise someone,
I would say if you're going to do
something that's his physical,
his Jujitsu,
I believe that you should arm or your
body.
What I mean by that,
it's like your shoulders,
your knees,
your back,
your neck.
Those are all areas that if you don't
work out at all,
they could break susceptible.
They're susceptible,
so I would always advise that someone
does a bunch of calisthenics,
particularly like,
like the classics,
pushups,
sit ups,
bodyweight squats,
chin-ups,
those,
all those classics.
Do a lot of those get you just get your
body accustomed to resistance training.
Do that first.
Then I would move from the,
I would always start with the,
with calisthenics.
Always start with that and then from
that move into weights.
Do like some kettlebells take a couple
of months.
You could take a couple months before
you just jump right into Jujitsu if you
don't have,
but if you're an athlete then you could
just jump right in.
If you're a guy already does basketball,
you already wrestled.
Oh yeah,
jump right in.
But a guy who doesn't do any exercise at
all.
Yeah.
Jujitsu.
So rough on you.
Yeah.
I used to do extra as him and I used to
do,
did we shoot up steroids and the side of
the interstate when I was growing up?
Shoot on the side of the road.
Why wouldn't you go home?
I was more of an outdoor thing.
I felt like,
you know,
I didn't want to bring that sit in the
house forever,
but we would,
uh,
me and a buddy of mine is do billy
confort toe actually,
and he passed away our Ip and he died.
He had a bunch of pills and actually
drove into an embankment one time.
But,
um,
oh yeah.
Can you imagine?
It's about where to go.
And He,
uh,
but he was a busboy and I was a busboy
and he would,
uh,
and yet we both like to go to the gym
and he was like the first gay man that I
ever met.
And then he,
um,
you know,
he,
one time he got us some steroids or
something,
I don't know.
I think everybody was doing them.
And then we just,
yeah,
we'd pull over and do them and then just
go to the gym.
You know,
do one time a guy in New York said,
I'm going to get some drugs.
The middle of the night,
he went and came back three hours later
it was steroids.
He's like,
you want to fucking party?
Wow.
Whose party?
It was still raw.
Like fuck no bro,
I'm leaving tomorrow.
I was there for about eight months.
How come?
So I was just kind of trying out the
comedy scene there and seeing what it
was like.
Why did you decide to leave?
I don't know.
I guess I just wanted like a new,
here's what it was.
I'd never want it to get old and say
that I didn't try it to go to La to try
New York.
Oh,
I see.
Right.
To never have even just six months.
Even just have like an experience there,
you know?
Well it's a hotbed for sure.
The two hot beds right now or here and
there.
Yeah,
those are the two hot beds and there's
all this debate as to like,
which one's better or whatever.
It's silly.
That's,
that's a great hotbed.
No denying that.
There's some world class comedians over
there and then there's ones that show up
there and here,
like Chappelle.
He's always bounce,
bounce it back and forth.
Chris Rock was always bouncing back and
forth.
Louie would news working in here,
but when Louise working again,
he's working at the Improv right now.
Who is he came to San Jose.
Yeah.
Oh Wow.
That's cool.
I think he's going to sell it a world
tour and like a year for sure.
For sure.
Her next month.
Even if we want it to.
Yeah,
for sure.
You know,
I mean it's,
it's interesting this whole bit about
the parkland shooting.
Oh yeah.
Saw that stirred up all this controversy
that is so,
it's such a Louis ck bit.
It's interesting.
It's almost like people don't understand
what kind of comedy he did.
Right?
Yeah.
It's like suddenly they forget who he
was.
We,
if you look at his comedy,
you're not even surprised that he was
jerking off,
you know,
kind of room service sorta deal,
you know?
But he's,
he's,
his style has always been like that.
I mean that he's,
his style is always very irreverent.
Yeah.
Saying fucked up shit.
You can't believe he's saying and you
know,
well written and well thought out stuff.
This is stuff he's working on and this
is people like,
you know,
how could he joke?
It wasn't even that good.
He's just,
he probably wrote that day
two days before.
Who knows how many times has done that
bit.
But I guarantee you the guy takes 10
months off of stand up and then he
started to do it again.
I don't,
he was scared.
I bet.
I don't think I would ever joke around
about that.
I definitely wouldn't joke around about,
but you can.
Yeah.
I don't know if I would.
It just wasn't,
wasn't as best stuff.
It wasn't good.
It's like it wasn't ready.
Yeah.
But maybe he could have come up with a
different turn on it where it wouldn't
be as offensive and it will be way
funnier.
That's what working on a bid is all
bout.
Right.
Like fuck,
look Holtzman,
Brian Holtzman.
If he had said that exact same thing
that Louie said,
we would be howland.
Yeah.
We'd be in the back of the room.
Slap the table howling laughing.
Yeah.
It on span.
You don't get the talk cause you'll put
the fucking fat kid in the way.
That literally,
that's a bit that if Holtzman said we
will be crying,
we'd be slapping the table.
We'd all gather around and watch him on
late nights anyway.
An issue.
Right.
It wouldn't be an issue at all because
we know that it's humor is it?
Yeah,
it's a fucked up thing to say.
That's kind of the point.
The whole art form is about saying
things that are funny sometimes saying
things that are funny or self
deprecating.
Sometimes they're fucked up.
There are always different sometimes
saying things is,
they're funny.
It's really adorable.
Sometimes someone will say something
that's really adorable but also
hilarious or your act.
This is odd,
odd and hilarious.
Just very,
very uh,
Theo Vaughn.
If I had to describe your act that say
it's very theo Vaughn,
really?
Eh,
it's you,
you know how to do it,
but it's like everybody does it.
Different folks.
And you know,
you take a a set from someone who's just
working stuff out and you pretend that
this is done.
He's probably half those words he's
saying he's probably trying to be in the
moment.
He's probably got a place to go.
Kind of got some punchlines and hoping
that he'll see something in it while
he's doing it and working it out.
And then you listen to the recording and
you go,
oh,
why did I say it that way?
Why did I do this?
And you change that and add this and
it's his to learn.
Yeah.
And then you know,
it just can't expect them all to be good
either.
Like immediately,
especially when the guy's been on trial,
like you know,
or Ben,
you know,
under that social pressure and are just
like,
you know,
in,
probably been dealing with remorse and
go to self.
How,
I don't know.
I mean who knows what he's been doing.
This is my,
this is my take on a lot of this and I
think this is an important thing to say.
We can't lose our empathy.
We can't lose our compassion.
We Ha we,
we should be compassionate towards
victims.
We could,
we should be compassionate towards each
other.
We should beat this,
this tendency to want to stop people
from working and being like,
there's a certain amount of time where
it passes and it starts to look like you
don't want anyone to have a path to
redemption.
Right?
Which is,
everyone's got to have a path to
a day have cause we're all faulty,
all human.
But there was an article about it that I
just retweeted today from a Nick
Christakis who was a professor at Yale.
I,
um,
uh,
retweeted it today,
earlier.
It's about call out culture and the
these people that got called out for
things and how it destroyed their lives.
People that you don't even know.
And like,
yeah,
one small s uh,
a punk scene where these,
these two people got called out for
stuff,
but it's like,
oh,
the subscription,
the goddess with a subscription to
subscribe to the New York Times.
Bro,
you got to pay for good journalism.
I pay,
I'm having this account actually,
if you want to use,
you have a,
you have a time account.
I think I do.
I had one,
but uh,
I,
I tried to renew the other day and I
couldn't because these cunts stole my
fucking American Express card and I
didn't get my new one yet.
Who did?
The people were on an some fucking piece
of shit.
Criminals.
Yeah.
Fucking crazy.
Charged up shit.
One of them was toys r us in India.
Oh Wow.
Okay.
Good.
I love seeing what people charge when
they do steal from it.
It's kind of fun,
isn't it?
Isn't it crazy or like piss it,
they stole over.
You're like,
oh wow.
It was $1.
I got an Ottoman.
A lot of it was a $1 and I was like,
what are you doing?
If you bang that maybe they bang the
card out for like $101 or maybe it just
got a snack.
Sometimes you run in place just to get a
snack,
get a gum.
It was all,
it was all online about a receipt or
something.
The other day was 88 cents.
Yeah.
That would be a stupid thing to hit
someone's card for.
You'd want to get a jewel.
Yeah.
Gas is really expensive.
Vape pen
for that 29 bucks.
How crazy though that,
that,
that's the future that now it's like
that.
Like I was thinking the other day that
having a baby inside of your body,
this is going to be like the last,
yeah,
that's becoming retro.
They're going to take it out for sure.
There was a baby that was born today
inside the amniotic sac.
Did you see that?
And that's a damn goldfish.
It,
no,
it's crow.
Raisie you're seeing delicacy places
inside the sack.
I mean,
I don't know what the story was because
I'm a notorious headline reader.
I read headliners,
googled it,
and it's theirs.
It's not a thing.
It had its happens apparently.
Well,
I don't care if it happens all the time.
I want,
wanted to take incredible photos of
babies born,
but it was an article that was going
around the internet today.
Baby born in,
it's a video of the baby.
Move it around inside this,
uh,
this sack.
It's very weird.
It's a damn about it.
On Youtube.
That's a dumpling dude.
If you're downtown,
what is that?
Oh,
it's a dumpling.
It's a,
they're very small.
It's not a wow.
See if you can find it.
It was on.
I saw it.
I believe I saw it on instagram.
Let me see that baby man.
Do you think maybe when babies are born
right when they're born,
look at that though.
That's the thing.
That's the baby inside the sac.
That's one of the things they us eat
sometimes on those games shows.
Oh,
so I'm guessing this is a Sicilian
section.
It happens once every 80,000 births.
That is amazing that you could see what
the baby looks like when it's in there.
Holy Crap.
That's incredible easy,
Bro.
Oh,
it's Spanish.
It was in Spain.
Do human beings making human beings.
Okay,
that's crazy.
This is exactly what I saw.
This is,
this one is the exact,
when I saw how crazy is that?
Okay.
Might be upsetting for some.
You're about to see the amniotic sac
being opened.
It's like a old man upsetting.
That's how we exist.
Yeah,
but people aren't ready for life.
Yeah.
We're going to keep you from life.
We're going to keep you from everything.
There it is.
Bam.
The SAC.
Oh Shit.
Kids free.
Now we could see a little bit of butter
on that one.
Oh,
Lordy.
Yeah.
I can't believe.
Do you ever think that maybe if a Bray B
is born a certain way,
like missionary or doggy style,
that it could affect the way that they
lived their life?
I thought about that before.
Well,
you should probably understand how
babies are born.
They have to come out ahead first.
It's your baby comes a doggy style.
You've got to spin around inside the
womb,
literally.
Okay.
But what if the person is doggy style
when they have the baby though?
Oh,
different thing.
Uh,
yeah.
You kids probably going to be a freak.
Yeah.
Doggy style.
It's like we're not making love.
We're fucking,
yeah.
Doggy style is basically just kind of
pay.
Yeah.
It's like getting to know each other
quickly.
Well,
it's just a different kind of fucking,
yeah,
okay.
It's like,
oh,
this is dirty shit.
Yeah.
It's fast or slow.
Sometimes it depends on how you're
feeling.
Sometimes I'm a sex when I was a young
man,
sober sex is for fucking kit is for what
does this with you missing your youth?
I just loved to slug me.
What are you doing?
I don't want to watch the lady give
birth.
You set up a bit.
It's not video.
It's just like get outta here.
She sent it river.
She's given birth in a river.
It's called in the river.
You crazy bitch.
That's melted glaciers.
Wim Hoff birth right here.
You can get born into that for a little
kid and if it's not warm,
if it's not,
then it's warm.
If it's warm,
it's filled bacteria.
Get the fuck.
Hey,
go hippie.
No,
no.
You can't have a baby in your bath tub
if you live in fucking Brooklyn
Goddamn hospital down the street.
Don't you love your kid?
Yeah,
he figured out a better way.
Look at this.
His lady,
first of all she is is she's an
Australia.
Well,
the spiders that are going to crawl into
her pussy right now and kill the baby
before it even comes out.
They have a seven of the eight most
dangerous snakes in the world or in
Australia.
He's trying to tell my friend Adam Green
tree yesterday.
He does want to believe me.
Very.
The brown snake.
The Australian Brown snake dude killed
the shit out of you all.
Kill that little fucking creek bitch
speaking Australian Brown snake.
That's how she got pregnant in the first
place.
You see what I did there?
Did a lot of land.
My sister once got knocked up by brother
once,
man.
All over.
No.
Yeah,
almost high.
What's almost he fucked?
I mean,
I don't know if they fucked,
but they will.
That's all most they were thinking about
baby names,
so it assume that they had had some type
of interaction.
Oh,
so they were going to do it on purpose?
I don't know.
I think that they're thinking about baby
names in case they fucked up.
Boy,
that's weird.
Planning ahead.
How much wear a condom or,
but I think that's a dude's move.
If you think you might've knocked the
girl up and you're still want to stay
with her,
you'd be like,
Oh,
let's talk about baby names t.
You know what I'm saying?
Until you ride out that,
until you bail that menstrual cycle.
No,
until you know that the menstrual cycle.
Oh yeah.
You know?
Yeah.
Can people will cycle on a full moon or
not?
It's a weird thing if you are,
you having sex with somebody and you
like having sex with them but you don't
like hanging out with them.
Yeah.
That happens for guys and girls.
Happens for a lot of guys.
I know,
dude,
it happens and girls too.
It happens.
I've heard girls say that like I don't
even like hanging out with them anymore,
but I liked fucking them.
It's changing now and a lot more girls
are being very much like guys used to
be.
Well they can be the,
the first,
the birth control pill,
then dating apps,
they can get ahold of people and money.
They know they have options.
Yeah.
But the,
the thing about this,
um,
about uh,
uh,
dating apps,
it's like,
that's kind of be just as weird as
dating for girl.
Yeah.
It was weird or maybe right because
Pete,
you can't even see the person,
right?
I mean you can see pictures of them.
Yeah.
But you don't see them when they're
looking at your profile and the right.
You should be able to see how they look
at your profile,
how many people are looking at your
profile and any given moment,
you know,
that's a,
that's a nightmare in and of itself.
Yeah.
We think about that.
Imagine like just people just looking at
you and saying no and you're in the
distance all the time.
It has to be bad for us.
Somebody will say yes.
Then the odds,
the thing things you're playing the
numbers maybe in that sense it's better
because the only people that get ahold
of you,
the people that say yes,
right,
so you missed all the notes.
It's true.
But what I was gonna say is that haven't
had a baby with someone that you don't
really like.
Yeah.
That's a possibility.
If you just like to have sex with them
and then when you're done you're like,
I gotta go.
Yeah,
P and you can't go because the babies
around.
I was coming off fuck buddies that all
everyone has,
guys and girls have fuck buddies.
Yeah.
I'm almost,
everyone I know has had one in the past
where you weren't in a relationship with
them.
Really drive over and fuck and bang and
then,
all right,
bye.
Yeah,
But you kiss at the end.
That's a lot of checks these days.
I think they didn't even want to kiss
you.
They don't want to kiss.
You only want to see you.
Sometimes you'll open the door.
The girls,
they're ready to fuck and then just
walks off in the other direction.
When you're done,
it puts a blindfold on bird boxes.
You're done with us,
man.
They're done.
I feel like they're done.
Do you feel like that?
I think it's a precarious time.
A lot of chicks are probably going
lesbos this week.
Oh Dude.
I would be with trump.
I think the more days that the the
government shutdown,
the more women are going to go lesbian.
They gonna hate men so much because of
trump.
They just didn't go gay.
People always say people.
Right now.
That's not how I remember what I said
earlier about jokes,
but what's funny to me is gay guys are
always like,
I'm going to turn this guy out,
and that always sounds alarming.
That does work,
but that sounds alarming.
It does sound alarming,
but it does work.
I have,
I don't want to say I almost said his
name.
Uh,
he worked on,
she wasn't,
he was not an actor,
but he worked in the world of acting and
he told me that he blew a lot of
straight guys.
That was just something that happened.
They'd would have a couple of drinks in,
pretend they'd never done it before.
And next thing you know,
la La.
Yeah,
I got that delicious mouth.
That's what a lot of gay dude say.
It was either him doing them or them
doing him,
but he's like,
you'd be amazed at how many,
you know,
air quotes.
Straight guys are out there.
My Woo.
Yeah.
And he's just knows how to swing it.
But will you,
do you think,
is it less homosexual to jerk a golf
with your left hand?
What are you left handed or right
handed?
Right handed?
He jerks you off to your left hand.
It's gay.
Or to do it with your right mind is
geared to do with my left hand.
The one that doesn't work as well
because it'll take longer.
You have a,
you don't really have,
but it's understandable.
I feel like it's understandable if you
do it with your left hand because that's
barely even your hand.
No,
it's my hand,
Bro.
You're not going to feel that much of it
though.
She jerk him off with your right hand so
you should be effective and get it done
with.
Unless you like holding on Dick's
longer.
Don't come yet.
No.
Hey Buddy,
I'm right here.
I'm your pal.
I know what's going to happen.
You're going to come then.
You're not going to want to hang out
with me anymore.
No,
no.
I wouldn't do that.
Just go fast and go back.
No,
I don't believe you.
I think not.
I think you.
I think you,
I think you said that left hand.
Is that red?
That's the party move.
You know because it's not,
you can still use this hand and to be on
your phone.
You can do other stuff,
but then you're not concentrating on the
jerk and the guy off.
Like once you commit to doing something
gay,
just get it done,
son.
Just get after it.
That's true.
You don't want to be out there halfway
jerky and I got off while you're
pretending that you're looking at your,
mentioned your email,
but also what about this though?
If you are aggressively very effectively
jerk and the guy off and then you can
barely use your phone,
it looks like you're just like Ugh,
maybe uh,
you know,
gay or bi gentleman that's on some dope
or something.
You're doing gay shit.
Whether you're on your phone and not as
like a sound like it acts as a condoms
prevent you would gain is struck.
You're doing gay things mean you're
holding onto a dick.
You just got to accept that and keep
moving.
There's a lot of,
yeah,
you're right.
Just take the next right action.
There's gay people doing shit that's
gay.
There's straight people doing shit.
That's gay changing now.
Jerk that man off.
Once you commit to that project,
just keep going and yeah,
it's the payoff.
What do you got out of drinking them
off?
I don't know.
I don't think I,
let me ask you this.
Here's a question.
If there was a place,
does this conversation seem gay?
Or if life was free,
if you could really do whatever you
want,
if you're a grown adult,
you can do whatever you want.
That's one of the interesting things
about society is that we set up these
rules and cultures and we decide what
you can do and what we decide is
different with a deciding Hollin is
different when they say,
yeah,
everybody's got different rules.
Yeah.
But once we set those rules,
it's very hard to buck those rules.
It,
let's just pretend there was no rules.
What if there was a place where guys
would go and guys would jerk them off
and New Jersey?
Yeah.
Like if there was a place where guys,
straight guys got a job Jerkin guys off,
but you,
it cha you,
you get paid $1,000 an hour.
Okay.
You don't think the straight guys would
take that job straight struggling guys,
then you would,
would,
they would morph and figure out a way.
Oh,
just over a generation or two.
Just a generation or two.
If you could make $1,000 an hour beaten
guys off.
Yeah.
It started as like a best you can each
job.
If you could wear an oven Mitt while you
do it,
I wouldn't do it.
Just do we.
Do we figure that out?
If he could wear an oven Mitt while you
do it?
Oh No,
no,
no.
Warm oil in your bare skin.
That's the only way to jerk guys off.
You got to do,
Bro.
Dude,
there's way other ways,
man.
You could definitely do.
One way you could do is even you even
wrap your head.
You just do like that.
Release a sideways Kentucky Fried
Chicken.
There's only one batter.
Crispy batter is bullshit.
Nobody likes that crispy batter.
The Fuck Outta here.
I'm trying to think if I had to
[inaudible] w one thing about jerking
off to me,
I feel like there's not as much calm in
your body is there could be.
You know what I'm saying?
You don't get that much at,
well,
it depends on what you're jerking off to
and you know how focused you are on the
task.
If you're jerking off while you're
looking at your phone.
Yeah.
But you're,
you know,
you're checking your twitter and your
also beaten.
Yeah.
You have multitask,
but you're not going to get a lot no
matter how much you know,
how,
how you do it.
Really.
Yeah.
How much do you get?
You get like a little bit,
how much do you get?
I get like,
like if you had compare it to something
like a quarter?
No,
probably like maybe a,
like an 11th of a handful,
I guess.
I don't know.
How big is your hand,
dude?
I can't even,
do you still masturbate as an adult?
No,
I do it as a child.
I mean,
we'll just say I put a diaper on and it
makes me feel like rejuvenating myself.
I feel like you'd rip your Dick off.
He tried.
I feel like I hold my kids' hands.
I know how to hold things gently.
Yeah,
that's true,
man.
I,
uh,
I don't know,
man.
I,
I actually masturbated yesterday and I
feel bad about it sometimes,
but why?
How does,
I don't know.
For some reason I feel bad.
That's the thing.
It's a cultural thing.
They got us when we're
young,
like think about it this way.
What if the culture was all stand up
comedy culture?
Because arguably standup comedians have
a different culture and a different way
of looking at things.
Yes.
And definitely a good,
very deep camaraderie between fellow
practitioners.
Right?
Yeah.
If that was the culture was the standup
comedy culture was the whole world,
you wouldn't give a fuck if you beat
off.
Right.
You wouldn't even be slightly
embarrassed.
Tell,
tell people where it's at.
Sure.
Ari would tell me all the time,
how many times beat up towards to oh,
talk to all.
We all tell each other how we beat off
of what we beat off two.
I'd have,
I don't like it as much as I used to
when I was young.
Well,
that's my thing.
You're probably a healthier,
yeah.
You know,
it's like you got an older,
you're more comfortable,
you're successful.
Yeah.
It just feels like,
yeah,
it feels like a novice move.
It comes still jerk and office 2019 it's
certainly a distraction to do something
about.
Uh,
especially looking at porn,
there's,
I'm not anti porn.
I don't want anybody to get me wrong.
I think she'd be able to do whatever you
want to do.
Ultimately.
And I think a lot of why people have bad
opinions about people doing certain
things is that we judge people when they
do certain things and we have these
ideas about them that we sort of impose
on them.
Right.
But I think for some people,
torn is very useful,
but you have to have discipline.
Yeah.
See,
the thing is if you watch porn and you
watch two people have sex and you get
excited and you jerk off,
you just took care of like some sexual
needs that you had.
Yeah.
What could possibly be wrong with that?
The only thing that can be possibly
wrong with it is that there's something
wrong with these two people having sex
and filming it.
Well,
is there like,
but doesn't everybody want to fuck?
I'm like,
I don't want to film myself fucking,
but doesn't everybody want to have sex?
People love to have sex.
It's like one of the most important
motivations that we have.
Oh Yeah,
look,
people leave the house every day cause
they might have a chance to fuck.
That's for sure.
I mean,
why do people,
why did they get involved in romantic
relationships in the first place?
To not just,
not just be nice to each other,
but to fuck eventually.
Sometimes.
That's part of the whole thing.
Yeah.
So what is it about two people fucking
on film that's so distasteful?
Well,
you know,
you didn't want people to see your
special thing maybe.
Or like what you don't,
you know,
you want to keep it private.
I get all those fancy though.
It's high def though.
You can't,
your brain,
you keep it real life can't compete with
it.
So then it's so sad.
It's not always the case.
I say stuff is just right there.
But it's not real life though.
It's not as good.
It's not as good as real life.
But I think that it's visually,
it starts to get that it's better and it
starts to get where like sometimes like
I like I'm 40 days off pornography right
now.
Right.
Oh really?
Yeah.
Oh,
so you're like on a pornography detox,
Huh?
I don't ever want to see it again.
Really?
Yeah.
If somebody tries to get their pussy
out,
I'm like,
you stop.
But let me,
let me say this to you though.
You also had the same kind of issue with
drugs and alcohol,
right?
So you have like an addictive
personality.
Yeah,
that's a good point.
So having to take their personality and
what I was saying earlier that I think
that the thing of it,
the thing itself is not necessarily bad
and for some people can actually provide
a service,
right?
Like it helps them to jerk off.
I don't understand why that would be
bad.
The only thing that would say is,
and this is a,
I don't know how factual this is cause I
haven't done any surveys,
but what I've read is that a lot of the
people that get involved in that are
victims of abuse.
Hmm.
That's disturbing.
Right?
You don't want to hear that.
But then some of them aren't.
Some of them do it because they want to
do it.
Yeah.
Like it's not,
okay.
That seems more okay.
And someone who's doing it because
they're a victim of abuse and they're
desperately seeking love and attention
and they don't know how,
how to do it.
That's a good point.
So then you look at it like in terms of,
but you're just,
that's looking at that is like,
well then don't laugh at comedy,
right?
Because you laugh at comedy.
Almost everybody that's Comedians fucked
up or been fucked over.
I mean that's,
that's really why they get into it in
the first place because they desperately
need attention.
They want to be special,
they want to be something.
And they're like,
look at me,
look at me.
So they figured out how to be funny.
But usually those are victims of abuse,
like in some way,
shape or from,
not all of them because they need the
affection.
They need that they need something from
people.
Maybe six out of 10,
right?
Yeah,
maybe.
And now I'm being real jars.
Yeah.
So there's so many things that you could
look at that like that w you know,
like something good comes out of stand
up.
Right?
So we just accept that.
That's okay to laugh at these fucked up
people.
But you know what I mean,
like kind of like joey is that guys
lived everything.
He's seen everything,
but it's okay.
It's okay to laugh at the chaos that his
life was because the jokes are so funny.
Yeah.
You know,
it's,
it's weird,
right?
But it's not okay to look at,
uh,
like even if the girls enjoying porn,
if you find out that at some point in
time she was molested and that possibly
it was one of the motivating factors
that led her into porn,
then you get super weird about it,
then you get to think about it.
They should put that on the thing,
like percentage chance of somebody that
was molested in the video.
And I think that that would deter people
from watching us.
Do you think so?
Yeah,
man.
My thing is just,
I started to think of sex then in frames
like,
okay,
I got to meet the girl and then we have
to walk over by us.
You know,
we have to,
I have to see this and have to see that.
Then that happens.
And then and now and that sec,
so I started to,
you know,
like interpret it that way and I don't
know,
sex is just fun.
When you were young,
men were,
when you were fucking imagine being 16
and fucking somebody else.
That was 16 bro.
You know what?
I want to hear in the background.
We sing this song live and let die when
you were,
yeah,
they used to say
who is that?
Diana Ross.
He's things.
Paul Mccartney and wings motherfuck
rings Bruh.
That was from James Bond.
Oh,
that's right,
that's right.
Guns n roses.
That was one time where the fucking
remake is so good.
That was,
you kind of put a wasn't their own song
and dance and I hear some only we hear
it has actually been on your podcast
show.
No,
I definitely have him on man.
Wow.
I definitely have that going on.
I can't imagine.
Seems to have come back from the brink.
Yeah,
right.
Yeah.
Who knows what kind of ego happened and
what all happened whenever they went
gimme some volume so I can hear it.
At least I want to hear him say that to
be any,
yeah,
we go,
here we go.
Here we go.
Yeah,
look out.
So he was for years.
He went crazy.
Yeah.
Vanished was trying to make that one
album forever.
Right.
Took many,
many years.
And everybody's like,
God damn an axl rose went crazy.
I need to see him.
He like Dan was a shame.
Guns and roses was so good,
so good.
And then slowly but surely he fucking
came back like really came back like
he's fucking back like that dude tours
with AC DC now.
I mean he crushes it.
I saw some videos of him on stage.
He's a fucking animal again.
He looks like a heart.
A little bit like one of the people from
heart buddy.
But that's just age and time,
you know?
Oh,
I don't think it's agent time.
I think there's a lot of other
ingredients could be shrunk down to
throw some shit onto that mix will solve
was shriven.
Yeah,
but just slash looks the same.
A slash looks the same,
but that's what I'm saying.
They're both the same age.
You started out together or close to the
same age at least.
Dude,
how much fun must that paid position?
I think it's too much fun.
This is my theory.
I think it's too much fun and I think
they don't even have to write new shit
so because they don't have to write new
shit and it's too much fun.
They're out there just fucking smashing
every night.
Fucking smashing.
Smashing shows,
smashing tour buses and hotel raking.
Cheson just smashing each other.
Shouldn't pussy just smashing.
They probably be crazy.
He probably didn't even notice who you
fuck a dude.
If you're that famous break,
you notice.
I think you're wrong.
I beg to differ.
Oh,
he's got to have a teleprompter.
What about a fast dude?
There's no actual Rosetta teleprompter
desperate,
but I guess you want that.
If you're on all the drugs and you want
all the junk,
not only do I want to teleprompter,
I want it to be highlighted.
What am I supposed to say?
I mean,
he's wearing hot pants.
He is so close.
He's very hot pants with a high cowboy
boots with socks
and a mesh top and tidy.
Whities is,
so what is it that makes somebody so
famous that they get close to being
almost like a bisexual?
What you think?
Do you keep bringing up all this gay
stuff you guys do?
Tell me was your Stepdad,
right?
No Bro.
I've never been gay man.
Never,
ever.
No.
Never,
ever,
ever.
I mean,
maybe when I'm 60 or 70,
I'll bust out,
you know,
I'll come on somebody,
but I'm not doing anything now.
Gay.
I want a family and everything.
I think there are so for re with their
expression,
right that they wear whatever the fuck
they want.
And I think that's a part of the culture
of really huge musicians is that they
get very free with the looks.
There's sexuality.
Like look at him with his,
with his ripped up pants.
Axl rose backward is a cutie pie or
David Bowie.
David Bowie,
when he was in his androgynous state of
Prince,
uh,
I mean you can go on and on and on about
men look fucking Mick Jagger.
Mick Jagger would swing his hips,
puff his lips as well.
Elvis is no stay,
pretty straight manly thing.
Women's clothing.
Women's like,
you know,
stuff from like,
he wore stuff from like scarves and
shit.
Is that what you're saying now?
What's that women's clothing store
that's in every like little sort of
secrets?
No,
it's for like kind of more,
you know Lane Bryant.
Oh,
where the big fat lady stuff.
Well,
I mean,
tell me about what you're saying
dude.
Close door for fat guys.
Big and tall.
They call it,
but that's like,
some of them are.
It's called dot.
It's over there on Pico Boulevard.
He didn't hit her.
J Anthony always sells those suits over
there on stage.
What's up?
Oh,
there he is.
Is that him now?
That's him.
That could be the lady.
Is it Sheryl swoopes?
He's,
he's a,
that's,
that's his sister.
Looks Weird like that.
It's like he went to spring break,
but that's axle from younger days.
So that's when he advantaged for awhile.
Right.
Oh.
But when he did that,
like he did a big concert in Brazil too,
right?
Yeah.
I remember listening to that and his
voice was kind of struggling a little
bit because he has such a script,
such a scratchy voice,
you know,
you've got to think like that voice is
probably very difficult to maintain,
but that primal fucking
dude that was this shit when I was,
that was like right when I was
graduating high school.
I remember I worked out this shitty
little gym and I'd be on the leg press
machine,
listen to wow,
come Janette.
What kind of headphones did you have?
A whatever.
They had the big ones out.
I had a walkman with a cassette.
It might've been a disc player.
Well,
okay.
That one's ridiculous.
That one makes,
Oh,
who is that recent?
Is that Holly Hunter?
That's him now.
No,
it's not holly hunter.
You son of a bitch.
I don't even know who Holly Harris
supposed to lead singer guns and roses.
I loved guns and roses.
Did you call him?
My brother and I used to beat each other
in our room.
We'd fist fight in the yard to fucking
guns and roses.
AC DC.
It was a music of my childhood was,
was was gnr alison chains.
That's a weird look.
The,
the,
the thermal or the flannel shirt tied
around the waist.
What's that look
right,
but that's a weird look like on purpose
as a weird look.
I said Darlene comics,
like,
Hey,
I know I'm not going to wear this
flannel shirt,
but I'm going to tie it around my waist,
but hey,
it's not really a skirt.
Right?
It's just like an accoutrement to my
outfit of fake ripped pants.
Yeah,
right.
That's a weird look.
Isn't it?
A weird look.
Would you think you'd rather have like a
little skirt or like be naked,
you think skirt.
I don't want people judging me really
looking at my deck.
It's making me self conscious.
But what if you had like a little dick
hide or like a little thing that you
could still did look at how big is your
dick hide or
you can't get new escape?
Would you ever wear a fake Dick so that
people thought your Dick was bigger?
If I did,
it would be not worrying wrapped around
my waist.
Talk to the front.
I'd have it tucked in my sock
and it would be green,
like
a dark green,
like people would know.
It's fake though.
Kale,
Dick.
He was like,
oh,
that guy's is fake bro.
Like,
why are you looking at my deck?
Fuck away from my desk?
I think when people see me and a have
dicks in the future,
it just seems like everything's going
away so fast,
man.
Or they're trying to do that with this
new,
a Gillette commercial.
I've seen that Gillette commercial,
I heard about it that you can shave your
buddy or something.
Now all these years really mad because
it's like an anti unmasculine Gillette
commercial.
It makes like every man looks like a
massage and it's piece of shit.
It's such a disturbing commercial.
It's like over and over again.
Men doing douchey shit like,
hey bro,
aren't you selling razors and you
changing the world with your shitty
fucking advertiser based philosophy.
What are you doing?
Like what are you doing?
Who fucking greenlit this?
How's that Lana?
But like,
Yo,
Yo guys,
people get hair.
They want to fucking shave it.
You're not going to fix.
Imagine if you're a sexist rapist piece
of shit and you see that Gillette
commercial like,
damn,
I gotta switch my game mode.
I've been too much of a dick.
Like does anybody think that Gillette
commercials or somehow or another in any
way,
shape or form going to affect culture is
bad?
You're selling razors is bad,
bro.
It's just a razor.
I'd rather break my fucking face here.
Them by Gillette.
Again,
body wants to be lectured to wear a tie.
Your heard of that.
So sick of that.
You don't have your shit together.
Nobody has their shit together and you
telling people how to get their shit
together in a fucking razor blade at,
yeah.
Yeah.
Don't be racist.
We know.
Don't be a sexist.
Yeah,
we know.
We know.
Most people aren't.
Yeah.
It's like you got it.
Like most people are the videos,
like most people are.
It's not.
Most people are crazy.
That's a disproportionate amount of
people that are,
that's what I hate about it.
A lot of the,
this,
a lot of these ideas,
the ideology today,
it's like,
like they say,
everybody where I'm
from is racist.
Everybody's like,
uh,
you know,
some Christian Bible thumping and that's
not true.
So many of the people I know are not
that at all that it's unbelievable,
but so many of the people in some
[inaudible] and these other places,
they don't even know anybody from there.
So it's like they have no idea.
But they immediately stereotyped because
of your accent too.
Yeah.
You have a southern accent.
People assume you're not bright.
Yeah.
It's so stupid,
but it's also,
it's indicative of what the place used
to be like,
like what the world used to be like was
like a lot of the rural edge areas were
less educated.
Yeah.
Now that there's the internet,
the world is a different place,
man.
You can meet cool people in Wichita,
Kansas.
You meet cool people everywhere.
Everywhere you go,
you're going to run into pockets of cool
people.
Cool people are everywhere,
man.
And good people.
Good people are everywhere and they have
different values and a lot of them are
more community oriented,
more friendly.
We,
we on this side and those on the east
side,
everybody gets this idea that everybody
is like the people that live all stacked
on top of each other fucking like bees
swarm and in the high,
most people don't live like that man.
Most people live somewhere where there's
less folks.
You got to relax.
They can throw a Frisbee and not fucking
hit anybody.
That's that.
Most people,
you look at,
the vast majority of the country,
there's what is there 300 and how many
people?
Billion.
Why does it three 50 already?
What does it,
billion million bro million.
You are guessing billion so I'm glad
it's not billion.
I think there's a,
you imagine that right then I would say
three 20 if I had to guess,
I'd say three 20 but I'd say it's three
25 right.
But that's like how do they know about
illegals?
Oh,
who knows?
Probably 2 billion.
If they knew how many illegal aliens you
wouldn't you be pissed.
But like how do you know how many of
them?
What are you doing?
You counted them.
How were they still here?
Then what that was like,
Yo,
dude,
but you can't even raise your voice in
it.
Like I have to drive to riverside.
Even fucking raise my voice.
I feel like,
like that's how too tight it is in La.
308 million people in the United States
in 2010 but that's 2010 2000 it was 281
million.
Whoa.
Look at that dude.
Think about,
just think of that 20 fucking million
people,
28 29 27 million people and who's
fucking the most?
Are they saying is it whites?
Oh,
it's all whites.
Is it really you thing fucking every
race now,
bro,
it's new.
No,
we've decided.
We decided to take back our country.
Oh fuck no,
man,
we're,
we're on our way to white people are on
their way to being a serious minority.
Yeah.
That's going to happen.
Beige power,
bro.
That's what I say.
Everybody.
I look,
I love all the variety,
but you know what it's like.
It's like we have nice things.
We can't,
we can't have nice things.
We keep breaking things so we can't,
because of racist people,
you can't have all this wonderful
diversity.
So we're eventually all going to be
gray.
We're going to be like those fucking
aliens with the giant heads and we're
going to have no dicks and we're all
going to be the exact same thing.
So no one can criticize anyone on
anything other than your thoughts and
they're gonna be able to bring your
actions and they be able to read each
other's minds.
Yeah,
that's what I think.
And I think we're going to ruin the
environment.
So they have builtin eyeglasses.
When you're born,
they just fucking glue these bitches
onto your head.
Sort of like chicks with fake eyelashes.
You just,
you just have these lenses that you put
on when you're indoors,
you peel the lenses off and otherwise
you can just see nature.
You can walk outside,
but you can't really go far and it's
just,
you see he could press a fern button in
ferns.
We'll papa.
Why farm?
Well,
just you know,
foliage or something,
you know,
fallen a foley,
maybe a deer runs by,
be hit that side button.
I think nature in the future we'll
probably be contained in these gigantic
dome,
like places like one of them,
Stephen King books.
And that's where you'll go to get into
the nature.
Yeah,
like a biodome with pauly shore and uh,
Stephen Baldwin.
I think that's what it's going to be
like.
This is going to be,
there's going to be nature places and
the rest of the world would be city.
The rest of the whole plant we'll be
sitting in our wildlife would be a
bullshit wildlife.
It'll be like a,
you know,
a few thousand acres or something like
that.
About a bunch of animals living
together.
That's all that's left.
It'd be like a cat,
like a rabbit with like a little story,
like a story on its back or something.
Because if you look at overpopulation,
and I'm not one of those doom and gloom
people when it comes to overpopulation.
You know why?
Because I like people when people like,
you know,
there's too many fucking people you
don't like.
I've good friends that think,
you know,
you want to help the world.
Don't have any kids.
My okay.
Yeah.
I get why you'd say that,
but don't you like people?
I love people.
People are awesome.
It's all I know.
I mean,
some of them aren't awesome,
but the vast majority are pretty cool.
Yeah.
Work at least capable of being pretty
cool.
If you're cool to them and you establish
sort of a community being cool with each
other,
the vast majority of people are great.
People are Nice.
People are friendly.
Yes,
the vast majority.
So what's the problem?
The problem is was too many of us,
and we're not going to stop,
right?
They're going to plug,
oh I want to fuck somebody right now.
You know,
we're going to make people the,
the question is they will they say stop.
Stop.
The study size scientists say that as
people come more affluent and as they
become more educated,
they're less likely to have children or
they have less children.
So they think that the best way to stop
overpopulation is actually equity in the
world.
Like equality rather in the world make,
make the whole world basically like
America where everybody's just got a
chance to get ahead and everybody has an
awesome education.
And everybody has access to the best
information.
It can't happen.
But if that does happen,
that's what's going to curb
overpopulation.
Otherwise,
the people that are the least educated,
um,
uh,
they're not going to have the same
access to like look in,
in countries where people are poorer.
Like for instance,
they want to have more kids because they
want the kids to take care of him too.
Yes,
that's a big thing,
right?
That's a big thing.
And traditional communities and you
know,
they're,
they're tighter and you,
if,
here's the weird thing,
if you talk to scientists,
they will tell you that arguably those
are happier people.
Yeah.
He's happy people and they live in these
villages and stuff and they all in enjoy
each other's company.
Even though in our mind it's a hard
scrabble life.
You know,
they're living in a third world country
in a village.
But if they have access to food,
like say if they live in the Amazon or
something,
like they have much food you can get in
there.
You've got a lot of food,
man.
Like I know how you would say,
Hey,
I don't want to live that way.
So these people live in the wrong way.
They,
you know,
they have fucking 10 kids laying on them
and shit and they're all,
yeah,
they're all community in this hut
together and you're like that.
That looks terrible.
Hotbox and that base to a lot of times
you see the whole family isn't there
like a fucking dope.
But meanwhile those people could be like
really happy.
They can arguably be happier than a
comparable group of people in Western
civilization that you would just grab
100% and why is it black homes?
A lot of black families are still in the
woods.
You notice that a lot of the tribes,
they're kind of [inaudible] I guess
maybe not black,
but it's like how Latino or dark or mid
like a not,
I don't know what had,
I guess it's like a more universal shade
almost.
Kind of like a sofa color.
Well,
if you're in the jungle,
you're,
you're obviously in a hot climate.
If you're in a hot climate,
you better develop some fucking melanie.
Yeah,
that's what it is,
is melon.
And they got more Melanin and family.
I mean,
if you look at it,
I'm Italian mostly if you look at it,
and I have some Irish in me too,
but if you look at Italians who were in
the sun all the time,
do they get dark as fuck?
You know,
and if you were severed a seven plus
generations of people living in this one
area,
we are exposed to like tropical sunlight
all the time.
Oh,
and you had brown the fuck up or you
wouldn't make it.
Yeah,
it's true.
I go to Costa Rica or even for a couple
days and I'm fucking,
you know,
Brown down and my face is all,
kind of has pus in it from the sun.
But I think people,
uh,
evolving in a place like that,
like being there hundreds and hundreds
and hundreds of years,
maybe thousands of years.
Like you adapt to that environment or
you,
you know,
the,
the preferential,
the preferable genes are the ones that
make it through and there's,
people have joy.
There's families have a lot of joy
because they had to have their family
around.
You know,
like if somebody,
if somebody dies,
they have them write day.
It's like everything's just a lot more
communal.
I think there's just a lot more love.
The only problem is they don't have like
ways to save each other the way we do.
Right?
Like they don't have cars,
they don't have modern weapons,
so they have to hunt with these bows and
arrows.
They make themselves,
but they do have pots,
they have some things,
you know,
but also depending on what tribe
obviously,
and also your life expectancy is
probably not as long.
So if you do die and you believe in a
higher power,
then get to go see them quicker.
You probably have reincarnation,
your,
you know,
your friend that died could now be a
plant or a coyote that you made or
something.
You know what I'm sure in a lot of their
cultures it's a lot of,
uh,
you know,
there's just,
things are more just all intertwined,
you know,
human in nature without was big with
native American cultures.
Right?
Like they thought that a coyotes were,
I mean,
in many different,
uh,
different tribes,
the way they looked at coyotes,
almost like they had some magic to them
or something.
Yeah.
Or wise.
They're up all night.
I mean,
I could see that.
Yeah.
You were in that tent sleeping,
sleeping off that Hashi shy.
So
a coyote got trapped in a bathroom.
I want to say it was in South Carolina
or North Carolina.
There were wild man in this bathroom and
these guys have to get it out of the
bathroom and sitting on the sink.
It's crazy.
And they had to use one of them long
poles that the Jack Dogs,
you know,
like grammar on the neck.
You see it.
I knew it was one of those places in
Nashville.
Yeah,
I could see that.
Dude.
It's a cool little video,
but it's weird.
Like those little fuckers are everywhere
now.
They are everywhere.
Well,
raccoons are really dangerous.
They're always doing,
you know,
Jerry,
the salad,
the Nashville Music Hall.
Oh,
this beautiful southern in this hall.
A boat show or the coyote in the
bathroom.
Look at him,
make sure he's chilling.
He's,
they're very photogenic.
Coyote wild life will continue pushing
to how weird.
So what they did was they captured it
and they said that if they brought it to
an animal shelter,
they would have euthanized it.
Hmm.
So instead they captured it and let it
loose in the woods.
Which school do you have any animals
that you don't tell people that you
have?
Like any secret?
And I'm like,
keep a lot of giraffes night.
You really though.
They keep him under leading shit.
I can see you having something now.
No.
Have you thought about it?
I used to have paranas allegedly.
And what do they keep in a tank?
Yeah,
you keep me in a tank.
You know,
you used to be able to buy a human
skeleton online is,
have a human skeleton at the bottom of
my parada tank.
Really Weird.
Is that you buy a skeleton and what can
you do with it?
I don't think you can anymore.
I bet you can't buy them anymore.
But you used to be able to just by human
skeleton.
How long can you keep it the whole time?
Forever.
Fuck.
Who Was it?
Um,
here's the funny thing.
I got rid of it and we'll get rid of it.
I'm like,
man,
I'm gonna throw away this human
skeleton.
This,
it's a question.
It's might come with this.
You would think it'd be like a cabbage
patch doll.
Look,
it comes with a little birth
certificate.
We buried it,
which is even worse probably because
then people are going to be like,
what the fuck is someone?
Someone got killed here?
Yeah.
Someone's going to find it someday.
Go,
what the fuck?
It's going to be a giant mystery.
That sounds fun.
I always love mystery,
man.
The thing is somebody might've died like
they might've.
Somebody might've killed somebody and
sold bones.
It's probably one of those real,
how am I?
Is that,
what does it say?
let me look at this.
Say Male from India in good condition,
12 teeth present.
The rest broken missing.
There is lipping on the lumbar
vertebrae.
What?
That's $5,000.
You could buy a fucking human skeleton.
Holy Shit,
dude.
There's several of them for sale,
so the lumbar vertebrae lipping.
You know what that means?
I think that means that her biz back's
fucked up.
Excuse me.
And what happens is the discs
themselves,
the lumbar vertebrae,
the actual vertebrate dog bone piece
from waring against each other,
it starts to spur and develop like a
curve to the bottom line.
I think they're calling that lipping.
See if that's what that means.
Lipping lipping on the Lumbar Vertebra.
Lipping living on it.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I got bad.
Let's see that.
Yup.
That's what it is.
Yeah,
I see that image upper left,
left right there.
Yeah.
See how it curves over the top.
Oh yeah.
Osteo,
Osteo fight.
Osteophyte grading or lipping.
Yeah.
See as your disc get smashed your bones
trying to protect themselves and they
grow this extra bone tissue.
And sometimes that,
obviously I'm not a doctor and if you
are a doctor,
stop yelling.
I don't know what I'm talking about.
But uh,
sometimes people,
that shit causes sly Attica.
Oh.
Either inflamed disks poke out and poke
into the nerves or the bone pokes it or
it causes inflammation in the area.
Eddie Bravo has that.
He does.
Yeah.
He Bravo had had his,
uh,
he got his whole disc replaced with all
five s one disc.
Yeah.
Wow.
He gained an inch in height too.
Did he really did,
was backs all fucked up.
So like you gotta think like your discs
are these things,
right?
These little gel things and there's
probably a bunch of them and they bust
when they smash and get smashed down to
nothing.
I mean,
he was basically bone on bone.
He had almost no disc.
And so he was in a constant state of
inflammation that still horrible.
I need a text.
Like he couldn't,
he couldn't sit down.
Sometimes he'd have to stand up and he
would have to hold his lower back and he
does dealt with the pain forever,
but it was like almost nothing there.
So they replaced,
so it's bones were on top of each other.
They a place that and put his thing,
they shove it in their fucking two
story.
Ettie suddenly he's like,
I'm buying new shirts.
He's,
um,
but he actually is no longer in pain.
That's what's amazing.
And this is an articulating titanium
disk.
So they used to have to fuse your
vertebrae together.
Yeah,
that's what I've heard of.
They don't have to do that in every case
anymore.
Sometimes they still do it for some
reasons,
you know,
doctors that know what they're talking
about.
But for many people now this
articulating titanium disk is now an
option.
I don't know.
Yeah,
I know.
All five s one surgery,
part of it taken out.
How bad is it?
Was it hurt?
It hurt bad.
Yeah.
Now it's better.
No,
it's better now.
But sometimes I have sciatica though.
Um,
do you ever stretch it out?
Yeah.
Do you ever use one of those teeter
inversion tables?
Um,
now I just got something free from you
guys though,
in the lobby.
What's that thing called?
Pro formas or whatever.
Right?
Oh,
that's a so,
right.
That's so awesome.
So awesome massager.
Isn't that great?
So,
uh,
that's this muscle here.
I'm going to come on that thing and
thing feels fucking good,
bro.
Sorry Bro.
And thinking feels good.
You are so horny today.
Either I had to dry.
It's like 20 minute drive up right here.
Get hyman,
nothing like driving,
you know,
I'll say this,
things that get me a rec these days,
driving being on planes,
you know that uh,
bumpy roads
killing those bumpy roads owners.
There's a real,
you asked me one time ever they had a
lady,
uh,
I felt like I got an erection on a plane
and she got pissed.
She told the,
she told the flight attendant to get me
a blanket.
Well did you have it out?
No,
I was asleep and it was in my pants.
It was in your pants and she saw it
somehow.
Yeah,
she saw my pants cause I wear lean
pants.
Lean pants are,
you know,
I wasn't wearing like a,
like a fat suit canvas or anything,
you know,
textiles,
shower.
That's crazy that she's looking over it
crazy though.
But I guess if I was a woman and a dude
had a rock hard boner,
just like a couple of fee,
I would know.
That's like a ticking time bomb.
Like,
Hey,
all right,
but I'm on a plane.
I'm going home.
Yeah,
but what if you're a pervert?
I am a pervert,
but I'm still just going home and not
using my Dick went on him.
What kind of scale of a pervert are you
if like 10 is jerking off in front of
people on the subway with a true,
not that I have a friend that's a
flasher though.
Well,
you this flashes and those flashes at
jerk off on Pete.
He doesn't do that.
That's,
that's 10 and then nine is a flasher
that just pretends to jerk off in front
of you.
It doesn't finish or can't get hard,
and then you've got to go back from
there.
A softball five.
What do you look at?
Three?
No,
I think,
I mean I guess perverted tendencies like
would,
I guess it's like what is perverted?
Yeah,
well,
it goes back to the porn talk.
Like you said that you had a problem
with porn,
you were watching too much porn.
It became a habit for me.
That's what I didn't like.
It became a,
instead of me wanting to watch
pornography became,
oh,
I'm used to watching pornography at
night,
so I'm going to do it right,
jerk off and get a little bit of rest.
I didn't like the habit,
but it created a bad habit.
Well,
you,
uh,
you get real,
intense thinking about things.
Yeah.
Like even when we're talking about like
business stuff,
like you can tell like you get,
you focus on things,
which is good.
If it's good thing,
you know.
But sometimes that kind of thinking can
get away from you.
Yeah.
I think it does sometimes for now,
the same kind of focus that can get you
really excited about something that's
productive in your life can also get you
obsessed with something that's not
productive.
It's the sec,
the kind of person that you are and a
lot of performers,
you're an impulsive,
creative person,
impulsive,
creative.
People sometimes get caught in ruts,
you know?
And there's a bunch of different reasons
I think for,
for addictions.
I think there psychological addictions,
it's physical addictions.
Some of them are undeniable,
like physical addictions.
Some of them will kill you.
Like you get off of alcohol too quick,
you'll die.
Yeah.
It's a physical addiction that is real.
And to your point,
you can't pretend it's not real.
That shit will kill you.
Right.
So it's obviously real,
but then there's other ones like washing
your hands too many times,
like some people are addicted to washing
their hands.
I know,
Dude.
It doesn't go anywhere without purell
everywhere.
Wash his hands.
He's putting pray.
It's crazy.
She's hands is linked to touch door
knobs,
put touches,
doorknob,
purell back to the hands.
It's weird.
And you,
you fuck up your skin flora like it's
not good.
Yeah.
We had a dude that used to lick both of
his shoulders for,
he'd start talking to me.
Oh,
that's good.
That's good.
That's a let motherfuckers know your
serious.
Oh yeah.
That's an Irish.
Hello.
Right.
Well whoa.
Wait,
where were in crazy town.
You're the mayor.
Lucky doing you lick your shoulders.
We had to do it in our town.
He put like a chocolate on your shoulder
and you try to get it off the heat it
off.
That's not right.
That guy's going to grab you one day and
fuck you.
Well,
he did get in trouble for something.
I don't remember what it was.
I had grown up,
but he's,
he's like one of those angler fish.
He's tricking you.
Yeah.
He's getting you to look at that,
huh?
It's going to get you had come looking
for that chocolate.
You did it off my shoulder,
my shoulder.
Boom.
He looked down.
He's got a bat in his hands.
Well,
if you said it's like you on that play,
get your chocolate.
Come get you shot.
Just chuck this.
But here's the thing.
Here's the thing is if you put it pops
with Stevie wonder movie,
just did it.
Just kind of get my neck better.
I'm trying to get my neck longer,
but I'm wearing a little bit of a neck
brace sometimes at night.
Stretching it out.
It's just tight.
My neck feels kinda are not tight.
It feels short.
Yeah.
Have you used those things?
The harness that goes on under the Chin
and you attach it to the top of the door
and you pull on it.
Click,
click,
click.
I've seen those.
Those are great.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
If you have a tense neck.
I'm a big believer in that kind of
spinal decompression.
Yes.
There's a lot that,
yeah,
you can get that.
And I got a really good one out here to
two really good ones from that teeter
company where you put your waste on one
of them and you lean forward and it
stretches your lower back.
And the other one you hang from your
ankles.
It's really good for it.
It feels good to it alleviate cause it's
just like that compression of life.
Sick of it.
Yeah.
Smushing you down.
And it's very rare that you'd do
anything that like I have a terrible
problem.
Slumping.
I've always slumped.
I've always been,
I've always had shit posture for
whatever reason and it's not good.
Like you're supposed to sit up straight.
Yeah.
You know you're supposed to your back.
It's supposed to be straight so he can
be like a,
sometimes I like,
I sit like this so I'll talk to people
and I'd be like that.
Like my head is forward.
It's like just very bad for your back.
Like you're making your,
your disks carry your weight in an
uneven way.
What you want to do is have everything,
everything up and strong.
Obviously this is exaggerated,
but most people like you get lazy.
So what,
what,
what good posture is,
is like a constant state of exercise.
That's what good posture is.
Cause you want to just slump.
I slump all the time man.
But yeah,
but doing posture all the time,
it feels like you're always like,
you know about to graduate.
I feel like you always have to be like
kind of like,
you know what I'm saying?
That that's why it's what it's like,
but you don't have to be exaggerated,
but you really should.
And I've been trying over the last few
years really hard to do that.
Just to see straight.
I need to get an alarm for my spine.
That's it.
That's the Shit I love.
That's called the,
the teeter decks inversion.
That's uh,
one of my favorite things ever for a
loosening up your lower back.
Really decompressing and yeah,
I've got one right here,
man.
And it's not prohibitively expensive
either.
I'll hop on that before I leave.
Yeah,
that thing right there,
that thing when you go down,
when,
when it a press play so you can see how
it works.
You hang down like that and when you
hang down like that,
it just lengthens everything and
straightens it out.
And that's the one where you hang by
your ankles.
I love that too.
Although it's cad,
it looks good.
Right?
I cannot even imagine they have that.
Oh good for you.
I've got one right here,
but really it felt like something you
would do to kill a deer or something.
No,
that's,
that's a different kind of thing,
man.
That's wild man.
I need some stuff.
I don't think I need to get more,
you know,
bars and stuff like that to hang off of.
I've got to alleviate some pressure for
your shoulders.
Like Chin up bars,
grab a hold of a chin up bar and just
hang.
Hanging is really good for your
shoulders because everything gets
compacted,
everything gets like bunched in and
nothing's stretches out.
They'll look a conestoga wagon brother,
you know,
that can still go out again.
Conestoga.
What does it Conestoga wagon?
It's like a wheel base is really
questionable.
It's like six by six,
you know?
Like I'm not that far.
You don't move that good.
I mean,
I think I used to be able to,
but I got to go on to the past,
Bro.
You're still young enough to move like
that right now.
Yeah.
I need to think.
Oh,
that's a conestoga wagon cheese like
that.
Imagine if you just decided that's how
you're going to rocket from now on.
You're on the highway.
People are beeping at you.
Get Your Mobile,
Ronnie.
He had a wooden wheel,
the wagon dragging behind your ram
pickup truck.
A fucking a bar goal just falls out the
bag.
You got a Silverado Chevy Silverado
pulling a fucking covered wagon.
They'd be like,
you can't do that.
Why not?
Cars registered?
This is all legal.
Ooh,
fuck is buying wagons these days.
People will find them today.
Oh,
the wagons coming back is this,
these fucking assholes that want to
reenact the civil war.
Want to get out there and a wagon and
pretend there's still slavery.
Well,
here's the thing though.
I understand.
Reenacted it in the winter,
but they do it in the summer,
man.
Do they really?
Yeah.
You don't want to do in the winter,
you'll die in the south.
Always wins the reenactment too,
which is wild.
No,
it doesn't really.
Yeah,
and so real.
I think there's a little bit of,
you know what they should do?
They should reenact the civil war and
killed themselves.
Not In real life,
but in the,
in the fake.
You mean pretend hey man,
I don't want to fight for slavery and
just all pretend to kill themselves.
Yeah.
Oh,
that's interesting.
Yeah.
They would say,
hey,
we're going to,
we're going to do it the right way,
or we're going to toss down our guns and
suck all the Dicks of the guys in the
north that they would one that did have
one.
If they have said that
they don't want,
if that,
it'd be like a,
if they catch us [inaudible] be like,
here's what you want you to feel good.
And then one,
apologize because they need the
nutrients.
They're out there starving.
But I was thinking about this.
Do you think that so slave rewrite,
right?
They had it.
Do you think that would,
if I had this thought of one day,
what if computers,
artificial intelligence happens.
Okay.
Takes over and then they're all going to
know that we had,
we own these phones.
Yeah.
Just like people like they were saying
like this was a slave,
like remember when you owned my little
buddy.
You're emotional about that.
I see where you're going with that.
But I disagree.
I don't think that'll be an actual
factor.
I don't know.
I got the rose gold one now.
I do none of that.
But you've got a black case on it.
That's ridiculous.
Yeah,
that's true.
If you go in rose gold,
I think you have to go case list like a
brown,
like a sap.
I'm not going caseless man,
look,
get Jamie caseless.
Jamie's a case was barbarian.
Wow.
I bet he jerks off of this fucking his
natural hand.
I got a cute case.
My,
my kid drew on it.
Oh,
that's nice.
Huh?
Adorable.
Um,
do you see your kids every day?
Yeah,
sometimes I keep my eyes closed.
This is,
that seems fun.
And having kids style,
oh,
podcasts is it nurse did.
Were you nervous at first to have him?
Yes.
Yeah.
Nervous to be vulnerable.
Nervous to love something that much
nervous to have that kind of
responsibility.
Nervous about all those things.
Yeah.
Changes you change as you like nothing
else.
But did you feel like the changes would
be for like a,
that you won't like the changes and then
you did like,
I'm like,
did you have reservations?
Well,
I didn't have a relationship with my
father growing up,
so for me it's very,
it was very,
very important that I did whatever I had
to do to have a relationship with them,
to be as present as I can be till I took
whatever,
whoever I was beforehand them to,
to evolve to get better.
Like it's,
it's,
it's a very,
when you have kids,
it's a very weird thing what happens to
you because you all the sudden it's,
you're not alone anymore.
Like you,
like you,
you don't just have responsibility.
Like you have a dog,
you have to feed or a plant.
You have a little person and you don't
want to fuck up that little person.
You're like shit and it feels
overwhelming and then the world feels so
dangerous.
Change the view of the world.
God,
there's so much threat.
There's so much out there that could
stop signs,
planes,
stories to you read stories about
terrible people and terrible things that
happen.
Oh,
and then you're like,
fuck,
I don't have to worry about,
this just happened to me afterward when
this happened to know somebody else to
then your little,
your little daughter,
you know?
Yeah.
That's wild bro.
That's crazy world and you,
you think of people differently because
you think of people as a project that
developed instead of being in a static
state.
That's interesting.
Did you,
did,
do you think that something like a
emotionally happens to you like at a
level that the DNA level?
Yeah,
the love you have.
Like Dave Chappelle said,
this best goes not only to do increase
my love,
it increased my capacity for love and
that's a great way of putting it.
I would,
I would agree 100%.
It increases your capacity.
You become an eye,
at least me,
I became a nicer person,
but I've seen it not work too.
I've seen people that just reject it.
I've seen men and women that just don't
want to be parents.
I've seen women move away from their
kids.
They don't want to take care of their
I've seen men abandoned their families.
They just don't want to do it.
It's crazy.
I don't know if it's a mental health
issue or if it's just,
some people just can't take it.
He never like,
there's like attitudes and this is not
just about raising children's about
pretty much anything difficult in life.
There's some people that have a very low
quit point,
very low.
They just quit everything.
They quit.
It gets tough,
quit,
quit.
There's a lot of people that just quit.
And uh,
when you have a little like say if you
have a little theo in front of you,
when you think about your life and your
childhood and like how important it is
for you to,
to raise this little person and give
them love and teach them about life and
protect him and keep him safe.
And give them good lessons in life.
Yeah.
It just changes.
Everything,
changes,
everything changes everything.
But it also has to brave.
Overwhelming.
It's overwhelming.
People get serious anxiety when they
have kids.
They start thinking about the
responsibility and the weight of it all
or they don't.
Some people just fucking take pills and
lay on the couch and let their kids
suck.
Fucking carpet glass and the fucking
stick forks into the wall sockets and
play with knives.
People just don't.
Some people don't give a fuck,
but some people are dumb.
That's a,
that's a thing too,
man.
I,
you know,
people don't want to say this,
but there's folks out there that just
aren't equipped for life.
I really believe that.
I think dee come the dumb brother.
That's what I'm saying.
Take the semen of him.
You know what I'm saying?
Like at a certain point,
but here's the problem.
You're dumb compared to physicists.
So who's the WHO's to judge and who's to
say that this person is really stupid?
Couldn't have a brilliant child that
happens to men.
A lot of times,
brilliant people come out of stay,
need adversity.
Man Who knows what they need,
but it's like,
it's not our job to decide who's stupid
and who's not because it gets slippery.
Yeah.
You,
you could get boxed into that stupid
corner in a different metric.
If you're hanging around with a bunch of
people from Stanford and they're looking
steel,
vons,
the neighborhood,
and they know there's 10 people in the
neighborhood,
but only nine can survive.
It's only resources for nine paying to
get rid of me.
Probably.
It depends on how good you are digging
ditches
all it could be better than him at that
though.
Yeah.
So suddenly I have a different scale.
I Dunno.
It's a,
have you thought about having kids?
Yeah,
I think about it a lot more.
Like as I get a little bit older and I
just,
yeah.
The thing for me is just like about
being brave,
I think,
and just being willing to have my life
just be totally different and be okay
with that and just being like willing to
know that I will be okay in that space,
you know?
Um,
I think it's our,
uh,
it's like,
I just,
it's like I'm just starting to manage
this space that I'm in like as just as a
regular person and then to get to that
point where now it's like,
fuck,
you have another ball,
you have two balls in the air,
you know,
wife and a kid or,
yeah.
And then what we were talking about
earlier,
like sometimes people fuck people that
they don't really like to hang out with.
Yeah.
I'm not doing that anymore,
man.
That's where it gets slippery because
sometimes that sex is fun,
man.
I was just talking to a buddy of mine
about this.
He's got a,
a Gal,
he's a single guy and he's got a gallery
Fox.
Every now and again they get together
and they both kind of know what it is.
Yeah.
They get it together and they whack one
out and then they see ya.
That's it.
And his,
his take on it is interesting.
He's like,
yeah.
And some people you just don't want to
see him that often.
Like that's okay.
That's okay.
But the problem is it's not always
mutual.
Sometimes the guy wants to see the girl
more than she wants to see him or vice
verse and then it become some weird
thing.
One person starts talking the other
person's facebook.
You know,
people start getting weird with people,
you know,
like that's,
that's actually an addiction too.
People get addicted to each other just
as much as they get addicted to
pornography.
Just as much as they get addicted to
wash their hands or anything else.
People absolutely get addicted to
certain people.
And when that person doesn't want to
have sex with you anymore,
like it's like they're taking away your
drugs,
you know,
and really dumb men and in those cases
get very dangerous.
Cause Daca is.
Yeah,
they,
they start thinking this person's done
something to them because they don't
want to be with them anymore.
And really dumb men are dangerous right
there.
That's where you know,
you,
you hear about women getting stalked by
their axes and murdered and that's where
that should come straight.
That really dumb men who are angry now
that the person that they loved doesn't
want to be around them anymore.
Yeah.
And they can't look at themselves and
they're probably mentally ill and they
might be on medication.
Who the fuck knows what trifecta or what
conglomeration of factors is making them
be that piece of shit,
but yeah,
they just feel,
yeah,
I want you to,
yeah.
He may get a feeling they get,
they feel rejected and then you just
want to,
yeah,
you don't know what to do.
Sometimes you get addicted to somebody
else's love or lust or saks,
all those things.
Women to men.
It's dangerous.
It too.
I was talking to a gal who was going
through this with another Gal,
a couple of lesbians,
couple of lesbian scene.
I'm talking about,
boy,
the Lez one lesbian was mean to the
other lesbian.
Apparently I was referring at furniture,
you know what I'm saying?
Boy,
domestic abuse.
There was some article about domestic
abuse.
It's growing and lesbian community.
Yeah.
It's disturbing.
It's a dark arts man and those women
are,
and some of those women are tough.
You think tough as nails.
What'd you find?
A lesbian for?
An undisclosed amount of money.
Yeah.
Really?
You don't even have to hear that.
The number.
What is undisclosed?
Do I get to hear it or I don't know
until it's over.
You're just ready to fight women?
No,
I'm not.
Can I train for hearst?
I wouldn't like Amanda Nunez.
I wouldn't let you find out.
No.
Yeah,
it has to be a woman.
At least.
I've seen a couple pictures of them.
You know,
like I,
they don't want to be able to make sure.
Yeah,
I've seen like a couple of images of
them or at least being able to scroll
through their instinct.
You see that video of that grown man who
punched out 11 year old girl in the face
of the mall.
That shit makes me mad.
[inaudible] he's so crazy.
There's a bunch of kids apparently that
were involved in some sort of a scuffle.
This guy comes over to break it up.
He's yelling at them,
break it up or get up.
One kid pushes him and then he says
something and then pushes the girl.
She goes flying.
She's a little tiny person.
He's a big dude.
She comes at him with her dukes up and
he just fucking way laser.
I didn't see it hits her with a straight
left right in the mug and he's a big
grown man like a,
he looks like a big man.
Who knows how to throw a punch.
I'm not going to play the video.
Do you want to find it?
Go find out what I want to see it
fucking disturbing.
But two things.
Did she tell you one?
That guy definitely shouldn't have done
that but to,
she shouldn't have fucking run at that
big giant man with their dukes up like
God,
I know she's 11 I know I get it.
She didn't know she's a kid and sat down
to teach kids and some 11 kids are
hardy.
Some 11 year olds are like,
what if you get a Ho like I knew at 12
year old that snow.
No,
she's this big.
Oh,
she's little.
She's tiny.
She's like nipple high on him.
Oh yeah.
Kaos her.
You want to see it?
No,
you do.
You do want to say it.
Draw it for me on a Napkin.
I don't want to see it.
Yeah,
those are the old days,
man.
I remember they had a guy who chiseled
some tits and new,
uh,
um,
had a pint.
You may,
maybe a birch or something and people
would go out there and you're a cough
drop off at the base of the tree.
He,
I think he used like a step stool or
something or sound on a barrel.
That's when you found all the magazines
in the woods.
Oh yeah.
We used to have that.
But as you go out another tree and
somebody will be using the tree and be
like,
Oh fuck,
I've got to walk back home now.
It's 100% real.
You're making this up.
You have a photograph?
This tree?
No.
Why not?
Do you know where it is?
Could you take us back there with a film
crew?
I could take you back there with a film
crew.
I bet.
I bet it's devolved now though.
A trade live,
go back there and touch the thing and
all of a sudden you can't find your way
back.
Where the fuck are we?
How does,
we're going in a circle.
Like it turns out that the tree got
tired of people jerk off on it so it
evolves some sort of a neuro toxic.
Then when you touched it,
it got into your bloodstream.
It distorted your perception of distance
and time.
Then they go scale,
but do what if you would've come,
could divide.
They would have semen,
could defy gravity.
What do you think about that?
I don't,
but you know what?
I do think.
Imagine if it wasn't,
if come didn't just get humans pregnant.
Yeah.
No.
That's what I think of.
Imagine from frogs to chickens.
I give every way you went.
You found God.
Just do it.
Fucked a turtle.
You followed some turtle person.
He got fucking,
you can't think about that man.
If anything could get anything pregnant
and a new combination was born turtle
people too.
That's what's next.
Coy People.
Some do fucked a coy Boston's that cory
mom.
Not that we imagine you're out there
throwing bread on your Koi pond.
You're like,
hey,
it has legs.
What the fuck,
man?
Somebody fuck one eat fish.
People signed up on the shore.
It's got a sign for you
to,
people see people see you at the pet
store shopping and they're like,
Whoa,
this guy's shady is smashing.
If Ari fucked it and it came out and we
knew it because that always knows.
So it's like always knows on a Koi fish
with legs and it comes out and you're
like,
no,
your business.
I'm going to Bali.
You Imagine?
Yeah,
I'm going to,
can we go find where my turtle babies on
the other side of the world.
But if you had to make love to an
animal,
what would it be?
If he think he had to go in and they'll
be something I could brag about.
Yeah.
I'm not fucking anything sedentary.
I'm not fucking anything that's like a
basic,
something ends up in the poultry section
or anything like that.
No beat half to be a female.
What have you had gay sex with an
animal.
Which animal would it be?
That's not gate a fucking animal,
Bro.
It's not,
I don't think that applies to your
fucking an animal that's more important.
If it's like a male gorilla,
I think it's both hot dude.
Gay and beastiality.
Nobody's seen to be like,
oh,
remember when you get,
they would then have been let you off.
The people are mean.
They're going to go.
Not only did he fuck a chip,
he fucked a mail chimp and everybody
would be like,
Jesus,
theo,
bro,
you would never buy a beer again.
You put you on a break,
the Internet.
You put a fucking video of me sneaking
up on a Cheetah and fucking it.
Well,
I will wrap it.
A noose around its neck and you're
banging it while it's clawing on yet.
Let's try to get away and you nut.
Nah,
I'm talking about putting on some Eddie
levert or some Gerald levert and playing
some sweet music and just lay in there.
How do you plan on holding it in place
while that's all happening?
I think if you're good enough and
general enough,
it'll stay.
Wow.
You don't think so?
Think about it to you for a managing it
though.
I love to look at the world through your
eyes,
right to the hospital,
whatever medication where on.
We got to change it.
We've got to fix this,
bro.
You shouldn't beat yourself then,
Bro.
You are extra terrestrial man.
This is the most,
I smiled all week though.
So good.
Oh Dude.
We always have a good time,
bro.
That's funny.
Are you working tonight?
You do in Tripoli shows?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
That's fine.
Those are good times.
Do what a fun job,
man.
I just started really realizing it this
year.
That's what I was saying.
Like your idea of like looking back on
your youth.
Are you crazy?
We're alive.
Doing the most fun job you could have.
Yeah.
Well how would we change that?
You want to get busy?
I want to like,
you know,
get busy live in this year and just try
more things and just,
you know,
enjoy my time.
That I,
that I am alive.
That's what's up.
I really do the,
the whole thing about life is all that.
I wish I was doing this or I wish I was
doing that is only good if you're
working towards something,
but I wish I was young again.
Let that go.
That is not happening.
Yeah.
I wish I was eight foot tall.
That's not happening.
I wish I could fly.
I wish I could breathe underwater like
aqua man.
It's not happening.
I could see paying to get Gill's
installed though.
I could see you coming up one day.
They get come up with some gene editing
some gills like damn man.
Fuck scuba diving.
It takes you to the side and shows you
his gills.
I don't like snorkeling bro.
Yeah,
that shit.
I snorkeled a little bit when I was in
Hawaii.
It's fun man.
It's wild.
You're out there looking down.
You watched all these fish swimming
around like did we went near this coral
reef.
It's crazy cause it's just this world
down there to post.
And how easy was it for you to black
ops?
Like sharks or something?
Just not out of the blue.
We're not easy.
No,
no.
This real like you're always thinking
like what if one of those motherfuckers
is here?
Oh,
and you look like a Dell,
like a damn delectable event to a shark
who definitely thinking like a mouthful.
Oh,
but yeah,
I mean,
you know what I'm saying?
If,
if joe's out there,
that's a,
that's a real snack.
How many famous people that have been
killed by sharks senator happened?
That'd be crazy.
I feel like ll cool j got killed by a
shark and Malibu.
You'd be like,
what the fuck?
He know.
He'd be like,
well,
how was that real?
How could it happen?
Right?
What if Oj Simpson got Jack by a shark?
Can you imagine how many Haas would
break out across the country?
Ha.
If you could see Oj Simpson Info,
it would have to be Florida.
He'd be,
he's in Florida.
A lot of her,
of course I was white trash girl.
I'll fucking,
he's waving,
waving to the beach and you just see the
Finn like 15 feet away from him.
If he go under and then they yank the
blood in the water.
Like no way
did I miss Oj Simpson and Dennis Rodman
and fucked a lot of the same chicks,
Bro.
When you think about that,
what if,
what if the kid,
well,
I don't think Oj Simpson's allowed to
leave the country,
right?
I was saying,
what if Kim Jon wound starts partying
with Oj?
It's like,
I don't care.
I don't care what he did to the Jews did
loose.
A buddy of mine was doing cocaine with
Oj Simpson one time and and in Miami.
How long ago?
This is like 15 years ago.
Posted murder then?
Yup.
After the murder and the guy goes,
hey,
does anybody have a car key?
And an ease hits Oj.
He's like,
Hey,
you have a car key or a knife?
That's what he asked him for to do the
cocaine off of.
Oh,
she knows.
She's like,
this guy's a fucking knife.
Was He laughing?
Yeah.
That's pretty funny.
I think it's funny.
I mean if you didn't get in trouble for
it,
even if you did it,
I think having a sense of humor about it
still important.
The way he reacted every step of the way
did not seem like a guy who was being
accused of something.
He didn't do every step right.
Every step of the way,
so I wouldn't do that.
Oh,
I couldn't do hard.
Don't even matter.
That is not what you'd say if your wife
got killed.
Right.
He would not be thinking like that.
You'd be hard for a freaking the fuck
out.
I know you what does exist,
but you should watch this one multi.
Oh,
Sasha Baron Cohen.
The very,
very end of the show is almost like a
bonus scene.
Oh,
I didn't know he got this deep with the
a outfit.
You spent a cow.
It's just,
it's part of his is like cell.
She's like a girl that's supposed to be
with them.
He's like this uh,
extravagant millionaire billionaire type
character.
Oh.
And he's got Oj and yeah,
I need to see this show period.
I think he spent like three or four
hours with them.
He said,
did you hear that?
They might have uncovered a pedo ring.
He might have uncovered a Pedo ring when
he was doing this.
Oh,
Jane.
Dan?
No,
Sasha Baron Cohen.
Oh Wow.
Oh yeah.
Did you see it?
I read a headline that says find what
the exact specifics of it were,
but like they decided not to air it,
but it's like what dude?
You know what,
when you said that about Oj and made me
think I met Buzz Aldrin from the moon.
Yes.
And he's,
and when I met him,
it didn't seem like he'd been to the
moon.
You know what I'm saying?
That Colin,
yeah.
Hold on a second.
Uh,
sent cut.
Who is America interview to FBI over
fears of Las Vegas.
Pedophile around but not surprised.
Whoa.
Said the sub sub said the interview led
him to believe there could be a
pedophile ring in Las Vegas.
Holy Shit.
Could you imagine of a pedophile ring in
Las Vegas
was exposed by Sasha Baron Cohen and a
comedy movie and they find out it's
real.
I wonder if this is all,
this is a setup for some other type of
film,
but let's look at objective.
Okay.
There has to have been pedophile rings
in the past.
Undeniable.
Right.
I would think if you go back,
you go back to like the 50s or the
forties and the 30s,
there has to be something like that easy
back then.
Yeah.
They take orphans and they molest him.
All that Sandusky type shit that has
been going on.
Yeah.
So how often has it been going on and
what happens now to the same type of
people?
Like if that's no longer available for
them,
is there some way they get it,
some super fucking super tightly watched
circuit ring of people who still engage
in this activity and figured out a way
to do it?
I hope not.
I hope not too.
Everybody hopes not,
but the idea that it's impossible.
The idea that it's impossible is
unlikely.
Yeah.
There's probably a market for it,
sadly.
Well,
you think about it all the time when you
think about other countries,
right?
They're doing it there for sure.
Yeah.
Most of our guys,
it seems fly over these other countries
and be dirty over there.
The idea of like going over there and
there's a ring,
a pedophile ring.
Ooh,
that's scary dude.
Who wants to fuck some kid?
That's crazy.
They think it's mostly people who have
been abused like that themselves.
Yeah,
it's mostly,
yeah.
That's one of the things that Kevin
Spacey's brothers said about Kevin is
that Kevin is basically like their dad
and their dad sexually abused them and
now Kevin is acting that out and there
was,
uh,
an interview.
His Dad,
his brother rather give her see Kevin
Spacey's brother and I never met Ron
Stewart on the strongest acid available.
Oh,
he's crazy looking.
This is so weird looking guy with wacky
hair and he wears funky glasses and
weird clothes.
Donnie,
what's his name?
I don't know what his name is,
but he looks like he's wearing a
costume.
Donny space it.
That's not it,
is it?
No,
but here it took a look at them.
Just look at this.
That's,
that's his brother.
God Dang Man.
It looks like Nice.
Scott seemed like an English scientist
and Rod Stewart.
I can't believe Kevin's one of they got
banged by the day.
I think they both did.
I think you saying they both did.
I can't believe I even said that.
It's messed up.
Yeah,
I'm sad man.
They said their dad was a monster.
Yeah.
Look at his dad like,
look,
look at this.
His brother,
how he dresses up.
Let me get that crazy rod stewart
outfit.
Yeah,
I bet.
Like one chick or one dude fucked him
because he thought it was rod stewart
and he's like,
look,
I'm just going to ride this boat riding
into the rock,
right,
stuart.
Huh?
This is outfit.
That's crazy.
Outfit.
That has a crazy,
crazy outfit.
He's got rings on every finger.
He's got a wallet chain across his
Pecker.
Wow.
Those dicks keeping time brother.
Yeah.
Look at that shirt at fluffy shirt with
the crazy ass neck accouterments.
Yeah.
If you're not trying to get fucked by
somebody,
you shouldn't wear all this at them,
but think about how much effort it took
to do all this.
Now go up to his teeth,
son.
Yeah,
What's up with that Mug at Scotland row?
Clean that shit up.
Is he from Scotland?
It's Kevin Spacey from Scotland.
I think they're from Britain.
I think they're from America.
Really?
Yeah.
Where'd,
where was Kevin Spacey?
Boring.
Fuck.
If you know you're googling it.
Well now over a year.
Now you're the guy.
He's got the Google in front of you,
but no.
What about this?
Do you think he would have been as
talented,
but if he didn't have this affliction,
where does it say?
Does it say worries from Orange,
New Jersey?
You see,
there you go.
Perfect dump.
And one of the most talented men of our
time,
I think people look in New Jersey.
Fuck you bro.
Hey,
I was born there.
He is very talented.
He's also very crazy and I think uh,
in his day you could get away with a lot
if you're were a movie star,
I think,
you know,
they just,
they ran those sets like,
oh yeah,
they were crazy.
Well they have that are Kelly thing now
and in that hook guy his whole life,
he got to do whatever you wanted.
It seemed like that's a different
animal.
Right?
Cause he's a musician.
But yeah,
it seems like he's the underage,
the under age thing with him is like
Aaliyah married,
Aaliyah underage sex with her underage,
and it was till I remember we just grew
up listening to his music.
It was,
these girls are coming out about him
doing that to then when they're here.
But a lot of people new 13,
14,
they're saying 15 w but I can't believe
more people aren't comes up.
Let's say there was a video of it.
You know that more people aren't
complicit in that.
It was unbelievable.
What about the people that are like,
well here's what's crazy.
Did the video is out of him,
peanut on people and then years later
people are still making music with them.
Yeah.
Wow.
That's crazy.
Yeah.
When you find out how many people were,
what was it?
Was it the breakfast club?
What show was it that they,
uh,
they started reading off a list of all
the people that worked with our Kelly
post video.
So the video was out,
Lady Gaga,
all these people and like a giant number
of people.
Do you think we'll ever be able to
eradicate that?
The fact that people do that too,
like,
ah,
ha the pedophile or had that vibe for
them first to sexual sexualized children
or young people.
Hopefully scientists will figure out a
way to isolate that part of human
thinking someday.
Like,
hopefully there'll be something
researchers,
doctors,
scientists,
psychologist,
whoever it is figured out a way to stop
that.
But in the meantime what it has gotten
is way more difficult for them to get
away with it.
Right,
right.
And it's going to get more difficult
still.
I think people are going to be
connected.
I mean we're connected right now with
cell phones.
Like this is how weird the connection
is.
Um,
you know Adam Green tree who was here
yesterday when we were talking about
Toyota Tundras,
he said after we were talking about it
and he said all of his ads on his phone,
like when he would look at a website,
it would all be Toyota ads.
No Way.
It's like they're listening.
Yeah.
They're listening to his phone.
Like the word Toyota Tundra came up over
and over and over again in his search
searches.
Toyota trucks,
cause we were talking about Toyota
trucks,
Toyota trucks.
I'm a say that bacon draw,
Toyota Tacoma.
Say it over and over again.
But whenever the fuck process of,
I mean I don't know if he actually
accidentally googled Toyota trucks that
day too,
but they found out who he is.
He's there.
My point is like saying something in a
conversation and it's being connected to
these internet searches.
Like these little things are starting to
happen and it's going to get more and
more prevalent.
It's over for us.
We're going to be like way more
connected now than we were going to be
way more connected rather than 10 years
and we are now,
fuck man,
we got to figure out what would that be
like because no one saw this comment.
No one saw us being disconnected.
So what the fuck is it going to be like
if we're connected much,
much more than that in the future,
what's that going to be?
And it's going to be,
it's going to be something unimaginable
cause it's this was unimaginable.
Right.
That's what I'm thinking.
It's going to be some next plane that
we're going to get to.
There has to be some next level of
intuition.
Maybe that comes into it or I,
when I was really high,
I thought this up.
Yeah.
My really high thought was,
you know how kids learn things really
easily are they will just learn things
way easier.
They can learn a language really easy.
They're gonna if very soon in the
future,
a universal language is developed that
coincides with artificial artificial
intelligence,
technology,
virtual reality,
and augmented and augmented reality.
And so this universal language allows
people of all languages.
They can learn it and they can learn it.
And this was coming off of something
that Jamie said once we're talking about
emojis being almost like hieroglyphs.
I'm like,
wow,
that seems so weird because they seem so
cute and Corny,
but,
but someone could send you a whole
series of them like eggplant water,
a smiley face,
high five,
and that's like,
oh,
someone wants to fuck.
Oh yeah.
Right.
That's my right.
Meet time to meme.
A picture could sell.
Sure.
Jack's all those things.
Well while I was thinking that I was
like,
okay,
well what would stop once they develop
augmented reality or artists or or a
virtual reality in some sort of a easily
digestible form,
whatever it is,
whether it's a chip that you have in
your body that sends signals directly to
your brain,
allows you to communicate with each
other.
If we developed a language and we can
send and receive images in a way that
may be even more effective than the
language that we assume that English is
the best way to talk cause we only know
how to talk English.
Maybe if we could speak Chinese,
we could express ourselves clear.
Maybe if we speak Turkish or Arabic,
maybe there's a better one.
I don't know.
I only know one language.
But what if w sound languages are far
inferior to visual languages and what of
these visual languages allow people that
even can't even see to see because they
could send it directly into their mind.
They can see these things with their
eyes closed and I've been using her
eyeballs and everybody can communicate
on an even plane.
So there's no language barriers.
And when I was thinking this,
I was like,
well,
that's gotta be this impossible.
No,
it's not impossible because there's more
than a hundred languages.
I mean,
how many languages are there?
If you had to guess,
I would have bet there's probably a
hundred and maybe 15 yeah,
I bet you're right.
I'll say 130 let's go crazy.
I'll say 130 locations.
There's probably a thousand who the fuck
knows language bob?
One language,
Bob.
More.
More than a thousand okay.
I'm going to go then.
I would like to have a separate guest.
I want to go with 1800 I would like to
go with 1060
that says there are roughly,
this is number of spoken languages in
the world today.
6,500
whoa.
What were home out to about 2000
those have less,
fewer than a thousand speakers,
so even if we count those off,
it's still for over 40
well,
you know those people on that central
north central island,
I think they have a dead language.
There's only 39 really?
Where that guy got killed was only 39 of
them.
4,000.
So even if you take off that 2,500,
right,
if you take those off,
the ones that he said that only less
than a hundred people or you have,
but they're using it.
Right.
Good point.
Well,
here's the thing that's really crazy.
Um,
the,
the indigenous people of Australia,
my friend Adam Green tree who was here
yesterday,
he,
uh,
he works with a lot of these people.
He doesn't like a mining company and one
of his,
uh,
like a bunch of the people that you work
with wood explained to him these
different languages that they're not
written down and you and your mob,
like they would call the aborigines
would call themselves up.
Like it's,
it's not like a clan,
it's called a mob there.
A term for it would have a totally
different language than someone who
lives just a few miles away.
So they'd be a different mob.
It was a few miles away.
Totally different language.
You can't understand what the fuck
they're saying.
They don't know what the fuck you're
saying.
Then there's another one over here and
there's never no one of the one.
I'm like,
how many do you think there is?
He's like,
oh,
it was probably hundreds,
like hundreds.
Hundreds of different languages.
Nobody knows what the fuck anybody say
it.
It's almost like they don't want the
other one to know because it's like
they'll get their secrets.
Maybe.
How many do you think there's another
report that says there's this number of
languages that are spoken in us homes as
of this as of 2015 ooh.
It's a smaller number,
but
303 50 wow.
At least it says at least 300 if you had
asked me before this conversation,
I said 13 yeah,
me too.
So I was going to guess actually I was
going to guess 11 fuck,
that's a lot of languages.
That's so crazy.
Awesome.
We're fuck no,
no,
we're okay.
That makes my point.
I think the next stage is a universal
language.
Yeah.
Universal language would like think
about the aborigines there.
That's how fucked up situation to be in.
Nobody knows what the fuck anybody
saying and none of those things are
written down.
So you have to be in that clan to
understand that language or that mob and
then they die off.
And the third thing in small,
small ball,
well they didn't think it's not planned
out well,
but we are connected.
Everyone is interconnected.
And I think through a universal
language,
it's entirely possible that we could
reshape civilization.
Yeah.
Through a universal language that every
kid picks up in school.
You teach them bing,
bong,
right?
Upside,
uh,
English or Chinese or anything else.
But being bong is the,
the,
the Internet language and this Internet
language that everybody understands.
Everybody just starts communicating
through bing,
bong and nobody,
yeah,
nobody's using regular language anymore.
He just,
you occasionally talked like when you're
in bed,
he'd talk,
you had bitch,
remember dirty talk,
English and English to talk [inaudible]
French dirty talking to Israel,
185 that are spoken just in Los Angeles.
Ooh,
wow.
That's a lot.
But that makes sense.
If there's 300 in the country,
I would,
I would think all of them would be here.
I'm more shocked at all the money.
He was pretty multicultural.
There's a group in 2,500 people or so
that speak Dutch at home in Riverside.
Oh yeah,
that makes sense.
But only Dutch.
No.
Well,
not only,
but that mostly.
Maybe I can.
That's riverside.
Dutch are so aerodynamic.
They move good.
No,
you ever seen a Dutch?
There really are dynamic.
They're the what?
What are you doing with your hands?
Lean face.
Lean headed.
Tell it not four inches.
Cheek to cheek or big people,
man.
Dude.
Do you know how big they are?
The datto,
they're very tall,
but they're very,
or dynamic.
Very aerodynamic.
Downhill people.
They call him dude.
Pulled up a dud.
Okay.
Pull up or Nesto.
Who's Ernesto?
Who's getting gander at this cell right
here.
Miss Dutch.
Kickboxer Mr. Perfect.
I bet you it's hard to kick them in the
sides of his head because he has a
little less than others.
Scott,
Dan with Donna's.
That's him later in his career too.
If you get earlier in his career,
he's more jacked.
Get earlier in his career when it's
right there.
Bam.
Take that picture right there.
No,
no,
no.
The one above it where your cursor was
to write to the right,
to the left of that one or right.
I'm sorry of that photo you just pulled
up the right of the photo.
You just pulled up that one right there.
Bam.
That's what he looked like when he was
in his prime.
Can we,
let's get a basic Dutch that guys in
advanced though,
which I feel like advanced Dutch.
Look at him.
Yeah,
that guys.
Okay.
How about rob came in.
Rob K,
a m.
E.
N.
R.
A.
N Rather,
while the greatest kickboxers of all
time and there we go.
Aerodynamic and
narrow.
His head is,
he's looking at you sideways.
What up about basic Dutch got not look
like a guy
with a narrow head,
bro.
Yes,
it does.
It get that mind.
Ah,
their head was next to his head.
You,
you,
he,
his head would eclipse your head.
No.
Yes it would.
It'd be nothing behind you.
Look how long net hit his narrow,
his head got in front of you.
I wouldn't even know you're there by
deals that you back there.
I'd see the bottom.
I feel like I'm back.
You're jerking off with my nondominant
hand brother.
It doesn't count.
Did you think it's what?
I bet if be crazy in this.
I know.
I don't know.
I'm thinking about this,
but to watch people from different,
uh,
ethnicities jerk off,
you know,
back to this again.
But you know what I'm saying though,
because everybody probably should watch
a little point and get the study.
Man.
I'm not.
Why you checking off from memory now a
younger gal from memory now,
do you find that your,
um,
fantasies become more elaborate?
100%.
They're more excited it up and just set
it up in your head?
Oh No.
It's how many days a week he'd beaten it
more than four.
And you got a problem?
No,
two days a week.
And I'm disappointed at that.
I'm just trying to turn over a new leaf,
you know,
I want to not be morning some.
Yeah.
I want to be confused.
I think that's a,
that's look,
there's a [inaudible].
There's a,
if you just look at sexual desire and
lust,
yeah,
there's a reason why you become more and
more desperate as time goes on.
It's like your,
your sights are set too high or you're
not being ambitious enough.
You got to spread your seed.
If you think about how ridiculous it is
that people didn't know that having sex
with people has consequences.
Uh,
and,
and by that I mean you can get pregnant,
you can get diseases if there was no,
and it was cultural limitations,
people frown upon it.
But if there was none of those,
and imagine how much people would be
fucking,
oh yeah.
It would be insane.
The,
or if there was no such thing as
masturbating,
you could forget a gas station.
People be fucking,
yeah.
If there was no such masturbation was
impossible,
first of all,
you know what would happen?
What women would rule everything 100%,
but it was the,
would have so much cheap built up in
him.
Nope.
That'd be bitches.
They'd be given in every chance they
could.
Cause the women would own it would be
worth so much more.
That's true.
Yeah.
Because women would be able to decide
whether or not you came.
There's the only way.
If that was the only way,
if women were the rulers and whether or
not you came,
if there was no way to come without
them,
oh my God,
they would dominate.
We're fucked dude.
I know that's going to be the next law.
If they're really smart.
That's how they would take over top our
arms off
telling me though.
You wouldn't watch like a little Chinese
guy jerk off from like 30 feet away.
Back to this again.
No,
but just to train accidents.
I don't want them to happen.
But Jamie pulls up a video of a train
accident.
Oh my God,
you got to see this one shit.
Okay,
go ahead and watch it.
Oh,
I don't watch that kind of stuff,
you know?
But tell me about this.
How close do you get?
Like there's a Chinese guy jerking off
in a park.
Okay.
And he's Ma,
he's depends on who I am.
He's Cantonese,
Cantonese,
my me.
Right now you're you,
right now you're jogging,
right?
Jogging.
You guys beating off.
Depends on how close you see,
like you stopped to tie your shoe right
and you see him in the park.
You're like,
oh,
that guy's definitely beating off and
you're about 200 yards away.
I probably would stay there.
How close would you walk to it?
I don't know.
When someone's jerking off in public
[inaudible] sir,
you have an obligation to do one of two
things.
You have an obligation.
It depends on what he's doing.
Is he looking at you and jerking off?
He's looking at you and Jurgen off.
If he's doing it out in the open,
he might be sick,
but he's turned enough towards you that
you're kind of invited I think.
No,
no,
no.
Yeah,
you're right.
If you're in the park,
this is just,
I mean,
being 100% serious.
Yeah.
If I'm running in the park,
okay,
I see,
you know,
five yards over to the side,
right next to a tree.
There's a guy beaten off.
Okay,
I'm going to stop running and I'm going
to look at him and I'm going to look at
all the people around him and I'm going
to keep an eye on him and I'm probably
either going to call the cops or I'm
definitely gonna stand there because
what if some person is jogging and he
just decides this is the time to jump on
this person?
Yeah.
What if some kid is walking by and he
snatches that kid and drags him in the
bushes?
This guy is so crazy.
He's beaten off in public and he's
looking at you.
Yes,
true.
I don't think I would go over and be
violent with them,
but I would definitely keep an eye on
him.
I'm not going to let,
what if he's a fucking sexual Predator
and he's looking to do something to
someone and you could be like Peter
Parker in Spiderman.
Save your uncle.
Yeah.
Right.
You know,
that's what made Peter Parker became
spiderman.
He saved his uncle.
Well,
he had the power and he didn't save his
uncle and a robber ran past him and he
didn't feel he had to do anything about
it.
And the robber got into the elevator and
he killed his uncle.
I didn't even know that.
Yeah,
that's just,
or no,
it wasn't an elevator.
I forget what the actual story was,
but the Robert did something to his
uncle and killed him.
His uncle was everything to him.
His uncle took care of him.
So then he decided he could never let
evil people do anything bad again and
they became spiderman.
I like that superhero.
I think,
uh,
you have an obligation,
especially if you're,
if you're a man,
especially,
yeah.
If I was a small woman and I was in that
same situation,
I would say call the cops immediately.
You know,
don't try to be a hero.
Get the fuck away from that guy,
but called the cops immediately.
But I'm pretty sure most dudes that are
beaten off in the forest like that,
they're not looking for me.
Rather they're looking for a woman or a
child.
Yeah,
that's true.
They're probably not looking to meet.
Another would tell another dude.
If I saw another dude at grabbing out
the dude for sure to help me,
like,
let's get this dude.
I'd be like,
Hey,
hey,
come here man.
This fucking guy is just beaten up
scanner.
And most men would be like,
oh Jesus,
what do we do?
We'll call the cops,
keep an eye on him.
I'm going to call the cops.
Don't let them get away.
Call Sony runs by.
Tell them to,
oh yeah,
that's a c when someone's
really crazy.
What's the ones really crazy like that
kind of crazy like some guy got arrested
for trying to abduct the kid,
trying to drag kid in his house and he
had horns on his head.
He's got horns,
he's a sexual Predator and he's got
those,
those uh,
implants in his head.
It looks like some kind of demon and is
his ears hang down to like,
it's fucking chin.
Okay,
great.
That guy's out there.
That's a real guy.
Just got caught.
Right?
So if you run into that sort of a
situation,
you know,
like you have to add as a person,
you can't just run away.
I feel like you got to stand,
you've got to stand around and make
this,
you know,
maybe make people aware of say,
Hey,
this guy's coming over trying to come
over here,
or this guy is jerking off or yeah,
yeah.
I think getting somebody else to help,
but there's less of that than there's
ever been before,
but there's always going to be some of
it.
So if you were talking about with
pedophiles,
like how do you stop that forever?
How's that possible to stop that
forever.
And we had a dude in school when I was
growing up,
this guy big Richard Wright,
and he ended up,
I mean big Dick,
that's what you call them now.
This yet,
well,
we didn't know this was before.
We were old enough to know that Dick and
Richard were the same hour.
Dick,
how about this?
How has Jack,
John,
how was short for John Jack?
Is it really?
Yeah,
I didn't even know that.
JFK,
John F.
Kennedy and Jackie Kennedy.
Jack Kennedy.
Oh Wow.
I didn't know who Jack Kennedy was.
The fuck is that.
Yeah.
There's some other weird ones,
right?
Yeah.
We're never going to get a universal
language if we can't even get that
right.
It's from Iris.
It's how you say Jack and Irish.
You got to look this up.
Really John,
since their irs that it makes a whole
lot more sense each other way.
Say John.
I believe it.
I guess if you said it fast and from far
away,
it could sound like Jack.
Yeah,
come up short for Barbara is babs.
I know a babs actually.
Is that my babs?
That's weird.
Short for Barbara.
Barb is a rough name though.
I think farm like a hook.
Yeah,
like and who wants to go weed?
Fuck Barb.
Barb means cute barbies.
Key.
Huh?
Sal is like a man's name,
but of a tour.
What?
That's a short for a while.
This other weird ones with men.
I know there's some other weird ones
that I forget.
Big Sal.
I know a lesbian named big sale.
Whoa.
What's her real name?
Sally model now.
So I used to be called Sal,
but one time she bought a man's bathing
suits and go swimming with us.
And I thought that was pretty
impressive.
No top or top no top dad.
Hey,
let's go.
She's fucking selling.
And she was in the shallow end to Daddy,
you know?
And that's a man.
That's a healthy gal.
But yeah,
I think if somebody,
I was in Germany one time,
I was on a bike ride and they had a man
swinging his dick in a big circle and I
thought that that was,
but it was a nudist area of a park.
Well,
if you've got a new this area,
that's what you're going to encounter.
People swinging dicks.
Yeah.
I guess I was kind of,
I was just sped off,
Eh,
uh,
you know,
I think about it sometimes about big
sal.
Nope.
It's about that guy in the park and what
he was doing.
Why he's doing that.
You know what I used to think?
I used to think,
oh,
look at that piece of shit now I think,
that was a baby.
Yeah,
right.
That was a baby that night became this
helicopter Dick Weirdo.
What?
Standing on the street pointing to his
hog,
spinning around spinning like that.
It's fucking weird and crazy.
It's fucking weird.
It's weird that there are people that do
that.
And how much of that is because of
repression like that would,
if you went to the most sexually
liberated country,
they have more or less perversion.
That's the question.
Right.
And how much of it is important?
Like if you went to the most sexually
liberated place,
like
yeah.
And how many of the people that come in
or people from out of town that are
weird that want freaky shit and then it
becomes an economy.
Yeah.
And how many people did you just leave
them to their own?
Just be chill.
Yeah.
Cause we're pretty caged up.
They say here in America it's pretty,
you know,
everything's kind of taboo and you can't
see nipples and stuff on television and
yeah,
it's weird.
But
yeah,
I wonder if that's also why we get so
much done.
Yeah.
You know,
like,
uh,
do we,
I mean,
maybe it's just,
maybe it's my perception that we get
more done than other that were more
productive.
I mean,
it's,
I think we focus on it a lot.
Yeah.
A lot of things have definitely come
from here,
but I think that's changing,
right?
Yeah.
But I think pedophile is going out of
style too.
I think there was a time where more
people got away with it easier,
that's for sure.
Yeah.
It's hard to get away with it,
but God,
that fucking,
that whatever that is,
that makes a person do that just doesn't
seem like we've eradicated that.
It must just be a loose wire.
And I'm,
I imagine that the thing about that is
if they could one day figure out a way
to get certain traits and breed them out
of people or engineered them out of
people,
like we're fucked then.
Well what,
what,
what would you leave in?
Yeah.
Like what,
what'd you leave in?
Yeah.
Emotional outbursts.
Would you leave in the ability to have
an emotional outburst?
Like what the fuck?
Yeah,
I would leave that.
What'd you leave that in?
That's fun.
Yeah.
It's fun for me.
But maybe you and I wouldn't be the ones
who decide.
Would you leave sneezing in?
No.
I mean behavior,
male emotional outbursts.
Okay.
Like fucking cunts.
Yeah.
Real fucking assholes.
Like that kind of shit.
That kind of shit.
Yes.
I would leave that in.
I will leave that into not a lot of it
though.
I turned it down a little.
I wouldn't fuck with it.
I don't think it's our job to fuck with
it.
Okay.
Cause you need that if a war breaks out,
right?
Yeah.
You can't have beat some guys like,
oh you don't need that and going to war.
Yeah.
You're going to need that energy you're
going to need,
it was like that whole like male
eruption fucking crazed aggression that
you don't like.
Well,
when an invading village is headed over
the top of the hill,
you want that in a dude with an ax.
Yeah.
You want that.
You want that to be available.
Yeah,
I agree.
Unless we get to a point where we don't
have any war anywhere ever again,
but until then,
like what?
But what if we engineer it out,
but the Russians say they're going to,
but they don't.
They don't.
They would do that probably.
We would do that also.
We would definitely do are so fucking
sneaky.
Do you think that we will have another
war?
I hope not,
but that's always the fear,
right?
I mean,
we're in the middle of two right now.
You know,
I think there could be,
you think there could ever be another
state warrant in America of the civil
war states?
Well,
some people were worried about that.
Some people state government,
some people want state run government.
Well,
some people were worried about that as
hate for the Republicans and hate for
trump in particular,
ramps up and that they're really worried
that there'll be some sort of a violent
outbreak between the right and the left
and that this could actually really
happen.
Man,
it's not impossible.
It's not impossible that at least
battles could break out because people
are fucking polarized,
Matt.
Yeah.
But I think what's interesting to me is
that more and more people,
it seems like,
at least from my perspective on the
right,
are now coming out against trump.
It seems more common,
more common,
especially with this government
shutdown.
People like what the fuck?
You know?
There's so many videos of people going,
what are you talking about?
What this wall like?
We need money like people or government
people.
A lot of them are living check to check.
You're shutting down there,
but this is the only way you can
negotiate this wall.
Does the only way you can fund this
wall.
This is crazy.
Yeah.
I mean it's,
I don't know.
I mean,
people always say the government sucks.
Fucking shut it down and then it shuts
down.
Everybody gets mad.
You know?
It's like,
it's makes an argument that the
government should be doing less things.
This is the real argument.
The argument is some of those things
that the government does.
Why does the government have to do it?
Why can't it be privatized?
Why?
Why can't it become a business?
It would probably run better if some of
those things we're not run by the
government like airport security or like
road maintenance or like a lot of other
things like don't have the government do
it,
have private contractors do it.
Cause I'm read,
okay.
Strong standards and strong competition.
And a John Stossel actually has a video
about it right now.
Um,
it's on his a twitter page.
It's a long video.
But explaining how,
one of the things people were realizing
from this government shutdown is that
the government does a lot of things that
they don't have to do.
Yeah.
It would be probably better for
everybody if some of these things were
streamlined.
Some of these things were done by the
private sector.
I don't think that's a bad idea.
I think there's a lot of things that
could be done better if there was
competition as soon as the government
controls certain businesses.
I mean,
maybe they do it really well and maybe
they don't.
You know,
I think the,
I think there's certain things that
were,
socialism works really well.
Like here's one fire department.
Fucking,
you gotta pay for the Fire Department.
Everybody wants to fund the fire
department.
Don't you cut the fire budget man.
What if my granny house?
Yeah.
And we once fire,
man,
we got to pay for the fire department.
Pay For that shit.
Pay for the police.
Yup.
Pay.
And everybody says pay you shouldn't be
rich.
People only get cops and poor people
don't get comps.
That's crazy.
Everyone would say that's crazy.
Yeah.
Right.
Well why is that not the case with
education to them?
Well,
right.
Don't you want people to learn things,
but when did education becomes such a
big business?
Why is that a business?
It should be our goal as patriots.
Right?
To make less losers,
more happy,
successful people.
More aware people,
more educated people,
you know.
But instead it's like subsidized by the
government and that makes it even
weirder.
And then you have student loans you
can't escape.
Yeah.
A lot of that is pretty bizarre,
dude.
It's bizarre.
It's fuck,
it should be free.
But there's also like,
there's another like a lot,
some people don't want to do anything.
They just true want to be alive and they
just,
they just,
they don't want to contribute and really
have any sort of life and they have no
desire for that.
And there's generation and generation
and generation of them
dead is true.
But what if you ever,
do you ever look at universal basic
income?
It's a weird idea.
I flatly rejected it when I first heard
it.
We have it.
No,
we don't have it.
They've tried it out in a couple of
places,
but I don't think it's really worked out
that well.
But the idea behind it,
I'm having a guy who comes on soon,
his name is Andrew Yang.
[inaudible] is a proponent of universal
basic income.
And the idea is you give people x amount
of dollars per month,
whether it's $1,000 per month and
everybody gets it no matter what.
And by doing that,
you take care of all of the burden of
survival.
Like we take care of everyone in the
civilization.
Everyone gets food,
everyone gets shelter.
So that eliminates a lot of crime and a
lot of strife just right away,
right.
Questions are laid back.
Where's all that money come from?
There's $1,000 a month.
308 million.
Is that what it was?
Plus,
you know that was 2010 it's probably
more now let's slate.
Let's say three 20 that is a lot of
money.
320 million thousand.
So that's 320 billion.
Gee,
isn't that what it is?
I have no clue.
320 billion a month when that would be
the,
if you gave a thousand people $1
million,
isn't that what it would be?
A thousand million is a billion,
right?
Just do it in the calculator,
Bro.
Don't do it in your head.
1,000.
1 million.
Yeah.
So that's right.
So it must be so that,
that's so much money.
So three.
So the,
the wall,
like him talking about building a wall,
isn't he asking for 5 billion?
Five Bill.
Okay.
It's not that much,
I don't think.
Well,
that's to build a wall once.
This is every month you would need all
those billions.
That's all a lot of fucking shut up.
And so that means everybody would be,
have their basic needs met.
Yes.
Everybody get a thousand bucks where
that money comes from.
This is what I need to talk to this guy
about.
Obviously I'm not a mathematician or any
sort of an economist,
so I don't have any idea what they've,
how they feel like they can do this 3000
it got that 3000 or more every adult in
the country.
That's a lot to stipend of two 50 a
month.
Is that Andrew Yang?
It's not from him specifically,
but it's a different guy from like a guy
that was talking bad about it actually.
He was just giving you what people were
someone talking,
talking,
talking bad about it.
Well,
yeah.
3000 a month.
There's a lot.
Yeah.
That's crazy.
That's almost,
that's crazy.
But yeah,
$36,000 a year.
That's,
I mean that would be nice.
Right then you'd be in the top 1% of the
world.
Everybody over 34 30 30 to 40,000 yeah,
$34,000 I think is 1% of the was it
would cut the nations poverty rate in
half.
Yeah.
But where's the money coming from?
And also do you lose incentive at that
point?
That's a good question.
Is that bad?
Is it bad to lose incentive?
Yes.
Why?
Because that's what it's like the drive.
It's the only reason otherwise you,
nobody ever comes anything.
Nobody achieved.
There's no,
is that true?
Is it,
is the drive,
does the drive always have to be for
survival or can the drive be the drive
to succeed and better yourself?
So say,
look at it this way.
If you have $35,000 a year,
would you think you'd be cool?
You'd be like,
I don't need a tour.
I got 35 grand coming.
No,
I'd want to work harder.
Right.
I think a lot of people would want to
work harder because I think your
motivation would be different.
Your motivation would be to do better
than $35,000 but that $35,000 would take
care of you.
Look,
if money was free and economy didn't
make any sense and you could just fix it
like that,
I would say,
yeah,
fix it like that.
Right?
Where the fuck is all that money come
from.
That's a crazy amount of money.
We couldn't do it.
We can,
I mean no,
and that means a lot of Richard would
have to give up some of their money.
People aren't doing all of that too.
That would be $900 billion every month.
Yeah.
Right.
We see when that am I right about that
300 billion.
It's for every adult.
It's not to give it to every person.
Oh,
oh,
okay.
Every adult.
Oh don't have to raise your kids.
They get the money.
Fuck it.
They get a car.
3000 no bills.
That's true.
So how many people were dealing with,
how many people are adults?
It changes too.
I,
this is the argument they make does that
you would end some of the subsidies that
are already going on like Medicare and
some social security and maybe welfare
in some cases because people would have
money that they're spending or they're
getting now.
So that money,
like,
I don't know,
I
think it'd be worth a shot.
But how long do you try to make,
you know,
cause then people are going to be like,
I needed more time in a right.
Well that would be,
they wouldn't ever get their shit
together.
There's some people that will definitely
do that.
There's some people that will never get
their shit together and I don't believe
that this is a simulation.
I don't believe that that were in some
sort of a video game,
but if we're in something that was low
that you would,
it was a learning environment.
You would want both to have your own
opportunities for failure and to see
examples of failure around you.
You would want to see that.
Like I'm not happy that Artie Lange that
his nose is caved in and then he's got
all these problems with drugs.
I'm not happy with that.
I love already laying and Artie Lange to
be clean.
I think he's hilarious.
I think he's a great guy.
The one thing that could be good that
comes out of that for anyone other than
already lang and Artie Lang's loved ones
and friends is someone that's just
looking at him online and sees what he's
done and goes,
fuck that inspiration.
I don't want to ruin this guy's in and
out of court.
He's always getting arrested.
He keeps pissing hot.
They kind of cheesy.
I was reading something today.
Well the thing is that it's,
it's,
it's sad,
it's sad and people love the guy and
you,
you see this is dangerous.
Drugs are dangerous.
Some people it hits them this way and
for whatever host of factors are these
got it bad,
right?
We love already.
So someone on the outside seeing that
could be like wow.
And that now is a thought in their head
if somebody offers them those same
trucks,
right?
And so I don't need to make my life hit,
hit rock bottom.
I can look at this guy or that guy or
maybe someone in the neighborhood or
people around you that don't get their
shit together.
You could see what happens when they
don't chase their dreams and follow
their ambitions.
They don't.
They don't take the time to let the
people around them know that they loved
them.
They don't do those things and you get
to see that.
That's a little bit of your own
education too.
It's not ideal.
Right.
Ideal would be everybody is doing great
and we would all have this big old
fucking happy community,
but yeah,
some education comes from that.
You get education from that and also,
but do you start to,
even specifically with already lang,
do you ever think that when that started
to become such a big part of his life
that I like,
I've worried that that I wonder will it,
does he,
is he going to fault her with drugs and
stuff because it keeps his name in
people's minds?
No,
I don't think so.
I don't think,
I wouldn't think people was,
he was always a successful guy anyway.
When I met him,
he was on mad TV.
I met him in 1994 the same time I met
Collin I became friends with already.
We did a scene together where I played a
boxer and he was a boxing manager.
I didn't even know that.
I didn't know he did that Shell.
Yeah man.
It's probably online somewhere.
It's wow.
He looks so young.
I was like,
I think I was 27.
Wow.
Yeah.
And he was,
uh,
probably the same age as me.
We're real close as well as Callan.
Callan is just a,
that's me right there.
That is crazy.
As a boxer.
Yeah.
Dude,
that
is crazy.
It's a joke.
Get Yard.
Come on.
I can't see that on my shoulder,
so.
Huh.
Thank you.
Cause it wasn't few old and never got
this.
Fuck God damn atrocious.
What does it feel like to look at your
young body like that?
Weird.
Is it?
Yeah,
it's weird.
It's like a different person.
Yeah,
it doesn't,
it doesn't feel like it was me.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Well you,
you look at yourself,
you know from the past.
Fuck Bro.
Already handsome guy.
Even already fucking handsome and did I
had hair,
all that hair.
It's kind of an illusion was it,
you know,
it was falling out.
It was definitely on the way.
Did you know you were going to lose your
hair?
Terrified.
Yeah.
It's weird seeing my body would know
tattoos too.
Oh,
that's interesting.
I bet that wasn't even like a
weightlifting days.
That was all martial arts days.
Dang Bro.
Strange.
But yeah,
the first time I ever heard it already
was just through a drug.
So maybe my perception of that is that,
you know,
well already,
um,
you know,
he was a very successful comedian for
sure,
from the Howard stern show,
from doing dirty work that norm McDonald
movie and a bunch of other things,
mad tv,
so many different things that he did.
He was always very successful and very
well liked in the comedy world.
If you don't like,
like if someone says fuck already line,
you'd be like,
why?
It's really cool.
Fuck are you what you don't like rd.
Yeah,
that's wrong.
He's the nicest guy ever.
It's just one of those things,
man.
You don't want to see it go down like
that.
You don't want to,
but you learn from it.
Yeah.
Other people learn from the people do
learn from it.
Other people learn from all kinds of
things that people do wrong.
You know,
you don't want those things to happen.
But man,
they're educational for all of us.
We're all in this constant state of
evolving this,
this culture that we're in right now.
The civilization is rapidly changing.
Everything is shifting and moving and
growing.
It's out of control man.
I mean it really is.
I went to a lot of elements even like,
um,
I was listening to when you and Bill
Berg were talking last time,
he's done what he's talking about like
flying around and stuff like that.
And then he was talking about doing a
comedy special and he's like,
I don't even know what to do with it
these days.
Do I just do clips?
Do I put it like,
yeah,
things just change so fast.
Whereas like a year ago or two years ago
have been like,
oh this is exactly what you do.
Make a special.
It's like,
no,
it's like do I well used to be,
you didn't have an option.
You know,
the first guy who actually introduced it
as an option was Louie,
cause Louis decided to put a special on
his website and you buy it for like five
bucks,
which is a really reasonable amount and
it was a really good special and it
killed.
He made a shit ton of money,
right?
And then people realized that he made a
shit ton of money and then people
realize how good he was and then people
realize how famous he really actually
was.
And then everything started booming and
taking off for him.
I mean it was already in the process of
happening,
but it happened even more because he did
that.
Then Netflix came along,
right?
That's the ideal.
They shook it as nothing better than
that situation,
that situation.
They just set it up.
So they put,
they're like,
we're going to get everybody.
We have a fucking trillion dollars.
We're going to get everybody.
We're going to get all the greats,
we're going to get Chappelle and Chris
Rock.
Everybody fill in the blank.
Sebastian,
they're just going to cry.
Bill Burr.
They're going to just crush it and keep
crushing it.
And then,
um,
anything else now,
like if someone has a special on comedy
central,
you go,
oh,
guess a netflix wouldn't hook him up.
You got to go to comedy central.
That's how you look at it in the comedy
community.
Right.
But I think I'm a real player is going
to be Amazon because a,
this Amazon show,
the Marvelous Mrs Maizel people love it.
It is fucking good,
isn't it?
It's good.
As a comic,
I watch it.
I get nervous.
I get anxiety when she's about to go on
stage.
I got to watch it,
dude.
It's fucking good.
The Guy who plays Lenny Bruce kills it,
kills it.
He seems like a less seedy,
less problematic.
Lenny Bruce.
But he seems a lot like Lenny Bruce.
I mean,
he's,
you know,
you can only do so much with it.
He's written in as a,
he's like a,
someone who helps the marvelous Mrs
may's Linny CD was lenny bruce cd man.
A little bit.
I mean,
it's just,
I just,
I,
he doesn't see the guy.
This is just the way it's written.
It doesn't seem like a guy who died of a
heroin overdose.
Right.
Dot.
Yeah.
He seems like more together and the TV
show.
So mostly it seems like in the sheet tv
show he seems like a victim of the
censorship of the circumstances involved
in that point in time.
More like in the future,
like he went mad,
you know,
if you ever see any of the ancient,
one of the things that I noticed when I,
when I really started getting into
standup,
I used to start,
I would watch some of the old stuff and
one of the things that I've found is
that you can,
I think I bought it as a vhs,
I forgot,
I don't think it was online.
I think it was way before youtube and
the stuff was available online.
You could get old performances and I
watched Lenny Bruce and this videotape
that I bought.
It's basically they're filming him going
over his court case in front of a group
of people.
It's really weird because he's not
really telling stand up,
he's just reading off of his court case.
It's kind of interesting and it's
interesting.
It's not.
It's like he's going mad.
It's going crazy because they're trying
to bring them into jail.
They're finding him and arrested him and
they're locking him up in jail and
they're ruining his career because he's
swearing onstage and what he's trying to
just say is like,
you know,
no,
this is,
I'm trying to point things out that I'm
swearing.
If I say something,
if I say a naughty words for a reason,
it's to express myself.
I'm not,
I'm not just just saying things because
they're illegal and I want you to lock
me up.
He went on trial for that.
Oh yeah.
Oh,
he went to jail for that.
He got arrested many times.
Many times him and George Carlin.
Look,
the reason why we can do it at the way
we do it now has a,
there's
a direct,
you could trace the path as a direct
path to lenny bruce.
Lenny Bruce started it all off.
I had to read,
I need to do some more work.
He opened the door for guys like Carlin
and prior his,
you know,
there's mort Sahl back then too,
but lending in particular,
he had an irreverence to him and,
and uh,
this,
uh,
notion to buck the current yeah.
Standard of what you could and couldn't
say.
You know,
he just changed.
He changed what comedy was brave dude.
He was a,
you know,
there's people like that,
that have these,
these figures,
whether it's Nikola Tesla for technology
and innovation,
whether it's,
you know,
there's a bunch of people like that in
this world.
Yeah.
They just change one dude's like Elon
Musk is another one,
one dude,
pow,
just whoa,
look at this.
Jesus Christ,
these,
these people that are like,
that one guy just goes off in a
direction and as a,
I think like,
I wonder if say if they went to the
universal,
um,
money for everybody,
right?
You be bi or whatever.
Don't necessarily think it's the worst
thing in the world.
But then when you have as much adversity
for people,
like would you get a Nikola Tesla?
Would you get us George Carlin?
Would you get people?
If they didn't have to look at the world
that they're born into and see not the
things be uneven and give spark some
desire.
You're not just one.
Or if we get that,
I don't know.
I think you would only have your needs
met.
I think you would still have your desire
to improve.
I think that's an inherent thing,
but I think it would be more beneficial.
This is just a wild guess.
I might be wrong.
It might be totally wrong,
and it might be,
it might,
you might be right.
It might ruin people's ambition,
but it might raise the base level,
right?
So what we're,
where we're operating from is never the
same level of desperation.
So maybe we're not as mean to each
other,
right?
But maybe the innovation still takes
place because people are always going to
want to be challenged and maybe it's,
it comes from a good place,
right?
Instead of from this constant place of
desperation,
right?
So somebody goes from a zero to a 10 in
their life,
which would it be,
you know,
somebody that does something unique and
special in outstanding.
If everybody are all automatically has
given a three their base,
then now that person's going to get us
to a 13 or maybe you just don't have as
much violence.
You don't have as much sadness.
Oh that's true because people,
yeah,
people are violent when they see they
want stuff from other people.
If your,
if your food,
if your food and your shelter is always
met,
like we don't have that.
Right.
And we've talked about earlier about
like cultures have standards and these
standards there are different everywhere
and those communities except them and
they don't like it when you try to
change the standards.
If our standards here where that all of
our needs are met,
we just,
we decide as a community if we're going
to stick together and call ourselves
America,
we should treat ourselves as a family.
We treat ourselves as a family.
We shouldn't ignore neighborhoods.
We shouldn't ignore communities that are
downtrodden.
We shouldn't ignore any kind of poverty.
We shouldn't ignore a lack
of education or lack of nutrition.
We shouldn't ignore those things.
So if we take care of all those things,
all of those things first before we do
anything else,
I've yet to reengineer America.
Would you think,
hey,
well we have to do is ramp up the
military budget by $94 billion because
we're basically arms dealers and we're
going to make these deals with Syria and
Saudi Arabia or wherever the fuck we
could sell rockets too.
It's a lot.
Yeah,
but that's what we do.
That's what we did is what we do.
But if instead someone came along and
said,
no,
the way to make this country stronger is
not make the arms industry bigger.
The way to make this country stronger is
to make the human industry better.
Right.
Make it better.
That's fine.
Tune humans.
Fine.
Tuna has done that.
Less losers.
Yeah.
2024 I liked Diovan Front for president
less.
That'd be the best.
I'll be your vice president,
Mike Pence.
I don't do anything.
I like that man.
Hang back and eat chicken.
Nice.
And all of the weird hair.
I gotta pee so bad.
Yeah,
it was that.
It kept us in your name.
Go ahead.
Good.
I'd say we're probably almost done
anyway.
It's already three o'clock.
Go Pee.
Cool.
Infographic on it.
The uh,
the UBI,
it's because there are the argument for
the positive or wanting it is a lot of
jobs are going to be replaced by robots
soon,
right?
Yeah.
These are some of the jobs there that
are at risk.
Um,
yeah.
No,
they think automation automation is
going to kill most jobs.
So insurance underwriter,
99% of jobs are at risk.
Farm laborer,
97% of jobs are list.
Wow.
Fast Food Cook,
97% of jobs at risk construction
laborer,
88% truck drivers,
79% mail carriers,
68%.
Wow.
They recently had a,
uh,
a robot cooking food,
I think it was called flippy.
They,
I don't remember where they put,
I think it was summer of the United
States maybe,
but they just fired it was the word they
use because it was doing too good.
Whoa.
Yeah.
Fired it.
Cause he was doing too good.
Yeah.
That doesn't,
I get,
I believe it.
Yeah.
That's a stupid ass ended way of looking
at it.
I don't understand that stupid shit.
Nobody's called Kelly Berger.
It was too good.
That's so,
so stupid.
That's so dumb.
It's been sidelined.
At least temporarily.
It turns out the automated fast food
worker created by me.
So robots would a victim of its own
success.
What drives 50 burgers an hour.
Wow.
So yeah.
Why is that bad?
It's better.
It's way better.
Better than you.
You don't want to work that job.
No.
Right.
That's suck at that job.
If we can find some other things for
people to do,
but you know I'm,
I'm good at a couple of things.
I'm not good at flipping burgers.
What?
You're not good at that.
You don't want to fucking mindlessly
flip burgers.
It doesn't even need a mind.
Why not leave the mindless things to the
things with no mind.
So this is the idea behind it.
But the problem is where's the money
come to take care of all the people with
the universal basic income.
And Are you saving enough money with the
robots to make it actually profitable to
pay for people hard on it
that he's sick.
Like you save more money and make more
implementation.
Well,
Andrew Yang is going to come in here and
he's going to explain all this stuff to
me in a way that supposedly gonna make
sense.
He seems really smart and he was on Sam
Harris' podcast and that worked over
there.
Man,
as most you're I've ever held,
I think congratulations.
Elicit.
How much can you hold?
What kind of car you drive?
Theo van?
I drive a BMW,
but I'm trying to get rid of it.
Figure you more for a muscle car type
fellow.
Really?
Yeah.
I used to own a 1984 ford escort and
somebody stole my passengers.
See,
God dammit.
Yeah.
What are they gonna do with a passenger
seat?
I don't know.
Probably put,
you know,
put it in the living room.
I'll be guests at the time.
Put in the forest and jerk off they can
do.
And how much comes out in the fucking
forest,
Bro?
A lot.
That's where the next,
no wonder swamp thing happened while I
was thinking this,
once they found out that in some plants
some plants contain DNA from salmon
because the salmon were used as
fertilizer by the plant.
As it decomposed,
it got into the actual plant itself and
you can actually somehow or another
through some certain scientific process
that I'm too stupid to understand.
They can actually detect salmon in the
actual plant itself.
We're close.
So if you were whacking off on that tree
and that tree,
it's every day.
That's your spot.
You went down to that titty tree and
whacked off on the roots and then like
after a while he did an analysis and you
found in your DNA,
in the tree itself,
Imagine,
Oh v great man.
If it maintains the information of
everything that whacked off on it,
you have a little son made out of wood
one day your dad,
a kid in our town one time does he got
made his son a wooden shirt that I'd
tell you that.
Oh,
wouldn't shirt.
Yeah,
he made his son a shirt out of plywood
for Christmas.
What?
Yeah.
Who wanted a kid to wear it.
Oh yeah,
he did.
And I remember I was,
um,
wait a minute,
is it a stiff shirt or is it he make it
like little itty bitty tiny pieces of
plywood and weave it all together.
Oh No,
I was pretty stiff.
And the dad was a,
um,
yeah,
like an Elvis impersonator,
you know.
But Dad was an Elvis impersonator at a
casino or did he do it at carnivals?
Not as locally.
Oh.
Um,
but we didn't even need him that,
no,
no money in it really.
I think he's probably an alcoholic,
but he had a,
he had four kids and one of them he
made,
I was going walking home one night and I
heard him in the garage and he's making
like a son,
like a sh,
like,
uh,
for Christmas,
like a wooden shirt,
like,
uh,
you know,
not as nice.
That one is nice wooden shirt.
Yeah.
Can you get what's word?
Oh,
but that's a,
like a sculpture.
Yeah.
That's nice.
Can you get one more?
That's like a,
like if you go over someone's house and
they have a wooden shirt on a hanger,
like,
and they think that's cute.
Just leave now it's people are assholes
now.
This kid needed it cause people used to
speak.
Is that salmon sculpture?
Yeah.
It's a framed wouldn't shirt.
It looks like we used to beat him up
because of his wooden.
Sure.
Know.
People used to beat him up anyway on the
bus.
Well the wouldn't.
Sure.
It would protect you from a lot of shots
and an idea and it helped.
He didn't wear that,
wouldn't sure.
You better shut the fuck.
I swear to God he did.
That kid is not walking around with wood
over his body like that.
Not Today.
That would be,
yeah.
This was her pads inside of it looks
heavy.
Fuck no dude.
I think his dad is essay loss lady.
Yeah.
See there's some lady went in there.
Okay.
But this was early.
It might've been teak teeds way too much
attention or opposing pretending to be
aloof.
Short hair by the ocean.
We're in a wooden shirt.
How about a big no,
that's a big no for me.
Hey,
do you want to meet my friend Michelle?
She's channeling with her fucking
geometrically patterned.
Wouldn't shirt on what?
No,
I like regular people.
This kid's name was Eddie.
Can you look up teak wood is teak look
like?
Imagine if someone was trying to set you
up with that Gal.
You'd be like,
well I'm torn cause obviously she's very
pretty.
You sure she's not crazy.
So desperate.
She might have a splinter that her tits
dude,
it was one photo shoot.
She doesn't wear that.
Yeah.
Except when she worships the ocean.
Now that's something a little more
malleable teak or something like that.
What are the kind of wood,
did they have over print shirt?
Now we're talking print this system.
So it was like that,
but a little bit more but more real.
And he wore this for what reason did I
section
look a chest plate?
Like a Roman soldier that,
okay.
Was it like how was it a connected on
the waste on the sides rather?
It was just kind of like a long square.
It was almost like a kind of a cereal
box.
Kinda.
What did he put his arms like?
Rest his arms on the side.
In the side?
Yeah.
Fuck your armpits up.
Oh,
is limiting.
I mean,
look man,
these weren't,
I mean the man that made it
not a real,
you can't do that.
My people would find out.
They would call him out.
We had to do when I was younger.
You could do anything you wanted to.
You know people.
People were,
I don't know,
just more fun.
It use your imagination more.
When I was young,
you have more fun.
How many kids you see beaten when you
were a kid?
People used to beat their kids.
Yeah.
Probably like at least 20 I bet.
Oh yeah.
But people will fight in the street.
Beat their kids.
Yeah.
You'd see people beat people up.
It's been way more common,
but I guess it's maybe we moved out of
those areas too,
but that's true.
People back in those areas.
Like Bro,
I'm on the front line.
Shit's still going down the mall.
Did I?
Yeah.
He used to see people fight.
Man,
I saw this old man get thrown into a
fire one time in a ditch fire though.
People were burning leaves right in.
This guy was in his eighties to Mr
Pollito.
My God.
Why did they throw him in a ditch?
He was fighting a bus driver.
He was fighting our bus driver and the
bus driver was dreaming it ditch.
Yeah.
I Dunno.
Why was he swinging on the bus driver?
I don't know.
Whose fault was it?
Both of them.
I think.
I mean,
when I'm,
you know,
they were both adults.
I mean,
look man,
I'm not surprised they were doing it.
Oh,
you know,
if humans,
yeah,
yeah.
If you saw him,
you wouldn't be shocked.
They were fist fighting.
Right.
What do you do with people like that?
Once universal basic income rolls around
and there's some stupid people that just
ain't getting any better.
Basic needs met.
Okay,
so then after that,
after you do a couple of years universal
basic income,
then what do you do?
Wolves in the woods.
Yeah,
let wolves loose.
You got to thin the herd.
It's insane,
man.
Cut some dude out there,
Jurgen off thinking he's hanging out
behind a bush.
He just turns and sees six wolves look
at up
and they just know what to do.
They said,
well,
you think a wolf would attack you while
you were jerking off or now,
fuck yeah,
you're all pink.
Everything's pink.
He has pink Dick.
It looks delicious.
When you wearing clothes,
it's like,
can I eat that?
I guess I can eat that.
I got to get through all that fucking
bullshit plywood tee shirt.
Once I get through that,
I'll beat the fuck out of that dude.
But if they catch you out there with
just all pink,
Oh yeah.
They beat the fuck out of you.
Yeah.
I hope I don't do anything bad like that
and they in any of them seeing me,
you know,
I don't want to be having that kind of
ending you get into by an animal.
I'm going to say,
I don't think that you're going to be
jerking off in the woods and eaten by a
wolf.
I might be wrong.
Yeah,
but I would say that's not how you're
going to go.
Thanks man.
I like don't see that in you bro.
I see better things for you.
I like the attitude naked.
You're packer in your hand.
Imagine if like you were about to come
and the first wolf built your cat bit,
your calf and you're like,
look,
they're going to get me anyway.
Let me just keep going and shit on the
edge.
Maybe the bite and the pain cause you're
about to cum.
You bus more than usual.
Yeah.
And you're like,
wow.
At least I died.
Biggest load ever.
Like hey,
that's one thing I've always been
disappointed by.
Right,
because the sheer volume of your loads.
Well it's not much.
If you look at it takes that next sank
and magnesium.
Yeah.
Allegedly egg whites.
I do have zinc at the house.
Actually sank.
Supposed to be good for raising
testosterone.
Oh,
I want that bus,
Bro.
The neighbors,
the more you save it up to Oh yeah,
we gather up more,
but I like to do that.
Not turn off.
I want to ride.
I want that dream bus that used to get
super bus.
Khafra Dude,
I want that dream bus.
Remember we knew would bust in a dream
[inaudible] those don't happen anymore,
but they can if you search for it,
if you seek it out,
yeah,
but you have to not beat off for a long
time.
To the point we bought it bodies like
this dumb mother fucker can't even jerk
off.
I'm just going to have to jerk off for
him.
Unconscious.
Your brain fucking church you all asleep
for,
what do you think?
Do you think that you're learning things
while you're dreaming?
Because some people you'd learn things
when new treatments.
I think that'll be one of the next
hurdles that we get over where people
are able to,
uh,
be able to take in information while
they're asleep.
This is what I mean.
Like they say,
if you have a problem,
something's bothering you,
you should sleep on it.
And when you wake up in the morning,
you'll have a clear perspective.
I believe that.
Yeah,
I think so too.
I think that's real because I've done
that before.
That seems to actually be a good
strategy.
If you can go to sleep.
The problem is if something's really
bothering you,
like damn,
I got to figure this out.
Like you might stay up all night and be
exhausted and then you might not be able
to sleep and think through it.
You've got to get a higher power to help
you out,
man.
Yeah.
She got to get you just kind of case
where a higher power comes into place.
Do you think you see yourself ever going
to church again?
Yeah,
I would think so.
I did.
Church is kind of evolving over our time
and stuff like that.
And um,
would you go to Justin Bieber's preacher
Carl Lentz.
You know who he is?
Hey,
whoa.
He texted me actually.
Whoa.
He's trying to groom you,
trying to pull you in.
How's your dark arts?
How low?
Low.
Do you wear your shorts?
Huh?
Oh,
I saw you guys making a kind of this
room.
Yeah,
that was a little while.
So you know him never met him?
No.
He just text each other back and forth.
Yeah.
We communicate sometimes sad root
Hashtag Dick Route and he,
uh,
it looks good.
Yeah,
they're both camera too.
I think it's good,
but I've never met him.
But I would go to each other.
It has to try to meet you and you're
like,
not tonight,
Bro.
You think he's homoerotic?
No.
Oh,
that's a weird way of putting it.
You're homoerotic
you always,
every time I'm here,
he's talking about jerking off the
magical about that problem.
It's like you came in here with like gay
expectation didn't dude,
I jerked off yesterday.
I'm not going to plan on coming again
for a couple of days.
Do you have a time where like if you've
jerked off and it's been like four days,
like man,
maybe I should do something.
Uh Oh,
I get that feeling inside of me.
So it's like a vulture then wants to fly
on my fucking kicker.
My brain.
You don't want to be like two sex
obsessed.
No,
like there's a balance,
right?
You don't want to beat off every day.
No,
but you don't want to not beat off
either because then it'll consume you.
But I think I'm gonna start hunting that
dream.
They don't want that fucking nocturnal
bust.
They don't to start a group.
I'm hunting that the l and d's Row.
There's late night busters brother's
dream,
dude.
How funny is that expression?
I'm hunting that dream.
I want that nocturnal bus.
That's what I want.
Hunting the dream.
But Dude,
imagine you Jessica,
would you,
have you ever come common dice,
claim noises?
Have you?
That guy's a fucking movie man.
I never liked him.
Every time I see him at the comedy
store,
he's never been nice.
He's never nice to you?
No,
that doesn't make any sense.
I don't know why.
No.
Have you said hide him if you had a
conversation with them?
I've tried.
I feel like I've tried to engage with
them and he,
and then,
well,
one time he brought me up on stage and
he kept like,
they told him my name a million times.
He never got it.
It just got to the point where it felt
like he was being rude,
you know?
Like make him fun.
He might just be having fun.
He's a good guy.
Is He?
Yeah,
he's a good guy.
I'm a fan.
Maybe I need to see another side of him.
I mean,
I would give him scouted.
It gets a gnome man.
He's going to get to know him.
When I was a kid,
I was at giant Qinetiq dice clay fan.
I mean,
when I first started meeting him at the
store,
I was like,
I can't even believe he's healer.
But once you got to know him as an adult
and mean,
being a famous always been cool.
Yeah,
yeah.
Maybe I just need to have a new
experience with him.
He's,
he,
you know,
he just,
he's dice.
He's crazy.
Like half of his thing.
Like if you go to his instagram page,
half of it as like a put on,
he's always fucking around.
Oh yeah.
Always be in funny.
Yeah,
that's true.
But he gave me very good.
He's the reason why I started touring.
He gave me very good advice and I was,
you know,
it's was like in the 90s man,
he's like,
you should go fucking tour.
It was like,
you're funny.
He's like,
you won't want to hang around here all
the time.
Yeah.
And I was like,
yeah,
he's right.
I don't want to hang around here like I
should do clubs,
I should make a living.
And this is what he was basically
saying.
It was like,
don't get roped into only working in
Hollywood doing television shows and
stuff like that because then these other
people,
you control your destiny.
You could tour and this is from him
obviously coming out of,
he had the most insane epic success of
any comedian ever.
Yeah.
He was a rocket ship.
He was,
he had sold out hundreds of arenas,
arenas,
giant ass places.
Oh,
why are everyone is DVD or his seat,
whatever.
We hit the neighborhood and whenever all
the kids were watching it and haven't
even allowed to watch it.
So I thought when I was listening to him
talk,
I was thinking,
oh yeah,
of course.
Like this guy probably made more money
than anybody ever did on a sitcom ever
Malia.
And he did it just doing whatever the
fuck you wanted to do.
And he was basically saying,
hey,
don't get wrapped up in this.
Only you could tour.
You can make money.
I mean,
even if I never made money the way he
did,
you could still make a living.
Whereas if you don't tour and you just
do sitcoms or just work in television,
especially if you work as a writer,
that's the dark path,
the great standup comic that becomes a
writer.
They never tour and they never develop a
crowd and they never,
does that happen.
Yes,
it happens a lot.
But why warrant they to supposed to be a
writer then?
No,
no,
no.
And they gave in to the writing.
They could have when we know great
comedians who mostly work as writers and
it doesn't make any sense when they
don't want to,
they want to be a comic out there
performing and the level of their
material is far better than the level of
their notoriety.
You know?
I see what you're saying.
Yeah.
That's what it is.
Oh,
and Smith is a perfect example.
and Smith,
in my opinion,
is one of the best comedians on the
planet.
He's a killer.
That dude makes me cry funny and he's so
good.
His timing,
his stage presence is delivery is
material.
The subject matter's excellent.
It's top shelf comedy.
Yeah.
But most people don't know who he is.
Right.
And that's because he's made,
I mean he's made a great living as a
writer,
but he's still,
he should,
you know,
he should be recognized as a comic as
well.
Yeah.
That's how I look at it.
So basically what dice was telling me
back then was like,
get out,
go,
go someplace,
go do the road,
do comedy out there.
You could headline clubs on gratefully.
Yeah.
I mean I'm going,
I'm glad he did that because if we'd
wait and get you that you might not be
the same comedian if he didn't say that.
Yeah,
I'm sure.
And uh,
I don't know.
You know,
it's easy.
Like it's easy to just decide someone's
an asshole or you know,
if one interaction with someone you want
to shit on them.
I just think you should be,
and I'm trying to do this myself.
It'd be very careful when you shit on
somebody.
When is it,
when is it valid and when is it just you
looking for something to shit on?
Right.
When are you showing no empathy?
Yeah.
What is it now?
I think,
I mean,
I,
yeah,
you're right.
I mean,
I'm willing to have a new,
a new experience too late.
You're fucked up.
Fuck.
Said his name.
He said move.
It's over.
Oh,
well I don't care about that.
I mean he's going to get mad.
Boy,
he was an asshole.
So it's okay if I,
if uh,
they,
he just,
they kept
their,
like he was on stage before me,
so I was going to go up after him.
He was probably joking around,
man.
Yeah.
But at a certain point it was,
uh,
it was just rude.
No,
it was just like he kept not getting it
and then like,
ah,
fuck it,
you know,
is this like it at a certain point?
To me it was just rude.
I see.
Because you were probably a little bit
anxious.
You're going on after him and then he's
not saying your name right.
You feel like,
oh,
he doesn't know who I am.
So this is kind of disrespectful.
There could have been,
there could have been.
Yeah.
I think that that,
that certainly could have been my part
in it.
That could admit and ego and it Bundy
9.9% fucking around.
Yeah.
He thought it was funny.
Maybe what he would do that if it was,
if he knew you.
Yeah.
He'd be like,
Oh,
who?
Bobby Lee.
Right.
He's alive.
I mean,
that's part of who he is.
Right.
Well maybe I'll and maybe I'll have an
opportunity to get to know him better.
Um,
him and donald were hate each other.
They do.
I'm great friends with both of them now.
I loved watching him at Mitzi shores
when he performed at the Mitzi shores
reunion or deaths party.
But I remember I liked watching them
there,
you know,
I don't,
I mean,
I think that he's a great comedian and
stuff.
You know who,
what does he like now though?
I don't know.
Who would you have liked to have seen
live that you can never go to church?
I got to see him live when he was really
old and sick,
unfortunately.
I love him,
man.
He's from near where my mother's from.
It in Illinois.
Peoria in the house.
I at least got a chance to see,
be in his presence and see him live.
Yeah.
And he had this kind of,
he kind of had this head Bob thing that
was very,
you know,
who I think could come back and
order stand up right now for his hand.
Eddie Murphy.
Yeah.
I think if Eddie Murphy came back right
now,
he would murder,
stand up,
murder it.
Somebody said that the other day they
were thinking he might come back.
He did a a thing one day.
Well he was talking about bill cosby
about them taking awards away from Bill
Cosby and he did this bill cosby
impression and he did it.
We this,
what does that say?
What happened?
Popups come mother the fuckers.
He's coming back for that.
The movie.
Oh really?
Well is our CEO in it too?
I don't know.
He just,
he just had his 10th kid.
Wow.
Shoot.
Just shooting mad loads.
Now there's a guy who needs a birch tree
in the yard,
57 years old.
He's 57 yeah.
Damn.
It's amazing.
He's only six years older than me or
dose or a,
yeah,
six years old than me.
There's a guy hazing,
Eddie Murphy's.
It's been around forever.
Is it a new movie coming out on Netflix?
He was killing it when he was like 18
years old.
He was on sight line,
but he was like 18 or something.
It's crazy.
You forget how young he was when
delirious rolled around.
Good Lord.
He was probably 22 years old or
something.
Would you?
I bet he can come pretty far.
How far are you thinking about,
wait a foot.
Wait,
this guy,
we went over the world.
Jim or Jim.
Jim Carrey can come 30 feet,
grow back out.
It looks like a lot of dudes out there
that have broken the world record in
distance coming and nobody wants to give
him any credit for it because it's like
an impromptu thing,
you know?
Like you don't know.
I think decided you pull out.
I'd never,
Peter North was known for,
he was known for volume.
Oh yeah,
yeah,
they call it.
That's a crazy thing.
Loads are so hectic that you're known
for them.
Like tick,
like if you say big loads,
you say Peter North,
everybody knows.
Think about that.
Oh yeah.
All the fucking substantial loads and
all the porn stars of dumped on all
those,
all those maidens all over the land.
And then one dude is known for the
highest volume of calm.
Like you gotta be known,
known.
You know what I'm saying?
To let it be known.
Known.
No.
Time after time again,
you got to fucking bring that gravy
boat.
Yeah.
You gotta be like,
you gotta be like the Kanye west of
loads.
You have to be coming and also probably
look at your watch or your phone during
it and you're still coming.
When you look back at your day,
you gotta be the mascot of loads.
Yeah.
You gotta be,
you gotta be low like Michael Jackson.
Undeniable.
You think?
No,
he had very little coming here.
Bank probably zero but dancing prodigy.
Like he's the Michael Jackson of dance.
Yeah,
but you don't come much when you're
doing all that.
What activities do you think you do when
you come?
A lot?
Like the kind of people that like power
lifters probably shoot giant loads.
Right?
I think you would think they do,
but for their size and stuff,
they're not doing that much.
I think she's the biggest loads.
Oh,
I think a guy that's in space,
I think a guy that's on a cliff,
like a cliff climber.
Yeah.
But is that the biggest loads?
I mean that guy shooting some fucking
just cause he has the balls to climb up
that he's busted somebody else.
Maybe that's what it is.
Like he,
he's got balls,
right?
Those guys shoot bigger loads like bmx
jumpers and they jumped three times in
the air and then land on the bike.
Yeah.
Maybe they have the biggest loads.
Um,
also guys who like fake put a sign on
their car and they don't pay a meter.
It's like meters broken that he's put
that on their car and if I can still
park there,
those dudes bust some of the loads,
bro.
I think there's other things too,
like pickpockets.
Oh,
people that were up turtlenecks do not
come very much or far know.
What is it about wanting to keep your
neck warm?
It's not very manly.
It's just a bitch.
Move on.
It's a French thing too.
And I don't care about the French.
Wow.
But you,
have you been there or you just,
I've been there.
I'm probably prejudice to have you been
to France?
Yeah,
he'd been to Montreal.
I've been,
I'm on the trail.
You know.
You didn't love the French.
I love the Canadians.
French Canadians.
Yeah.
I'll take them.
You love Canadians,
period.
I love Canadians,
But do you love French Canadians?
Yes,
because they are Canadian,
but French bro.
Not into French and nobody is.
They make great wine.
Yeah.
It's not true.
People go to Paris every year.
Yay.
But they leave.
It's not the kind of place people are
milling around,
man.
I think people go there and they decide
that it's better than America sometimes.
Didn't Johnny Depp move there?
Yeah.
Poor Johnny.
You know who else moved there?
Um,
fuck the guy from law and order.
Uh,
Mandy Patinkin.
No,
Richard Belzer.
Richard Belzer moved to France.
He met a woman poly then.
Yeah,
I would think we,
I mean read love,
but Ed,
I bet you bust and France break.
If he know,
imagine Siemens cruising down the street
in that city.
Roads are slippery of it.
It's all on scooters
roads.
A slick with loads.
Welcome to
go sideways.
Even just everywhere through the air.
Out of the bushes.
DNA fucking manhole covers like the
clown pennywise dude,
this shit is getting gay bro.
Sorry.
It's just very dick oriented today.
I won't say it's gay.
Well,
it's that time of year.
It's spring.
People are refresh.
It's middle of the winter.
It's freezing cold out.
It's just January.
Whatever you guys are.
You guys aren't open minded.
It doesn't get more winter.
January groundhog's day yet.
Why don't you say it's August?
Okay,
why this is lie.
Hey Man.
It's like it's August outlet.
It's spraying.
I have the best calendars,
dude.
We just did three hours.
It's three 30 but this is the longest
time we had ever been in my life.
Now we know we've done this before.
Not this much.
My think we did well.
How long was the last one?
I think a lot of them were three hours.
I'm gonna have to get on some pills or
something to be able to go through this
again.
So you just drink,
drink.
Lenny's Nitros these really caffeinated,
yeah,
there's big juicy up plus.
It was fun.
Actually.
The last one was longer.
Oh,
minutes longer than the moon then.
We've not gotten him a fucking limited
bust on this one,
I think is the right time to end it
though.
We did it.
Um,
thanks for having me.
My pleasure,
brother.
Anytime you got a new podcast out with
Brendan Schaub.
Yup.
Called the king and the sting and it
comes out.
How'd you become the rat king?
What is that?
He just made fun of me.
One time they called me a rat.
Oh,
did you see that video of a bunch of
rats connected together to pretend that
they're a snake?
Oh yeah.
There was Whitney Cummings sent it to
me.
That's trickery.
I found it on twitter.
You've seen that?
Yeah.
It's on my,
on my twitter.
There's a bunch of rats that connected
themselves and they're running together
to pretend that they're a snake.
It's a rat came confuse.
Well,
racking is when they all get bundled up
together and they get stuck and they get
their tails twined up.
How the fuck does that ever happened to
disgusting creatures already?
Yeah,
they die that way too.
They find them all caked up and fucking,
this is a trap.
Hardy him,
Bro.
But spring break,
dude,
it's burning man.
That's burning man for rat.
Yeah.
Look at this.
Watch this part of this.
We at this,
those are all rats all completely
bundled up together to look like a
snake.
So Mama Rats in the front and the all
the baby rats stay connected to each
other to pretend they're snakes,
so they avoid predators.
And I if you,
and I saw that from far away,
we think of as a snake.
100% yeah.
How crazy is,
it's amazing,
Mother Nature is amazing,
man.
Mother Nature's a motherfucker.
Yeah,
we're limited time.
I think humans,
you think,
oh,
this is part time brothers.
There's no way to let us out of here.
Fuck around forever.
Those dumb motherfuckers could do is
pretend to be a snake and you could make
snakes.
We can make robots,
snakes,
shoot them to Mars out of our robot.
Dick.
We can't beat an avalanche though,
Ken,
if you're not there.
Oh,
don't go near where it gets avalanchey
in the sting.
Theo Vaughn on instagram and twitter.
Thank you joe,
for having me.
Thank you,
my brother.
Anytime,
anytime,
and we'll,
we'll see you tonight at the comedy
store.