How long is it gonna take me to get to
lax and what time should I be there?
If you leave at two you have no problems
at all.
Okay,
no problem.
Call me if you leave it to you.
Just kind to the coast in are we live,
we're trying to figure out la traffic.
Liz Gentlemen,
you got to plan for that shit to do man,
like a natural disaster in many ways
they're very similar.
When I moved to Colorado for just a few
months and then came back here was
instantaneous,
like the recognition of what effect it
has on me.
You know like every,
there's so many people you drive and
it's like
when you go somewhere where there's very
few people you have,
there's a,
a real feeling of relaxation.
Like it's legitimate.
It's real.
Yes.
Yeah.
It's almost like if you could buy that
like a,
yeah man,
I'm,
I'm taking this gum.
It puts you in like a small town feel
like woodsy,
Colorado feel going through evergreen.
Look at it.
You can buy that.
You just have to get out of out of
California.
No,
for sure.
But I was just thinking if you had a
pill,
a pill,
it did that,
that'd be a really expensive pill or a
patch or some gum.
And you're like nicotine gum,
some,
you know,
peace and quiet.
Gum Transports you to the wilderness.
How much would people pay for that?
Right.
Like think about the people that buy
Xanax and shit and just anything.
Just take a little bit of the edge off
just to take this edge off.
I don't know.
I would,
uh,
I would probably just buy it and smoke
it.
Yeah,
it's smoked the shit out.
Right.
But then would you be happy like living
in downtown La and some graffiti coming?
Building horns go off.
I love the weather here.
I do.
I think that's why I have to come out
for work or anything else.
I'd never mind because every day is
perfect.
So I've been here for like four days and
it's raining most of the time,
so it's my luck.
But a la traffic,
you just basically,
I think you just sort of accept that
you're going to live in your car,
right?
You're going to be in your car,
lock your reading.
Of course everybody has a nice cars.
That's why everybody drives nice cars in
that way.
It's also because we were all really,
really shallow.
Oh,
we want to show everybody like,
look what I got,
bitch.
You know?
There's a lot of that.
I liked cars.
I you too.
That's okay.
I think about your song.
When I drive my bronco,
you got an,
you got to really Nice Bronco.
I unfortunately no longer have a bronco.
I need a bronco in your life,
man.
Yeah,
but then I'd have a second car.
It took me five years just to buy my
first car.
So yeah,
you're one of the minimalist type
characters.
It doesn't want to admit they're
successful.
I understand.
No,
I got no,
probably admitting that.
I just thought,
you know,
I look like I've always,
I think it's from living out of a bag
most of my adult life and then you
start,
you know,
I had one guitar for the first two or
three years.
I was on the road one day you wake up
and you have five guitars now.
Do you have a thing where you don't
really need all these guitars?
You know,
I only need that one.
Maybe two guitars is good.
So if I feel like guitar makers who must
want to get you a guitar,
right.
Does that happen with musicians?
Actually I got one Martin made for me
and that's,
that's kind of a honor obviously.
That's amazing.
Yeah.
The old really old historic legacy
company.
Um,
but then yeah,
he buddies build them and that kind of
most,
I've always made my own at apartments,
like at least telecasters and stuff.
You can buy parts and assemble them,
uh,
just as good as anything coming out of
like what like a custom shop might be
for a fraction of the cost.
Wow.
That I didn't know that was,
and maybe even build an instrument that
is,
you know,
more comfortable to play because you're
building to the exact specifics that may
be somebody doesn't mass manufactured.
Well I guess if you know guitars as well
as you know them and you've been around
them your whole life,
that totally makes sense.
Like what?
It's wood in parts,
right?
Telecasters basically this table bolted
to a baseball bat cut in half.
You know what I mean?
It's hard to fuck that up.
The rest of it's just the electronics
and the pickups have a lot in anything
outside of that's just your fingers and
who's actually holding the thing.
But like to build one is not that
complicated.
Wow.
No Les Paul or a Martin Acoustic Guitar
that's,
that's literally like a hand shaped,
uh,
piece of work that has to be made from
start to finish.
Whereas,
you know,
the guitars I'm talking about building,
you're just assembling.
There's like parts that are widely
accessible.
I have a buddy that's a classical
guitarist.
That's an art.
That's another thing.
He always had his nails grow long.
What he do Jujitsu.
Dimitri,
shout out to my friend Dmitri to Chenko.
Uh,
he had,
uh,
to tape over his fingernails like when
he did Jujitsu cause he had claw called
bitches.
ISRC yeah.
How might the fuckers,
I mean he had ridiculous a long nails
and powerful nails too because he
strummed with his nails.
Like that's what he did.
Like he did everything he did with his
fingers.
He's amazing at it.
I mean,
just freaky.
Amazing.
You'd watch him play and he'd be like,
Holy Shit.
Yeah.
You know,
some play live a bunch of times and he
would do like people would hire him to
do like parties and shit,
but it's like a,
it's an art form that for whatever
reason I don't think gets the kind of
respect that it deserves.
No flamenco and classical guitar
players.
That's,
that's someone as highly complex
musicianship.
And so he would always explain to me
like guitars,
like how they were constructed.
And it's amazing to me that there is,
that's Dimitri,
that dude was the heavyweight on the
taekwondo team that I was on when I was
a,
like a lightweight.
I was at 155 pounds and he was fighting
heavyweight.
That dude used to fuck people up.
He's got those crazy Ukrainian genes we
just got to do.
She can pick anywhere that's like,
oh,
he's a bad motherfucker.
I don't know shit about guitar.
I know it sounds awesome.
And I know that sounds awesome.
But to you as a person who plays guitar.
Oh,
that's country guitar.
That's like he's checking what we call
chicken pickin.
What he's doing when their class group
tours.
Pretty cool.
He could,
he might as well be on lower Broadway
right now.
It's bad mother fucker.
Mother fucker for sure.
And
was a Massachusetts state.
Taekwondo heavyweight also doesn't make
silly faces.
I like that,
you know,
he went on to compete after I stopped
competing.
He competed a really high level
nationally,
like fondant to the one he puts like a
tar down.
He's still a bad motherfucker.
That's a legit bad motherfucker.
He's a big boy too.
Like he's a natural to 20 like the Big
Ukrainian rock people.
They're just sicker people.
The Rock people,
they could pick rocks up and shit.
Then on top of that unbelievable
guitarist.
Crazy.
How do you,
how do you know him?
We used to do taekwondo together when we
were kids,
we started out together.
I was like,
I think he's a year younger than me,
so I think I was like 15 or 16 when we
met and he was like 14 was he like eight
hours a day sitting homeless guitar?
Like all this discipline,
man,
I don't know if it's disciplined so
much,
Eh,
I think everybody that that plays music
and it really gets into it that heavily.
There's like,
there's like a,
it's a,
it's an ocd that you have to have a
level of spectrum or to sit and just do
the same thing over and over
repetitively,
eight,
10 hours a day.
Especially in as a kid when you're
really learning,
you like when he gets you and you hook
into it,
it's like you just did this.
The other thing that nobody else can be
a part of it.
Yeah.
You know what I mean?
I get it as an outsider,
I get it.
It's like you can do some thing and once
you start doing it,
it must feel amazing to be doing it
well.
Yeah.
Okay.
Yeah,
I think,
well,
I mean I played soccer and stuff when I
was a kid,
but it was always like,
I've never was one of those guys that
the team thing.
Yeah.
So it was just like introverted and did
and so when I found really found guitar
and got into it as like,
oh,
this is something I can,
it's not a competition.
It's not,
uh,
you know,
other than what you,
what you're pushing yourself to learn,
I guess.
Yeah,
you did.
You don't have to rely on other people's
personalities or,
well,
that's what bands are for.
That's what I always thought about
bands.
Like that's gotta be the hardest part is
everybody just being cool.
Typically the crazy artists.
Well,
yeah.
You especially,
um,
okay.
I mean it's really all about the hang
more than anything.
I'm uh,
I'm d I got me and three other guys in
my band now cause it,
and it's like
everybody's a great hang.
Dad's awesome.
Everybody gets along and we're like
actually friends and you go out every
night.
We're just like,
you know,
if you could pull that off and it makes
the road better.
Like when I go on the road,
I bring like Ian Edwards or Tony
Hinchcliffe or any my other friends that
that can do it.
If it's,
it's all like,
whether that they're free that weekend,
that's usually how it goes.
You're going to be around these people
for weeks,
man.
Oh Man.
We have the best time.
I don't do weeks.
I do still a couple of days at a time.
I never go on the road for more than a
Thursday,
Friday,
Saturday anymore.
I just stuck in warrior.
Yeah.
Really.
And I only do it twice a week.
Is that because of the kids and just be
at home?
I like being home and also because I can
travel makes you old.
Well,
it's just not good for you.
It's just not good for you.
Um,
it's,
so,
it's all those things.
It's,
I like being around my family.
I like being at home.
I like being around my friends and also,
um,
I just don't think it's a healthy thing.
I think travel on occasions.
Okay.
But I think once you start getting into
like every weekend flying,
I've heard of people doing that and I'm
like,
you're beating your body up.
Yeah,
there's no,
there's no if ands or buts about it.
It,
well it's,
it's,
it's one of the best things about
certainly my job and your job.
You get to go out and perform,
entertain.
But I bought since since things sort of
took off for me,
I realized very early on I'm,
I get paid to travel.
The shows are free.
Like that Shit's fun.
You know what I mean?
We're out there doing what we love to
do,
but it's all the in between and the beat
down your body takes and being out of
any kind of routine and away from your
family.
That's,
that's the really the thing that you
come off for like four or five weeks
straight or that,
and you know,
I'm a,
I'm a pretty healthy 39 year old dude
and it takes me four or five days just
to get off the fucking couch after a
month long run.
And my wife,
she finally started to understand like
it's cause you're
the travel,
you know,
it's a different kind of exhaustion.
You can't really articulate.
I think there's a travel,
there's the sleeping cause usually
you've got to get out if you're doing
every day to,
are you busting it?
Are you flying around buses?
Mostly.
Unless it's like
the logistics is just crazy but you
still got to be there so you might bust
part of it and then one night you're
flying everybody or,
or a red light red hour the next morning
and do that thing and then get back to
the bus or meet up with the bus.
What helps me is cardio.
Like uh,
when uh,
whenever I go to a place,
if I just,
I don't want to,
I feel like shove like Ah,
fucking tired.
But if I could just force myself to get
to the gym and just do like 45 minutes
on an elliptical machine,
just that 45 minutes out of the day.
Just that,
that's what I'm doing,
period.
Nothing else.
Put the headphones on,
listen to a podcast listener and just
get that cardio.
And then I'm good,
then I'm straight,
then everything levels out.
But if I don't do that,
if I don't do that every couple of days,
at least I just feel worn out.
I think it's also an endorphin
imbalance.
Like my,
uh,
my buddy bobby that plays,
we're going to be,
but he works out like a madman.
I mean like it's kind of insane.
You guys would get along.
Uh,
and I think a lot of those to balance
out,
you know,
just energy cause every night you go out
and do,
we get two hours of cardio right on
stage and just massive adrenaline blast,
especially when it really locks in and
there's all this energy just slamming
you in the face and then you walk off
stage and it takes like four or five
hours to come down from that every
night.
Yeah.
And then,
so you know,
in the next day now your shit has to be
off balance naturally.
You know what I mean?
Just like you just had this massive
blast of all these chemicals that your
brain's pumping out endorphins.
And now the next day you're just like
waking up trying to figure out where to
take a shit and get a cup of coffee.
And is there a shower today
and he gets
weird when you do a bunch of them in a
row,
right?
Like how often do you wake up and stare
at the ceiling?
Not exactly remembering what town you're
in.
Um,
not,
well,
that never happens because I'm like,
oh,
I'm always staying a week or two,
I guess the adventure,
the journey,
so to speak.
But,
uh,
I do wake up sometimes and just sort of,
well,
honestly it's,
it's bitter sweet because the longer
you're out,
the more you're playing in,
the better the music gets.
So,
you know,
by the last show you,
there's always this really like,
man,
you know,
I'm exhausted.
I really want to go home,
but I can't believe this.
We got to take a break now because
everything just got super greasy,
you know?
Right.
Um,
it's different every night.
But you just the chemistry and
everything and you lock in and you just
kind of getting that head.
Yeah,
I could imagine that it's a,
comedy is very similar.
It's very similar.
Like when you're doing like a long
stretch.
I only did it once with Charlie Murphy
and John Heffron.
We did this whole tour together is the
only time I've done like 30 days where I
did like 22 dates where it's just
constantly out.
I was only home for a day or two and
then went back out again.
But you get group,
you get in that groove,
you just get lawyer where you just
relaxed.
I've been doing it a lot.
If you feel it,
you get on this nonexistent Clark.
It's a,
it's a,
a routine of new routine is how I'd
describe it.
Every day is the same but completely
different.
Um,
but I,
I don't mind that man.
Like a lot of times it feels like I'm
just back in the navy because we still
asleep in bunks on the bus.
You know,
we,
we'd go out to sea for like 90 days and
shit and that was,
that's probably way better for you
psychologically when you go onstage than
if you're staying in some giant suite
when you're walking around the suite and
they get on a plane,
can't do the hotel rooms,
ma'am,
I get,
I get it.
You know when he started out and you
meet all,
you start going on,
you play like festivals or shows with
your heroes and they're on buses before
you are and you go on and you talk to
these guys and then you realize like
they live in this thing,
they're institutionalized in the back of
this bus and they never get off the bus
and you're like,
I don't get it.
And then it happens to you and you
realize that that's like this little
safe space,
like a hotel room overnight for me.
I'll go,
I'll go crazy waiting for a show.
You're like caged up in this little box,
you know,
with cable TV and nobody to talk to.
And I got soured on buses when they
pulled over willy and arrested him for
weed on his bus,
I guess should have been demoted man.
Like
for sure we got Willie on a pot shard as
good for you sherlock.
How dare you?
Whoever you are does things.
You just gotta let slide.
That was in Texas too,
right?
Yep.
Texas doesn't play when it comes to
weed,
unfortunately.
It's really silly.
If it did,
it would change Texas.
It would make it better.
Like could relax some of those fucking
cowboys settled down.
And why you saying it shouldn't be legal
stupid.
That's crazy.
The fact that that's still an argument
in 2018 you know,
they said,
here's a funny one,
one of the most recent arguments that
I've read,
was it pedestrians walking
out into traffic because of legal weed
and dying.
So like there's been an uptick
everywhere.
I shouldn't laugh at that.
That's rude.
It could be me,
right?
It could be me.
Why am I laughing?
Almost me this morning.
I'm an asshole.
I'm sorry.
I apologize,
but I thought it was pretty funny.
This idea that a,
there's an uptick in people just walking
out in the cars getting hit by cars
cause they're just spacing out cause
they're high.
I think it should be legal just because
I'm from Kentucky and if they gave all
those farmers and,
and uh,
you know,
x coal industry employees and an
industry that would really thrive since
it grows extremely well and Kentucky,
uh,
you know,
instead of soybeans and tobacco,
those guys could actually generate an
income.
What do you think is holding it?
The family community politics.
Actually that's not true.
Mitch Mcconnell or if they,
or somebody somewhere like really
staunch right wing guy in Kentucky came
out and was even pushing for legislation
towards at least the hemp industry,
which would be incredible.
Yeah,
the Hampton,
this tree is a no brainer.
Then you can look at the tax numbers
alone.
Well,
you know,
we buy him for on it and for the longest
time we'd had to buy it in Canada
because you couldn't get it in the
United States because until recently it
wasn't legal to grow.
And so to get like the best stuff that
is the highest protein content,
we'd have to fucking ship it in from
Canada.
You can't even grow it here now you can.
Um,
but when,
I mean,
what did we start on it?
And it's not that long ago,
wants to like seven years ago,
something like that.
So we,
that was like one of the first things
that we did is a make a really good
help,
a hemp protein powder.
And when we were looking into it like I
can't even believe that you can't grow
this.
Like it doesn't do anything to your
consciousness.
Zero.
It doesn't affect you at all because
it's related to pot.
It's illegal.
The national hemp
museum is in Versailles.
Kentucky isn't really where I graduated
high school though,
cause it's Woodford county.
Kentucky was at one point the largest
hint producing county in the entire
nation.
It just,
I don't know,
something about the limestone,
this whole conditions,
the humidity,
sunlight,
oh,
shot and hemp grows really,
really well.
Wow.
The first legal 508 or acre hemp farm in
Kentucky unveiled.
So now it's legal in October.
Oh Wow.
So now they can grow it.
Excellent.
Beautiful.
I don't live there anymore,
so I'm out of touch.
But Hey,
that's great news.
That's fantastic news.
That's amazing.
Well,
we were just talking about something and
I was going to bring up,
uh,
Shit.
I can't remember.
It's something about something about new
Mr. Nelson,
something new,
stuff that had to do with,
um,
with legalization of marijuana in
Kentucky.
We were just talking about,
yeah.
It's just,
it's just pretty crazy that you'd have a
hemp museum and have it be illegal for
so long with no argument.
There's like,
there's no science.
It doesn't pollute anything.
It doesn't do anything.
Dean environment,
the nature makes amazingly
built on it.
Everything was made out of that shit.
Did you ever see the first Henry Ford
model t where he made the fenders out of
hap and he's hitting it with a hammer
and not know that?
Did you gotta Watch this?
We'll play this for you.
It's the craziest shit ever.
Henry Ford's very first car that he
made.
He made the fenders out of hemp and
you're watching him hit this fucking
fender with a hammer and a hammer is
bouncing off the fender.
Check this out.
This is crazy.
I mean,
I don't know.
When was this?
What did it say?
Jamie was the time it said there.
1941 1941 so in 1941 before it was
illegal,
so it was made,
it was made illegal right around the
time where alcohol prohibition had ended
and they needed something to go after.
So then they started using the same guys
to go after wheat and this was pre that,
look at this,
he's hitting this fucking thing with the
back of an ax and it's just bouncing
off.
It was also a great way to discriminate
against Mexican immigrants.
It was,
and a black people too.
The whole name marijuana came from a
Mexican slang for a while.
Tobacco didn't have anything to do with
marijuana.
They just created this thing like when
they made it illegal,
the people that were,
they didn't even understand they're
making hemp illegal.
They had to all dad explain it to
everybody.
Then they were like tax stamps that you
had to,
dupont understood that.
Oh they incidents then understood the
fuck out of it.
So that William Randolph hearst,
that guy was the craziest.
The Guy who citizen Kane was a based on
rules boob.
That guy was the craziest.
So here it is.
This guy's hitting this hemp fender with
a fucking hammer,
Henry Rollins testing it.
Henry Rollins,
goddammit.
Look,
you barely smudge the thing.
I mean there's so superior to metal and
it's easy.
It's a renewable resource.
Like we're,
we've fucked this up so bad.
It's so obvious.
It's one of the biggest exam people
said,
why do you drone on about pot all the
time?
It's cause he's things like that.
Or one of the biggest examples of just
how agregious making it illegal is it is
a,
it's one of the most amazing plants
we've ever discovered.
You can make your house out of it.
You can fucking eat at it.
You can get high with it.
You can make your clothes with it.
It has all the amino acids you could use
for heating oil.
You get what intrigued cancer patients
to treat cancer patients with this here
for,
I mean,
somebody put it here,
come on,
come on.
Right.
It helps reduce tumor sides.
It's crazy.
Helps a host of different diseases.
I know a lot of people that have like
serious inflammation problems and they
smoke some weed and they're all right.
Just lightens everything up and it's
illegal and you can grow it.
You grow your own.
You could grow a shit ton of it in your
backyard.
Anybody could do you have a sprinkler?
Okay.
You guys good dirt.
All right.
You got some weed that we just good to
go.
That's a fucking hardy ass plant.
Yeah.
My Grandmother,
uh,
she just had some,
some,
some health stuff and it's like,
you know,
how do I,
she was pretty old school.
Like knowing there's this thing out
there that that isn't anything that
these doctors are going to offer her.
That's just gonna make her feel awful.
Yeah.
And,
and,
uh,
you know,
or have to go through all of those
things that just gives you comfort or
ease,
nausea or make you want to eat food or
those kinds of things.
Like why wouldn't you want someone you
love and care about to have that?
But then at the same time,
you know,
you want to be the person trying to
feed pots,
your grandmother.
Yeah.
It's a hard sell.
It's just
stunning
how well propaganda from 1933 carried
all the way the fuck to 2018 it's
stunning.
Is it?
I mean,
but it's almost a hundred years with
what we like the amount of information
that you can get on a subject now.
Like say if you're the bit the medical
benefits of cannabis,
just google that and you'll just start
reading all this shit.
Like if it seems to me that enough
people would go,
wait,
what are we doing?
Like why is it illegal?
Nobody's died from it.
Like no one more people die of aspirin
every year.
Okay.
Cause Zero die from pot.
So it's really the number zero.
It doesn't mean that people aren't going
to get high and walk into traffic.
Some psalm we're Gunna,
but I think part of that is because
we're not to teach teaching people how
to get high properly.
Someone gets hired for the first time
you looked up tone or how many of those
people that are getting hit by cars,
we're actually looking at their phones.
Could be a lot.
They were high and looking at their
phones.
You don't see that here like you doing
in Nashville.
I drove around and I know that's like,
I can't hate that every time I'm just
driving around town and everybody's
texting.
Everybody's looking at you can always
spot on the interstate.
Yup.
Weaving,
but you don't see that in California.
He goes,
you guys have like really heavy wall
today.
Yeah.
Today,
some lady had drifted completely in my
lane and I looked over at her and I saw
the the back of her head like I was,
I was on her driver's side.
I was on that side looking over at her
and all I saw was the back of rich.
Literally wasn't looking at my car and
she was just looking at her phone and
working her thumb.
And occasionally like looking up at the
screen or looking up at the windshields
like,
whoa,
you crazy lady.
You think just cause you're going 40
miles an hour.
That's okay because you were on a side
street.
Like you're not even looking where you
going.
You travel to a car.
What if you hit a kid?
Jesus Christ.
Okay.
Fuck.
What if you slam into some Old Lady?
You know what?
If you rear end a bike,
you're not even looking.
You didn't even notice the bike was
there.
Boom,
you run over some guy's leg.
What in the fuck lady or dude,
maybe I was mis-gendering.
I don't know.
I don't know what her status is.
You gotta be real careful today.
Sturgeon makes it like that and
Nashville is ever be like super.
I don't know Bro.
I don't leave the house.
I really don't have any idea.
I just,
I think that's a good move.
Um,
you know,
I like my kids.
Um,
I mean
I'm somewhat aware of everything going
on.
It's so surprising that none of that's
really hit the music business as hard as
it is.
But um,
uh,
there's just,
yeah,
I try to just do my thing.
Yeah.
It's a weird,
weird world we're living in today.
I would like a,
I would like us to figure this out
better.
I would like us to do just a little bit
better job,
being nice to each other,
getting our shit together.
So weird,
weird time.
It's real worse.
The strangest,
strangest times in my lifetime,
which isn't that long,
but that I can recall.
I don't ever remember things ever being
like whatever this is,
you know?
Yeah.
And I,
and I don't mean that in any generalized
middle of the road just says go at least
like
crazy shit with superpowers talking
about nuclear bombs all the time
everyday now.
And it's just like,
how did we get back there?
You know,
how do we get back to Putin telling us
that he has some new nuclear missile
that you see that shit like,
yeah.
1500 meter tsunami wave of apocalyptic
death.
That thing could Bama is why the fuck
man?
And we don't have a defense system that
can deal with it.
So he's basically saying,
I could kill you.
I have a gun pointed at you had a gay
anytime.
Welcome to 2018.
Oh yeah.
Donald trump's president.
I did that too,
by the way.
Yeah.
I don't know what I mean,
it's terrifying is,
it's definitely cause for concern at
all.
This wall pot's illegal
pot's illegal,
but it's legal to have a guy who was the
host of the apprentice
run the nuclear armament or armory,
you'd say armory.
Right.
Uh,
you know,
I got some trouble a few months ago
because I did this.
I had nothing to do one night and I went
down and it was all,
the whole thing was just the protest,
kind of based on like answering
questions.
I was just like,
the promise I made this buddy of mine
had a,
he videotaped it and he had a press
pass.
They couldn't tell us,
turn the camera off.
And somebody asked me,
what do you think about trump?
And I answered it.
But uh,
so what they didn't ask,
what do you think of all politicians?
You know what I mean?
To me like nothing ever really changes
look right,
left this or that.
It's all just sort of a different
version of the people you never really
see.
We can't have an Alpha chimp.
Yeah,
it's a stupid position.
We shouldn't have it anymore.
We shouldn't have had it a long time
ago.
We should have figured out a long time
ago do.
You can't have one person run the whole
show.
It's insane.
It doesn't work.
It's crazy for them too.
It's not good for anybody.
So w w we can't pretend anymore that one
person is special above other people.
Like royalty doesn't work anymore.
It doesn't work.
We're all just people.
It doesn't work and you can't get voted
into the number one person on the world.
That's fucking apparently
you can't.
You can,
but you shouldn't be able to.
It's it's too old.
It's too antiquated and there's way
better options.
There's just way better options.
You can't have all of us like,
and you can have like some arbitrary
date.
The prevalence [inaudible] episode of
the voices are saying,
well it has,
it's got a timer thing as a buzzer.
The voice now man,
that's,
that's just how it works,
you know,
or American idol or something like that.
There's a bustle big contest.
You mean during the trophy when you,
when you vote there's a buzzer did
buzzers over,
you can't vote anymore.
Right,
right.
The votes are in,
that's it.
And the drum roll please.
I mean it's Showbiz.
I Dunno man.
It doesn't make any sense that you,
I mean I guess it does because then
people could arbitrarily decide to
remove a leader and put a leader back in
and like you would just be able to vote
and change your mind with the tide like
constantly.
But that's one more reason why we
shouldn't have one person did stupid
should have,
first of all,
we got to,
we got to overhaul the way we teach
kids.
We've got to have more informed people.
Then once you have more informed people,
you let them in on what the fuck we
should do.
And we all decided as a group,
like the way they do it now,
right.
The way they do it now,
it's just,
it's,
it's bullshit.
It's fake.
Like you're pretending that you have a
choice.
You do have a choice.
You have a choice between this guy or
that guy,
neither one you like,
so pick it.
But both of them are embedded in all of
the special interest groups and all the
lobbyists and was supposed to be a
republic.
It was always supposed to be about the
people.
Yeah,
and by the people.
For the people who know I don't.
Yeah,
it's,
it's been cooptive by money.
It's real simple.
Big Pharma and all companies,
I don't know.
Well,
the amount of people that are allowed to
spend millions and millions of dollars
to prop up politicians.
It's like,
why would we let that happen on both
sides,
both sides.
Why would we let that happen?
That seems crazy.
That seems like any other job where you
were in a position of influence over
someone else's job,
you wouldn't be able to take money from
that person to make sure that you did
the right thing.
That would be called bribery.
Right.
I don't know what I mean,
it is like bribery.
They do it right.
They do do it,
but they get in be like,
here's the one that they get in real big
trouble for.
Here's one that I think is interesting.
They um,
trump recently did something about
steel,
about uh,
bringing steel back the United States
and steel manufacturing back in United
States.
But before he did it,
one of his homeys bought a shit load of
stock could steal like one of his,
like super rich dudes.
And so then the question is like,
hey,
should he have been allowed to do that?
Isn't that insider trading?
And you're like,
wait a minute.
You can't just know shit.
If I know shit,
what am I supposed to do?
I'm not supposed to buy stock.
Like,
well then if you do no shit and you buy
stock,
is that fair?
I didn't seem fair.
What's the answer there?
The answer is the system sucks.
You got a wacky fucking crazy system
that all your monies based on who people
could just buy and say,
sell parts of companies or all or all
Chinese pretty much bought all the steel
companies,
right?
It's a world by,
they were smart enough to say,
Oh,
you don't want that.
Okay.
Nobody's ever going to go back though.
Once you can make money off the stock
market.
Fuck that.
I'm making money off moving numbers
around on my computer.
Fuck you.
I'm staying.
Do you play it now?
It's just terrifying.
Terrifying.
No Way.
No.
Get the fuck out of here.
With that,
I've,
I've have gained and lost before I was a
victim of a pump and dump scheme.
I get nervous at the wheel of fortune
dollar slots,
man in Vegas.
You know what I mean?
Much less shit.
It display.
Okay.
They lure you in.
I'm down 19.
I've got to get the fuck Outta here.
You know,
I was a victim of a pump and dump
scheme.
Um,
this dude told me to buy the stock and
he's like,
dude,
I'm telling you this talks about to blow
up.
The guy was a coke dealer,
so I knew he was honest,
trustworthy,
easy,
listened to,
right.
I didn't know he's a coke dealer at the
time.
I just thought he was a comic and so he
would tell me about the stock and we
bought into it.
I don't think I bought that much,
but it was like a few thousand dollars,
which is not that big of a deal if
you're a,
you know,
looking at the greater spectrum of how
much money people lose.
Right.
In the stock market,
that's a g I lost nothing.
I mean people lose their whole,
their whole life savings,
their fortune,
they're there.
What they've inherited,
people can lose it like that in the
stock market.
So we bought in,
me and my business manager and it went
out for a little while.
It went up because more people were
telling more people to buy it and then
it just crashed.
And when I mean it crashed,
it just went to the floor.
Like it didn't exist anymore.
It was like,
it went from,
I forget what the number was,
but it was like in the many dollars down
to like a fraction of a cent or a
center,
three San or something like that.
It went down to virtually worthless.
And we're like,
oh,
we've got pumped and dumped.
Like that's what they do.
They,
they pump it up,
they get a bunch of people to join and
then once beach,
a bunch of people are buying this stock.
They're like abandon ship.
And I got fucked.
I remember shooter going on years ago of
all what the bitcoin shit man.
Yeah.
You got hung up on the bitcoin for a
minute.
Oh,
she loves it.
We,
I listen.
He loves that Shit.
He,
he's um,
he's a a bitcoin believer.
Yup.
I'm a bitcoin.
Hmm.
This isn't me.
I'm like,
I don't understand that and I probably
never will,
so I'm going to stay over here.
Yeah.
It's a good move.
I just every
like a little pyramid schemey does it,
I don't know.
I mean it's,
it's nervous.
It makes us nervous at this point in my
life.
I just assume everything is a pyramid
scheme.
It's always like a trickle of,
you know?
Yeah.
If it could be proven to be as stable or
more stable than money,
I think we just go for it.
That's what I think.
I think why fuck around.
Why?
Why use all these old crazy rich banker
dude's money when you could just do nerd
money is digital nerd money.
We'd all booed.
Take is people having to agree to it.
Right.
That's,
that's all it would take if everybody
just agreed to just use bitcoin
or if everybody agreed to an implant
that had all your info on it and all
your,
your money,
don't you do that storage cool.
Walking to your movie,
man.
You know that's coming.
Yeah.
Someone's going to give you the benefits
of it.
If you just put this in your Dick.
Well first of all,
it just,
they just have it inserted it.
Yeah,
but we all have one,
you know?
Yeah.
They haven't turned it on.
It's in your pocket and not your wrist.
Well,
some people it's on the rest too.
I was who I was texting one night with
the guys in the band.
This was what really scared to show me
where I like I got off social media
while back completely again.
I tried twitter,
Ghana,
I told Jason Isabel would give it a
second shot,
but I realize my kids are way more
interesting and like I'm trying to,
you know,
I just rather be writing a song or doing
something else.
But one night all we were all had a
group text going on and somebody said
something made a joke like,
uh,
it was a lot of 80s film buffs in our
band and somebody made a John Claude van
Damme reference and doodling and five
minutes later,
I'm not in any way exaggerating this,
all my wife and I are sitting and
watching TV,
surfing netflix and instantly it's like
my entire channel is full of John Claude
van Damme selections.
And I was just like,
what in the fuck is going on?
I've never watched the jock cluff and
damn film ever on Netflix.
And now there's all this,
it's like somehow that got cross
marketed to my television set just cause
I'm on my telephone and talking about
this fucking guy freaked me out,
man.
I was like,
no more.
I'm dumping everything,
Dude.
I've heard people tell them weird dude.
They were having conversations on the
phone with someone and then what they
were talking about showed up in their
google ads on there on their laptop.
How's that work?
How does that work?
I have no idea what they listening
constantly.
Sometimes he says,
yes,
Edward Snowden says yes,
but that,
but the fact that it shows up in your
Google ads.
Isn't that a little fucking obvious?
I mean that hasn't happened to me.
Do you think that's real?
A hundred percent a hundred percent
Jamie's looking at Lee,
he looks like he should have a guy
fawkes mask on right now.
Slip on one of them fucking anarchist
masks.
Look at him.
He's smiling over there 100% they're
listening to us.
Goddammit.
Cheat meals free for a reason.
You know,
Ooh,
boom.
What's the read it definitely.
Yeah,
they're reading everything.
Wow.
It all makes sense.
Now.
Now I'm freaking out,
Jamie.
Thanks.
Thanks buddy.
Hey,
fuck my head up man.
Here to help.
Is that okay?
You know who signed off on that?
How many people have ever read those
terms of agreement?
I don't have you ever the fifth thing,
that's what I think you're,
when you buy the Alexa,
you're just like,
yes,
go say you're buying.
Yet.
Those people are crazy.
Having those things in your house that
you talk to and it listens to
everything.
Fuck all that.
That just seems like too hackable.
So weird man.
It's getting,
and by the way,
this is just the first drops of water
that's going through before our roof
collapses because it's,
it's,
it's coming.
We know all cars now are more bills.
It's all in electronic systems and GPS.
Yeah.
I'm not a techie guy,
so excuse me if this is a really
ignorant question,
but like what's to stop somebody from
hacking into your car and crashing you
until fucking wall was,
that was always the case against Michael
or the death of against the definitely
guy that he's tasted.
The CA.
Yeah.
Yeah,
I remember that.
Well.
They don't know if the CIA or who are
all,
you know,
but he wrote a story for rolling stone.
He was embedded in Iraq or Afghanistan,
I forget.
And he wrote a story about this general,
it was very unflattering.
And what happened was he got stuck there
with them and he lived with these people
for a long time and they let their guard
down.
And uh,
you know,
they said a bunch shit they would say
around each other.
They made a movie about it today.
I don't know,
do they?
I don't know.
I don't know about that.
Maybe they might've,
but this general,
uh,
apparently got fired and it was one of
the best generals that,
you know,
it was very highly ranked and I'm really
respected by the troops and people were
really,
really pissed at this guy.
And,
um,
he was starting to say that he was in
danger and that his life was in danger.
And I think even said something about if
for whatever reason he commit suicide
that he didn't do it.
And,
um,
he was driving his car and he drove
straight into a treat over a hundred
miles an hour,
I think it was on sunset.
It's car exploded,
um,
engine flew from the car,
like crazy horrific shit.
And then afterwards they talked to these
computer experts and they say,
well,
is it possible to take a modern
automobile with all sorts of,
there's all sorts of devices inside
modern cars,
right?
That makes them hit the brakes.
If you're getting too close to something
or literally move out of a lane,
some of them have automatic pilot so you
could just fucking press the destination
and it just navigates there.
I mean,
that's what in Pittsburgh or was there
some weeks back?
Those are crazy.
If the self driving Uber's there and
they're getting better and better and
better at that.
Hmm,
let's,
I dunno,
I mean,
where do you go?
Next thing you know,
there'll be trying to shoot humans
through pneumatic tubes or something,
you know,
but you think it's people who kill
people,
uh,
literally for a profession,
right?
Professional soldiers,
especially the ones that this guy mean
embedded in combat.
[inaudible] I don't think it's outside
the realm of possibility that they would
like that guy up for getting that
general booted out.
Right.
I don't think it's outside the realm of
possibility at all.
They would think that guy is the enemy.
And they said that he had amphetamines
in his system and for awhile I was like,
oh,
yet amphetamines.
Maybe he's going crazy.
Then I realized that almost all
journalists are taken fucking adderall.
Right?
They're all taking,
you'll find it.
Amphetamines and methlick substantives
and all of them.
Not all of them don't get mad if you're
straight.
You're like,
dude,
all I drink his coffee.
Don't be a dick.
But a lot of them,
I have many friends that are writers or
journalists.
I can think of two journalists that are
friends of mine,
both take a lot out of Raleigh.
I love that shit.
Yeah.
Good Buddy of mine who's a doctor,
was just telling me that when he was in
college and he was going through,
uh,
all of examinations,
his friends started taking adderall and
he recognizes giant jump in their
performance and you're just like,
what the fuck?
He goes,
they were smoking me and the grades and
I realized,
Oh,
these guys are on pdds.
I never,
I never did it.
I remember trying to,
uh,
want to try right now.
Not really together.
No,
I don't.
I'm,
I kind of like to be down here.
You know what I mean?
I don't,
I've never understood that.
Uh,
I guess it just never appealed to my
disposition.
I don't think I would function if you
wanted to build a log cabin right now,
right now,
might be the way to go.
Right.
Well,
they said when Jack Kerouac wrote on the
road,
he was,
uh,
they were on a lot of bins.
Adriene or like this snow and hail and
things.
They used to borrow them and he'll sit
down and wrote the whole thing and like
three days,
Jesus Christ,
maybe a day,
I can't remember the,
I don't,
you know,
I'm not a beat efficient auto,
but I know that he was,
hopped out of his mind on speed and
wrote the whole Dang thing.
Like in a scroll on a roof in Mexico
while Ginsburg was probably downstairs
molesting a little kid or some shit.
I don't know.
He's,
that's a dark picture,
right?
Yeah.
There used to be,
uh,
what do you got there Jamie?
How a generation of beat writers burnt
out on speed.
Wow.
There was a big pool scene
back then.
Yeah,
that's what I was going to say.
There's pool players.
That was the,
uh,
the thing with pool players back then is
that they would,
uh,
take speed and gamble people.
When people first found out about speed,
it must have been the most amazing thing
ever before they realize like how it can
wreck you.
How many think about there's no speed.
And then all of a sudden,
10,
20 years later,
everyone's on speed.
I mean,
it happened out of nowhere.
There wasn't a bunch of speed burnouts
that everybody could like look back on
and go,
oh,
look at that guy over there,
learn from him.
Like,
especially like adderall.
Like there's no,
there's no burnouts.
So everybody's would just been taking it
for a few years ago.
Has it been around 20 years?
As long as,
uh,
how long thing adderall has been around
Jamie.
Yeah,
probably it after Ritalin probably,
right.
So,
yeah,
15,
20 years.
It was invented at the same time as
gluten.
Kara whack took so much amphetamine
amphetamine when he first discovered the
inhaler high that he lost most of his
hair and his legs swelled up with,
what does that worth?
Thrombo flebbe Bitas thrombo phlebitis
wow,
that's,
that seems like you went overboard a
little bit.
Say.
Anyway,
he went deep,
you know.
Um,
do you know who that a beardie man guy
is?
Does a electronic music?
It was like one of those,
what do they call those m artists?
Would they call them Edm,
Edm,
all those,
you know,
those fellows,
he's got a beard,
but he,
uh,
Greg Fitzsimmons and I were going over a
hunter s Thompson's routine before he
would,
uh,
write and he would just start off like
early in the morning,
drinking a whole laundry list,
bleeding until start work at midnight.
It's midnight.
Hunters Thompson is ready to ride.
I'm like,
Holy Shit.
And,
but him,
same thing right in his body just gave
out man,
his body was just falling apart by the
time he's tired.
He just burnt that fucking thing to a
crisp.
Well,
they didn't know what we know now down.
You know,
they were,
those guys were riding the lightning and
they,
they never thought there'd be any,
yeah.
But I think with hunter,
it didn't matter whether or not he knew
he had done this exact same thing
anyway.
Like he,
he was of a mindset that he's just like,
he's not here for a long time.
He's here for a good time.
Right.
And that's what he did.
And this,
I mean,
that's why people love that guy.
It's one of the main,
not just because of his brilliant
writing,
but because that mother fucker went for
it.
And then when it was all over,
he said,
yeah,
the same fun anymore.
You take care,
put a gun to his head.
And that's a wrap.
Told everybody who's going to do it to
said,
hey,
I want to get to a point where I don't
like this anymore.
I got fake hips now.
Can't move always in pain.
That's a wrap.
Take care,
boom.
The second you can't walk up or down a
few flights of stairs by herself.
That's kind of when it's over.
You know,
for a lot of people,
you know,
a lot of people manage to still find
some reason to keep going and enjoy
themselves and,
and you know,
and they're fine,
but it's like when you're a guy that's
just still hit it hard every day,
he never got,
he never sobered up.
There was no sobering up at high watch.
So what point though,
is that sad?
Yeah.
When is it,
I mean there's obviously a pretty
inherent level of self medication going
on to,
to get through the day so you don't wake
up and blow your brains out.
Right.
You know?
Yeah.
Um,
maybe it was just me.
I don't know.
Um,
I think with a guy like him,
his,
his path was probably pretty clearly
carved from the time he was very young.
He just,
he wa,
I mean,
the thing that's so interesting about
him and said he was so genuinely
thoughtful,
like you really did think about it as
one of the greatest writers of our time.
The questions I'm and a Kentucky and so,
yeah,
there you go.
It's gotta be all right.
Yeah,
I read a lot of it,
but I read it way too early because you
know,
in your,
I was one of those kids got just at
older cousins.
You get exposed to all that shit.
It was too soon.
You know,
probably high school.
I went on to read,
uh,
the,
the campaign trail thing.
The Nixon book.
Yeah.
That was a great one.
His,
his documentary.
You ever say that Gonzo lifetimes of
fucking amazing.
Yeah.
You want to just do something with your
life after you wash that?
Not to,
I don't know.
I don't have any friends that like way
44 magnums around in their living room
though.
It's not good.
You're right.
100%.
He definitely want to go to that party.
Don't get me wrong.
I go to that party too,
but you might get shot.
I wouldn't move in.
No,
no,
no.
You go to the party.
Johnny Depp moved in for like what,
six weeks?
All the way they went.
They went her head too though.
I wonder if he cooked Johnny Depp's
brain.
I wonder if that's when giant deb
started going wacky.
Holy Shit.
It probably is.
I'm going to spread it.
Conspiracy theory.
Jai Dep was reasonable and calm and
polite and had his shit completely
together until he did too much acid with
hunter s thompson and that's why he's
wacky now.
When you think,
I don't know,
it's not outside the realm of
possibility Kentucky too,
so I'm not going to say damn,
it's a full Kentucky House.
Did you ever read the Kentucky Derby is
decadent and depraved?
Yeah,
absolutely.
And it's,
and it still holds true.
Oh,
it's an amazing book.
Are Amazing article rather.
Well that was,
that was where he sorta really found the
style.
That piece in particular was where it
was like,
I'm going to go over here and do this.
Yeah,
there was definitely that.
And then that fear and loathing in Las
Vegas thing to where that started out,
he was pink,
paid to cover a motorcycle race.
It became this just fucking crazy screed
about drugs and partying and we're
outside of Barstow when the drugs began
to take hold and it's fucking bad to the
air and shit that driving a convertible
cadillac across the country headed to
Vegas.
I mean it's a fucking amazing,
amazing piece of work.
And it started out as a sports
illustrated story.
They wanted him to cover race and also a
very,
you know,
fitting and beautiful eulogy to the
whole sixties flower power shift that
just caved on itself.
Yeah.
Does that one line to fucking quitters
man?
Well,
what do you think happened with them?
I think they took away their pot,
I think took away the acid and they
arrested a bunch of people and they
don't want to clamp down.
And then,
you know,
you have a few
calls through massacres and uh,
you know,
the,
the sensationalization of the Manson
murders probably didn't help.
Right.
I'm sure it became like a big narrative.
Hippies,
LSD Martinson.
Yeah,
it was all all tied in.
Um,
but you know,
the musically since I should stick to
talking about things I know about,
which is music,
I think that that was probably just the
best shit that ever happened.
It never will happen like that 65 to 70
there was,
it just sort of exploded in all
different directions and a lot of things
happen that maybe they couldn't happen
now or even two decades ago.
They couldn't have happened as a
musician.
What do you think was the catalyst?
Like what made them go from the 50 sound
to the sixties
just experimentation and,
and mind,
whatever,
you know,
looking for different ways of life.
Philosophically speaking,
maybe.
I think what they're all writing about
it,
but I mean,
and then some guys were just pushing the
sonic limitations of the studio.
Like Hendrix didn't really do that much
drugs,
you know what I mean?
The guy was all just about like,
I mean,
yeah,
he partied,
but he wasn't like a Druggie,
you know,
he probably ate acid on stage a couple
times in both of those.
I think he was spiked.
Really?
Yeah.
And the dude,
he's just a serious blues head and they
wanted to stretch out and uh,
really pushed what the limitations of
the gear at that time in the studio,
you know?
Well,
I don't,
I don't only want to have eight
channels.
What would,
if we had 16,
I'll you have some of the
experimentation things that guys like
him and pink floyd and uh,
later bands,
you know,
alo,
just really pushing the parameters of
what you could do with a traditional
style of music in terms of arrangement
and how you frame that.
I always assumed that because he got
arrested in Toronto with heroin,
that he did drugs.
I feel like if you have heroin on you,
you got drunk.
Did he get busted for,
I thought it was barbiturates are just
good question.
I'm pretty sure it was heroin.
I don't think he ever like,
I could be wrong,
man.
It might be right.
You might be right.
What does it say?
It says a small amount of heroin and
hashish
chasing the dragon.
Yeah.
See.
So when I read that,
I'm like,
hmm,
how much do we know about what Jimmy
Hendrix did during his day?
Like you don't know how high I'm
getting.
I know a of how would they,
how would they know?
I mean,
if they see us get high on the show,
they know all high I got today.
Right.
But they don't even,
because I could get high before I go
running.
I might get high when I'm sitting home
to write.
I have people telling me that I'm high
when I'm not even higher.
Yeah,
but you probably are a little still.
He's really sleepy.
Be Like Hound dog guys who'll,
I'll always look harder.
Even something,
but whatever.
It doesn't matter.
Um,
Jimmy,
Jimmy liked,
he wasn't as some weird shit.
It's kind of a,
I know he had this thing about video
filming women walking away from the
hotel.
I said they found this big collection of
like home movies of him hanging out off
hotel room balconies.
Like they walked away,
walk as they walked away with some kind
of weird,
interesting fetish.
What does that,
he was not guilty on the charges.
They don't know that they might've been
planted on him.
Oh,
interesting.
They're not sure if they're interested.
Mustang.
Interesting.
It said he had no drug partner for
Nellie in his luggage or needle tracks
on his arms.
No,
he smoked pot,
but he doesn't know.
They might have fucking frame.
Damn that dude.
That dude was too creative and prolific
just in the amount of time he was alive
to have been a junkie.
You know what I mean?
Like yeah,
you gotta you gotta make a junkie get up
and do shit.
That's true.
But they say that about potheads too.
But I know a lot of pretty prolific
potheads.
I don't buy that.
I don't either.
Smoking pot gets me off the couch.
Yeah,
right.
It makes it a little paranoid.
Totally.
Yeah.
Like I got to get some shit,
you know,
like I'm maybe not working hard enough.
It makes me feel like that.
Like I could be getting more shit done.
Yeah.
They said linen actually and I want,
and he was on heroin for a while,
but that motherfucker laid in bed with
like 18 cats,
you know,
and it didn't do anything.
And then they said Paul would be like,
Oh,
I've got some songs.
We've got to make a record.
And He'd be like,
God damn it,
wake up and have to write five songs in
a week.
Oh really?
Cause he just released.
So he just lay around like a sloth butt
naked until all the,
all the maids to pretend like he wasn't
there when he walks through the kitchen
naked.
Get a glass of milk.
You couldn't do that anymore.
They take your house.
That needs to be fired.
You couldn't even make it like an
arrangement.
Well,
you can't make an arrangement the other
way though.
There's like a top was made service to
come over your house and they'd take
their top off.
See,
that just seems weird.
It's definitely weird.
I don't know.
I would be like,
imagine the people that those poor
ladies have to deal with on a daily
fuck,
man.
Yeah,
that ain't a good time.
But um,
you could have a topless maid service,
but you couldn't have a,
you come over and wash the house while
I'm naked deal.
Because if it's your house and you're
naked and they're walking around your
house,
then you're forcing them to look at you
naked.
Right.
I would think that that's,
yeah.
People are losing their careers over
there right now.
Yeah.
You can't really not supposed to do
that.
Yeah,
but in the old days,
like a king who didn't give a fuck,
he would just stroll around and let
everyone look at his cock and walk right
through the fucking building.
Wouldn't give a shit.
Have Your Head Cup Cup chopped off if
you didn't have sex with him.
I would not want to live in those times.
I've been watching a lot of vikings.
I would seen it,
man.
I feel like for people telling me to
watch that shit,
I don't have time.
I didn't believe them.
I'm like,
there's no way it's on regular tv cause
it that good.
It's fucking good.
Really.
It's a good shot.
You,
you have to get through the first couple
episodes.
First couple episodes,
you're a little bit like wet and yeah,
my buddy forgot all about it.
He's like,
man,
you got to get on his bike Vikas.
Damn man,
they have to set things up.
That's the problem with shows.
You're not,
you're a little skeptical until you get
to know everybody and then you get the
feeling of the characters and then you
get sucked in.
That's why binge watching it so awesome.
Like it is watching is great for if
you're,
especially if you're a touring musician.
Oh go so right.
You know,
I can never get into shows when they
come out because I'll see a couple of
episodes and then we go on tour for two
months and you're like,
what the fuck happened?
But now I can come home and just,
you know,
watch a season of something in a day
while I'm recuperating.
Yeah.
My wife's pretty,
she knows what like good.
There's good shows,
the programs and shit.
Like I don't have,
I wouldn't know what to watch,
but I've found a lot of things.
Have you seen stranger things?
I saw the first season or no,
I did see that.
Yeah,
we saw those.
What about Ozark saw that?
I like,
I like Bateman.
That's good.
I like that sort of Donek Shit.
There's a new one coming out with jared
leto but the code,
is it a movie?
It's a movie.
It's a movie on Netflix.
Yeah.
You joins the Yakuza most handsomest
white looking Kusa guy ever
perfect.
Right?
Because that happens all the time.
It's happening in this movie,
Bro.
How about spend?
A little disbelief for jared or less
walking around.
She Shinjuku looking for white dudes to
fucking run shop.
You know,
I think he's learned how to speak
Japanese.
I hope so.
It's gonna be pretty weird if you've
done beautiful.
He's prettier than most women.
Oh,
he's pretty than a lot of women,
man.
If you put him on like a long
hair wig type situation,
it's beautiful.
There it goes.
We go on and look at pictures of Jesse
supposed to be half Japanese.
I think he's supposed to be her misses a
show.
I better not be cause he's got his hair
do that anymore.
That shit is cultural appropriation.
You're not allowed to anymore.
But how else was the white dudes going
to get you Kusa he's gotta be,
he's gotta be like a catch there.
I think he was a soldier that was
friends with a guy stayed over there to
help them.
Gotcha.
If you have a movie today and you have a
Chinese character in the movie,
but you have a Japanese guy play the
Chinese character,
you're fucked.
Right.
People will get angry.
You can't do it anymore.
No more pretending you're someone else.
Like can you like if you lost your
Robert Downey Jr yeah,
he could get away with it,
but not anymore.
He got away with it and that one movie.
But like if you were an Asian guy
though,
I firmly believe no one would have a
problem if they took an Asian guy and
gave him some sort of facial prosthetics
that turned him into a European looking
guy and then gave him lead roles and a
movie where he plays a European guy,
people would have to shut the fuck up.
They'd be,
they would want to say something within,
they'd go,
it's amazing how far,
uh,
we,
we watch old movies on,
on the bus sometimes.
And I want,
if I'm at home and my,
and I'm by myself,
like I'll watch weird shit.
I'll like old films and a lot of old
westerns and stuff and I'll watch the
same movies I've seen a hundred times
over and over as opposed to watching a
lot of the newer shit.
Um,
we do watch a lot of these old westerns
from the fifties and it's like,
it's all white dues painted up like
native American Indians with the head
resident just looks so cheesy and they
have these,
these have affected a horrible accents
and you're just like,
how the fuck did that ever happen?
But then you get to the eighties and you
watch something like 48 hours now and
it's the most sexist,
racist,
misogynistic shit.
Like,
and they were just pumping those things
out of studios two or three decades ago.
You know,
where they,
any female characters in those films,
like you're either hooker one or
secretary at precinct who everybody
dismisses.
You know what I mean?
Like those were the only roles.
Yeah,
that just happened.
That's when we were kids.
Yeah.
When we were kids.
Yeah,
we were on that movie.
I would just call out specifically.
We washed it on the bus one night.
We were all like,
this would never fucking get made at
random.
There's no way so much we'd never get
made.
It's weird.
I mean,
is that,
is that cultural evolution?
I think so.
I mean,
I hope so.
There's a little bit of it,
but it's happening.
It's not just like catchphrases and
shit.
I hope it's actually doing something.
I have weird ideas about this.
Um,
I really feel like if we weren't
completely embedded in it,
that we would look at,
this is like a system that's pulling us
into its web
and,
and forcing us to be more and more
entangled in this system is the system
of electronics.
It's like almost like it's,
it's preparing for us to give birth to
artificial life.
And so in the meantime,
it's completely sucking us in and making
us be completely embedded.
Phone's in your pocket,
constant.
Alexa,
listening to everything you do.
It's all just as deep as it can in the
biological systems world and pill.
It gives birth and we're going to force
it out of exist,
force it into existence just by being
completely fascinated with electronics.
Are We?
I'm going to [inaudible].
Yeah.
Is it the universe forcing it into
exists that too.
I think it's a natural thing.
Wow.
I've always described it as like a,
it's figured out a way to interconnect
itself.
You've been more man.
Yeah.
It has data.
And forced progress.
Like thinking about what they were
saying about Putin,
like if Putin,
who really does have that later.
So fucking Skynet,
man.
It sure is.
Yeah,
there you go.
But if someone has that kind of power,
right?
If there really is something that a
person can think up that didn't exist
200 years ago,
that wasn't even the thought of it.
So in 200 years to small amounts of
measurement of time and relationship to
the entire age of the universe,
they could figure out a way to kill
every person on the planet like that
literally wreck the planet where no life
would be.
It wouldn't be possible to have life.
There's enough nuclear bombs to do that.
What is it going to be like in to 200
years from now?
It's going to be way,
way,
way more accelerated.
Let's almost going to get to the point
where the universe
is going to be a place where you could
visit.
Like people can go places if not people.
Things can go go places.
As long as I'm holding a lightsaber
before I die or you'll get one of those,
it's all fucking worth it.
But the problem,
the light sabers,
I was always like,
well,
why does it end there?
Why doesn't it just go on for infinity?
Like a lazy boy?
Yeah,
right.
Why is it only three and a half feet
long now?
What's he doing?
Unless it was a rod and then the laser
went around the rob,
but it knew to stop at the top.
That would make sense.
But the fact that laser only extends
three feet or whatever it does the fuck
out of here.
George Lucas was a big crew.
Saw a fan,
was he?
Yeah.
All that Shit's based on Samurai films.
Oh,
that's right.
And Leona films and all those guys just
like,
it's like generations of dudes paying
homage and ripping each other off the
lead to the new thing.
It's the same as music.
Wow.
Well Quinn [inaudible] has always been
pretty open about that.
Right.
He makes unapologetic like cinematic is
right down to framing shots and scores.
Like he's uh,
yeah.
Does it masterfully though?
Like it isn't it?
What are you doing when you remaking
King Kong making money?
Yeah.
You make your money,
you're making a lot of money,
but if you do it right,
you,
you see you're making art.
I don't think anybody has done King
Kong.
Right.
What is Donkey Kong?
You might not be able to do King Kong,
right?
Maybe it's a bad example,
but the hug the CGI for me,
man,
it really took the magic out of
everything that was hd.
Cause you watch Harry and the Hendersons
with your kids now or something.
And that looks better than a lot of the
stuff coming out.
It's just,
I don't know,
is a suspension of disbelief isn't there
to hdtv just fucking ruined movies for
me cause I'm like,
yeah,
give me some vhs.
You know,
it's better.
Blur the lines a little bit.
Yeah.
Like digital music.
Same thing here.
All that separation and air and uh,
sterilization,
I guess is the best way to put it.
I think it definitely works that way for
physical things.
Like,
it's one of the reasons why the original
alien movie was so terrifying.
It was a physical thing.
Fucking that was a,
you knew where the first Halloween,
yeah,
there was no blood in that film.
It's just tension and thread and real
dialogue and real people and some crazy
fuck running around in a William Shatner
mask,
even American Werewolf in London.
So quick.
Also from Kentucky.
Why is he really,
Yup.
Damn Kentucky.
And Muhammad Ali.
Yeah.
We don't fuck a Louisville.
My Ingraham Lincoln,
Daniel Boon dam,
uh,
Harry Still Harry Dean Stanton.
Imagine the Daniel Boone days.
Imagine being brother.
I don't have to imagine where I live
now.
It was like Daniel Boone day I walk out,
it's like,
Yup,
there's a,
they found this some,
there's some caves down.
We,
we moved to the smokies or do they just
give land away down there?
Really?
And uh,
yeah,
a fucking
my own woods now for less than what a
townhouse in Nashville would cost.
But they,
the people bought it from,
they found a cave on the back,
back of the property down to can we kind
of backup does national forest and um,
there's a bunch of like 3000 year old
Indian cave paintings and they're like
native American k.
So there's university Chicago came down
and studied it at all.
So now I'm going to spend the rest of my
life trying to figure out how to keep my
fucking kids from going in there and
doing something,
you know.
Right.
And Dick was here.
Yeah.
We're drawing a big cock and balls on
the Indians,
you know,
but here's a thing that cocky eric would
be revered by people who found in years
from now.
Right.
Why do we say it?
Yeah.
I mean if you went to a cave,
uh,
2000 years from now and they uncovered
some cave and it was a bunch of advanced
life comes off.
Yeah,
people would be excited.
They'd be like,
well,
these things,
3000 years later,
what happened?
Well,
if you look at like some of the ancient
artwork,
right?
Like how about some of the statues are
dudes
grabbing each other's dicks and
wrestling?
Do you ever see?
Yeah,
yeah.
They were wrestling and in the process
of wrestling,
one dude's grabbing of the guy's junk,
which they did do the crush your balls
and shit.
That was a move back then.
And so all those be honest,
like in a real fight to move.
That's the move.
It's a way to go.
It's definitely the crush a man's taters
or take away his ability to breathe.
The fights pretty much over.
There was actually a mma fight where
they took place back when there was no
rules.
There's a guy named the Pedro and he was
fighting.
A guy named big daddy goodrich and big
daddy reached into his pants and grabbed
a hold of his cock and balls and crushed
it in his hand.
See this guy,
it's just grabbing Dick's man.
The guy in the bottom is grabbing deck.
He's holding that guy's hog.
It's rude,
but that's how they wrestled back then.
They didn't give a fuck the,
the Dick was something you could also
hold on to.
You can hold onto the foot.
Why not?
Why can't you hold onto the Dick?
So they were yanking on decks and
pulling people along or they really
turned it up back then to this day,
had to,
how long were they live in?
You know,
I mean you,
if you were one of these bad
motherfucker wrestler Dude's,
how much time did you have to be that
guy?
That Dick roll around in the dirt and
then we'll go eat some grapes.
That guy's got a hard on TV and watch a
lion eat my friend later on today.
That's not the day.
Look at the apple and the end of that
guy's Dick,
the size of his hog.
If that was real,
he was hard.
This is sex then.
Is this not fight for the death that
guys getting off on that or if he
doesn't,
if he's not getting hard and that's just
how big his dick is went soft.
This is not at all where I thought we
would go either.
On my way over here.
It has to be said last time that we
talked about bigfoot.
Yeah,
no new opinions on that.
Oh,
I got a big foot story,
uh,
freely.
No,
I think I already told him I made it.
I think did our,
I was going out.
I used to live out west a long time ago.
I'm a buddy of mine were driving up to
this little town called Leavenworth
Washington to go check out just like
this weird little aspen,
Swedish ski town and fucking northern
Washington where you go get your potato
soup.
That's another story though.
And,
uh,
we stopped at one of these roadside
coffee stands,
which are every 300 feet in Washington
state,
but this one was on like this sort of
timber road going up through the forest
and you pull over speaking to Harry and
Henderson's.
Wow.
It's all serendipitous.
But uh,
we get out of the car and the wooden
statue from the,
from the beginning of that movie is like
in the driveway.
There was this old sasquatch statute and
I just,
that's where I remembered it from.
I was like,
that looks just like this thing from
with day.
Yup.
And uh,
no,
that's not,
that's bad ass though.
It's there.
A lot of bigfoot sightings out there.
Well,
funny you should mention that.
Uh,
we,
we're stopping and we're getting coffee
or from this lady and I'm like,
you know,
whatever,
trying to talk about the statute from
the movie.
She's like,
yeah,
they stopped and here and then she pulls
out these,
she had these old photo books,
like the family photo albums,
like huge photo albums.
Two or three of them,
at least full of polaroids of sasquatch
that her family had taken in this house.
Supposedly it's greatest idea to sell
coffee ever.
Polaroids like photographs,
like fucking old of a real sounds.
Photos of Scat,
Sab.
Well that's what she really wanted us to
think.
Um,
there are just so many of them.
I remember thinking like God,
she really went to some trouble here
man.
Cause there's like giant photo albums of
sasquatch and they were all sasquatch
photos.
I'd taken off their back porch or out
the windows of the house and the for,
cause they lived like right off the side
of the road and it was just fucking
wilderness,
you know?
And that's my satisfied story.
Was
there any of them that made you go?
Not a damn one.
Cause I was,
I I don't believe in big foot.
So it definitely used to be a real
thing.
I think that's what I think.
You think at one time it definitely
existed and they're all gone now.
There's an animal called the gigantic
Pythagoras,
right?
You know about that one.
Right.
That was a real thing.
So that was basically a big foot.
There's an eight foot tall,
gigantic bipedal ape.
So they know that that was real.
So if that was real,
it's entirely possible that one of them
made it across the bering land mass with
human beings should entirely possible
because they were from Asia and they
were from Asia.
A ride around.
Yeah.
Yeti.
Yeah,
a Yeti.
Um,
neanderthal.
I mean,
I'm a sasquatch.
You could,
there's like a bunch of different names
for them,
but it was a real animal that lived,
I think they found bones that were as
recent as a hundred thousand years.
So anatomically modern humans definitely
lived in the presence.
So what do you attribute all the
sightings too?
In the last bull showers?
Her Blair's hurt.
Bears.
Bears hurt their paws.
They walk the walk of Hind feet.
They do it all the time.
Um,
I think most of it's bullshit.
The reason I say this because there's no
real compelling evidence other than like
a couple of footprints that you think
someone could have for you actually had
it.
You didn't,
you'd be like,
you got to show for a while.
You want her to talk to all these crazy
fight.
Yeah.
Were you ever at any time like this guy
might've saw something.
One lady had think saw something.
I don't think she was lying,
but I think she probably saw wounded
bear and she saw it very briefly.
And the problem,
the real problem with people's memory,
especially in some situation that freaks
you out,
like you think you might've saw a
sasquatch,
your brain starts fucking with you and
it starts filling in the blanks with a
bunch of shit and then you start
repeating that shit as if it's that
enable that something is wrong.
But I would imagine if you're,
if you,
you've,
I'm sure you've been,
you,
you lived in Seattle for a while,
right?
For a little while.
So you know what it's like when you go
up into those mountains.
It's like so thick.
It's beautiful.
Unbelievable.
If that was going to go fuck off and get
lost somewhere,
that would be,
dude,
that's lets us from that some real
wilderness Mt.
Rainier,
right?
Yeah.
God,
it's gorgeous.
Um,
but their wilderness is so dense.
I was described it as like trying to
look through a box of q tips.
It's a petri dish.
They just,
it's in the,
the ground is so soft and smushy from
all the pine needles.
So my point is this lady saw something
in the distance,
she saw elk running,
right?
And then she saw something standing up
and she looked at his face and she
realized it was an ape.
She's like,
oh my God,
I see an ape.
How is there an ape?
And then she,
she said to herself,
oh it's big foot,
that's big foot.
And then it went over through this patch
of timber cause everything's super,
super dense,
you know,
10,
20 yards further and you can't see it
anymore.
She lost it completely.
But it makes sense that a bear was
chasing elk.
That's what they do.
They do it all the time.
They're probably chasing the elk.
There's probably a fon,
they'd probably try to get it into the
bear.
Might've been heard this shit taste.
Yeah.
And the bear might might've been hurt,
in which case,
which happens all the time.
And when bears or her,
they walk on two legs.
So if you're looking at this thing,
bears can grow nine feet long,
right?
That's real.
Black bears can be nine feet long.
A really big black bear.
So if you're looking at this thing and
the Pacific,
it's probably rare,
but there could be seven feet all day.
You can find a bunch of seven foot black
bears.
Those are,
those are legitimate.
So this black bears walking around seven
feet tall,
standing up on its hind legs and you're
seeing it through the trees 30 yards
away.
Like,
oh my God,
I see big foot.
So in her head,
I don't think she was lying.
I think she definitely saw ash animal.
She saw elk running and shop.
She saw a big ass animal in pursuit,
but it easily could have been a bear and
she could have filled in the blanks in
her mind with all these false memories
that are attributing like,
oh,
I saw his face,
it looked at me and annoys and all that
stuff.
Like people get wacky.
Like you think you saw something and you
didn't.
It does no bodies.
That's the problem.
There's nothing like no one's,
no one's found shit.
No one's found anything and not a single
fucking bone.
I mean,
they found this gigantic [inaudible]
bone in an apothecary shop and China,
and then they did a dig.
They went back to the spot.
These anthropologist said,
where the fuck did you get this?
They this giant primate tooth.
There wasn't a gorilla,
it wasn't a human being.
They're like,
where'd you get this?
And they take them to the spot where
they got it and they find bones.
They find job bones that indicate that
it was by pedal.
It's kind of controversial apparently,
but apparently by the way,
that jaws design,
they knew the distinct stood upright and
it's huge.
I Dunno.
I met some dudes from stornoway,
Scotland wants,
which they look like they were from
another planet.
They were like the biggest fucking
people I've ever seen in my life.
There's four or five of these guys at
this little music festival and Kilkenny,
Ireland,
and they'd all come down for the
festival.
And these are men.
I'm not shitting man.
They were the biggest people I've ever
seen and they were all over and they
were just like fucking mountain mountain
blocked off the light when they walked
through the door.
And then these like long gray hair and
beards and shit,
and they're like,
you should this come up and play in
stornoway.
Fuck it.
Only it takes eight fucking fairies to
get there.
You know?
It's just like,
I would actually love to go up.
Oh,
I think of those dudes whenever I think
of those atlas stones.
Do you know what atlas stones are like
the most manly way to workout ever.
You basically picking up these enormous
balls of stone and these dudes lift them
and they get them on their chest.
They hoist them onto these blocks.
They have contest to see who can,
like when they do the straw man contest,
they picked those atlas stones up and
put 'em on progressively higher and
higher shelves.
Giant,
giant people.
Stone.
Yeah.
Balls,
giant stone balls.
Those people,
I mean those are the ancestors of the
Vikings for sure.
Right?
For sure.
That's where the vikings turned around,
I think.
Yeah.
Yeah,
I'm not mistaken.
They got there on their own,
this
they shot loads and to everybody it got
winter time and then they bailed old
as fuck this place.
It's always raining.
It's going out of here.
They took off too depressing.
I got it.
I got some really good buddies now.
Uh,
and Glasgow,
all musicians you meet over the years
tour and a couple of guys particularly
that,
um,
if I go over,
sometimes I'll do a little pickup band
with my,
with these guys and they're both like
hard glaswegians and my friend Lloyd
went to last summer I was over there.
He took me up on a proper like car trip
up to the highlands and back down and
one day I think we got as far as like
Oban or,
anyway.
But yeah,
there's,
there's parts of that stuff.
It's,
it just,
it looks like you're on another planet,
man.
I can't even describe it.
I remember we got out of the car and a
couple of places and you try to wrap
your head around how ancient that shit
is and everything that took place there
and,
and how,
you know how one were just standing
outside of the car on the side of the
road.
And I'm like,
I'm fucking freezing to death.
You know,
in the middle of August.
It's just a raining,
literally upside down and it's not even
raining.
You're just like this.
It's some harsh,
brutal shit.
Always cold,
always cold,
always wet,
even when it's not,
somehow I don't understand it.
It'd be like sunny and a mile and a half
later was like a blizzard and it was
just like fucking mental man.
But it looked like another planet.
I was only,
I've,
I felt like it could,
could've been a c,
uh,
setting out of star wars or something.
Yeah.
If you think about it,
when you think about Scottish people,
you always think of hardy,
right?
Oh yeah.
Hardy.
Tough people instantly comes to mind.
Well,
you know,
that another weird thing about it is you
always pure Americans especially like
were where you're from your ancestry and
this and that.
And I was,
grew up in eastern Kentucky and then
moved to Central Kentucky.
But like most of the,
the early settlers in the Appalachian
region was really predominantly Scotch,
Irish and some German.
So the first time I went to Scotland
to play music,
I had jet lag.
And the first morning I woke up like
really early,
you know,
and I was like,
fuck,
well,
might as well go walk around and check
things out and get out of the city and
everything's kind of coming to life and
people are going to work.
And I'm looking around at the faces,
man.
And it,
he realizes like,
Yup,
this,
I might as well be in Hazard Kentucky
right now.
It's the same stoic,
very guarded,
you know,
uh,
disposition.
But then like once you get to know them,
and especially when you become friends,
they're just like,
they would do anything for you.
But it's very regal,
stoic,
working class city.
There's something really special magic
by Glasgow.
And I just kinda hit me like,
this is definitely where my fucking
people came from.
You know,
like that might as well be my uncle
bobby right there.
Uh Damn.
The people that live there today,
man,
like they get to go buy castles and
shit.
There's castles near that.
You drive by every day.
And how old those castles?
Like what's the oldest castle in
Scotland?
Uh,
I'm not sure what the oldest one.
I mean there's like,
it wasn't all 1000 years.
I think the one in Edinburgh is probably
1200 years old.
Um,
wow.
God been been penicillin matching
anyway.
Yeah.
12 can look 14,
1600 years.
And we played,
uh,
there was somewhere in Ireland,
this little town and across the street
from the hotel was this guard tower that
had been there for 1300 fucking years.
And there's like viking boats they had
on display around,
I'm just thinking,
yeah,
somebody a thousand years ago was up in
that window with a bow and Arrow,
you know,
that's all they had.
That's all they had shooting arrows down
at invading people.
It gives you perspective though when
you,
especially Europe in terms of old world
isn't that old when you think about
China or a lot of Southeast Asian
cultures,
you know you're talking about 10,000 but
like Europe is a good example for me.
Every time I go he gives me perspective
cause you think about everything
happening in our country and everybody's
like,
oh it's,
it's fucking going to hell.
And you know we're such a baby.
You know there's,
there's churches over there that are
five times older than the United States
and that it's still working somehow.
The oldest shit we can't have is like
when I was living in Boston,
there was a cemetery that you can go to,
we could see tombstones from like the 17
hundreds and you barely read it.
You can pay,
they're all weathered and worn out.
Cause that shit with it in the 17
hundreds and you could just go over and
touch it.
It's right there.
But people's,
how'd you too much because it's got a,
the numbers are all fucking worn off and
shit.
Look at that one right there.
Which just one that cathedral built in
1471,
the oldest building in Glasgow,
I think 1471.
The coolest Gig I ever played was in
London at,
it's called St Pancras as his old church
building.
Um,
which I think,
you know,
monks at one time it was,
they built it acoustically and designed
it out of stone for acquirers,
like chamber bars and they didn't even
have a PA.
It was just me and an acoustic guitar.
I remember sitting there thinking like,
it was the most insanely beautiful
natural reverb I'd ever heard in my
life.
And it's a really,
uh,
it's an,
it's like right around King's cross,
you know,
kind of a busy intersection,
but I think cause that it right there,
st pancras.
No,
that's the,
uh,
the train station.
They look older.
Good St Pancras old church.
It was really special though.
I remember walking for sound check and I
was like,
I don't give a fuck if anybody comes to
mind.
I just get to sit here and play my
guitar in this room.
Yeah.
This is it right here.
That's it.
Yeah.
It's like a little cute building.
Yes.
And so in,
so the way they built the whole place,
it reverberates while the rounded edges
and everything.
Actually that's the side hall.
And then there was a,
that's see the one third from the right.
The darker one?
Yeah,
the door.
Whoa.
Wow.
That's beautiful man.
That was really special.
So if somebody wants to look at this,
Jamie,
what does the image,
if someone's listening to this saying
pay Chris,
p a n c r a.
S.
Pancras p.
How beautiful is that construction?
It's the oldest standing house of
worship.
I don't want to,
I hope I'm not misquoting this,
but I think it's like the oldest church
in the United Kingdom and it's in the
center of London.
Wow.
So they designed it so that people could
play acoustic that was built to sing in
like just be like,
oh yeah,
it does.
The thing that the old keyboard affects
just have built in.
Just pissed that like,
wow.
The bloom on everything.
When I was a kid,
uh,
I lived down the street from this place
called Echo bridge.
An Echo bridge.
Is this a,
it's a near,
it's a newton upper falls and it's this
place where we'd all go hang out and
drink,
but if you get underneath the bridge,
it gave you this crazy echo,
just like ridiculous.
Dickless hello and uh,
let's shut geeks like me walk around.
Constantly listening for,
yeah.
Every kid in my high school thought he
was billy squier when you'd go down
there,
you know,
when you find yourself alone,
you'd be screaming it like a fucking
Dork.
Remember we knew how to do the van Halen
thing on a notebook.
The Vh logo.
First concert.
Yeah,
man,
it freaked me out.
Inhale.
And they were amazing.
I had a buddy,
I used to work at this grocery store in
Nashville when I was,
how it kicking it around.
And uh,
this guy was,
he's really cool.
He's older,
he's in his fifties and he was local,
grew up in Nashville and I was like big
music guy,
you know.
And uh,
so he saw like every show that ever came
through town and the seventies and
eighties.
What kind of grew up in that?
And he just,
he'd always like,
tell me about the shows,
you know,
cause he's,
he remembers,
he saw van Halen at the little call cm
and Nashville like down on the north
side of town back in,
I think he said 77.
So it was before the first album had
come out and they were opening for black
sabbath and you know,
but this time,
deep purple and all these like riff rock
bands were just sort of the thing.
And he said,
these guys come out and he said it was
like a bomb exploded in that fucking
place,
man,
look at it.
He's like doing back flips off his aunt
and all that crazy shit.
No,
we never heard that stuff,
you know.
Wow.
And he said then Sabbath came and
everybody
basically walked out after the third
song cause like they realized they had
just seen what was next
man.
I saw kiss when I was like 10,
10 or 11 years old.
I saw him live.
Where you into them or is did you just
totally,
and I was really into him and my uncle
worked for their,
uh,
advertising company that designed their
average,
uh,
the album covers Howard marks
advertising company.
They're the ones that did well.
He's a genius.
Howard marks marketing,
whoever's handling the marketing on
that.
Well it was uh,
my uncle vinny and his friend Dennis
where the artists,
they would make the album covers.
That's crazy.
Yeah.
So I get to meet h freely without his
makeup.
I was like 11.
Ace freely is actually the first guy who
ever did the harmonic tapping on tape.
Really?
Eddie later got all the acclaim.
He took it and ran with it.
But I think the first time that was ever
recorded was on a kiss song.
Somebody using that technique.
He was fucking phenomenal man.
Okay.
When apparently they were really nice
guy too.
Right?
Ace,
I don't know.
I'd never met him.
Oh,
I know that he didn't get along with
some of the other guys like Gene Simmons
and cause they're all hosting pricks.
I think the ace,
I think it's supposed to be like the
sweetheart,
the guy that's maybe,
maybe uh,
Paul Stanley who's nice.
He was a nice guy of Gene Simmons has
been nice to me.
You know,
obviously everybody knows it's part of
their thing.
Man.
I get it.
Yeah.
I mean they were just,
they were rock star.
They've been rock stars for so long.
We think about that.
They were rock stars in the 70s they
were rock stars when,
when it meant something.
Yeah,
it's a difference.
I'm not sure what it,
if it even is necessary.
Do we really need like roll what order?
That is a rock stars.
Yeah.
Here's the problem.
We know too much about them.
All the mystery is gone because they
know it used to be like Robert Plant
would come down and fucking magic
carpet.
We didn't know where he was coming from.
You know,
it would show it at the time.
Thought he was on one.
You know Robert Plant in his prime,
right.
Who the fuck ever sign anything like
that?
Before they were taking elvis off the Ed
Sullivan show because he was shaking his
hips.
Robert Plant has got a piece on him and
it's pressed up against his pants,
his pants or his tied as a glove.
He's got no shirt.
He's like a shirt is completely open,
right.
Be completely bare chested,
long hair and a voice that you'd never
heard before.
He never heard someone sing like hold
out of love.
I mean it's just he's doing something
different.
He's got some new thing going on and you
don't know shit about him.
There's no fucking podcast that he does.
He doesn't have a twitter page.
We said stupid shit about trump and
hillary.
Yeah,
they they,
they actually did.
They never did any interviews or any ray
didn't release singles actually pull out
people.
Did you hear all these classic songs on
the radio now,
but they'd never put single.
They refuse to do singles.
They didn't do press dude there.
If you wanted to see led Zeppelin,
you had to go to the show.
Yeah,
look at his cock.
Look,
look at it.
Look at his car.
He wants you to do up against his pants.
Of course he does.
I mean,
I don't know if he had a sock there,
but I want to believe,
I want to believe that he was just out
there slinging tick.
A dude was like 17 when that first
record came out.
Imagine he wasn't even the first choice.
They went through a few people.
Jimmy page.
Do you,
when you put the band together?
Uh,
one,
one of my favorite singers of all time,
I love Robert Plant would always felt
like if Steve Marriott,
I always wanted to hear what that would
sound like if he didn't do the guy from
humble pie.
Fucking incredible voice and he's
supposed to be,
I'm not,
I want to say maybe page one Indian,
but he couldn't do it.
I know they'd talked to maybe Rod
Stewart was it was it faces at the time
or earlier there were there,
I know Robert Plant wasn't choice number
one.
Do they had to talk Bonderman to taking
the Gig page and John Paul Jones had
known each other through session work in
the mid sixties and when the yardbirds
broke up,
Jimmy somehow thought he had rights to
the name and he wanted to put together
like a super band of all his,
the his favorite musicians he played
with and bottom was a recommended by the
Bass player John Paul Jones because they
had to go and like talk him into it
because he's playing with bands at the
time.
They paid him a lot more money.
Wow.
On Jimmy's,
like I had to explain what they were
trying to accomplish and sell him on the
idea that was,
that was sort of a,
like every,
we're talking about vans that are put
together by labels.
It wasn't,
Jimmy page was a genius and a in a very,
you know,
visionary kind of guy.
So he knew he needed to build this band
to take over the world and that's what
he did.
Wow.
Great producer too,
to fucking phenomenal guitarist.
Right.
Probably one of the most inventive
guitar players ever.
A lot of people say sometimes,
especially later when he's on the
morphine.
Some sometimes it can be a little
sloppy,
but I like that.
I like,
I hate perfect.
I would nothing more boring than
perfect.
So is that,
is the sound of a guitar is similar to
like a voice?
Like sometimes to doodle have a raspy
crazy fucked up voice and it just makes
it right.
I mean,
yeah.
Any real artists player with an
instrument.
It doesn't matter what the guitar is
with amp or anything.
Like anybody that has their thing,
they can pick up anything.
And within like three notes,
you just know it's that person,
you know.
What do you think of that?
How do you say his name?
Lee Ray Lamontagne.
Is that how you say it?
Yeah,
he's a like a songwriter.
Do you know that song?
Jolene?
Yeah.
He's got a really cool voice,
ma'am.
My Buddy Dan did a record with him and
I've never met him,
but now he's a really cool
dude.
His voice since think he's Kinda like,
he was Sorta,
if I'm not mistaken,
I won't be like,
well it's more like came into it later
like I did.
You had to jobs and shit before and then
just started doing it and that makes
sense.
Found successful later on.
I think that makes sense with a lot of
people,
man.
I just think people like Justin Bieber,
like he's Kinda way
harder road.
So way harder row to try to figure out
like all things considered.
He's probably handling it.
Okay.
He's handling it.
Would you think about he was,
what,
fucking eight or 24 years?
Only four.
Holy Shit.
He just told us already having just
turned 24 and he's rolling around on a g
seven that's his day to day,
you know,
whatever the fuck he wants to do all the
time.
You know,
you don't pay attention to things.
I'm not like I'm,
I'm not glued into pop culture,
but somehow like you just can't not know
what Justin Bieber's up to once a month
just walking around in the world
anymore.
But I would say that kid for most people
to be handed that type of existence and
all of that scrutiny and all the shit
that comes along with that does things
to people.
You know?
It definitely does,
especially if your personalities not
even formed yet.
Yeah.
I can't imagine like I'm so grateful I
got into this business at 35 yeah,
and not 21 because I was talking to my
friend John this weekend about this and
I was saying that it's almost like if
you made an epoxy,
right.
You know,
if you have a proxy,
you have to put a couple ingredients in.
Like there's one thing and you mix it
with another thing and then it hardens.
But if you add some shit in that that's
not supposed to be there and it's fully
developed,
right.
You're not going to take that shit out.
I'll give you added oil.
You just wrote some oil in the epoxy
like,
oh,
and now you fucked that whole thing up.
That's kind of what you're doing to a
person.
When you raise a person famous,
have you take some reality star from the
time they're five and then they're gonna
sit calm and a movie and then you've
gone through your whole,
I don't know why I said Reality Star,
but you've gone through your whole life.
If you're that person,
if you're Justin Bieber,
you've gone through your whole life
under the eye,
and it's gotten bigger and bigger and
bigger and more and more people paying
attention.
Like you never had a moment like you did
when you're working for the railroad
tracks.
Right.
Or like,
you know,
I did going on the road for years or do
some of the jobs that I had before I was
ever a comedian.
They don't have any of those.
They don't have the wondering if you
could pay your bill feeling.
They don't know that feeling.
They don't have the,
let's see,
I still feel like that,
you know,
that's what's fucked up.
My wife just like,
I'm still like,
I just,
I'll never not feel like that,
you know?
Yeah.
From never really had money or anything
like that or any aspirations to own a
house or those kinds of things.
So it's just a,
okay.
Um,
you know,
especially with kids now,
like I just don't,
it's,
there's no
flamboyance yeah.
But now he lives a different life for
people like Rihanna.
These,
they're like literally citizens of the
world in any day of the week.
They could be in some five star hotel
and God knows where,
you know?
Yeah.
God knows where.
Wow,
that's a crazy way to live.
Very bizarre.
I'm just shitting sentence flying on.
I couldn't it man because
there was no way I don't ever,
I don't ever want to wake up and have
that kind of career cause it takes so
many people around you who are on a
daily basis just to maintain and keep.
See it's something,
a machine that Laura's rolling,
logistically speaking,
that you become enslaved to the job.
You know what I mean?
Cause you have all these,
there's like,
there's always this name,
like when you have superstar acts,
you know you put this head right here
and then everything below that just to
make that thing go around.
You know,
and it just turns into this,
it's like a corporation really like with
20 semi trucks and all this shit,
you know,
and you've got to go out and make that
happen because now all these people
depend on you for their livelihoods and
careers and that's going to affect the
artistic decisions you make because you
have to stay relevant culturally
speaking.
And if you,
if you want to do something different
next time,
well now this massive fan base isn't
really going to fucking deal with that
very well.
You know,
I can beastie boys put out Paul's
Boutique.
Exactly.
People want and what the fuck they want,
what the fuck.
But now it's a,
it's one of the class most greatest
records ever made.
But people back then didn't know what
the handle,
they didn't know what to do with that.
They didn't,
they didn't have the beastie boys
classified in the artist's box.
Right.
They had him in the pop music box.
So this is silly.
You got to fight for your right to
party.
We get it.
You guys are partiers.
Cool.
And then all of a sudden,
you know Paul's Boutique,
it's like,
Whoa,
what is this?
Oh you like David Bowie went from ziggy
startups to doing a solo album and like
nine months with Luther Vandross and
yeah.
Well those are huge,
classic,
amazing records now.
But like you realize those guys were
playing in theaters when all that shit
happened.
Whoa.
And he's just like,
I'm done with this.
I'm going to go do this now.
You literally cannot see anymore because
I fucking killed it on stage.
That's over,
you know?
Do you think Rod Stewart gets enough
credit?
I don't act on either.
I think especially man faces and even as
early solo records,
there's are some amazing albums.
His voice is incredible.
The Hammer.
What too much pussy do you think I'm of
his brain
when he hit that?
Everybody like,
check please.
He's like,
wait,
I'll,
that's all I got to do.
Because remember,
go back to Maggie Mae,
you know,
wake up Maggie,
like that song was that was there was
something in that song,
right?
There was a guy trying to figure his
life out,
hanging out with some chick stewards of
bags.
Oh Man.
Question.
What does that song as they called
Maggie Mae?
Yeah,
him and Elton John.
All those guys.
Like that's,
yeah,
he was a beast.
A different level.
But they started wearing like leopard
tight pants and shit cause he could,
I mean look at that shit.
It ain't like he's not working looking
at luck.
He actually was,
I think he almost played professional
soccer for Celtic or somebody.
Wow.
He's like a really great soccer player
when he was a kid,
but he was too small.
So he had this and he's another one
right.
That like basically like you never get
to see one of those again.
No,
I don't think so.
You're never going to see a lot of
things again just cause it,
there's just no,
nobody that's actually,
that might know.
That's not necessarily true.
You might see more things now because
that's true too.
That's true.
Getting ahead of myself.
Like I,
you know,
for all intents,
I,
I shouldn't be here.
Right.
That it wasn't an industry creation.
So now like anything really is possible.
Yeah,
that's a good point.
You just have to fight and sift through
so much shit.
Most of the mediocrity to get to
something that really hits you or that
you connect with.
Well,
I think you're also saying this out of
your own personal experiences where you
realize you could,
you could have not been you like easily.
You could have not turned out into being
you.
Oh,
if I were to sit down in a room with a
bunch of people who know what's best,
I wouldn't have been me.
Yeah.
You and most people that are successful,
you know,
we,
it was just how it is.
My first record,
we did shop to a few labels in town,
but you know,
I was a little bit ahead of,
ahead of the whole neo trad curve that
sort of kicked off in the last few
years.
I made this really traditional country
record.
And,
uh,
but it was,
it was like hard country.
It was very,
uh,
like an album I always wanting to make
and we shopped it to a few people and
they just didn't really know it wasn't
the right time so nothing came of it.
Uh,
so we self released it.
So then when I did the second one,
the metal modern and now we've got this
whole record about like,
you know,
mine
the,
the journey of the soul or mind or
whatever,
talking about turtles and fucking
tripping and shit.
Right.
I was like,
I knew nobody is going to get this.
Like I can waste time trying to find
somebody to release or we can just put
the damn thing out.
And I'm so glad we did it that way just
because I know what happened was a
result of people hearing it and sharing
that with their friends 100%.
That's how I found out about it.
I found out about it for people online
and I got to tell you the cover of it
threw me off.
At first.
The cover of it was that was me being a
smart ass,
cause I was like,
there's all this like,
uh,
you know,
you go to these festivals and stuff,
I'm like a grown ass man.
You know what I mean?
We're fucking stupid jobs now.
I was in this all of a sudden this
position and going out playing all these
festivals and looking at these kids and
stuff,
doing it and on this is great.
You make a lot of friends,
but there's it,
there's a lot in any industry,
there's a lot of,
uh,
people like for the wrong reasons,
you know what I mean?
Like just chasing something that they
want to see themselves in as opposed to
something they see within themselves.
Right,
right.
And so we started doing these festivals
and there's a lot of like what they call
like the younger hipster kids and stuff
when they had these 10 type photos that
were really popular a few years ago.
And I was like,
well,
how can I out hipster the hipsters?
So I'll do a painting of a 10 type photo
and surrounded by like the tackiest
outer space.
My buddy that I did the thing with,
we were actually trying to make the
worst album cover of the year and we
ended up,
we ended up making a top 10 list on
rolling stone.
We didn't get the cherry,
but,
uh,
I was loose just making the tackiest
fucking thing we possibly can.
I like the cheesy fonts and um,
it's kinda crazy because the music was
to me was so heavy and personal and
real,
so I was like,
God,
man,
I don't want to be the kind of wanting
to make fun of like the Dude levitating
in the fucking k before,
before people turn you into that.
You know what I mean?
Cause like that's not at all.
A lot of the shit was just stuff I've
been reading about or you know,
you're in character.
Yeah.
But it was psychedelic country music.
It was like,
well,
which is a lot.
I love a lot of sixties rock and some of
my favorite country records ever made
were made in the late sixties.
Some of the,
uh,
Gene Clark and some of the early vern
Gosdin brothers type stuff.
There was this level of Psychedelia and
the production that was made.
It was so beautiful.
I got to get a list of shit to listen.
Well I'll throw you some shit man.
Um,
but then talented guys and I was kind of
a task masker so it's such a,
such a young band because they wanted to
play loud and you've got to pull things
back or like you can only have this
symbol,
that kind of thing and get it down to
the structure of the songs.
And we spent like three months on the
road just carving those songs out and
the arrangements.
And I had it pretty much,
you know,
Doug Pussy tight,
which is waterproof.
And then we,
you know,
we came off the road and went right into
the studio the next day for four days
and just banged it out.
Oh Wow.
We're in the groove.
Yeah.
Basically just plug up like five mics,
don't move anything and just lay it all
down.
And then Dave and I are with the mixing
and then he had some great ideas and
postproduction like getting the sounds
around but then you come back and we had
all these separated recordings.
So to me I've realized the real fun is
putting everything in sequence and
making these cycle to maximize I guess
the emotiveness of the records in terms
of a rollercoaster of emotions if you
know instead of just one.
So like every time we do it now it's
always different.
Like the record I did after that was
recorded,
that one a totally different way,
still going fast.
But you know,
I are always wanted to make a big kind
of lush orchestra,
all soul record.
And then what I've learned is that I
don't want to be in the music business
because I'm going just going to be in
the surgical business.
Um,
because there's this like the mechanical
timeline of it all.
By the time we go in and make that
record your,
so you've been processing and thinking
about it so much for,
for months and you get in and you have
that release and it's,
it's like I equate it to driving in a
really heavy downpour rain storm for
like an extended period of time.
Or it's just like there's a mental
exhaustion that comes for it,
but you have to just kind of like keep
going and,
but by the time it's finished and mixed,
you've heard this thing like a thousand
times,
you don't ever want to hear it again.
But now you got to go out and play it on
the road every night,
a year and a half.
So we were constantly trying to reinvent
every night,
how to keep that fresh and exciting
while while holding the pause button on
going over here and recording what
creatively
you may already be on to.
Wow.
So I'm,
I realized this year I'm going to take
the reins and want to do like I'm going
to play 30 festivals because those
things are always so fun just to go out
and get all the energy in your face.
And then we're going to do probably a
double album and another record and just
recorded also that when I do turn around
and want to go do like a really big long
two year tour,
we have all this new material and the
old stuff to pull from.
I like how you,
you're approaching it and so like you're
approaching like a plan.
It is a plane.
You have to look at it like a plan.
Do you think everybody does that?
Oh,
there's all kinds of different plans.
I just know it works for me.
I've learned more importantly what works
for my family and my sanity.
Um,
I don't need to go play 300 shows a
year.
I don't,
you know,
I'd rather go play
30 or 60 shows and know that every one
of those was 110% as opposed to,
you know,
you got the Tuesday and Wednesday shows
to get you to this weekend market where
everybody's counting their checks
already and shit and you're exhausted
and in the show suffer and these people
pay money or maybe they don't realize
that.
Like you can't hear anything for 40
minutes cause you don't ever want her
project negativity from the stage if you
can help it.
But there's going to be bad nights.
I just went every night to be great and
then,
but most importantly right now for me,
the fun is,
is this the studio and the,
the process of trying to push it,
you get to what's next.
You,
you totally different albums.
Every time you put an album out it's
like completely [inaudible].
I'm a music listener in lover first and
foremost.
Probably musicologists more than a
musician at this.
Is that a word?
Yeah.
I mean I guess that's my field of study,
I guess.
Ecologist.
Yeah.
If I had to like say that I have
obsessed over one subject enough to
where somebody should probably give me a
fucking piece of paper that says I know
what I'm talking about is probably
music.
Um,
did you,
when did it start?
Did you have this your whole life early,
early after a whole life?
Wow.
Probably honestly first time,
um,
from Michael Jackson.
Maybe I was like,
you know what's Kinda fucked up about
this?
But you wouldn't have been you if you
didn't come into this so late.
No.
Hell,
your hope,
but then your hard life,
right?
Your whole life.
You'd loved music.
You could have easily just been on a
path from the time you were in high
school.
We'll always played.
Right.
But I'm glad I never like right.
Recorded anything right until,
yeah,
cause when you're younger,
you know,
Eric Clapton,
I love her clapping.
Huge influence.
Never met the guy.
But uh,
there's a great documentary that came
up,
but you can look back in his career.
He was so young and passionate and
talented.
Uh,
there's one particular record he did
with a guy named John Mail.
It was like kind of the birth of like
rock and roll guitar tone is the first
time everybody plugged a Les Paul and a
Marshall and just crank the fucking
thing and that record that sound,
everybody's like whoa.
Like that was the thing that happened.
But you can look at his career and he
was such a chameleon going through all
these phases and a lot of it was
emulation or re-interpretation because
he,
you know,
got into substance abuse,
but you can see how much his career
shaped him more so than,
and all the people he'd been around and
was friends with an exposed to and him
rubbing off on them and vice a versa.
Wow.
But you'll,
you,
anybody in their twenties is still,
anybody I know in their twenties is
definitely still figuring out who they
are as a person.
Much less than artist.
I'm almost 40 and I'm still figuring out
who I am as an artist,
you know,
cause every year,
you're going to feel different every
fucking day,
much less two years from now and it's
time to make a record.
Yeah.
And you're going to change it up as you
see fit.
You're going to go with what?
What's going on in your mind right now.
Right.
That's a beautiful thing.
Right?
You don't have a,
I mean even though you have like a whole
sort of entity behind you in terms of
like people carrying your stuff and all
the jazz,
it's going on.
All the equipment that's involved in
doing one of your shows are very few
people.
How many people you got?
Uh,
myself,
three members of the band.
We have a tour manager,
we have a,
our side monitor sound guy,
the front sound guy and my merch girl.
See he got blind penile keep us with,
with the driver's side and I'll always
be in one bus and we got one truck to
haul the gear and all that shit.
That's pretty minimal compared to some
bands in,
in respect.
Like what you do kind of shows you do
that to that.
That is pretty minimal.
It's a,
I would like,
I would keep it there as long as
possible no matter what happens.
Just because,
you know,
I've never been like a big lights guy or
any of that stuff.
It just putting away,
those guys in my band are all pretty
amazing players.
We try to go out and put a show on if
you were doing something else though,
like say if you are a part of a band,
that band was being promoted very
heavily by some record company that had
put the band together,
you know,
some,
they do like those manufactured bands or
something like that.
You'd be in a situation where you're
basically required to do commercially
successful and viable music.
You couldn't just free ball like you're
doing and doing whatever you want to do.
Um,
I honestly like,
I don't know,
man.
All I know is that what's happened to me
and most of the people,
most of my friends are people that are
just kind of do their thing,
but there's definitely is that element.
But there's,
you know,
um,
I've only,
I never thought I'd ever sign with a
record label.
Really.
Um,
yeah,
never had any interest in it whatsoever.
And the,
and then we,
you know,
all of sudden things kind of took off.
We met all of them came knocking.
Um,
but like it was working fine by
ourselves,
just sort of subcontractor my team.
And the one thing I,
the only reason any artist should ever
signed with a record label is for larger
recording budgets,
you know,
a larger toolbox right with and wish to
use to make your product,
let's call,
you know,
for lack of a better term.
Um,
so they have like serious places where
you can go to,
you can get to ridiculous studios and
they know we're not,
I mean I still,
I still recording that,
you know,
my favorite city of Nashville is nothing
fancy about it.
It's just money for players and,
and gear you might not have or a and
then mixing and then the more time to
spend in the studio,
it really is.
I don't,
you know,
we,
we did,
we did matter modern and three or four
days because we had to,
it wasn't necessarily,
you know,
dark side of the moon was made like nine
months.
Yes.
That's a funny way.
I don't know.
But yeah,
it was definitely like two separate
extended sessions.
Wow.
You know,
you don't just for me it's the,
that's the fun is sitting in that room
and figuring out how to break shit and
make sounds I haven't heard before.
And you need time to do that.
You need,
um,
you know,
money.
Uh,
but you can,
you can make great records for very
little money to,
so what's the benefit of having a record
company?
They pay for the gear.
Well,
they pay for,
the benefit of having a record company
is simply,
um,
somebody else pockets or you,
it all comes back on you.
And you know,
we don't want to pull the curtain back
too much here,
but you're basically,
I looked at it as like,
uh,
going into business with a bank for at
least two records,
uh,
take out a loan that I'm pretty sure
I'll never pay back because I'm the
recoup,
you know,
it's in there.
But I feel like I'm more of like a,
it all comes down to the bean counters
eventually.
Like,
I know my records sell to 300,000 copies
and at some point they'll have to decide
whether that's fiscally viable to them
anymore because they don't,
they don't make any money off me unless
I sell records.
You know what I mean?
Like they don't,
it was a very friendly,
structured deal like touring and all
that.
Publishing shits completely separate.
It has nothing to do.
I just make records and they have to
sell them and I get to make the records
that I maybe couldn't or would make on
my own,
I don't know.
But outside of that,
a record company or perform,
um,
provides marketing or reach or push or
even sadly in the music business,
there's probably less bullshit and
politics.
There may even be less politics and
Uh,
you know,
I probably would not have been up for
album of the year at the grammy's last
year had I been on 30 tigers as opposed
to Atlantic records.
You know what I mean?
Um,
no,
I think it was a great record.
I know I deserve to be there,
but it wouldn't have happened if you
didn't have that kind of weight at the
table.
It's very honest and that can make you
feel like jaded against it all.
Or you can be like,
okay,
well you know Wiz Khalifa,
they probably spend more money on
marketing one single for Wiz Khalifa
than the mind higher project costs.
So because they make all those records
and Bruno Mars or whoever sells 18
gazillion records,
guys like me get to make records and
that's how it works.
It's a trickle down
and it's all based on the money that
they made from a long time ago.
Really?
And then maintaining some sort of,
they're still making money,
man.
The streaming thing,
you know,
they're all in bed now with the
streaming services we've talked about.
Province
steadily climbed back down,
but not really for me.
Really truly artists crazy.
I have nothing against spotify.
I know people are like,
fuck that shit,
but look at it like this man.
The people that are streaming music,
they're not buying records anyway,
but they're still finding your music.
There's still telling their friends
about it.
They're still coming to your show,
which is how we get paid playing shows.
They're still your family so you have to
either embrace it or go fucking do
something else.
Yeah,
that's good point.
But now when,
when spotify starts kicking songwriters
12 points,
then yeah,
I'll do commercials for them until then,
you know,
but they are doing,
whether you realize it or not,
you see it does count up but it counts
up.
But it is a weird thing when it's very
weird.
All is based on you selling art and you
don't pay for it specifically.
Even even with that,
I feel more like Atlantic went into
business with me.
I fill in many ways still feel like a
very independent minded artists.
Like no,
I don't go to meetings.
Nobody's telling me what to do.
I don't have a manager or even
technically a publicist at this point.
I'm just sort of floating and making
writing songs and making records and
then we'd go play shows and that's if
you could just keep that.
Yeah.
That's just,
yeah.
I've in the last figure five years,
figured out where I want to be and what
parts of it mean and something to me and
I know I'm getting and giving back with
the fans.
Well,
I think it's also when,
if you can stick into that groove,
you stay in that groove right there.
You can maintain who you are,
you can,
you could still explore new ideas.
You can you,
you're not,
you're not being pushed too much.
You know,
if you were,
if you were like being pushed to
constantly produce new stuff and it
could,
I could imagine that wears on artists.
Well,
I just spent so much of my early life
working for other people.
I just made a 0.1 day where I'm before I
moved to Nashville.
I'm not going to do that ever again.
I don't want to work for anybody else
unless it's something somebody I really
admire or as like a really exciting
creative thing that like I feel like I
could benefit from or learn from being
involved with.
I understand that thousand percent but
what's interesting is when I talk about
on the podcast,
sometimes people who don't do that,
they do work for someone to have a job.
They get upset,
they feel like,
it sounds like you're talking down on
jobs,
but the reality is you're working there
for money.
We've all done it.
Everybody's worked for my boys worth
more.
Some of my jobs,
I loved the railroad game.
If this all gave up tomorrow,
I actually,
it could be just fine.
I go back to the railroad and be totally
happy to go out and throw switches 12
hours a day,
having my four days off and make a good
salary,
you know,
whistle while I work,
all that Shit,
man.
Yeah,
but a plant,
it doesn't hurt to have a plan B,
but no working for other people.
It was never something I enjoyed,
but I think anybody that even hears a
say that the reality is if someone gave
them the option,
you don't have to work ever again.
They'd go,
okay,
what would you do though?
He'd do whatever you want.
What I would do,
I would,
I would fill my day up with learning
shit.
You're one of the busiest fucking
people.
I know though.
You don't have a job,
but you,
you,
you were very proactive.
Human being.
You know,
you do,
you want all day long,
but it doesn't mean you're not working.
You're not benefit.
I do whatever I want,
but I earn it like I do shit.
I earn it.
I feel like I have to,
I have to work.
The thing with my job does,
it doesn't feel like work.
Right.
There are parts that did feel like work
that I identified that really have
nothing to do with what I want to wake
up and do this now.
I just don't do those things and now
it's like,
you know,
the travel sometimes feels like work.
The things that I do or don't feel like
working like this does definitely never
feels like work.
Podcasts don't feel like work.
Stand up doesn't feel like work.
Working for the UFC doesn't feel like
work.
Those things don't feel like work,
but the stuff in between those things to
make sure those things work well.
That's the work.
Sure.
Like do,
do you handle the day to day admin or
100% yeah.
I don't have anybody.
I don't have an assistant.
My,
my take is always,
if you need an assistant,
just do less shit.
You don't want someone that you have to
constantly check in on and make sure
that they've got their shit together and
I've had some friends that had
assistants and then your life becomes
their life and your problems come their
problems,
their problems become your problems as
well.
Anybody you invite into your life,
you're inviting their problems into your
lives.
That's ultimately what I've learned and
it's also,
I don't necessarily think in my case
it's necessary.
Maybe other people are more busy and
they need assistance and nine,
I have a lot of friends who have
assistants a lot,
you know,
but I just thought,
I don't function that way.
I I want to,
when I wake up,
I set my,
I have a bunch of Shit I'm going to do
today.
I set my alarm clock and I have a
schedule.
What?
That schedule's mine.
I made yours.
Yeah.
When I went running to the change it
whenever you,
whatever the fuck I want.
Yeah.
But her manager is like the sweetest,
most empathetic human being I've ever
met.
And you know,
he's not just,
he's not just responsible for me.
Well he's like the babysitter and the
mother of the whole family.
But like sometimes if we've been on the
bus for awhile or are rolling Mo more
than anything to give everybody else a
break and do him a favor.
I'll go off on my own and like stay at a
different hotel or I'll go to a
different city for two days.
And he's always like,
you know,
he's from New Zealand and he's like so
sweet and he's like,
fucking gigantic and uh,
you not me book your room.
No,
I got it man.
It's like,
are you sure?
And he's almost like,
I almost feel like I'm hurting his
feelings because I won't let him take
care of my day.
It's like,
motherfucker,
I got priceline.
You know what?
I can do this if people don't expect you
to be doing that though is interesting.
Right.
The one they want to be able to handle
it so you don't have to do the mundane
things that a normal person.
So you got eight other people to take
care of.
Right now I'm grown ass,
man.
Yeah.
I would never want to do what you were
saying.
John Lennon did just lay around,
walk around naked and I can't do it.
I don't think he liked to work.
Yeah.
I mean,
he was a true artist.
Yeah.
I get it.
I mean,
I get it,
but I,
for me,
it's almost like I know what makes me
feel like shit and I know it makes me
feel good.
Right.
It makes me good.
It's when I get shit done.
What makes me feel like shit is when I'm
lazy.
Then I get anxiety depressed,
feel weird.
I don't feel good.
I don't feel like I'm getting anything
done and people think that,
oh,
because I work hard and I'm constantly
doing something that I never feel like
that now I definitely will feel like
that.
I just saw something recently.
They proved that task completion,
your brain releases a chemical that
makes you fucking feel great.
Oh yeah man,
I did this.
I did something on purpose.
When you finish your album,
when you're done phasing.
Oh,
but it's also terrifying.
Of course I'm short.
You're like,
God,
I got to like release that.
Yeah,
people are going to hear that shit.
But yeah,
it does feel like
a release.
It was the best way to put it.
Yeah.
I think everybody should experience
that.
Even in a small,
I think little kids get that when they
earn their fucking karate belt belts and
they see a little kid get a yellow belt
and they tie it on there beaming it's
face.
Oh my God,
I can't believe it.
I did it.
And give him my oldest to hire fire for
anything and it's like you see them
light up that affirmation.
Yup.
Getting something done.
They did it.
It didn't,
I mean think about what specialty when
you're talking about like little
children,
like my seven year old loves to draw.
She's really into art and like she takes
a piece of paper and this is not a big
deal to us as grown men.
She takes a piece of paper and that
paper is blank,
and in her little brain she decides it's
going to be on that paper.
She's like,
I'm going to draw a dog and then boom,
it's a dog and I'm going to draw a dog
that has a wing,
also has a tail and has a tale that
grows out of his forehead and they just
make wacky shit up and she thinks it's
fucking hilarious.
Like gluck.
He's got a tail on his head high,
but in her little mind she's learning
that she can do whatever the fuck she
wants with that time then you shouldn't
do that.
No one's saying anything and little kids
gravitate towards that man.
When little kids start drawing,
they gravitate towards this expansion of
the creative aspects of your mind,
like whatever it is in your mind that
causes you to have these ideas,
whatever in your mind that causes you to
think of a story that you want to write
down or up a drawing that you want to
try to accomplish and try to put down
those little things to a kid or magical
because they didn't have any of that
before.
I mean they,
they just learned how to talk.
She seven,
there's only been talking for five and a
half years,
you know,
all that other stuff before is jibberish
and all of a sudden she's sitting in
front of the pad.
No one tells her what to do.
Little seven year old like,
hmm,
I think I'm going to paint today.
She gets,
gets out the paint and it just puts a
little,
this,
a little of that.
You're flexing those little muscles,
you know,
just as if you were doing pushups,
your flex in those creative fields,
you know,
and to encourage that with kids.
That's what we all love.
We all love doing something and people
say,
well,
I'm not very creative.
I just like working with wood tea that
is fucking creative.
Like carpenters,
a guy named Craig,
you built a house,
motherfucker.
Do you understand you can't do that.
I can't do that.
I'm in,
I'm in all of that pleasing.
Grew up around construction.
It's fucking hard to do.
You build a bad ass house.
That shit is to do.
Or people that are like highly
mechanical inclined can can just take a
car completely appointing and put it
back together in the garage.
I've always been really envious.
Build cars.
That's art.
That's art mechanics.
There's an art to even being a mechanic.
Just doing it all.
Perfect.
Putting it together,
using your mind,
thinking out how did it maybe a good
bore out this and put that in and swap
this out.
And what's the issue with the vehicle?
And there's like a,
there's like there's a creative aspect
to anything that's really satisfying and
I think that,
you know,
we kinda pound that out of kids,
man.
Yeah.
I think that's
very true.
We pounded out of true,
we will.
The,
it has no,
it doesn't serve capitalism.
Yeah.
You know,
so,
uh,
the,
like I was saying earlier,
I had this just train job and the first
year I was there I was just like out on
the ground,
like throwing the switches and
disconnect and the trains and hooking
them back up and that kind of thing.
And then I got,
I got promoted to the,
what they call the yard master or like
whether you your a yard balls and you're
in the truck and you're sort of in
charge of the inbound and outbound
manifest and everything that comes in
and how,
what gets blocked apart and switched
over to this track and you're building
other trains and you've got to get them
out of Tom.
And like as soon as they put me in that
job,
it was like the greatest job I've ever
had because I was playing tetris.
You know what I mean?
It was just like fucking Baron von,
which housing and my little fucking
truck with my 8,000 radios like Taryn
trains apart and just watching it all
like happened and get it out the gate on
time.
And get it became like a high,
you know,
cause it's high pressure.
Very dangerous.
There's only three guys out there and
making all this shit.
Have you got the guy driving the
engineer to do breaking apart and then
whoever's on the back like sort of
playing the chess board?
Ooh Yeah.
I was like,
this is fucking awesome.
I got a big old thermos.
All that shit.
Some good jobs for sure.
But if somebody came up to you in the
middle of that good job and said you
don't have to do this ever again,
you do whatever the fuck you want,
you would leave.
Okay.
It's a good job.
What I did.
Yeah,
it's a good job for a job.
Well,
I fucked up.
Took a management position after that in
these offices.
Totally out of my element getting
screamed at on the conference call with
some other asshole.
Didn't get the train out on time.
Isn't that crazy?
Because you went from having this cool
high pressure job that makes you feel
good to making more money,
but you'd only get that juice anymore.
Yeah.
I was like,
man,
this is way too stable.
I better be a songwriter?
No,
I burn out.
I hit vapor lock cause it was just those
other,
I'm going to go to fucking golf.
I can't imagine shit with other dudes
and khaki pants now.
Like it's port came pretend to be this
guy.
Like what am I thinking?
Those are the guys that I think of when
I,
that thoreau quote.
Uh,
most men live lives of silent
desperation.
Yep.
Those are the man I think of those men
that have fallen into some salary
position where they're not happy and
they want to get out and they don't know
how well they have.
They have the,
the downfall of being highly efficient
individuals and other ceos recognize
that and be like,
I can put you on and working 90
hours a week and you're going to get it
done because you won't let yourself
fail,
but you'll probably fucking drink five
pots of coffee a day and listen
sturgeon.
Yup.
If you keep going,
you've got a good position in this
company.
I'm telling you,
you've got a bright future.
He didn't make it happen.
401K 51,
nine.
[inaudible] I'm making those numbers up.
All that shit.
That's crazy.
It's most people,
you know,
people get tired of people hearing this
because they don't know what to do.
And so I didn't know what to do forever.
I mean,
I would just work,
you know,
but then you do,
well,
you always played music but never
thought it was something you could even
do for a job.
You would have non well known where to
go or how to do that until uh,
Mary's my loss Martin mean Wednesday and
I was like,
man,
I'm really unhappy.
And she's like,
it's because you're supposed to be
playing music,
dumb ass.
And uh,
so I was like,
oh,
that's probably true.
So,
but if you did it earlier,
you wouldn't be you.
It's the craziest thing ever.
It's like you had to go through all that
bullshit to get the sound that you have
now to get to the soul behind it that
you have now.
That's the sound of a man who suffered.
Oh yeah.
It's a sound of a man who understands
that's the woes as me.
That's real.
That's a real,
there's a real emotions,
you know,
like that Jolene song that we're talking
about,
it's your all is lost though,
man.
If it had happened when I was younger,
it had been way more interesting to
watch.
I would have fucked it up so hard.
Right.
So good.
No,
I mean that's props to Justin Bieber and
we were hitting me and I'm just keeping
it together.
It's hard to,
uh,
it's hard to complain.
Yeah,
it should be.
You've got a great,
great,
great band and families healthy.
You're in the groove.
I'm in the room doing my thing as far as
I want to.
You're in what my friend Vinny shoreman
calls Hakalau it's when you,
he's a hypnotherapist.
Trains does a lot of mind work with
fighters,
like a mind coach and he's like,
there's this state that you get in where
everything just flows,
everything's flows.
And that's does what you've,
what you figured out how to do so
brilliantly in your life is after you've
been through a bunch of bullshit,
he figured out to get to a place of
success and then you're able to just do
your thing.
That's,
that's your flow.
Like you found your thing.
That's uh,
yeah.
And I had to learn that even in the last
few years,
you know,
cause it's so easy when I've always
said,
you use a metaphor and you're on the
train.
It's hard to tell how fast it's going
and more importantly where it's going.
Because a lot of times you don't really
have any control or even say so in that
matter.
And in some regards,
you don't want to know how the sausage
gets made.
But then
I am at a point now where as,
as,
as far as I ever want to go because I,
I'm,
I have all the freedom to do what I want
and it might not sell as good or as,
as great as the last one did.
But like I'm having fun and it's going
to be okay.
You know,
I don't think you're going to have any
problems.
I think the real issues have always been
in the past about distribution in terms
of like radio play,
a album sales,
so we don't do,
and I like you.
Yeah.
And a guy like you,
you're so locked in,
you're in,
you came along at the right time,
man,
you came a lot,
you'd locked in the Zeitgeists but you
came along at the right time of the
Internet where like you're like she'll
look and right time.
I mean definitely not all luck,
but there was definitely like
Roto song about turtles that year cause
it would have been very different
outcome.
It would have been like that year that
they had the two meteor movies.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
Right.
Exactly.
You can't have a fucking,
Canada.
Canada
wrote a book this year with the same
title as long as me and he's getting all
kinds of shit on her and I was like,
I didn't fucking come up with it.
Like don't send this to me.
Yeah,
he stole it.
Yeah.
Turtles all the way down.
People don't want to look into things.
I didn't know what it meant until he
explained it.
I don't still don't know what it means.
I just thought,
you know,
yeah,
it was cool.
Now I know what it means,
but in a very dumbed down for the fit to
make this a standalone podcast explained
to people what turtles all the way?
Well,
it's a jocular expression,
uh,
more of,
um,
a funny way to put what is originally a
concept as far as I know that was first
described in detail by a swit priest's
name appeared on Chardanne.
Uh,
all about how about the Omega point,
the universe and how all consciousness
amidst from this one central point of
origin,
where the whole thing banged out from,
and it's all just expanding and
reciprocating back to itself and like
absorbing everything going on.
But it's this one point where all things
spiritual,
scientific,
metaphysical,
all matter in the universe,
all fucking knowledge emits from,
and he got blackballed from the Vatican
for preaching that Whoa.
Cause he was like,
you don't necessarily need to stand in a
building to talk to God because God is
everywhere and all around you and inside
you all the time,
whatever you want God to be or you know.
Um,
so the,
the,
I got it from a Stephen Hawking book,
we're,
and it's weird,
you can go around the world and there's
all these ancient civilizations,
whether it be some native American
tribes or parts of Far Eastern Asia
where they find like these adherence to
turtles and elephants and older culture
and Hindu mythology.
There's even a Hindu illustration
representing sort of a similar figure or
myth that it all set on the back of this
great turtle like flying around in space
because they,
the hills,
those animals in such regard as old and
wise creatures actually turtles are the
oldest living species on the planet.
They predate crocodiles.
Wow.
And the,
the,
the symmetry of their shell designs,
no matter what species,
it's always 13 pieces,
which a lot of the old tribes thought
had something to do with the lunar
phases of the sun and how it was all
tied in together with,
you know,
um,
hello.
Anyway,
lost along the way of saying that song
was
written as a result of a lot of fucking
reading.
No,
not necessarily taking drugs,
you know,
it wasn't that the original,
um,
one of the more original calendars.
Who's narrow your 13 lunar cycle
calendar?
Is it mine?
Yeah,
mine are.
I think that is what it is.
I think it is a Mayan calendar,
but it's all these things I sort of
found or symbiotically we're connected.
I was reading at the time and it just,
and I was about to have my first child
and was just like,
man,
I want to make a country record about
all this shit.
Or like,
you know,
write a song about the book of the dead
and,
but as a traditional country record and
then incorporate some classic rock
Psychedelia.
So that was all that was,
that's how I found you.
People Online,
like,
Yo,
they do skype making psychedelic country
music.
You've got to have him on your pot.
Then everywhere you go,
people are making like handy,
like hand blown glass,
third eyes and shit.
You know what I mean?
Like you get,
you get some real interesting
characters,
man.
Get a little too many of those.
Throw it out there like that.
Just too many bongs out there.
Right.
People still rock the bond though.
It's gotta respect that.
You know,
it's like driving a manual car.
I never was a bond guy.
It's too heavy,
man.
I got shit to do,
I can't.
Oh,
that just peeled down or the DAB thing.
The,
I got friends in Colorado,
California now.
The first time I ever did with shit.
Uh,
this is pretty embarrassing story,
but my,
my buddy,
you know,
they were all like California,
Colorado guys.
They roll pretty hard.
I'm not really a heavy smoker man,
to be honest on the road.
It keeps me occupied from time to time.
But if I'm writing maybe,
but at home,
you know,
there's no need.
So it,
the first time I did that shit,
I didn't know what it was.
You know,
I just pulled it like it was a big old
bong rip and they're like,
everybody's face was like,
oh,
you know,
it was like I need you instantly know
you just did something you shouldn't
have.
Oh No.
And uh,
I was like,
Oh fuck man.
So I sat down and looked at a couple of
minutes.
I just started getting really cold and
clammy and I was like,
Yup,
I'm going to Puke.
So I went over and was like,
I'm fucked this guy.
So I right in the sink and I was like,
dude,
I got to go home.
I feel like dog shit now.
And I'm pretty sure I'm dying.
So I had,
we lived in this apartment and I was
like,
went out the door and turned the corner
to go down the hallway to my,
and it was full on vertigo,
like the hall.
Every time I took a step,
the hallway got twice as long.
That was like,
this is fucked up.
My wife was out of the country on work
at the time and I was like,
I remember I was sitting down in the
hallway just like trying to get my shit
together man.
Cause was I thought I was having a
fucking heart attack.
It was just like pat like sweating and I
remember this voice saying,
get up you stupid junkie.
Fuck before somebody comes out here and
sees you,
you know,
sitting in the hallway like a dumb ass.
And I managed to like pop out of it and
as soon as I get back to my place and
sit down on the couch,
everything was fine.
But it was just so initial and the rush.
I was just like,
I don't,
nobody needs to be that stone
that fast.
I'm sorry.
Yeah.
What kind
of milligrams are you getting you think?
Or they just had like Neil head torch
thing,
which is $3,000 glass piece.
I was like,
you guys are taking this shit way too
seriously there.
You could be cured and fucking cancer
somewhere right now.
I'm pretty sure if they put the effort,
energy,
and mind power.
And have you seen the laser bongs now?
Some I got a video sent to me.
The daylight sky,
like a pressure activated laser bong.
He like shoots a beam and ignites the
flower of Jesus like that.
Why is,
what's the fuck's that guy?
Come on,
man.
The thing is they might be curing cancer
space colonies that somebody is going to
need to build.
You know how many cancer patients are
taking dabs?
That might be the key out here.
Probably a lot.
Get them on it.
If I,
if I had,
if I was dying of terminal cancer,
that's when you want to be that high.
But at this thing,
do that again,
Jamie.
Yeah.
Oh,
that's it.
Look at this thing.
Of course he had a fucking hates the
light laser.
This is fucking insane.
Now how do you not go blind staring at
this?
So he's heating it up.
It's cooking.
It's a good question.
And then he takes a big hit.
Wow.
Yeah.
Anyway,
the,
the medical strength stuff.
I totally understand.
And this seems like you go blind,
like you were standing at a welder.
Yeah.
You know you have to wear a welding
mask.
My very,
very close to my life in my life
recently that went,
went,
it was dealing with that,
uh,
vertigo,
no,
like heavy medical issues,
health issues.
And we got him some edibles and he's
like,
it's the only thing that made it okay.
Like that discomfort.
And so when I had to have a sinus
surgery,
we talked about this when we played the
grammys out here last year,
I was sick as fuck man.
Like I was getting all year for like the
last year and a half on the road.
I was getting his horrible sinus
infections all the time.
And I will,
I just assumed it was allergies.
Tennessee's really bad about that.
And we'd go to Texas or Atlanta places
in October when all these crazy dogwoods
are kicking off.
And I would lose my voice.
And you know,
by no fault of my own,
it became very frustrating from a
touring standpoint.
Cause I felt like I was always sick.
And it was because I was,
so,
we flew out into the grammys.
I was all plugged up,
couldn't sing,
obviously biggest gig in my life,
kind of stress in it.
So the label guys sent me to this doctor
who looked up in there and realizing I
probably had my nose broken at some
point or just a really deviated septum
when I was younger.
So I like a broken air filter.
But then when they did the scan,
they,
all of the cavities were just completely
caked with residual bacteria and
infection.
And he's like,
he's like,
if you get on a plane and fly home,
you probably going to get meningitis.
So we had to play the grammys.
He put you like nuked me with all this
shit.
I don't even know what he did,
but it opened it up for like a day.
It's where I was able to sing.
So the next day,
the whole band,
they flew home.
I just stay out here for like nine days,
I think can go in every morning,
twice a day for Ivs,
for him to clean that shit out so I
could home.
Wow.
So then we came back and did the surgery
to correct it all,
like went in there and scraped and
cleaned them all out and shit.
And uh,
along with the,
the Septum they fixed the Septum.
So I haven't had a single issue since
all that happened.
I haven't been sick one time,
which is like changing my life.
But while I was recuperating,
long story short,
I didn't want to take any of the opioid
or the fucking pills that they gave me
to deal with the pain.
I was like,
I'm not taking that shit.
You know,
you're going to give me this for four
weeks.
Like no,
no way.
And so I just got a bunch of medical
strength edibles and my wife and the
kids,
they had to come my way to run a house.
We had it bad to be here to like recover
and Shit and man just laying in bed,
listening to headphones stoned out of my
mind for like a week recovering.
And that's was kind of awesome because
you feel like when you're actually in
pain or when you need that type of heavy
type of alleviation,
what,
what it is actually doing an offering
you in terms of relief.
And it gave me a whole new understanding
and respect for like the medical side of
that shit.
Here we are back on pot again.
But um,
and then my buddy who dealt some pretty
serious cancer said it was literally the
only thing that made him feel better.
So what did it do for you?
Like see your,
your terrible agony.
Yeah that was all fucks all plugged up.
I had like all this galls in your shit
and know I could feel where they'd been
in there like behind right.
Been scraping and I can just,
you know,
so it immediately like all that was gone
and you just sorta get really docile and
euphoric and rely on me so fucking high.
But like it didn't affect me in a,
in an overdose.
He nauseous sorta way like too many
edibles cause your body actually needs
it.
Needs it.
Yeah.
I laid there listening to headphones and
came up with the record.
I'm working on that.
That's great for me cause it was like I,
that's what I want to do next,
you know?
Um,
yeah,
it's,
it's a crazy ride,
those edibles.
But if you can take that ride,
you get something out of it.
And sometimes people take the ride and
the feeling is just to,
to self examine a tuna the nor yet and
to sing.
Sometimes she just can't handle a on a
mass legality issue.
I mean,
if anything,
I know it's just gonna fuck pot up,
you know?
But from a medical stance,
I do,
I can't see any reason why we're still
even talking about this.
Yeah.
You know?
No,
it doesn't make sense.
We were were being fucked over by giant
pharmaceutical companies that are making
billions of dollars and they would
realize how much more money they would
be losing every year.
If marijuana becomes fully legal,
they've already lost money for sure.
I guarantee you there's people that are
buying edible marijuana right now that
would have bought pain pills.
They know it.
Also insurance companies,
you know,
on the job accidents.
Oh,
he had weed in his system.
We're not going to pay that.
So I got my life insurance now.
I man,
this is crazy.
I did one of the first interviews I ever
did.
I think I talked about what like the
first time I moved to Nashville and how
like I didn't really know anybody and it
was like 2005 and it was a different
town then.
So like I basically
I said I spent most of my time listening
and playing blue grass and drinking,
which is pretty much what everybody
does.
The first year they moved to Nashville,
but uh,
then I said like,
after that,
while I moved out to Utah and got this
job and you've got sober was working on
with them.
So somebody put on my wikipedia page
that I've talked about my struggles with
alcohol and those people read that Shit,
man,
when I had to get a life insurance
policy,
like they showed up,
they'd read all the interviews and like,
wow,
you've been really open about this and
that.
And I was like,
yeah.
And they're like,
so you do the whole medical test.
And of course that test positive for thc
because I'm on the road all the time.
And I was like,
but I don't,
I don't smoke it.
You know,
I vape or edibles.
I don't actually,
I'm not a smoker.
I've never smoked cigarettes.
But they list you as a smoker and now I
have like a criminally fucking insane
yearly life insurance policy because of
course like,
you know,
they think,
well,
if a musician too,
this guy's going to die.
We can't fuck.
Yeah.
The exact same thing.
It's insane.
Like,
I don't know,
I don't even smoke,
but I'm listed as a smoker and it's like
literally $9,000,
some crazy fucking premium just to make
sure my family's okay if I die on a
business trip.
Yeah.
They,
um,
they tested me and uh,
they said,
well,
you tested positive for pot.
I go,
yeah,
that's cause I smoked pot.
You're need to know that.
Like,
what are you doing?
Trying to pretend I'm not hardly ever
died from smoking pot.
No,
it's stupid.
It's a dump thing.
Unless you think that I'm going to do
dumb shit cause I'm high all the time.
If that's what you think,
but that doesn't make any sense.
You need to test how healthy I am.
Guess what?
I'm fucking healthy,
right?
Yeah.
I work out all the time.
Super healthy,
eat good.
I know what I'm doing.
Like you don't know what you're doing.
The problem is you don't know what
you're doing.
You're the insurance guy,
right?
You don't know what you're doing.
If you knew what you were doing,
you would look at each individual and go
at this guy's fine,
this guy's healthy.
It's guys concentrating on his health.
This guy who doesn't smoke pot and just
eat sugar all day,
this guy's kind of fucked though.
Oh,
that guy's a real fuck.
That guy is fucked.
This guy who,
who's on adderall because he's got a
prescription for add and you'd have a
problem with that.
That guy's fucked.
All these other pieces.
There's a lot of people that are fucked
out there and these insurance companies
that think that a guy who smokes pot,
it's more likely to die.
There's no statistics to back that up.
There's no statistics that say that
people smoke pot or more likely to get
diseases or die of some sort of a
fucking debilitating syndrome that came
about because of overuse of thc.
It doesn't exist,
but they're not even testing you for
alcohol.
Didn't even tell.
They tell you,
ask you how much he drank but not
testing you like they can't test you.
It's not your system anymore.
Really strange cause uh,
in the navy and the railroad,
there were very stringent,
obviously highly stringent drug
policies,
but you know,
drinking your ass off every night is
completely fine.
Completely fine.
You know,
don't,
don't smoke a joint at 5:00 PM,
but killed that six pack and come in
here and build this train the next
morning.
You know,
the,
those were always the guys that made me
nervous.
Not only that,
there's like a culture of honor behind
it.
Like how much you can handle your drunk,
how many,
how much can you handle your drink.
And Bobby had 17 fucking beers.
A swear to God,
Bro.
You would think he had zero.
He's right there.
Good for bobby's
an animal.
Yeah.
Bobby puts him down like there's like a,
a badge of honor that goes to that.
Bobby's meanwhile he's taking something
that's completely hindering his thought
process is his stability.
His emotions are all out of whack.
Like he's fucking drunk as shit.
He doesn't know what he's doing.
He's,
he's wrestling.
His brain is wrestling with alcohol
right now,
which is one of the weirdest depressant,
you know,
awful.
One of the weirdest drugs.
It's a [inaudible].
You spend a lot of time on the road
traveling constantly.
One,
you can't really drink,
especially at our age,
it just does things.
But he looked at a room full of people
every night that are Amazon's really
drunk or like if you work with people.
Yeah,
I don't,
I refuse to,
I don't like really let people drink and
my band on the road and it's cost me
players cause they'd rather drink than
be in your band and it just,
would you say you don't drink,
can they have a glass of wine with
dinner?
Well,
there's,
yeah,
well that's like,
you know,
a beer or two to,
there's not getting Hondas,
tennis people that shouldn't drink rye.
You know what I mean?
Like the guy that has one drink and
instantly turns into a different
motherfucker all together and then by
the time he's on that third one and
everybody's like,
how much longer we got to do this?
There's a lot of those guys out there
too.
A lot of people I didn't know that
existed until,
uh,
the first time I met one one where the
switch goes off and they get your blogs,
jekyll and Hyde drunk verbalize,
verbalize.
Wow.
That's a good way to put it out there.
Like,
and shit gets weird.
Well,
and they're moving around like they're a
normal,
a woke person Hashtag woke.
Yeah.
This is a,
a weird contradiction we have in this
society.
We were constantly drinking drugs in the
form of caffeine,
constantly getting drugs in the form of
whatever your doctor prescribes you for
depression or anxiety or adhd or
whatever that is.
Constantly going out and having drinks,
taking drugs,
the drugs,
being alcohol,
taking,
taking a whiskey drug and a vodka drug
and no one,
no one thinks anything of it.
And they're like,
well,
I don't do drugs,
drugs all day,
all day.
It's so few people who don't do any
drugs.
Some drugs are super beneficial.
I think about that.
Those we'd edibles that made you write
this album.
That's a beneficial,
what didn't make you right?
Yeah,
but you were on it when you wrote it.
It was,
oh well I'll give it a little credit.
I was listening to some old records,
early love and it's like,
yeah,
that sounds good.
You could feel music better when you're,
hi Brittany Spears.
Sounds good.
You got enough,
man.
You kidding me?
Turn that shit up.
Like,
yeah,
Brittany.
God bless her.
I like Miley Cyrus's music while I'm
high.
I'm going to admit it right now.
It's Song Malibu.
It's good fucking song,
man.
It's a good song.
Don't laugh at me.
Jamie
mocks me as if a young herd it young,
cute girl can't be a real artist sign of
a bitch.
Like the first thing
you played in the studio here in the,
in the July super loud.
Yeah,
I'm serious.
Oh yeah,
of course.
And the gentleman was filled with
speakers.
Good for you.
I want it to uh,
my name drop real quick cause yesterday
was probably one of those,
one of those days were like,
yeah,
this is why I do this.
Um,
well I ended up going up to Malibu to
Rick Rubin's house and it was playing
him some of the,
some of this record I'm working on just
to get some feedback.
And it's one of those moments when you
like,
you realize you're sitting like Rick
Rubin's like all engine stolen.
His cows head banging like a fucking
cave man.
And he had literally the best sounding
stereo system I've ever heard in my
life.
Could only imagine,
I mean better than any top Ray's studio
monitors I've ever sat in front of.
It was just like,
Yup,
it's really Rick Ruben too.
That's the other is the coolest part was
that was the only thing that was in the
fucking room was the couch.
He was like literally like the Tiki,
a guy sitting in the chair in front of
this town,
you know,
it's like just the stereo on the floor
and this is fucking empty room and I
don't know what it was or what the
speakers even were.
I'd never seen anything like it,
but I bet it's like when Mason's has
Henry Rollins says these speakers we
were talking about the other day,
they're like a quarter million dollars.
Is that what they were?
Quarter million dollar speakers in his
living room these days.
Towers,
these two towers.
And they just,
I mean,
I've never,
I've never experienced it,
so I don't know what it's like,
but I got to assume that you've spent a
quarter million dollars for some
speakers.
I thought,
I thought I'd heard some pretty
impressive speakers in my time,
but this was like,
like some really holy shit.
This exists kind of moment.
Right,
right.
It makes sense.
It doesn't even have to be that loud.
Right.
It's just that the sound is so powerful.
Right?
Yeah.
The only thing,
I don't want a car,
I want,
I want a Samurai sword and written
Ruben's home stereo.
That's,
that's what I'm aspiring to now at a
Bronco and the light Saber Bronco
lightsaber.
Yeah.
I gave,
I had a bronc out,
a bad ass bronco.
My second one we moved,
we moved to Nashville and Bronco.
My wife,
my wife's,
it died and I ended up scoring a sweet
one,
this redneck and Livingston,
Tennessee or somewhere a borrow from
him.
It was a [inaudible] 92 and he'd like,
Matt blacked it out.
My buddy bobby took it for like a month
while I was on tour in Europe and
stripped all the interior out.
We rhino hide the entire liner,
took all the,
all the plastic,
everything.
It was just like a fucking Mad Max death
trap.
And we had these bucket cold beer,
leather racing seats.
We bolted in.
Oh.
And then I had two kids and mom and it
was like,
I'm going to die driving in this thing
and had a 400 wins or rebuild with
Kansas header is the whole God damn
thing.
Like when neighbors hated it.
And,
um,
I gave it to my drummer when his truck
died and he actually liked,
unlike most kids of the millennial era,
really put time and money and effort and
work into,
it was like fixing it up and making it
his,
and then he's getting married so he's
getting a tree,
got a real trucks.
Now that Bronco is gone.
I feel like it's probably time to find a
sweet bronco.
Yeah.
That's a good era to the ojs bronco year
is more understated Bronco.
Yup.
The locking hubs,
the move is to get one of those and keep
it plain Jane on the outside.
But on the inside just put a battery.
That's where I really want to do is uh,
um,
cause I don't,
I'd like to have,
so yeah,
it's very unassuming.
And then on the inside,
just look like a rocket ship with all
the accoutrement that can be done
easily.
Um,
and very modernized,
user friendly,
but they give you what you're going to
pay to do that.
Man,
you could fucking go by 1970 [inaudible]
or something.
You can buy a house,
right?
Yeah.
You could buy a house where you live for
real.
Yeah.
By a fat piece of land.
Actually Nashville,
the real estate has gotten pretty crazy.
I don't live in Nashville anymore,
but uh,
I don't know it much like Austin.
I mean five years from now there may not
be any music in Nashville cause I don't
know how many musicians are gonna afford
to live there.
Yeah.
That's why I keep,
it's so fast,
like an explosion,
an explosion.
And it logistically in the
infrastructure of the traffic,
it's like a marriage reversion la.
Now when did it start?
Hard to say.
I mean,
I are,
the first time I lived there it was in
2005 and it was a different city than
none of this had happened.
Um,
a lot of the hip bars now,
like that could have been eight people
in there on a Friday night.
Um,
I'm not really sure.
I moved there 2011 and I think it was
right in the last two or three years.
The,
or all the gentrification started around
there and they were building these,
you know,
what used to be the blown out
dilapidated parts of town in the high
rises,
started going up and,
and,
and shopping centers and that sort of
thing.
And uh,
and there's still very much the old
Nashville,
it was just,
it's almost like two or three different
cities in some cases in terms of
personality.
But the influx and all this change is
sort of changed what it,
what it is.
But like Austin used to be a thriving
music scene,
but now it's like all the tech industry
moves down to the cost of living and
properties.
Just insane.
Like struggling service industry job day
to day as we say,
artists,
people trying to make it can't,
they're all having to live like an hour
outside of town and commute in for the
gigs.
Wow.
That's crazy.
And what did,
what do you think was the catalyst?
Like what,
what caused the launch became a cool
place to be.
Okay.
Yeah.
I mean the,
well there was,
there was a,
I'm not sure.
Well,
it terms of what's always been a
publishing hub,
right?
No,
it's not.
I mean it's a music town,
but there's,
and there's all kinds of music.
They're not just country music,
but about when did that TV show come
out?
There was a big Nashville TV show that
would have been about four or five years
ago.
Do you think that fucked it up.
All those Dorks,
they go,
Whoa,
go to live there.
Well,
I mean there's definitely tours from
that TV show,
kind of a match.
Mason Jar.
It's such a soap opera version that
isn't really that far enough away from
how that world probably works.
I never saw it.
I didn't either watch them.
My wife watched it one night and I just
was like,
no,
I've been there a bunch of times playing
xannies
done.
Okay.
Now that little street where you're
talking about that corner on eighth
avenue,
they're xannies.
You got doug was corner.
Then there's like some,
there's a lot of shops that I go to on
Sundays there,
the auctioneers.
I was like,
dude,
he's the oldest state sales and then
really cool furniture.
But that little pocket,
that intersection is probably one of the
few remaining bastions of funk left in
Nashville.
Like that's probably my favorite little
corner in Nashville cause I can just
stand there and it still feels like
relatively similar to what it probably
felt like 30 years ago.
You know what I mean?
Um,
but a lot of other things change around
things that don't.
Does that make sense?
It does make sense.
Yeah.
Those are cool little pockets then,
right?
Yeah.
I think I got a good friend Billy Wayne
Davis.
I met him at xannies
one night back when I was on twitter.
He was,
he reached out like a plane here
tonight,
free tickets.
So my wife and I went,
we liked comedy and got to know him and
they ended up opening a tour.
Forming that place is one of those
places where you know it's good and old
based on the number of dead people on
the wall.
Right.
So you're just walking around and you
let go up Richard,
Jenny,
you can walk in and taste cocaine.
Yeah,
it's,
you know,
well,
I mean,
the photos,
the head shots,
right.
A dead comedians.
There's so many of them.
You know,
that place has been around for ever,
aren't you?
Coming to Nashville?
So,
yeah,
like a couple of weeks.
What day?
I don't know.
I should probably know.
I'm doing the Ryman on,
um,
the 30th,
30th,
yeah,
the 30th on the Ryman with the Golden
Pony,
Tony Hinchcliffe.
Then we're in Charlotte the next night.
That's what I like.
A little short weekends.
Bang,
Bang.
Four shows,
two shows Friday,
two shirts.
Saturday.
Have you done,
have you done the ramen before?
Yeah,
a couple of times.
Yeah.
I love it.
It's fucking off.
It'll be out of town,
man.
I'm bummed.
What are you going to do?
What are you gonna do?
Like in that book?
I'm always coming through,
come through like once every year.
It'd be a year and a half at most.
I love it.
I might come through again and do
xannies um,
after this,
when I write my new hour just to fuck
around,
stretch it out because you really want
to stretch it out at a comedy club.
You don't want to stretch it out in
front of 3000 people.
It's just not,
it's not a good sign of good,
uh,
development ground.
It's not the room to try things out.
The big rooms in the room,
that's when you're done.
You got it.
You got the set.
You know what you're doing,
you fuck around while you're up there,
but you basically have a structure for
your act.
You have a structure for each bit and
occasionally y'all deviate.
But what I don't want to do,
I don't want to work out brand new
material in front of 3000 people.
Fuck that
one night.
Well,
I think what came to watch your show at
the store?
Yeah.
And this was,
uh,
like a year ago and you had to jet right
after the set and go to Pasadena for
another set.
My buddy that I brought with me,
we were going to hang here,
see who comes out and like Jeff Ross or
somebody comes out and he's doing his
bit and right in the fucking middle of
it,
the back curtain opens and Chappelle
walks out and just kind of like taps
were also on the corner on the shoulder
like fuck off,
I got this,
you know,
and just jacks the mic and pretty much
everybody else has set who was supposed
to perform that night.
And he stands there for like three
hours,
man,
just sitting there,
I was like,
dude,
this will probably never happen again in
your lifetime so I'm not fucking
leaving.
And we just sat through the whole time
and he sat there rocking Tequila bombs
and get drunk and just really talking.
There were times where it was the
funniest thing I've ever seen,
literally.
And there were times where like it kind
of got dark and you're like,
where's the fuck's happening?
Where's this going?
And he was working things out.
And then later on those netflix specials
land.
And I realize I've already heard like
90% of these jokes and cause the guy was
just saying I'm going to go hijack the
main room,
work my shit out.
Cause I got it like that.
I'm Dave Chappelle,
you know,
but it was fucking amazing.
Yeah he does that a lot where he'll just
drop it into place and just do a set and
that's,
that's how he kind of works as material
out.
You know,
he just kind of drops in and keeps
tweaking it and it,
it's,
it's if he has a structure,
right?
Like,
if he has a few ideas that he's talking
about,
he can just riff.
And especially if he's drinking,
just go on stage and then the drinking
and then he's always got dudes behind
them that are taken down notes,
letting them know like all you talked
about this day,
and I'm sure they record it too.
And they'll go over it and eventually
boil it down to like what that Netflix
special was the two Netflix back that
shows you how prolific that dude is to
put out a Netflix special and then a
year later put out to Netflix specials,
right?
And then Netflix is like,
we'll take it what he got.
And he was like,
Hey,
I wrote this one this month and I'd like
to put it down for all eternity.
He cool with that.
But most people like you write something
and it's a good solid year before you
even consider putting it in a special,
you know,
some guys were doing like a special
year,
but too much of it was like half cooked.
It was like if you just waited six more
months,
this thing would be like an all time
great special.
But instead you're banging them out one
a year.
You never get the essence of the thing.
Well his thing too,
he part of his thing I think is is
making it look like it's so easy because
the night at the comedy store and it
just like,
it did feel like he was just sort of
making this shit up on the spot and then
you see the netflix specials in,
it sort of feels the same way.
Like he's just being dave and be like,
he would was a little subtle things that
I noticed like probably 10 times
throughout the night.
It really awkward moments.
He would call the waitress to get him
another drink,
but he would,
he would only say borrow whore.
And every time you say it they get a
little,
a little more awkward,
like a little less appropriate each and
every fucking town.
We're probably like it.
Eventually everybody in the room was
like,
that's not really cool.
And then at the end of the night,
he's like,
the last thing he says like,
I'm really sorry,
I called you bar hourage don't have any
fucking jokes.
And he walked off the stage.
It was like,
yeah,
that's how Dave writes.
That's one of the ways he writes.
But he's,
um,
he's got it down,
you know,
he's
got it down to a science and the other
thing he does is he just travels to
towns,
just decides to travel to a town and
then go on stage,
show up.
I'll feel more.
Yeah.
But I mean,
he doesn't even,
he'll do that,
but that's booked.
He books that you have to craft a book
that shit nine months.
Right.
Like if he works somewhere else,
he just shows up.
Like he'll work at a comedy club and
just show up.
Gotcha.
You know,
it's like I was in Denver wants and he
just showed up.
I came in the green room after the show.
It was a,
after the late show,
Friday night,
I went backstage and Dave's in the green
room.
I go,
what are you doing man?
And,
uh,
I think it goes,
hey Joe Downs fucking around here.
You want to go on stage?
He's like,
shit,
I ain't go fuck.
Yeah.
I grabbed them,
bring the people back in.
People were already getting up and
leaving.
I said,
ladies and gentlemen,
get back.
Dave Chappelle's here.
Of course he wants to go on stage as
well.
This is he there twice.
It's what he does.
He does his thing,
you know,
but it's just weird to say like,
oh like this guy is so free.
He could just fly into a town where he
knows his friends are going to be,
he doesn't even have to call you in
advance,
you know,
he just flew in and I see him like,
Oh yeah,
get up there.
Like he's,
he's his free as a bird.
He does like whatever he wants and then
he does these netflix specials,
they pay my ass load of money and then
he just does shows whenever he wants to.
But his creative process is like almost
like engineered around being loose,
like doing whatever he wants,
go on where he wants to go.
Doing what every once and then writing,
you know,
and then figuring out on then riff in it
and just fucking around.
It's fascinating.
Fascinating to watch.
It's like jazz almost.
Oh,
it's very much like,
yeah.
I mean he's um,
he's also got B and Dave Chappelle down
to a science.
Like you were saying that you are in the
sturgill simpson business.
He's in the Dave Chappelle business.
Yeah.
It does what Dave Chappelle wants to do.
That's the key,
I think.
I think that's the key.
If we could all be in the business of
whoever the fuck you are,
whatever you do well is I like to write
songs and make rutgers and pretty much
say no to everything.
I think that's a good life.
Dave seems to be on a,
on a much grander scale.
You ain't like yourself.
I mean,
is there any point of the day,
were you ever do anything you don't want
to do?
No.
Not Anymore.
I mean,
I do things that I know I have to do
that I'm not looking forward to,
but that's mostly like exercise shit.
Right.
You know,
like sometimes I'm just not looking
forward to it and I have to force myself
to do it or writing.
I love writing,
but sometimes I have to force myself to
sit down in front of the computer.
But other than that,
like I know it on a computer.
Yeah.
Really?
I can't,
uh,
write,
write by hand too,
but when I write by hand,
it's really just rehashing things right.
When I ride on a computer,
I see there's no way I can write with my
hands as quickly as I can type.
I can type pretty quick.
So if I'm,
if I have an idea and I don't want to
hear my voice,
so I don't want to say it into a
microphone,
I want to just figure out what the beats
are of things.
Interesting.
Yeah.
Well I was gonna say that I always write
by hand because
usually the meter or the phrasing,
there's a way it makes me think about
it.
It goes down right the first time or as
opposed to them just like writing poetry
on a computer screen or whatever,
you know,
you don't necessarily have a sense of
uh,
the beat,
whereas like I want things to flow a
certain way and land on,
on hits and that and I usually just like
throw all the continents away.
Hmm.
You know,
Bill Clinton wrote his entire memoir on
um,
like legal paper.
It doesn't surprise me.
He wrote it on lecture.
They go,
what's your writing as well?
I think he wrote it on like a regular
notebook,
like maybe one of those,
uh,
black and white ones that used to get
when you were with the,
with the splatter recovers stacks of
those things the best.
I still reach out to those when I write.
I,
uh,
when I write on a piece of paper,
I'm really just reminded myself most of
the time.
Occasionally I have an idea that I have
to like circle and I put an x next to it
and it's all slow.
But if you read my notebook,
you think I was a crazy person.
There's something to that too.
In terms of memory,
like if I learned a long time ago,
if there's a song I want to learn and
you got to remember all the words,
uh,
I'm never going to remember him until I
just sit down and write that song down
on paper.
Like one time.
Once I write it on paper and see it,
it's like it's there.
Yup.
And like whether it's mine or somebody,
I only forget the words to the shit I
write.
Weirdly.
That's kind of like,
and shows it never fails.
If I get lost or forget something,
it's always a song I wrote.
Never really 8,000 old country and
bluegrass songs like would just pull out
of my ass on a diamond,
remember all that shit.
But it's always the ones I wrote.
I wonder why.
I don't know.
Man.
That's interesting.
That makes sense to elect,
right?
Because the other ones that you
remember,
they just had an impact on you.
Like they mean something to you or it's
the one you wrote,
like he like comes out of nowhere.
It goes through you to your pad.
Right?
It's like,
it's almost hard to recapture that state
and then you're like a normal person
trying to remember what you thought of
when you were in that zone.
Whereas if it was a song that somebody
else made.
Yeah.
Like,
Oh,
I love the song.
I know.
I don't know if it's like,
because you're reacting to it strongly
more strongly.
I mean,
uh,
well this is,
I think there's a thing of creativity
that involves the no self,
right?
There's that state that you get when
you,
oh,
there's a lot of shit that I write where
I go back over it.
Like,
Mike,
how can I write that bit out?
And then I'd go back and read it and I
don't remember any of this.
Half of it.
I don't remember.
I took us the hard,
the hardest part though,
those getting to that lack of self.
Yeah.
I mean even I think that's with any art
when you're not thinking about it or
self aware or have any preconceived
notions about where it wants to go.
Yeah.
You know,
do you smoke weed and,
right.
Okay.
I don't ever like do one way or another.
Specifically,
I'm just,
whatever I have written while I'm high
written one,
I'm not,
you know,
what about performing
generally?
I don't enjoy,
it depends.
I can't,
I don't,
I don't really like to smoke weed
anymore.
It's something about the way it hits me
when I inhale it and hide.
It becomes more heady and internalize
and like any anxiety or the paranoia of
people talk about that.
The only time I've ever experienced that
is when one of smoked weed.
But my problem is I don't like going on
stage stone anymore because you're so
ultra sensitive my ear because like I
already struggle with it enough.
I'm hearing everything happening and
dissecting it all,
like hypercritical in real time and you
can't do that and performing let go.
So you kind of have to like,
it's two different brains.
Um,
but if I'm up there singing and looking
at an audience,
if I'm a stone,
I know enough about myself to know like,
I'll,
I'll get internalized and just only
start listening to the band and the
music.
And you sort of forget that.
Like there's all these people there.
You have to give a show too.
And again,
maybe that is the show and we get lost
in the music.
And then I've also played some of the
best gigs I've ever played in my life,
uh,
on edibles.
Cause you,
you know,
sort of like an anti anxiety and just
like very free and you feel everything
much more delicately and in terms of
response,
but it's not something I would like.
Oh,
we got to get high.
It's good trump template gig.
You do or you don't?
I don't honestly kind,
but I mean is you do what you do
whatever you want.
You don't.
Yeah.
There's no,
if you are,
it's just this is tonight.
Right.
You know,
it's not like you have a ritual,
right?
Yeah.
I like a drink right before I go onstage
a shot.
So that messes lot.
I'll call messes with my voice.
I get that.
You gotta stay away from it.
I just like
a little,
just that little feeling that you get
with one shot,
like,
oh,
here we go.
I like that.
Well,
no,
I did.
Uh,
what about food?
Oh,
that man,
it depends.
I don't like eating close to a show,
especially certain,
it's just not good.
Not Good.
I'll eat a big lunch and then just fast
and I'll eat after the gig most times
because I jumped around a lot and get
into shit.
Yeah,
me too.
Um,
and then one time we did this like radio
thing or some shit and I was,
or I couldn't fucking sing.
Anyway.
My voice was going as this freebie
throwaway thing for serious and we'd
been in there setting up and rehearsing
in the studio all day and then they
realize like,
oh,
we haven't eaten.
I'm fucking starving.
I'm gonna play gigs.
So we had some fid delivered and I ate
it like 10 minutes before we're supposed
to be correctly.
Most people don't even know what fun and
uh,
it just bombed me.
Dude.
Like your worst nightmare.
You're out there like trying to really
push and singing on a microphone and not
shit your pants.
Um,
so I've learned my lesson.
I
hit the wall the other day in my house.
I don't know what the hell I ate,
but I literally had to put my hand on a
railing so I could squeeze my butt
cheeks together harder so I couldn't
shit myself.
Jeez.
It,
it broke through some weird barrier
where I thought I knew I had to take a
shit,
but I was thinking maybe I could let a
far to how first when I'm on my way to
bathroom,
I don't know what I was thinking.
The gambler,
Bret took a step.
I took a step and all of a sudden it's
like,
like if I had a water bag inside my body
and it just broke and then I'm holding
it all together with my asshole and
squeezing my ass cheeks and the fucking
abdominal pain is like,
whoa.
The litter,
it's,
I feel like you remember when you were a
kid,
used to put your thumb over the garden
hose and just try to really clamp that
fucking thing down and like you got to a
place where you stopped all the water
from coming out of the garden hose,
but barely,
I mean fucking barely.
That was my ass hall the other day.
And I'm holding onto the railing,
just wheezing.
And I did these little baby steps like
this towards a toilet where I was not,
I wasn't even picking up my legs.
I was just sliding my legs over,
barely,
barely got my pants off and it was like
a broken fire hydrant came out of my
asshole just uhg.
And I was like,
where was this?
Where'd this come from?
Like five minutes ago,
there was nothing wrong with me.
I felt 100% normal.
I wouldn't have imagined that this could
happen.
Right.
And then all sudden it's flying at me.
That's terrifying to think could happen
at anytime.
You can be on a plane.
Yeah.
Stuck in your seat and you just shit all
over your socks and your pants and then
just runs up your back and down your
legs.
It can happen
in anybody.
Have you ever had full blown,
absolutely horrible food poisoning and
coming out both ends and you literally
think I might die.
Yeah.
I had a real bad once.
Well,
I've had it real bad twice,
but that Barracuda than I used to have
this cool 1970 barracuda.
It was named the sick fish.
The reason why I named it the sick fish
because I got food poisoning.
I ain't linguine with clams and
Illinois.
There's no fucking clams anywhere near
And those things got me hard,
man.
I couldn't even make a fist.
The next day I was walking around like a
Zombie.
I was dead.
I spent the whole night throwing up and
shitting myself and then the next day I
was just dead.
I drank like five or six cups of coffee
cause we had a film,
this thing where we were,
they were putting the engine in the car
and they were going over the design.
I was like barely able to stay awake
while I was doing that.
I was so wrecked.
It's all I had at one time,
uh,
from this Chinese buffet and it was a
for or you know,
it hit me hours later.
It was later that night and all of a
sudden it was just,
it was in this bathroom for four or five
hours and it was those things like it
was the worst shape I've ever been in.
But in the,
in the back of your mind,
you know,
you're like,
it's okay.
I know,
I know this is food poisoning,
but like it's good.
It's okay,
it's going to hit,
it's going to go to a point and then,
and then it just,
throughout the night it just kept
getting worse and I kept asking,
where's this point going to be or do I
need to go to the hospital?
Because there was very uncommon,
you know like up.like abdominal tremors,
shit from puking so hard and your
muscles are just spasming and no,
you can die from it.
I mean people have died from Eco Lye
poisoning.
There was a
scene in food inc where they talked
about this little kid,
they got food poisoning from a,
I think it was at Jack in the box and he
wound up dying was right.
Yeah.
It's horrible.
It's a terrible way to die and you're
ingesting some sort of a poison and it
just takes over.
Your system just kills your cells.
Your body can't process it quickly
enough,
can't get it out enough.
You're shitting yourself and throwing up
and doing everything you can to get
whatever the fuck is inside you out,
right?
Yeah.
All at food.
Food on the road,
we play it pretty safe.
Yeah.
I'll skip meals.
A lot of times I'll not eat if the only
alternative is something like really
shitty.
Yeah.
Just because,
not because like,
oh,
I'm a health nut,
but it's just not worth it.
You don't know.
I bring a lot of protein bars.
Okay.
I bring a ton of protein bar,
so if I'm stuck and I need eat something
I just down like,
uh,
we have a bunch of on it.
Protein bars.
I like those.
I like those quest bars and I mean sugar
in them.
I like a Mussel farm.
I some good bars just,
I don't live off of them,
but it's way better than that.
I'm not getting a burger or you eat
sugar?
Very little.
I'll give him like last night I had a
piece of apple,
rhubarb,
strawberry,
rhubarb pie though with whipped cream.
Ooh.
I went deep,
but that's rare.
I did a thing a while back.
I kind of got pressure,
but I tried to see just how long,
as long as I could without any sugar and
carbs you go.
I was like 12 days something crazy.
That's,
it was nice man.
You,
well this is hard because everything has
sugar in it and you just,
but and then,
but after even just abstaining that
short amount of time when I did eat it
again,
at first it was like everything tasted
so sweet.
You could really understand how much
we're getting drugged with food.
Um,
but my thing is coffee.
I drink coffee in the morning.
I'm not a breakfast guy voted in but I
just can't drink it straight cause it
takes like a bucket full asshole.
I got to cut it with something.
I could cut out coffee with my life.
I could probably cut out sugar.
Oh did you say you cut it with some sort
of sugar cream and sugar and they
usually see I just used cream man or I
drink these.
Did you like this?
The Caveman's I get a bunch of those in
bad.
Yeah,
that we'll have lunch sent to you.
How do you get the mud but down?
I mean,
it's just like,
I don't get my bud from this.
Right.
I don't know what I ate that made me get
mud,
but,
but whatever it was,
it turned out to not be anything.
Like I had that one terrible shit and
then the rest of the day was golden.
It was no problems.
It's like something got in there and
microbacteria I ate a lot of probiotics.
I don't know if that helps.
I'm hoping that that helps and that when
I eat something funky,
all the good stuff that I eat.
Like I eat Kimchi almost every day.
I drink every day,
but I hate as cancer.
So I don't eat steak very often.
I don't think state cancer.
I like,
you're like Raul or like really,
you know,
rare,
rare.
Oh look,
your raw.
So I just know that the,
the,
the rare occasion when I have a steak,
I'm going to get the Cias.
It's just worth it.
But,
uh,
it makes me eat red meat very little.
Now what was the last time you had wild
game?
Oh,
man.
Like real gail wild.
Um,
probably
when,
uh,
when I was out in Utah,
I worked with this kid who was a big
hunter and he would bring in elk,
like filet medallions that are like
hamburger and he that he,
he would,
he lived in Wyoming so he could pull
like two or three extra tags year,
much like the 18 deep freezers full of
every possible cut of meat you can think
of made from elk meat.
And he would bring it in sometimes when
we were working and cook that shit in
the first time I ever tasted it,
I was like,
I don't ever want eat beef again.
That was the most delicious meat I've
ever tasted in my life.
I basically eat it almost every day.
Elk almost every day because I,
we shoot an elk,
I sh I try to shoot an elk a year.
You don't always get one.
Obviously this year I got lucky.
I got to,
I scheduled two elkanns.
Um,
and I figured I was going to strike out
if not both of them.
Definitely one of them.
And I just,
I got real lucky on both.
Yeah.
Wow.
Again,
it is.
There's,
there's definitely a having really good
guides that good guides,
you know,
cause I had a long be yourself and your
family here one year off a year.
And I heard a lot of it to my friends.
I give a lot.
I give Gary Clark some,
some elk,
honey,
they took some elk.
Wish you around,
man.
I'll give you some elk too if you lived
right here.
Well,
we're,
we're living now.
I'm probably gonna sit on my back porch
long enough.
It'll probably be pretty easy.
Well,
um,
Kentucky actually has a new elk
population over the last like 40 or 50
years.
I think they've,
uh,
reestablish it to the point where it's a
hunting destination now.
They opened it up.
Uh,
I think you and I were talking about,
I think we were,
uh,
it used to be flooded with it back in
the 1800 800 amount and they,
they repopulate it.
I want to sit in the 90s,
early two thousands,
and now there's so many that they're
opening it up again.
Yeah.
Shout out to the Rocky Mountain Elk
Federation.
That's what they do.
They,
uh,
they established a habitat for these
animals were down in sort of in the
south east corner,
uh,
around the smokies.
Man.
It's,
it's,
it's really weird.
A little wild Turkey and deer be amazing
there.
I saw Armadillo in the woods at my
house.
I was like,
no fucking way.
Like can't and ensures shit.
Like they've migrated that far over and
up.
Wow.
So they're really vomity.
They don't really do much good.
Do you have any elk near you?
There's gotta be when were in were you
ever hear it?
I don't hear him.
How long have you been in this new spot?
A while.
We really haven't even been in,
I stayed there off and on a couple of
times when dealing with contractors,
they just,
they just really got finished and out of
there,
which is perfect.
I got to go back to work,
but you won't really know until
September.
Right?
You're starting here.
I'm
so many.
Turkey and deer.
It's kind of a going to be an issue.
I can walk outside and kick the fucking
Turkey out of the library.
He's a crazy man.
They get aggressive with you too?
Yeah,
I don't mind.
The only thing I tell you what man,
we've got all the snakes and the spiders
and all that sugar.
A secretary up in around playing with
like baby copperheads and the creek.
My Mom spanking the shit of me when she
called me like,
cause I don't worry about this stuff.
I tell you it was fucked up.
My wife found she was sweet.
We get lady bugs that come like in this
time of year they tried to come in and
the on this,
it's like some porch and she's sweeping
a pile up and found a scorpion.
Oh,
I found a bunch of [inaudible].
I was like,
what the fuck?
They're Scorpion and Tennessee now.
I got to worry about that shit.
So that's pretty crazy.
Yeah,
I couldn't believe it man.
I mean I hate spiders,
but that's like a whole other level.
They're supposed to be in the desert,
aren't they?
That's what I thought.
But there are two species of Scorpion,
native Tennessee.
He's basically like equivalent get stung
by honeybee,
but they just look so evil.
Man.
I don't want to walk into the bathroom
and have to be like checking on her,
my toilet bowl from fucking scorpions.
I always assume they'll that shit.
When you see a Scorpion,
I assume it kills you.
Well,
you know why?
Cause you're remember the original clash
of the titans?
Oh,
that's right.
When you're moving the blood dripped out
of Medusa's head bag and it turned into
a giant scorpions.
That was just,
I was a kid.
I saw that.
So it's like there were giant,
the giant like staying in that guy.
That movie was fucked up actually.
It was pretty fucked up,
but it was good.
It's terrible when you watch it now.
That's where I got Harry Housing Music
Movie,
right?
Where it was like stop animation from
some soap opera or whatever his name
was.
I don't know.
That's right.
Medusa as right.
Cracking Harry Hamlin Hamlin here.
You fucking Hamlin.
And I know that.
And the guy that played,
uh,
Haiti's,
you know,
like the Red Devil,
God's turn into like a dude.
I forgot all about that movie.
If you saw that kid,
it was like the tbs that when I was a
kid that would play that and beastmaster
back to back like every fucking two
hours piece masters.
So,
uh,
but yeah,
the original clash of the titans man
would dusa did a number on me.
What he got.
I think that was any of it.
Look how bad it looks.
I think that might've been the first
time I ever actually saw boobies wasn't
medicinal signs the blood.
It's the ground pins pop up.
The robotic owl.
Look how bad the fucking special effects
were.
But we were like,
dude,
I'm in.
That's how they did it.
Yeah.
You had to believe.
Wow.
Look at that dude.
Sturge well you better get the fuck out
of here.
You're not going to catch a flight.
Okay.
It's two 20 right now.
Yeah.
Should do that.
We've got to get you moving next time
you're in town.
I got to grill back here.
I got to grill and I got some meat.
I'm gonna Cook for you.
Thank you.
We'll have a meal.
Awesome.
Sit down like men will drink next time
you come to Nashville.
I won't be there and I won't be able to
repay the favor.
Well,
I'll be back again.
I'll be back at Janie's.
Okay.
See you soon.
Bye everybody.