Good morning everybody.
It's morning,
it's like a real job.
This is like a regular,
like a regular job.
Uh,
this episode of the Joe Rogan experience
is brought to you.
Buy naturebox.
Naturebox is a,
a way that you can get delicious healthy
snacks delivered to your home or your
office.
I haven't delivered to my house,
but uh,
they're the official snack of the Joe
Rogan experience.
Now official.
Really yummy stuff and you can get it as
good for you as you like.
Meaning,
you know,
you could order pretzels or if you want
to,
you can go gluten free.
Low Sugar.
They have zero trans fats,
zero high fructose corn syrup,
nothing artificial.
And they're great.
They taste delicious.
There's,
there's the ones that you guys will
never see this show.
Raja cashews.
They're not getting in here.
They never make it.
They get to my house.
I opened the box,
I pop it open.
I said,
where the cashews give me them bitches.
I never,
I'm never bringing them in here.
I just tell you right now Jamie,
never get any of them.
Sriracha cashews.
Unless they send like a triple order.
They're too good,
they're my favorite new snack,
but naturebox has free shipping anywhere
in the US and it's just an awesome.
I'll alternative to vending machines.
Snacks.
If you're at work and you're looking for
snacks all the time and you hit that
vending machine and you're like,
what can I eat here?
That doesn't make me feel like a piece
of shit.
Usually the answer is nothing.
You know,
maybe might go with potato chips over
candy bars are fucking cookies or
something stupid.
But you could,
uh,
you could eat fairly clean.
Um,
I mean,
you could,
you could get really clean where you
could have like a,
they have these spicy pistachios that
are delicious.
Or like I said,
you can go with pretzels,
but I recommend the Sriracha cashews.
Oh,
they're so good.
They're so good.
Dude.
Trust me,
it would be your favorite thing if I
ever bought them in.
They'd never make it an end here,
son.
Um,
but naturebox,
uh,
just allows you to eat,
eat healthy and have it delivered to you
and cut out all the nonsense of that
terrible feeling that you get when you
eat crappy food.
And just get angry at yourself.
Um,
but they have a south Pacific plantain
chips are another one.
Fantastic.
That never make it in here.
They just get devoured.
But go to naturebox.com/Rogan
and say 50 percent off your first box.
That's naturebox.com.
Forward Slash Rogen naturebox.com.
Forward Slash rogen.
Enjoy it.
I enjoy it.
And like I said,
they're the official snack food of the
Joe Rogan experience.
Would you say enjoy it and enjoy it?
Brody,
Stevens and joy.
It.
Uh,
we're also brought to you by [inaudible]
dot com.
That is o n n I,
t on it is a human optimization website.
We sell you the tools that you can use
to optimize your health,
your life,
your fitness.
We sell things like strength and
conditioning equipment like kettle bells
and battle ropes and mace balls and
these,
all these things that we use for steel,
maces,
all these things that we use for
strength and conditioning workouts as
well as healthy foods like hemp force
protein powder.
I'm earth grown nutrients,
which is an excellent supplement to your
average diet.
The average healthy diet.
Most folks,
the reality is you don't quite get
enough nutrients.
You don't quite get enough healthy
protein,
don't quite get enough good foods and
you're in your diet.
Most of us are too busy.
Most of us have jobs.
Most of us work well.
There's,
there's certain ways that you can add to
your diet where you can give yourself
the building blocks,
give yourself the tools that just the
healthy nutrients that your body needs,
like earth grown nutrients in earth.
Grown nutrients is an awesome new
supplements that we have that's a
combination of a bunch of different
things and antioxidant Brent blend that
is all food based based on things like
Peruvian purple,
corn,
ice fruit,
grape skin to a ton of different
ingredients.
And it has a jaw dropping,
75,000
ORAC score.
The ORAC score is the antioxidant score.
Um,
all of that is explained on,
on it far better than I'll be able to
explain it to you.
It also has a power green blend with
Spirulina,
Alfalfa,
oat grass,
Kale,
barley,
wheat grass,
all these different things.
You can add it to a smoothie,
you can add it to just a glass of water
and drink it,
and what it does is it gives you a
little cushioning.
It gives you just sort of a nice
supplement to cover the distance between
what most folks eat and what really your
body actually needs and deserves and
what on it is designed for and what
were.
What our goals are is to give you
everything that you need to optimize
your health and your fitness and just to
sort of bridge the gap between what the
average person takes in their life and
that he has in their body and what you
really could actually use and need.
And when it comes to the strength and
conditioning equipment,
we just buy the best shit we can
possibly find.
Whether it's ab wheels or medicine balls
or kettle bells.
We try to find the highest quality
stuff.
We try to find the stuff that we find
that is the most beneficial for strength
and fitness and then we sell it to you
at the most reasonable way.
Rates that we can.
If you use the Codeword Rogan,
you will save 10 percent off any and
supplements yet on it.
That's o n n I t and use the codeword
Rogan.
Alright,
Randall Carlson is here.
It's early in the morning.
Why fuck around Jamie.
Cue The music,
the Joe Rogan experience podcast by
night trying to get the old brain fired
up in the am.
It's very unusual that.
Well,
I usually get up around this last
time.
So do a podcast around this time.
Randall Carlson,
ladies and gentlemen,
uh,
I first met Randall quite a few years
back in Atlanta.
He,
any,
it blew my brain open with a bunch of
crazy talk about asteroids and just all
kinds of crazy shit.
Sacred geometry.
And you're a very interesting cat and
you,
uh,
you got a lot of cool stuff to talk
about.
So,
uh,
I'm glad we finally got you here on the
podcast.
You were a much requested guest on my
online forum so folks know about you.
They know about your work and your ear.
Oh,
all these years of,
of uh,
and on anonymity.
And now I'm suddenly A.
I don't know if I'm ready for this job.
I think you're ready,
dude.
I,
I feel it from you.
It's,
this is your time to shine.
All right.
Joe,
Carmen from you.
That's all it just altered requires.
Well,
we had a great conversation when we
first met and we did.
Ever since then I've been trying to
figure out a way to,
to repeat it online.
There's videos of us actually having
parts of the conversation,
but it's,
there's music in the background.
We're at the comedy club and uh,
yeah.
So,
uh,
um,
you,
you first,
uh,
I don't remember what we first started
talking about,
but you blew my mind when you started
talking to me about the Holocene crater
and um,
that this pretty distinct evidence that
there's been more than one events on
this earth besides the one that
everybody knows about the 65 million
year ago,
one with a big chunk of rock hit the
Yucatan and killed the dinosaurs,
but there's been a series of those and
that these things may very well be
responsible for a lot of the cataclysmic
stories that are in epic of Gilgamesh.
The Noah's Ark Story,
all these different fables and tales of
ancient traditions may be based on these
cataclysmic disasters and now since
we've spoken science has started to
validate a lot of your theories and
ideas even more substantially the
discovery of this nuclear glass that
they find all throughout Europe and
Asia.
Tell me about all this stuff.
Well,
did you catch the thing about a month
ago?
Um,
I think it was in the New York Times.
Most of the major newspapers are a group
of former NASA astronauts and scientists
came out,
said we were new evidence was showing
it.
We're probably somewhere between three
and 10 times more likely to encounter
things than anybody had previously been
estimating even five to 10 years ago.
It was a pretty major article in most of
the mainstream media.
You mean by encounter things by getting
hit by something?
Yes,
of course.
You remember what happened on February
15th of 2013,
right?
What happened on February 15th?
Was that very Russian?
Yeah.
In.
What was really interesting about that
is because everybody was at least people
who are interested in this sort of
thing.
We're kind of looking to the sky anyway
because this was the closest I'm pass of
a of an asteroid.
I'm coming within 17,000
miles of the earth at the same time.
This object totally out of the blue came
in and exploded over Chelyabinsk
Siberia.
So it was very interesting and
coincidentally,
if there are such things as coincidences
that here when we're expecting this very
close fly by of an asteroid,
a near Earth asteroid coming actually
within our geosynchronous satellites,
within the orbit of those satellites at
the same time that this object is coming
within 17,000
miles of the earth,
suddenly unexpectedly,
here comes the second object and
explodes with the force of about a,
uh,
I believe it was about a 50 kilo ton
nuclear weapon.
And of course it had exploded.
I'm quite high about 20,
I believe,
about 18 to 20 miles in the atmosphere.
And so it didn't kill anybody.
However,
the thing to bear in mind is if that
object had been just a little bit bigger
or it had been a little bit dancer or
the angle of approach had been a little
steeper.
Instead of 1600 injuries are probably
could have been 1600 or more casualties
at that point.
I think the world would have really sat
up and taken notice.
But,
um,
it was basically just a warning shot.
It seems to me that our knowledge of
asteroids and meteor impacts and things
of that nature,
these are our actual experience on it is
based on this short window that we call
human history,
which is for the earth,
such a brief,
tiny blink of an eye.
It is,
although I like to point out there that,
you know,
when you say human history,
we're talking,
you know,
4,500
to 5,000
years ago.
Generally,
I think most historians of,
of ancient history will usually say that
the emergence of cuneiform writing in
the Middle East marks the beginning of
official recorded history.
But you've got to bear in mind,
we,
modern humans have been around a lot
longer than that right now as far as the
hard evidence goes to switch,
which is what I like to refer to.
Um,
which means skeletal remains,
skeletal remains of humans.
That as far as we know,
are basically no different than than
modern humans.
If you put flesh on him and dressed him
up in modern clothes and they walked
down the street,
you wouldn't think they were anything
unusual.
Modern skeletal skeletal remains with
modern humans are now dating between
$150,
180,000
years.
So when you think about that,
compared to what we actually have our
have our record of history or record of
history is one 20th,
one slash 25th one 30th of the actual
time that we humans have been here now.
Now it could be that modern humans have
actually been here much longer than than
180,000
years.
We have no way of knowing at what point
we moderns first appeared on this
planet.
But when you think of 180,000
years compared to let's say in round
numbers,
5,000
years,
it means that there's a lot of the human
story missing.
And the thing that's always intrigued me
is that given the assumption that they
would have had the same intelligence as
us,
the same,
they've got the same brain case size,
the same cranial capacity.
So one would assume that with brains as
big as our modern brains,
they were able to think they had four,
thought they were able to plan ahead,
presumably have a,
uh,
you know,
have some kind of a tradition that could
be passed on from generation to
generation and accumulated learning.
But what we see is that there's
basically no record to speak of,
of what people were doing culturally.
Um,
and,
and that has led a lot of scientists to
assume that for all those tens of
thousands of years and hundreds and
hundreds of generations,
that people were essentially living
nothing more than a subsistence,
a kind of a hunter gatherer existence.
Right?
But what they haven't taken into account
is the extremity of some of the global
changes that have occurred in,
in the interval that we humans have been
here.
And as we go through our discussion
today and it will pull up some images,
I think you'll begin to get an idea of
how extreme and how sweeping some of
these changes have been and why in the
aftermath of those changes,
we wouldn't,
shouldn't expect to find a whole lot of
hard cultural evidence.
Because what you'll hopefully begin to
appreciate is that we're some of these
events of the scale and magnitude that
have happened probably a dozen or more
times in the 150 or 200,000
years that we've been here.
Were those events to occur today.
Ten thousand years from now I'm
archeologists would be sifting through
the,
through the rubble looking for any kind
of evidence that we had ever been here.
And that's the thing we have to get into
our consciousness,
you know.
And well I guess if there's any,
any implication of the work that I've
been doing is that we certainly can't
take our president position for granted.
It seems very difficult for us to put
into perspective numbers like 10,000
or a hundred thousand or a million.
We know that the universe has been
around allegedly for 14 billion,
so the earth is four point 6 billion.
Those numbers are so weird to us.
They don't register.
They're just like,
I know 4 billion is more than 400,000,
but both of them are alien.
You know what I mean?
It's like,
I don't think we could really wrap our
head around the idea that 10,000
years is such an incredible length of
time that if you left a car out for
10,000
years within,
you know,
three or 4,000,
it would be absorbed completely by the
Earth Joe within three or four
centuries.
Really?
Oh yeah.
I mean,
if you look at,
I mean steel body cars I remember very
well as a kid,
not far from where we lived.
There was a auto junk auto graveyard and
um,
all the teenagers around there who were
racing cars back in the fifties and
crashing them up and everything,
they seem to end up there.
And as a kid I used to like to go and
kind of hang around there and play in
some of the old cars,
but they were already after sitting out
there for 10 years,
I mean already well underway to,
to rusting away.
I mean,
once that process of oxidation begins to
take place,
it accelerates not far from where I live
in Atlanta.
There was an old iron bridge that had
been built around the 18 nineties and
it's no longer there,
but by the,
by the 19 eighties,
it had almost rusted to nothing.
And within a century it almost rusted to
nothing.
Yeah,
metal does not last long.
When exposed to the elements.
There was an interesting series of shows
a few years ago.
Um,
I think it was,
it had to do with the idea of if,
what if humans just suddenly depart?
What if we took humans out of the
equation?
What would happen to all of the
infrastructure left behind just under
normal kind of gradual listic change
that we're used to within the last few
centuries.
The upshot of it was the 10,000
years from now,
it's pretty much gone.
You know,
I mean if you look at the,
the,
the great buildings that make up all the
metropolis metropolitan areas now of the
world,
most of them are steel frame structures
and they're clothed in a skin that,
that will keep the elements out maybe
for a half a century.
But without maintenance,
I mean,
you know,
that the,
that,
the Golden Gate Bridge up in San
Francisco is constantly ongoing,
undergoing maintenance because if you
stopped maintaining it immediately,
it starts decaying immediately.
It starts rusting and interesting.
If you think about,
if we suddenly,
if humans left the planet 10,000
years from now,
some,
uh,
interstellar anthropologists arrive,
what would they see that would indicate
that we had been here?
What do you think would still be left
after 10,000
years?
There's actually two things that
they named in this particular program.
I bet you can guess one of them out
rushmore.
Mount Rushmore.
Good,
good guests.
Yes.
That's one of them.
And of course the great pyramid with the
other one and that's it.
You know,
everything else has gone.
Wow.
Now,
when you,
when you now begin to factor in,
the thing that I've been basically
working with is the idea that we have
these intermittent,
I call them nonlinearities.
A discontinuity is within the normal
orderly progression of things.
The catastrophes,
if you will,
superimpose a few of those in the
process and basically 5,000,
10,000
years from now,
you're not going to find much to show
that we had been here.
That's incredible.
And when you see structures like a go,
Beckley tapping,
which is within the last couple of
decades,
been on earth in,
in Turkey,
which has really thrown a giant monkey
wrench into the timeline of the hunter
gatherer,
a transition into the modern
agricultural,
a city.
We were in a weird state because people
are starting to dig up these things and
go.
Beckley.
Tempe was a completely unknown structure
until this one farmer or hurt or had
found a stone.
And,
uh,
started to unearthing it and then
realized it was these huge stone pillars
of an unknown civilization carved with
three dimensional shapes of these
animals.
Some of them weren't,
aren't even native to the area.
So it's incredibly confusing and
purposely covered up 14 to 12 to 14,000
years ago,
which means that who knows how long it
was there before it could have been
several thousand years old when they
decided to cover it up,
but it was purposely filled in and
enormous area purposely filled in
somewhere around 12,000
years ago.
Could it have been purposely covered up
in order to protect it and preserve it
could be right that we were hoping or
they were hoping rather than someone
like us would come along,
not us,
like definitely not me.
Maybe you know,
someone would come along and uncover it
and then go,
Whoa,
what's,
uh,
what's this all about?
Like maybe they knew that there were
going to be moments in time where these
things happen,
these impacts these asteroidal impacts
and that there needed to be some sort
of,
a way of keeping track or some sort of a
way of preserving well that that would
probably be one way of preserving it for
sure.
And the other thing would be just like
you mentioned the two things,
Mount Rushmore,
integrate pyramid,
of course,
are both built of stone,
which is obviously much more durable
than steel or you know,
the fabricated materials that we're,
we're making today.
Even plastics,
plastics are gonna Degrade over a few
millennium.
But if you want to preserve something
for Malania,
make it out of stone and making
monumental.
Um,
and you know,
we're looking at at something like,
you just made an interesting point about
it.
Could we,
how much previous to,
to the,
to the burial edit actually been there.
And you know,
it's difficult to dates don't.
The way you would dates known is,
you know,
you can use various,
um,
oh,
cosmic magenic ways where when you
expose stone to atmosphere,
it's going to accumulate cosmic rays
which caused changes within the stone
that can actually be measured.
But if it's buried,
it's not going to be subject to cosmic
rays so that you can't date it that way.
Which you would probably have to do is
date.
Find some organic material within the
soil matrix or matrix of material around
it and date that material,
but even there,
see that's not going to tell.
That's only going to give you a minimum
date,
so in other words,
the structure's there for who knows how
long they decided to bury it and they
bring in the material and bury it,
and if some organic material is in that
soil,
it's not necessarily going to be
indicative of the age of the stone
structure itself.
It's going to be indicative of the time
at which it was buried and how did they
determine that it was buried at 12,000
years ago.
Was it the uniformity of the depth of.
I would assume now I haven't made a
study of Go Beckley tappy yet.
I'm hoping that when I get a chance to
hang out with Graham Hancock,
I'm going to get filled in on all the
details of that.
I don't know specifically about that
other monuments.
I do suspect that,
you know,
name Pedang is probably very old.
Seen Indonesia,
a lot of the monumental stone work that
we find like a bailed back where you
have these monstrous,
a megaliths probably go back to
pleistocene times.
And when I say Pleistocene,
I'm talking about the period from like
10,000
years back about two and a half million
years ago.
The time during which there has been
this succession of glacial ages and
Interglacial Ages.
Um,
and you know,
you mentioned the term policy,
we've talked about that.
Holocene is essentially the modern
geological epoch.
We've been in this Holocene epoch for
generally they say 10,000
years in rough numbers,
although it's becoming much more
precisely dated now.
You'll find a lot of references in the
scientific literature that says,
gives the date 11 point six or 11,600
years as being the onset of the
Holocene.
Which is an interesting date for me
because I don't know if you've ever read
plato in his accounts of Atlantis.
There's two of his dialogues,
courteous and tomatoes in which he
describes Atlantis and he gives the
dating and near a,
at least on three separate occasions.
And he always places that you know,
there's this whole success,
the whole lineage of the story goes back
to Solon,
who was a historical character,
unauthenticated historical character who
lived at about 600 BC and he was a law
giver and poet in Athens and due to
political pressures and stuff,
he went into a 10 year exile and during
that 10 year exile he went to Egypt and
it was there that he presumably would've
heard the tale of Atlantis from elderly
Egyptian priests.
And he was told and came back and then
told the story to his grandson who told
it again to,
to several individuals before it
actually got to socrates and Plato who
presumably wrote it down.
But what it's interesting is that in in
Plato's account,
he,
he gives the dating for the demise of
Atlantis as 9,000
years prior to solange exile to Egypt.
Well,
given that,
that took place and give or take a
decade or two,
600 BC,
we go back,
that's 2,600
years ago.
Okay.
Add that to the 9,000
years.
And we've got 11,600
years ago now,
according to Plato's account,
he says that it was shortly after this
great war between the Atlantic eons and
to produce Athenians,
that there was this tremendous cataclysm
and Atlanta sunk beneath the waves.
So he's giving that date at 11,600
years ago.
We now know from the scientific record
that at 11,000,
600 years ago,
there was a major climate transition and
there was a catastrophic warming spike
that was associated with a,
a mega scale meltdown event of the great
ice sheets that were covering North
America.
It was this event at 11,600,
essentially jerked the planet out of the
depths of this ice agent.
It had been in for thousands and
thousands of years with that melting.
You had a rapid rise of sea level.
Um,
so it's very interesting that the date
that he gives is precisely now the date
that,
um,
that the scientists are giving for this
transition from what's called the
younger dryas.
I think Graham has mentioned that,
um,
in,
in some of your interviews with him that
the younger dryas,
which was this climate spasm that ended
the last ice age.
So if we look at the chronology of
events around 26,000
years ago,
we were in the later phases of a what
appears to have been an interglacial
period,
not too much different from what we're
in now around 26,000
years ago.
The climate rapidly degenerated and
these massive glaciers had expanded,
um,
during this,
what they call the final phase or,
or,
um,
the late Wisconsin,
they refer to it because initially they
were looking for this evidence into
state of Wisconsin.
So they,
they named the,
this last final phase,
the late Wisconsin.
So around 26,000
years ago,
we see the,
the launching of this final phase of the
ice age.
The late Wisconsin then at around 13,000
years ago is the dates are now giving
it.
There was this enormous spasm of warming
and this seemed to be associated with
rapid melting and the first real rapid
sea level rise.
Okay.
What happened is after a very short
interval of time,
the climate snap back into the full
depths of glacial cold.
Now what had happened was if you go back
18,000
years ago,
this was the coldest part of the ice
age.
I mean,
this was bitterly cold period of time.
Um,
where I live in,
in Georgia was the forests that grew
there were like the forest you find in
Canada now you had Tundra up in Northern
Kentucky and Southern Idaho Tundra in
southern southern Ohio.
Excuse me.
Um,
so it was a really,
really different climate.
And once you got to northern Ohio and
the northern United States where New
York City is,
Chicago,
the Great Lakes,
the Dakotas,
all of that was under this massive ice
sheet.
Thousands of feet thick.
When you go up into Canada over Canada,
the ice was up to two miles thick.
I mean,
think about that two miles thick of ice.
And it reached from the Atlantic to the
Pacific Ocean and from the northern
United States as far south as the 45th
parallel all the way up to the Arctic
circle.
Now that is a drastically different
world,
bare in mind too,
that with that much ice piled up on the
surface of the land,
sea levels which contribute to dewater,
that formed that ice had to go down and
it's now well documented that sea levels
during the depth of the ice were at
least 400 feet lower than now,
which,
which means that the continental shelves
of the planet,
we're basically exposed now,
um,
where I live in Georgia.
If you go out and stand right now on the
beach,
like a Cumberland Island,
which is beautiful wilderness preserve
your stand there on the beach.
If you were suddenly transported back to
the depths of the ice age,
you'd be in the middle of a boreal
forest,
meaning a northern forest with spruce
trees,
large trees,
alder trees to kind of trees.
You find now in the northern United
States,
Canada,
that area and the beach wouldn't have
been anywhere,
anywhere close.
It would have been another 50,
7,500
miles further to the east because as the
sea level drops,
what happens?
It recedes,
right?
And so when this final phase of the ice
age came on,
sea levels begin to drop,
and so what it did was it exposed all of
the shallow marine ecologies that,
that redeemed all of the continents to
the atmosphere,
and basically would have caused enormous
ecological havoc.
Well then within a millennia or so,
the forests had,
had expanded and had now grown out.
So now off the eastern seaboard of the
United States,
they constantly will find the remains of
tree stumps and forests that had been
growing.
They're 14,
15,
16,000
years ago.
Now the ice begins to melt.
Sea level begins to rise.
Now it's important to realize that if we
look at the way modern civilization has
evolved,
what do we see is,
where did the first city show up?
Don't,
aren't they mostly trading cities that
show up up there?
Port cities,
they show up along the confluence of
rivers.
They show up where rivers meet the
oceans,
they show up on the,
on the coastlines.
Okay?
So if you had major cities during the
ice age,
as Graham has pointed out,
there are now 400 feet underwater.
Wow.
So you begin to appreciate when you
begin to really look at the history of
our planet,
what you realize is that it's just
almost unimaginably dynamic.
This an alteration from a,
from an interglacial to a glacial age is
an extreme process.
And so I guess the upshot of it is,
is that you know,
when,
when we look now at the climate record
that we have in hand now,
which has been pretty much reconstructed
with a fair amount of accuracy back to
about 400,000
years.
And these are primarily based on ice
cores extracted from Greenland,
extracted from Antarctica,
extracted from mountain glaciers,
and and most mostly mostly Antarctic
agreement.
No,
when you pull out that ice core,
it's layered.
You think,
think,
think of cutting down a tree and looking
at the annual layers where you can
actually count the number of layers in
a,
in a cross section of a tree log,
and you'll know how old it is.
Right?
Well,
it's very similar in a,
in a nice court,
you've got layers and layers because
each year they're snow.
That falls,
it gets compressed into Fern,
F,
r a n,
which is the transitional phase between
snow and glacial ice and it eventually
gets compressed into glacial ice and
when you look at a cross section of the
ice core,
you'll see these find layers in there,
right?
So they can go back and they can look at
these layers.
They can count the layers and there's a
lot of things going on in these layers.
Oxygen isotopes are are critical one for
for ascertaining climate changes because
oxygen isotopes are a function of
temperature and we have a graph here.
We'll pull up in a minute.
We can actually look at that,
but what we see is that the climate has
constantly oscillated back and forth and
when we look at the Holocene,
going back 10,000
years and then we take that
comparatively and we go back 250 to
400,000
years,
we can now begin to reconstruct these
intervals of glacial periods.
Interglacial.
And here's the thing that should be
sobering to,
to everybody on the planet today as we
think about climate change and all of
this.
Because obviously it's constantly in the
news and all the longest interglacial
period now on record for at least last
quarter million years.
The longest one,
the longest unbroken period of
interglacial warmth is the Holocene.
The one we're in now,
we've already exceeded by several
millennia,
the longest previous period of
interglacial warmth.
I don't hear them talking about that.
I don't hear Al Gore talking about that.
I don't hear anybody talking about that
in mainstream media,
but it's hard scientific fact.
Yeah.
We would be shitting our pants way more
if it was a global cooling than if it
was a global warming,
and let me tell her under.
We're going to pull up another graph
will pull up a graph in a minute which
shows you that even within the last
couple of thousand years,
periods of global cooling have not been
pleasant times.
Periods of global warming is when we see
human population expanding.
When we see cultural advancement,
when we see lifespans increasing,
when we see infant mortality,
decreasing periods of global cooling are
when we see populations going into
decline.
When we see lifespans diminishing,
you know,
we had a period of global cooling that
began between 5:36
and 5:40
a d.
It was this period of global cooling
that launched what we know of the dark
ages,
and this has now been well documented by
dendrochronologist.
Mike Bailey is one of the leaders of
this who's been looking at the climate
changes of the last couple thousand
years as preserved in the tree ring
record between 5:36
and about 5:44
a d.
We find that forest growth in the
northern hemisphere almost came to a
stop and one of the consequences of that
was this,
it was associated with a global cooling
and for multiple years running,
there were agricultural collapses were
because of the cold and damp that came
on with this.
Um,
you know,
the,
the historical record is interesting
because you read some of these accounts
that were preserved from that period.
They talk about weeks at a time where
they couldn't see the sun.
They talk about when it did show up,
it was just a feeble imitation of
itself.
They talk about,
you know,
years with no summer basically,
so what you had was succession of crop
failures that lead to people becoming
malnourished once they become
malnourished or immune systems became
weakened and in 5:40
to add about six years after this well
documented transition occurred.
We had the onset of the justinian plague
which wiped out a third of the
population of Europe and it took 300
years to recover from that.
And it didn't.
We didn't recover from it until the
climate shifted again and we went into
what's known as the medieval warm period
and the medieval warm period was the
time when the scandinavians were farming
on the west coast of Greenland,
where now it's perennially frozen and
for about the next couple of hundred
years,
the climate was according to some
researchers and some scientists as much
as two degrees warmer than now.
And do you think it had to have been
warmer if,
if they were farming in greenland where
it is now?
Frozen ground?
It had to have been warmer and one of
the things that happened with was with
this warming,
you had an expansion of the growing
season and you also had the latitude
belt at which viable farming or
agriculture could be.
Practice shifted three to 400 miles
north of where it had been,
which meant that for the first time,
England actually had a flourishing wine
industry which didn't exist previously
and it has only existed until recent
times because of genetically modified
crops is now allowing them to grow
grapes where they haven't been able to
grow wine grapes until we go back to the
medieval warm period.
So what happened was now there was a lot
of food for people to eat,
right?
People got healthier.
A human population began to increase,
right?
We begin to accumulate wealth.
We begin to,
to carry on commerce and trade.
After this 300 years of dark ages were
learning receded into the,
into the monasteries.
And life was very unpleasant,
very short,
very brutal,
very unpleasant.
Now we had this warming period,
okay?
With the growth,
the expansion of agriculture and the
abundant food supply.
And the,
um,
prolific harvest people were getting
strong,
healthy again,
a statute and it's been well documented
that during this two or 300 years of the
medieval warming period,
human stature actually increased by
inches.
Average human size,
okay.
Um,
by 1150,
this accumulated wealth that had ensued
from the,
the,
the benign climate of the medieval warm
period is what allowed the,
um,
the Great Cathedral building era to
ensue which began between 1130 and 1150
add and what we see as eco magnificent
cathedrals.
If you've been to Europe and visited any
of the Kathy put that on your to do
list,
get there and look at some of these
extraordinary works of art that were
built during the high gothic or high
middle ages between,
like I said,
about 1150 and the early 13 hundreds.
They built 80,
about 80 of these gigantic magnificent
cathedrals that,
that required the organizing of,
of thousands of highly,
highly skilled craftsman armies of
workers and craftsman.
You had stone masons and carpenters and
glaziers and astronomers and GM
attritions and,
and all of these people brought together
to create these incredible cathedrals,
and it was made possible by the fact
that European society had become
relatively wealthy and this wealth was
brought on by this global warmth.
Right now what we see,
go ahead to the,
to the beginning,
to the end of this magnificent gothic
building.
Boom.
And,
and by the way,
there's about 500 smaller abby's that
were constructed during this interval.
This was a very prolific time for a
number of reasons.
This was the time that you had the
templar knights forming.
You've probably heard of that.
The tempur nights,
I'm sure.
Um,
you had schools of Kabbalah being
founded in Spain and,
and you had the rise of Catheter Ism.
You had the troubadours,
you had these amazing spiritual things
going on.
Um,
amazing.
Culturally.
It was a very extraordinary time.
Those high Middle Ages.
Well,
a lot of those gothic cathedrals were
never finished.
And what we see is that some of them
have the appearance.
You know,
I'm a builder by profession and you know
it's,
I've looked at some of these in a what
it's very much like as they're going
along building and then all of a sudden
one day nobody shows up to work and
there are still tools laying around or
still materials that are often a pile
that we're waiting to be incorporated
into the structure.
And what happened was that the climate
began to cool again between 13,
15 and 1320 precisely.
When we see the end of this tremendous
gothic building boom is when the climate
began to cool and it's cool for the next
several decades.
And what we then see as a repeat of what
happened between 5:36
and 5:42
had agricultural collapses.
Crops rotting in the fields.
People going hungry between,
I think it was around between 13,
14 and 1345.
The onset of the black plague.
And once again the population of Europe
was decimated and it took 150 years
basically to recover from that.
And what we see is that what what what
was happening is the planet with
shifting into what's called the little
ice age,
where you probably heard that term,
the little ice age,
right?
There was two phases to the little ice
age and the first phase began,
like I said,
around 13,
20,
lasted about 150 years and there was a
break and it was during that break,
that warm period that basically the
renaissance kicked in and we began to
really move forward.
The second phase of the little ice age
came in during the 16 hundreds and it
was actually even colder than the first
phase.
And worldwide glaciers expanded to the
largest.
They had been in 10,000
to 12,000
years since the end of the big ice age
throughout the whole Holocene glaciers
had been smaller.
Now during the big eye,
the little ice age,
they grew and they grew to the biggest
that they've been in 10,000
years.
It's important to have that context of
understanding when we talked about
glacier recession because the glaciers
begin to recede around the middle of the
19th century worldwide,
as the little ice age began to wane and
global warmth,
warmth begin to return to the planet.
This happened in the mid 18 hundreds,
around 18,
40 to 18,
60.
We see the little ice age coming to an
end,
and at that point,
the glaciers worldwide began to recede.
They begin to contract.
They've been pretty much contracting
uniformly since then,
so when we're talking about glacier
recession,
it's important to understand that the
glacier recession really began a century
and a half ago or more,
and his basically considered continued
more or less uniformly since then with
no real change with the advent of of
human a fossil fuel to the atmosphere,
a human carbon dioxide which began
really in earnest during the Second
World War is when when we begin to add
significant amounts of carbon dioxide to
the atmosphere,
it's important to realize that the
glaciers had been receiving almost a
full century before that point.
So when you see all this,
a modern hysteria about global warming
and the human created global warming
that we,
we keep hearing about in the news and
that our influence on the atmosphere.
Does it drive you crazy?
I mean,
do you think it's silly?
It obviously human beings are
contributing to the carbon footprint,
right?
Obviously.
Yeah.
And obviously that has an effect on
global warming.
Yes,
yes.
But you've got to bear in mind at carbon
dioxide is only one variable in a very
complex equation,
right?
There are many factors influencing
climate of which carbon dioxide is only
one.
My problem with so much of the stuff
that's coming out in mainstream media,
which is coming through the
intergovernmental panel on climate
change,
is simply that when,
when they were instituted back in early
nineties by the United Nations,
the United Nations Framework Convention
on climate change basically gave them a
mandate which is demonstrate that humans
are causing climate change,
right?
So they focused exclusively on carbon
dioxide,
but there's all kinds of other things
going on.
For example,
cosmic rays are constantly bombarding
the earth,
right?
Cosmic rays produce clouds.
The more of the cosmic rays penetrate
the atmosphere,
the more a low altitude cloud cover
there is.
Low altitude clouds reflect heat back
into space.
Now the amount of cosmic rays are
penetrating the atmosphere.
A function of a couple of things.
You've got the helio sphere,
which is the whole,
essentially the,
the,
the energy envelope of the sun,
which encompasses the whole solar
system.
The Sun actually is fairly variable.
Um,
and what that means is that when the
solar wind is an in more intense phase,
like when,
when the sun spots,
for example,
are very active,
the solar wind is,
is much stronger.
What that does is it serves as a buffer
that prevents cosmic rays from
penetrating the atmosphere of the earth
as,
as strongly as they did previously.
Also,
the geomagnetic field of the earth acts
as a buffer.
So here's two things that are completely
not included in the scenarios of the
ECC,
but probably have a very profound effect
on global climate.
Um,
the earth's geomagnetic field is,
you probably know that the geomagnetic
field has periodically throughout earth
history disappeared completely.
Sometimes it's it's disappeared and come
back with reverse polarity will let
geomagnetic field acts as a buffer,
which helps to reduce the amount of
cosmic rays penetrating the atmosphere.
How's it disappeared completely?
I don't know,
and I don't know if really anybody
knows.
I haven't kept up with all of the most
recent research.
What's the geomagnetism,
but you know when you've got you hold a
little compass in your hand and it
points to north,
right?
Right.
Okay.
That's the Jew magnetic field that's
being measured by the compass.
It's moving,
it's fluctuating,
and for whatever reason throughout the
the history of the earth,
it has completely disappeared at some
points and his reverse polarity.
It's.
It was the reversing of the polarity of
the magnetic field that helped prove,
prove the reality of continental drift
because as the mid Atlantic Ridge
separates and and and a lava flows out,
it crystallizes and locked into the
crystal and structure of the of the lava
is the direction of the magnetic field
and the polarity of the magnetic field
is imprinted in there.
If you look at the research going back
to the 19 fifties,
they realized that you had stripes
effect effectively as you moved away
from Tomato Atlantic Ridge as the,
as the lava flow it out and
crystallized,
locked in the magnetic field.
They looked at it and they could see
that there were times when it had
completely reversed itself.
And so this was like very powerful
evidence that the,
that the theory of continental drift was
right,
that,
that the Atlantic Ocean had been
spreading.
And getting back to this whole Atlantis
thing,
which is interesting to me is because
when you look at,
at um,
replay those account,
he describes Atlantis as being a west of
the pillars of herrick lease,
which of course is the Straits of
Gibraltar,
the mouth of the Mediterranean.
He describes how if you go,
you come to some islands,
then you come to some more islands and
that was the island complex of Atlantis
and beyond.
That was another whole continent.
He describes that,
right?
If you look in the middle of the
Atlantic Ocean,
you've got the [inaudible] plateau,
which is now a couple of thousand feet
under the sea.
The aes or islands are the tops of
mountains that,
that emerged from the surface of the
ocean,
right?
And they sit right on the Atlantic,
uh,
the mid Atlantic Ridge,
now,
some of the thinnest crust on,
on the planet,
right?
And if it's like a giant suture or a
giant crack that runs up halfway around
the planet,
well,
when you have an ice age and you start
piling ice up onto like the North
American continent,
what happens is the weight of that ice
begins to crush the crust of the earth
down into the mantle.
It's called isoss to see which is a
vertical movement.
You know,
continental drift is horizontal.
I saw stussy is vertical now it's just
like right now you're sitting on that
soft chair,
right?
And your ass is creating a depression in
the cushion of the chair,
right?
That's isostatic depression.
You didn't realize that.
Did you know that your ass is creating
isostatic depression?
Right?
And when you get up and you walk away,
then you will have isostatic
compensation.
You'll have isostatic rebound because
the cushion will now rise because the
weight has been removed.
It's the same thing with the ice mass on
the continent.
The ice mass was hundreds of billions of
trillions of tons of ice.
It pressed the center of the North
American continent or,
or the center of at least Canada down
perhaps as much as several thousand feet
into the mantle.
With the removal of that ice,
the land begins to rebound.
Hudson Bay is the depression leftover
from the thickest part of the ice right
now.
Our photographs,
we could probably even pull some up here
in a minute.
There are photographs taken where you
can see the elevated shoreline
surrounding Hudson Bay because it's
still rising,
right?
What's interesting too is if you look at
the,
uh,
the distance between these shorelines,
you'll see that early on there was a
greater distance because the land was
rising faster.
As the millennia have have gone on,
the distance separating each shoreline
has diminished.
But now you have to think that all of
that weight is being transferred back
into the ocean basins.
A lot of it was dumped directly into the
Atlantic Ocean,
either via,
like the St Lawrence River up there,
the Hudson River,
up in the New York area,
or via the Mississippi River into the
Gulf of Mexico.
Now you've got all this water dumping
back into the ocean.
Like I said,
ocean levels are coming up hundreds of
feet,
right?
So now you're adding all of this weight
to the ocean basin and now you've got
the mid Atlantic Ridge,
which is some of the thinnest crust on
the earth.
Right?
This is what it's doing.
It's like a hinge line.
Right?
So now you picture during a glacial age,
when the weight is taken out,
it does.
This lifts up,
lifts up,
listening,
not watching.
Yeah.
When the ice melts,
the water goes in,
sea level rises,
it subsides.
Right now you look at the [inaudible]
plateau is a chunk of the African plate
that got left over when the continent's
separated around 70 to 80 million years
ago.
Right.
If you've seen the maps into the showing
how you can fit the continents together.
Yeah,
if you fit these back together,
if you,
if you reverse continental drift,
go back about 70 or 80 million years and
it's all fits together like a piece of
the puzzle,
but when it's separated,
a piece of the of the African plate got
left behind and this is what is the
[inaudible] plateau and it sits right
there,
a stride.
The Atlantic Ridge,
it's maybe a little bit smaller than the
than Iceland,
which is considered to be an island,
but a pretty good sized island right
now.
If you're doing this and you have as
much as two or 3000 feet or maybe more
of this vertical movement,
right,
and you added that to 400 feet of sea
level rise.
Now you can,
I think,
begin to get a scientific rationale for
how you may have had a large island in
the Middle Atlantic back during the ice
age.
Also,
additional evidence has suggested that
the Gulf stream,
which now basically brings a subtropical
warmth up to northwestern Europe.
I mean,
if you were to terminate the Gulf
stream,
England would,
would have some pretty,
pretty,
um,
malignant times.
So in northwestern Europe,
because the warmth is being brought up
by that Gulf stream,
right?
Well,
during the ice age,
the Gulf stream diverted to the south at
about 45 to 46 degrees,
which was hundreds of miles further
south and it now goes.
So essentially if you look at the
[inaudible] plateau,
a big chunk of that,
a source plateau would have been above
sea level during the ice age.
And that Gulf stream with its warmth
would have just basically embraced it.
See?
So if you suddenly,
joe found yourself transported
mysteriously back to the ice age,
that's probably where you might want to
go is the [inaudible] plateau.
It might've been,
uh,
one of the most benign places on earth
to live during the ice age.
And if there was a place where
civilization could evolve,
that would be a very logical place for
it to occur.
There's nothing really pseudoscientific
now about assuming that there could've
been some type of historic reality
behind these stories of Atlantis.
Of course,
the problem is as the wound will factor
that has gotten so grafted onto these
stories,
but you know,
crystals and aliens and flying ships and
you.
I mean we don't know,
but you know,
we don't have any hard evidence,
but the hard evidence does suggest that
there could have been some very benign
habitable islands,
large islands in the mid Atlantic during
the ice age.
Wow.
So that's intense.
That's so incredible.
It's so.
It's,
it's,
it's so crazy to think how,
how much things have changed while human
beings have been here.
The idea that during go Beckley tappy,
which is 12,000
years ago,
that North America was covered with ice
and they.
This was when these people in Turkey had
created this incredible structure.
So when you see this,
the modern hysteria about global
warming,
which is really essentially been like a
wrestling match between the left and the
right,
it's this weird thing where the right
wants to support like burning coal and
they don't want to diminish the economy
by putting all these environmental
regulations on natural resources.
And then the left,
which is screaming at the top of their
lungs that the sky is falling,
the oceans are going to rise and people
are going to drown.
W when you,
when you know so much about what has
happened over the course of the earth,
when you've studied this for a great
deal of time like you have,
what is your take on all this stuff?
Well,
I guess my intake is,
is,
is fairly simple.
I,
I tend to think that,
you know,
if you know,
if you're looking at the,
the,
the whole process of if you look at the
carbon cycle,
for example,
what,
what you see there is interesting.
We can talk to this to this as much as
possible so we can have his little
variation in the tone as possible.
Thank you.
Um,
you know,
putting this into context,
we have to say,
right now we're approaching 400 parts
per million of the ambient amount of Co.
Two in the atmosphere.
AT the beginning of the industrial
revolution,
it was about 100 parts per million less.
It's,
you could say basically that over the
last century we have increased the
amount of co two measurable co two into
the atmosphere,
assuming that it's all from us.
Now,
I meAn there,
there,
there's questions about that too,
because if there are other factors
inducing global warming such as changes
in,
in solar irradiance,
the amount of installation penetrating
the atmosphere and so on,
it means that the oceans are warming as
a result of that.
Okay.
Oceans are a gigantic carbon dioxide
sink.
When they're warm,
they exude carbon dioxide when they're
cold,
they absorb it,
right?
So if you have a natural warming,
it's gonna expel some carbon dioxide.
So it's not even clear necessarily that
that 100 parts per million is totally
the result of fossil fuel burning.
But for the sake of argument,
let's say that it is okay,
100 parts per million,
that's minuscule trace of this very
important constituents of our
atmosphere.
You know that carbon dioxide is what
fuels photosynthesis,
right?
And if you start reducing the amount of
carbon dioxide in the atmosphere and
you'd start,
once you start dropping below 200 parts
per million and you get down to about
1:50
to 100 photosynthesis plant,
photosynthesis starts shutting down.
I mean it's kinda like the amount of co
two in the atmosphere right now is at
the very bottom of the scale.
You know,
if we look at history going back when
you mentioned the cretaceous tertiary,
when the dinosaurs ruled,
there have been many times more the
amount of ceo to up to well in excess of
a thousand parts per million.
Several thousand parts per million in
the atmosphere.
But if we have increased the amount of
co two by 100 parts per million in 100
years,
it means we've for every million
molecules of air up there,
we add one molecule of co two every year
or two.
Maybe try to make it a little bit more
comprehensible.
If for every hundred thousand molecules
of air up there every 10 years we had
one molecule of co two.
I.
I'm not convinced that that's going to
lead to global catastrophe.
I mean,
think of it this way,
you've got a huge tank with a hundred
thousand fish in it every 10 years
you're throwing one more fish.
Are you even going to notice that?
You know,
I think that what's happened is that ceo
to,
like I said,
is one variable in a very complex
equation,
but all of the other variables as far as
the,
the government funded research ngos have
been excluded from the debate.
And what dismays me is that we're told
that all scientists agree on this.
No,
all scientists don't agree.
When you have though a major government
funded program like climate change
research,
which is funded to the tune of about
$2,000,000,000
per year,
you're going to have a large vested
interest in basically.
I mean,
if these guys came out and said nascio
two is really not a big deal,
it's perhaps fueling plant growth.
Um,
and this is an interesting aside,
you know,
if you look at the,
um,
the projections of forest in inventory
back in the fifties and sixties based
upon deforestation is a result of timber
as a result of agriculture.
The projections that at how quickly,
um,
forest inventories we're going to,
if you look at those projections back in
the fifties and sixties and then you
realize that in the ensuing period of
time,
we've now got exhaustive,
highly accurate satellite surveys that
can actually count the number of
hectares of forests.
what's interesting is in the nineties
when they really started looking at this
date of just how much forest there was
compared to what the projections were,
there was like 25 to 40 percent more
forests worldwide than anybody had
predicted.
What fueled this prolific forest growth?
Well,
it's very likely that at least part of
it was because of the slight increase in
ceo to Israel resolved as a result of
our fossil fuel burning.
Now we,
we put in every year we burn about a,
in introducing into the atmosphere about
6 billion tons of co two.
Well there's about 750 or 760 billion
tons of co two in the atmosphere
naturally.
And at least a third of that is cycling
through from the atmosphere into the
biosphere,
into the oceans and so on.
So our contribution isn't really that
significant,
but another part of the.
The argument is that,
and this has been admitted right in the
ipc reports,
is that based on the amount of fossil
fuel that we're burning,
there should be twice as much co two
into the atmosphere in the atmosphere as
we're now measuring.
So what they have been talking about for
about 15 years now is where's the
missing carbon?
What's this missing?
Carbon sink will probably.
Some of it's going into the ocean,
but most likely a lot of it is going
into fueling plant growth and forest
growth worldwide.
And there's a lot of studies that are
beginning to come out now that shows
that perhaps some of the desert areas of
the planet rather than expanding are
actually contracting.
So,
you kNow,
at thIs point there's a lot of things we
still have to learn when it comes down
to understanding the climate.
We're in the infancy.
You,
you can't talk to a single climatologist
and come up with one single coherent
answer or agreement on what has actually
provoked the planet to go into a full
ice age or what has caused it to come
out of an ice age if you don't have,
if you don't know that.
We still have a hell of a lot to learn
about how the climate works,
so I get really frustrated when I hear
this claim that the debate is over.
The debate is over because the debate
hasn't really even begun yet.
You say we need to really look at all of
these other factors as well.
I mean,
when you look at at at wind currents and
ocean currents,
you have the,
the el nino,
southern oscillation.
You have the,
the,
the indian ocean dipole,
you have the pacific decadal
oscillation.
All of these things have a very profound
influence on the climate,
but they're essentially being
ignored within the.
Within the government funded science to
a large extent and you have a lot of
scientists who have objected to some of
the claims of certainty made by the ipc
see scientists,
and for the most part the left likes to
demonize them.
This is people like,
oh,
I think probably the the leading demon
of climate deniers is fred singer
because he wants was given an a,
a $10,000
unsolicited donation from exxon years
and years ago,
but you've got guys like Roy Spencer and
craig ensure would id,
so when robert balling and Timothy Ball
and and and the list goes on and on.
These are distinguished climate
scientists that have devoted their lives
to understanding climate science,
who say,
well,
there's a lot of flaws in the
methodology of the ipc,
but by saying that now they have entered
the,
the spawn of hell according to the left.
Now in.
You're right.
See what happened.
It's turned into a political football.
It's an idler ideological debate.
It's an ideological debate,
a political debate,
and it's just too bad that the science
of the thing has had to suffering.
The consequence.
It is,
it is fascinating because even hearing
you say this,
I'm,
I'm thinking like it starts popping
triggers like I'm not the type of person
that worries too much about being
labeled because I've been labeled a
million times already as an idiot.
It doesn't.
It doesn't bother me to start
contemplating the possibilities of
controversial ideas,
but when I'm listening to you saying
this,
all I'm hearing is the knee jerk
reaction of climate denier climate to
always a climate denier.
This guy's a climate denier and seeing
these fucking things that we've grown to
be accustomed to on television where you
have a guy on the left who has one point
of view and a guy on the right who says
something wacky and then everybody
fights about it and then the youtube
clips.
You look at the comments and it's filled
with this guy's a faggot and that guy's
effect.
This guy eat shit.
I hope your house goes under water.
You fucking climate denier and when I'm
listening to you and you mean this
podcast has been over an hour already
and it's incredibly complex.
We have barely scratched the surface and
you're never going to hear anything like
this on any television show because most
people feel that the general public does
not have the attention span to absorb.
All of this information is really
complex explanation of the known
science,
of the changing of the atmosphere of the
earth.
So when people start talking about
climate denying and you know what,
what is going on with climate change,
what they're really doing is
establishing their position on what side
I am the side of.
I'm a person who believes in science and
education,
but how much of this have you actually
explored?
How much of it as anybody actually
looked at?
Well,
I'm a person who supports industry and
I'm a person who believes the United
States needs to recover from our
economic disaster and we got a frack,
a few wells,
you know,
so be it.
You know,
there's these two very distinct and
oftentimes shallow ideological
perspectives.
And when I say shallow,
shallow from the point of the general
public person like me who's not a
scientist observing it.
And just picking aside with very little
information really,
and you talked to,
I would like to grab,
grab the average person,
the average leftie and the average kid
that thinks that they're,
you know,
they have an opinion on global change.
And just just do me a favor and just
write down what you know,
just write down.
I don't want you looking online.
Do you have an opinion?
Write down what you know you wouldn't.
You know,
dog shit.
most people know dog shit.
It's true.
Joe,
it's so fascinating.
It's so fascinating to me because it
becomes another one of those things.
Ideology is.
I mean,
I don't remember who said it,
but it's,
it's the enemy of free thinking.
You get in these ideological clusters
and then anything outside of this thing,
these predetermined patterns of behavior
that you have to subscribe to anything
becomes forbidden.
It becomes you.
You can't even entertain it.
You can't even approach the idea or you
see it with everything you see with
atheism.
You see it with,
you see it with any isms,
with feminism,
with the men's rights.
You see it with people who subscribe to
the right people,
subscribed to the left,
any variables that don't fit into their
equation that they've already subscribed
to,
they don't want to be labeled as that
other side and anytime they don't want
to be labeled that they start ignoring
any evidence or any ideas that don't fit
within this really rigid description.
That's exactly right.
I mean,
that is,
you hit the nail on the head job weird.
Exactly right.
People get locked into these ideological
paradigms and then from that point on,
basically their perspective is modified
more by emotion and rationality is more
by,
you know,
their feelings rather than real
information.
And,
and it's too bad.
I mean,
I don't know what to blame it on.
Maybe the fact that the government runs
all the schools,
I don't know,
you know,
the government monopolizes the education
system,
so they're not teaching people critical
thinking skills.
They're not teaching people how to
actually become,
how to be scientifically literate,
um,
which is really sad.
Um,
but you know,
it's like,
you know,
you keep hearing the term climate change
denier,
right?
Well,
there's no such thing,
I don't think you're going to find a
single climate scientist of any
persuasion that denies that the climate
is changing and you got to realize that
the terminology has shifted.
It was global warming originally when,
when James Hansen gave his testimony
before congress in the summer of 1988,
um,
you know,
and proposed these potential tipping
points and catastrophic outcomes of our
burning of fossil fueled.
We've gOne from there to the united
nations getting involved in the united
nations,
setting up the whole the epcc and
channeling all of this funding to it.
And I think the consequences is that,
you know,
when you say again,
excuse me,
we went from global warming to climate
change.
Why dO they not really used global
warming is a term anymore is mainly
because for 15 years the average global
temperature is flatlined.
And this is based upon,
you know,
the most accurate like satellite
surveys.
The ipc generally focuses only on ground
based sensors which are subjected to,
uh,
perhaps some considerable bias because
you know,
you picture a ground based sensors,
most of them are sitting at airports
when these things were being put in post
world war ii,
the bulk of them,
forties and fifties into the sixties.
Many of these airports were rural.
They were,
you know,
adjacent to small towns.
They were surrounded by fields and
farms.
For us,
what's happened is the urban area has
encroached,
you know,
every when you,
when you create streets,
pavement buildings,
all of this absorbs heat,
right?
And,
and no one has really done an exhaustive
study of the potential bias.
It's introduced into the ground based
sensors.
That part,
at least part of the warming of these
ground based sensors may have nothing to
do with carbon dioxide at all.
It may just have to do with the fact
that they're sitting next to a huge
parking lot.
You see,
and I mean you knoW yourself,
if you walk out,
you know if you're walking in a field
and then you walk onto an asphalt
parking lot immediately,
it's,
it's much,
much hotter.
You see Anthony Watts,
who is another one of the,
the,
the dissenters that who's demonized is
the only one who has really attempted to
exhaustedly document the accuracy of the
ground based sensors and what he's come
up with is that perhaps as much as 30 to
50 percent of the perceived warming of
the last century,
which is about eight tenths of a degree
centigrade,
is probably as a result of that bias.
It's been introduced by what's called
the urban heat island effect and all of
the major city.
La has a urban heat island mitigation
program underway.
All of the major metropolitan cities are
now trying to mitigate the effects of
this heat because of all of the samantha
in the buildings and the pavement in the
parking lots.
They're always hotter than the
surrounding rural areas.
So the question has been legitimately
raised.
How much of a bias has been introduced
into the,
um,
into the ground based sensors?
Well,
when we turn to the balloon sensors,
the radio sonne balloon sensors into
satellite sensor is basically what
they're showing is that the average
global temperature has been flat for 15
years.
Well,
because of that and,
and many of the,
the key,
uh,
scientists like phil jones of the ipc
has basically publicly admitted,
yeah,
the,
when you look at the average temperature
from that perspective,
it hasn't warmed in 15.
Now there are regional pockets of,
of warming,
and you know,
records being sacked all the time
because local conditions will affect
change enormously.
Just like I was talking about the urban
heat island effect is,
is a local or regional condition,
but because of the fact that the climate
hasn't warmed statistically
significantly in 15 years,
now we don't talk about global warming.
We talked about climate change,
but those two terms are not
interchangeable.
Global warming.
It's a very specific model of climate
change,
which is that you've got this 15 micron
wavelength of co two in the atmosphere
that's trapping infrared radiation
emanating from the earth.
Right,
okay.
But if you're talking about climate
change,
now suddenly you know our,
our umbrella goes much,
much huge and it now encompasses all of
these other things that I was talking
about and and to question the consensus
idea,
to consent to question that ceo two is
the primary or sole driver of climate is
not to be a climate change denier.
See,
because no,
I would challenge anybody even uses that
term will show me an example of any
climate scientist,
no matter where they fall in the
argument that is denying that the
climate is changing.
I mean anybody who has studied the
climate all knows that it has changed
dramatically in dynamically on any scale
you can look at whether it's the decadal
scale as centennial or millennial or
beyond.
it changes on every level and that's the
thing.
We have to recognize that if we stop
burning fossil fuels tomorrow,
we didn't drive another car.
We didn't.
We shut down all the coal plants.
I'm going to tell you this.
The climate would not stop changing.
When you see a story like here's one,
it's in the news about a us senator
marco rubio's denial of manmade climate
change should play well with his tea
party base who support he'll need if he
indeed runs for president in 2:16,
but in taking this position,
florida's junior republican senator
ignores the vast majority of the world's
climate scientists who say human
activity is contributing to climate
change and rising sea levels.
Human
activity is contributing to climate
change.
No doubt.
There's no doubt that human activity
contributes to climate change.
Human activity,
again,
is one variable in a very complex
equation.
I wish mark marco rubio would keep his
mouth shut until he goes and spends
about six months or a year.
Really doing the homework because then
you could talk a little bit more
intelligently about it.
That is the problem,
right?
It really does take that long.
It does.
Like he.
I know you have.
What did I meet you at six,
seven years ago?
Something like that.
Yeah,
and you had already spent decades
observing the effects of climate change
and of asteroidal impacts and the
history of these things.
I mean the amount of time just absorbing
the information so you could rattle it
off like this in a podcast.
I mean,
what the fuck got you into this?
How did you get down this rabbit hole?
Well,
this is an odd rabbit hole,
right?
Rabbit hole.
It's a fascinating rabbit hole.
I'm so thankful.
Not only that you've gone down,
but that you're willing to exchange this
information with us or imparted on us
because it's.
It's a very different perspective
because I know you're not a right wing
lunatic.
You are very science based guy,
but you're.
You're looking at this and the way
you're explaining it is incredibly
rational and incredibly frustrating to
me that there's not that many people
that are,
that are saying this well.
The upside
I think of the whole global warming
issue or the climate change issue is
this,
that if you know,
the thing is,
is I made the point that even if we
stopped all fossil fuel consumption
tomorrow,
the climate is still going to change and
it's going to change dramatically.
It's going to change sometimes even
catastrophic when we need to do from
here on out is basically think about
strategies of adaptability if as a
result of this whole issue,
even even though I think it's misplaced
based mis misapplied,
if part of that comes out of this is
that we begin to develop strategies of
adaptability.
That would be a good thing if however we
focused so exclusively on carbon dioxide
to the exclusion of everything else.
That could be a bad thing.
Um,
because the climate is going to change
no matter what we do or where we go with
it,
the climate is going to.
So you can put up solar power panels
until the cows come home.
The houses that are on the beach in
malibu are still going to be underwater
in 100 years.
Well,
not necessarily.
Not necessarily so buy real estate in
malibu.
Well,
see,
the thing is,
if you look at the.
I mentioned earlier
that there was a break in the,
in the little ice age of about 150 years
that that basically led to the
renaissance.
Right?
Well,
we've been in a,
in a receSsion of the little ice age,
a an interruption of the little ice age
for about 150 years and right now you
know,
and again,
the ipc,
one of the things that frustrates me is
that they basically excludes solar
physicists and solar scientists who are
essentially saying that insulation
levels,
insulation,
the amount of solar energy penetrating
the atmosphere is one of the lowest
levels in thousands of years.
and I mean there are solar physicists
that are saying,
you know what,
we could be at the beginning of another
phase of the little ice age.
Now if our ceo to it's helping new
ameliorates somewhat returned the little
ice age,
that would be a good thing.
So muscle cars or green,
that's what I'm getting out of this.
Coal and muscle cars are good for the
forest.
Well,
the property,
the problem with coal is not so much the
ceo to is to me,
it's just the particulate matter.
You know,
that's a different question altogether.
The pollution,
the pollution,
which is horrific.
In China,
when they had these coal plants and you
see these people that are essentially
walking,
it looks like they're in the middle of a
forest fire.
They're walking down the street and it's
just dark everywhere.
That's a different issue,
you know,
and,
and I'm,
I consider myself a conservationist in
the respect that we basically need
examples of an,
a pristine nature because ultimately
nature is the most powerful teacher and
we need examples.
We need places where nature's just left
alone to do its thing without
interference of human beings.
We need clean air.
Nobody has the right to dump shit in the
air that other people have to breathe.
water that other people have to drink.
To me,
those are different questions and really
where are the more of our focus should
be rather than these abstractions.
I have found the course.
I've gotten some flack over the last few
years by saying some of the things I've
been saying here.
You know,
that I've had people stand up and
accused me,
oh,
you're just saying we can just do
anything we want.
We can just destroy the earth,
which of course is not the case,
and not saying that at all,
not saying that at all.
And,
and when we began to look at the bigger
context of this thing and we begin to
understand that the extraordinary
changes that this planet has been
through,
um,
and even to some of the lesser things in
recent years,
mt.
St helen's,
you remember when that erupted in 1980
tens of thousands of acres were turned
into a lunar landscape,
right?
Well,
if you read the accounts of the
scientists,
the biologists,
zoologists,
the ecologists that had been studying
what happened to that decimated
landscape and the aftermath,
what you find out is they're surprised,
almost shock.
It helped quickly nature recovered from
that and how quickly,
you know,
colonizer plants moved in,
uh,
and was followed by a whole,
the whole succession,
ecological succession of reclaiming that
land.
If you look at the,
the exxon valdez disaster up in Alaska,
in Alaska,
and that was over the short term,
devastating to the local ecology.
And yet,
what's interesting again,
um,
there've been several books written by
some of the lead scientists involved in
that talking about how remarkably quick
nature begin to reclaim and recover from
it.
And here's some irony where the
government forced exxon to go in and do
it's cleanup is actually suffered more
than the areas that were just left alone
for nature to reclaim.
That's fascinating.
So the chemicals that they used in order
to break up,
that was the issue with the gulf as
well,
right?
With those dispersants that they were
spraying over the area,
they probably should've just left the
gulf alone because,
you know,
when you have a submarine earthquakes,
they can expel huge amounts of
hydrocarbons into the ocean.
Nature has been dealing with massive
expulsions of hydrocarbon into the
oceans and into the marine ecology for,
for millions and millions of years.
Um,
you know,
it was bad.
But I think what we'll see is that the
recovery time has been consumed faster
than most people believed possible.
you see,
I think what's,
what's really going to turn out in the
end looking at all this,
is that nature is robust.
And when we begin to look at the number
of times that nature has been disrupted
by,
we've been talking about asteroids and
comets,
and here's,
here's a perspective for you,
you know,
at the peak of the cold war,
when us and the soviet union were
eyeball to eyeball with our nuclear
weapons on,
on high alert,
and we had,
we had 10,000
weapons on our side.
They had 10,000
weapons on their side.
The total nuclear arsenal at the times
had about 18,000
megatons of,
of energy capable of being delivered.
18,000
megatons.
Now that means 18 million tons of tnt.
The bomb that destroyed hiroshima was
about 10,000
tons of tnt.
So 100 times a hundred hiroshima bombs
would be one mega ton.
Right now there was aBout say 15 to
18,000
megatons total in the arsenal of the
superpowers during the height of the
cold war had we unleashed an all out
nuclear war and
fired every warhead that we had in our
arsenals at each other 15,000
warheads,
you know,
I mean,
yeah,
20,000
warheads,
15,000
megatons.
It would have been an environmental
disaster,
unprecedented in history.
You remember the scenarios about nuclear
winter,
right?
Because of all of the fires and the suit
and the particulate matter thrown into
the atmosphere.
It could literally bring on a a mini ice
age,
right?
And and probably cause without even the
radiation caused,
major collapse of the human population.
Right?
Get this number in your head.
15,000
megatons.
Okay.
Now even a small asteroid impact or
let's say,
let's say the,
the asteroid impact that that struck the
yucatan.
There's a simple formula that you can
use when you look at the crater size.
you take the size of the crater and
raise it expressed in kilometers.
Raise it to the power of three point
four and multiply the result by two
point four and what it's going to give
you as the energy yield in megatons of
that object striking.
If I put in 180 kilometers into this
calculator here,
which is the diameter of the yucatan
crater,
and I raise it to the three point four
power,
and then I multiply that by the two
point four power,
I get the,
the megaton yield.
All right,
that number comes up to be three,
one,
111 million megatons.
I divide that by $15,000.
And basically what we have there is
about equivalent to the entire nuclear
arsenal of the superpowers 8,000
times,
over 8,000
times over.
Now,
what kind of an environmental
consequence would there be to that?
Well,
we saw that global firestorms,
you know,
that this,
uh,
the studies of the amount of suit at
that boundary layer shows that the
amount of biomass that went up in
firestorms,
that the kt boundary was about
equivalent to every plant on earth today
going up in fire,
right?
You had tsunamis that we're perhaps a
thousand feet in height.
You had global earthquakes probably
measured 10 to 11 on the richter scale.
And you know how the richter scale
works.
It's logarithmic.
So that an eight point,
oh,
earthquake is 10 times more powerful
than a seven point.
Oh,
nine point.
is 10 times more powerful than an eight
point?
Oh,
an 11 point.
earthquake is going to be unimaginable.
The whole framework of the globe would
have shaken.
You probably would have massive failures
on every fault line on the planet.
Now,
the kt event was the middle of the five
great extinction events.
Right?
There was ordovician,
silurian.
There was the permian triassic.
There was a couple more.
Two of them were more extreme than that.
Now even even much smaller than that.
Right.
You know,
w when they talk about a tipping point,
you know,
are we talking about a tipping point
that could trigger a climate change,
a disastrous catastrophic climate change
is being a few parts per million,
more of co two or as a tipping point,
really a mile wide asteroid slamming
into the earth at 100 times the speed of
a rifle bullet.
That could be a tipping point,
my friend,
and that has happened thousands of times
and hundreds of times since we humans
have been here hundreds of times,
hundreds of hundreds of times,
and one was the most recent one.
That was the holocene crater.
Well,
probably it's,
there's evidence emerging now that the
collapse of the late bronze age
civilization is around 4,200
years ago,
may have been precipitated by a series
of impacts.
There's evidence emerging that the
climate downturn that occurred between
5:36
and 5:48
that I talked about earlier may have
been triggered by a series of multiple
impacts.
one that looks like it occurred off the
coast of Norway and another one that
looks like it occurred off the coast of
New Zealand.
Like tandem impacts right around 5:36
and,
and we're basically faced with the idea
now that literally impacts from things
from space maybe hundreds of times more
likely than anybody was even imagining a
generation ago.
So we're essentiallY this civilization
that is banking on the knowledge that
we've accumulated over a very small
amount of time.
And as we're uncovering more and more
evidence,
more and more information,
we're starting to realize our ignorance.
We're starting to realize how little we
know about our own history,
the history of this particular species
and how it's interacted in this crazy
volatile environment of earth.
And how many times we've been hit by
rock.
Yeah.
And see,
you know,
a hundred years ago,
the assumption was what are these,
these images of these craters are
impacts.
Oh yeah,
that's,
that's actually 10 years old.
But it shows now all the identified
impact.
And this is 10 years old.
So since then some new ones have.
Oh,
does the dozens more.
Yeah.
And since then has been discovery of
this nuclear glass that they've found
all over europe and all over asia,
I think.
Are you referring to the possibly the
thing that graham was talking about the,
the 13,000
years a year ago
of event,
I think.
I think that's what it is.
What I'm referring to is there was a
mainstream report about all these,
these pieces of this very similar
material to what they find at nuclear
blasts and that it was all over the
place at when they did the core samples
around 12,000
years ago.
Then that's exactly what graham stark
and and yes,
the evidence is getting stronger and
stronger each year that there have.
There may have been a multiple impact
event.
The terminated the ice age and this is
still a very controversial idea because
the gradualists just don't want to go
there and this is probably what killed
off mass extinction of the woolly
mammoth mass extinction of the saber
tooth tiger and a series of animals that
they really have not figured out why.
like there's,
there's been all sorts of theories about
why the woolly mammoth went extinct and
some of them are ridiculous like that.
people did it,
you know.
I'm glad to hear you say that.
That's ridiculous idea.
Well,
it's ridiculous.
When you think about what kind of people
were around 12,000
years ago and what kind of weapons they
had and what a fucking mammoth looks
like,
like jesus christ,
how many of them more and the other
thing that's ridiculous about,
obviously when I say ridiculous,
I am ridiculous.
I shouldn't even be making that
statement.
I don't.
I've done very little research,
but the research that I've read and the
people that have questioned it,
have talked about the mass graves where
they've found these animals that have
died instantaneously,
thousands of them and not consumed
either.
They don't show signs of predation or of
butchering.
They're there.
They've died in full form.
Full body.
Yes.
And the massive,
massive,
massive graveyards.
And,
and you know,
for centuries a pristine mammoth tusk,
ivory,
who've been hauled out of the permafrost
of siberia in train load lots.
You know,
and this has gone into the global ivory
market literally for three or 400 years.
Um,
some estimates are that there may have
been as many as four to 10 million
woolly mammoths worldwide.
Most people don't realize it right here
in north America.
There were three species of provo city
and are three species of elephants
during the ice age.
Africa has one species.
Indian India has another species.
We had three species here during the
time will go.
Beckley.
Tappy was being built.
Yes.
During the time elephants in ai.
Elephant,
here's another perspective.
Is that one that they found.
What is that?
This is the bArest safka mammoth that
was found in 19.
Oh,
one quick frozen.
Uh,
yeah,
with flesh.
Now,
at the time this photograph was taken,
a wolves had eaten the flesh off of the
skull.
That's why it's,
it's,
um,
it's bare.
But what you see there immediately.
Dirty wolves.
Yeah.
Eating some million year old meat,
gusting assholes.
Probably $13,000.
Zero.
So that's a little.
Not quite as bad as stills gusting,
but you can see the,
the,
uh,
the mammas left for liam just in front
of his face there.
You see how it's,
and if,
and if jamie toggles back and forth
between this image and the next one
you'd be able to see.
Um,
yeah.
This was how the woolly mammoth was
found.
And so they took photos of it when it
was found like this,
and then they left it alone
and the wolves came and got it.
This is not,
this is a reconstruction,
I believe in the leningrad museum.
So what they did was they took the
remains of the woolly mammoth and then
taxidermists came in and reconstructed.
But this shows the position in which he
was found sitting on his haunches like
that.
And um,
at the time that the woolly mammoth met
his demise,
he was eating flowering plants right
now.
It's important to keep that in mind.
His stomach was full of about two dozen
different varieties of plants and sedges
and things that he had been munching on
up in siberia at the time that he,
that he met his death number of
interesting things.
The contents of his stomach could not
purified right now.
That's mysterious.
The fact that his,
his flesh was still edible,
at least by wolves.
You know,
the stories about,
you know,
the scientist eating mammoth burgers is
probably made up.
But the wolves definitely were able to
eat the flesh.
Right?
It was described as still being marbled,
almost as if it had just been frozen,
you know,
a week ago,
but since the time that the woolly
mammoth died,
it had its whole carcass.
Now this was a six ton woolly mammoth,
so he had been frozen for how many
thousands and thousands of years and so
thoroughly frozen that the contents of
the stomach putrefying now a woolly
mammoth of six tons,
has a lot of internal heat,
right?
Clarence birdseye,
the,
the founder of birdseye foods and the
inventor of the fast freezing of foods
for preservation got involved in
examining and in speculating about this
woolly mammoth,
his conclusion basically that did
something like this in order to prevent
the contents of the stomach from
putrefying,
the entire carcass of the woolly mammoth
would've had to been frozen through and
through in 10 hours or less.
Now,
bear in mind that this woolly mammoth
was eating flowering plants right now,
how cold would it have to be to freeze a
six ton woolly mammoth in 10 hours or
less?
His estimate was probably somewhere
around 150 degrees below zero.
So from flowering plants to a 150
degrees below zero in 10 hours in 10
hours.
How,
what,
what causes something like that?
Well,
there's been some speculation.
Um,
w,
the speculation that I found most
interesting was possibly volcanic gases
that had been ejected up into the
stratosphere,
approached absolute zero.
And because of the cold fell back to
her,
I think you could get the same effect
perhaps with a gas is released from a
disintegrating common nucleus.
It's still a mystery.
I,
anything that anybody says at this point
is purely speculative.
However,
it's clear that whatever this mammoth
underwent was disastrous in the extreme
you saw I'm sitting there on his
haunches right.
Both of his hip bones were broken,
which means that he was slammed back
onto his haunches very violently.
He was also found with an erect penis,
which means that he died by suffocation,
which meant that he was entombed
virtually instantly by the material that
later became the permafrost.
We were talking about the little ice age
earlier and I was talking about how the
little ice age ended around 1850.
well,
this guy was found about 19 oh,
one after the climate in siberia had
been warming somewhat see,
and what happened was a part of a clip,
a cliff that had been next to the barest
safka river,
the [inaudible] river had shifted its
channel and eroded some of the cliff
face back and then one year,
one warm spring,
there was a collapse of the cliff face
that exposed this mammoth to the
atmosphere and at that point is when the
wolves came in and began to devour the
flesh on the on the skull.
See,
so clearly this morley mammoth is an
example of or indicative of some type of
a catastrophe,
whether it was a global catastrophe or
local catastrophe.
Nobody knows,
but clearly it was catastrophic,
but that woolly mammoth.
There's only one of dozens of examples
of flash frozen late pleistocene mammals
that that died under similar
circumstances
and these large graveyards of mass
extinctions of thousands and thousands
of animals.
What are the best examples of them?
Because I know that I've seen some of
them online,
but I can't pull them up like I'm sure
you can
got some right here.
If I can get my laptop there,
pull jamie,
pull up,
look towards the bottom of the list
list.
You'll see place to seeing the lost
world of the pleistocene.
You see that pdf?
No,
it's a.
It's a powerpoint.
It's in that list of the powerpoints
that I gave you.
I have some photos.
You're freaking me out.
I just want to tell you right now.
I get freaked out.
Pretty easy,
but she freaking me out.
I actually frozen mammoth.
I have to confess that one of my
objectives in coming here was to try to
freak you out.
Well,
you did it.
Congratulations.
You're successful.
Um,
I've been terrified of yellowstone for,
for years now.
I've watched some late night.
Documentary was a huge mistake.
It was one of those things.
I was about to go to bed and I was just
flipping through the channels and they
were going over this thing about a
called dara volcano in yellowstone.
And I was like,
what the fuck's it called dara?
And then they started talking about what
it was it something like 600 kilometers
wide or something crazy like that.
Which is something like 300 miles,
and they were saying that they didn't
even discover it until they started
satellite imagery
of a of earth,
and then they realized that,
oh,
this was a giant volcano that was so
violent in its eruption that it blew the
mountain off of it and it became this
massive crater and that it happens every
six to 800,000
years ago.
That the last time it happened was
600,000
years ago.
So hopefully keeping our fingers
crossed.
We got another 100,000
years if we're lucky.
Yeah,
but see,
that's another aspect of this component
of the dynamic history of planet earth.
These,
these gigantic volcanic eruptions.
There's been some interesting work
linking asteroid impacts with giant
volcanic eruptions as well,
and it would.
It would make sense that that,
that the energy injected into the earth
by a major impact could trigger volcanic
eruptions.
We know that during the great meltdown
event of 11 to 13,000
years ago,
that there were enormous,
massive volcanic eruptions and mount st
helens,
for example,
was,
was massively erupting at that time.
And I have photographed.
I have some photographs right here,
I don't know how much time we have to
look at some of this,
but where I have gone out and found
thick layers of white volcanic ash from
mount st helens sandwiched in between
these flood layers and and it.
It shows that it undoubtedly had to have
been a response to the fact that you had
this enormous mass transfer of weight
that we were talking about earlier from
the continents back to the ocean and
when we go through maybe it's time to go
through a few of these images that I
brought.
You can begin to see some of the
consequences of this melting.
You'll begin to appreciate that.
Yeah,
there were these just enormous mass
transfers of weight unloading in certain
areas,
loading and other areas.
This would clearly have a profound
effect on the subterranean stability and
could easily lead to major eruptions and
there was a spasm of major volcanic
eruptions globally at the time of the
transition out of the ice age,
which would only have added to the havoc
of that transition and why,
you Know,
half of the great species of megafauna
disappeared.
A megafaun is basically defined as an
any,
any animal in this case,
mostly mammals over 44 kilograms and
body weight,
which is about a hundred pounds.
Right?
So that would include us.
And if you started thinking about all of
the animals globally worldwide that are
more than 100 pounds,
depending on how you divide up the
species,
there might be 100 to 2,130
different species.
And I'm talking about the lions and
tigers and bears and elephants and
rhinos and hippos and moose and caribou
and dr.
Right down the line.
Right.
okay.
Let's go back to the ice age.
The extinction,
the loss of species at the end of the
last ice age was about equivalent in
number.
The loss of species of mega mammals was
about equivalent in number two,
the number of species of mega mammals
that still exist,
so in other words,
these events that terminated the ice age
basically decimated half of the species
of of mega mammals on earth.
Half of the species disappeared.
So if you were going to try to affect an
equivalent mass extinction of species
today,
you basically have to eliminate every
animal on earth,
over 100 pounds in body weight in order
to get the equivalent of that mass
extinction episode of 12,000,
13,000
years ago.
That's insane.
It's insane,
but it's absolutely the truth.
I.
What is the official like or mainstream
explanation for this?
It doesn't exist.
Okay.
You brought up the idea of of it's
called overkill,
which has been the dominant theory for
for decades,
which is that human hunters exterminated
the wooly mammoth and in some vague way,
the extermination of the woolly mammoth
being at the top of the food chain
somehow had a ripple effect down through
the ranks of species and somehow perhaps
in an unaddressed way resulted in the
loss of all these other species.
But theY just don't address that.
And the more you said that theory is
ridiculous and that's an understatement.
I mean you're talking about,
you know,
perhaps bands of few hundred or maybe
even a thousand individuals,
migrant bands,
human hunters coming in and somehow
able.
So you've got to bear in mind that the
estimates of human population during
this time globally is less than the
estimates of the population of woolly
mammoth.
But somehow our ancestors were able to
wipe out 4 million to 10 million woolly
mammoths so fast that they couldn't even
reproduce.
So there was only like 10 million people
back then.
That's well see,
that's based upon more or less the
conventional interpretation.
Now of course,
what we've been talking about implies
opens the door to their possibility of
there being a lot more people and then
mass extinction also including a massive
amount of human beings as well.
And,
and there is some interesting evidence
emerging now that there perhaps was a
population collapse between what is
called the clovis culture and the folsom
culture.
The clovis culture appears in north
America to be what is believed to have
been the earliest culture and the,
there's a site in New Mexico that was
the first discovery of the,
the association of human artifacts,
meaning spear points and arrowheads and
things like that along with extinct
mammals.
Right.
This is clovis,
New Mexico.
It's a very interesting site.
I visited there about six or seven years
ago,
uh,
in order because I was looking for this
so called black matte layer,
which has now been documented at dozens
of clovis sites around north America.
And the black mat layer is this unique
layer,
uh,
that,
that essentially separates the
pleistocene from the holocene and it's
full of soot.
It's full of a radium nano diamonds,
microsphere olds and all of these
signature things that are indicative of
some kind of a cosmic event.
Is this an image indicative of that?
Is that what this is that.
yeah,
that's kind of a blurry image,
but right there you can see it up here
too.
So you can face the microphone.
Yeah.
The white strip in the middle shows the
black mat layer.
That's exactly it.
Um,
and what you see below it are the bones
of extinct mammals.
And what you see a couple of thousand
years later,
his bones of extent,
mammals and nowhere above that black
matte layer.
Do you find the bones of the extinct
mammals?
What is extent?
It means dead.
That snow still.
It's still exist.
Okay.
You know,
uh,
bears are extend.
I see.
You know,
that's the only mammoths are extinct.
So there's a very distinct line that can
be attributed to some sort of an event.
Yes,
some sort of innovate something before
that.
They're all alive,
something.
After that,
they're all dead.
They're all dead.
And a massive amount of the larger
mammals gone,
wiped off the face of the planet,
wiped off the face of the planet.
North America lost about 75 percent of
its species of mega man.
holy shit.
Three quarters.
Yeah,
there we go.
There we go.
There's some of them.
I learned that thing below that thing
below.
What is that fucking thing?
That giant ground sloth.
That fuCking thing is thE mega theOry.
I'm american.
I'm,
it's the giant ground sloths.
It was the size of an elephant.
oh my god,
these are the glyptodonts these are all
10,000
years ago.
Not this guide is a dinosaur's obviously
did norris.
Maximus is the giant moa.
This guy threw him in here for rock is
because he's just such an awesome
preacher.
The terror bird,
right?
It's the terror bird.
Yeah.
Scroll back up,
stop scrolling.
Jimmy,
look at that fucking bird.
That's a seven foot tall.
Bigger than that with eight.
Nine foot tall.
Yeah.
A bird that doesn't fly.
So essentially a murderous ostrich.
And this was the top of the food chain
during the miocene.
Really?
Yeah.
This was it.
This was the,
the,
the baddest ass predator on the planet
for awhile.
Really more so than a saber tooth tiger.
These guys existed before the saber
tooth tiger.
Wow.
But they succumbed to one of these
global events.
You got to bear in mind that if you take
a census of all the species that ever
existed compared to the species,
now it's conservative to say that 99
point nine,
nine percent of all species have become
extinct.
Wow.
And in the ones that,
uh,
and,
and of course most of those had went
extinct without any help from humans at
all.
Stops growing.
What does that fucking thing?
That's the last materium siberia come.
Jesus christ,
you begin to appreciate.
It's like a bowl that fucked a rhino.
It's like that.
Wow.
That's insane how big that is.
Oh,
it was huge.
I mean it was elephant sized,
basically a woolly rhinoceros the size
of an elephant.
And this is sila donta,
which is the classic willy right now.
So there've been quite a few species of
these guys found that were flash frozen.
And this is 12,000
years ago.
This thing existed.
Wooly rhinoceros.
Yes.
And we're in north America.
Jesus christ.
That's incredible.
And what is,
what's the mainstream explanation for
these things going away?
Good luck on trying to find one.
I have looked.
There iS none.
There is nothing.
They don't.
There's nothing.
So is this something that they just
haven't formed any theories about or
they don't try to or it's been ignored
because there's not enough information.
It's been ignored.
And here's why.
At the dawn of earth science,
geological science,
and early,
early 19th century to a man,
every one of the founding fathers of
geology,
whether it was william buckland or qva
or sir James Hall or or rodney merchants
and adam sedgwick,
you could go right down the line.
All of these guys from 18,
20 up to about 18,
60,
every one of them was task surfaced to a
man.
Everyone because these were guys
basically who had not been indoctrinated
into any particular interpretation of
world history.
They went out and they looked at
evidence in the landscape.
In their conclusion was,
you know,
something really catastrophic has
happened.
And then what happened was you had
charles lyle play fair and hot,
james hot and these three guys came
along and basically establish the
doctrine of uniformitarianism is.
It's called a mouthful,
right?
And basically the idea of
uniformitarianism was this,
is that we look at modern processes to
explain ancient process.
So if we see a river eroding,
it's bank moving sediment,
creating a sandbar with that.
If we see like during the early 19th
century,
we were in the last phase of the little
ice age,
so glaciers were receding and these guys
could essentially go up there and look
on a year to year basis and see what was
happening as the glaciers were receding.
Right?
So Basically what they then did was
extrapolated from modern processes to
try to explain all the ancient
processes.
This is the doctrine of
uniformitarianism.
Okay.
It's a very powerful model for
understanding ancient change.
However it became ensconced as dogma so
that by the turn of the century as we
come right up to the,
to the threshold of the 20th century,
it was now considered
unscientific to try to explain anything
in the past that we couldn't see
happening today.
Right?
So as we go into the 20th century,
this gradual,
as dogma became ensconced in academia,
in every geologist,
from about 1900 up to about 1980 was
thoroughly indoctrinated into this idea
of the gradualism that all of the earth
change that we see going on on the
planet today has occurred.
One grain of sand,
one drop of water at a time.
And it was considered to be very
unscientific to begin to evoke things
because initially some of the founding
fathers of geology were a lot of them.
Interestingly,
we were theologians who oftentimes a
number of like adam sedgwick is a good
example of somebody who is a,
a traveling theologian,
a traveling minister,
right?
He was traveling around england and he
was seeing things like the team's river
valley,
and he was seeing that the tims flowed
in this gigantic channel that was
completely outsized relative to the
river that was flowing in it.
And he says,
that must've been a huge flood wall.
He was a theologian,
right?
So he said,
no,
his flood.
Right.
Well,
as it turns out,
there are enormous jus morphic effects
of gigantic floods all over the planet.
Right.
We know that now,
right?
In the 18 hundreds,
they assumed that if you saw effects of
gigantic floods,
it had to have been noah's flood.
Well,
at the same time that you had geological
gradualism on the ascent,
jeal a biological gradualism came along
in the form of,
of darwinism.
And the two sort of complimented each
other in,
in,
in mutually supported each other.
Well,
if we've got infinite time,
you know,
millions and millions of years of
gradual geological change now that
allows us millions and millions of years
for gradual biological change.
And these two paradigms were mutually
reinforcing.
So now we come to the 20th century and
for the first three quarters of the 20th
century,
that was the dogma that was
indoctrinated into the minds of every
earth scientists.
Right?
And to vary from that was to be pseudo
scientific and you're trying to revert
back to biblical fundamentalism if you
start talking about giant floods,
right?
Well,
what happened was,
and it was left to people like emmanuel
volokhonsky.
It was not a neuroscientist.
He was a psychoanalyst and he wrote
several books in the mid 19 fifties
where he had gathered together in one
place all of this anomalous evidence
from the earth history that did not fit
the uniformitarian paradigm.
Now,
his books were popular successes,
but mainstream science just slammed him,
slammed him and said,
this guy's a nutcase.
Right?
well,
he did make some serious missteps in
trying to explain this anomalous
geological evidence for catastrophe and
it was those missteps that they were
able to focus on to try to discredit
him.
However,
the amassing of evidence for
catastrophes in earth history has held
the,
the test of time and and what we see as
1980 was a pivotal year.
That was a year that three separate
teams published evidence showing that
the cretaceous tertiary boundary,
the dinosaur boundary was profoundly
catastrophic,
and that opened the door to begin a
reconsideration of earth history.
Now,
at the same time,
with the advent of the space program,
we are beginning to realize that near
earth space is not a completely empty
place.
It's actually densely populated by all
kinds of things.
See,
prior to the apollo moon program,
it was believed that most of the craters
on the moon,
if not all of the craters on the moon,
where volcanic right post apollo.
The realization was that no,
they're not volcanic.
There impacts of things from space c.
Now you're looking at the surface of the
moon and I think I'm the last image on
the joe rogan images.
There is going to be a picture of the
moon and you'll see that it's littered
littered thousands and thousands and
thousands of craig
and because it doesn't have an
atmosphere because it doesn't have
plants,
we can actually see we can't explain.
It's happened
and the point joe is this.
If we were unable to strip away the
biosphere,
the thick layers of sedimentary rocks,
the oceans,
the earth would look like the moon.
God damn it would look like fucking
moon.
So it's simply a matter of time and
perspective that we really,
well thank thankfully these people like
you that are paying attention tests,
but we with the amount of time that
people have been videotaping things and
writing books,
this tiny little window that just hasn't
been enough time to really get a real
account of how often this takes place
because that,
that amount of time,
although it's a grand amount of time
compared to our lives,
the life of an individual for the life
of the planet,
it's nothing.
It's a perspective issue,
the perspective.
Yeah,
exactly.
Exactly.
And,
and this is one reason why I'm an
advocate for moving forward and
essentially becoming a cosmic
civilization.
You see,
I came of age during the heyday of the
mercury and gemini,
gemini and apollo programs,
and you know,
that was the one thing when I looked
back and I go,
well,
what?
One of the last times that I was really
proud of my country was when we put
those men on the moon.
You know,
when we planted our aMerican flag on the
moon,
and I really believe back in 1969,
1970,
that we were america's destiny was to
move the human
into this grander cosmic environment.
And then of course,
you know,
the Vietnam war came along and other
priorities and money got shifted in the
nixon administration shifted huge
amounts of money away from the space
program.
The timetable that was set out that we
were going to have a permanent lunar
base by the end of the seventies,
first manned mission to mars before the
eighties was over,
perhaps a independently self-supporting
colonies in space by the year 2000.
Remember I was a junior in high school
when a kubrick's 2001 a space odyssey
came out.
Have you ever seen it?
Sure.
Yeah.
Nineteen,
68.
Nobody had any.
It was no stretch of the imagination to
assumed that by 2001.
Yeah,
there were going to be orbiting hotels
in space.
RIght.
That could have happened,
but we lost our vision.
We lost our will and we just got
sidetracked.
You know,
I'm remembering the seventies talking to
people about the potential of colonizing
space,
using the materials and resources found
in space and that the knee jerk response
I always got was,
well,
we've got too many problems here on
earth.
We got to solve those problems first.
Well,
my response to that was,
well,
good luck because you're basically
talking about altering human nature,
right?
And it's going to take something more
than just some policy to alter human
nature.
What it's going to take is some serious
a consciousness excursions,
uh,
perhaps people going into space.
You know,
here we had these astronauts.
I met edgar mitchell years ago.
He's a a mace and he came to my lodge
years ago,
edgar mitchell,
who was one of the astronauts.
He was one of the many astronauts that
went into space and like as in free
mason as in freemasons,
everybody freaks out and you say
freemasons,
illuminati,
black helicopter nonsense,
and we should have a whole session just
to deal with that ridiculous nonsense
next time you freaked me out about that.
Okay.
So edgar mitchell,
when you met him,
was he talking about aliens?
No,
no,
no.
He was talking about going into space
and seeing god.
Whoa.
Crazier than aliens.
Yeah.
Crazier than the aliens.
Has god made aliens?
Perhaps.
So he saw god in the sense that he got a
sense.
It means without even saying god,
he got a sense of the,
the,
the grandness grand universe.
yes.
And,
and yes.
and you know,
the potential role of humans in that.
Have you ever been to the keck
observatory in Hawaii?
No,
I haven't.
The keck observatory in Hawaii is a very
unique place because it's on the big
island of Hawaii and it's very high up
in an altitude.
And when you get up there,
you actually drive through the clouds.
I took my family,
there are several years ago and uh,
we were bummed out when I was like,
god.
So clowning,
we're not gonna be able to see anything.
But then you pop through the clouds as
you continue to drive.
And the view is magnificent and in is
to this day,
one of the most intense experiences,
consciousness expanding experiences I've
ever had.
I believe it without drugs.
I mean,
it was like a psychedelic experience.
It really was because the,
the amount of.
That's the keck observatory.
See how it's above the clouds when you.
That's a daytime shot.
See jamie,
see if he could pull up at nighttime,
nighttime shot because they set the
camera aperture to capture the.
I didn't,
I had a regular camera I couldn't have.
I couldn't really capture the,
the actual stars themselves.
But you see the milky way,
like,
not like that.
It's way more intense than that.
You see the milky way in its full form.
You see?
All right.
Yeah.
And there's so many stars.
It's,
it's so shocking.
You,
you're immediately forced to accept the
reality that we're in space,
whereas it's so easy to deny when all
you see is the moon and a couple of
little dots,
like whatever,
man,
I'm in hollywood,
I got to go to work and you drive and
you get.
That's what it's like.
Yeah.
And it's.
So,
it's,
that's just a photograph and that's,
you know,
obviously there's some doctor and going
on because I don't know what those lines
are,
but it's insane how intense it is.
It's insane and it's,
it's,
it's right above you.
It's right above us all the time.
That's what I love about the high desert
plateaus.
You've got this dry atmosphere and it's
like literally you can almost reach out
and touch the stars.
You know what you're talking about.
You've never been to la before.
This is your first trip to la because
when you're in California,
you just go to the mojave and stare at
space space and I stare at the rocks,
the rocks below my feet and the stars
over my head.
Yeah.
How dId you get involved in the
exploration of all this stuff?
Well,
you know,
I guess I better,
it's time to come out of the closet,
like I did a little too many drugs back
in the sixties.
Uh,
I think he did the right amount.
Yeah,
I think you're being hard on yourself.
Actually.
Actually,
I'm in 1969,
so of course I wish I was raised in
rural Minnesota and where we grew up,
we lived on the shores of a puddle of
meltwater puddle leftover from the
receding of the glaciers.
yeah,
call it a puddle.
It's,
I call it a puddle.
It was three quarters of a mile long.
It was just,
you know,
Minnesota,
Wisconsin has got what,
25,000
lakes and every one of them is leftover
meltwater puddles from the recession of
the glacier,
so I can still remember being like six
or seven years old.
And my dad telling me,
you know,
once upon a time,
this was thousands of feet under the ice
and that's how this.
We had land on the edge of this lake.
And um,
as a kid I used to sit in my backyard
and fish for sunfish and crappies and
bulkheads.
That's what I don't understand that
interrupt for just one second.
How the fuck does that happen?
Were 10,000
years ago.
It's a glacier.
Ten thousand years later.
There's fish in there.
Where the fuck are the fish coming from?
I don't know,
but they were there.
But how?
Where's the large mouth bass come from?
What's the.
All this with the lake trout and the
great lakes.
Where the fuck did they come from?
If if 10,000
years ago.
That
was frozen.
Solid.
Frozen.
Where the fuck the lake trout come from?
I'll have to get to work on that joe,
because I don't know the answer.
I need to know man.
I'm freaking out.
How about northern pike?
I mean northern pike.
You go to saskatchewan.
People fly in from all over the world to
go fishing up there because they have
this massive population of beautiful
northern pike.
These big that was frozen.
Yes.
Saskatchewan was a mile of ice.
What the fuck man?
I'm freaking out.
That doesn't even make sense.
Yeah.
So you saw this.
So you were a kid.
I was a kid growing up with that
landscape,
so I got fascinated by it,
but in 1969 I went to a rock on outdoor
rock concert that was at an airport
called eden prairie.
that's in the.
I'm just outside of the twin cities,
minneapolis,
and it's on a series of bluffs that
overlooks the Minnesota river valley.
Right.
I'm,
of course I'm stoned out of my gourd and
I was taking a break from the music and
the ladies and everything and I went
over and was standing on this bluff,
andy and jamie,
if you would pull up.
I think it's near the end of the
pictures I brought for joe.
I have a beautiful example of scale
invariance and this is going to be
similar to what I saw.
And,
and when you see it,
um,
that's,
that's like the 25 images that's labeled
for joe picture though.
It'll be towards the end.
It's a picture of the snake river.
Find it.
wow.
The snake river.
Wait till you see this joe.
now this is an example of scale
invariance.
Now what that means is that,
you know,
yeah.
Here we go.
now look at this,
what you see here,
where can folks that are just listening
to this go and see these images is a
there.
Are they on your website?
Uh,
I think this one is on my website.
Yeah.
I think this one's on the snake river.
You see the snake river scale and
variance,
meaning that the river at the bottom,
obviously you see the lines all around
it where it indicates that there was a
much,
much larger body of water.
One point much better.
This,
the modern snake river is about 50,000
cubic feet per second,
right at the end of the last ice age,
the river here was about 30 to 40
million cubic feet per second.
So wAs that because of the melting
glaciers,
the force of this particular was not
directly fed by the melting glaciers.
It was the result of the catastrophic
overflow of lake bonneville,
which was the result of massive,
prolonged torrential rainfall that just
drowned all the deserts of the southern,
of the western and southwestern United
States.
And there was an overflow,
a spillway out of the lake,
bonneville basin in northern Utah,
and it's spilled over into the snake
river plain of Idaho.
Thirty to 40 million cubic feet per
second.
Cut this channel.
Now you'll notice that the modern snake
river occupies a small channel within
the big channel that scale invariance
I'm the big river,
would have been about equivalent to six
to 700 of the modern snake rivers.
And what you're seeing here is an
example of scale invariance say that the
little is superimposed upon this big
sea.
Now in 1969,
I was standing on a bluff overlooking
the Minnesota river valley,
similar to this,
right,
looking down at the little Minnesota
ribbon of the Minnesota river and seeing
it in this huge channel.
And I had an aha moment.
I had an aha moment and I realized I saw
then that this channel that this bluff I
was standing on had once been the bank
of a gigantic river,
thousands of times bigger than the
modern Minnesota river.
But I didn't know it rationally in the
sense that it took me another 10 or 15
years of study and research before I
could go back and say,
yeah,
what my initial instinct,
looking out and seeing this matching set
of bluffs for five miles on the other
side and seeing this small version of it
into modern river that I was right.
That I remember one time in the
eighties,
I was giving a talk on that and I.
There was a geologist in the audience
and he got up and he goes,
no,
no.
That big channel that was millions of
years,
millions of years.
It took for that channel to form.
And I said,
no,
I don't think so.
And what happened was,
is by him challenging me,
it really,
you know,
I said,
okay,
you know,
like an,
an,
an mma fighter getting challenged,
says,
okay,
I'm going to take you on,
you know,
I rose to the occasion and I spent
literally years doing research on
glacial geomorphology on paleo
hydrology.
And of course,
at the end of the thing I knew that I
was.
My instincts were absolutely correct
that yes,
now there is solid scientific,
documentable,
verifiable evidence that this whole
channel of the Minnesota river valley
was filled,
brim full with water at the end of the
lesson,
so when he was saying it was millions of
years,
he's saying that same exact channel of
water had never varied and that it had
just cut through over millions and
millions of years very slowly,
but does that sort of.
That doesn't seem rational because of
the width.
No,
it doesn't.
You'd have to.
It doesn't.
It doesn't make.
So this goes along with what you were
talking about earlier,
that the idea that the ideas of science
with that everything had taken place
much like evolution on a very gradual
pace.
Exactly.
Is this the grand canyon as well?
No,
I would.
Here's what I would saY about the grand
canyon.
I think that the grand canyon is
presently.
we can observe it,
that we can observe the Colorado rIver
eroding the grand canyon.
However,
I think that the erosion of the grand
canyon is not uniform.
It's episodic or which means that the
grand canyon has probably been there
between two and 5 million years because
for one thing,
the grand canyon wouldn't start eroding
until the Colorado plateau had lifted up
and 10 to 12 million years ago,
the rim rock of collar of the Colorado
plateau is limestone,
which implies a shallow marine
environment.
Right now when it's down at marine at
sea level,
it's not going to road.
It's not until the whole plateau lifts
up between five and 10 million years ago
that the downCutting can start.
So my takE On the grand canyon would be
that.
What happens is is we have.
You have to understand this now.
This is,
this is I think now is the,
is the merging emerging paradigm.
There are two modes of change.
The gradualist mode that we've seen
dominating through know the last few
hundred years at least sInce the advent
of modern science and then the,
if you want to call it the catastrophic
mode,
where is much change.
It's compressed into a few years or
months or sometimes even days or weeks
as normally would take thousands and
thousands of years.
When I look at the grand canyon,
what I'm seeing there is episodes of
catastrophic erosion,
probably stretching back over two and a
half million years.
Remember I said the pleistocene was
about two and a half million years.
What characterizes the pleistocene from
the previous plyo scene is this
alternating succession of glacial and
interglacial ages.
This swinging back and forth between
these two extremes,
those episodes of transition appear to
be profoundly catastrophic and they are
associated with things like massive
storms,
massive rainfalls,
rising and falling of sea levels on a
extreme a basis,
and I think it's that that has created
the grand canyon predominantly.
In fact,
the inner channel.
I know if you've ever seen grand canyon.
Yeah.
Okay.
There's an inner gorge I could guess at
that inner gorgeous,
probably less than 100,000
years old and uh,
probably a lot of it was cut 13,000
years ago.
Wow.
And so that's when the pleistocene ended
somewhere around 10,000
years ago.
Ten to 13,000
Wow.
Yeah.
That's a,
that's not a real fixture is it seems
like an artist's rendition.
Yeah.
I have pictures somewhere in there where
you still get a sense.
Yeah.
Now the,
the,
the accumulation of the sedimentary
rocks.
Yeah.
Took hundreds of millions of years,
but that's one process.
The downcutting,
the erosion of the canyon is a different
process.
So again,
it comes to a matter of perspective that
we're almost incapable of.
Let me,
I think,
you know,
academically
and you could sort of explain how all
this takes place and explain what's
happening,
but in our minds are our perspective of
living a hundred years.
Looking back,
it's very difficult to go back 20 years
ago.
Oh,
I remember when that happened.
Wow.
Barely.
But this is,
that ain't shit compared to the earth,
the earth,
the earth is just constantly changing
and our knowledge of human history,
we have this sort of static view and
occasionally we have that meteor that
flew over Russia recently and blew up in
the sky and everybody's like,
whoa,
what's,
uh,
what's that?
And then it stops.
Then nothing go back to work,
go back to work,
go back to sleep.
Yeah.
And that thing that blew up over Russia,
that was,
that was a spec and there was nothing.
And then those turn goose which blew up
in the early 19 hundreds.
Nineteen.
Oh,
eight.
June 30th,
19.
Oh eight.
Which just flat and thousands and
thousands of acres.
Oh,
well,
let's see.
It was 800 square miles and 640 acres
per square mile.
So it flat and a half a million acres,
a million acres.
And that was the energy of that was
about equivalent to a 15 megaton bomb
pull up.
There's an image of tongue goes.
Yeah,
just all the trees completely flattened.
Completely flat.
A few look at that.
Gangster tree is still standing there.
Hasn't happened.
I know.
It's just like every now and then just
one bad motherfucker tree.
That's how people stay alive,
right?
Because just like everybody else died or
most things died and most of the species
died.
a few people figured out a way to make
it.
And then they decided to have babies.
What a bunch of crazy fucked.
Could you imagine?
A giant asteroid hits.
Kills everybody.
Rotten people and woolly mammoths all
over the place and you're still horny,
still horny,
and you make a baby like wow,
and you raise it and that baby makes
more bikes.
What does it say in the book of genesis?
Be fruitful and multiply.
Now get this the word,
replenish the earth,
replenish the earth and subdue it.
I think clearly that's a clear hint that
saying this is not the primordial
creation.
It's a subsequent creation to something.
A previous order of things.
Why you used the word replenish.
Be fruitful and multiply.
It would make sense if if the human
population crashes in the wake of a
global catastrophe and we're down
hovering at the threshold of viability
where you know,
we could become extinct if just anything
else happens and we want to.
We want to preserve our species while
the.
Probably the thing we need to be doing
is having a lots of sex.
Hm.
That's what I'm talking about.
Yeah,
I know.
I mean we need to do a lots of screwing
and we need to screw and make scientists
to figure out how to get us off this
rock.
Yeah.
Well,
see,
be fruitful and multiply.
It makes patient replenish the earth
and subdue it.
What the hell is that?
Is this a subdue it?
Subdue it.
That's in genesis in genesis.
What the hell are they talking about?
They're choke the earth.
Well,
I see.
That's the way it's been interpreted.
I think it's being interpreted to say,
look,
you guys are the only rational species
down there.
You've got these big brains,
you know,
you gotta be born before,
it takes you years and years to actually
get where you can survive on your own
because you've got these big fucking
brain.
See?
So we're kind of like nature's answer to
all of this.
You know,
only one species right now has the
ability to intercede and prevent the
next global catastrophe.
And that's us.
Do we rise to that challenge or do we
say,
well,
we're going to let nature run its course
and if 50 percent of the species
disappear,
civilization is over.
We go back to the stone age struggling
for existence.
Well,
so be it.
That's what's in the cards or do we say,
you know what?
We could be in one generation be
harvesting to resources of asteroids,
which we could be if we had the will
innovation and the thing is,
is that the most dangerous asteroids
that are out there,
it's the closer they get to the earth,
the more accessible they are.
And,
and you see we already could be
harvesting the resources of astra.
I meAn asteroids are loaded with
precious metals and ors and
hydrocarbons.
there's virtually nothing that we are
now mining from the earth that we
couldn't mind from asteroids.
Wow.
What does that suggest to you?
Well,
and,
and think about this,
if,
if I like to kind of imagine a scenario,
suppose we had discovered,
remember shoemaker levy nine?
Yes.
Okay.
Discovered in march of 1996,
within about eight weeks of
observations,
the astronomers were able to predict
that these fragmented pieces,
we're going to orbit the sun and
comeback and be crossing the orbit of
jupiter at exactly the time to jupiter
was there,
right?
There was going to be a t bone
collision.
It was like two vehicles coming to the
intersection at the same time and they
were able to predict that right down to
the,
almost to the minute to the hemisphere,
what if we discovered that there's an
asteroid orbiting the sun out there
that's got our number on it and it was
going to strike the earth and three
years or 10 years or 20 years or
whatever.
What would be our response to it?
What will we do?
I think globally it would be,
there would have to be some sort of a
collective x effort.
Yeah.
The scientists from China and Russia and
all these different various countries
that have a vast technological
capabilities would probably get together
and have some sort of an agreement.
I would think that that would have to
happen and it would fact,
it would probably make our petty human
conflicts pale into insignificance if we
were faced with the demise of
civilization or even possibly our
species,
but suppose we discovered it and it's
coming in a couple of years and there's
no time to respond.
What could we do?
Well,
perhaps if we had a loNg enough lead
time,
we could actually deflect.
All we need to do is is is an asteroid
that's on a collision course with the
aerosol it has to do is be nudged a
little bit in a direct hit,
can be a wide miss.
See,
that's all we would have to do is just
nudge it a little and there's various
potential technologies whereby we could
do that,
but what if we didn't have enough lead
time and we knew that,
that it was going to slam into the earth
and for a thousand years gonna be havoc.
What would we do?
Well,
perhaps we could go build a base on the
moon or build a a something in space
that would allow humans to survive at
least until the dust settled enough that
we could return and begin to replenish
the earth.
you know what a bummer it would be if
you had a base on the moon and everyone
was living there and you wash the earth
below up.
Total bummer,
but it would be even bigger.
Bummer if you didn't have it and you
were sitting on the earth.
Knowing that that's it,
man,
that's all she wrote.
How many different times do you think
that this has happened while human
beings are alive and how the,
the,
the great speculation has always been
when they see the pyramids or when they
see any incredible structures that we
really haven't totally explained how
they built what like bow back in Lebanon
is what,
how advanced were they?
How advanced were they before the shit
hit the fan?
Well,
it seems to me then in order to,
you know,
you gotta go,
why would primitive cultures move rocks
that weighed 200 to a thousand tons?
Apparently with impunity,
they were doing it all over the planet,
right?
W why would,
why would somebody be motivated?
I mean,
you know,
like again,
I'm a builder so I know how much work it
takes to move even a,
you know,
without a crane,
without modern technology to move,
uh,
a beam into place that weighs a ton.
Right?
Well,
you know,
we've got stones in some of these
ancient temples that way.
Hundreds of tons and again,
all over the world.
It seems to me difficult to imagine that
they didn't have some kind of a
technology that we've forgot what that
technology is.
I couldn't say,
um,
but it would sure seem to me that there
would be no motive for moving,
you know,
500 tons stones,
unless you had some convenient way of
doing it or
if not a convenient way of doing it.
just explain how an inconvenient way
they could have done it.
When you get something like the
acropolis or the parthenon that's on the
acropolis,
right?
Isn't that,
what is the part?
The acropolis is the stone and the
parthenon is what's on the hill complex
on it,
but the parthenon is one of those
impulse.
The acropolis is a manmade construction
that has massive,
massive stones that they just don't
explain.
Yeah.
I mean,
they're there.
They're in there.
They're in cusco in south America.
They're in Egypt.
Yeah.
There it is.
The ball back one is actually probably
even more impressive.
Chamie.
See if he could pull that up and stones
have a ball.
How do you spell it?
B double a l,
b,
e,
k and there there's these stones are
just unbelievably big.
Yeah,
and no explanation for how they moved
them,
cut them and them got them into place
and what year it was all done,
right.
That's one vision of it or a picture of
it,
but if you search for others is actually
a closeup of the actual stones
themselves and they show people standing
next to the stone so you get a
perspective of it.
Much,
much taller than a human being.
In fact,
I think 10 or 11 feet tall and some
places like there's one rock just like
fuck that.
But some of the stones,
the.
That's not a good one,
jamie.
There's some where you can see the
massive amount of,
uh,
of,
of stone that was in each individual
one.
Some of them are literally building
sized and it's just an individual stone
and yeah,
there's one like,
what the fuck man,
what the fuck is that?
That is so big.
They moved that.
They cut that query.
Didn't move it.
Yeah.
I mean,
I don't know how many people they had to
do that,
but boy that doesn't seem like something
that a society which is really concerned
with feeding itself is a is going to get
done what?
So when you see like the constructions
of the great pyramids,
which is one of the great wonders of the
world and to this day they're always
trying to come up with ways that they
did it,
but the sheer size and to put it into
perspective,
if you cut and I think the number is 10
stones,
that debt is $6 million,
300,000
plus stones in the great pyramid of giza
and if you cut and placed 10 a day,
it would take you 664 years.
Yeah.
I,
you know.
Yeah.
Having seen the great pyramid and many
of the temples in Egypt,
I'm convinced that they had to have some
means that we've forgotten about for
transporting these stones.
You know,
they may have used fairly primitive
methods to quarry the stones,
but when it comes to transporting the
stones,
you know,
I mean,
we could imagine that they're putting
them on rollers and dragging them over
hill and dale,
but again,
you got to go really all over the whole
planet.
It just,
it's one of those things,
it's like the demise of the frozen
woolly mammoths.
There's just no real explanation.
And,
and we can invoke explanations that are
basically designed to avoid the
implications of admitting that there may
have been advanced knowledge,
scientific knowledge in prehistory,
and that somehow or another,
that knowledge was lost,
whether it was because of the burning of
the library of alexandria or whether it
was just a cataclysmic event that wiped
out a massive amount of the population.
And what was remaining was buildings
like that.
Those things survived.
And then people tried to recreate them.
People eventually figured out some of
the techniques and made similar
structures,
but not over a period of a thousand
years or two years,
but maybe 20,
30,000
years.
That's always been the work of graham
hancock,
the,
uh,
the ideas they bounced around and uh,
I remember there was that charlton
heston narrated a documentary on the
sphinx where they had gone into great
detail about the erosion and they
brought him the geologists,
robert schoch from boston university.
I know robert,
I want to get him on the podcast too.
He's a fascinating cat and he concluded
that the temple,
the sphinx,
the enclosure where it was cut out of
shows thousands of years of erosion by
rainfall,
which there wasn't rainfall in the nile
valley before 9,000
years ago.
So it predates the pyramid construction,
the average or the,
uh,
the conventional dating of the pyramid.
There it is right there.
There's some explanations.
It predates the,
what the conventional date of the
pyramid is by more than 5,000
years.
Oh,
I'm convinced.
And I've had conversations with robert
where he will basically say he's got one
number for public consumption,
but he's perfectly willing to admit that
perhaps this makes is much,
much older than that.
And I,
what's the dark number?
What's the crazy number?
Oh,
I think that the crazy number is tens of
thousands of years if you pull up.
It's not that crazy though.
Now it was kind of crazy when that
charlton heston documentary,
the documentary was around,
but now that they found go beckley
tapping and they know that 14,000,
12,000
years ago,
whatever it was,
they were absolutely building these
enormous,
immense structures that would be what,
8,000
years,
70,000
years earlier than the pyramids.
Not that.
Not that big a deal.
Not that big of a deal.
They,
they,
the conventional dating of the great
pyramid of giza is 2,500
bc,
which may be correct,
but it still doesn't mean that the
sphinx wasn't way older than me.
Way older than that.
Exactly.
And you know,
I'm convinced having seen it firsthand
that that erosion is water induced.
I've looked at a lot of erosioN over the
years and you know,
it's got the classic parabolic profile
that you would expect if you started out
with an initially square.
I'm jamie,
open up the powerpoint show entitled a
cataclysmic,
most global super flood,
cataclysmic global superstar.
That's my new band.
It's going to be my new band.
Go for me.
Cataclysmic.
Cataclysmic was the greek term for the
destruction of the world by water.
Oh wow.
From where we get our term cataclysm.
Whoa.
And their term.
See,
you know,
the greeks believed that they were
alternating destructions of the world by
water and fire,
right?
Eq per paralysis was the term greek term
for the destruction of the world by
fire.
Wow.
And um,
cataclysmic of,
of water on this stuff is so
unbelievably fascinating because there's
no way that you can attribute all of
this stuff.
I mean,
these,
all of these ancient structures,
there's no way you can attribute it to
what we know about their culture.
We don't know enough.
There's just not enough evidence.
There's not enough.
We don't know enough about ancient Egypt
or you know,
or their construction methods are so
much.
There's so much thinking,
so much guesswork,
so much.
You know,
when you look at these giant structures
and you wonder,
like,
what,
what were they doing?
How did they do this?
Who are they like?
It's so fascinating.
I would just,
I would love to be able to go back in
time inside a giant bulletproof bubble.
I know.
Just hover over ancient Egypt.
That was going on back then.
I know.
When did you guys know jamie go?
You've got a global super fluid.
What is this image?
Go to slide 58 slash 58.
The infamous slide 58.
Hanger 18.
Slide 58 hours.
There it is.
Wow.
That's beautiful.
Okay,
that's amazing.
Now what you can see there is you got to
get it into the microphone.
Get on the microphone there.
The valley temple up there.
Oh yeah.
Okay.
The valley temple with stones quarried
from the ditch around the sphinx and
you've got to remember what the sphinx
is that originally it was a yard day,
which is a,
which is a limestone outcrop that sticks
above the surrounding landscape that
yardang was the head of the sphinx.
Everything else was below.
Now go to the next slide,
jamie.
Okay.
There yoU can really see the ditch
surrounding the sphinx and the layers
forming.
The sphinx body correspond to the layers
into surrounding ditch.
Now wanting to me notice the scaffolding
next to the sphinx.
They're there.
They're there,
they're undertaking these campaigns of
rests,
quote unquote,
restoration grows,
but what they're actually doing is
they're covering up the real message of
the sphinx.
Know why are they doing that?
Why are they bothering to try to rebuild
the thing?
Know it's so stupid like,
wait,
you're not rebuilding it.
You're building new shit.
Yeah,
you're just rephrasing it with,
with new stones.
So gross,
but at least nobody is messing with the
quarry walls where you can see the water
erosion so effectively displayed.
Go to the next slide,
jamie.
Now what we see here is an abandoned
quarry.
It's hard to tell the scale here because
that opening is like 40 feet high,
but if you look at,
you see the striations in the rock wall.
Okay?
This is where they quarried the blocks,
right?
And remove the blocks.
Go to the next slide,
jamie.
Okay.
This kind of shows the methodology that
they use.
They,
they would create these separation
trenches.
They would usually go by the,
the natural bed bedding layers of the
rock.
Go to the next slide and you'll see
here,
here's the presumed process where
they're cutting a separation tranche and
there's a block about to be quarried
there.
And then you can see there would have a
stack of four blocks there.
And these blocks are enormous.
Several tons.
Oh yeah.
That,
that block there would be,
it looks like it's probably about four
by eight by probably 10.
So like 320 cubic feet at 160 per.
So,
uh,
or 180.
So you're looking at about 57,000
pounds divided by 2000.
So yeah,
about two.
Yeah,
about 30 tons.
She's got 30 tons for that rock right
there.
Now go to the next slide.
Thirty tons.
Okay.
Now the reason I'm showing you this is
because this is the process they would
have used to quarry the blocks away from
the,
the surrounding the sphinx and exposed a
quarry wall.
Well,
at the time that quarry wall was
exposed,
it would have been essentially a flat
surface with this slightly stepped
profile like we saw in the photograph.
Right now,
go to the next slide,
right?
So there's now would be a cross section
with all of the blocks removed.
Okay,
go to the next slide.
And what we have here is stone pick
marks in a limestone quarry from
pharmacy times about 1200 bc.
So about 3,200
years ago.
So here's a limestone face of a quarry
that's been exposed for 3000,
200 years and it seems like they used to
some sort of a chisel to get that out.
Exactly.
The pick marks are still visible.
Go to the next slide.
Okay.
Here's stone pick marks in a quarry from
nearly new kingdom circa 15.
So 3,500
years ago you can actually determine the
type of tool that they used to quarry
the rocks.
The picks are the chisels.
Go to the next one based on the market
are based on tomorrow.
Yeah.
And here you see that the chisel marks
made or pick marks made by stone picks
in an old kingdom.
Limestone quarry,
2000 years bc.
So here's a 4,000
year old quarry that's been sitting
exposed to the desert elements and the
pick marks are still visible on the
face.
Now go to the next slide.
Now here's the spanx.
Go to the next slide and look at that
quarry wall.
Yeah,
that's crazy.
It's crazy.
Yeah.
Now,
supposedly this quarry wall is only a
few centuries older than net.
Last picture.
We just saw where we could see the pic
marks.
Does that make sense?
Well,
the only way it would make sense as if
there was a vastly different type of
stone.
Well,
it's not though.
It's the same.
It's a.
Well indurated limestone.
Robert can tell you all about the
composition of that stone,
but the.
The composition does vary though.
Oh yeah,
correct.
Like some.
Some of it's more dense than others and
that's.
you can see the changes and you can see
that that indented layer about halfway
up,
it's going to be a softer limestone.
Absolutely.
It certainly looks to the layman and I'm
clearly a layman,
but it certainly looks like like water
fishers,
like,
oh,
fishers that are driven rainfall.
Even to the trained eye,
it looks like water,
but some legit egyptologists and even
legit geologists have tried to attribute
this to a wind and sand.
Well,
again,
you know robert has shown pictures of
the comparison of wind erosion or water
erosion and they don't look the same,
so the only reason to attribute this to
wind and sand,
it's not based on the scientific
evidence of what it looks like when
there's water erosion.
It's to confirm or to conform with the
known or established timeline of
construction.
Yes,
and that's why I showed you those
examples of other core like that old
kingdom quarry that's almost the same
age as this,
so it's actually really not scientific
to try to attribute it to wind and sand.
It's just your.
What you're doing is confirming to
confirmation bias.
You have,
you have an idea in your head and you're
trying to to make this really odd
erosion fit into that,
but that doesn't look like wind and
sand.
Go to the next in lik joey,
jamie,
I'll jam band.
So there's the depth of the,
of the,
of the ditch.
It's about 22 feet and eric show shows
each of the layers.
Like if you look at layer of Lebanon,
that's going to be a softer limestone.
it's eroded deeper right now.
Go to the next slide and you'll see what
I've done is superimposed what the
original profile would have looked like
and there's been an enormous amount of
rock limestone rock removed and we know
the profile would have looked like that
because the stones that were quarried
are what make up the sphinx and valley
temples.
The no's have been eroded as well,
but unfortunately they've covered that
up with this reconstruction.
Most likely,
most likely,
and I think robert would confirm this,
that the limestone blocks at formed
those temples were sheathed in hard
granted.
Whereas this quarry wall was not.
It was exposed and then there's also the
issue of the sphinx head itself,
which seems to have been altered in
this.
This is a timeline thing that folks may
or may not know,
but there's been.
The Egypt changed quite a bit,
mean Egypt.
Ancient Egypt was around for thousands
and thousands of years and at some point
they were conquered by the nubians and
the more african,
what we think of as traditional african
feet.
Obviously Egypt as part of africa,
but the more traditional looking african
faces is what you see in the current
face in the temple this face.
So probably whaT had happened is a later
date pharaoh said,
you know what?
Fuck this line.
I want my face up there.
So they put the face of this probably
catherine [inaudible] and I think both
John Anthony West and robert schoch
would concur with.
That's why there's so little erosion on
that face.
That face is only a few thousand years
old and why it would be
disproportionately small compared to the
rest of the body.
So fascinating.
I've just.
I would give so much to know what they
knew then if any point in time to go
back in human history and just to be
able to observe.
That would be the time that the just the
middle of Egypt.
I would love to see what it looked like
before they raided it and took off.
For folks that don't know,
it was covered in smooth limestone and
they cut it all up to build cairo.
They rated it.
Yeah.
There was an earthquake that flattened
cairo and you know they had attempted to
penetrate the great pyramid prior to
that without success,
but apparently the earthquake,
which I think happened,
I think it happened in the twelfth
century,
loosened a few rocks from near the top
of the pyramid that allowed them to get
some levers in there and begin to pry
them loose.
So I've read a bunch of fucking assholes
talk about vandalism that get this,
whether this is true or not,
we have no way of knowing,
but there are many,
many arabic accounts and accounts of
early travelers and pretty much they all
unanimously declare that the entire
outside of the pyramid was inscribed.
Now think about that.
What in the hell would that have been
telling?
What kind of message was that that was
being sent to the future?
That must've been amazing.
Yeah.
I get.
I get my.
My hair stands up on my legs.
Just thinking about inscribed.
Yeah.
Hey listen,
there's rocks in space and occasionally
they land and when they do you're
fucked.
Build one of these.
get inside,
wait for
further instruction.
It's amazing that there.
I mean,
if that thing existed,
if you've robert schoch has corrected,
nothing existed before the holocene
events.
Those are the only types of structures
that would still be here.
Yeah,
exactly.
Fuck,
did people make it through there?
I wonder what the number was.
Well,
I'm going to adam and eve story.
Here's my theory on it.
You know,
all over the world we have traditions
about cactus catastrophes and cataclysms
and giant floods all over the world.
They've come down to us and there's a
lot of deviation,
but there's also a lot of similarity in
them.
The idea that a small group had some
kind of foreign knowledge,
you know,
whether it was knowing the bible or do
kalien in the greek myths or wooten,
a pitch to him into samarian myths,
or is this a thrusts or man knew.
I mean the,
the,
the culture heroes that survived these
great cataclysmic floods are into dozens
and dozens.
Right?
American indians had prolific traditions
about giant floods when,
when george,
caitlin,
the famous indian artist,
spent decades of his life going around
living with various indian tribes like
40 years painting and in writing about
him,
very interesting quote in one of his
books,
he says that they're widely divergent
with traditions and language and customs
and so on,
but have a hundred and 20 tribes that he
visited.
They all had one thing in common that
they were descended from survivors of
some gigantic cataclysmic event.
That's american indian.
Do you find it in north America?
You find it in south America.
You find it in the polynesian islands.
You find it in Australia,
Japan.
I mean,
it's around the entire planet.
This idea,
and now modern science is confirming
what we assumed was merely some kind of
superstitious nonsense.
Have,
you know,
pre scientific illiterate,
barbarians.
And we're realizing that those myths and
those stories and epic tales that have
been handed down for centuries and
centuries actually contained hard
scientific truth from surviving
eyewitnesses.
Well,
if these craters actually do exist,
and they do right,
craters undeniable.
The nuclear glass throughout asia and
europe,
undeniable human beings were alive then.
Yes,
and if human beings were alive,
then they got fucked up.
There's no doubt about it.
Yeah,
they did.
They,
they,
they would have suffered enormously and
just like,
you know,
if,
if you know,
if three quarters of the species of
animals in north America when extinct,
do you think that the 25 percent
surviving came through completely
unscathed?
No.
It simply means that there's a threshold
above which species is viable.
It can survive.
There's there and below,
which you know,
there may have been survivors,
but there just weren't enough of them.
They were too widely scattered,
serious habitat loss which would have
diminished food supply in a just died
out,
but either directly or indirectly as a
result of these catastrophic
environmental changes that accompanied
the ending of the ice age.
Humans had to have been affected by this
and all of the myths and the stories
would totally concur with that idea.
You know,
that,
that there were humans and,
and they're all consistent with this one
detail,
that there were some humans that had for
knowledge and so they built arcs to
kalea and built an ark just like noah
did,
wooten,
dipesh to built an ark.
Zissel sutras built an ark man,
new built an ark.
Where are these stories coming from?
You know,
are they just completely conjured up
independently of one another and that
detail is just thrown in or is there
some kind of a reality behind this that
there were people who had for knowledge?
Well,
if there were people that had foreign
success to suggest to me that there were
two groups of survivors,
those who survived because they
intentionally planned to survive.
They had for knowledge.
They took steps to secure their survival
in freemasonry there.
So the account of,
um,
of lamech or the account of enoch,
there's variances on it.
But enoch,
the story of enoch in,
in,
in masonic tradition says that enoch
had,
you know,
he was in the,
into the patriarchs before noah had this
for knowledge,
that the world was going to be destroyed
either by fire or flood.
So he created this underground vault.
It was deep underground,
and it was cool.
It was preserved within nine layers of
stone.
It was nine layered vault and you only
in unless you had the key to accessing
to,
to how to access this vault,
which was now like a time capsule that
preserved the science and the knowledge
and the wisdom of the [inaudible] world
or pre flood world.
He then set up two pillars,
pillar of brass,
and a pillar of marble.
The pillar of brass designed to
withstand the effects of the cataclysm.
The lottery destruction.
The pillar of marble,
if I'm remembering it right,
was to withstand the,
the,
uh,
the destruction by fire.
So there were these two pillars that
basically informed any survivors that
there was this nine chambered
underground fault that contained the
secrets of the previous world age that
has what's coming to a pass.
And that's an intrinsic part of masonic
tradition.
In fact,
the whole masonic symbolism is based
around that idea.
And um,
and it has parallels throughout other
traditions as well.
Well,
what I'm getting at here is if,
if there was some people who had for
knowledge of it and took steps to
survive,
they were the ones who preserved the
knowledge of the pre,
the,
the previous,
the antediluvian world order,
the other survivors just survive by the
luck of the draw.
Like that tree standing there,
right?
They just happened to be in the right
place at the right time.
They survived,
but now they are going to be the ones
who are going to be wholly preoccupied
simply with the task of surviving,
finding enough food to eat and shelter.
Because clearly the planetarium
environment was going through all kinds
of changes.
Whereas the other group had taken actual
steps to survive and preserve knowledge.
Now,
when we look at the beginning of
recorded history,
4,000
to 5,000
years ago were basically halfway back
through the holocene.
Right,
okay.
Let's for purposes of conjecture,
assumed that the end of the holocene
human population crashed,
right?
Well,
if you want to build a pyramid or a
great temple,
you've got to have a labor force,
right?
Well,
if you've got scattered bands of
survivors,
you basically aren't going to be able to
accomplish that.
Now,
let's assume that you've got two groups
of humanity,
one that's sitting there with all of
this knowledge at their disposal,
just like imagine if our modern society
was wiped off the face of the earth,
but somebody somewhere in some deep cave
underground was able to preserve our
knowledge of physics and chemistry and
and the various sciences.
Well,
obviously in order to run this computer
that we're running here to do this
broadcast requires an intact huge,
intact infrastructure.
Right?
Well,
we could know how to build a computer.
We could know how to do,
how to broadcast,
but if we don't have the infrastructure,
we're just sitting on information,
right?
Well,
let's assume that you have a group that
survived,
right?
And they've got,
they're the custodians of this body of
knowledge right now.
It takes 3000,
4,000,
5,000
years for the human population to
reconstitute itself and now you've got a
labor force and let's suppose that
there's gonna be another cataclysm
impending,
you know,
such as the one that perhaps caused the,
the,
the noah's flood,
which,
you know,
there's evidence now that around 5,000
years ago there was an asteroid impact
into the indian ocean,
right?
That plunge through two miles of ocean
water and blasted a,
a 12 mile wide hole on the floor of the
indian ocean.
And what year was this?
This would have been about 5,000
years ago now.
How much of an impact would that have
had?
Oh,
it would have created tsunamis.
Well,
I'm on the island of Madagascar and the
southern island of Madagascar,
and it should be in this,
in this program that we've got open
right here.
Jamie.
Um,
if you go to slide number,
yeah,
go to slide number 111.
It's so ironic that today our focus is
closer and closer to the cloud and
closer
to chips to solid state,
hard drives,
all these different things that are just
not going to last,
right?
No paper.
No,
but no one's carbon.
Anything in stone,
you know,
the knowledge that we have is like how
much of what,
what everybody has his own hard drives.
I mean how much of what everybody has is
in the cloud on a server somewhere.
Yeah.
And who the fuck is going to be able to
figure out how to read that shit a
thousand years from now.
Yeah.
Just anything happened to us.
We're trying to figure out how to read
egyptian hieroglyphs.
Okay.
Look at.
Look at slide number 111.
Now wish I had my pointer here.
Go to the next slide so you can see we.
Okay.
Right there.
You see,
you see those weekly things like dragon
scales?
Yeah.
What that is is it's water,
ocean water that washed on land and
washed up and you see it kind of comes
to a point and then it washed back out.
This is,
this is a tsunami deposit and those few
features that you're looking at,
the kind of look like this there,
she called chevron's right?
That's what happens when the water
washes in,
makes deposits of giant ripples and then
washes back.
What kind of timeframe are you talking
about when this happens?
How long statistics do the oh hours.
So that all happened in hours.
In hours.
And you could still see it today.
Oh yeah.
Go to the next slide.
Jamey.
We're getting a closer up look here.
Now you see how,
see how they're shaped.
Almost like that's the chevron,
like a sergeant stripe almost,
right?
Okay.
Go to the next slide.
Here's a cross section of one of those v
shaped hills at 600 feet in height.
Wow,
that's incredible.
Now what?
So what you're seeing in the back.
That up.
One more jamie.
So those images right there.
What we're seeing there,
it looks like the effects of a river or
water or something.
It is water.
Yeah.
But then when you go back,
you see it from the ground.
It looks like hills.
Yeah.
Six hundred feet high.
So you're talking about a massive amount
of water.
We're talking about a tsunami whose
minimum run up height is the height,
the thickness of these hills,
600 feet minimum,
minimum minimum,
and that's of course massive amount of
weight and devastation.
And this was all 5,000
years ago.
Yeah.
Go to the next slide,
jamie.
Uh,
keep.
Yeah.
There's Madagascar location of the
chevrons on the southern edge of
Madagascar.
Let's see.
Go to slides up
and
over on the other side at the same age.
If we look at the southwestern coast of
Australia,
I think the next slide,
we'll get a closer in view.
There we go.
You see that?
Splurge.
That's,
that's the technical scientific term
isn't really blueedge.
No,
I just made that.
You bet.
You
see,
you see the stuff that's been washed
over.
You can see it.
It's very clear there.
Okay.
That's the other side of the ocean.
So the other side of the ocean directly
opposite of where this thing impacted.
Yeah.
Go to the next massive impact in the
middle.
Yeah.
Ancient crash.
Epic.
Wait,
let's go back to that slide where from
the word says ancient crash,
epic wave.
Next slide.
Keep going right there.
Right there.
Can we read that?
Yeah.
The southern end of Madagascar lie for
enormous wedge shaped deposits called
chevrons that are composed of material
from the ocean floor.
Each covers twice the area of manhattan
with sediment as deep as the chrysler
building is high on close inspection.
The chevron deposits contained deep
ocean microfossils that are fused with
medley of metals typically form by
cosmic impacts.
Wow.
Holy shit.
Yeah,
yeah.
Holy shit.
And so that,
if that happened 4,000,
800 years ago,
um,
what,
what kind of an impact would that have
had on human civilization?
Oh,
well it pretty much would have wiped out
anything adjacent to the indian ocean.
Anything close to it.
But what about on the other side of the
planet?
I mean,
there would have to be some massive
effects.
Oh,
there would be.
Most likely.
What we would see on the other side of
the planet is extreme weather events,
hurricanes,
torrential rain falls,
things like that.
Winter kill a huge amount of people
worldwide could kill a human,
a huge amount of people worldwide.
Yes.
Wow.
And so that is probably the most recent
one.
That's probably the most recent and no
record of it because people really
didn't have any records.
I think the record of it is probably
when we see these stories like noah's
flood and the rest.
So that's probably about this one.
So it's not even about the holocene one.
It's about one 5,000
years after the house in one.
Yes.
See,
that's what we're beginning to realize
now is that these events have happened
with a much greater degree of frequency
than anybody hit imagined.
well,
congratulations.
You freaked me the fuck out.
I just want to say,
you know,
you had an objective and you pull it off
of five stars a plus freakout.
Wow.
This is a.
This has been an intense three hours.
It just flew by three hours.
Yeah,
we just did three hours.
Wow.
It's over.
Yeah.
That amazing.
We got to do this again.
I bet you could talk for another 16
hours.
Yeah,
I mean we've barely scratched the
surface here.
Oh,
please,
let's do it again.
Let's take a couple months off,
regroup and come back in again.
Oh,
I'd love to do some more.
Thank you very much for doing this.
I really,
really appreciate it.
It is incredibly enjoyable,
incredibly enlightening for me.
I really,
really appreciate it.
I knew it was going to be like this.
Just the brief conversation that we had
a chance to have in atlanta,
you know,
many years ago.
I've been looking forward to talking to
you again.
Thank you very much for doing this.
Oh,
it's been awesome.
I really,
really have enjoyed it.
If people want to research more your
work,
read
more of your stuff,
where can they go?
Where can they,
what can they find?
Go to sacred geometry,
international.com
and there are links there.
I've got another website that linked
from there,
so like in sacred geometry,
international idea with a bunch of
different stuff.
Not directly connected necessarily with
what we're talking about here,
but there'll be links to another website
that I've got where I'm really exploring
like the catastrophic stuff or I've got
lots of images of,
of things.
Um,
yeah.
cause I've done lots and lots of field
exploration.
They have thousands of images of just
awesome stuff.
Does it sacred geometry have anything to
do with this stuff or is that a totally
different sacred geometry?
Put it this way as we've inherited this
corpus of ancient knowledge,
sacred geometry is one of the keys for
deciphering these ancient traditions
because all of these ancient temple
structures which are the textbooks in
stone,
if you will have several components in,
in common astronomical and geometrical
being the two predominant.
And if you understand the geometry,
you realize the geometry is like a
universal code by where whereby you can
preserve certain types of information
because geometry is universal.
It doesn't matter what your spoken
language is,
the principles of geometry are what they
are,
you know,
the relationship of a,
of a radius to a circle is the same and
it doesn't matter what culture you come
from.
You see,
and so geometry is a critical means of
decipher the,
the knoWledge that and I think that the,
that the predominant way of preserving
ancient knowledge is in the temple
structures and they have to be looked at
as textbooks in stone and once we begin
to realize that,
then we can go.
It's like when you go to Egypt,
it's not just the hieroglyphs that's a
part of it,
but it's also the geometry and the
astronomy that's encoded there and we
can see the same astronomy at work,
whether we're looking in Egypt,
whether in geometry or whether we're
looking at megalithic structures in
ancient england or whether we're looking
at,
um,
mega a monumental earthworks up in the
Ohio valley or we're looking at this,
the mind you've been to teach an eatsa.
Right,
okay.
That whole complex there is laid out
according to principles of sacred
geometry and astronomy and it's exactly
the same principles underlying that is
we find in Egypt.
That will be our next conversation.
I'll be a great.
I can't wait.
Thank you so much.
Really appreciate it.
Randall carlson,
ladies and gentlemen,
you can follow him on twitter.
It's a sacred geo int for sacred
geometry,
uh,
international.
So yeah.
So sacred geo I n,
t on on twitter and sacred geometry
international.com
is the website.
Thank you so much man.
Really amazing and I can't wait to talk
to you again.
I'm going to
start going over your material on your
website and gear up to,
uh,
for our,
for our next conversation,
man.
Just a amazing,
amazing stuff.
Thanks to our sponsors.
Thanks to on it.com.
Go to o,
n n I t use the code word rogan and save
10 percent off any and all supplements.
And thanks also to naturebox the
official snack provider of the joe rogan
experience.
Go to naturebox.com
forward slash rogan to save 50 percent
off your first box.
That's naturebox.com
forward slash rogen.
We'll be back tomorrow with dr rhonda
patrick returns.
And until then go fuck yourselves.
how about that?
I don't mean it.
I love you.
Big con.