Or recording the Joe Rogan experience
podcast is brought to you by the
fleshlight.
If you go to Joe rogan.net
there's a little picture
little we'll fleshlight logo
and you click on that.
It takes it to the fleshlight website.
Enter in the code name, Rogan,
and you get 15% off. Oh,
here we go. So good freaks.
Neil Brennan is in the house.
We're ready to get the party started.
[inaudible]
and go. No, Brenda Wa
you film this too, right?
Yes. It's on Ustream
right now. Yeah, it goes,
you got your own camera over the
jail? Yes. There's a camera for you.
It was a camera can say if you want some
come. Thanks. I'm getting piece of this.
We've got to go crazy.
If I get behind the every now and then,
come on over a little. The
door's always open. Well,
we used to do it on the couch where used
to get a big view of all three of us at
once.
I saw that with Stan hope, I think,
or I saw it with somebody and it was,
it seemed seemed odd at Beth.
The couch is wicked. I'm comfortable. Just
wasn't good. It wasn't good for talking.
You think that accounts should be like
really comfortable with but nothing can
fuck with a good office chair. Yeah. I
think they got office chairs figured out.
You know you can get in this sucker and
you know it's, it supports your back.
Your arms have a good comfy place to rest.
It's way better to sit in
office chairs and couches.
Chairs now sponsored the show, correct
it. Should I wait a flashlight?
I think.
I think movie theaters or fee figuring
it out too now because they used to have
like really good comfortable chairs
where that you could have like the thing
that goes up when you put your drink
in then you can make it a couch.
The other day I went to a theater and
they had torn out all those chairs and
went back to the old style where you
can't move the, the, the armrest anymore.
And I was like wondering why and then
you think about it was a lot more
comfortable though.
Like the actual chair part.
So now I'm thinking they're just designing
what theater was that. My numbers.
So universal citywalk uh, they,
yeah, they're nice. That's probably,
they're dealing with too many douchebags
doing stupid things to those cup
holders.
And I think by douchebags you mean Mexico.
I was gonna say Mexicans,
but I'm glad you didn't stood
there is no more if you want,
if you're from out of town,
you'll like gear from Illinois and no,
we don't have a lot of
Mexicans out in Joliet.
This is what you need to do just
for a fucking goof. Take a trip,
come to Hollywood.
And the first thing I need you to do
is go to a movie at city walk on like a
Friday night. Yeah. And
there's two things going on.
There's the movie and then there's a
show where the young Mexican kids are
yelling out at the stage trying to make
each other laugh. Yeah. Which is funny.
It's ongoing. I mean, again, you're
prepared for it. Yeah. If you've,
I've heard people yell funny shit out.
I was with a girl once and she yelled out.
I've heard of people
yell funny shit out too,
but I was with a girl once and she yelled
out at these guys that were talking
while the movie was going on and she
didn't tell me she was going to do it
either. She just turned and, and this
was when I first moved to Hollywood too,
right?
I was fucking ultra paranoid.
I'd heard all these crazy things like
when you're driving down the street,
if you guys will drive with
their headlights off and
when you flash them to let
them know that there are headlights are
on. Well it's a gang initiation thing.
They have to find you and kill you.
That's cause I was out here then 93 yeah.
That's like where get like Nwa and
all that shit was hot and it was,
it was scary. It was, I mean, I don't
know if it was all all paranoia,
but it was like, it felt
different. There's a lot of posers,
there's a lot of people that were really
legit gangsters. Like I've read up,
there's a great book about the crips and
the bloods and history of gang banging
and La. It's a fascinating book.
I'm sorry, I forgot the title of it.
There was an HBO documentary too.
That was really good.
What it's means it's been going on since
forever, you know, I mean it's just,
it is the way it is.
But when rap music and Gangsta
rap got really popular,
that was when like the whole country
started to be aware of this and then as
people started acting like them,
you know, so anyway, the point is,
I'm in this movie theater, so I'm
with this girl, she's a nice girl.
She just misguided, you know,
excuse me, would you please shut up?
We're trying to watch this
movie. And I'm like, Oh fuck.
Was she got it for saying that or
for going out with any of that? Both.
Both clearly but clearly for going and
going into his hand and immediately.
Yeah, yeah. And then that automatically
you're responsible. Yeah. And I'm like,
I'm going to die. She had done a
couple of things like this before.
She would have like cut off
people and traffic and shit.
Like if someone got in front of her,
she would like speed up,
go into the oncoming lane
and cut them off. Yeah,
she was fucking crazy. And maybe it's
Chicago thing. She was from Chicago.
I like a year. Nice girl.
She was a nice girl.
Other than that it was weird cause most
of the time she was super friendly but
when she felt like anybody
was fucking with her,
she would get like really angry
and like go to a 10 like you said,
like right away, you know, and I
think they need at movie theaters, uh,
going back to that is that they needed,
I know that you're supposed to turn off
your cell phones during movies and stuff
like that,
but instead of if you see some guy
running the movie that the worst thing is
actually having to go out and find him.
Imagine being able to like text it or
going to text a projection is, hey,
just so you know,
it's fucking quiet in here.
Or we were encouraging texting and
complaining. I completely agree.
But it should be like only for
emergencies, you know, like, Nah,
you can't ensure that people
go to emergency, you know,
do use it only during emergencies.
When you give people the option to text,
I mean look,
look at fucking youtube comments.
That's what you're going to get in your
text. You got to get those same retards.
They're just
finally getting to the theater.
I have a, I don't care. People text
during the movie really don't care.
I care if they're near me.
Man.
It's like the blue light care of
him doing standup and cemetery.
It's like as long as they're not,
as long as it's not,
I'd way rather than texts
than talk. Yes, I agree.
Because I love to text so I get,
you know what I mean?
Like I enjoy it and I don't want to, I
certainly don't want an iPhone. Yeah,
I'm rocking and iPhone. Okay.
You don't fuck with droids
I fuck with a droid. Yeah.
I fuck with the
HTC evo four g.
How'd you log it?
They should be ashamed of themselves for
releasing a telephone with that crappy
battery ashamed of themselves.
It's like the fact that it
even went to market yet,
this iPhone is the best
anything I've ever had.
That's a problem with all
the four g's and androids.
All the four g's and an android phones
all have usually have the worst battery
life must because of the screen.
I would spend most of the day
managing the better. Yeah.
I had a droid for a day,
the droid to at the slide out keyboard
for one day and I brought it back to them.
I was like, you gotta be fucking
kidding me. It's a battery.
I've played with it for 20 minutes
for the full battery and it had half a
battery life and yeah, 20 minutes.
That's ridiculous. And they're like, oh,
you need to download. You
know man, come on man.
Fuck I do you guys need to
get your shit together. Yeah.
Why can't they figure
that shit out at all?
But outside of that figure out how to
shut people the fuck up and movies.
I mean, look, we can boot man now,
but try to get Mexicans is telling,
yelling out funny shit.
Keep Mexicans out of city.
Does the phone itself though
is pretty good, right? Hmm.
Other than the battery life
phone? No, the HTC evo. It's fine.
I was always nervous about it was like I
worked for the phone like look I got to
get, I should look it off cause I don't
want my phone to act crazy like this is,
it was fine. Yeah. I can hear you're
always worried about the battery life.
I'm still a little bit worried
about it and I haven't had too much.
That is a fucking terrible feeling.
Looking down in your shit says 10%
battery life left and like you're out.
Oh yeah.
I'm so [inaudible] right now.
It's going to try midnight and my
phone's going to turn it into a Turkey.
It was going to go with the
back to the future thing.
It's like my hands disappearing.
Was that when Marty McFly Yan would
disappear when he looked fine? Yeah.
It's like you have that picture when you
time traveling you always have to look
at and make sure you're not like
destroying. So you're an older guy.
Cinderella's more of a reference for
you. I have daughters, young guys.
Keep up with the hot movies
like back to the future,
which came out 26 years ago
that God does stand up biff from
back to the future. It does stand up.
I always see him at the comedy
store. Yeah. Real Nice Guy.
I've never seen him at the store see
there. I've seen him four times there.
What is his name? Uh
Fuck. I don't know. But
yes, there you go. He's real
nice and actually there was,
I know how many people hate this
but they had that, this class there,
you know that taught comedy to people
or stuff like that and he actually was
making an appearance to do like a speech
was the last time I saw him there.
Right. You were taking the class?
No, I was just out smoking. I see.
Were teaching the class.
I was just there hanging.
I don't have any problem with classes.
A lot of people do and they say that
the people that are teaching the classes
are losers and that's why the
teaching the, and they have nothing
really to teach. I think anything
that lets people just try it and it,
and some people like some sort of a
structure and that is a structure.
The structure of a classroom,
you know, you're curious.
You know you have a job you
don't like God man to try open.
Mike night is calling class. I'll just
sign up for that. And that's a step.
I think it
and we'll get hot. Like everyone
that comes out of it's awful. Yeah.
It's not like they're, they're good
comedians that have come out of it. Sure.
I don't, I can't remember
any of them, but like,
here's what I'll say that are the,
have the top 20 comedians of
all time gone to a comedy class?
No. Yeah. It's not necessary. No,
but it's not, you know, it's a start.
It's a start. It's any sort of,
it's any sort of a jumpstart.
There's something about comedy,
man, this is a very daunting,
the idea of getting up for the first time
with owning your own words and no one
helping you. Some people like, hold my
hand, hold my hand, get me on the stage.
You know, that's all they
need. They need, so it'll help.
Yeah.
So go ahead and anyhow,
that were sponsored by Neil
Brennan and Joe Rogan's comedy.
We're going to start one up
next week. You, you started
comedy later in your life.
Are you,
did you grab onto it quickly or were you
always in this scene and she was always
in, that's how I know. I've known a
old man Rogan hair for a ninth, 18,
19 years. Wow. Yeah, he's still work.
I work the door at the Boston
Comedy Club, uh, for Barry Katz.
I made $235 a week. Uh,
which did Barry take a cut?
I'm sorry man.
I don't know what welcome to
show business. That's a good one.
That's a really good one. Uh, so, uh,
so yeah, so I was always just around it,
but I was,
I don't think that I,
I was more like shy and retiring
and like, ah, you guys, go ahead.
I kid and I could never,
and I also,
I also judge my own desire
for attention and be like,
what a low impulse to want attention
from strangers. And then, you know,
and then at a certain point it was like,
I don't want attention from strangers,
but also I was sick of other parts of
show business telling me that I wasn't
funny when I was positive. I was, um, we,
if I'd write a script and
they'd be like, Eh, okay.
And then you'd go do standup person.
We had this exact same tone
of the conversation with
Brian Post saying yesterday
we were talking about writing and the
idea of delivering stuff to people that
aren't funny and they get to judge you
on whether or not it's funny and how hard
it is to make a fucking
TV show. It's, it's,
it's unbelievably hard to get past
all these people that, uh, have a say.
Yeah.
Well Post saying,
I thought post saying we both did
two days on the Oscars this year.
Yeah. The Oscar telecast
and uh, cause Jordan Ruben,
who's a funny dude and I've known
him forever, it was like, Hey,
will you come Judd sort of supervising.
So I was like, all right, Judd Apatow.
It was like getting judge good,
greatest due like two days.
We impose saying they,
we pitched stuff,
they use none of it.
And then I saw Judd like a
week later I was like, Hey,
are you doing anything with that?
Oscar's saying he's like, I don't know,
they send me shit but I don't know.
So it was like, oh okay. It's just,
they use Judd to like
get you in and then you,
and then it ended up being an atrocity.
The funniest part was I was
just shitting on and on Twitter,
just going off on it like and
do like being really funny.
And then it, the telecast ends and it's
like written by Neil Brown. I was like,
oh wait, did I just see Neil Brennan,
other guys?
It was a different time.
Did you have to almost a year ago, did
you have to write the fake conversation?
So we just try to come up completely.
Most of them aren't pattern.
Like I'm here, we're here
to like the the, the guy.
Well I should say literally,
I've never watched an award show ever.
I've been in the real man.
I've been in like the spike award
shows a couple of those. Right.
I've never watched one.
That's great.
I uh,
I almost didn't do the Oscar saying
cause I hate award show so much cause I
think they're awful. Yeah,
exactly. They're just,
they just make everyone that's
not their feel like shit.
And they encourage losers too.
Like you can dream and you can be here.
No you can't,
unless you have crazy talent,
you can't
be there. I don't have any
problem with that aspect of it.
My problem with it is first of all,
the idea of judging art is ridiculous
because it's so subjective and it's so
inside.
And what you get is you get the,
the people that judge it have so much
influence over what gets released.
Cause there's people that target
those people with their work. Yes.
Because they know that these type
of movies get this tied bubble.
That's what's funny is happening,
having
cast a movie and, and Ben is, and
it drives me crazy. And I even said,
you know what's crazy?
I see it in podcasts as well.
People will cast who like in movies,
they'll caste the person
from the hot TV show.
So if there's a movie they're like, you
know, we should get a guy from the wire.
And it's like, oh, what a
great idea. How do you think,
I remember when I was pitching,
when you pitch to direct a movie,
I directed a movie for paramount called
the goods. That pivot was in Calin.
I love it. Thank you very much. It's funny
people didn't see it, but um, and uh,
so I remember I was pitch when
you pitch to direct the movie,
you have to go like some casting ideas
and for one of the casting ideas I was
like, you know, it'd be great in this
part is Warren Beatty. And they're like,
that's a great idea. How did you
think of that? And it's like,
I watched the movies and I
saw Warren Beatty like that.
But that's an idea. You
know what I mean? It's like,
it's a fucking sheet of paper and
it's like he's good, he's not good.
But the idea that they,
they go like,
we got to get the guy from the wire or
we got to get the guy from the office,
like everyone from the office.
Then they're the only people
in comedy with value is like,
cause they're the critically
acclaimed show. Uh, that,
and then people can't even see where
they're like, oh, Tina's a great, Tina's.
Tina is really funny.
But they're like,
Tina's amazing all that pail and stuff
that she wrote. She didn't write it.
Seth wrote it. Seth Myers wrote it
like, but the idea that you can't, uh,
it just becomes like, did you,
if someone said to me today,
did you see what trace at what Tina
said about Tracy? Yeah, it was fine.
Like condemning Tracy,
but these people just get such a markup,
uh, which you've probably
never gotten. I would get a,
during Chappelle show was like,
what's next?
W what do you mean by a markup? You get
like, you get upgraded automatically.
Like everything, my ideas are
better because of, because of that,
just automatically. Yes, I agree with you.
I agree with you about like the office
and every Steve Carell movie has to be
brilliant and he's always hilarious.
That's why I like no name actors. Like,
remember when we first saw
it, what 300? Like, like all
these actors are like, yeah,
yeah. Like brand new to you. I hate
that dude. No. Yeah, I know, but still,
it's the fuck out of me now. I'm sure
he's a great guy. I don't hate them.
I'm just saying every time I see him
at some fucking stupid Jennifer Aniston
movie he did goofy smack
of is les is his lips.
How fucked up here Elliot to from
Super Eight, uh, he's brand new kid.
Never been been in a movie already.
Can tell that kid is going to be in
movies now and there's like a bunch of
actors do man. Well. Yeah,
it's funny like what they,
you do good work or personal
work and then they'll go, um,
like I always used to say to Chappelle
and most def after we do a sketch,
I'd be like, fellas,
it was a great sketch.
Hollywood called and they
want you to play cops. Like,
like Hollywood calls and then you're
fucking upgraded into some shit.
You didn't want the first place,
but you're so award shows and shit
like he and entertainment tonight,
it's good for your career. You should
do it, but it, yeah, but it, it,
it trains you to,
it brainwashes you into thinking like
that Hollywood is valuable and you just
fucking walk like a Zombie toward dollars
and get like, where do I stand here?
We'll then Hollywood pussy. And that's
when, that's when the game changes.
That's when it does become valuable.
You know,
when you go into a club and everybody
goes fucking, you ever seen chocolate,
Dell and the club? Yeah. I like kind of
months ago I saw, I've seen chocolate,
Dylan, the club you when you see
that level of fame, you know,
and you'll talk with Delta MMA fighter.
That's what's funny is I
would mean nothing to me.
Like you're not a young horse.
It could be chocolate dough.
Are you tracking with that? Yes.
Uh, do young horse go crazy?
Cause I wouldn't even think
girls would know an MMA guy.
Delirious MMA loop. I
know you're, you're the
exact opposite but I'm not,
I'm not for it against it.
I just am out of it.
Huge percentage of girls know who those
guys are. Huge. It's a big percentage.
You're also in that road also and like,
like my girlfriend doesn't know who any
of these people are in either did the
prior or the prior.
Like none of them did.
Like he ha there a point
and those are the girls that
are willing to fuck you. I mean the
level of broad, we're talking about it.
I mean the real trash, there's not
many girls that Lashi and tired. Easy.
The human flashlights. Go ahead.
There's definitely a huge, huge,
a bigger percentage of
male. Yeah, for sure. Yeah.
My point is the reason why these guys,
once they get into movies and they get
big and then they start going to clubs
and it's just fucking calling the winner
circle where it's just like everyone's
during the winter, like
literally you, I it's like, it's,
remember the Eddie Murphy sketch where
they're like silly negro when he dresses
up like a white guy and uh,
and he,
he like the world turns around and like
he gets a bank loan and all that, um,
immediately because he's white. Uh,
and, and the banker goes up a black,
he had just turned down a black guy
and he goes, silly Negro. Anyway,
how much money you need. We got to any
just starts throwing money at Eddie.
Why Daddy? That's what it's
like to like be successful.
They like the old rules don't apply.
I remember going to shows with
Chappelle and people and they,
and or pin and they, people literally
don't, they don't ask for tickets.
They don't, it's like you do
whatever you want, walk right in.
Do you can't, this is a legit,
it's fine. Yeah, come on.
You're good. You're good. Oh,
you're good. It's fascinating stuff. Uh,
Vegas, it's the craziest, well, yeah,
exactly. I've been to Vegas with him
and a couple of times and, and uh,
it really is like one time the best me
and pivot we were doing when we were
doing the goods.
Uh,
we went out for a fight for,
um,
I think it was Ricky Hatton
and a Floyd Mayweather,
which is a hilarious fight mostly because
all the Ricky Hatton fans like booed
the national anthem. It was like
hilarious. It's like movie funny,
like with like doing, filling this shit
where they're building the national land.
They brought like a kettle drum
and it was awesome. Uh, so we were,
we flew private, which is also
great. Um, and when you fly private,
you're like in a, it's basically
like going to a rental car place, uh,
where they don't really say like, you have
to line up and you just, they just got,
oh, what's your wind number? And
you go, SJ, whatever. They go, yeah,
the planes out there.
So they're like, yeah,
the plants out me and pivot or killing
time, just kind of fucking around.
And then we're like, we should go
into the plant. We get on the plane.
Sly Stallone has been waiting for us.
Yeah.
So that's Chalan it's been
waiting for us so that they can,
it was like the planet Hollywood jet a
and we ended up going flying to a fight
in Vegas. Hollywood has a jet, uh,
just because they were like
falling apart at one point in time.
This was before they, I don't know. I, and
maybe they just charged out of casinos.
Flies. Jet? Yeah. I don't know. Oh
yeah. No, it was to go to the casino.
So the casino is sending you guys out for
what? For an event or sending? It was,
it was getting sly and then
they were like, and get pivot.
Was there an event or something?
It was the fight. Oh, the fight.
So they were flying you in
for the fight? Uh, yeah.
I guess there were
flying sly in and then we
hopped a Rut. So I get upset at you now.
He was. He was, he was real cool about it.
He's a funny dude. I met him once. Very
nice to talk to him. That's funny. Yeah,
he's very good. He, the thing,
the great thing about him is he
understands who he is to people.
He doesn't, I mean he'll go like, hey,
I'm a rocky. Yeah. Instead of like, hey,
that was a long time ago and like he
understands like he knows what anecdotes
people want to hear and shit.
Like he seems very genuinely friendly too.
Yes and happy. Yeah. Fun. Yeah.
A really enjoyable guy to look up.
You're going to fly in a private jet
deal with slide 64 and fucking shredded
cocoa butter.
Does he smell like cocoa butter?
It seems like it would smell like
a cocoa butter because Kendra car,
he doesn't not smell like cocoa butter.
All right. I wouldn't rule it out.
The bouquet,
he's what I call our
canary in a coal mine.
We'd never seen a 64 year
old looked like that before.
Yeah. Who knows how like his
face looks like meat art,
like strips of meat,
combine like bacon forehead.
And like,
that's a great way to put it. It really
is like his nose was made of like mutton.
Well,
there's certainly something
then going on with his forehead. There's
been times when it was shiny and mobile,
which always disturbs the fuck out of
me when I see is that guy you think that
takes g h a botox?
Right? Okay. Yeah. Uh, surgery and Botox.
What do you into these days?
What's your
okay, my cocktail. Yeah. I go to,
I've described it on the podcast,
but so in brevity,
I go to a hormone replacement therapist
and what they do is they look at your
hormone levels and they,
first of all,
they give you vitamins and adjust
your nutrition. That's the first step.
How often do you go?
Every couple of months I get blood work
done and then go and have all my stuff
checked. And once you will, they adjust
it as much as they can with nutrition,
which can make a huge difference. Uh,
especially, uh, eating shitty food.
You'd be amazed at how much
that lowers your testosterone,
lowers your human growth hormone. Yeah.
You shitty died. I'm V incredibly bad.
Are you? Yeah. And then, um,
once he adjusts you enough with nutrients,
then they give you a very small levels
of human growth hormone and testosterone.
Thyroid, I have hypothyroidism. So it was
taking thyroid medication before this.
And all it does is it basically brings
your home levels up to a healthy man of
like 25 to 30 years old. And
as you get older, you know,
your body just stops producing hormones.
It's a, it's really simple. It's,
and it's preparing you
for death basically.
And you can either choose to accept that
and just let your body slowly kind of
deteriorate.
Or you can replace the hormone.
I honestly want to do that. It's
a, sorry, can I see it as like a,
it's, it's a, it's a health move. It
affects so many aspects of your life.
Any side of it. I have there been any
side effects? Weakens your bones? No, no,
no.
You were so with what
I heard, he's so good. Was it that or is
it that or lip something with the liver?
It's one of the two. No, no, no, no,
no. It was steroids can give you liver,
but those are oral down. This
stuff is oral, oral. This,
the deliver stuff is the stuff that
your liver has to process cause you're
eating it for the most part. One of
the side effects is having a podcast.
Go ahead. Yes, that's number one. Well
if you, the side effects come from abuse.
The side effects of all performance
enhancing drugs come from abuse.
If steroids and performance enhancing
drugs were as dangerous as they said,
people would be dropping in the
fucking streets. Right. You know,
where are the bodies when you hear
about these pro wrestlers dying,
it's not steroids that are killing them
and these guys were on massive doses of
steroids. It's pills for the most part,
unless it's suicide and a lot of them,
they're dealing with concussions and all
sorts of other stuff and a lot of them
get very depressed.
But the abuse is what's really dangerous.
As long as you're going to a doctor and
as long as you're eating really healthy
and monitoring your nutrients,
you got to,
you got to give your body the tools
to repair itself. It's so important.
So many people don't eat any fucking
vegetables. They don't eat shit.
And this is why Brock Lesnar,
who was the UFC heavyweight champion,
he had diverticulitis
because of his bad diet.
He had a diet where he would only eat
meat, he would eat steaks. Diverticulitis.
Diverticulitis is it's,
you have basically a protein gets stuck
in your gut and it starts creating
abscesses and it can, you know, eat
a hole through your fucking stomach.
And with him,
it got so bad that he almost
died get hospitalized.
They thought they were going to have
to give him surgery on it and then they
decided that they didn't.
But then because of all his training,
when he's training, it starts to flare
up again because once you have it,
apparently it can recur. So they had to
remove 12 inches of his fucking colon,
oof, 12 inches of his colon. This is
all diet related. You know his case,
they used it for Stallone's face.
I knew you were going there a call back,
but this guy's diet was so,
it's fucked them up so bad.
And some people are absolutely correct
that it's not always diet related.
Doing so when he pointed this out that
you can, it can be a congenital thing,
but it wasn't in his case.
In his case it was,
and he didn't eat any fucking vegetables.
He didn't eat broccoli.
You didn't need any fiber. You've got to
clean your system out. So for me, it's it,
it does, first of all, it
helps your immune system. It
keeps you from getting sick.
It helps you recover from things you know,
and when you're doing it correctly and
properly with the right nutrients and
very low levels,
everything has a very low level.
You can't get crazy with anything
when you're doing it. It helps you.
You feel better, you have more energy,
you feel like you enjoy life more,
you're happier. You know,
it's, it's so simple.
It's like the reason why people are old
and cranky as cause they're tired as
fuck. Okay. Their bodies stop
producing hormones and that's not good.
It may hate at all.
Ethnic groups is the first thing that
happens. Sure. You get cranky, you can't,
you just use that new, but it's
people's dead or something. Know what,
like it just seems mover, right? No,
but there is negative side
effects to it. Right? Well look,
there's not enough people doing it
for them to have real studies. Right.
Are you constantly
monitoring all this?
Because that is pretty hard.
Quarterly I would be like on
Twitter every day. Like, look,
people have been substituting
hormones forever.
I mean thyroid medication has been
around forever and people have been doing
that forever.
This is not that much difference between
substituting your thyroid hormones are
substituting pituitary hormone gland.
You know what I'm doing is that deer
antler spray, you know that that helps.
Supposedly spray can put supposedly
pumps up your HGH levels.
Uh, I, and I find that if I just jog or
even a couple of miles, you can get it.
You can order it online is,
it was, it tastes light a,
it tastes kind of delicious.
It doesn't taste bad.
It's because there's some
controversy whether or not it works.
A lot of football players use it,
but some people do believe that it
does work maybe in small levels.
But that's been actually I just find
like when I exercise they can recover
quicker. Really? Yeah. You really
feel a difference that much.
It's funny cause I stopped doing
it for awhile and then I was like,
why am I sore?
And it was because I,
I mean I at least empirically
that was the, it's you know,
it's right now it's at a stage where it's,
there's a lot of experimental shit going
on with hormone replacement therapy.
I mean obviously it wasn't around for
our parents is this generation is the
first generation. It's sort of
experimenting with things like that.
You and I are really at the avant garde
of that. They were on the edge, bro.
Gotti canaries in the room.
I said, what do you,
what do you, how do you,
what does it do to you physically
doing that? You feel much better.
You feel healthy, you
recover better. I mean,
I've always been a guy who exercise
and I've always been in shape,
so I never really let myself get to a
position where I ever got frail or got out
of shape.
I should have adjusted along the way as
I realized that I was getting older and
then I wasn't recovering as fast as
I was starting to get injured more.
Then I started looking into it and
so for the past like five, six years,
I've been doing it. Great,
and you do it. Like I said,
as long as you're doing it with low
levels and you're sitting margins on it.
Yeah. It doesn't sound cheap. Less
expensive. No, not really. No.
As it scales out, it's not. I mean,
you can get some fucking shit
from China that's not as,
I wouldn't fuck around with that shit.
That's what it was.
My point was that what is basically
is this low level genetic engineering.
It's just the tip of it and what we're
going to see over the next decade is some
shit that's going to blow this completely
the fuck out of one worst fear with
this stuff. With, with taking this look
your worst fear period, his death. Um,
you know,
but yeah,
I believe that if you're taking care
of yourself and you're watching your,
your blood levels and you're
reasonably safe, you know,
as long as you're doing it with
a good doctor and you know what,
what the risks are and you know what
the levels that you're taking on and you
don't get crazy,
that's a lot of people get crazy.
And this is some things when you
see like a guy who's a bodybuilder,
you see like some big giant
guy was giant muscles.
There's only one way to get those fucking
muscles. Okay. I mean, hard work. Yeah.
You've got to take monstrous levels of
shit where you get to put your body into
a state that's completely unnatural
and that's when things start firing.
It's like having a computer
and overclocking and hey man,
I got a seller on 301 clock,
this bitch up to four 75. I got these
coolers. Yeah. How long does that last?
Those fucking things. They'd
go out, you know, it blows
out. And that's exactly the,
like the human body. But if you're a
smart and just keep it within levels,
you know, long as you keep
it within healthy levels,
nothing hyper, nothing crazy.
It was a lot of science behind it.
There's a lot of studies behind it
that show and there's a lot of really
intelligent doctors that do do it to
themselves and one of them happens to be a
very good friend of mine who, uh, has
been in this business for a while and he,
you know,
he's very,
very well versed on all the pros and
cons of hormone replacement therapy.
And in his point is always the
best. He's like, he's like, okay,
here's what's going to happen. If you
don't take it, you're going to get old.
You're going to die. He goes, you're
probably going to die if you take it too.
But you're going to enjoy that time more.
You're going enjoy that time where
you're gonna enjoy your body more. Yeah.
I enjoy my body too. You really,
I'm really and turn the lights down.
I got a huge kick out
of my own human body.
What's your take on his wiener character
pulling his cock out and taking
pictures. Here it is. Uh, don't,
if you're a guy,
don't take a picture of your cock.
Nobody because a girl doesn't
really want to see it.
Girls want to see like,
maybe they might want
to see your ass like,
but more than anything they want to see
like girls need their aesthetics that
they need like lighting and fucking
shadow. You know what girls want to say.
They want to see that, that muscle. Sure.
You know the name of the
muscle where it like,
it looks like your lower abdominal
area heading in your cock.
The ramp,
the ramp,
the garage door and give him the ramp
abs. Uh, they want abs. I want Rep.
They don't want caulk. All right.
So that I would say, don't do it.
Don't ever just be like, oh, sorry
baby, I got to go to sleep or whatever.
A friend of mine, Jack, go ahead.
Sorry.
I have to interrupt because a friend of
mine is married and he's a great guy and
he doesn't cheat on his wife.
He's a comic. And, um, uh,
this girl send them an email,
oh, you're so hilarious.
Blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
I will, I would love to take you for
a ride, you know, lol. And so he,
uh, emails back like, Hey, um,
uh, that's very nice, but a,
I'm married, thanks. And so then
she starts saying, oh, well,
I totally understand and I think that's
really awesome and you're married and
you know, and I, I totally,
completely respect that. And then, uh,
well you're hilarious. Anyway, send.
So then an email comes a minute later
and it's her and her lingerie, lol.
I totally fucked up and sent you this.
Oh my God,
I'm so sorry this sending this.
So then he sends it back.
Well, no, no harm done.
Then she sends him pictures of her
fingers, health. So then it's like,
and then she's like, come on, I
want to see your big fat cock.
Send me a picture of big fat cock at
this point. I'm like, that's it, dude.
Okay. That's a fucking dude. There's
a dude who's trying to do that.
You're getting trolled.
You just went Boston and a fucking dude
fucking queer.
He's got his cock in his hand.
The probably a bit and the other dude,
I will like you. You Go,
you're getting trolled son.
There's a guy who's trying to get a
photo of this comedian's Dick for sure
going on here. That's why 90%
of the time I send fake photos.
That's what I was going to say. I,
I what I, what you do with fellows,
if you're really have to take a
picture of go get a play girl,
take a picture of a cock in the playgirl,
send it. And then with the caption,
mine is similar to this.
Send her the blackest one you can
design and say picture one liked this,
but white and maybe not quite as,
not quite as big,
not quite as bad with better credit folks
did. It will be quiet in a movie. My
Cock. We'll be quiet in a movie theater.
So did you,
you didn't enjoy the half movie?
Didn't I did enjoy it. Uh,
not really. Cause you know,
where'd you get this segue?
We, well I wanted to bring that up. It's
one of my favorite movies. He didn't,
he didn't even enjoy it. I didn't hear if
you should direct it. What did you know?
I didn't Roni and Chappelle, Rhoda
and um, uh, yeah, it was just,
we were both like young and we didn't
really understand like we should have
rewritten it more. We kind got way
late in term, the whole process.
We just got way late.
Like here's who is going to be in it.
Here's your starting
now here's the director.
And we didn't know till we didn't know
what to stand in time move like we didn't
know like to say what
fight to fight and uh,
and so it just ended up being,
there's parts of it I like,
but for the most part it just sort of
like didn't end up the way I'd hoped her
day. David hoped. I think. And maybe
you might not have got what you wanted,
but what you got was awesome.
Oh yeah, totally. Yeah. Yeah.
I mean people, I mean it got
demolished at the box office,
but having said that, we
opened against titanic. Yeah.
We opened against types Hanoch
golden eye and goodwill hunting.
Wow. Holy Shit. Haneke titanic
three asked me this or
quite answered me this.
Who the fuck is still going to see
James Bond movies? Zero more suspense,
less boring fucking series of movies
where you have nothing invested in it.
I couldn't give a shit and this
new guy looks pretty bad ass
standard credit guy. You would like
the first or second new one with him?
I don't know. It's pretty bad. Do
you like the Bourne movies? No.
Yeah. One guy kicking everybody's
ass like that. I'm like, shut up.
Somebody grabbed that dude.
It's to me it's like someone playing
guitar and a movie and they don't really
know how to play guitar. Write.
That shit drives me crazy.
I have a very hard time watching a movie
where one guy is doing all this crazy
Kung Fu badass shit where I'm
like, stop it. Stop it. Stop it.
Which just drives me nuts. This guy
took on 10 people. No, they would.
They would grab him.
That's not how people fight.
They don't stand around you
like a retard wagon train. Yeah.
He fucking dive on you at once.
Somebody
grabs your legs,
they'd kick you in the fucking head
and then your unconscious and then they
raped them and kill you.
That's why you make short films.
You make very short action. Action
films are 15 minutes long. It's a guy,
he thinks he's a bad ass. They break in
the warehouse, they fucking hold him down.
They shoot him in the
face and that's the end.
And that's the end of the bureau credit.
And they just learn you've lost a
lot of money making these minutes.
They're real.
What people want is real.
She tell you what you today you'd
deliver them on the Internet.
Very cheap to film with the CGI
that's available on your Imac.
You could pull it off.
You're the Joe Rogan action film.
So I'm fucking serious, man.
Simple. I it was that move.
What does it final cut pro tools and
what you're talking about
is those like those, uh,
the dude who the punch out videos.
What's his name?
The black dude who tried
to Kimbo Kimbo videos? No,
not entirely. With maybe a giant.
Yeah. With like a soundtrack,
getting chased by a giant penis.
They Chase Kimbo and then he punched him.
I've never been one for trying to come
up with movie ideas, that very reason.
So that was your first movie.
You did that.
And then I wrote a couple of scripts
in between there that didn't get made,
and that was, I sold them,
but they didn't get made.
And then that was the period
where I was like, why am I,
it just was making me a little crazy.
That's when I started doing
standup a little bit. Um, the,
but I remember when people, if for an
idea of how stupid showbiz this is,
me and a buddy of mine used to,
we're pitching a movie in 99,
2000 and they were like, who do you
want to be in it? And we were like, oh,
Dave Chappelle welfare
on, they were like, uh,
how about Tom Green
and Orlando Jones slow?
And they were dead serious. That's that
like heat game that I was talking about.
It's like Rob Greene was hot firm and
as a comedy where you're like, yeah,
I think will Ferrel's way funny.
Even Tom Green,
like Tom Green's a stunt and they're
like, what are you talking about? Stunt.
They don't even understand what
they're looking at, but they just go,
there is a lot of commotion over
here. Right. We got to get it.
But they don't understand like,
yeah,
but to be that it takes some
other shit and then obviously, uh,
will and Dave proved to be the, the, um,
in the long, the long money was on them.
Oh, for sure. I think Tom Green,
if he's very misunderstood,
I think if you watch his, uh,
that movie Freddy got fingered.
I think that's a good fucking movie.
I haven't seen a rock.
Chris Rock loves that movie. I've
never seen. It's fucking hilarious.
It's hilarious and crazy and that
gross. That's really who he is. I mean,
he's just as Nutty, dude. I mean, I
know he's getting a bit of an anarchist,
so like you look at his show that show
that he did on fucking basic cable and
Canada and then look at his
show that he did on MTV.
I think he's fucking hilarious. He's
a, yeah, no, he is absolutely fine.
Not Utilized correctly, which is
why he decided to do his own thing,
that web show. But the web showed to me
sort of became like the tonight show.
Yeah.
He was trying to make it into something
that was like really like he should just
try not to swear. And you know, at one
point, and he was, he's Carson in. Yeah.
It was like, it was going,
it was just a different mode.
Scaling shut down would have been the way
to go. But he, he tried to keep it like,
hey, big production. It's like, dude, it's
the tried to do it. Like everybody else,
there was a desk in a tie
or a suit rather, you know,
it was like the whole thing was set up
like imitating all these ones that were
under the confines of broadcast television
and other people's opinions and input.
And now here you have this thing
where you have no confines.
No one's telling you what to do.
You can do whatever the fuck you want.
You're just going to imitate whatever
all these old schools Steve Allen guys
have done before. You can seem silly
to me. Uh, it seems silly to a lot of,
it's not what he is. You know what he
is? That's funny is Freddy got fingered.
It's fucking a dead Moose on the
side of the highway. You know?
Remember they got stand up now. I haven't
seen it, but it's pretty good. I heard,
I heard he's doing well. He's
doing well. You know, and it's,
it's always interesting when someone,
so 39 years old or whatever the fuck
they are when we tried to do stand up for
the first time.
It's kind of weird when you,
and you're already famous
like Charlie Murphy. I've,
I went on that big maxim tour with
Charlie. Mark did. Really? Yeah. Yeah.
We meet him and John Heffron toward the
country. We did like 22 gigs together,
theaters and shit.
And you know,
Charlie fucking was 40 something years
old before he ever did standup comedy.
And he was famous as fuck before and
offered his hand one of the best up,
some hostile of all time. Huge movie
star. I mean his little brother pressure.
Yeah. The pressure on him, his fucking
tremendous. And through the roof.
And all of a sudden this guy goes from
being on this TV show to a year into
standup comedy. Not even, I think
nine months. He's headlining,
headlining and doing theaters.
These got to do 50 minutes. Yeah.
It's fucking crazy. Yeah. Yeah.
Ridiculous. Really hard to, it's hard.
It's the worst way to do whatever.
It's like what I always said about Brock
Lesnar fighting in the UFC. You know,
when Brooklyn's their first
started fighting the UFC,
he went immediately and fought the former
champion and his first fight that he's
fighting heath herring. He's fine. He's
fighting nothing but killers right away.
And I'm like, you know,
yeah, he can do that.
But you know what's the best way to do it?
The best way to do it is to come up
through the fucking ranks of the smaller
shows. Get less money.
That's what I, when I was,
when I started doing standup again,
like people were like,
you should go out and did it.
And I was like,
I don't have the time and I don't
want to rip people off. Good for you.
Now I've got the time and
you're ready to rip people off.
You can really rip some bump people off.
I need money.
Yeah, no, I, I need this so bad. So you
weren't doing standup when you were,
uh, one of the, when you were the
producer of the Chappelle show,
you weren't doing standup then job's
the creator and Co Creator and writer,
whatever you were the grand poobah
of the Chappelle show. Grand Poobah,
the Cro Grand Poobah you weren't
doing comedy at that time? Mm.
A little by little. I mean, you
can when you have a TV show,
because I didn't know of you as a
comic. No, I know one, no one did.
The people are barely
starting to get on board now.
I remember when I did it,
the first time I did it was that we
were just walking down the street.
We ran into Dave, he had a
mustache on. He's like, hey Joe,
you want to be on my TV show? The
show wasn't even, didn't even exist.
And bobcat Goldthwait was with direct.
And then it's like, what am I going to go?
I only have like a half an hour.
He's like, okay, just hold this box.
And we went out and
wandered around and uh,
he gave me boobs. Yeah, we had
this ridiculous fucking donkey.
Kong was totally forgot you were in.
And then the second time I did it,
I did it with you was when we did the
fear factor. I was actually at the,
at the bath. The one your
boobs on the bobcat one. Yeah.
I didn't remember seeing you
though. But I remember. But anyway,
my point was that I just knew
you as Neil, you know, I didn't,
I didn't really know what your
Gig in life was. You know?
I knew that you worked at the
Boston comedy club and yeah,
and I would also like to note that you
are always a really good dude when you
didn't,
when I didn't have credits,
you were almost exactly, you are exactly
like you are like, you weren't like,
you're not, you're not one of
these like you come on in. Oh God,
you're not a star fucker.
You're not, uh, uh,
credit fucker unless it's struggle very
hard to be the exact opposite. Well, no,
but I,
that's what's,
I think that's where you live is a
testament to that in this shithole.
No law. No. He just lived in the
middle of nowhere. And by the way,
I'm too close to people if I
could. I mean, I lived in, uh,
talked about this yesterday.
I lived in the mountains of Colorado
for four months. Did you not swear?
I wanted to live last year till my dog
got eaten by a mountain lion and my wife
got pregnant and because my wife
was pregnant by the mountain lions,
the altos fee, it was a crazy
week for the mass crimes trees.
I'm in denial. It was Joe's worst
week, the mountain lions, best week I,
but my instinct is
still live in the woods.
I mean that's where I really would like
to live as far away from. So I mean,
I'm not much on Hollywood than a,
an opportunity to make money.
Yeah. And I'm sure you liked doing
stand up. I love doing standing. Yeah.
But I love doing standup
because it's not Hollywood man.
When I was in Vancouver this
weekend, that's, I'm in Vancouver,
you know what I'm saying?
There's nothing Hollywood about that.
It was just me and a bunch of cool people
in Vancouver and we're having a party
and you know, I'm telling
jokes and everyone's laughing
and it's great time. Oh,
you did a show where you did
the stand up and then I did, uh,
well I did two nights of stand up.
I did one at the vogue tier.
It was fucking awesome.
First Time I've ever done it encore
and never did an encore before.
I went back out on stage. And then Ben
is that she's told a lot of jokes to do,
well not stolen claim their mind call
or something I served George Carlin do
once. I don't, I, I let people
know. So I did, I did, uh,
that and then the next
night I did the comedy mix,
which was used to be Yuk
yuks which is the shit.
It's Vancouver is a fucking amazing.
I was up there for a while. One time,
and I'm going to go back cause I'm
starting to do now that I'm starting to go
out and rip people off. Uh, none
of the club, first of all, what
the clubs pay is a slave wage.
Like what comedy clubs pay to have someone
come in for the weekend is like what?
Well, if you haven't been there, this,
the only reason is it's what it is, is if
you don't draw, this is the bottom line.
It's if you're just coming
in for the weekend though,
the reality is that most clubs have a
very hard time selling tickets for an
unknown comics. So would they have to
do is they have to pay for the room.
So they have to give away.
So they can't afford to give the
comic that much money. No, I get that.
But they could, they can certainly afford
to give them more than they're given.
I don't know. I'm telling you man, it's
hard out there. It's hard out there.
And you know comics need to realize that
look with social networking and Twitter
and Facebook and all that shit,
you can eventually build up your
audience where you can ensure that hey,
I can ensure you that you're not going
to have to give away any tickets.
You're going to sell this place out.
And people have done that without even,
you know,
any television credits at all.
There's a bunch of guys who are doing
really well just on the Internet,
but you got to work at it. You can't
expect a club to just pick up the tab.
So when
back to anyone but,
but it's first of all there's plenty of
clubs just won't headline me cause cause
I haven't done enough TV. I don't
know why. They don't know yet.
They would on a week
night. Yeah. No. So well,
what I'm doing is do what
I'm doing like music, venue,
shit like that and getting
most of the door. Yeah. And,
and I have like 63,000
followers on Twitter,
which isn't a lot
grants to you. 64 by the end
of the day. How about that? No,
actually you'll learn an in,
you ain't tweeted,
well that's the name of the game is
getting celebrities to tweet you.
And I know a lot of celebrities.
Ooh,
I know what if you retweet me,
that
goes up.
Um,
so I'm hoping that the people
that follow me on Twitter, we'll,
you know,
get into the spirit of like this kind of,
we're doing it off the grid and
which is what I like about this.
I think they do too.
And people will do stuff for free,
which I think is a really cool,
like people will just, I'll like,
I'll say like, hey, can someone make a
picture of blog of this, of like, oh,
a Barack Obama with like a
teardrop tattoo after the,
after they've been long thing
and someone made it. This girl,
Rachel made it like in 20 minutes and a
buddy of mine works in the White House,
was writer for Obama who I met at the
correspondence dinner and he goes,
I showed it to everyone in the White
House. I go, I go, how high up did again?
And he goes, not as high as you
want it to, but it got a pretty wide
and the show to Obama I
know would appreciate it.
Yeah. Obama's only 47 years.
You don't think you would
have been? Oh Shit. No,
he would have thought it was funny. Oh
Shit. Oh, shut up. Let me ask you this.
Do you think that they really killed
those bin been logged and dumped his body
in the ocean?
Uh, the dumping, the body
thing, I had a funny,
the way they handled it was like
the classic media manipulation.
The thing that got me was the
thing to where they go, you know,
he used a woman as a human shield. That
was the first thing that they release.
So everyone goes that mother
fucker because America
didn't know how it going to
play her.
And at first
he was saying he was armed, he was
armed and it used a woman as a human.
Then they were like, wait a minute,
wait a minute. Like a carts says Trump.
The armed. Yeah, like a cartoon character.
He used a woman as a human shield and
you picture like a whore from Barney
Miller. Well it's apparently it was, it
wasn't him that used a woman as a shield.
There was someone else but, but originally
that's what they said and people,
they know that the first story is a story
people are going to remember. Right,
right. And then they go, oh by the way,
he didn't use a woman as a human scale.
I've been telling people in the audience,
it's like if I said to you like, Hey,
I'm going to introduce
you to my buddy Bobby.
He said hate rate took a shit today at
Mcdonald's and you think about that for
an hour and a half. And then I got
by the way, he didn't take a shit.
When you meet Bobby, you're still going
to be picturing him taking a shit.
And it's more to me,
I think like people being accused of rape,
but there's no way to unexcused
everyone who gets accused of it.
You have a black flag on you forever.
Absolutely.
For because of one person's
decision. But I, so I think, uh,
what I think the false part
of bin Laden was just the,
it was a Trump,
he was a trumped up God.
Like he like he was a one hit wonder
nine 11 was his big hit and then the rest
of the time it was,
they just used the threat of him as a,
an excuse to just get more
power to the government. Um,
there's a video on youtube called the
last word on Osama bin Ladin that is so
fucking enlightening as far as like
how intertwined his family was with uh,
oh yeah. With the Bush administration,
they built Mecca and all that. God,
you guys watch the video.
It's called the last word on Osama
bin Ladin and it is so fascinating.
It's about 15 minutes long and it goes
into depth about there their there,
the families were doing business together
forever and this guy gave them visas
to leave. They got them
out of the country, out of
the country. Wouldn't mind.
One was like al Qaeda was not the threat.
They claimed it was like since nine
11 out Kate is killed, I don't know,
300 civilians.
And my point was more people have
died at like six flags then that,
but yet there's like we got an in and it's
like, dude, they killed the, it's not,
there's way bigger risk and that I'm
off for like hunting them and, and,
and law enforcement.
The law enforcement part of it and the,
but the war part is like, it's,
there are a bunch of fucking,
there's more crips than there are
members of Alec. Well not only that,
they're on the other side of the planet
and there's no way of disconnecting them
and their history from the United
States and the CIA. There's not,
the mujahideen were being trained by
the United States government to fight
against the Soviet Union. I mean, that's
just a fact. The whole Jihad thing,
you know what Jihad used to be with the
original meaning of it in, you know,
the holy scriptures was, it was a
war against your own personal vices.
That was like a real jihad. What?
But we turned it into a war,
a holy war.
And we turned the,
the idea of suicide bombing
was introduced by America.
I mean it was our idea that we brought to
them, like you guys really got so much.
But, uh, there's a documentary
again on Youtube, um, called, uh,
the power of nightmares as a BBC thing.
Yeah.
A really good and it length like Christian
evangelicals with a extremist Islam
and, and how it was both born in
the 50s and sort of sprung out.
And I'm an eligible Hari who tried to,
he was part of the people that
killed Anwar Sadat and he got,
they have footage of him in [inaudible]
79 [inaudible] in the leader of
[inaudible] and he was in jail
talking to TV. Um, but, uh,
but yeah, I mean, yes. Is it an American?
Uh,
I don't think it's a American backed
issue. I think a lot of it had to do with,
with us just dumping Afghanistan
after the Russians left.
And I think that created a vacuum here.
It comes to talent,
but there's also,
you know,
they realize how things really work
once they start dealing with America.
I mean that's the,
the real cold hard situation of it.
What's really fascinating was there was
a recent video that was released from,
someone leaked it from a Pentagon hearing
where these guys are sitting around
and it's a,
a doctor and a scientist is explaining
about the potential for developing
vaccines to uh,
to attack certain areas of the brain
that are Cree or that are related to
religious fanaticism.
And they were showing like activity
and different sectors of the brain.
They can come up with this vaccine that
could literally attack those areas and
nullify these ridiculous
a religious fanatic ideas.
I believe in my lifetime
there will be a thing,
a part of a brand like you will be able
to set your brain to override negative
impulses. I think so. I mean,
like, I don't think it's
the Scientology is about it.
Is, is it? Well, yeah,
but I'm saying like you'll be able to do
it with a pill or some sort of implant
or something where it's like it will
override shitty impulse and then it'll be
the decision. Do I want
to override it? Okay,
well then this becomes what is shitty.
You know,
it's objective hordes of
barbarian taken over your land.
It's not shitty to hit somebody
in the head with an ax.
You know what it's like what you gotta do.
Yeah.
Well you'll have to go
through preferences. The,
my next door neighbor where I used
to live, it was a nice guy. And, uh,
he was a scientologist and I
found out about the wolf. No, no,
it was sort of a bit full.
No, it was in Calabasas.
It was a nice guy. But, uh,
he was talking to me about this piece
of property that it was looking to buy,
but he couldn't because
his wife was going clear.
And so I go with it. What does that,
what does that mean? And he goes, well,
we're Scientologists. And then he pauses
and looks at me, I'm like, Oh fuck,
you know? Okay, well I want to
be as accepting as possible.
He's a nice guy. Yeah.
I mean, look, my other neighbor was a
Mormon and they were, they were nice too.
I mean,
I had no problem with you and your wacky
religious ideas as long as you're a
good neighbor.
And also don't try to proselytize. I
don't do what ever you want, but don't,
absolutely. Don't try to sell me on. And
he never did and neither did the Mormon.
So they were all cool. Mormons are very,
they don't really, they're like Jews.
They don't want you to
join, you know? So, um,
so he starts telling me that his wife's
going to be clear and it's going to cost
$50,000. So I go $50,000. I
go, what does this entail?
He goes, well, you know, uh, basically the
work is already done. And what this is,
is sort of a confirmation
in the ceremony to, uh,
ensure that she is no longer affected
by negative energy and negative
influences.
And that what this does becoming clear
protects you from all negative influences
and stimulation.
And it's actually been proven that
ceremony and then big events and even the
donation of the large sum of money to,
you know,
accentuate some sort of a situation
like this can actually help the results.
So like this guy is weird pseudo
scientific way of looking at this fucking,
there's a really good article.
And then from the New Yorker,
like two and a half months ago about
Paul Haggis, who's a film director.
But there was a really long
piece about it cause he left.
They're going on holiday. Yeah.
They're going after him and it's,
it's really personal and it's one of
those New Yorker articles. It's just like,
whew, this is long. But it's so worth it.
And the recommend everyone read it. Yeah.
The thing is, it's like, you know, they
become the people to lower level people.
They become like soldiers and they act
out in the best interest of the church.
And it's not just about, you know, it's
like a gang. It's not just, I mean,
all churches are man and it's right.
Find that. Yeah. The, uh, any, any,
any group people, Steelers fans,
absolutely. They just go like, this
is for Roth Lisberger meanwhile,
Rosberg with what?
I would find that with Chappelle,
there'd be all these guys around him
like, Hey Dave, let me take care of this.
It's like he doesn't want it,
but if you're the person
who it's being done on the,
in the name of it's flattering.
It is flattering.
But it's also,
it's a weird tribal instinct that
goes back to the time where there was,
you know, 50 of us and we had to
stay alive and stay in a group.
We have these weird group
instincts, you know? Yeah, yeah.
That's,
I actually wrote a essay that I think
I'm going to post later on today about
please let us know and we'll tweet
it. I would love that. You guys,
what'd you do that for me? Um, about, uh,
about the thing with
Tracy Morgan saying that,
you know,
I'm all for like gay groups coming out
against them because it is technically
reprehensible. I got a couple of
thoughts. One of the thoughts is,
as Comedians were going to say,
we have to talk a lot,
we're going to say fucked up shit from
time to time. The same way Nike or,
or Levi's has an outlet
store for irregular shit.
We're going to say some irregular shit
every once in a while. It's not fucking,
it's just gonna.
It's like the Don Imus thing.
He has to talk 25 hours a week.
He's nappy headed hoes is the
only time that comes slipping out.
So my point with Tracy is, uh, I don't
mind giggers coming out against him.
Everybody else shut the fuck up because
every single person on earth has some
racism, sexism, some homophobia,
some classes have some, uh, uh,
uh, political, big, you know,
uh, prejudices and, uh, and,
and they think that by
coming out against Tracy,
it distanced themselves from them from,
from their own sort of darker impulses.
And it makes them seem like
they're really doing something.
Meanwhile, you're not doing shit.
It's not. It's like I said, you know,
all the people that,
uh,
all the media outlets that came
on came down on Michael Richards.
Are Black people better off today
because of the fucking hammer?
No, in fact, they're worse off.
So if you want to help black people
build a fucking school or a hospital and
shut the fuck up,
I don't think,
I think the Tracy Morgan
thing is different from the
Michael Richards thing for
two reasons.
One,
because I think Michael Richards was
talking to a group of people who are
heckling him and he was trying to
insult them in the most dehumanizing way
possible.
And he was on coke and he was trying
to be funny when he didn't deserve May.
Do you think he was not coping?
He's pretty sure. I don't know.
I'll prove me wrong.
Okay. Just prove God. Uh,
you know,
he was at the comedy store before and
by all accounts he was gacked out of his
mind. I don't know if it's true or not.
Maybe I'm a slandering him or whatever,
but, uh, I don't think he's going to go
after me for this. I think for this one,
he's going to leave it alone.
You don't think he wants to revisit
this may call you the n word.
At least you know he's willing to go.
That was less offensive. And I think when,
you know, if people want to, uh, get
on him about that fucking magic word,
that's ridiculous.
When black people say to each other
every fucking day of the week,
I think when I looked at it, I was like,
oh, well he shouldn't have done that.
And that wasn't funny. But my other,
my initial thought was, it's not,
he doesn't deserve to be on stage.
He shouldn't be on stage on a
fucking Friday night factory.
Troll yourself to not,
if you're under,
if there's a chance that
when you're getting heckled,
you're going to yell that out.
He's not, well, he's a
comedian. Yeah, exactly.
He's a famous guy and he's going to go
on after like Al Madrigal or you know,
someone of that nature who is not a name,
who's going to crush and you know,
Tom Segura and then you're good luck. Good
luck. Fall those guys. Yeah. And you're,
you're some fucking slap sticky guy.
If you ever seen what he does. No,
he used to go onstage and the
comedy store and he had no material.
He would just fall down. He would go on
stage. It's boy, he don't let fall down.
I can't believe this was happening to me.
I got a whole separate pair and he would
slip again and fallen. It's back in my,
this is my kind of comedy.
Go on. Fucking ridiculous.
I mean he would do it for like 1520
minutes, fall down all over the place.
I don't think what he said is anything.
I think what he said is just
him being weak. But it would,
Tracy Morgan said was like,
Whoa, like you want to,
if your son was gay you would stab that
little nigger. But I think that that's,
I think that what he's doing is just
trying to be funny and I think he's
probably ad libbing, which Tracy
does for like most of it's set now.
If you've ever seen
Tracy Morgan do stand up,
he'll start talking
about eating pussy man.
Well it seems that lived. It's generally
not ad Lib, but like I fuck a midget
and the mouth and like all that shit. So
the idea is I'm a bit sad. Yeah, fine.
Gay stabbing his son Shit was
part of that. First of all,
I'm sure that got a laugh and in the
abs up stabbing your son for any reason.
Is Bernie Mac called his nephew a faggot.
Where was the outrage called him a faggot.
Kings of comedy night,
2000 Sag. It didn't mean as much back
then. It has escalated over the last,
where are people going back and going
like, and you Bernie Mac. It's like, okay.
Again, I don't, if you want
to help gay people, uh,
give money to, to gay charities
and, and, and, and uh,
glad and going chastising Tracy isn't
helping gay people hardly at all.
It's helping them a little,
but it's the bare minimum,
absolute bare minimum. What people
think. It's not, people think people go,
it's better than nothing.
It's,
it's almost worse than nothing because
at least nothing knows it's nothing,
you know? Whereas this, it's like I'm,
I'm look at me, I'm chastising Tracy.
Right. I agree. What you're saying in
that when something like this happens,
the people that make a big deal about
it and talk about it and make press
conferences, those are all
concerns that that is just a fact.
That's a fact in almost every situation.
The people that are, you know,
a lot of comedians on Twitter
were coming out against it.
I never liked her and it was just like
silly few fucking pussies. It's just not,
it's not a good point.
It's not a well thought out point.
It seems like you're taking a safe route.
It doesn't take much.
Like it's not much of a thought exercise
to get where I got where it's like,
well wouldn't you know,
but to have an opinion about it.
I think it's an interesting
subject of debate.
I think to have an opinion about it.
I think there's going to be the non
comics opinion and there's going to be the
people that are,
you know,
sort of a bit more sympathetic because
you know they'd realize that comics a lot
of times you'll,
you don't know what the fuck you're
saying before you're saying it.
You're saying it on an impulse and
what you would say in front of me,
like if we were standing around,
if we were sitting in my
office and you and I said,
well what about if you had a gay son?
I need to like,
I'll stab that little nigger.
I would start laughing my fucking ass off.
Well that's the end of Tracy
Morgan was yes, there's two house.
And guess what if you said that in
front of a different crowd, you know,
one crowd would fucking laugh
hilariously, uh, 10 o'clock,
late night show and Cleveland,
you know, and well that only 50th
as comedians were supposed to have a
shorter distance between our impulses and
our words. That's why, that's part of what
comedy is. And then when it goes awry,
when there's an irregular common,
people are like, fuck this guy,
I'm going to fucking, it's like, Yo
man, you gotta let us be a little,
and I'm not saying I'm,
I'm like,
I'm trying to set myself up
to say something fucked up.
I just think if you're in the a
aggrieved group, if you're the,
if you're a, if, first of
all, if you're Tracy's son, I
would, I would boycott Tracy,
um, or suck a dick and take a picture
of it. Oh yeah. Look at that dad. Yeah.
You look, I've known Tracy, as long
as I've known you and Tracy dear,
really think Tracy Morgan's can stab
his son under any circumstances.
First of all,
do you think Tracy knows where his son is?
Actually,
I actually heard a lot of those jokes
were actually jokes that he's Hbo and
nobody gave a fuck. C'Mon. Nannette
Johnny Today on the podcast.
And he said, Oh yeah, I've heard
those jokes before. Really?
So He's been saying that shit for a while.
And then someone just had to stand
up and complain about it. Yeah. Huh.
That's people being terrible
writing Tracy. I said, uh, well no,
the thing that I said in my asset,
my unpublished definite is that, uh,
people think that B,
the,
I said the louder someone says I
don't have a racist bone in my body,
the less likely they are to have a black
or Latin friend cause I have a shit
load of black friends and I'm a racist.
And guess what?
My black friends have me as a friend and
they're fucking racists and your racist
and you're homophobic and you're sexist
and you're anti, you know what I mean?
Everybody's everything.
So one guy said something like
accidentally on a whim and everyone goes,
I am not okay, stop. This is not a
whim. This is, this is his material.
Okay, fine. This is completely done.
It's his material and now
what's a different story?
Well, you know, then someone,
he's talked to him and tell him that
shit's not funny because it's just,
it's just silly. You know, if you're, if
you're saying that every show funny, I've,
Tracy was saying some shit that wasn't
getting a laugh, he would stop saying it.
You sure I'm positive?
Sure wouldn't just try to rework positive.
He might rework it for like three nights.
You can't use the impulse thought
though, you know, if it's his material.
But even if it is material,
if it wasn't working,
he'd stopped doing it and things that
clearly did not work the night he did it.
So now he's going to set up and
everything I heard that was that he got in
trouble recently in New York for doing
something very similar and like it was
like an a day or so.
No one knew about it anymore,
but this one just happened to come out.
Right.
This whole act is about being this wild,
crazy fuck yeah,
we don't want you to that crazy but fuck
midgets in the blowhole or whatever the
fuck his job. Like he talks about
fucking a woman in her inner voice box.
It's like, but every, but again,
people are fine with that.
That's absolutely fine because the
voice box people, ironically enough,
don't have a voice stabbing. No one
people. So, but once you say stab me,
then it's like, hey, hey,
no, no one, no one there. You
can't talk about that. Yeah,
you can not,
you can make a joke about somehow
you can make that funny but,
but just the idea that that somehow again,
gay groups absolutely should,
should boycott him but,
but all these other for to
use your word cunts, uh, can,
can,
can eat a dick because it's like let them,
you don't,
first of all your rate every,
it's all these fucking white
lightning deal saying that.
Why didn't you say that everyone
is racist and everyone, it's tribal
racism.
I mean are you really racist or do you
just recognize the fact that some people
and some ethnic groups do fucked up shit
because you're aware of the news that
doesn't make you racist.
Pattern recognize and you make assumptions
based on a parents as human beings.
That's what you do.
I don't think that's racist,
which is to say these fucking white,
there's a reason why we
like to say for the record,
black people think.
I think sometimes,
I don't know if you have
a big black viewership,
but black people think that when they're
not around, white people are like,
so the niggers and did it,
the amount of times that I've
heard someone give a screed
the way Mel Gibson did,
I, I've never heard anything
like that. Like I've never,
white people are not like,
so, all right, they're gone. Now look,
can we talk about these darkies or,
and I've never heard any of
that. I've never have. Uh, so,
so I would like to the presumption he
did interesting Gibson, when he goes off,
it's still going off. Uh, I had, uh,
yeah, but so the idea that somehow,
uh,
it,
the white liberals would say that it
is racist to be presumptive to make any
prejudicial, uh, decisions.
Well, you know what, that's,
that's silliness because you
should analyze, you know,
a few,
if you know that 99% of all Chinese men
stab people and you see a Chinese guy,
you're like, fuck, ob is a 1% or,
right. But again, yes, but but
white liberals would say like how,
what this ridiculous. He asked the guy
and go, hey, you're not a stab, right?
Oh No, no, no, no. That's not racist. Yes,
everyone will admit to this,
but you can't say it in any kind of
public forum and I think that there is
obviously a difference between what
we're talking about and Tracy saying
stabbing,
stabbing his gay.
What do you potentially gates
on political correctness.
Why is that shit still here is and why is,
why are the words more important than the
intent still? Well, that's what I said.
It's like black people wouldn't,
if you built a state of the art hospital
in Harlem or a state of the art school
in Harlem,
you could call it nigger high and they'd
be fine with it as long as they were
great teachers there and fucking state
of the art equipment and fucking yes,
my son went to nigger high like
they would really be really,
I promise it does it all right.
I'll say this for political correctness
because I've seen it. It came really to,
it came to full bloom
in the early nineties.
I think it is good in terms of
it it like calling black people,
African Americans. I
think that it does. Uh,
in some ways it's largely symbolic.
It's almost entirely symbolic,
but there was a five to 7% a range
in which I think it is an effective,
it does distinction. Yeah, it does make,
I mean a homosexual is better than
saying it fucking fag. You know,
like there are words that,
but is it better than
saying gay?
More ennobling than others.
Sexual better than
saying gay a gay problem.
One is African American
better than saying black.
I say black cause I don't cause African
American sounds like my friends or
dignitaries, whereas
they're just dudes. Right.
I always find it is strange. This
is a strange word. African American.
I've been saying, I've been saying nigger
in my act and it's, it's, it's great.
Go for it. You just do it on black
routes. I did chocolate Sunday on Sunday,
did great and I'm doing
tripping on Tuesdays tonight.
I'm going to go on and be in the back
of the room with one knee bent and one
foot in the launching position,
like the starting blocks.
My point isn't to run out of the room,
hang out with black people.
I get called it all the time.
Right? You get called the time.
So classic store hanging
out with black guys,
they say it back and forth and
you're not supposed to say it.
It's almost like when you're like you're
grounded and your brothers outside
dancing in the yard like woo, you
can't book and be on it. So, so, uh,
so the bid is about like,
I fucking,
I mean I say I would write it on Chappelle
show. I would, you know what I mean?
Like I wasn't that an issue on the
Chappelle show with comedy central.
I mean never. I mean that was,
no, I heard that. You guys know.
Yeah. You know where you heard
it from? From Dave's press
junket. So it's not true.
Well,
we were the golden geese of comedy central
or a license to print money for them.
So when Dave was saying that they were
telling him to stop saying, nigger,
that was bullshit. Absolutely. Wow.
Yeah. Holy Shit. I mean, again,
in my experience that was, that was, well,
I'm not going to say, here's the thing,
I say one thing about Dave and he can
go on Oprah and fucking trashed me.
So like I gotta be careful, but, but
that wasn't my experience at all.
Why would he go on Oprah trash shoots
he trashed me. Has, yeah. What happened?
You guys had this, what will he, you
know, we're doing the show popular show.
You'd been on it a few times. It
did wonders for your career. Um,
and uh,
and then
we were doing great. And then,
uh, we renewed our contracts,
which was extremely ugly comedy central
play, divide and conquer between us,
which I said they're going to do
this cause they are gonna make,
they're gonna they have to pay you.
They don't want to have to pay me.
The only way they're going to have to
pay me as if you demand that they pay me.
So what they did is they poisoned,
uh,
me in within Dave's mind and
how they do this with this.
Ah,
like David said one time at wraparounds
that he couldn't do the show without me
at, during a taping. He said that, and I
said that to comedy central. I was like,
Hey, just so you know, Dave said
he couldn't do the show without me.
And so they called him and goes,
you know,
Neil says she can't do the show without
him. And then he's like, motherfucker,
so just becomes an ego thing.
Well,
wait a minute,
you guys didn't have the kind of
relationship where he would call you up?
We did prior to that,
but
the negotiation started then it became
like a, I can't talk to anybody, you know,
really?
Yeah.
It was the w let me,
let me be clear with us.
It was the worst period of my life.
I can't imagine the worst period.
And it's just because the stakes were
so high. And then he was, became,
it became an ego thing
and it just became like,
no, I can, I can accomplish as to
what the scene on the set was. A,
when we did a,
the fear factor spoof and what it was,
was Neil was running everything and
Dave was in character all day running
around, you know, uh, you know,
I'm Rick James Bitch, and, and, and
I think that's an exaggeration,
but it was, but you know, I mean,
you had a huge part in that shows
the point coke ran, or the shell,
like it wasn't, that's the thing is
like, but I think what happened was,
uh,
you know,
they made it seem like by
David admitting that I was,
Lorne Michaels once
said in reference to me,
and Dave Comedians don't like it when,
when people realize they have help.
And I think in Dave was the one
who would say that I was out.
Cause it was fair because it was
only fair. He would have to say,
Neil makes a big contribution to show,
because I did,
it was conversations with calmness, Shit.
We said, whatever. Uh, but again, I,
uh, contributed, I believe I
held up my end of the bargain,
but it just became this thing
of like, they may, I think,
I don't think they made,
I think part of it was in him anyway,
that he just resented the idea
of being on a team. Really.
Yeah. And where did you
draw this conclusion from?
The Jews had a conversation with him
about this. This is just, yeah. And what,
what did he say?
Uh,
we're not a fucking team.
Whoa. Whoa. That was after
two years of the show.
And this is
teams. We were a team when
it, when it wasn't popular.
God Damn, that sucks. Yeah. Pain. I
know. That's the thing is like, look,
me and Dave are cool now and I don't,
I think that that's,
uh,
I'd like to think that this was all
circumstantial. You know what I mean?
Like in the circumstances, he was
just under a lot of pressure and end.
He felt like,
you know, the, the what you're
saying, you know, the other thing
that I will say is that, is that in
the, when me and Dave wrote half baked,
I knew that people in
comedy would all think,
would think that he wrote all of it and
people in show business would think that
I wrote all of it because people in show
business are predisposed to think that
the black guys had dummy
all that shit. Dude. I would
say to people, I swear to God,
I was in a meeting with a producer
and he, I promise you, he goes,
seriously how much of that script to
Dave, right. I prom and I was like,
half of it, man. Have
them. And sure enough,
everyone in comedy thought Dave wrote it.
Def Jeff Ross referred to me as
Dave Chappelle's typist. Okay.
Does Jeff Frosto? Well, I mean
he's the roast master general,
but that's a little bit beyond the Pale.
That wasn't it.
It wasn't that a row rude. Especially if
the guy doesn't update exact very often
by himself. Um, yeah. Um, uh,
Jeff, if any writers are listening.
When I was younger, I would, uh,
most certainly had a problem with
working with a garden and then having to
reveal the fact that this guy was
writing half of my material again.
But the idea of Hap, it's not, there's
so much work on, on doing a TV show,
it's just, it's a lot. I did a lot
of work. Here's the other thing,
Dave did a fuck load of work too.
And Dave is a hall of fame,
one in a billion comedian. I honestly
do that. Like one of the billion.
There's like Eddie Murphy, him,
Chris in terms of like, I don't,
I think he's very different
than any Murphy I think. No, no,
but I'm saying in terms of the decathlon
of ability, Dave can do stand up,
he can write sketches, he can think of
characters, he can write movies, he can,
he's got a visual sense like
he's got, he's got the full, uh,
a portfolio. So the idea that that, uh,
you know, he didn't like, I don't want
to come on here and be like, Dave,
Dave Chappelle, you know, doesn't exist.
That's not the truth. The truth is, well,
you're talking about a god that
cracked under pressure. It's all right.
It's not like he sucks. He's still
one of the greatest comics I knew.
So I knew early on in 97 that people
were going to give me too much credit or
him too much credit. So we had a deal.
We don't tell people who wrote what,
like how to deal sat down
and came up with the deal.
The idea was that we didn't
hammer it out or anything,
but I can deal with it was my
idea because I knew that if,
if I, if, if he'd heard that I said
I wrote something, he'd be pissed.
And uh, if I heard that, um,
he wrote like if it just,
it doesn't serve the team.
When people ask who wrote that
joke, they don't, they don't have,
they don't have your
best interests at hearts.
They basically saying they're like,
they're going, where's the one of you two?
Can I discount because
this hurts my feelings.
I think it's a good quality
of this hurts my feelings.
So they want to find out who I want to
find out who stinks. And he's funny.
That's interesting. Like, and, and so
I recognized that immediately. And so,
so we, so, but having said
that on true, because you know,
that's the Matt Stone Trey Parker thing.
Everybody who said Trey
Parker writes everything.
Matt stone just sits from jerks
off many times. You heard that?
That's why they say that because South
Park's the greatest fucking show that's
ever existed and it's fully good.
Yeah.
It hurts people who aren't producing
Matt around cause he hates money.
Gray hates money. He just wants
to give out. It's like, God,
I can't take, oh, I fucking
hate this money. Uh,
so the idea that somehow, uh, he didn't,
he didn't like the idea of
the implication that, that um,
uh, the white people would
think that I was doing it.
All people would say shit like we'd be,
we were somewhere and,
and one of his agents
came up. It's like the genius behind
the man to me standing next to Dave.
Now I know the agent is just trying to
be a fucking agent and be like schmoozy.
Right. But it's like, Yo man,
don't say that shit first of
all because it's not true.
And secondly, because it fucks, it
poisons our relationship, you know?
Hmm. Um, wow. There's a lot of ego
going on here. Uh, there's a, uh,
yeah,
yeah. A lot of ego get into show business
for, for attention. Like, you know,
for personal attention.
It's some point though. The idea is
to steer it towards the work, right.
To steer that energy into instead
of it being personal tension.
The real satisfaction is creating
something that's really good.
People love and passionate response and
people still love it. But that's the,
but the thing is if you're surrounded
by people, you know, there was a,
there've been some studies where
they, where they said, what is,
uh, they, they, they put
people in a situation,
a bunch of volunteers in situation, and
they asked another group of volunteers,
what do you think these people
will do and why? And they,
they said they are going to do the
negative thing because they're all dicks.
So they,
the people did the thing,
people devolve this group did the thing
over here and they all did the negative
thing. And these people said, yeah,
cause their dicks and then they put
these people in it and they did the exact
same thing.
Not because their debts.
It's because as a human being in that
situation, you're going to do the thing.
People don't know how they're going
to react in certain situations.
And most of the time it is circumstantial.
It's not characterological.
And that's the thing with this is I think,
uh,
if I,
if I had been Dave,
it's very easy for me to say I would
have treated Neil differently. But again,
you know, or, but I wasn't dating
circumstances,
exposed character though.
I mean that is the idea of
character in the first place.
The idea of character is strong,
character is able to survive under
adversity and that's what it's all about.
And that's why when someone doesn't have
your back, when the shit hits the fan,
you lose respect for them
because you're like, well,
this person has enough character. This
person is not my friend. You know,
this person is looking out for themselves.
They're weak, they're egotistical,
they're whatever.
They have a flaw.
Yeah, he'll, he'll bury me for
this by the way. Really? Oh,
do you know on this conversation?
Absolutely. Really? I
mean, I would bet my bet.
So you're feeling bad right now that
you said anything? I don't feel bad.
I mean, I, I actually don't feel like I've
said anything bad and I think I've been
sympathetic. I mean, but no one here.
The thing that was so disgusting about
the whole thing was nobody asked me my
side of things,
60 minutes called and I wouldn't do an
interview in New York Times called I
wouldn't do an interview.
Well explain to everybody
how it all went south.
So you guys were in negotiations,
you're about,
everybody heard the number 50 million.
That's what I keep hearing.
$50 million are going to make
another season for $50 million deal.
And then Dave goes to Africa,
right? What, what, what exactly went
down. But what happened was the,
there was the negotiation part,
the divide and conquer thing that I
already talked about about them going,
you know Neil. So then he
can do it without them. You
can't do it without them.
So which would make Chappelle like, Fuck
Neil, you're basically comedy central.
You're deputized to low ball him
even though, I mean he never,
I don't think that was
ever explicitly said.
But if they say like they came to him
at one point and like could you do the
show without Neil?
And He,
and they had poisoned me to him so
much by that point that he was like,
yeah,
but it would take three people.
Could you have decided to get together
and form a partnership in the form of
some sort of a corporation and say this
corporation is what you are contracting
to do this television show and the fee
for the corporation will be X. Right.
But there was all guys,
Ben and some sort of illegal things,
so you don't have to worry
about this ever again.
I couldn't have been done that could have
been done ahead of time, but I'm not,
we're not a fucking team. Keeps
that shit from happening. Yeah.
Um, so, so, so yeah. So at that point,
uh, they was the divide
and conquer thing and, and,
and so, all right. Yeah. So that,
so our relationship was pretty
much once my deal was closed,
you couldn't call him and go, Yo dude,
this is, eventually I did. And eventually,
literally were on the both on the phone.
I'm crying and I think he may
get out of my house right now.
Joe, this is how Whiz,
what a bitch I am. Uh,
it's Tracy Morgan would
stab me right now. Um, uh,
so a cook a steak for you after
this is over and Ah, no, I'm crying.
Chappelle may have been crying.
He was definitely tearing up
because on the phone. Yeah.
How'd he know he's tearing up on the
phone. You can visit hope vocally.
You guys on Skype.
We were on a I chat.
Um, and uh, and it was basically like,
dude, like what are you doing? Like,
and then, and then, so finally it was,
I basically said like, why are
you doing this? Like, what did I,
you do your deals closed. But they made
basically his deal was closed, right.
Bunch of money. Uh, and
then my deal was open,
but they made it somehow seem to,
Dave,
like any point for me
was a point against him.
And it wasn't the case,
but I think,
and so they were letting him know
there's only a certain amount of money.
They knew they weren't,
they never said like,
you're going to get less money if
Neil gets more. Dave Steele was close.
It was just the idea that
like they didn't want,
it was like they planted in Dave's
sort of psyche that he didn't,
or maybe it was already in there,
he didn't want me to get in too
close in terms of compensation.
They made it about an
ego thing. Like, well,
how much does Neil [inaudible]
Neil worth? You know? Uh,
so they were basically
deputized to low ball me.
Well, typically show
runners get, you know,
almost as much money as
the stars of shows. I mean,
you look in terms of like this
fucking guy with this chuck Lorre Guy,
Charlie Sheen,
you know,
everybody's talking about Charlie Sheen
making $2 million an episode. Guess what?
That chuck Lorre guy probably makes
more secular, would kill himself.
He was making 2 million and up.
Yeah.
Uh,
Chuck Lorre,
he's done a lot of big shows and it
wasn't cast contingent and all that.
Like Dave brought me on. Right. You know,
so I couldn't really go like, fuck you.
And the other thing is I can't
just go do the show with like,
I'm going to get fucking Orlando
Jones and do that. It's not, and I,
nor did I want it.
That was the thing is the thing that about
me and Dave was like, I love the dude.
You know what I mean? Like I like a
door. The dude, I love writing with them.
I love writing. I love, like, I would
work like fucking a crazy, I worked,
I told my brother this the other day
because I'd forgotten. I worked one day,
there was a,
there was a period where I worked for 12,
at least 12 hours a day for
35 straight days to try to,
just to get the show done, to
get the show on the air. Um,
he was working his ass off too, but
it was just the idea that somehow, uh,
they just made it about
like pitting us against.
Okay.
So for those nation go crazy.
They pitted you against him.
You guys wound up fighting.
How did you never resolve it?
How did you never talked to him?
We've resolved it,
but it was still this thing of like,
when push comes to shove,
you don't want to be in a fucking team.
Uh,
you don't think I'm,
you think I'm fractionally
worthwhile of the show? Uh,
it was just kind of a vote of like,
fine.
It was just this resentment of
like that I was getting this, this,
that I got some money to do.
Yeah.
Well I don't understand that.
If he thinks that you guys are a team
and it didn't affect how much you were a
teen, but he knows that you guys
work together to do the fucking show.
Right?
You're basically saying that it was
completely an ego thing on his part.
That's what you're saying.
You're saying that he didn't feel
like you were worth as much as him.
He didn't feel like you're working.
Contribution was, like I said,
he's a one in a billion guy.
Like he's, uh, he's, uh,
he deserved more money than okay. That,
that said he already had his money,
so he was already getting a certain
amount of money. So what, what,
what you're saying basically is completely
different than anything anyone's ever
heard in the news. No kidding.
Cause no one's ever asked
me, God, this is so crazy.
So my point of view from all this time,
it was greatest show in my opinion,
greatest comedy show of all time,
Chappelle show number one,
greatest show of all time.
That fucking Clayton Bigsby character,
that's the greatest sketch in
all of television, black racists
self idea. Like he had been, he'd had
it in the heat and it's a brilliant,
brilliant still remember writing the
sketch. It's a brilliant, I remember call,
yeah,
I won't say who wrote.
So what I had heard was that there was
all sorts of input from the network and
they were saying him that he used to
stop saying nigger and make it more
friendly to commercials.
This side,
I don't remember where it heard
this or you might want to be second.
There was a lot of stories
and that he,
because he left the show and then I
think he had to figure out a way to make
himself look like the victim,
but in my estimation he wasn't
the victim. Wow. Um, again,
no one wants to hear it again.
He's like,
he's an unbelievably charming guy.
Hilarious.
He's everybody's friend. Like I get it.
He's, he was my for, he's still living.
We're still friendly. Like we're friends.
We weren't for like three, four years,
but now we're friendly and hang out when
he's in La. Let me ask you this man, why,
why doesn't he do like fucking
concerts and theaters and put out DVDs?
I mean everybody's so excited to see
him do standup, but like you know,
you never hear about it until he
like shows up. Lee Thomas show. Yeah.
I'll show up at the store.
He'll show up,
showed up in Seattle and was doing
shows in a park with a speaker.
He pulled out a microphone and a speaker
and plugged it in and just doing shows
like outdoors and I saw,
I'm like about a month and a half ago
and it was just him on stage and he was
kind of fucking, it felt like he was
fucking around. He wasn't like doing bits,
but then I was told that no,
that's his new style where he just
does a lot of audience interaction.
It's almost like a, an evening with, yeah,
it was cool because you know what you're
like. Okay. Really? I mean, again,
the guy can channel Shit, like he can just
stand in there and he's, he's riveting.
I saw Dave do a street
performance in Montreal.
He did a standup comedy on the street.
And what he would do was, uh, you know,
we were doing these shows at club
soda and then after the show he goes
downstairs and shit, man. He was like,
I don't know, 19 or something like that.
And he goes downstairs and there's a
group of people and so he just starts
yelling, gathered around,
gathered around lazy. Yeah.
That was when one of the period we met
and I started doing friends for like,
I invited on the show to him,
finding him on the podcast so we could
get him in here and wait, wait for him.
I think he'll be here any
minute, dude. Hey, it's day.
Um, I, this is, this is very
disturbing. Uh, I mean, again,
all I've ever said about it,
it was very like behind the music.
How come he's not doing shows? Do you
have any idea? I don't know. It's like,
it's not advertising your shows. It's
weird. I mean he's selling out everywhere.
I mean he does shows every once in a
while for like no DVDs. No, you know,
I want to see the shakes.
You know I having a contract and having
to be someplace and I have a copy of
Dave Chappelle when he
got back from Africa. He,
he did a set at a comedy club and I have
a copy of that on MP3 and it's really
weird as you make the copy,
I don't know want to talk about it but
I like I boot like staying home a month
ago really cause I that he does a bit
about doctor drew and I had to play it for
someone. It's like you had about doctor
drew just about piece of Charlatan.
He is fun. He's a whore.
Yeah. Dr Jews purely.
I'm all completely anti Dr drew now.
I mean he's a nice guy.
When I see him I'll say hi, I'll be his
friend. But he started doing this stupid
shit on a CNN show about pot having severe
withdrawal symptoms and that the THC
is in a higher content today,
which is physiologically
a fucking ridiculous thing
for a doctor to say because
since it's not physically addictive,
just because there's more THC does not
make it addictive. You know, it doesn't,
it doesn't all of a sudden change the
properties of the fucking drug, you know,
and anything where it's addictive at all,
it's psychologically addictive,
which by the way, anything can be
psychologically addictive. You know,
it's like saying,
well we need to take away porn because
porn psychologically addictive,
no more gambling because some people
can't handle it. Fat Foods, fatty foods,
no more cheeseburgers. Cause some
people get addicted to fatty foods.
It's like fuck that. That's
the, that's nonsense.
Talking only like half the country
gets addicted to fatty foods.
Those were fucking idiots. You know? I
agree. That's evolutionary. I'm with you.
I'm not into nerf in the world. And so
his, his proposition that marijuana,
you know, should, it is dangerous
and illegal or should be illegal,
it's fucking completely ridiculous thing
to stay. Especially when he, you know,
pharmaceutical companies are producing
shit that's 100,000 times worse and it's
available everywhere.
It's a stupid,
ridiculous thing for a doctor to say it's
a terrible position for a Dr site and
it's ignorant,
you know?
And the only reason why he's saying it
is because he thinks that that's what the
people who listen to him want to hear.
He's a whore. That whore behavior.
I used to love him on in though.
I thought it was really informative
and helpful and I just feel like it's,
at a certain point it's like,
dude, you're just, uh, you,
you want to be famous for everybody else.
Exactly. Yeah. He's, he's working hard
for fame. It's like his fucking show.
It's the most ridiculous thing.
The idea that he's really helping those
celebrities to get clean, you know?
I mean, come on, man, you got
a fucking camera in their face.
It's the worst possible scenario
for someone to try to clean up.
They give them attention
and the end of their career,
when everything's fucking
completely falling apart,
you're going to give them
attention and put a camera on them.
Whether weeping and shaking
and pissing their pants,
and they should make it like a,
whoever remains the sober the longest
gets some kind of money. Yeah.
That's what it should pay, right?
Yeah. Let's make it a game show. Yeah.
That's a good idea. What is,
um, what does Stan hope spit?
What does he say about him? Do you
mind? I think I have on my phone.
Yeah. I had such a good bit. It's
like such an, uh, it's, uh, it,
it was a crazy good bit. Um, so, uh,
whatever, I, I, they would
take me forever is fine. Right.
But were you still
involved with Chappelle?
The Chappelle show had like that kind of
wrap up show and stuff like that? Yeah,
cause I liked the sketches. Yeah.
Dave wrote this sketches together.
So then it became this thing of
like, it was, it was, uh, and again,
like I, I don't want people to think
that I'm a dick or Dave's a dick.
I just, it was a, it was a,
it was a stressful situation.
Um,
you, so you were involved with the
season that he was involved in,
which was like he, he was, he
was, we wrote the sketch together,
but he wasn't involved
in putting it on the air
was not involved in putting them on the
air. Yeah. Did he not want it on the air?
Uh,
I think his perception in my,
my feeling about it was
his perception of what was,
uh,
recorded.
No perception of what was relevant or,
or what was, what was, it's what's right,
windows racial become racist and,
um,
and just got sort of blurred and I
don't think he could see the difference
between,
so he thought some of this stuff
was racist. It's not a racial,
and it was based on
completely random random. Uh,
so what you basically saying is that
the pressure of this show over two years
was so intense and that so many things
happened and there was so much going on
that he kind of cracked a little,
which is what a lot of people
thought when he moved to [inaudible].
I mean when he went to Africa, uh,
is, is, is, I don't know, again,
I don't, I don't presume to
know what it's like to be a,
a famous black comedian.
Uh,
it like it because the
thing that black eyes,
black comedians get that white
people don't is you become a symbol.
You know what I mean?
Like you become the elect the spokesman.
So people on news shows start going like,
well,
I saw Dave Chappelle show
that you can do today.
I saw that a thousand times when people,
it became this thing,
it became bigger than
the intention where it's,
the intention was like this little,
this show that was almost just to make
each other laugh and then it became this
big thing. It became like this
bully pulpit and, and so it,
it became, it was so much responsibility
I think for David. He actually,
it stopped being fun because it
wasn't like it wasn't, it was,
it was the idea of like
he said on 60 minutes like
dance, like nobody's watching.
And then it became like dance, like
fucking way too many people are watching.
And, and I think it got
in his head about about,
is this responsible or is this,
which again, as a white person,
you just don't have to worry about,
no one's going to go. You don't,
you're never going to be the spokesman
for white people ever. Do you hear me? Um,
if you keep this up, uh, no. Like
you just can't, you'll never,
so that's the thing that as a, I think
as a, as a black comedian, it's just,
it's like Eddie Murphy,
The Times I've spoken to him and hung
out with them is still still seems upset
by the fact that, that he
got like picketed, you know?
Yeah. He's like, man, if
fucking, I'm just doing jokes.
And then next thing I know I got people
outside picketing. It's like, well, yeah,
but you're doing dice. Obviously dice had
the same thing. So it's not just racial,
but
it's your PR. It's the perceptions
that you're, you're, you're,
you're very influential.
And when you're on stage and you're saying
a bunch of really negative shit about
black people.
I mean,
Eddie Murphy said a lot of really mean
shit about black people. You know,
people you mean? Yeah. Excuse me. Gay
People. So it wasn't, it wasn't, um,
it wasn't just, you know, he was
doing jokes. It was, you know,
the jokes were really nasty.
Yeah, no, I'm with you. I like, I
don't like all the Ilab but, but,
um, but having heard that, I just want to
say that Eddie is an awesome dude. Yes.
Yeah. Great guy to hang out with,
to talk to. Hilarious. Um, but uh,
but so the eye are just jokes, but
they are just jokes. I mean, but again,
if you're doing jokes in a
club with a hundred people,
it doesn't take on that mom mentality.
Whereas when you're in fucking Nassau
Coliseum, you started to go, oh wait,
this is almost too much, uh,
influence over people. It's,
it's one thing when it's a club, but
when it becomes this big like, hmm,
what next?
We had Brian Posehn on yesterday and he
was talking about the gathering of the
Juggalos. He's doing standup at
the gathering of the Juggalos.
And I thought about it after you left.
I got baked and I was writing
and I was thinking, you know,
it'd be cool if we had some fucking crazy
death squad meeting somewhere cause I
know Stan hope did some shit like that.
Like you had these parties in the desert
but it was really just like a loser
festival. Yeah. It became a bad idea but
doing some one crazy event every year,
you know,
something like that.
But that's when things get dangerous when
things get dangerous is when you have
like a movement behind you and then
you have a logo and shit. Yeah.
It's very difficult to fucking keep
your, your, your interest pure.
It's also, yeah, it's
hard to uh, it's it, yeah.
It's, you kind of go, wait, what? What
am I doing? It becomes this corporation.
It just becomes like this,
like a corporation and fucking a lot of
you meet with lawyers more than you meet
with the writers. You know what I mean?
Like, that's the thing, part of it that's,
that's perceived of managed it
fine. Oh, here we go to you.
Do you have a huge issue
with the Oprah like Oprah?
Yeah, I do. I know you don't like hope.
No. She had Dave on. He's trashing me.
No one from our CEO calls me.
She doesn't have for my side of things.
No one warns me. No. And then she,
but she's this like great humanist.
Well, in her defense, I mean,
is she going to have another show where
you can at least tell me or at least
happening?
How does she have any idea that you
were going to get trashed on the show?
She knows that she had Dave on, he
had it in the can for weeks. Right.
But what are they going to tell you that
the day of trashed? You really think,
why would they email me
something? Really? Yeah.
I don't worry if you're going
to have someone telling you
retelling a story, it's
like, have both people on,
I wouldn't expect that. Um, I would
think, you know, here's the famous guy.
Let's see what he's got to take.
No, it's, you know, we're friends.
If he goes on Oprah, I'm sure we'll see
nice things. Then I'd like Oprah. Well,
that's what you think until two weeks
later. And if he doesn't, uh, you know,
I'll write something online,
but I can't believe you said that.
And this is the reality and the fourth,
the Douche bag and
thanks to you, by the way, I don't know.
I'm guessing I'm going to
have to blame you for it.
Now on Twitter where it
says similar to you, Oprah,
the whole file comes up now
has to be because of you.
Because I like about Oprah.
I think she is a positive
voice to people like her.
She's a positive voice to older women.
She gives him something
to look forward to.
She has this fanatical following of
likeminded people in her message is
essentially positive.
Her messages of life improvement and
of dietary improvement and behavioral
improvement or messages of spreading love.
She's nothing like me.
There's nothing about her.
I bet she probably hates everything
I've ever done of every outside of news
radio. She likes your MMA. I bet she hates
UFC. I bet she hates fear factor out of,
but it's all good. I'm very
different human being than she is.
But I recognize that as a
human being who she is is uh,
very beneficial and very important to
people like her. I like, I like it.
Game recognizes game son.
She's positive. Yeah,
I think she's a fucking ego
maniacal. Well she, me, she might be.
I had a friend who works
for and he painted a very
different picture of her. Uh,
then, uh, you know,
you see of her on her show when she's
being interviewed by likeminded people.
But my friend who interviewed her is
kind of a cunt and he likes to start
arguments and I bet he would have a
real hard time working for some powerful
woman. And I said, I assume that that's
probably what happened. You know,
he got stupid with her because he used
to get stupid with me when we worked
together. So I'm assuming with her it was
probably even grocer, you know? I mean,
I just did the math, but you know, I
mean, yeah, I mean, I don't know. I just,
you don't like her because
of your own personal,
but I didn't like it before that.
What didn't you like about it before that?
She's an ego maniacal phone.
It's all [inaudible] Oprah.
She doesn't give a play.
It's like the last week where there
people on her farewell shows where there's
tea,
there's uh,
people are gathered around to honor this
woman that they've made a billionaire.
Like thank you for letting
us make you a billionaire.
And she likes fucking like this.
Like a fucking like a queen or something.
Okay.
But how would she have handled it?
How, what's the other way to handle it?
Came out and start flicking them all. Just
say good night. Do a final show. Well,
you know,
maybe she wanted to give them the chance
to say thank you and she wanted to give
herself a chance to thank them.
Why didn't Johnny Carson do that?
Why did Johnny Carson smoked five packs
of cigarettes a day and dive a fucking
magazines because he's a bad ass.
You ever see the pictures of
him when he's about to die?
I'll never forget these photos.
They had them in like star
magazine or one of those things.
He had this giant gut,
like he swallowed a basketball and he
was smoking like call malls and he was
just insanely unhealthy when he died.
It's amazing when you think of a guy who
was that loved by so many people was so
fucking miserable, so miserable. Uh, yeah.
You ever hear Wayne Newton
talk about them? No.
Wayne Newton talking about Johnny Carson
is the most hilarious shit cause Johnny
Carson,
we should tell jokes about Wayne Newton
and his shit on Wayne noon and Wayne
Newton was, you know, he's a fucking
ego maniac and he couldn't take it.
So apparently like he confronted
Johnny Carson and grabbed him at,
threatened them and said he was
going to kick his ass and yeah,
that's pretty funny.
Anyway,
Johnny Carson's stopped doing it
and like flew in to see him. Yeah,
it was pretty funny. I wonder if
it's true though. Oh yeah. Yeah.
I mean Newton might've said
that he threatened him.
He might've gotten in there and so you
stopped telling the drugs by me and
Johnny one kicked this fucking guy out
of here. They probably pull the bed.
What I like about you and your
toughness is that you don't,
uh, you're so physically
threatening that you don't,
you just, the parameters with you
are very clear. Whereas I think with,
I just, I ate, we'll never
get to violence with you,
but I liked it if you just said like,
Hey, would you stop doing jokes about me?
People would just do it.
Yeah.
I don't think anybody's really worried
about physical violence in this day and
age, you know, not from
someone kicking their ass.
This is so much at stake and so much
to even pretend that you would do that.
Like,
you know,
I'm going to go kick some of these
asks cause they told jokes about you.
That's silly. I'm not, I don't
think that way ever. My, you know,
I've never been one who's into getting
in fights. Never. Even when I was young,
I just,
I think it's dangerous and scary and
I've seen too many people get fucked up.
I just been into martial arts and so I
was a kid because I have terrible primate,
savage instincts and I'm trying to curb
every fucking step of the way I'm doing
it to try not to fuck people up. I'm
doing it. Sure. I try to not get angry,
you know?
Yeah.
Uh, no, that's good. But that, that
was what the thing with you and Carlos,
that was what your size,
uh,
made it,
it kind of took that off the table.
Like you couldn't be like fuck you and
fight you. It just, and I also think,
and that's,
I don't know if you remember when I gave
you $20 a few weeks after it cause I
just thought you deserve,
you deserve recompense for what you did.
But I think that you're the only
one who ever did that. That video,
that video made it,
uh,
made joke thievery and unacceptable.
And I think that that Carlos,
his career has suffered as a result
of the video because it just made,
it made something that was a behind the
scenes and only communities, you know,
and it made it put it in the public eye.
Well it's also because of Brian.
Brian is wanting to edit it and edit
it the way he edited it and made it so
entertaining news 10 fucking minutes long,
listen to 10 minutes of that nonsense.
This argument back and
forth between two comedians.
It would have been really boring and it
probably would've gotten not a fraction
of the hits.
He made it so interesting because he had
all these other people saying that see
mencias steel's material and going back
in time and you know, and, and you know,
switching the time and that you know,
where you go in the past and then the
future and you know, going back and forth.
He made it really fascinating to watch.
That was
what's,
what's the luxury about that whole thing
that happened is actually I had been
doing my research about the guy wait
beforehand and I actually had made a prior
video that you did your
doctoral thesis? Yeah. Yeah.
I mean I was waiting for a day like this
to happen and it all like pretty much
Bates the first time I ever met him.
Like he like stopped and it like
went shoulder to shoulder with me.
He looked at me and did that
chicken neck thing where he's like,
like that kind of like to make me flinch
or something like that can get out of
my way, get out of my way. And I'm
like, really? Okay. Are you, were you
hanging out at the comedy store talking
to Duncan Trussell and uh, he's a cunt,
you know,
it's weird.
He was a real problem, you know, there,
I've never been in a situation like
that where you really realize how the
business is structured and
that no agents gave a fuck.
No club owners gave a fuck.
Everybody knew he was stealing shit
and they kept using him because he was
putting asses in seats.
And it was so shocking to watch everybody
turn a blind eye to him cannibalizing
old Richard Pryor seat.
Right as you went around those
people to the audience and said, Hey,
are you both did and said, hey,
this is what's actually happening.
And the people have since spoken
with fewer asses in seats.
Well you can also read his Twitter and
you realize how fucking crazy he really
is and watch his little Facebook
videos that he puts out.
Then you get to see the real human being.
Now behind this facade of being a fake
Mexican and now being the number one
Latino comic,
you know,
but the reality is the Latino market is
fucking gigantic and they were looking
for a superstar. And so
Mitzi shore said, hey,
why don't you change your name to Mexican?
So she made him become this phase.
Actual name was Carlos Mexican.
That was Mitsis ideas. Name's
Ned. That's a stranger.
Yeah,
but not that I really liked that in
that it made people more aware of joke
thieves and it made it,
it's people,
there was another like
confrontation like a month ago,
guys material, which was excellent.
Yeah. I didn't see it, but uh, I,
I heard it's pretty good. I don't want to
even, I, I'm so connected to that world.
It's like I avoid led.
Yes.
That world plagiarism
and exposing plagiarism.
Like I don't want to,
I just don't enough already.
I've said more than enough
negative shit about it. It was a,
an issue that had to be dealt with and
an issue unlike any people bring up all
these arguments about parallel
thinking and you're absolutely right.
I've had jokes that I thought, I
know I wrote. I know I wrote. Yeah.
And then I'll watch some
fucking HBO special from 1984.
And it's like basically the same premise.
Here's a perfect example.
Yesterday we were talking about a racist
about if dolphins could talk and we
were talking about they,
cause they came up with a machine
to decipher dolphin language. Right.
And then I said, uh, that we
would have the first words
were I hate Jews. You know,
and then we, I was watching a clip,
somebody posted on the message board,
you guys did a bit of a Chappelle show
were racist Dolphin and here the nigger
hating dolphin.
Yeah.
I'm here to reclaim that bit
from you Joe. I did a bit, uh,
I was doing it for like three weeks.
It was killing so hard that I had to,
I had to close with it cause it
was just killing so hard. Uh,
and then about three weeks into doing it,
Jim Norton goes,
Hey Jim Florentine used
to do with that bit. Fuck.
So then I see Florentine and he's like,
I did it 15 years ago and he's like,
you should do it. And I was
Kinda like, I can't. Yeah, it's,
it sucks cause it's one of those things
it's like, ah fuck. It was such a good,
and I know I wrote it like I,
cause I remember Joe,
I work with this kid in Vegas
and he was doing bits off my old,
my CD from 1999 he did three bits.
Yeah.
Just reworked them and changed them. So a
few years back our, he couldn't make it.
And Anyway, long story. Uh, so I
was like, you know, do I even say,
I mean I'm not doing any of this
stuff anymore. I don't do it anymore,
but God damn dude,
I mean you're going on right in front
of me and you're redoing my own,
my old fucking material. Did you say
anything? No, no. He was so terrible.
It was like, you know, I'm never going
to run with this guy again anyway.
The odds are know. Yeah, it was. But
you know, when you have a bit that,
you know, you found out that someone,
you know, George Carlin did 20 years ago,
you got to let it go.
Yeah.
I mean,
but there are bits that I've written
that that recently that like someone else
and it's Kinda like I don't fucking,
and then you get into what day
did you write it? Well, you
know it's a tweet. Everything.
There's certain things like the news
stories when things happen that it's
unavoidable. When you know the Mel
Gibson arrest happened unavoidable,
there's going to be some similar shit.
You know when you're talking about
Charlie Sheen is going to be some similar
shit,
but when it comes to like,
you know a a bit that's like
really like a signature premise.
I've had this issue with a couple
of friends where I was like, dude,
you've got to drop that bit.
You know,
that's this guy that's like
real similar to this. It's been,
I've heard it before and they go, yeah, I
don't think it's that similar. I'm like,
look, you're going to do it.
What are you going to do it?
You're going to be this unoriginal
guy, man. You someone in the audience,
you're going to be out there on stage
and you must know that there's 300 people
out there. Someone knows
that there's another guy who
does that bit, at least one,
maybe one person for me, I can't
do it for me. I can't do that bit.
Now if you can do that bit to me that
says something about you artistically,
that you're, you're, you got
some low standards, you know,
and that you're willing to compromise
to come up with new material,
which is like really close to stealing.
It's like, yeah, that's one
of those things. It's a bit
of a, that's like, that's a,
how do you live with yourself?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. It sucks man. But
sometimes you've got to let things go.
I mean, it is sometimes, you
know, someone will say, Oh,
this guy has a bit just like that.
And then he'd go, oh no, he doesn't.
You listen to it and it's
like a similar premise,
but you went in a totally
different direction with it.
Yeah. Some kid accused me, I did,
I wrote something on Twitter like two
months ago and some kid was like, zs.
Aziz Ansari did that bit
on fucking his special.
And I was like, I know. How
do you think I got the idea?
Well, we were making fun of m
a r Kelly's video, real talk,
which I watched again after a year.
I haven't seen it either. Video.
I have a song memorized.
See the video, the videos.
It's one of the greatest videos. Milton.
Milton. Milton. Yeah. He's trying to,
Milton's at the end of the fighting,
they stop the fight or flight.
It goes bogus girl. Yeah. Bitch.
I wish you fun clothes. And so, uh,
we were making fun of it on the
podcast and someone tweets me. Yeah.
Aziz [inaudible] already mixed
fun of it. I'm writing. No,
he doesn't know that.
Sorry.
You don't get to own one of the greatest
fucking unintentional pieces of comedy
ever. I don't care if he makes fun of
it. I haven't seen him make fun of it.
I'm sure he does. I know
he does. An r Kelly bit.
You don't own make it fun to r Kelly.
That's like owning making fun of Michael
Jackson or make it fun to Shaquille
O'neil. You don't, yeah.
You don't make your own.
You don't own making fun of something
ridiculous. Yeah. So there's that.
I see that.
But man,
when you find a joke that you know that
used to be on some fucking Richard Pryor
CD,
you gotta let that job.
Yeah.
It's hard.
I mean even cause I have a good
memory for jokes so it becomes like a,
it becomes a hard,
but I guess it just forced you to be
more original. That's when I
knew him and see was a thief.
There was a first thing that he ever did
where it really popped a red flag back
when we were friends is he did a bit
about a Ufo landing in the hood and that's
like some old negatives or
steal that shit. You know,
thinking about stealing
the Ufo from the aliens.
Chappelle did a joke when he was in
high school that if alf came to his
neighborhood, uh, a week later you'd
see a nigger in an alf skin coat
and he was like 15. That was your
body. That's fine. Uh, yeah, yeah,
yeah. So Carl, so you really, yeah.
You just kind of go, ah, yeah.
Makes you not really want to
get a drink with them after.
Well, it made me, made me like tell
him and then I told him, he said, no,
I've been doing that bit for a
while. I go, do, do, do, do bits Ana,
unless you've been doing it since 1981,
not even seventies.
Like that nigger's crazy.
It's on that one.
I think it's thinking it's one of the old,
it's like a set.
It's probably just released recently
on CD or something, you know? And uh,
you know, he was like insisting on doing
the pin. I'm like, wow, that's crazy.
Like you're telling me that,
you know that Richard Pryor did it already
and they to keep doing it because you
came up with it on your own.
Yeah, I look at that bill Cosby
wine, you know, playing football.
Either your dad that was, that was the
one that you guys inspired and do that,
you know? I know, but
that because of you guys,
that was the nail and that was
the final nail in the coffin.
Yeah, I think so. I think that was the one
where people went, what the fuck? Like,
there's like, he's a sacred,
you know, deity in comedy.
Bill Cosby. Yeah. You know,
there's not a single comic that'll,
you know,
ever tell you that bill Cosby
ain't shit. You know, those,
the fucking Noah's Ark bit, you
know, and Noah, what, you know,
you remember that bit,
that whole thing.
And he used to do like his stories
these long, like, he was like,
he had a real particular style of
comedy man. Yeah. He invented the,
he invented a style. Yeah. The long story.
And when a punchline at the
end of this story, you know,
I, I'm not a fan of his show. I
wasn't a fan of the Cosby show,
know what I really want to
give was just condescending.
It was just the whole shell was like,
children are morons and I'm going
to chop them down every week.
I'm just kind of like, all
right, man. Yeah. Well, you
know, it's a fucking Sitcom,
man. Yeah, no, I get it. But honestly,
calm you like, I liked family tides.
I'm not even fucking around.
Like, I liked family ties. Uh,
but that's about d like
two and a half men. Uh,
I'll say this for two and a half men.
I've seen it on mute a few times on the
plane and it looks like they're having a
good time.
Then maybe the best anyone has ever
really done all these guys are with a good
time and then on occasion I'll hear
like a Dick joke and I'm always like,
that's a pretty strong dick joke for
the, for, for a sitcom at that time slot.
I only watched it once recently and I
thought it was the most unbearable thing
I'd ever seen on television and I thought
it was incredible that it's so popular.
We were talking about it yesterday.
I, I'm, I'm, I was baffled by it.
I couldn't believe how bad the jokes
were. I was like, this is just,
this is just an alien language.
Right.
I'm watching it with my mouth open and
I'm hearing the laugh track and I'm like,
this isn't even my language.
Yeah.
If you don't watch a show with a laugh
track for a while and then you do your
life.
Yeah,
I would like to watch it and have it all
the laughs extracted like someone do it
through pro tools,
go in there,
extract all the labs and just have him
say that the jokes and have no response
and see how they fucking bizarre.
She had,
I wanted to do that where every po you
take the lapse out and then every punch
line I just go Bam.
But I mean
see like, you know the curb, your
enthusiasm has no laugh track. You know,
and it's hilarious.
But if you did that with like a show
like two and a half men take out all the
laughs. Yeah. And only have them
act out the scene. It's fucking
posture. But having said that,
cheers. Had a laugh, track sign photo,
the laugh track friends had a,
hey,
there's nothing wrong with a laugh track.
What I'm saying is when
something's really horrible. Yeah.
And then you're just
faking it. Yeah. And when,
if you could just listen to it without
the laughter, it would be so soon.
That's like that movie that looks
that like, uh, the movie with them.
I always forget the guy's name,
the guy from who hosted the Oscars
and he's handsome. He brought over
playing the steel steel robot boxers.
That looks good.
I get that lifts off.
It's like transforming a boxing match.
It's like a boxing the deck.
Rocky mixed the transformer.
Everyone looks like this is
called a real steal. Rosio.
At first I thought it was a
knock. 'Em sock. 'Em Mood. It is.
And that's pretty much what it is.
Yeah. I thought it looked good.
Just cause I liked that.
Transformers Hugh Jackman shirtless
in the real steel trailer.
I am. I want to see that
bastard. I'm a nerd.
You fucking ruined the
Wolverine Character, man. I
don't care what anyone says.
Wolverine supposed to be like
five foot three and built.
I find those movies pitiful.
I find the odd,
the fact that they can only do
superhero movies now, just pitiful.
Like it's there. It's, I
told someone it's like,
it's there for dumb people to be
able to explain to other dumb people.
Like there's a dude and he got bit by
a spider and he's half and half man,
and he wears a uniform.
So you're never confused about who's
who and he's got a logo on the superman,
has a logo on the front and
the back in case you get them.
You're telling me you don't like
comic book movies, man. Uh, I liked,
I'm such an old man. I liked to
Chris Reeves, Superman. Whoa.
And uh,
which other ones have I liked?
I didn't like men. I didn't like,
uh, yeah, like Spiderman. Okay.
I'm watching the trailer for this,
this rock 'em sock. 'Em robots movie.
Oh, I like the Batman movies.
I like the new Batman.
I like the Tim Burton ones and I liked
the, uh, the, the, what does names?
Yeah.
This,
by the way,
this premise of this film where there's
robots and the people like where this
robot outfit and get in fights.
It's a fucking great idea, man.
That's actually real robots.
Oh,
these are robots in their controlling
them remotely. That's what it is.
No, they're just, they're
just training robots.
Have our Avatar robot.
Yes. Pretty fucking.
Have Avatar robot fights.
To me it's no different than racing cars.
You know what you're racing cars,
you know, you're not supposed to be
moving that fast. You're using a machine,
move that fast,
you know,
and you're bumping into each other and
cutting and cutting each other off.
In one of those that was
in, uh, it was in, um,
the end of x men or the
end of, uh, of, of uh,
ironman wasn't, that wasn't Jeff
Daniels and like, uh, or it didn't,
didn't I liked that movie too.
Yeah. All right man. It was fun, right?
Yeah. He's a new cognac. It looks fun.
A lot of people are shitting on it online.
It looks pretty fucking bad ass to me.
And they're like saying that they owe
that guy can't be cone and he's not built
enough. He's not this. No.
Nobody really looked like
Arnold Schwarzenegger and
the fucking 1500 BC. Right.
That shit's unrealistic. No carbs. Yeah.
All red meat back then he was
on a strict diet in the, in the,
in Paleolithic Times. Paleo Diet, Paleo.
That's what a lot of people are
doing right now. Cause that's true.
It's all the rage. I didn't
know that. That's a good book.
Paleo diet is all like vegetables. No
grains, no rice. Oh yes, that's good.
It's all things that are meat
and vegetables. You know,
things that people in the Paleolithic
would've eaten right before agriculture,
before hot dogs and shit.
Um, yeah, those, those uh, you
think that that's, I guess I'm, I'm,
I'm out of touch with what
the people want. Yeah.
I just a big fan of robots and,
and good CGI.
Yesterday's you're a big fan of frogs now.
Doesn't it look like good CGI in a
financial way of looking at this movie?
I think it's the most genius thing ever.
You're mixing like fighting
like UFC mixing it like robots.
Like it was generated by a computer
robots and fighting like the was a guy who
had guys down on his luck and then
the, you know. Yeah I see that too.
I mean, but I don't know. I think it's
a good idea for kid, for a kid movie.
I'm guessing that's what this is kind
of like a teenager movie is good.
You mean a movie? Cause that's their
all for fire off of these goddamn teens,
teens. Uh, no. I've said, I told somebody
that if the Godfather was released today,
Michael Corleone, a word,
a spandex suit, she on it
and drive a fucking buy like a Batmobile,
but it'd be like no,
be a cannoli movie.
Moly.
And he would sue the G on it.
Oh, how funny would that be if
somebody pitched that in the meeting?
I just think he's the best.
I just, everybody loves
him. He's number one. Right?
Right. Anyways, an outfit
that's different. He separates
him. Yeah. He puts it on.
He goes down, he fucks up and
know that they know who it is.
Um, wait, everybody's got a costume.
Just a costume that retarded
people can understand.
That's superman. You just go, oh
yeah, he's fucking, I'm retarded.
That definitely superman.
What is your take on this
fucking Spiderman thing that
they're doing in Broadway?
You know the, you know the whole
story behind this, the Spiderman play,
it's the biggest,
most expensive play they've ever
produced by far on Broadway.
And apparently it's a
fucking financial disaster
and people are dying. People are getting
heard of their fucking backs and shit.
I was,
if there was another accident,
I was gonna do a Twitter,
a tweet where I'm Spiderman himself
came out and condemn the music.
I was like, look, we've
got to stop as Spiderman.
Please give me a bad name.
That's funny. Yeah, no shit.
Does this the thing where
this is the guy's a hero.
He wants to save people and it's flooding
and it's just more people have been
injured then. Yeah. Then they've
killed more people in the Green Goblin.
Am I right? Yeah. I'm all right ladies.
They're flying around during
this broadcast, right?
They're only there during
this, uh, this performance
flounced around like they're on a Webinar,
they've reopened it.
They're trying to just read it, brought
the original director back. It's just,
it's like, hey, you just want
to say it. I'm like, Hey,
you guys know you don't have to do
this. You're going to stop. Right.
That is everybody. Like,
just maybe just stop.
It's hard though. Once you
commit to something, it's
pretty much over. You know,
it's very difficult to quit something
once you're rolling. Admit that
you know there's a, the term is motivated
reasoning where you just go, oh no, no,
it's good.
Yeah.
The whole reason you're saying is
because you want it to be good.
You also tell what people's pitch.
Oh yeah.
The worst is when you go to a table
reads and you hear the producers with the
fake laugh because yeah,
try not make sense. Is that
there's any, yeah. Anything Grocer.
It's a, it's, it makes you want to, it
makes you want to move to wherever I am,
right?
No, whatever the fuck I am.
The hills. If you want to,
you think stalkers
wouldn't even bother you,
would it to stock you out here
would take a lot of money.
You spend a lot of money on gas.
Getting down here,
nothing. I, I would be very
happy if I didn't have my,
a marital situation and children
be very happy living in the woods.
I would like it, but the, all the
people that I see when I do the UFC,
all the people that I see when I do
comedy shows and all the other bullshit,
I need the opposite. I need to, I need
a balance. I need to counterbalance that
documentary.
And in the shining a DVD,
there was a documentary that Kubrick's
wife made. No, it's excellent.
Like scat man Crothers is just
crying for no reason the best. Um,
but uh,
Jack Nicholson says in the documentary,
a famous person meets uh,
in uh,
in a month the same amount of people
that a non famous person meets in a
lifetime. It's true. Yeah.
Which is just about true.
Like just you have no capacity
to remember them anymore. It's a,
I get embarrassed sometimes
but not remembering people,
but it's a thing called Dunbar's number.
You literally only have running in
your burners hundred 52 plus, you know,
plus or minus.
But you know,
you only have room for that many
people in your brain and you know,
want every fucking weekend. I meet more
than that. Yeah. Every weekend at the UFC.
Well that was, I met Obama
at the, at like a month ago,
the on bin Ladin Eve cause my really,
yeah cause my buddy Seth Meyers hosted
the correspondence center and I wrote a
bunch of shift form. And so I was there
and I met Obama. And so that debt and,
and we had a really fucking
funny, cool exchange. Like,
like I said, uh, I, my
name's Neal Brennan,
I created Chappelle show cause I coker
British special cause I know Michelle was
a fan and he's like,
Oh man, we'd love that.
In fact it's got to be the greatest show
of all time or something. I was like,
man, how cool would it be if you could
get him to say I'm Rick James Bitch. Uh,
and uh, so he's like, Michelle,
this guy credit Chappelle show texture
has to have Michelle comes over.
And she's like, we were still upset when
it went off the air. And I was like,
how do you think I felt? And so, so, uh,
so then we have a exchange and I was like,
I'd said to Obama was like,
this is also odd man. I go, do you ever
get used to this? And he goes, nope.
And he goes, but I can't just
up and retire like Dave did.
Okay.
Really funny. That day he had
gone to Alabama to survey the,
the tornado.
He went to Cape Canaveral to,
they were going to launch something.
Gabby Giffords, the woman who got shot,
the senator guard, the congresswoman
who got shot was there, saw her,
gave a commencement address at
a Miami Dade Community College,
flies back to DC,
has to be personal and engaging with all
these hundreds of people are lined up
to get a picture with him and
then he's got to do standup also.
He's got a hit out on, been loud
that he knows. And the people like,
this guy's is too cool, easy to cool.
Would you want them like, oh my God,
fucking stressed out. Like he's
not, he's the right amount of cool.
And the fact that he knew
to be like, he, he'll,
he probably doesn't even remember
meeting me. I'll never forget it.
You know what I mean?
Like, and he knows that.
He knows that part of the
job is just performing. Uh,
the job of the president wears, you know,
you've got to perform Joe Rogan. Um,
no, but I'm sure there's a party
that you, you just want to go,
I don't give a fuck and walk
away, but you have to like, no,
it's part of your duties sometimes.
I don't think you asked.
I don't think that you're overwhelmed.
You get overwhelmed, but you Kinda,
you kinda can't,
it's part of life.
I would say that it just, people being
nice. You, it's what most of it is. It is.
Yeah. No, it really isn't. If you were
a hated person and that was going on,
imagine if you're, you know, Monica
Lewinsky or someone like that. You know,
where everybody's like goofing
on you or a Le Bron, you know,
everybody hates him now,
you know, any, any that's,
that's gotta be fucking really hard
to be a celebrity who's done something
really fucked up. I love, you know. Yeah.
Yeah.
It's gotta make you gotta fuck with you.
So what are you doing these days when,
when you have to,
uh, doing stand up and, um, you know what,
I'm going to start doing it as a,
I've been shooting cause I
like based on this paradigm,
I'm kind of into the idea of just auto
to do everything myself, put it out like,
and so I've just been shooting
some sketches. I haven't shot,
I haven't edited them yet, but I've
got a lot of sketch it. My brain is,
my brain kind of wasn't working
that well for like two, three years.
It was just a little sluggish.
It was like my hard drive was full and
I started taking this shit called five
HTP.
Yes.
And in sense that my brain
has just been like our fit.
How much milligrams of per day are you
taking? Do you have any idea? A hundred.
400, which is way too
many. Yeah. But I don't, I,
I've always suspected I didn't have
serotonin and this is serotonin. Um,
so since then I've just been
spending a lot on ideas for sketches,
for stand up, you know,
for jokes, for whatever.
And it's gratifying that I'm going
to try to do it kind of on my own.
Cause I don't know, you
know, people always say,
why don't you write for
this show or that show?
I'll write for sath cause
he's my friend and, and uh,
and I don't,
and I don't want to be on a show where
I can't control what's being selected.
Right.
So you don't want to do something on
the Internet where you can control ever.
Yeah.
Well I mean I can,
I could probably have a show somewhere
and control a lot of it, but I just,
I just want to stop
craving corporate approval.
I want to get past this idea of like
if you've been a benighted by Viacom or
whatever,
then you're more legit.
Cause that's the great thing about
Twitter and Facebook and all this stuff.
He's like, it takes them
out of it, you know? Uh,
so I'm going to just try to shoot some
sketches and, and do stand up and,
and I would love to be a standard. I would
love to like do what you do, you know,
obviously being,
doing the TV stuff greatly helped your,
your draw.
Yeah. It all helps. But this has
helped more than, than anything.
This podcast has been the biggest impact
on my stand up by far by a giant long
shot.
That's great.
I never have been able to sell things
out way in advance like this before.
And it's just from, from you feel like
people have a better understanding of you?
Yeah. In two things have happened. One,
I put out that comedy central special,
my last one talking monkey's in space,
which is a good,
it was one of my best ones.
It was a real representative of a real
set too because a lot of times you're
doing. And when did you release
it? Year and a half, two years ago.
Something like that.
Year and a half. And um,
when that came out it was
on comedy central, even less
like less than a year ago.
Um, that made a big difference
because people say, oh, but
the fucking knees actually got material.
It's actually funny. You know what,
this bill burr said,
Netflix has been big for him.
I have a one on Netflix as well.
My first one I did was on Netflix.
Netflix produced it in 2005
and then showtime bought it.
So it was on showtime in 2006.
But that wasn't as good as my talking
monkey's in space one. That's my best one.
Yeah. So I mean, so that would be,
I finally have, I could do an hour,
so I May, so that's when you're going
to do these music centers and you know,
clubs. I'm going to go out and
start doing an hour and, and then,
and then hopefully I'll, uh,
hopefully I can and I, you know, I,
I would also like to direct my own hour.
I think that would just be like a
Dickie, that'd be cool. Be Cool.
Like really cool. Yeah. Like,
cause I don't think anyone,
Louise probably done it.
Um, but uh, but yeah, I just, I'm
sort of like aspirational again.
I just want to take the all of like
the sort of corporate shit out of it.
Cause I just think it's,
it sets up a Shitty, yeah.
Like I don't want to shoot something.
And then someone got like, they,
the audience will may not see
this. And it's like, yeah,
but I shot it and it felt like me and
Doug did a pilot for showtime and it's not
bad like David off. Yeah. Uh, and it's,
it's all me and Doug do with thing.
This just if there's any comedians
listening to this is really helpful.
Once a week we have to write thousand
word essays and give them to each other.
Like, so we have gays. Fuck,
we have to. And so we have to,
uh, so it just helps writing,
right. Of course. As yourself. Uh, but
yeah, so just the idea that people aren't,
you read a book, you guys should both
go write a book and you know that the,
the essays that you write to each
other back and forth for a year,
that's a fucking great idea. 40
each other, they're just like about,
they're basically stand up.
It's just trying to flush them out.
But it's not like dove the fat
the past week with you has been,
I think we should start doing that.
You and me, we'll write to each other.
If you want to talk to each other, we can
make a podcast scared. Just scared of,
right.
I'm
scared to be judged. Uh,
yeah. So, so I, yeah,
just doing shit from the ground up
I guess. Cool. I mean, you know,
I don't really have, I'm doing a bunch
of dates, which are, I'll be posting.
What am I, what the fuck? I'm in
Chicago this weekend doing it.
I'm doing a show with George Lopez at
the Vic theater called Viva opening for
him. Viva Larissa? No, it's like
a heat. Everybody does like 20.
It's like four people do 20 minutes in
Emc. Really? Yeah. Called Viva Larissa.
What is it? Ah, they've done like
three of them. Are You Spanish? Well,
um, no, but I am a hard worker.
Uh, are you willing to get a
Tan? Uh, they, uh, no I don't.
It's just George. I think he just
sees it as like a way to, uh,
have people that he thinks are
funny to time and he MCS and,
and then I'm open for Seth,
uh,
on Seth Meyers.
I think that's at the,
that's somewhere in Chicago. It's so weird
that your friends, you look so similar.
I know it is fucking hot. Like people
think we're brothers from there. Um,
if we were brothers I
wouldn't speak to him. No,
it's a family joke. You guys get it.
So you've been through a lot of shit,
but it seems like you're having
a good time. Yeah, man. I mean,
sorry to blow your mix
up, but uh, but yeah,
like the Chevelle thing was not
easy on me. Like it was not,
I don't even think I realized it.
Like how sort of rough it was,
the disintegration cause it,
you know,
we were best friends for
like 12 years before that.
So would you ever come on Dr Phil and
maybe with him and to work it out? Yeah,
no, we've talked to Phil would
probably, oh no. Uh, Dr fell,
Drew's got a pro now. Me
and Dee ever cool? No.
So what happened with him on the
plane when he freaked out on the unit?
Any information about that?
Uh,
I was on a plane somewhere and they've
actually shortened the flight and landed
early because he was freaking out.
He told me that they were,
the pilot was fucking with them
and just being a dick for TMC.
I Dunno. For tms or like
they at TMZ was like their,
when they landed or something like
I dunno, that's what he told me.
I didn't like the pilot called
TMZ from the cockpit. No,
I don't. I honestly have no idea. That's,
he told me that the pilot was being a
dick and like fucking with them and like
doing this with the controllers or
something. Why? That's, I dunno.
That's what he told me.
And then when he got here I was saying,
I don't know if he's willing to wait
anymore. I don't, he might not. Yeah.
What exactly is that possible?
You mean not really. Yeah.
I can't even wrap my head around that.
How's it possible that he
wouldn't be smoking weed?
I know some people don't smoke weed.
Yeah. But when they smoke that much weed,
lot of theory about black weed smokers
in white weed smoker, which is,
I've never met a black burnout,
but yet like there's new,
like he like black hippies,
whereas white people can get
fucking completely burnt out.
I don't know what it is, but we
actually did like, uh, uh, uh, study.
We did a thing on Chappelle show words.
I think maybe the day you were there were
snoop got high with a bunch of people.
Uh, we, and we ran and snoop got
high and then a bunch of like,
our staff got high and we ran them
through a battery of tests because I just
have an idea that there is no such thing
as a black burnout cause snoop is a
sharp motherfucker. Dude, there's a lot of
smoke more weed.
He's gotta be in the top
thousand Americans in terms
of the amount of weeding
smoke that I've seen him smoke and
he's the smartest guy. I know, Bob.
I think it's on misconceptions,
man.
Smart Guy with weed is not
going to be a dumb guy.
It's going to be a smart guy was high
dumb guys on, we'd just get dumber.
They just have more enhanced right now.
They want to talk more about their stupid
ideas and they appear even more stupid.
But there's
plenty of black burnouts man. I know
a lot of them have that theory sucks.
I know a lot. Go to the hood.
There's a lot of black dudes smoking.
We'd sit on the porch. Do you want to do
shit? That lazy as fuck is a lot of them.
There's a lot of people
that are smoking weed.
They're lazy as fuck white or black,
you know,
they're just lazy fucking people that
they get high and they get even lazier,
you know? But you're a smart person.
Marijuana I think enhances you.
Uh, yeah. I mean I, I found
that it would not enhance me,
but I just didn't like it and get the
right shit. Nah. Was a diva. I like,
I like, uh, I personally like who I am.
Do you know the difference
between indicates the Tiva?
I like how you said that.
And with Joe on the end of it,
he made it a personal decision.
I made it a personal, I don't know
the difference. Oh, there you go.
The whole culture of it kind of bores me.
The culture is gross.
We talked about this yesterday with
Brian posts saying in the interest of
brevity again, the a, there's a huge
difference between indicative sativa.
Endeca is a really relaxed like couch.
Hi Macy,
right?
That's Endeca Sativa makes you want to
watch documentaries and stare at space
and looked through telescopes.
Right. It's a totally,
completely different
psychoactive experience.
Uh,
I may have never interacted with that.
Hi. Dot. Som. If you're mom tried
yet, I'll give you a road. She use it.
Use Your own discretion.
You don't want to be around me.
So, uh, yeah, never. I don't care to,
um, and uh, I'm trying
to think of what else.
Yeah, just outlook for me. I think I'm
doing in the next month and a half,
I'm doing Portland Doing
Columbus. I'm doing work. Can,
we'll find out about these dates. Uh, I
will post it on Twitter. And also there's,
I have a whosay page who say,
what does that say. Dot Com.
It's a page, you know, people don't
know this when you post shit to Twitter,
Twitter owns it. So if you don't
post it to somewhere originally,
if you post a picture, Twitter owns the
picture, they can sell it to someone.
Uh, so, uh, people set up
these whosay guys set up a,
a, uh, they're actually through
like ca, like the agency.
Like they set up a page where so that
ca clients can tweet shit and own it.
Um, cause there's gonna be a case
eventually where someone's going to go,
I that it was my property
and you've sold it. Um,
but it just hasn't come about
yet. Yeah. Uh, so, so yeah.
So who say dotcom slash Neal Brennan.
Okay.
And they can find you on Twitter and
Neal Brennan and e a L B r e n n.
A. N. And M two. Thank you very much
for coming on. There's a lot of fun.
It really wasn't a lot of fun and it was
a, it was a cool way back machine man.
Think about you at the Boston Comedy
Club in the village in the late eighties
were old people. Yeah, we
are now officially we have
gray pubes alright. Yeah.
Plenty of those. Actually I don't have
any grip cubes. I thought I saw one,
but I have some you can borrow on
the, uh, those drugs don't help.
That will be
a great views. Denied
everybody. Thank you very much.
It's a right now it's nine o'clock.
It,
it goes up online and say no, it'll
be out. Well, it's online already.
People have been watching it live.
You got to cut all that shit out of a day.
Thank you to the fleshlight.
Go to Joe rogan.net.
Click on the link for fleshlight
and enter in the code name Rogan,
and you will get 15% off the
number one sex toy for men. Um,
thank you very much to
everybody. Uh, June 25th,
Joe Diaz and I are going to be at the
Carnegie Music Hall in Carnegie Library
Music Hall in Pittsburgh.
Go to Joe Rogan. Dot. Now,
I don't remember all these dates.
And then July 1st we are also going to
be at the Mandalay Bay theater in Los
Vegas, Nevada. Shit's gonna get crazy son.
And Brian's going to be there to confirm.
We just got us tickets today.
So if you want him rape Brian,
that's the, that's the time.
And Joey Diaz and argues
your fear will be there.
So it'd be full desk squad event.
And that's it. Thank you very much.
We're trying to get
somebody else tomorrow. Uh,
someone very special and
don't know if it's gonna.
We're gonna be able to pull it off, but
we're going to get them sooner or later.
And then that's it.
And I love you bitches bought by big cast.