There we go.
Beautiful.
Ladies and Gentlemen,
welcome to day 25,
Brian,
25,
25 week,
week 25.
You stream podcasts.
We've got a double podcast week.
We're getting crazy.
Today is my good friend.
Mad Flavor,
Aka Joe t as in the motherfucking house,
one of the funniest human beings I've
ever met in my life.
I've known joey for about a decade.
Oh,
before we go anywhere before we get
started.
Fleshlight.com.
We are sponsored by the flashlights and
this is the butthole version of the
fleshlight.
It's sponsoring the podcast.
If you go to a Joe Rogan.net
and click the link,
you get like a discount.
Joey Diaz.
Have you ever seen one of those in
persona?
That little burp it up and explain it to
me.
They'll say,
let's talk about it.
This is the one that I haven't fucked so
you can touch it with your finger in
there and tell me that's the butthole
version.
Those the butthole.
Is there a vaginal birth yet so far is
really retarded.
How perverted either.
Could you imagine if the vaginal one
went out of style?
Because nobody wanted to fuck it.
It's like everyone's just wanted the
asshole.
Well it is tighter.
So you think everyone would want to fuck
because everyone likes tight pussy.
Fucking square.
It was a good big Scott to be like a
fucking square.
I love it.
This is tremendous.
You got to fuck one of these things I'm
telling.
Are you fucking crazy?
It's way better the beat.
Now if you bit off right?
So you grab it like this and just go
like this.
Like a little fish in the bucket.
Some fish in the bucket.
It's just take the piss out of the
bucket.
That's your move.
Dude.
I don't want to check this out.
How awesome is this fish in the bucket?
Look at that thing.
That's how you wash.
It pulls out it wiggles.
So you come in that thing and there's a
cap on the bottom.
When you undo the cap,
your load comes from.
I love hanging out with these guys
because technology,
they always keep me up.
This shit.
You know what I'm saying?
We're up to the latest.
This is the latest in masturbation.
Technical people hanging out with that
disappeared.
This is show up with a box with all of
the product.
There's a solid product and this product
comes under a lot of unnecessary heat,
in my opinion.
Now,
let me ask you,
what if you want to go the other way?
There's this come in different colors.
What if you want to fuck?
You know what I'm saying?
He had a brown one.
You get a Hindu one.
We've got to find that.
They got to.
Or a slum dog.
Millionaire.
One smells like a fucking lottery.
Tickets.
There's a difference.
A bunch of different colors there has.
We can't just be white.
That's prejudice.
There's 2010.
You got to mix it up a little bit.
Shit is this.
I mean,
yeah.
I guess I would do a black on her mother
as well.
One of the Asian one and what?
The little muffler.
Slowly twice cooked pork,
but there's a reason why like the black
ones show the cross.
How dirty it is.
More probably,
you know,
it gets white.
What's it going to say?
Black and she'd be a little too high.
What are you talking about?
Okay.
We're on the front page and I just see
nothing but white pussy.
Yeah,
let's
go with the champagne collection.
They have a loop,
a version of it.
You know who Lupez all white buzzy.
The Puerto Rican singer from the 17th.
No,
Lupa is this new porn star.
They have a loop,
a version of the flashlight,
and I was just at the hardrock x fans
convention and she was there.
Man,
that chick is amazing.
She's like four feet tall,
but yet the proportions perfect of a
regular female,
like everything's fits perfect.
This looks like a little girl now,
like a midget.
I wonder if you can get a blue one so
you can pretend you're fucking that
avatar.
They have vampires.
Vampire ones.
They should totally make it.
Twilight ones.
Do you say the twilight one?
Flesh lines.
They have things.
They swear to God.
They have fangs in the tube that goes
down that,
you know,
rubs against your Dick has like fangs on
the tube or something like that.
So it's like fucking a vampire pussy
because I know you'd like vampires
better than where it was.
Have you lost your fucking mind?
You.
You're so big.
That's 100 percent true.
All of that is that in Werewolf who
loves do you said you liked him last
week better,
right?
Goodness.
And I've been thinking about this whole
time because he likes making shit up.
Brian's,
you didn't say that.
You didn't say you were choosing just
back to the eighth grade silly eighth
grader right now.
Outside when you're not supposed to be
there.
Right.
You got out of the gymnasium when you
and your buddies got high and now you're
cracking jokes on them.
You're back in Columbus,
Ohio right now.
Wait,
wait,
wait.
What's going on here?
Your barbecue barbecued.
I know you are because I am and I'm
listening to you talk and I'm like,
this kid is too high.
I got to help him out of here.
I got to pull them out.
Pull out of this conversation.
But they do have a vampire fleshlight.
That's unbelievably ridiculous,
but I'm more of a Werewolf guy,
so that's why it's ridiculous.
I don't even like vampire really tired
of vampire movies.
The wolf man sucked.
Okay.
I did not like that movie.
It was dom just didn't work and I still
bought the fucking blue.
Right.
Okay.
How about that?
That's how much I am.
Uh,
was there any special features?
Search itunes for werewolf movies,
Bro.
Do you get this?
I watched werewolf movies that are
terrible.
You know why?
Because I know there's going to be at
least a guy's going to turn into a
werewolf and flux and people up.
So you know what I do?
I watched the beginning to get their
names.
Okay.
This is Bob.
This is.
Okay.
Let me just know what the fuck's going
on.
Let me fast forward until I see solar
turtle where all fucking the best latest
technology and the dude turned to
werewolf and just fucking people up is.
I just think those are the craziest
movies.
The idea that I show American Werewolf
in London got me hooked.
Yeah,
that was 1981 and I was aware will fan.
I was done,
but we still do other shit like Lon
Chaney member.
Like the problem with this wolf man
movie,
they went with a mask.
It's Benicia del Toro and a mask and
he's like,
and his lower jaw sticks.
I show the transformation with the arms
and the fucking thing,
you know,
they do.
I mean there's a lot of,
a lot of cool.
There's a lot of cool CGI in the
transformation,
but the final product just looks.
It just doesn't look right because it's
like he tried to use the old wolf man
from like the 19 forties or whatever the
fuck it was.
He was at Claude rains,
I think it was,
to try to use that version of the wolf
man and just make a more modern,
updated look after you go to American
Werewolf in London,
you can't go backwards.
You can't because American Werewolf in
London,
that fucking thing was evil man.
It was like a dog person.
Demon thing was on a four legs because
that I'm blurring just for cats on Blu
Ray.
I got that Shit's on.
And like when they're running from it
and you just see it,
they did that movie so well.
You don't really get to see it that much
because the technology was not that
good.
The only one time you get to actually
see the Werewolf,
he's going through the streets of
London,
snap and people's heads off from
everyone who was running through the
streets.
Nobody's freaking out and car accidents
and shit.
That's the only time you get to see it
moving around every other time in the
movie.
It's like you're barely see it,
but you see it enough that it's fucking
terrifying.
And the transformation scene just off
the chain,
you know,
that's the kind of shit that we had in
1981.
Okay.
Now what do they have?
They have vampires that don't bite
people and where to just growl at
everybody and can change back and forth
when they want.
What the fuck have we come to the fuck
are we?
Tell them to joey,
bro.
I can't even.
I've never watched the twilight's,
but I've seen what those two little
fucking half a fruit cakes look like.
I can't believe they're vampires.
Vampires are bad.
Motherfucker bottom.
His College.
That's a vampire shadows and you know
when you were vampire,
you fuck guys,
you fuck chicks.
It don't matter.
You Ain't gay.
You just slinked Dick,
you fucking dogs.
It don't matter.
You a fucking animal.
You know what I'm saying right now,
Gary Oldman,
Gary,
get the fuck these vampires a tool.
I don't know how to say it.
The to me,
it's Disney.
It's.
We've got a whole group of kids now that
are growing up with horrible mediocre
entertainment that's designed just for
them as opposed to when we were kids
were so fucking kids shows you add
sesame street,
you know,
you had a,
a fucking,
a couple other different shows,
you know,
that you could wash it,
but like kid oriented shows and
everything else was a fucking adult
show.
But the only kid show I ever watched was
Betty Hill,
like a motherfucker.
Anyway,
that was a kid.
I was really fucking great.
Every once in a while they show you a
tinder or a great point.
You were six.
You last for a week.
He was like the first guy to figure out
that very simple combination.
Tits,
tits,
tits and comedy and silliness and,
and started the accident way before
gender.
Massada high.
The linguistic.
The answer the phone.
Unless people do make you think that
shit is legit,
Susan,
for those late night infomercials.
So as an English person describing some
products like God,
people pay more attention.
They think they're cooler or something.
When you meet a chick that has an accent
from over there,
I don't know,
but it makes her like two levels hotter.
Know you think,
well you know English dude.
Say that to Dave Bishop says out of
American girl,
that American accent,
he said he just so hot.
Damn.
I'm your soulmate dexter.
Yeah.
There's an English chicken,
Chinese chicken.
The why would have English accent.
Oh,
you talked to her.
You lose your fucking.
Yeah.
You might want to take a yoga class that
check.
Yeah.
No,
she's a very nice.
That's a strong.
That's a strong combo right there.
That's a double exotic.
You know,
that's a proper exotic and another
exotic on top of that.
Oh,
you got to hear him.
But a strong one too,
you know,
look like a fucking guy in the life up.
You know what I'm saying?
Shit like that breaks up with you and
starts fucking some new guy.
And you know what kind of pussy she's
slinging at him.
You know what kind of crazy shit she's
doing to him.
You know,
she said to put it in my ass saying
crazy shit with that English accents to
fuck you up.
People worshiped him saying you can't
eat Chinese food or watch fucking
beverly hills.
No more flashbacks.
It's horrible for her.
Favorite Shit.
She links to get fucked in the mouth.
My mouth.
Was He hard competition?
Was he hard competition you have.
Is that the American version of Benny
Hill?
Because it seems like it's a TV show
was.
It was a variety show country.
They used to have like songs.
They would play songs.
They would do like sketches.
Listen,
it was a dumb ass show,
but when I was a kid I enjoyed it.
I used to go there for boobs also.
I remember Benny Hill and he hollered my
to like,
I'll watch that.
He will have cleavage.
Yeah.
They had the blogs with Benny Hill would
show you it as something and they
wouldn't catch it on channel nine and
those days.
So he got away with murder.
You know what?
I'm saying Benny Hill was the first guy
to have like a real silly showing him
chasing after girls and you know,
that famous song that they use all
fucking stressed as hard on this country
has forgotten about the heart on.
No fucking respect to the heart on your
right.
Benny Hill always.
That's because there's too many people.
Do you think that when when there gets
overpopulation naturally people get more
reluctant to hide shit like that.
We took,
we disregarded the heartland because
they got cialis.
No it shouldn't.
Nobody would fucking beverly hills.
So they're just too common.
The hard ons to common now because of
big,
because of a dick pills don't matter.
I see.
In the old days it was a big deal.
It was a big deal because you can take
fucking pills.
You know what I'm saying?
Like the old days,
a 62 year old guy that had a harder and
it was like,
wow,
that guy is excited.
Whoa.
Get Him.
He's got a boner and 62.
What'd you now?
It's like,
oh,
that'll creep.
He's on fucking Viagra.
Look at them.
Have you done any research on these GNC
versions of Viagra that,
that,
that are big right now?
They're almost like,
you know,
there's just a bunch of vitamins and
stuff like that.
Flashlight was telling us about that.
Telling us about one that works,
the one that actually had vicodin Viken
invite Viagra in it as a good 30 percent
of.
It was weird to me because I wonder why
it works.
They of course they had a booth like
that at that.
This x fans party I went to and the guys
were selling it and was like,
I'm no doctor.
I'm like,
yeah,
what's in this?
And I was looking through it and it was
probably 300 different
routes in like fucking bird tiers in
Agora Shit that works,
you know,
because all those routes and shared
those aren't going to work on a 60 year
old dick.
You know,
all you know,
taking your fucking Gingko Biloba.
That's not going to give you a boner
when you're 80,
you know.
But viagara will fucking rocket via
grower will rock it.
Ever taken phrase 72 when he tells me
the stories,
how he's banging this shit out of
fucking stays home Sunday through.
He walks a refund park every morning for
miles that he goes home,
eats Viagara,
buxom chick the debt.
Wow.
That's like a 30 year old chicken.
He was driving.
He goes back and remember Brian Holtzman
rubbed by Agra because now these young
girls that go out with these old rich
guys,
they have to fuck them now for that
video and his load,
his load.
It's like paint that's been sitting in
your basement for a year.
It's not a fresh product.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Remember that?
Remember that bit?
Brian Holtzman,
ladies and gentlemen is probably one of
the funniest guys that unfortunately
you're not going to hear up.
Are you not going to see on TV?
You're not going to see them as special.
I hope you do.
Unless you get it at the comedy store.
Does he still even go there?
I heard factory.
Unless it gives you a ticket with a
little beach,
right?
Fucking guy that was in a parking meter.
Maid combination dog catcher.
Which.
How funny is he is a fucking dog.
He's a goddamn reality show waiting to
happen.
Someone follow him around.
He's the meter man dog catcher and he's
Brian Holtzman,
one of the funniest comics streak,
and you give him a fucking a camera in
front of him and Mike and mom.
That's a great reality.
Show somebody out there act on this.
Can you get ahold of Brian Haltzman?
But Brian ultimate is like,
well,
there's only a few guys like that that
you meet in your life.
And you go,
Oh man,
this motherfucker like what?
What happened?
Like,
why didn't,
why didn't anybody see this?
Why he's so good.
Why doesn't anybody see that?
You know,
like brody Stevens is another one.
Brody's got some stuff going on.
He was in the hangover and you know,
he's got good friends that are really
funny.
Guys respect him,
but fruit is should be a national
headliner.
He should be fucking killing it all over
the country.
People should be like buying tickets to
see him in advance and looking forward
to getting fired up at Brody's in town.
But you know what,
the weird thing about brody Stevens,
I almost don't want him to get that
famous because I love just watching
Chelsea lately and seen like
miscellaneous parts in the movie,
the hangover and stuff like that.
It's like kind of like a hidden game.
Like find brody Stevens out of nowhere.
No,
no,
no.
I know.
I obviously,
I don't mean to,
it's kind of Nice.
Kind of cool.
Only knowing who he is at the store
lately.
He hasn't been getting spots when we get
the man show.
Brody was the warmup guy and his warmups
were so fucking funny.
You can tell the same joke 10 times in a
row and I,
I'll ask for it,
you know,
I'll keep you on out.
Did you do any modeling?
And it'll,
it'll do his whole fucking.
That whole piece that he doesn't bottle
in Beirut,
Pakistan on the cover of camel beach.
Enjoy it.
What's ready?
Stevens at twitter name.
We just throwing that out.
Brody's.
Brody's friends.
Yeah.
I'm brody's brody's friend.
Follow this guy.
This guy is quite the,
but he's a fucking great human being.
At least like six in the morning and he
has the cutest dog that has the most
human face I've ever seen in my life or
this is so hilarious.
Let me go back to Seattle with brody
brody when they used to drive his car to
the Gig harbor and he used to cry that
was speeding in this car.
Tell us a classic brody story.
We put them in the truck and drove to
Gig harbor.
He told me they would take them two
hours and I said,
I'll bet you any amount of money I could
do it.
Not when.
He's like,
no you can't.
And we put them in the backseat with
soundgarden blast and they kept saying,
global people don't live like this.
I'm doing fucking right hand lane,
cutting off.
He's like,
Stop Joe Diaz.
I would not want to be in the car with
you.
Reckless driving.
If I was high,
that's tonight.
He stopped the show because there was a
bunch of head shots on the wall and he
stopped the show because there was no
Jews on the wall.
Not One fucking jewelry.
That black people,
you got white people.
Whereas the Jews,
next time I come here,
I want a Jew on the wall.
Brody gets these bad late nights spots
or at least he used to at the store and
you know,
sometimes he'd get up there and the
crowd would be dead.
There'd be no one left,
like,
you know,
the show starts at 8:00
at night or something like that.
And Brody would be on like after 1:00
AM 1:45
or something like that.
He'd go on and he would just start
playing the drums.
He would pull chairs up and pull out as
drumsticks and start playing the drums
and just start ad libbing and fucking
around.
And before,
you know,
you had a fucking show showed there was
eight people there,
but that,
that was all rock and eight,
you know.
And that's,
that's one thing that,
that creepy place was the best best
giving you those little tiny ass crowds,
those tiny ass crowds where there was no
one in the audience and people barely
paying attention.
But every now and then someone would go
up and just do something magical in that
zero crowd.
Eight people was all I needed.
Let me tell you,
let me tell the story about you.
Joey Diaz.
One night we were at the comedy store
and it's one of those nights where it
was just,
it was kind of dead.
It was it a Sunday that when you went
to,
when you get onstage and you were doing
the [inaudible] while I was a Saturday
and the mainland and it was late at
night.
There was nobody.
This is the early day.
There was the comedy store.
Went through some dark periods where we
got real bad crowds for a long time,
you know,
and this was.
This was like pre fear factor,
right?
This was a long time ago.
Yeah,
between this fact.
Okay.
So.
So it's one of these late nights and
there's only maybe like fucking
literally like five audience members
left in this main room and joey goes
onstage and Joe,
he tells him to put up with at Wartburg,
tells him and he fucking
cranks war pig and Joey fucking sings
along,
takes his shirt off and screaming into
the microphone on key with every lyric
and the place goes fucking bananas.
And Bananas.
I had to say it there because that's
what it was.
Everybody was going nuts.
Everybody came in from the fucking
kitchen.
All the comics that were still left in
the.
Our came in to talk to you in the
parking lot.
Came in by the time joey was offstage,
it went from 10 people to the only 30
people that were in the whole fucking
building.
And we were just clapping and laughing.
It was like,
there's these magical moments where,
you know,
a dude just hit some rare place on stage
where he's just free as fuck.
And that place,
that place at the comedy store.
There was so many of those moments.
When did you,
when you did it,
it was,
it was such the moment.
It was so real because there was no one
there,
there was no one there.
It wasn't like you could see large
audiences.
Sometimes you can trick them,
you can sing,
you know,
and sound like fucking,
some other singer and they,
they clap and they love you.
And in the end they give you a big
standing ovation.
But it's really a bunch of dumb shit,
you know,
you've just entertained them
sufficiently,
but you're not going to get that kind of
response at all.
Like five people when there's only five
people there.
You've got to give them some real shit.
It's gonna to come from some crazy place
inside you when there's like five or six
people.
There can be no fat in your act.
That's where your jokes sounds so gross
and jokey.
They like all the unnecessary parts.
Your Act,
they just seemed so stupid because now
you're only talking to a few people.
It teaches you.
That's one thing I give the comedy
store.
I'll never take away from the comedy
I never hit magical moments like that in
another club.
The original room and the main room
emphasis on the original room after
midnight,
see a lot of comments.
She'll talk like I'm getting for 15
spots.
Little do you know for a guy like me at
1215 spot is a gold because I go in
there and do what the fuck I want to do.
Which is really what comedy really isn't
a way.
You know?
It's unprepared.
You go in there,
if you go up there with three of your
jokes about me and my girlfriend broke
up,
it's going to be a long,
15 minutes,
you know that,
and that's what the comedy store pull
data.
You pulled that out to entertain for.
I love going up and that'd be four
people.
That's my world.
That's my fucking world.
Five hundred.
That's my world for five people on
Tuesday nights,
somewhere at the sentence.
That's as fun as it gets.
Start laughing and rocking.
It's so genuine.
You know?
Those moments are so genuine.
It's so.
There's no fat,
no small crowds,
man.
It's a totally different style of comedy
and that's something I realized when I
started doing larger venues.
Sometimes it's harder sometimes to get
you to be like one-on-one reel with a
large venue because like you don't want
to give them too much,
like dead air taught him.
You don't want to give them too much
time to contemplate.
There's too many people.
It's just too hard to control all of
them anyway.
It's more,
it becomes more of like a show.
Whereas like if you're doing it for like
just a few people,
there's something fucking crazy about
that man.
Every is dangerfield story where we did
call me like four different guys did
comedy for two people.
We were at dangerfield show as part
started,
like,
you know,
8:00
or something like that.
My spot was at like 9:30.
I got there at 9:00
and everybody's just waiting in the bar.
I'm like,
what's going on?
Like,
no one's here.
No one,
no one,
no crowd at all.
Nothing.
So what do we do?
We leave now.
We're gonna wait for people to show up,
see if nobody shows up.
So we went,
okay.
And were there for maybe 15 minutes and
a couple walks in.
And now there was a guy bobby who was
the dorm and this big fucking
powerlifting,
Scottish guy.
He was this guy who used to do power
lifting with fucking bags of cement.
He would take bags of cement and pour
them into those big white plastic
buckets and do fucking power lifting
with them.
I mean,
it's just just,
uh,
a gorilla,
just a gorilla of a man in a crazy sense
of humor.
So the people who've probably way
funnier than 99 percent of the comedians
that ever worked at Dangerfield funnier
than me when I was a kid for sure.
I was like,
how come this guy is the doorman?
He's fucking hilarious.
And um,
you know,
some Dildo to do stand up without a view
of the world yet,
you know,
and,
and I'm,
I'm the one on stage.
So anyway,
the,
the couple walks in and he goes,
come back this way,
ladies and gentleman shows up to stop,
you know,
it's crazy.
Scottish accent.
It's terrible impression of him by the
way,
pulls them down.
System down to people like sitting in
this room,
like we're by ourselves.
What's going on?
Ladies and gentlemen?
Welcome that danger fields,
please welcome your host.
And whoever the fuck the host and the
host goes out there by himself and he
does stand up for this couple and he
does like 20 minutes and then he brings
on the next act.
The next act is a half an hour.
Then it brings up the next act and he
doesn't half an hour and then they
brought on me and I did a half an hour
and I brought on until all these fucking
people sat there and watched a whole
comedy show,
just two people and they sat through the
whole thing.
They probably felt trapped,
but they probably had a blast too.
They had a blast event from a different.
There was some good comics.
There were some good comics that night.
Danger fields was a good place to work
out.
It's very similar to the comedy store
and nobody was there that was going to
watch you.
There was no industry people there.
You know,
danger fields is not where you're gonna
meet your manager or your agent.
It's just weird little club that only
the comics like because in a place like
the comedy store,
the good thing about like a lot of
people like,
well,
industry won't come to the comedy store.
I'm like,
well you don't.
You don't get this kind of a club.
This kind of an atmosphere.
If the agencies want to come here,
they don't want to come to this kind of
place.
They want to come to the kind of place
where they're taken care of.
It's very professional and the manager
takes care of their tab and seats them
and shake their hand and kiss their ass.
The comedy store never gave a fuck about
the agents.
They don't give a fuck about you.
You don't even get free tickets.
Fuck you.
And the only way they get free tickets
have you call in.
You say,
Hey,
I need two tickets from my agent.
Then the agent gets free tickets.
If the agents on his own,
he's fucked.
You know you're going to have to pay
costs 20 bucks and this guy over here,
he's going to take your money.
They,
they don't do that in other clubs,
but because of that,
that place was just this place where you
just saw wild shit.
I saw your deck there at least 100
times.
There was at least a hundred times with
Joe.
He pulled his dick out as,
this is the way I got to tell this.
The first time,
girl,
what's her?
That's
what the fuck's her name?
A female comic or the one that sued on
barrel name?
Judy.
Judy can see it.
Okay,
so this is what happens.
She goes on to state,
we shouldn't have said her name.
She goes onstage.
So she's.
She's on stage and she's not doing very
well and we're all barbecued.
We're high as fuck.
It's eight people.
It's a Monday night,
Monday night know there's nobody there.
There's no one there.
It was a small crowd.
So she's on stage.
Joey goes into the back area.
There's like this backstage area that's
like in the or the or is a small room.
It only seats about a buck 50,
but it does have a stage with a little
backstage area.
So Joey goes into the back stair,
Jj area.
He goes to the backstage area.
It takes off all his clothes and he
waits and so she's doing her act and
when she gets to her punchlines,
she hits the punchline and Joey opens
the curtains and shakes his dick and
then closes them up real quick and the
people go crazy and you see this spark
in her eye like working.
I can finally doing it.
Oh my God.
Now I see what it's like.
I could do it all.
You could see her loosen up and get
confident.
You could see her relax and every time
she had a punchline,
joy would pop up in their current shakes
closer and the people were fucking just
stopping their feet laughing,
slapping their tables.
She'd never did know that you did that.
If she ever knew she never needed them,
we couldn't break her heart.
She thought that she was on the phone.
She had so much confidence.
The next time you remember the last,
the next time we saw her on stage at the
same jokes,
just just didn't,
didn't work.
It was like the same day she had the
magic that she had for one night and she
didn't even know.
I wonder if she's like,
thinking back to what she ate that
night.
Like I got to eat the same food everyday
and she's been eating Heiko Baloney
sandwiches for the last 20 years.
It's hard to talk shit about any booze
now.
Funny because nobody's fighting in the
beginning.
You know?
It's like how come some people figure
out how to be funny and some people
don't.
I mean,
funny is a strange thing.
There's some folks that,
you know,
they might be intelligent,
they might be cooled and met with.
There's something about them that's just
not funny,
you know?
And it's just that no matter how hard
they try for whatever reason,
it just doesn't seem to connect with.
I know guys who have been open Micros
for 20 years.
Right.
You know those guys.
Yeah,
they're happy.
They're,
some of them,
some of them still can't figure out what
the fuck it is,
you know,
it's been falling like really weird
people on twitter.
Lately I've been falling Dexter's,
uh,
ex wife or I guess wife.
No,
spoiler alert.
But you know,
the main girl from Dexter on twitter.
It is so weird to follow somebody that
you know was supposed to be dead or
something or that's supposed to be like,
oh my God,
it's going to be following our dexter is
going to get pissed.
You know what he did to the neighbor,
you know,
but you know about that dude that Donnie
was dexter that dude up in British
Columbia.
Really?
But wait,
wait,
I haven't heard this giant crazy dexter
fan and winded up committing a murder
and getting caught for it.
I do feel like after watching that show
so much that I find myself doing things
like,
you know,
uh,
like I'm always thinking twice,
like,
what would my dad do?
You know?
I'm like,
wait a second,
I'm not,
I'm just getting the mail you episodes
on a fucking lie.
One shot stone.
That's psychologically,
that's a dark show.
Well,
it's kind of Kinda weird.
Good though,
Huh?
The first season and now I can talk
about it.
Uh,
I thought that John Lift goes season was
the best season.
Okay.
Maybe it was.
I mean,
when I said it was only based on the
very first episode that I saw,
granted I was getting a little tired of
the whole.
Every week somebody gets murdered,
thing for whatever is a formula to it
that if you get caught with 20 minutes
late,
20 minutes left in the show,
who's going to kill?
Well,
you know,
I tell you what,
that whole,
the smiths,
third season,
whatever his name is,
Jimmy Smith or whatever his name is,
Don thought that was the worst season.
I hated that.
So yeah,
I did not like that season in mind.
It wasn't the best.
The best season was the first one.
The first one was,
first of all,
the first one was a motherfucker because
I understand the guy got sick and you
know,
and he had some health problems,
but the first one he looked like a
killer.
Like he was built.
I didn't buy him when he lost all that
muscle.
I mean,
I know it sounds silly,
but I just,
I'm like your Jujitsu and people and you
look like a skinny athletic.
I never even thought he had muscle to
begin with.
If you look at the first one,
you know what it looks like to me,
like there's dudes that you go to
Jujitsu with and you see him and they're
like purple belts or something like
that,
and you look at me like this fucking guy
is going to be a pain in the ass.
It's going to be hard to roll with this.
It's got like a big neck,
strong shoulders.
I'm like,
this is going to be a battle.
You just look at them.
That's kind of what he looked like in
the first season.
It looked like a dude who's like a
sturdy dude,
you know?
I bought that.
He was like this killer that he made him
look just a little more sinister.
Even though he was polite.
He looked so much like a victim yet,
but maybe that's why they picked
Jonathan Lithgo because they're like,
oh,
he could be him.
Here's my problem and this is.
I mean,
granted,
I'm a commentator for fucking cage
fighting,
but when John Lithgo caught her in that
weak ass rear naked choke,
I was like,
you ain't cook put.
Nobody's hit that bitch.
You knew.
It's so funny and in the fucking chick
with a bronc people bought,
they don't just lay there and accept the
fact you're choking him.
I try not.
Let me tell you something.
My daughter who she's just fucking to.
Okay,
she's 30 pounds.
She had something stuck in her nose last
night.
All right,
and it was a.
She shed a little Barbie doll shoe and
she fucking shove it up her nose and it
was like upper nose and she was pulling
at it and I had a hold her down and get
it out of her nose and do.
She's fucking 30 pounds and she's
screaming and freaking and kick in and I
can barely get a hold of her nose and
hold her little tiny head to pull this
thing out there.
John with NGOs.
Got some woman,
a grown ass woman who knows some crazy
man's about to fuck her dead body and
she's just going to go,
oh my God,
you're putting me to sleep.
Shut the fuck up,
right?
Take that crap.
The actor have grabbed the act and just
hold them down.
Just start smacking him in the face.
Get up,
get up,
have them fucking freak out
thinking you're gonna.
Die Like you.
You might die in this.
I might not ever let you up you.
Fuck,
I might just beat the fuck out of you to
death right here.
And there's nothing you can do about it.
But that's how you feel when someone is
choking you to death in a bathtub.
You don't just always got me.
That was stupid.
You know what though is like,
it's so funny because while I'm watching
it doing John Lithgo doing these moves
and stuff,
I'm like thinking of you watching this
and they're like,
ah,
you know,
Joseph's getting pissed right now.
No,
but we're so pleased that you get so mad
about just the,
that the choke.
But I can't buy that fucking cell phone.
It looks like it was made in paintbrush,
you know,
like incoming call.
Where are you at when you look at the
graphics?
You know,
there's no fried.
Makes that crap.
So tech cell tech is not a real phone
company.
That's hilarious.
I just,
you know,
to me that that scene where he kills a
woman,
the tub is just as unrealistic as spock
grabbing people by the neck and putting
them asleep.
That's just just like a Ninja deft touch
to me.
People freaked the fuck out when you're
choking them.
Okay.
They hyperventilate.
They kick,
they spazz.
That's a,
that's made by someone who's never seen
anybody get choked and the guy was doing
it to never choked anybody and there was
no girls.
Never been a show that nobody should
have been freaking the fuck out.
You don't just choke someone like that.
They go crazy,
right?
I try to survive.
You're gonna fucking bathtub with a
naked old dude is behind you and you
just kinda just.
You would bite that motherfucker.
You'd be fighting for your life.
At that point.
I would be more believable that he would
move his blood samples out of the air
conditioning unit.
After the first,
second,
third,
or fourth time,
the.
I'm thinking more of Shit like that.
I'm like,
come on,
you take your fucking blood samples that
you put underneath the toilet or
something like that.
Little thing that evidence the little
thing that he,
you know,
the trophies didn't need that,
but I guess that's a thing that serial
killers do though,
right?
Yeah,
I agree.
But you know,
I look at a show like that,
but then your last week Eddie said that
he liked trueblood and and I just get so
angry.
I've been fighting people off twitter
all week about true blood lovers.
Another goddamn vampire show.
How many vampire shows are there now?
There's a new one.
Nigga.
What the fuck?
What happened to the black shirt with
the fucking thing?
What happened to the thing that they
hypnotize you with that just fuck all
evolved.
That it.
No Gate and no nothing.
They show up with that.
Robert Patterson looks like he's been
getting punched in the nose.
The other fucking kid and the chicken.
I don't know.
Even play the vampire.
Fucking go there.
I don't go halfway there.
My wife watches true.
What?
I leave the fucking house.
You understand me on Sunday nights?
I don't like that shit.
I don't know where it came from.
It just snuck up on us,
like fucking brings you out of a swarm
of vampire show.
No show.
Everybody's got a show about the and I
don't listen,
but I don't know.
There's.
What's that other popular show with kids
right now?
There's another vampire show,
vampire diaries,
her diaries.
That one.
What the fuck?
Then there's another one that's just
about to start.
That's brand new.
That's coming out soon.
Can you have too many fucking vet?
Will there be a bounce back?
Can we expect?
I don't know because there's people in
the chat room.
They're saying,
dude,
true blood is legit.
You know,
they just don't get what I'm talking
about.
Just the fact that there's a chat room
of people talking about right there that
destroys my life is too God damn easy.
People are soft as fuck.
They are soft.
Some are people are fucking soft and
they're not even interesting.
Fucking vampires.
That's safety.
They have no character.
Well,
they don't have anybody.
They live off La Luis,
the twilight ones.
He lives off animals and he can go
outside in the daytime.
What?
You knew,
what they've done.
They've pretty much taken this soap
opera,
a dying thing.
They've taken off the evil guy with the
patch,
made him a vampire and that's what the
shows you guys are watching his fucking
soap operas with Vampires.
So guys,
I'm not gonna lie to you.
What?
I bought the fucking movie with Wesley
Snipes.
Spade a spade a spade.
Limited speed.
Wasn't a name for a black guy.
Wouldn't be nearly as where he met with
the Chinese people.
I bought that shit.
I was like those Chinese.
Oh,
a huge bleed.
I was a big blow.
I love as a kid,
but that's it.
That's where it ends.
I don't want to see all this new shit.
Guys were arrested in hand.
True blood that a vampire.
That's bullshit.
I don't like.
That shit scares me.
I don't fuck me.
I was a kid.
Yeah.
Glade was my.
One of my favorite comic book
characters.
That was a bad.
It was black and he used to have little
knives made out of teak wood.
He would kill people with teeth because
they were all vampires would kill them
with wood.
So we had wood knives made out of is
really hard.
I love that.
Everything else I got to tell you guys,
I don't even go and fucking put this
shit on.
They change so much about the whole
vampire lore.
I mean the whole thing.
What the fuck happened to Transylvanian
out Seattle now?
But I want to see where the fuck the APP
for the iphone is.
The fucking Transylvania.
When I was a kid,
you want to see a vampire?
We to go to transport rating.
Now they don't even talk about fucking
Transylvania just disappeared.
Go look it up.
Fucking Transylvania.
What the fuck is it's people like they
had an accent and shit like that where
they'll from Bulgaria.
All of a sudden now they're fucking
Spanish.
So if I was a smart man,
everyone should like bet money.
What the next monster is going to be.
You know,
it's like it's not going to be vampires.
What's the next thing?
And Big Foot's going to come back and
make a comeback or.
So there's another
vampire thing by Google Eramo del Toro.
I don't know how to say his name,
how you say his name is Guillermo del
Toro.
He wrote a book called the strain and I
saw,
I read the book.
It wasn't that good.
It started off really good.
It started off like,
wow,
this is a crazy ass vampire movie.
Like this is like really suspenseful.
But then towards the end it was almost
like he was just trying to finish it.
It's like,
you know,
and then the guy jumps out of the car,
the guy killed him.
It was like,
it was really bad.
The end towards the end,
like it's almost like he was trying to
jam a six series book or a two or three
series book rather into one book.
So
it,
it dies,
but they're,
they're going to do something with that.
They're going to make that some sort of
a big event,
but at least he's a murderous evil
fucking vampire.
And He.
And then he runs,
you know,
like takes over New York City.
It's pretty crazy shit,
but it just ends bad and maybe if they
can fix the ending,
but the in the writing in the script and
it maybe it was creatively directed and
they did a good job with it,
but the writing was just.
It was kind of clumsy at the end,
but what?
What?
What is it about people that are fucking
obsessed with vampires and all the
animal,
all monsters,
all the things to be worried about in
the world.
Why would it be vampire?
It's none of the obsessed.
It's the hot thing right now.
In two years,
this vampire then will be gone.
Twilight.
Those two fucking half of fags will be
dead somewhere.
I'm telling you,
I think it's going to keep going.
You know why I think it's going to keep
going.
Sex in the city.
I didn't understand sex and the city.
I couldn't believe that.
I mean,
I watched it a couple times.
I'm like,
yeah,
it's kind of a cool show,
but it's not just that people like it,
but they go fucking crazy for it.
Grills,
they respond to it like it.
It resonates in them in a way that a guy
can understand,
you know,
took out like Uri,
you watching.
Oh,
that's funny.
Show.
But to them it's like a movement.
It's like something that validates them.
Like this fucking movie.
The,
the last one,
when they went to Dubai,
I saw more people get fired up about
going to city.
No,
you sought though,
right?
We talked about.
That was a terrible bad.
It wasn't bad.
The first one on cable when the second
one came,
I was in the hotel room.
You know,
it wasn't back.
I think with that is when we talked
about it for two hours.
That's the kind of resonating to
entertainment for women.
Okay.
That twilight is for like young girls
and young girls.
Young girls were in their thirties or
forties or there's a romantic aspect to
the vampires that,
you know,
there's something in the writing.
Know how we can do it.
We can.
We can kill vampires today guys.
We make a movie about vampires that
cheat guys.
Empires are cheaters.
That'll be an asshole.
I don't.
I never watch TV and they suck.
What is,
what is the suck blood?
What the whole thing of of twilight.
I don't say this,
there's a family of vampires and they
try not to eat people because they're
nice,
but why are the women in love with them
is because they're super.
He's super romantic.
Like the read the book is all about him
being.
He's really romantic.
You know?
He's this guy that lived hundreds of
years ago.
Meanwhile he's a fucking Pedo is banging
some high school chick.
How the whole thing is kind of creepy
when you think about it.
I mean the guy's fucking 300 years old
and he's hanging out with some 17 year
old trick.
What the fuck do you have to say to a
chick was 17 when you're 300 chicken.
That movie.
What I'm saying?
I think that the biggest problem that
does movies,
it's the chick though.
She chose somebody that's dead instead
of somebody that just turns into a dog
once in a while,
but he's alive.
Can you imagine that chick was trying to
talk to you about some stupid new song
that was out like,
oh my God,
I love this song.
He'd be like,
bitch,
I was around when they didn't have cars.
Do you understand that?
There was no photographs when I was
born.
How the fuck yeah,
we used,
we used to find a way across oceans by
staring at the stars.
What do you want to talk to me about?
You stupid.
Fuck.
He would just kill her in either.
He wouldn't be able to take that
bullshit.
Three hundred year old man talking to a
17 year old girl.
Can.
You're 44 years old.
Can you talk to a 17 year old fuck.
You could talk to her like she's a nice
kid.
Like,
so what do you want to do when you get
out of college?
So what are you thinking about?
That sounds cool.
Oh Wow.
That's a child.
This guys banging her.
This is a stupid ass fucking movie.
It's the premise is absolutely
completely ridiculous.
It would've been way better if it was a
grown woman like in her twenties or
thirties or something.
Gets divorced,
branches out our own meats,
a vampire falls in love that would work.
Just fucking high school check.
He's going to high school and he's
banging a 17 year old and no one thinks
that's crazy about the fact that he's
evil.
He's interested in her.
She's fascinating to him.
It's a fucking baby.
It's a baby.
Imagine how young 17 year old girl is to
you.
Your 44.
What the fuck would it be if you were
300?
You know,
I mean look like if I was 300 that
motherfucking could speak Latin and he's
talking to the interviewer 300 years
old,
you'd be fucking black chicks by then.
You know,
you'd be done with the white race out
there.
You'd be like,
you're getting the darkest black.
And does that happen with so many older
Italian guys?
Oh,
like Deniro type guys.
Bill Maher's all black too.
They just go fuck like bitches.
I'm tired of it.
You don't want to get freaky.
Want to complain?
You don't want to shake that ass down
for the party.
Get the fuck out.
Go,
go.
I'm done.
Alan fix all black too.
I heard Alan Thick.
Alan thicke is a cool motherfucker.
Gets up on the side.
We had Alan thicke on.
Um,
we had them on fear factor.
He did celebrity addition.
That dude is funny as fuck.
Smooth Professional.
Always got a smile on his face.
One liners just coming left and right.
Totally.
Naturally I was getting delirious.
Hilarie will just say I was kidding
about the Alan thicke thing.
Oh,
you didn't make up something about this
chick that went around the world.
The red filming.
Oh,
that poor little quit letting these
stupid young chicks get it on rats just
cause they want to break records.
There has to be laws against sabre.
They put it back on the boat and yeah,
it's fucking retarded.
That's what,
that's what Farmville is for chick.
Well,
you know what,
man,
it's irresponsible over parents,
man.
It just flat out is.
There's no way you can have your shit
totally together at 16 years of age.
There's no way you should be allowed.
Not just out there living in an
apartment by yourself or staying at a
hotel room by yourself unsupervised.
No.
You know,
you,
you might be a little bit naive about
the way the world works.
You might not have ever been fucked
over.
Might not truly understand like how
deceptive people can be.
You shouldn't even let your 16 year old
be by herself in a big city.
You're going to let her out in the
ocean.
You crazy.
Fuck.
You're going to let her get on a boat
now with this start.
It started raining.
Apparently like a really good boater.
Oh,
where?
What location?
I don't know it just counting county.
Where's she going now?
But I just want to know where it started
and where.
Find.
I was just looking at pictures of her.
I just want to know where it started.
Where it there?
What's it say?
What's the story?
Brian?
Sixteen year old girl.
Lost.
See?
See two words.
Two holes.
First one that hit.
Click on images and send.
Let me know if there's a butthole.
Okay,
hold on.
By the way,
have you seen that Miley Cyrus?
We were talking about it.
This is high level Internet Geek Shit
that Brian is throwing at you.
Brian.
Probably does this with every story in
the news and I just want to see searches
to get tickets.
The first buckle is someone will put up
a goat c and attach it somehow with tags
and it will be on Google images and
he'll hack his way though the first
position.
I absolutely know that will my girl
Miley Cyrus Felton was showing my miley
Cyrus's Jj on his website.
There's a picture of it.
Someone took a picture of it,
I don't know.
Miley Cyrus was getting out of a car and
there was like a,
like a Britney Spears crotch shot and a
president put it on his website.
He twittered it.
And then like a couple hours later,
the picture that was taken down from
twit pic or whatever you put it up.
Now the picture is fucking Vagina,
Maria,
whatever her name is miley Cyrus's
vagina.
And people are saying,
you know,
that's child porn,
just 17 and stuff like that.
So then there was this whole movement
showing that the other pictures from
that day,
uh,
like,
you know,
minutes or seconds before and it shows
her having underwear on now a
[inaudible] went on his website saying
today,
hey,
that's not a real picture,
blah,
blah blah.
It's been photo shopped,
blah,
blah blah.
Right,
right.
So,
but then you go to,
what would tyler durden do?
WWT D,
D dot Com.
And there's pictures of her from the
same shoot where it doesn't show the
underwear.
Like,
like you can't see the underwear
anymore.
So you think the underwear was supposed
to sell it.
Now it's doing that whole shit.
When Britney Spears at people did this
too.
They're fucking putting fake throws out
to cover up fake or real photos or
snopes or something grabs it.
It looks at it and go,
oh,
that's not really her vagina.
It's probably love to do the opposite.
It's presence people probably to.
Well they should be.
He's pretty web savvy.
Ryan.
Him,
he owns a giant website.
Even if you put up a photo of a fake
vagina on a 17 year old,
I believe it's illegal.
Absolutely.
It's illegal more.
That's why I'm on the board.
The mods have pulled pictures down many
times where it was a girls that even
just looked like they were under 18,
you know,
because you don't want to get caught
with that kind of shit.
Man.
That's some serious,
serious,
serious shit.
Even just like a fake picture of a young
girl's pussy can get you locked up.
You can read a lot of problems.
President's a fucking retard.
When he used to make fun of Adam
Sandler's kid and doing all that
bullshit,
that's just,
you know,
he just needs to be shut up.
Would benefit
from three years in jail.
I think that's why that do beat him up
or the black eyed peas,
whatever.
That's embarrassing and listening to
them afterwards was so ridiculous.
When you sit on the couch,
got violence is never the answer.
Oh my God,
yes.
It is the fuck beat out of you.
You want to.
You want to fuck with people.
People are going to hit you in the head.
Stupid.
The only thing that protects you from
that as the law.
All right,
that's it.
Human beings want us.
They want to pass that.
They want to just find a way around
that.
They want to cause you pain.
You know why?
Because you're putting out a lot of
negative energy.
You know what?
I want to see Jonathan Lithgo and pres
in a bathtub.
Him choking him out from behind.
So I say that.
Do you think that he would struggle?
No,
I think even just let it go.
Let it happen.
Do you think his butt hole would open up
like a flower fleshlight and just lock a
hold of with cow's body and pull them
into his asshole garbage disposal as
bottles get fucking sharp teeth and
shit.
Hilton Bro.
He is so fucking disgusting.
As a human being,
I get that whole.
His whole site is set up to be mean to
people and some of it's funny.
I think some of what he says is funny,
but I mean I think he could.
I mean,
I think we could all benefit from a
little less negativity in the world.
Let me say the negativity shit.
I buy the same dementia doesn't make me
laugh.
You know,
when Shit's on people's kids being ugly
or you know,
call certain women,
ugly,
you know,
you don't like the way they look.
Who gives a fuck you.
Unless you're saying something really
funny,
you know,
you shouldn't,
shouldn't shit on him.
Like that shit on things.
They can't control what they're fucking
kids look like.
Like really?
That's just negative,
you know,
it's not.
And the people that enjoy that are cons.
They're the people that don't feel bad
when someone shitting on someone's kids
like,
whoa,
really know because they're ugly man.
What was he saying about his kid is the
same as ugly and Blah Blah,
blah,
and they can find a pallet.
She looked like a kid,
not,
not Adam Sandler.
I think his kid,
he's probably had a lot of people fuck
with him in his life and he's probably
got a lot of pent up hostility if I
guess we'll wait to fucking rappers who
don't get.
That's what happened.
The willingham thing.
They were so lucky that that was
outside.
Yeah,
but we'll,
you know what I'm saying?
It was another one.
It's because you know what?
He will,
will I am said,
you know,
I'm a fucking artist,
like respect me.
I'm an artist.
And he goes,
you're not a fucking artist.
You're a fucking faggot.
And someone went,
oh,
no,
fucking hand came out of nowhere.
He clips him.
I mean,
the dude barely got hit.
Okay?
It was a scratch,
a tiny little square vial.
It was nothing.
And he's screaming.
The next day mean it was like another
version of leave Brittany alone.
It was so ridiculous.
It was like,
Dang.
I wonder if he was thinking like,
Oh my God,
I'm idea this Brittany thing was he
believed in at one point in their life
needs to get their ass kicked.
You know,
I'd get my ass kicked all the time and
Jujitsu and I think that is very good
for you.
It's very humbling to get your ass
kicked and when dudes have never
experienced the frustration and anger,
have another dude on them taken out in
the physical.
If you never experienced that,
you're going to talk a lot of stupid
shit.
You know you're going to get mean to
people for no reason.
You're not going to be civil when you
can be.
You have the option to be a nice person
and you're choosing not to be and you're
making it a pain in the ass for all the
rest of us and someone's going to punch
you in your fucking head.
Right?
And if no one's around,
you're fucked.
Okay.
If no one's around and they find you and
you've been mean to people for no
fucking reason,
talk shit on someone's kid,
they might kick you in the Dick or
they're going to cover their whole
kitchen with plastic and when he's going
inside the kitchen,
he's going to come up from behind him
with a syringe and the neck and he's
going to wake up,
covered up and part of that movement
where they say shit to you when you
smack them laid down nine one,
one.
That's one thing in it though.
See,
there's a living in it.
People enjoy it.
They enjoy being shit and that's.
That's what the problem is.
The problem is that,
and I'm as guilty of it as anyone,
I'm not.
I'm not saying that I'm above this in
any way,
shape or form because I'm definitely
not.
I'll go to those sites.
I'll go to,
I'll pick up US weekly if I'm taking a
shit.
I've seen US weekly.
I'm like,
all right,
who's up?
Who's doing something mean?
Who's who's an asshole?
Who's getting sued?
You know,
I draw,
come coming out of your mouth all the
time.
Oh,
how rude.
But you know what I'm saying?
I mean,
it's just,
there's a,
there's a part of us that likes,
likes getting upset at people.
There's a part of us that life's going
to be how you fucking loser posted
before there's a guy on twitter you
posted before that I was going to come
up.
Everybody put some nice stuff on that.
One.
Guys said,
fuck you.
Tbi.
You know,
of course.
But what kills me is if you're going to
be a tough guy,
come out of the fucking live today.
There's a million tough guys.
Well,
there's a million fucking tough guys on
the Internet and when you tell them to
go fuck that mother in the ass,
then you'll never hear from them again.
Seattle fuck around.
I tell them exactly.
Go light your mother's pussy on fire,
whatever.
Then they don't bother me.
No.
This stuff that I don't like,
stuff,
I don't really fuck with it that much.
You know,
I,
I got into it with a kid from my
hometown on facebook couple of weeks
ago,
a Bible breather 20 years ago.
I was stuck.
He was selling me,
quite alludes that he's telling me that
I shouldn't curse on facebook a
motherfuckers.
I hate all that shit.
You want to hear some negativity in the
Internet.
This is a hilarious story and this
happened this weekend.
I was in Vancouver for the UFC and
apparently I got an elevator with some
dude and the dude didn't say hi to me or
nothing,
but he said I gave him this look like I
didn't like him or like a,
you know,
like back the fuck off look.
And then he says that.
He said take care guys.
And then we said nothing and then he
left the elevator like wow,
Joe Rogan's a fucking hassle.
So he goes online and makes us whole
thread about me being in an elevator
with him and no conversation taking
place at all,
but me being an asshole like I'm giving
him this look,
I think I'm a bad ass and I got short
man syndrome and you know,
and then fucking I got problems with
communicating with people.
Like it was crazy shit and I'm like if I
saw you,
if you said something to me,
anything,
if you said you know,
take care of,
I would have definitely said you too
man.
I always say that I not,
I could fucking hate you.
And if you said take care man.
Have a good day.
Bye Bye.
All right dude.
Take it easy.
I would fucking respond to you.
I wouldn't just stand there stone faced.
Even if I fucking hated you,
I would say something.
I'm not a mean person.
I'm not the type of person that does
shit like that.
So it's either one or two things happen.
Either he said it and I didn't hear it
or I responded like our dude take care.
And he didn't hear that either one.
And the dude was high,
those the other thing,
so he was probably a little bit paranoid
and a little bit star struck,
but he makes this crazy fucking thread
and then I tell him,
you know,
I get on,
I said,
Hey,
I'm sorry you had a bad experience,
but it was probably a misunderstanding.
I'm,
I'm out.
I'm a nice guy.
If you're nice to me,
if you're not retarded,
you know,
and you're cool to me,
I'm going to be holding you back.
I tried to be cool to everybody.
Like it was just a misunderstanding.
Well,
the threat.
He says,
all right,
cool man.
Sorry.
No big deal.
Well,
the thread keeps going on and on and on,
and he keeps commenting on it,
like it keeps going back to it and back
to it.
Like I did something to them.
And then finally I come back,
I go,
listen man,
you're out of line.
I go,
nothing happened.
You're making this thread about a
conversation that didn't take place.
Do you understand?
We didn't even say a word to each other
like,
this is crazy.
You're still going on about this.
And then he comes back,
fuck you,
I'm out of line.
You fucking piece of shit.
Wow.
You fucking short man syndrome.
You're like one of those Chachi's
window's tight shirts.
And you walk around like you're fucking
crazy.
Is that.
And I'm why you can't back down now.
You know he has like,
this was not easy.
Yeah.
You.
This is out of nowhere.
I'm going to.
I'm not saying anything negative.
I'm saying he's out of line for other
guys.
Have you elevated with three other
people?
Me and Eddie Bauer.
Fuck,
is he.
Anyway,
I'm on the phone on the way here.
I stopped.
I've totally somebody.
And the next thing you know,
somebody comes up to me.
No,
excuse me.
I would've never come up to somebody.
But that's the little tread over here.
Your Joe Broken.
So you have to say something.
I don't think he was that.
This is what I think it was.
I think he was a little high.
It was a little paranoid.
And I think he's a little sensitive.
And you know,
sometimes people think that people think
they're better than you and that fucking
sucks.
Nobody wants to be around some.
If I'm around someone like an actor or
someone and they get Douchey,
I'll say something stupid to them,
you know,
if I'm around some asshole actors,
one of the reason why I don't like being
around actors,
a lot of them play fucking games.
They say stupid shit to you.
They said like,
I was on a set with this one guy once
and we were about to do the scene and
uh,
I'm just being cool with them like,
right.
All right dude.
And he's about to walk away.
And he goes,
so you have almost no hair.
And he walks away.
I go,
what?
What'd you say?
Nothing.
And just walks away like he said
something to try to fuck with my head
before I did the scene,
like picking on my hair,
falling out to so and so.
Then I saw him the next day and I was
still in my head and so he started to
try to fuck with me again and then I
just,
I just said something to him like,
dude,
don't,
don't fucking get stupid with me,
you know,
don't,
don't like play little insult games.
Me,
I go,
you and I will never have a real
conversation ever again.
Right.
You know why?
Because you're a fucking idiot.
I was nice to you and you came with
this.
You,
you know,
it wasn't like a joke.
It was like he said something like a
little slightly insulting thing and then
walked away.
I mean,
you could say that like,
dude,
your hair's falling out.
I'm like,
fuck you,
you ugly bitch.
You gotta mirror and there will be
joking with each other and we can be
friends.
But when I know that someone's trying to
fuck with me,
like why are you doing that?
This isn't funny.
Like you're trying to be shitty with me.
That happens with actors all the time.
With actors,
you're always dealing with little
psychological bullshit.
They're all fucking tweaked out and
freaked out because they don't create
anything.
They have to have someone come to them
with scripts and ideas and pick them and
choose them.
It's like the only art form where
somebody has to pick you so you can
perform,
you know?
I mean,
if you're a fucking musician,
you,
you do your goddamn music,
you make your own shit.
Your comic,
you write your own jokes.
If you're an actor,
you have to sit around and wait for
someone to give you a role,
you know?
I mean,
you could.
I guess you could put together your own
shit and throw it up on youtube if you
want to get crazy.
I had,
I ran into something that goes along
this whole line at the same a couple of
days ago.
This guy I know wrote something to a
friend of mine that was so fucked up
like,
and so I took a screenshot of it.
He wrote,
you're a dirty fucking whore.
Your tits look like shit.
Obviously you're desperate for
attention.
Get a light.
Three minutes later he wrote,
you are so desperate for attention.
Your tits.
You Post.
Look like Shit,
you're a funny girl who is lonely,
so this guy,
I'm like,
who the fuck is this guy?
And I'm like going.
Somehow he has connections with opie and
Anthony,
not really sure how yet,
but then I go through it and he has this
fucking envelope where has this full
address and so dexter style,
I googled his address,
fucking took a picture of his house and
on another twitter account,
send it to them and goes,
that's a very rude thing to say.
Now he deleted all those photos,
a post and stuff like that.
His latest tweets I've been,
I feel really sick.
I've never been this sick in my life.
Instead you them the fuck out.
It's so crazy because he has like his
pictures and his whole twitter is a real
twitter and he's a family guy.
His daughter,
he's a sign nothing.
How do you do this when you have a
daughter too?
So I'm really interested in finding out
what his connection to the open anthony
show.
It's because he has all these shots from
like in the studio with Jim Norton,
blah,
Blah Blah.
Oh yeah.
You can find out you got pictures of him
and everything.
Oh yeah.
I'm looking at it right now.
Okay.
Well tell us what Jimmy will tell us.
Yeah.
Wow.
Crazy people.
So this guy I got on afterwards and he
goes back and forth and starts bringing
up a video of me being an asshole to
some guy from like nine years ago as
proof that I'm a Douche bag.
I'm like,
you're trying to distract from our
conversation.
Like we didn't have a conversation,
right?
There was nothing.
Nothing took place and you've made this
whole thread about it.
Now you're screaming and swearing at me
and insulting me like this is craziness.
Do you understand this?
And so he actually came on and
apologized and then I came on and so
it's all good,
you know,
no harm done.
It's just.
I think it sucks when the thread by this
time everyone's piling on.
Everyone is like,
you insecure a piece of shit.
Like what the fuck is wrong with you?
Like what are you crazy?
Like?
So many people are saying the guy's
crazy.
And a few people say,
oh,
I met Joe Rogan introduce bag.
Some of them are like making up stories.
I just told us to sign my autograph,
which is just crazy horse shit.
So anyway,
the dude he apologizes and I say it's
all good,
you know,
I think that we all learn from a being
criticized.
It doesn't feel good to say people need
to hear people say you suck at and to
hear people,
you know,
call you piece of shit and criticize
you.
But it's good because when you realize
that you're having a negative effect on
people,
it makes you think like,
what is this a fact that I'm not seeing.
I'm thinking I'm doing the right thing.
I'm thinking I'm living my life.
What am I doing that's making people so
upset with me?
Like,
what is,
is it real now?
What is it?
Is it,
is there is a jealousy issue,
is a,
as an Alpha male issue,
is it a,
am I being too insensitive?
Like what is it?
I think it sucks to admit that we all
have like little,
little issues,
but being criticized like especially
online,
I think it accelerates your social
development because it makes you a
little bit more aware of what a bunch of
anonymous people really,
truly feel about what you say.
No,
you don't get that too much in real
life,
in real life.
You know?
There's a lot of people that especially
like until the internet came around,
they were there know they could bullshit
their way through.
You know,
you could bullshit your way and charm.
People be can't fucking charm anonymous
douche bags on the internet,
anonymous Douche bags and the Internet
will go,
fuck you.
You fucking hack.
You suck.
You know you're nothing.
You're a loser.
You're going to die like that.
Like they'll go after you,
man.
They'll go after you,
but you develop two things.
You want to develop a thick skin from
that were like,
it doesn't hurt anymore.
Now it just feels weird.
It's like,
what's this guy doing?
It doesn't make you do something like
that.
I hate you guys.
Got To be something wrong with it.
Elevated with God.
Having a good day,
guys,
it didn't hit me or whatever.
I get off,
I go home.
It's like the people go to comedy clubs
and write 11,
saying that you would sell it though,
that you wrote a joke or you said
something on stage.
What would make you go home and write a
fucking letter about your experience at
a comedy club?
Or if somebody said,
well,
here's a lady that wrote a,
ever tell you the time to.
The lady wrote about my retarded Jesus
joke.
Remember my retirement.
I had a joke about cloning because there
was a.
There was a group called the second
coming project and the second coming
project they were going to take some DNA
from the shroud of Turin or some other
religious artifacts and try to clone
Jesus and they thought that that would
be the bringing back of the Messiah.
That would be the second coming would
actually be through science and that
they would clone Jesus.
And so I,
I wrote this joke about,
well cloning is not been perfected yet.
Like Dolly the sheep shed all sorts of
genetic issues and she died young and
you know,
that was considered a success.
There's a lot of failures,
I'm sure that we never heard about.
They were like horrible genetic
disasters.
Fucking monsters and shit.
I'm like,
what if they clone Jesus?
And the first one comes out retarded.
I mean that's possible because that down
syndrome,
what do they do?
They kill it.
You start from scratch or.
Yeah,
maybe it's a test.
It's a test.
He's testing us instead of turning water
into wine.
He turned like dog shit in the cookies
home thing where they were following
Jesus everywhere.
He was like,
I want to go into the park today.
They're like,
don't you think we should seal the hip,
you know,
heal the sick or help.
No,
no,
no.
The park.
So they were all waiting for him to come
up with,
you know,
the fucking answer.
Great.
Manatee.
Well this woman got so mad.
She gets so mad.
She wrote this fucking shoot.
This was.
I thought it was really funny about it.
She said not only did he tell this
horrible job,
but when the audience didn't respond,
he insisted on talking about the same
subject instead of moving on.
She was upset that I wouldn't move on.
Like her version of comedy is you got to
do what the audience wants.
Like you're not,
you're not supposed to be coming from
your own head.
You only do what they like,
you know,
it's like,
like you're,
you're a band.
They can yell out,
you know,
do hot for teacher.
Then you have to sing up for Dj,
you know,
like I thought it was running and there
was people that were laughing.
So that's the same woman that doesn't
change the radio station when they're
talking about boobs on opie and Anthony,
there's fucking read.
That's a form of retard right there.
Well,
it's also a person who's very self
righteous because she thinks that she
can get away with telling people what to
say and what not to say.
You don't have to like comedy,
you don't have to like accommodate.
So for everybody,
but just either shut up or leave,
you know,
don't fucking get angry.
Don't yell shit out of me because she
was yelling at me to stop and stop.
Stop.
Like what?
I'm talking about your fake guy.
Sorry.
I'm talking about a fake retarded guy
that I made up.
It's killing you.
Remember,
remember,
remember when the first videos I've
filmed for you was.
I was sitting behind a guy and he was
getting so upset.
Oh yeah.
Watching your show.
I was filming his legs starting to
Flinch.
He was like fucking looking around.
There was the Noah's Ark Shit,
was it?
Yeah.
Then he wrote a letter a couple of days
later and we've had a bunch of letters.
Where does the phrase,
when you say science,
where did that originally come from?
Thomas Dolby.
And Thomas told she blinded me with
science.
If you've ever seen the video.
The guy was the uh,
our answer to the scientist on TV in
England.
He's old.
If you see the video,
he would just yell science.
That guy's a real.
He's like our bill Nye the science guy
video.
So that's what I wanted to talk about.
What we were talking about,
the whole Jesus thing,
I almost forgot was that giant fucking
statue in in Columbia.
It was at Columbus,
Cincinnati,
this fucking 70 foot Jesus got hit by
lightening,
caught on fire and right across the
street was the street from.
It was a big billboard for the hustler
store.
I love.
And so billboard not a scratch.
I love the quote.
Yeah.
It was like,
I think it's Kinda messed up,
but the hustler billboard didn't catch
on fire and that's just not right.
One Guy said,
my favorite quote,
one guy said,
I didn't expect that.
Expect that.
I expect that.
I'll thought the magic man.
We've got a bit.
I mean the stupidest thing about it is
you're not supposed to make like idols
of Jesus.
Isn't that like even in the Bible you're
not supposed to like make,
make churches even.
Doesn't that say in the Bible that he'd
rather have you do it under a tree than
break would or something like that make
a church or something,
something like that.
Something like that.
I don't know.
I cannot quote the Bible here.
Can I just have no fucking at the part
you're saying I don't know a goddamn
thing in it anymore.
I read it when I was younger.
When I lived Florida.
They made us read
it.
They didn't make us read it,
but they gave it to us and they gave us
an opportunity to read it.
They handed out bibles in the class and
I went from San Francisco to Florida in
San Francisco.
Super Liberal,
had gay neighbors.
My aunt used to go next door and smoke
weed with gay neighbors and they would
get naked and play the bongos together.
So I was like around all these hippies
and war protest type people in San
Francisco.
So I moved from there to like Super
Religious Retard Florida.
So I'm like right around retards and
they're.
They're handed out bibles and this one
kid,
he gets his Bible.
I swear to God the word fucking 11.
He gets his Bible.
I'll never forget this.
He goes to read the Bible.
That's what he said to read the Bible
and then he sits there all like crazy,
like excited to be reading this book.
Like,
Whoa,
what that fucking kid's face and what he
said.
Well,
it burned into my head.
Definitely.
Definitely lochner.
I went to Catholic school.
I don't remember shit from that Bible
for years.
I went to Catholic school and I went to
a Catholic school.
It's so fucked up that the people should
allow anyone to push any ideology on the
kids.
Everybody thinks that like having your
kids grow up.
Religion is no big deal and you know,
it's good for them.
I agree to give some kids some morals
and set some standards of behavior and
to tell them that you know,
about communicating with people that
what's important is you be positive.
You can do good things,
be a good person,
you know,
and,
and spread out that good energy spread
out love.
But to make the kid to go to any fucking
super religious school,
you're going to fuck their programming
up so bad,
you know,
but no one is objective enough to see
that people just want to have good kids
and they want to carry on the tradition
that their family has.
Religion as a child should start off as
in a different religion and then move
onto Christianity or whatever.
Like I should start off as Buddhist,
like just teaching to be a good person
and then you get into like that that
they should do is teach you the
different principles of each religion
and not say either one of them is the
fucking answer,
right?
There's too many of them.
You look at all the good aspects of all
the different religions and say,
well,
where did all this come from?
We don't know.
We don't know where it came from.
We assume it came from some wise people
that got through a lot of conflict and
figured out some way to live life and
then they wrote it down and some of it
makes a lot of sense even today.
But when,
when the book that you're basing
everything on includes treating women as
second class citizens,
condoning slavery,
murder a fucking angry God who punishes
people by death and you're gonna burn
into fucking fiery hell,
come on,
just shut the fuck up.
Just stop it.
You're talking goofy nonsense.
You know you,
you got to show me something.
You've got to show me up fucking youtube
clip.
You got to show me something before I
went and believe in,
in this kind of goofy shit is silly.
But in 2010,
we still let that slide.
We still say,
well,
you know,
everyone has their own freedom of
religion.
Do whatever you want.
But if you start saying like,
stop,
this is fucking completely ridiculous.
You're saying your way is the only way
you're saying people should die if they.
You're saying
you know people can't be gay and get
married.
You're saying you're,
you're imposing all your bullshit on
other people.
And we still accept it in 2010 except at
the Church of what's happening now.
That's where I'm from,
church.
That matters in my book.
What are we going to get past this?
When are we going to get past?
When were you going to step up and say,
no one knows.
No one knows.
You don't know.
Don't say,
you know you can't say,
you know,
if you say,
you know you're crazy,
tell me your experiences.
Tell me what happened.
Throw it in the pile.
Let's all sort this out.
You can't tell me that you know this is
the way and you're the chosen people and
she just shut the fuck up.
Stop your all your Joseph Smith and
you're fucking nutty.
Scientology.
Stop.
It's all crazy.
You're awkward and it's fucking up
everything because when people pretend
they have the answer,
it fucks up.
Everybody else had searched for the
answer because there's an option to not
even think.
There's an option to like,
fuck joining the search to figure out
how to live the life the best way.
Let's just fucking follow.
These douche bags are doing.
Did you ever.
Were you ever religious when you were a
kid?
I made my first communion.
I got thrown out of there.
I got thrown out of there before my
confirmation.
What happened?
I beat up the fucking none storytelling
stage.
That's the true story.
Tell me what happened.
I was in the fourth grade,
fifth grade,
and my friends,
I hung out with these two little twins
and the one kid's mother was having a
baby and he wanted to call and then
we'll let them fucking call.
So he's crying.
You know how twins are.
One starts crying,
the other one started fucking crying.
They're crying.
I'm trying to learn my fucking abcs.
And I said,
just let him call.
And she's like,
mind your business,
little quality.
Pay Your Bill.
How can you not let somebody call the
hospital?
This isn't like a corridor.
Joe Rogan,
I this your mother and the none wouldn't
let him.
So I said,
you know,
fucking get up and go.
So she'd made me in the two other guys
get up and wait outside.
Then she took me into the stationery
closet and she beat him up first and I
could hear it outside.
I'm in the fourth grade now.
My mom used to always say,
don't let people hit you if they hit
you,
whatever.
So she takes me to the closet and she
turned her ring around and she just
started hitting me,
hitting fucking hit me,
hit me,
hit me in the face and shit,
and I like a taste of blood in my lip
and that's when I couldn't take it no
more.
I just fucking grabbed her and took her
around and I didn't know nothing.
I just hold it by the fucking throat and
I said,
I'm calling my mother.
This is going to fucking stop it real
quick.
No,
but here's what's crazy.
It was a disciplinary in there that
walked around with a stick and he hit me
in the leg and his name was Jack.
He had gone to the school.
He had stayed there as a teacher's
assistant and he's the one that lit you
on fire.
Every once in awhile he would light you
You know what I'm saying?
What do you mean he will hit you?
You know he was punching or smell hunch
you.
Oh yeah.
And I fucking would punch you oprah on
the chest and shit,
and I had that in mind.
But if you went home and told your
mother you were kind of scared.
I just couldn't,
couldn't take people hitting me.
I never liked that.
So I grabbed her.
He threatened to call.
He didn't,
didn't even threaten to call the cops
because I had blood coming out of my
mouth.
So I said I'm getting to the payphone
and called my mother.
She's going to come here and we're going
to straighten this up.
But the funny thing is my mother came
with like 20 dudes from the bar so that
we made a deal.
They couldn't expel me because I didn't
do nothing.
I just protected myself.
It was my fucking lip hanging like
chocolate.
Does your mother,
you're mad at him?
Yeah,
my mother went off and then that's when
we made an agreement.
I'm going to stay till June.
This happened in April.
So for two months at a time,
Jack got close to him.
Remember when my mother said,
I'll fucking kill you motherfucker.
So for the last two months of my fourth
grade,
they couldn't even say nothing to him
and I started revolting having other
kids telling their parents.
Now it's just such a joyless religion.
How can you go back and see her pulling
my ear or give me a punch to the back or
something.
I don't want to Catholic schools.
I went to Catholic school from first
grade.
I was very religious when I was a little
kid.
When I was a little kid,
my parents got divorced when I was five.
They separated and I was really lost and
I was really scared.
I remember thinking like,
my dad's not around anymore.
This is crazy.
It's just me and my mom and my sister.
It's like,
it was very unsettling.
My mom had to work all day and we had to
be in different people's houses while
they babysat us or grandparents,
whatever.
It was unsettling.
And while this was all going on,
I went to Catholic school and it was my
first year in Catholic school,
first grade,
and they were so fucking mean.
Dude.
I don't remember shit about first grade.
Okay.
I don't remember anything about being
six years old.
You know what?
I remember sister Mary Josephine at Our
Lady of Chester Hova in Paterson,
New Jersey.
I think it was patterson,
Patterson or NORC.
I remember that.
I remember that experience.
I lived there for a year.
Okay.
I went to that school for a year and in
that year I went to school everyday
terrified and everyday that was just
fucking cunt.
Old.
Wasted up,
used up life.
None.
That was just evil to everyone.
Every day it was always yelling at you.
I would cry like I missed my mother.
Like the first day I cry.
You might cry like a baby.
Crazy man.
This fucking evil cunt.
And if you didn't do your work right or
you didn't listen to her or anything was
wrong,
she'll tell you.
She's going to make you sit on a nail
and the closet.
It was like a fucking pink floyd video.
Is that just east coast religion or
something like that?
Because you guys just go after these
scary.
Don't let them fuck when people don't
get the fuck they're not happy.
Period.
End of discussion.
Your whole life is no deck.
How are you going to be happy?
You're not going to come.
You don't come at all.
What does the Guy Do?
He doesn't come because he his a fuck
the Fox.
Nolan.
He can't even jerk off.
What kind of a life is that?
That's a horrible existence.
It's not love.
It's not passion.
Emotion,
celebration of life.
Now it's all just do what I tell you.
Follow my rules or you burn in Hell and
let me touch a cock.
There's a lot of that.
I was going to go back and talk to them,
but the school's governing,
it's in New Jersey and I was there one
time and I was like over there and just
talk to them,
but they will.
That school was closed up.
It was when I got older and I started
hearing stories about kids getting
molested.
I get fucking angry.
I got angry at my mom.
I said,
how are you letting me go to school in a
place where it people getting molested,
you know,
like the preset were molesting kids,
but I don't.
No,
nobody was always close.
It got covered up fast,
but there was almost like this thing
that they deserve it though.
What the fuck are you doing being an
altar boy?
So it was like,
don't you know,
there was like this weird little like,
C'mon wasn't why was,
why is he being an altar boy?
You know,
it's like maybe when they were altar
boys,
like he was like almost an excuse that
maybe he knew and he wanted it like
fucking crazy.
So weird.
Because like my band,
my religion was completely different.
It was like there was a starbucks there,
there was like a band,
you know,
with that kind of like a party.
It's totally different.
Yeah.
But there's a lot of good products that
are like emily luther,
they become a good part of the
community.
It's like a nice step off point where
everybody gets together and promises to
be nice.
You know,
you promise to abide by the laws and
respect your friends and you have
cookouts and shit and there's a lot of
positivity in,
in,
in being,
in a church.
There's a lot of positive shit about any
big community gathering where everybody
agrees to be nice and the best way to
get everybody to agree to be nice to say
that's what God wants.
There's a lot of fucking great things
about church but not the Catholic church
pro that is shut.
That shit ain't good.
This fucking thing that's going on with
the,
the uh,
the pope we've talked about or are they
on a show?
But for people that don't know,
the guy who's the pope right now is been
accused and there's all this evidence
that points to the fact that he was
shielding child molesters.
The Guy,
this guy who's the pope,
he was protecting the church and
shielding known child molesters and then
putting them back in action around other
kids that the guy went on to molest
again.
And the fact that there's people that
are calling for that guy to be arrested
for crimes against humanity.
You know,
like Christopher hitchins is called for
the,
for people to,
to arrest him and charge him with,
with pedophilia or charge him with child
labor and child endangerment or whatever
the fuck he did though was involved
knowingly and exposed pedophiles to
children with some of them moved to try
to protect the business of the Catholic
church to a different place.
Behavior.
So yeah,
exactly that.
Nobody.
No,
you didn't let the church know.
You didn't let nobody know that this
fucking guy likes to dress up as Peter
Pan.
I mean,
Hey,
I don't mind.
Let's handle the fucking problem,
but don't put them in the witness
relocation plan for priests and ship
them up to Albany and two years from now
you got another molestation.
Ship them across the world to
Philippines.
Then they're at all.
When they fall,
they do something there.
They shipped them to Germany.
They just keep moving them around.
Avid capital.
It's been proven.
Now if you,
what does that,
um,
what is the fucking documentary?
The documentary a one horrible one.
The priests.
Hold on,
I'll find it in two seconds because I
got it on my itunes.
Did you watch it?
Yeah,
I watched half of it and I couldn't
watch it anymore because it was just
driving me crazy.
It was just so horrible.
Deliver us from evil and this is all
about a guy who was just his whole life
boys.
Girls just molested,
molested hundreds of them and they just
moved this motherfucker around.
They just moved them around and
protected.
I'm protected the church.
There's so many of them that are doing
it,
man.
It's not like one or two.
There's so many of them.
It's a percentage.
It's not like a small number,
you know?
It's fucking terrifying and a lot of it
is just accepted.
A lot of people just keep the fucking
mouth shut.
Just avoid the creepy flux,
you know?
And then I guess like,
you know,
maybe some of the kids that get sucked
into like gay kids get sucked in and who
knows,
you know,
but it's the idea behind it is
ridiculous that these,
these crazy assholes that don't fuck
have a front row seat to God like they
have.
They have the best connection they got.
They got God's best cell phone number.
Like it's fucking crazy that they don't
even get a special spot in heaven,
you know,
and we all grew up with it.
I mean,
Joey can tell you,
anybody who went to Catholic school,
nobody went to Catholic school and had
an awesome experience.
I think we got a little less.
That's the thing I just beat the fuck
out of.
Yeah.
No,
nobody even beat me.
I think she whacked me with a ruler
wants,
but it wasn't bad.
It was just a little slap,
you know?
It wasn't anything like nobody ever did
what they did to you.
Well,
don't get me wrong.
I always fucking fueled crazy lit.
That's why they put me there.
I'm sure.
I'm sure you will.
It wasn't for the beat and that they
would give him.
Listen for that.
He never,
never allowed to beat a kid Po.
That was terrible.
You never lead with you that.
That's a crazy angry human being.
She wasn't a lack of love fucking bitch.
Dot Eisen was a vape sister Mary ice at
the.
Something like that.
If you had a choice between hanging out
with an old nun or hanging out with an
old porn star,
who are you gonna hang out with,
you know,
pretty simple,
hanging out with Nina Hartley.
I bet she's a nice lady.
You know?
I bet she has a good conversation.
I bet she's cool and friendly and I
better eyebrows.
Look really creepy.
Eye lashes but crazy fake eyelashes.
That's old school.
That's the old school.
Look,
that's a hot look back in the day,
but you know what I'm saying?
I mean it's,
it's just an unfortunate choice to waste
your whole life,
you know,
in a non loving,
non friendship oriented sort of a
situation like that based on a bunch of
fucking silly,
crazy old rules we need as a human
being,
as a human,
the human beings as a race,
we have to,
as a race,
get past where we're at right now and
move into some new way of designing the
way human beings behave and act and it
can't be based on some nonsense.
It has to be based on just positive
energy and success.
Success as a race success,
as a neighborhood success,
as a group of friends,
you know there's a way to live your
life,
there's a way to be positive and there's
way to figure out a way to spread the
most positive energy and the way they'd
be the most honest,
the way they'd be the most creative and
the most friendly and the most
productive and the most satisfied.
There's a way to do that and it's not
through religions currently.
Re tweeting,
you know,
he's a little positive bump,
right?
Like I just said,
man,
retweets and pokes.
Retweets are actually cool when someone
cool retweets you.
Wow.
I always forget to look though at the re
tweets because I use just the twitter
website.
I don't use it too much,
you know,
so I owe you have to go to like
retweets,
go to the twitter website,
do I give up on tweet deck and all that
stuff just keeps timing out and I'll
type it out.
But I love having all the different
lines.
I love having,
you know,
my timeline and I tried to respond to as
many as possible.
Some people get crazy.
Dude,
some people you don't respond to them to
get upset and you're like,
dude,
I can't like 100 of these in an hour.
There's no way I can keep them up.
When you get to like 130
something thousand people and you say
something funny or say something
interesting,
you'd throw up some new.
I'll get like a hundred to 53 crazy.
If it's crazy one,
it might be a couple hundred.
You can't respond to them all.
It's impossible,
you know,
but the beautiful thing about twitter is
even if you respond to them,
it's like a real quick thing and nobody
can send you these goddamn story of
their lives.
You know?
Some guy sent me some fucking material
he wanted me to assess the other day.
Some guy says I'm thinking about doing
standup comedy and those sort of really
weirdly written letter like utility guys
psycho and he wants me to review his
comedy and then he just writes out his
whole fucking routine.
I'm like,
dude,
come on man.
I'm not gonna.
I don't have the time.
I can't just sit here and review your
comedy and tell you what I thought about
this paragraph.
It's like fucking up to page little
email.
Do you just write back,
send back that email in a tweet?
That's what I've been doing lately.
All these people are sending like Brian,
check out this documentary,
this,
ignore this scientism,
blah,
blah blah.
And I'm like,
dude,
write it back in 130 characters or less
and I'll
reply.
Yeah,
people need to learn how to edit in real
life too.
I think twitter is awesome for that.
Yeah,
twitter's great for jokes.
It teaches you to,
to reply in,
um,
in like a short amount like,
t to get your point across in the
shortest amount of words possible.
Could you imagine being able to tell
women that that's how you're supposed to
talk to me?
And for now on,
it has to be tweaked.
One hundred 30 words or less lady.
You know,
Mrs Rogan just hit me with a story the
other day.
Oh,
it was about chicken salad as opposed to
a chicken salad and this fucking story
took it.
And meanwhile I'm on the way that gym,
so I'm getting fired up and ready to
fucking hit the bag and shit.
Fuck shit up.
Right?
So I'm all,
I'm all amped and she corners me with
this chicken salad,
chicken story about how well I always
get the chicken salad at this place.
But today I decided to try the chicken
salad sandwich.
So I ordered the chicken salad sandwich.
But since I always get the chicken
salad,
they gave me chicken salad.
So I got home and I was like,
oh,
it's chicken salad.
Dammit.
I wanted to try the chicken salad
sandwich.
And then it keeps going on.
Like I got it.
I got to see what happened.
Who's on first base over that?
Man,
there's a window opens.
She's still a callback.
Shiny,
happy Jihad.
No fucking neighborhood.
Chicks love to just talk.
They love like reassuring communication.
Some of them do his rash generalization
of course,
but some of them just like to just keep
fucking talking man.
They just like keep talking.
Yeah.
I got an ice machine the other day.
By the way,
Joey,
this is a new snack for you.
I don't know if you like snow or ice.
Told me about the Margarita.
Everything.
Yeah.
You just sit there and make up on at
1:30
I dropped.
No,
but it's great because you have the Big
Cup of ice.
So that's like zero calories,
right?
You get sugar free syrups like root beer
or grape or something like that.
And it's just like the.
There's like ice pops,
remember this frozen pops like the
bottom and it gets all mushy and you
know,
eyes.
It's just like a whole
cup of that.
But there's no calories in it.
I restrict myself to one diet coke a
week.
No Diet coke.
Yeah.
As I'm getting older I'm like,
you've got to pay.
Okay.
Nothing is for free.
Right?
And when you're eating this stuff that
tastes sweet and it's not really sweet
and it doesn't have any calories,
what the fuck is really going on?
What's going on,
man?
I mean you could tell me the diet coke
is safe and I'm sure it is.
I mean I've drinken a bunch of them.
Nothing's wrong with me.
You know,
I used to do a joke.
If you get cancer from diet coke,
you're a fucking pussy.
Reality is.
The reality is that kit check can be
good for you.
Yeah,
but I mean it's like what?
Do you want diabetes or do you want
maybe a ankle cancer?
I'll have a water.
You.
They have to have a coke.
If you didn't have water,
okay.
If you were just forced to drink coca
cola every day and then someone gave you
a nice ice cold water and be like,
God,
this tastes so good.
If water was like super precious,
I know like there wasn't that much of
it.
So you'd go to like a fucking restaurant
and buy some water and you know,
for real good water it would cost you
$100 a bottle,
like a bottle of wine and you drink it
and be like,
oh,
this is delicious.
It's so satisfying.
I don't want it to end anyway.
You just take it for granted.
You open up a bottle but a little,
a little drink it.
No big deal.
Water Tastes fucking awesome.
All right.
We just don't think it tastes awesome
because we want that goofy sugar rush
and then that Goofy Coca Cola sugars
that we're all addicted to.
Caffeine rush.
I went to Baja fresh the other day.
I had a chicken burrito and it's big
mother fucking dichos dude.
It was giant.
I direct that thick and I was wired.
That was wired.
It was like.
It was like I had a 20 ounce starbucks.
Another big ass coat.
The worst is have you ever had like you
were really thirsty at night and you
only have like a diet coke on your
nightstand in Chug it and that's the
worst warm.
Oh yes.
Sitting there all night.
Caffeine.
Yeah.
I.
You know what's good man?
I got these new drinks that these dudes
sent me.
If you're into energy,
not an energy drink,
but workout drinks,
just healthy,
good for your drinks.
A lot of Ginseng and shit in them.
They're called good for you.
Drinks.
These guys sent me a whole case of these
things.
They're fucking awesome.
They're like the best workout.
Drink less.
You have gatorade.
Gatorade is good after you work out,
but it's like a little too sugary.
I always add water.
Two months.
Yeah,
you have to pour water in and I did that
with all juices to apple juice,
orange juice to citric for me.
Let's mix it with some water.
Anyway,
these people that if you.
It's good for you.
Drinks good.
The letter,
the number for you drinks.
You could find them on twitter.
You can find them online.
I'll go google them.
It's shit.
If you're into a good workout,
drink and they support mma.
I found out about them through Shane
Corwin and I know they've sent Jason
Ellis some some shit.
They're good guys.
They'd go get it now for a word from our
sponsor.
Flashlight back at the beginning.
These gentlemen,
fleshlight dot Tom.
Masturbate.
Ladies and gentlemen,
and I know you do.
Let's be real.
Wouldn't you want to fuck something that
feels better than your hand?
I know I do because I know when I'm
masturbating at least half of my body
saying,
hey dude,
you've got a dick in your hand and it
doesn't feel as good when you.
When you're thinking about that and you
think about the fact you got a dick in
your hand,
it doesn't feel as good.
So what I proposed last gentleman,
as you go to fleshlight.com,
you get one of these things and you fuck
it.
All right.
You got to get past the embarrassment
and I tell you from personal experience,
because I knew about the shit,
I'd heard about it on TV and on TV ads.
I heard about it on the Internet.
I heard about people talking about a
little Eddie Bravo.
Told me his flashlight story before.
He's had a flashlight for awhile,
but I was too proud to walk into a store
or order one online.
I will approve too proud to even admit
that I masturbate.
That shit's ridiculous.
So my dad told me about this fucking
thing that he's hooked onto right now.
Cut a reserve or a patrol was vera
trawl.
R E S v e r a t e r o l yeah.
Dioxin.
Very potent antioxidant that exists in
wine and I've been taking it for years.
Yeah.
So He's been doing like this huge.
He's like crazy research guy when he
gets hooked on something,
it's actually,
it comes from plants when it's stressed
by parasites or various infections like
the plants,
like a release like this,
like fucking chemical or whatever.
So people are taking this a chemical and
putting it,
you know,
you can go to Gnc and stuff,
but then there's kinds that are mixed
with other things that uh,
but if you get it as pure as possible,
that benefits from it or like insane.
It's saying that this is all in like
rats.
They found that the rats have like
cancer gone away from it.
A lot that in person routes of cancer,
like bus route and they're saying that
it will block colon cancer in humans and
uh,
it will your life will you be 30 percent
more life.
You live longer and stuff like that.
It's also saying there a difficulty in
absorption that we were talking about
this before.
That's what I'm saying.
I've,
I've heard that your body absorbs very
little of most of the brands that you
bought.
That's a,
you have to find out how pure it is.
And if you look on the bottle,
look to see how pure it is.
You want about 200 or 2:50
to 500,
it goes up to $500.
But look how the pure of the actual
chemical of that.
So two to 5,500
milligrams.
Is that what it isn't?
So milligrams milligrams.
So the higher the milligram,
the more pure it is,
the higher it's just that chemical mixed
with other things.
So it a mix with what are the other
things that they put in with it?
Oh,
I like grape grape seed extract,
stuff like that.
Yeah,
he is also an anti.
Have you been taking the Brian?
I just started in two days,
but my dad's been taking it for about a
month now.
And he says a couple things.
He said that he feels like he is just
nonstop energy from when he wakes up to
something that he hasn't had in years.
He also said that his hip pain,
he has a bad pain.
He took,
stopped taking it for a week and his hip
pain immediately came back.
And he also said that,
uh,
that he has stomach is always getting
full faster now.
So after we,
it gets like second side,
a dinner or something like that.
Now he says he feels full after the
first time your dad selling resveratrol.
No,
he's not a scam motherfucker.
He's not,
but he's to somebody.
He's somebody that like when he could
find something to eat,
like researches the fuck out of it and
stuff like that.
If you said that whole thing in an
English accent,
I probably wouldn't get online.
Yeah.
But anyways,
there's a whole thing that I emailed
you,
Joe,
that you should look for that it out.
Have some in my,
um,
my,
my vitamin cabinet.
I don't know,
I never even looked at what the dosage
is though.
I mean it says a blocks,
colon cancer in mice and then right now
that they're trying to find out that the
problem is we're not mice.
Yeah.
Well we're mammals.
We're mammals.
So they're,
they're looking into it and a lot of the
research are finding is all positive.
Interesting.
I'm sure there's definitely a connection
with camp,
but there's a lot of shit that mammals
can eat that we can't and we can't,
that they can.
Like dogs can't even eat chocolate.
Dark chocolate.
They'll get fucked up.
Shit's poisoned.
Poisoned.
Did her stomach kill them and if you
give a sheep,
DMT,
they die.
You know that sheep,
there's certain types of grass that has
dmt in it.
She eat the grass and they just fucking
fall down the little feet,
just twitch in the air.
It just boom.
Explode their brain.
If you put a snail on a listerine strip,
they melt.
Yeah,
but listerine strips on the nature,
son.
That's ridiculous.
Well,
if you flipped,
hit a monkey with a rocky dies,
Huh?
That's all my dad.
My Dad's the one that first told me
there were about splendor like seven
years ago.
How about all the bad shit about bad
when people are just getting on splenda.
He was like,
send me reports about how the brain like
things like sugar,
and this is seven years ago he was
sending me this shit.
So He's pretty coke.
The sucralose.
One's a weird one,
right?
Splenda what?
SPLENDA as any of those chemicals tricks
the brain into thinking it's sugar,
so it does the ship that it does do
fight a burn off the sugar,
but it's not there,
so it's just.
I guess it has a lot of bad negative
side effects.
It's pretty critical.
Aspartame is a bunch of them now.
I don't think any of them.
I think actually sugar is probably the
best.
The best one for you.
That's why a lot of these companies
though.
Here's the key.
You got to exercise.
You can't just eat sugary shit and if
you're going to have one of those
things,
you have to have a body that can process
that sugar.
You can't just be sedentary and be down
in sugary drinks that will fuck your
whole system and want everything in
moderation.
Yeah.
There's nothing wrong.
A little coke in moderation.
The drink.
Yeah.
Lately I've been buying those small
little mini regulatory fuck cock sucker.
Why you looking at me?
You know?
I don't know.
It'll.
It'll totally because I wanted to a diet
coke for awhile.
Terry bought like 95 of a costco.
I stuck to my points.
They actually gave away fucking sodium
is.
Oh yeah,
you've got so much water with kidding
me.
So now I've been,
I got off of that.
I just drink them when I go to a
restaurant.
And even then I don't because I feel
that they only gave me the wrong batch
of shit.
Right.
So I stopped,
you know,
because I just don't want it at all
right now.
Have you been following e three at all
this week,
Joe and seen all the
new shit that's coming out with Xbox,
Sony and all that stuff?
No,
I saw the,
uh,
the,
they made the xbox smaller,
but I mean,
what are they going to do?
This really interesting new things.
It's like they're all turning into the
Nintendo wi with the motion controllers
and stuff.
But what's really cool is like,
Sony has this one which is like it,
like it looks like a microphone or a
fleshlight or whatever,
but in the game you're like in the game
and then it turns your controller into a
weapon.
Kind of like,
you know how cgi they have like the Ping
pongs all over and stuff,
so you're looking at yourself with a
weapon and it's Kinda,
it's Kinda trippy.
So like that's the whole thing with the
xbox and the ps three is that it's
turning you into the controller.
But I think I'm sick of all this.
I just want to play video games.
I,
you know,
I'm a grown man.
I don't need to be dancing around just
trying to fucking cast spells on dragons
and stuff for a lot of people they've
lost a lot of weight.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
For,
for,
for people,
for young kids.
I'm sure they're loving this shit,
but you know,
we fit,
we fit shit.
A lot of people have lost a lot of
weight with that stuff and they also,
Nintendo just released a new three d
game.
Boy that I,
I don't think you have to have glasses
for.
Maybe you do,
but I don't think you do.
And they said that it's actually coming
out.
Wow.
What about like,
that's,
that's crazy man.
What about that Microsoft thing?
There was a Microsoft thing.
They're working on,
that was a,
it was a emotion detective thing that
we're going to be able to do with
martial arts game.
Yeah,
that's it.
That's one of the things.
That's what I believe it's called a,
I forget what it's called now.
Vizio or something.
I can't remember.
But uh,
so that's,
that's my xbox version,
you know,
I think they both,
they have both a positive so I'm going
to get it.
They're cheap.
They're $49 for the ps three and
something I think we're ever going to
get to reality helmets,
you know,
like alternate reality helmets.
Remember when they had those,
when they were trying to do that for
awhile though.
The virtual reality there were there,
there was like a big thing like that.
Someday we're going to be able to put a
helmet on and you'll know if it's going
to be like that.
I was,
when I was in Vegas,
I was talking to all these,
uh,
there was a tech conference going on
there and this guy I know from San
Francisco owns this whole company and he
was telling me about what was big in the
tech shows and he says,
you know,
the big thing that's going to be next,
he's like,
porn is kind of at a dead right now with
no dvds,
fucking porn.
So red porn.
He says,
he says some of the technologies coming
out,
Yo.
He's like,
he's like,
you know,
that's going to be big where you can
just lay in bed with no pants on and you
feel like the legs are wrapping around
you,
you know,
and you're fucking sitting there with
their flashlight on and you're immersed
into it like a helmet.
He's like,
that's what's going to be big.
He said the TVS weren't even that
impressive.
He said,
what was impressive this year at this
convention was the digital projection,
three Ds.
He says,
that was just amazing.
That's like some help me.
It will be one time shit.
Kind of.
Yeah.
Imagine having this whole wall behind
you be three d,
You know,
you're just fucking sitting there in
this chair over here and you feel like
you are in Lord of the rings or
whatever.
Yeah,
you got to flinch and next thing is
going to be way more immersive.
Every step is coming to watch.
The TV is going to be your wall and it's
probably gonna.
Be Greedy when it moves past the flat
plane,
that's when it's going to get really
crazy.
When somehow know that they figured out
a way to bring you more into the action.
Some some invention that allows you to
be
like a virtual reality type situation
when you watch movies.
So the guy said at that convention they
had a 40 inch tv that didn't require
glasses.
He said it kind of sucked,
but he said he saw just looking at it
how eventually that is going to be huge
and it's going to be three d,
so it's going to add a depth.
So you walk into your room,
you could have a picture on the wall,
this long hallway,
and you're gonna.
Feel like that's a long hallway in your
room.
You know what I mean?
There was a thing I went to at the
planetarium the other day was one of
those science shows where you lie on
your back and they take on a tour of the
all the different astrological
configurations in the sky and
constellations and stuff and so they
were.
They were taking you on this tour and
all this different shit and space and
everything.
I was like,
how intense is this?
Like the whole ceiling is a fucking
screen and you're lying back.
Like almost like a lazy boy chair.
You lay all the way back.
Like I fell asleep even so I was tired
when I was there.
I'm an old man.
I fall asleep with the movies,
so I'm standing up there watching this
fucking thing and I'm like,
well this is so much more immersive than
television.
Like that's what the next step is going
to be.
It's going to be like,
you're going to go to the movies,
but the movie is going to be like a
ride.
You know what I'm saying?
It's going to be like some space,
mountain type shit.
It's not going to just going to be used
sitting there and everybody gets
strapped into a seat and you know,
you put a helmet on captain fucking
chair moves and Shit and you go on a
ride through the movie.
I think they have similar things
probably already at like Disney and
stuff,
but not only for a couple minutes till
the ride starts,
you know,
but the.
Oh,
did you ever go in the Jurassic Park
ride?
Jurassic Park rides a dope one.
They have.
That's one of those.
I think that's the one I'm thinking of.
It's a.
it's almost all our score.
No,
no,
no.
It's not Jurassic Park.
There was another one that they had and
that was old school has a robocop shit.
I don't know what the fuck.
No,
there was one I feel maybe it is dressed
park where there's the one.
They had a universal studios that was
all three d.
It was.
It was all rather a virtual.
You're in a chair and the chair moves in
you and you go on this adventure,
but it doesn't last very long.
I don't remember which one it was,
but it was one of those ones where
you're like,
wow,
someday this is going to be what movies?
You're like,
no,
we need a fucking three d avatar.
Need this rather a blue avatar.
Vagina needed.
We need to really contact them.
Don't they need to kick that up a notch?
That would be a big seller amongst the
geeks.
The new.
We've got to do this,
man.
You got to do a get in touch with James
Cameron.
I'm sure he'll agree with me.
You get smurfette pussy one of the two.
Just don't tell them it's an Avatar.
Pussy.
Just he won't agree to it with the
little sparkles of some little glitter
on that pussy.
The new,
um,
the new Jack asses in three d and which
is kind of gross and weird about that.
But you know what?
Here's the thing,
I have this problem where Johnny
Knoxville or Bam or none of those people
have been on in the news at all for like
years,
it seems like,
you know,
now in the last week on TMZ,
they've been in the news like four
times,
you know,
and I'm almost wondering if this is just
all promotion for the new movie because
smart guy you got beat up.
Isn't that what could happen?
All that.
But the problem is someone got arrested,
someone got arrested and it's on the
news,
right?
Here's an $80 ticket or whatever.
First assault,
attempted murder.
She hit him in the head with a baseball
bat.
It was like some serious assault
charges.
Some 59 year old woman baseball batted.
Bam.
Mark Air outside his bar in
Pennsylvania.
How much you all that follow that shit
and see what happens.
I'll let that girl finally gets Ryan.
So cynical,
but so right.
So right.
So often you're right.
A lot of tell you that fellow you've
called a lot of fake things and I was
like,
10 ain't fake.
Fake,
fake,
fake.
You get angry.
Fake.
Well,
what's crazy is when tmz first announced
it,
they were like,
he's in critical icu condition,
you know,
blah,
Blah is looking bad,
and then the next thing is like,
oh,
just talk to Johnny Knoxville.
He said he was like,
he was a heavier.
Yeah.
What was,
what were some of the fakes that you've
called in the past?
You've called it quite a few fix where
you were way ahead of the curve.
Well,
there was one that there was like this
really horrible fight and somebody had
filmed it and it looked like a dude was
punching the guy fight.
See,
I think the added sound effects to a
real fight totally added sound effects
to a real fight and it looked really bad
because it was the same noise didn't
sync over again.
It was not sinked up.
I blew up that video so you can see
where the hit,
you know that's true.
But I,
I recognized from years and years of
watching dudes get fucked up.
That was real.
That guy got punted in the head when he
was unconscious and his whole body move
dead.
I mean,
what?
It was a real,
I don't think I ever told you I found
out what happened about that video was
actually made for one of those shocking
TV things.
They had like America's funniest home
videos.
Like ads,
like oh no,
invoices and stuff.
They pump it up.
That's another thing.
By the way,
I'm gonna.
Have you guys ever seen this?
Like America's funniest home videos.
Don't do it as much,
but any of those like sending your video
type shows if you really pay attention,
they don't want to pay people and stuff
like that for certain things.
So like most of the voices are all done
by the same guy.
So it's like,
hey honey,
come over here and look at this.
And then you see here the same guy,
like two videos there go,
oh honey,
look at how you know,
and then you realize it's just one dude
and it ruins the whole show for you.
So next time you watch one lady's like
video shows,
listen to the voices.
It's just one guy redoing all these
weights.
Like,
oh no,
look at this.
And you can tell us the same guy.
It's horrible.
Brian's ruining childhood memories,
crushing dreams,
right about Carlos conduit.
What the fuck.
Fucking Wolf,
Carlos Condit and Roy Mcdonald.
What our fucking fight.
Battle Royale kid is a first of all,
props to Carlos condit for coming back
after those first two rounds.
The first few rounds he was getting
beat.
He was getting taken down.
He,
you know,
he's getting clipped a little bit on his
feet,
but he tacked our kid quite a few times
too.
The kid know kid took some big shots.
There are a lot of people are saying
like,
you can't take a punch and like you're
crazy calls.
Conduit rocked him on the button and he
was coming forward.
I mean,
no one takes good shots when they're
coming forward.
You know when you're coming forward,
that's when you can get hurt and you
know,
they,
they had a rock 'em sock.
'Em robots fight and then Carlos condit
pulled it out at the end,
got them down and just start blasting
them with elbows.
Man hit him with some hard left.
Oh God.
It was his eye up.
And you know what?
The kid has massive class man after.
It was over and I interviewed him.
He was so classy,
like the way he handled it,
there
was no ego,
no bullshit.
The kid was like,
you know,
when he kicked my ass,
who's the toughest guy I ever fought?
You know,
I was asking them,
do you think the fight was stopped
prematurely?
He was like,
no,
no.
He was kicking my ass,
you know,
the kid was just ultimate class and
honesty and just the way he handled
himself,
you know,
and he's so fucking talented and he's
like one of the first cars being 20
years old.
He's one of the first guys that started
out training mma that started out as a
wrestler or a or whatever.
He started out learning the whole sport
altogether as one thing.
So it's pretty impressive to watch that.
That kid's got a super busy,
you know,
you could tell.
What have you heard about the first
fight?
That was anything,
unfortunately.
Yeah,
they're gonna Redo it.
They'll definitely do it.
Fence.
Dana knows the fans wanted to see that
fight again.
That was just a mistake.
You've made a mistake.
It happens,
man.
Being a referee is very hard to avoid.
Tyson Griffin.
That was a good fight.
That was a great asset grid.
That Kid Evan Dunham is a study that is.
He's fucking good.
These are great fights to sweet,
but standup is good.
His fucking Jujitsu's good.
How dare do they think of in the middle
of the Goddamn POC.
They knew that they shut that shit off.
That's probably my manager.
She's probably thinking about like
calling me to tell me that you're
talking about the flashlight too much.
That was a good.
Anyway,
that was a good fucking car.
There was some good pricing.
What's up with pat?
Barry's shit.
He broke.
He broke his foot and he broke his hand.
He broke his neck when he punched cro.
Cop in the first round and then dropped
them.
The second punch he hit him with,
he said he felt is not going to give
out.
And then he uh,
apparently broke his foot somewhere in
the fight to his foot.
Swole up like an elephant foot took
pictures of it online.
Like he has the two feet together and
one of them's like literally twice the
size.
It's nasty,
but a great fight though.
Woo.
That was fun.
That was a fun fight and fun.
Comeback to watching cro cop turn it on
at the end of Glasgow and then take us
back and choke him and then Cro,
cop campaign for the submission of the
night.
That was a good article.
Yeah.
Tell him what do you call them?
Strategy.
I don't remember what he said,
but it was funny.
There was a for him,
man.
I hope that's his last fight.
I really do.
Because he's been talking about
retiring.
I hope he chooses to go out that way.
It's nice to see a guy go out on a high
note,
you know,
that was a high note.
That was an awesome performance.
At the end he addressed the crowd and
address the Croatian fans and it's
pretty cool.
I gave him the microphone.
Yeah,
I just gave it to him.
I mean it was just,
it felt like I said something to him.
He was so proud and so happy and he
could feel and I was happy for the guy
and the crowd was going nuts and
everybody was happy and I said I looked
down,
I saw was Croatian flags and I remember
him talking about how many Croatian fans
are going to be here in Vancouver
because a lot of Croatian people lived
there and I said,
do you have anything to say to your a
Croatian fans out there?
See,
you got a lot of support and the crowd
goes nuts.
All the correlations go fucking ape
shit.
And then I just knew I was going to give
him the mic and he knew I was going to
give him the mic.
I didn't say anything to him.
He didn't say anything to me.
I just,
I just handed him the mic and he took it
and he started walking and pacing and
talking in his native language and the
crowd went nuts.
It was just a beautiful ending.
You know,
if he,
if he decides that he doesn't want to
compete anymore,
I mean,
who knows?
He might decide.
He might be saying that now because it
was a lot of stress,
but they'll get up and get back in there
again because it was one of his best
performances in a long time.
He looked real good,
especially in that third round.
You know when he,
when he had barry backed up and he was
nailing and with punches.
He was,
he was looking sharp dude.
He was nailing them.
What's the fucking hands,
you know?
So who knows,
man.
He might decide.
He might decide to keep it light and
heartbreak.
My doubt broke my fucking heart,
man.
Well,
it's good,
but this does seem to me.
It seems like it's happened.
Like the last three fights.
It's broken my heart.
I thought I didn't know he was even
going to fight again.
I was like,
really?
I mean,
because he's been getting knocked out.
What the last three fights he got
knocked down.
Yes.
I mean it's like,
I think it's.
Oh,
got.
Well you got to look at it two ways.
One way is the last four fights actually
now he had one in there with vandelay in
between and they keep charging.
One actually was after the rampage last
two weeks for two.
Um,
you,
you got to look at it two ways.
One,
you got to look at it.
The fact that the guys fighting top
level talent,
I mean,
rampage knocked him out.
He got knocked out by Rashad and he got
knocked out by Shogun and he got knocked
out by ace rich Franklin.
So you've got to think about these are,
those are four killers,
you know?
Yeah.
It's,
it's unfortunate.
Yeah.
It's,
it's very hard to watch him lose like
that.
Especially when you grew up like,
you know,
basically I came up in the UFC,
watched that guy fight.
One of the first,
the first fight that he ever had in
1998.
I was there live.
I saw him fighting.
I think he fought.
I think the dude's name was Louis
Hernandez know Econ Zalas knowing,
knowing your man is no Hernandez.
Those,
the comedian Louis Gonzalez is the
comedian.
So it's known as the fighter.
Right?
The Guy,
the guy had really said that too.
I always go,
what?
He fought a boxer,
a real good boxer,
and it was a good fucking fight and I'd
seen a bunch of chuck's fights.
I saw the fight that he had.
I wasn't there live of course,
but I saw the fight that he had in
Brazil against Palae in Valley Tudo.
This is back when Paleo was in its
prime.
Paleo was one of the baddest
motherfucking Muay Thai guys to ever
come out of Brazil and he's one of the
guys that helped train Anderson Silva
and he was the best shoot box guy
knocked out Matt Hughes when he knocked
out a lot of dudes.
He was a killer.
So anyway,
Palae his fight and chocolate,
Dell,
any fucking head kick?
Some ba boom.
I mean with a shot that would kill a
normal man.
Chuckles down,
gets right back up.
He had kicked him twice.
Now.
Fight and dropped them in the end.
The fight.
Chuck's on top of them beat the fucking
shit out of him.
Bare knuckle into the netting on the
bottom of the rope.
The bottom of the rope has a net.
Okay,
so that you can't slide out.
So you've got to get stuck in there,
take your beating.
So Chuck's on top of them just fucking
punched him in the face.
I mean,
it was a bare knuckle old school.
No rules war.
I mean this is the kind of fight to that
guy was involved in.
He wasn't just involved in the UFC five
rounds,
you know,
for the championship title,
five minute rounds,
Nevada state athletic commission to
presides over it.
No,
no,
no.
In Brazil,
in the jungle.
Okay.
You know what I'm talking about.
He's frightened that no one in the
audience has shoes on.
Okay.
Either fucking screaming and yelling.
Those IBC value to those.
Those were savage fights,
man.
There was always like browse would break
out.
Henzel Gracie got stabbed in one of
those.
Okay.
He's frightened that would tatio I think
that's the guy's named Eugenio tatio
who's an old school Luta leave ray guy.
And so of course,
you know,
old school,
Brazilian Jujitsu,
Gracie family guy,
and they're fucking battling out and the
lights go out.
Okay.
Somebody kills the fucking power,
you know?
And there's a lot of speculation.
Who did it?
Maybe they thought that someone was
getting their ass kicked.
Who knows?
There's a fucking crazy mats.
Couple goes on.
Henzle gets stabbed.
Okay.
Fucking people are stabbing people in
the audience.
I mean,
these are the kinds of fights that that
chocolate Dell went through.
I mean,
he did it all.
He fought in the early days.
He,
he found the first time in the UFC was
wearing shoes.
He was wearing wrestling shoes,
kicking dudes.
You know,
there was very few rules,
you know,
things were totally different back then
and that has been through so much.
He's been through it all,
you know,
it's just the last few guys that he
fought,
he's a step below,
you know,
always a step behind where he used to
be.
If he was fighting lower level
competition,
like say if they put chuck against,
say some of the guys that fight at two,
oh five.
When the ultimate fighter or some guys
that are like lower level guys don't
have the kind of standup up the ass,
he'll be fucking a lot of dudes up.
Do you think though that brain,
his brain just wants to go to sleep
though I it knows that like,
hey,
I know when a knockout is now I,
you know,
I mean he's lost his chin.
That is what everybody says and that is
what happens with fighters.
That is what happened with that.
There's no getting away from that at a
certain point in time made it happens.
Joe.
He knows that it happens with football
players once they got hooked on it.
Yeah.
When,
when guys start getting knocked out,
it's just when you've taken a certain
amount of concussions,
sidewalk bathrooms,
you got hit on the side and he went out
and we'll talk afterwards because
nobody's,
you're not miked up.
But um,
you know what?
He's a,
he's a legend.
He's a guy who's had a gigantic career
and he was one of these when he was in
his prime.
He's one of the scariest guys.
Every one of the most exciting fighters
ever.
When you went to see a chocolate Delphi,
you knew that someone was going to get
their fucking ass kicked,
you know,
and it was going to be brutal.
You know,
he was going to smash somebody,
he was going to get a hold of you.
He's going to kick you and punch you and
smash you.
Remember the first time he knocked out
randy couture,
it was like,
oh shit.
He can knock out randy.
Randy had been in there with Pedro
Huizar.
Randy had been in there with Maury
Smith.
Randy had been in there with big,
strong knockout,
high level kickboxer heavyweights and
they had knocked him out,
but to get in there with chuck and Chuck
blast to orbit with one punch.
So like the way he could knock dudes out
there was.
There was very,
very few human beings that could stand
in front of the guy,
that guy when he blasts,
but like a lot of guys who have a very
particular style.
Once you know,
once,
once your reflux it start to go a little
bit.
Once you've taken too much punishment,
you don't have other ways to win.
The more ways you have the wind,
the more unpredictable you are,
the more successful you're going to be.
So I got to like GSP,
he doesn't even hardly get hurt.
Mean got hurt by Matt Serra,
but he got clipped and he says he didn't
take Sarah.
He took Sarah a little bit lightly.
But if you,
if you're the type of guy that nobody
knows what the fuck are you going to do,
where they're going to shoot and go for
a take down or are going to in the bang
if you're cautious,
but you know when to attack and went to
move,
you've got to be like always one step
ahead.
It can't just be just run in there and
brawl and,
and chuck was so fucking good at running
there and brawl and he had such a good
chin.
It was such a good counter puncher.
Know he based his whole style on that.
And because of that he was the most one
of the most successful guys and one of
the most exciting guys.
But you know,
that's not the style that allows you to
keep going deep into your forties.
Like Randy coture.
He's got a safer style like you stands
with guides,
but he just wants to get a hold of your
ass and went to get a hold of your ass.
Pressing up against the cage,
beat the fuck out.
You kick your knees,
no,
kick your legs rather knee you in the
legs,
elbow you punch,
you get that dirty box and going and
then hopefully get your ass on the
ground,
beat the shit out of you down there and
then choke you.
You know what I mean?
That's how randy's rocking it these
days,
especially in the coalmine fight.
Oh,
that's in the coalmine fight.
You get to see him,
um,
you know,
in the coalmine fight,
like he had a totally different
strategy.
Beat Coleman standing up and then took
home and down choked him.
You know,
he's,
he's diversifying,
adding more shit to his game.
I think of chuck had done that and it's
fight who had been a lot better off,
but I think he hits so fucking hard and
he's,
you know,
he's so used to blast and guys and
there's so much success that it just
feels good to them.
And once it starts going,
he just chases these motherfucker down
chase's,
these motherfuckers down.
He wants a blast them.
But Franklin condom with that really
well timed right hand a current
overcommitting so chuck was moving
forward and he just catches him with
that counter.
So even though it didn't look like the
hardest punch in the world,
rich has a hard puncher and chuck was
moving forward and so it was a hard
shot.
Man.
It busted open his lip.
Do you see what his lip looked like?
It looked bad.
A big,
big cut.
So it wasn't like.
It wasn't like,
you know,
a shot that shouldn't have dropped him,
that Shaka dropped anybody.
It was a hard shot.
Sick two years ago we'll have dropped.
I think it would have rattled him a
little more maybe.
I think he's gotten this in his head and
says,
you know what?
I had to sleep apnea first.
When you first have an extreme,
you wake up like this,
Joe.
So what happens is every time you lose
your breath,
when I was 400 pounds,
every time I chase you or walk and I
lose my breath,
my body was going through anxiety.
That's how.
That's why I had to go to the ICU.
So your body would start thinking about
the trauma that you've had in the past
and when you,
when you have sleep apnea,
you wake up choking,
you wake up on your feet going like
this,
no grasping for air.
So every time I ran on the air for a
long time,
even on planes,
there was just a connection,
just the connection and yet,
okay.
So there's that.
And then on top of it,
just the raw data that we know about
people that take concussions,
you know,
you cannot take too many concussions.
Oh,
you don't want to.
Yeah.
You don't want to know that putting the
finger.
Like I told Eddie,
Eddie goes,
well,
soccer.
Robert came back and he just started
covering him.
Stuff like all the way chuck is right
now.
Somebody will just hit his hand and he
could hit themselves,
knock himself out.
That's how sensitive that switching.
And it's a shame.
I'm as big as four.
He took a couple of shots before that.
Before that Bro,
he took one to the head.
He took one to go back to watch the
fight again.
But I remember him getting clipped a
couple of times.
Yeah,
he got clipped a couple times.
I heard it.
The whole place smelled like weed.
Was that true?
Oh my God,
Dude.
When I went to the bathroom,
I went to go take a leak and that's how
I was running back to the bathroom.
It just stunk of weed in this one area
and it's the same area.
We're dudes.
We're stealing dudes.
Hats.
Two guys were baked.
It's fucked.
They snatching hats off people's heads
as they would walk,
walk through the tunnel on the way to
the arena sign.
They got their hat on their focus and
just snatch and dude's hats off.
And there's all these animated gif files
online.
Other guy's hilarious.
Is the same guy and they got these big
stupid shit eating grin on their face.
Like that's awesome.
And the funniest one is when he tries to
get Martin Kampmann his hat and he just
misses.
Just misses.
I got walks by and you see the guy who
like to retweet that later.
Oh yeah,
I will.
I'll find the link.
Was the seller Sarah Pailin.
He's losing his mind just like Sarah
Pailin to set aside from,
you know,
chill son and uh,
he stolen Aziz Ansari joke.
It was like doing one of his,
uh,
his speeches about Anderson Silva and
his manager and he did a disease joke.
That's awesome.
He called the little ghetto brothers
busted on that.
You can't do that.
One is a punching bag and the other one
I'm not worried about.
Wow.
He said that they'll get was black belt.
You get a Mcdonald's and a gift set or
whatever.
The happier.
He's the best shit talker by far.
A fucking nice guy too,
man.
When you talked to Chael Sonnen like
outside,
he's a fucking funny,
nice guy.
He's just real good at talking shit.
He's a politician and he can fucking
fight dude,
bro.
Me and all this emotions that he's
charging up and this is all like,
look,
you think about what Damien Maia got mad
or got Anderson,
Matt Damon My.
This is what he said.
He said,
I respect Anderson as a fighter.
I don't respect them as a person.
Whatever the fuck that means to
Anderson.
Why?
I don't know.
But that made him crazy,
he got so angry and so we never seen
Anderson standing in front of a guy
yelling and screaming,
screaming at him,
calling him rich boy and you know,
show me your Jujitsu and swearing at him
saying all these different squares and
then just beating his ass and mocking
them.
Never seen to Anderson do that before to
anybody.
And Demian Maia is generally known as a
really nice guy and respectful guy in a
martial artist.
But that one statement,
whatever the fuck it meant,
threw him into a tizzy.
What is gonna happen when he gets in the
cage with channel Sunnen?
Charles Center has talked so much shit
about them making sacrifices to pick me
God's and fucking all kinds of knots.
He's going,
fuck.
It doesn't stop.
He doesn't stop.
He goes to Pailin certain Doug,
his twitter is just rampant with it,
whose twitter is all like him talking
shit.
But I have not even seen this.
Thank you for opening up my house.
He does these questions and answers.
I missed the one he did in Vancouver.
I,
I missed the other one before that,
but everybody was talking about that.
It said it was the funniest fucking q
and a by far.
My facebook.
Somebody say yes.
Peter Fogle the Guy Willie bar setup
broke his nose,
emailed it to me.
Well,
he just did another one.
It just did another one.
Okay.
This is the second q and a.
Then two of them so far pumping up the
Anderson fight.
Dude,
he's fucking hilarious,
but he fucked up when he's told that as
he's Antasari joke,
they're not going to do the Internet is
not going to let them ride that out.
Have you been to a website called a
Wolfram?
Wolfram Alpha.
This Wolfram Alpha
for people who aren't aware of it is
just project where they're trying to
take the next step after Google and it's
trying to be a website literally that
you ask it a question.
It gives you an answer.
Right.
It's so cool because like I put in my
birthday in the weather and I got the
exact temperature when I was born to the
exact hour.
I got the lows,
the highs during the day.
That cloud cover the population of
Columbus at that time,
the humidity,
the pressure,
the wind's blowing so much shit that if
I was with doc from back to the future,
I could totally get to the right second
of the day that I needed to go back in
time with,
you know,
if this will give you the information
for that.
You know,
it's really funny that you just brought
that up and then you're talking about
this because there was a subject that
was on the message board the other day
that I thought was really interesting.
There's this new scientific discovery
that they found where they do believe
that it's possible that the universe
might be far older than 14 billion
years.
That's what they think it is.
Now.
They think it's like 150 billion and
it's just this small group of scientists
and astronomers,
the that have this possibility in their
head and you know,
it hasn't been sold yet entirely,
but when you start thinking about stuff
like that,
people.
There was like an argument on the board
and the argument was there's some things
about the universe.
You're never going to be able to know.
It's pointless to even try it.
Never got to know when the universe
began.
How the fuck do they know that?
How do you know that you're not going to
ever be able to know?
We are.
If our understanding is constantly
increasing.
Okay.
What we know today is so much more
advanced than what we knew just 100
years ago or 200 years ago or 300 years
ago,
you know,
a couple hundred years ago to get
around.
You have to be on a fucking animal.
Okay.
You wanted an image of someone.
You had to draw it,
right.
There was no cameras.
Right?
Think about that.
All right.
That's just a couple of hundred years
ago.
We don't know what the fuck kind of
innovations going to come up a couple of
100 years from now or a couple thousand
years from now.
It might very well be possible that not
only can we decipher exactly how the
universe began,
but we can probably.
We're probably going to be able to get
an accurate map of the history of the
planet from the very beginning to now
much more detailed,
much more precise than we have today.
We're probably going to be able to
recreate or capture every single moment
of every single day of every single hour
that that's ever existed.
That's it's all very possible.
They're going to get crazier and crazier
with time.
with breaking down the quantum mechanics
of the universe.
You know,
when you start getting into like the
crazy subatomic particles that disappear
and reappear and exist in two different
places at the same time or in a
superposition and these things that they
don't understand well.
As we get more and more understanding
and know more and more about the
weirdness of the world,
we're going to be able to figure out how
to fucking decipher it.
You know,
and it might be that like,
you know,
like a time machine when the,
when they invent a time machine or
something like that or,
or whatever the fuck you want to call
this next stage of understanding of
matter.
When they invented the idea of a time
machine is the only way you're gonna be
able to travel back in time.
It's once the first time machines
invented,
so they're going to invent a time
machine and you can't go before that,
but what you can do is anything from
that,
we'll be able to come back to that
point,
so everything that exists from now until
whenever you can access it,
as soon as they invent a time machine,
why not?
Why fucking not shit's going to get
crazy.
If you can do this,
nobody would have ever thought you could
be able to do this.
If you talked to someone in
Shakespeare's day and say,
do you think there's ever going to be
able to time where I've take something
out of my pocket and through the air,
I ask it a question like,
you could mean Wolfram Alpha.
You can't do that.
We can do that with Google.
You can google voice it.
You know what year did the Sistine
Chapel get built?
Bam.
They tell you instantly and if you get.
If it gets to a point and it's gone to
if they've got the google,
if it gets all Wolfram Alpha point,
we can have.
You can ask it a question,
you can give any answer or it can give
you any answer on any question of
anything that's ever happened ever that
human beings are aware of and you'll
have all the information right there
were you told that to people that lived
in Shakespeare's Day.
They were told you about her fucking
mind.
It's going to get crazier than this.
It has to because everything gets crazy.
What the fuck is next?
Sometimes I just drive in my car and I
sit in traffic and I go,
what the fuck is next?
Is there going to be some crazy new
thing that's going to change everything?
Like is it,
are we in a race between human beings
figuring out what the next thing is?
The next crazy innovation is or us just
completely fucking everything up with
polluting the fucking ocean and you
know,
nuclear explosions and wars and all that
other crazy shit.
Like are we in a race between like
Schumann retarded chimpanzee instincts
and technology?
You ever thought about it like that?
Like when we talk about like the peak
oil documentary that we watched,
we thought it was bullshit,
but the idea of peak oil is a terrifying
idea.
If it was true and if there was a finite
amount of oil and they do bust into it
and then we have,
we're fucked,
we have no oil.
Things could get really crazy like that
is really possible.
Are they going to come up with something
that's going to replace that and make
everything better and make everything
even more advanced and more simple and
more,
you know,
more natural to the,
to the environment.
Are they going to figure that out first
or are we going to run out of supplies
and resources first?
Like is that a battle is a battle
between the human retarded monkey
chimpanzee behavior of take,
take,
take.
Don't think about the future and
technology and innovation and the
ability to harness matter.
I think whatever happens is not going to
happen during our lifetimes.
I don't think so.
No.
I think something crazy,
a lifetime.
Twenty years ago when you were finger
banging,
that chick behind boulder,
Boston high school,
that was going to be a milkshake thing
with the same shit that is every year
something new technology.
Every year,
every year there's going to be after we
think the reaction to all this oil in
the ocean.
It's got to be a rehab.
It's going to be.
There's going to be innovation.
Some.
It's a horrible,
horrible disaster.
Some west coast,
you know what I mean?
Hopefully like what have jersey shore
and the whole east coast beach gets
destroyed and all those people for
summer vacations.
When it come to the west coast this
summer it might be.
It's too much of a drug to go from.
Problem with that show is there's so
many people like that and now think they
can be famous
too.
They can get on a fucking jersey shore,
bro.
I'm fucking auditioning for that.
I'm fake Tan and Everyday Glendale
lately.
No.
Glendale is off the hook now version.
Yeah,
the PR.
They use that to Psycho Mike from K rock
in La.
That the thing that he did the video
about,
uh,
about Glendale.
No,
dude,
it's hilarious.
It's all Armenians in Glendale.
I forget the fucking bit.
It's a really,
really funny song.
Did.
It's ridiculous.
This one place I go to Brooklyn,
it's one place to go to called a Sushi
joint.
It's like this change,
this strip mall.
It has like Ernesto outdoor stores and
there's a Sushi place,
but all the stores are like fashion
outlet and then like the windows are all
black and stuff like that.
And then the next thing is like
something else.
But what's weird is if you go by there
at like two in the morning,
none of those places are open.
But yet every single car there's like
100 cars in the parking lot.
It's like,
what the fuck is going on?
That's how Glendale is.
Everywhere you drive,
you see these fake rug stores and shit.
You know,
it's partly luck and armo party,
like an original song apparently.
I'm going to watch that later.
Uh,
yeah.
Somebody sent a,
I think the video.
I think Opie,
opie and anthony twitter the other day,
a nature's little flashlight.
And it was at monkey using a frog to
whack off like a fleshlight.
Yeah,
that's old school video.
Funny Video.
That monkey fucks that frog's mouth.
That's the monkeys are down for their
down for rape and shit.
You know,
we think about those champions to like
Bj and the bear.
We think they're all cute and shit.
Then you find out about like their chimp
at eight.
That lady's face.
And another chimp that fuck that dude up
and rip his balls off and ripped his
feet off.
Chimps eat babies.
Man.
There's been recorded instances of
chimps stealing babies and eating them.
What the Fuck Joe Rogan.
Why bother me with this shit?
I got to what was sitting there having a
good time.
Like gentlemen,
you got to talk to me about chimps.
Eat and babies.
What the fuck?
Kind of been a table conversation.
Is this cocksucker
he hit the two hour mark with me.
That's the two hour mark.
Yep.
Alright,
well we'll come up with one subject then
we're gonna.
Wrap this up.
Joey,
that's up to you.
The subject.
Uh,
you had a job before you fucking Brian.
You had to go with and stuff.
What was I talking about?
Senior,
old surf.
See?
No.
The other one before that.
You see going to bring it up during the
podcast.
Oh,
uh,
I thought.
I don't remember.
I can't order an iphone.
Shit.
Is this,
you're the fucking captain Kirk or this
program for a word from our sponsor from
1:00
AM to 3:00
AM.
Just trying to access the island.
No,
I wasn't.
I knew I wanted to talk about that
fucking guy.
That Christian warrior who went looking
for a lot.
Yeah.
That's what I wanted to talk about.
If you don't know this story,
there's a fucking dude who is this just
old white guy who's just Christian
warrior from America who put a fucking.
He got a sword.
He took a sword with them and a gun and
he went to the fucking mountains of
Pakistan and he went to the mountains of
Pakistan to try to find Osama bin Ladin
to kill him.
And they caught his ass.
Wow.
Like,
what are you doing dude?
They put them in jail.
I can't believe they didn't kill him.
I mean,
this guy was sitting in Kentucky or
somewhere and they said,
when they fuck it,
I'm sick and tired of waiting for a sign
to live.
This has been going on for 10 years.
Yeah.
That's borrowed money from his cousin
and he said,
fuck it.
I'll go over there like a boy scout.
He made that grace your bitch.
He ain't first you last a story.
A 52 year old American citizen who said
he was searching for Osama bin Laden was
detained in Pakistan near the border
with Afghanistan this week.
His name was Gary Faulkner from
California was carrying a pistol,
a sword night vision equipment and
Christian religious books.
What that might be,
the last guy in the world you want
looking for you.
The last thing,
the last dude in the world you want is a
52 year old man with a sword and a Bible
and he's.
He flew to the other side of the fucking
world,
defined you.
He's got religious books,
a gun and a Bible and a sore.
Oh my God.
Do.
There's guys like doubt out there,
out there,
and they're ready to go.
You've got to remember that it's
sometimes it's,
you know,
sometimes it's good to go online and
watch some fucked up videos just to know
that guy's out there.
I don't like watching murder videos,
but I watched one recently,
but the Mexican drug lords killed this
fucking guy.
I cut this guy's head off.
They showed a video.
They put that shit online.
Watch youtube.
I stopped watching this.
Who started cutting his throat.
Fuck that shit.
My am.
I need to watch the whole thing.
Apparently he cuts his whole head off.
The guy's squealing and making noises
and over that crap coming out of his
whole apparently terrible.
It takes awhile for them to saw his head
off and that's how they kill them.
Hard to watch,
man.
Hard to watch.
They tied the stood up,
you know,
just fucking cut his head off on video.
Next time you see a video like that,
go to kick [inaudible] dot com and white
stag instead it and refresh your memory
like gingers cake for this woman.
That puts a cake down and as he sits on
it and then she farts into the camera
and it's the icing and everything
bubbles.
That's such a little fucking Weirdo
because that.
That'd be like ginger to your fucking
taste buds.
After watching a d heading you up and
tell you about these websites.
It's all my website,
my message board,
you know I go to when I go to Joe Rogan
Dot net,
that forum,
the forum right now is over $3,
million posts.
Some guy emailed me that does go to cake
farts that come and watch that video.
It's just in the main forum.
There's 2 million,
737,000
posts now and then you count the retard
room and all the other shit on there.
There's more than 3 million posts or
anything that's fucked up.
Anything that's crazy.
And the Internet whenever it comes out,
it's like a portal to all things
interesting and fucked up.
So just it's my own website so I can't
get away from it.
If there's anything nutty that's out
there in the world,
I have the choice whether or not to
watch it,
but I don't have the choice whether or
not to know it exists because someone's
going to put it up there,
you know,
like that human centipede.
I ducked and dodged that human centipede
video for a long time because I thought
that it was like a short clip.
Something fucked up.
Like somebody who's mutated or someone
who did something crazy to somebody then
turns out it's just some Nettie horror
movie.
You know the whole story behind the
human centipede.
Did you go fucking see splice?
No.
I downloaded it,
but the people don't even who are
pirating it don't like the movie said it
like they don't care about the quality
of their torrance right now,
so I have to wait because it's so bad.
I couldn't even watch it.
I was like,
I can.
I'm not going.
I'm not going to pay to see this.
The bad version.
Horrible version like that.
Halfway through the camera,
man.
The sucks.
There's nothing funny.
The little ones,
will they do it in a movie theater when
someone like,
how did he get away with that shit?
Just put a little fucking tripod on
that.
A little thing where those soda sets,
they put a tripod in there,
Jack that sucker up and keep an eye out
the door.
People who've gotten caught,
they got caught.
No,
they would go into a theater in Chicago.
So the uh,
the became took codes and you have them
on the top side of your screen,
right?
Narrows it down to the theater and
that's how they know,
you know,
so they can break down the images and
they could find in the movie,
boom.
They go to the top feeder out of like,
where do we go?
What's that club we went to.
It wasn't Chicago but it was the one
with the older Sharpsburg.
It's right in that area because I don't
want them showing it.
And it was an AMC and AMC said fuck it.
So they put codes on the film then,
but how they know who did it,
they don't know who did it.
But I guess the theater is getting
charged for it,
so they have to make sure they have
ushers that go in and look for cameras
and grow.
They find the theater.
Right.
Well,
this theater here at this day that he
has this ring,
all the ushers were part of the rent.
Oh.
So that's how they knew that it was the
screen.
And I used to buy old school
back in New York.
We could walk down the street and be
walking home from a comedy club and
there'd be some fucking guy was.
He had a little box out looking for
people.
They just put that.
Put that video on the computer.
Yeah,
these guys would do it on vhs.
They would make copies and every fucking
copy would be,
you know,
Shittier and Shittier.
So if you came to the dude like a couple
of weeks after the movie was out,
you're getting like fourth and fifth
generation vhs copies of some fucking
Bruce Willis movie.
So tomorrow you're going to have bill
burr on the posts coming in tomorrow at
3:00.
Cool.
This weekend I'm in three different
places.
I'm going on a fucking mad candidate
tour.
I'll tell you where I'm at right now,
and we said,
well,
at the end we should always sponsor is
fleshlight.com
100 times in the contract we had to do
at the beginning of the contract.
Smarsh track.
Alright.
I'm in Saskatoon on Thursday night at
the Saskatoon Arts Intervention Center.
I'm in Grand Prairie,
Alberta at the Cran prairie regional
college and then I'm in Winnipeg and at
the Burton Cummings Theater.
So this is my just three Canada stop
weekend.
I'm looking forward to that.
Canada is always a good time.
They won't let Joey Diaz up there
because he's a fucking criminal.
You ever tried to get to Canada?
Yeah,
they turned me down two years ago.
What did I say?
Uh,
they didn't tell the club,
but it was,
it just said my passport was no good and
I didn't know what it was.
I know Canada is and let you in.
If you have a salt,
they don't let you in.
If you have a felony,
If you're a drunk driver,
they don't let you in.
If you're fucked up at all,
either Dui and they don't fuck around
man,
but you know what,
it's one of the reasons why Canada is so
nice candidates.
Fucking nice man.
People are nice and shit up there.
Especially in Vancouver because
Vancouver doesn't really get that cold
and now it doesn't get like Boston
called slows a little bit here and
there,
but it's mostly rain in the winter,
you know,
pretty temperate climate,
a little rainy and shit,
you know,
it gets rainy,
but Goddamn,
it's cool up there.
Restaurants are awesome.
People are cool.
The UFC,
there was fucking funny as shit.
I had a good time but I suck because I
couldn't do a show because they usually
have a.
I usually get booked at the uh,
red Robinson theater and unfortunately
they had a gig there already and they
couldn't cancel it and I couldn't.
So.
And they didn't want me doing a local
show.
We like a little place.
I'm like,
what if I just do like a little rock
club or something like that.
They wanted me to not do it totally.
They moved to UFC from Utah because they
couldn't sell tickets.
Selling tickets on Sunday.
Man,
that's a Jesus Day.
Awesome chick fil a deck.
Two in Utah is very religious man.
People are very religious.
You know,
it's a strong mormon community and a
strong religious community.
People don't want to go out on a Sunday
night.
It's tough.
It's amazing.
Who else?
The UFC cells like it's a Utah.
You can criticize that.
I could.
I'm saying myself,
but you know,
you're looking at Utah and I fucking
played there.
You know,
it's pretty,
pretty decent place to live and I heard
a lot of those Utah girls kind of
slowly.
Of course they are all religious.
You're fucking crazy.
They get a little crazy,
right?
The army base.
I used to drive up there from boulder
and shit.
If you want your kid to be a freak
number one rule of thumb is making
religious cause you're gonna get one or
two things.
You're going to get a really crazy
scared religious adult or you're going
to get someone who rebels just shocks
the first time they suck that 16.
She just stops.
She takes that fucking cross and the
cross curls up.
It's darker.
The Berry,
the sweeter the juice.
Fuck yeah.
She can't wait to get some black dick
too.
Right?
The crisis at target.
What?
The cross is a target for Brian.
You know,
I took it to a bad place.
There's no need to end the show on such
a sour note.
Baby.
Jesus.
Well Ladies and gentlemen,
if you want to follow Joey Diaz,
exploits on twitter is mad flavor on
twitter and a d f l a v O r m and a also
Joey Coco Diaz Dot com,
right?
Yeah.
Website.
Joey Coco Diaz Dot com.
And do you do do a facebook?
Facebook was just Joe.
It's out there.
What are we playing games here?
You want to fucking send me away?
So a follow them on.
Follow them on twitter.
Fucking hilarious dude.
Where you were?
You have this weekend?
Uh,
Donna sub,
uh,
on Friday bitches at the Hollywood bowl.
Oh,
you're going to go see.
Hey.
Ready?
Saying that you want to come right here?
I got fucking tickets.
They're adopting her in the hall of
fame.
He having sex with that night?
Nobody.
No one.
No.
But we can take a bus ride from your
house.
That dropped us off right in front of
the fucking starts to glow sticks.
I got.
And a pacifier.
Let's get this show.
Can we use your pacifier?
No.
You know what?
I forgot how fucking good domus Donna
summer was.
Really forgot.
I put it in the other day and I felt
really Good Friday.
No,
dude,
this is.
This is.
This is what I remembered.
I remembered when Joey Diaz told me,
Joey Diaz and I were at the fucking Bray
Improv.
Was it the brain?
We,
we're the brain improv and I pull up in
my truck,
has a real good sound system,
and he goes,
put this in your fucking car right now.
Joe Robin,
put this in your fucking car.
He goes,
put on his fucking track.
Put on this track so it puts on hot
stuff.
This fucking truck right here is this
guy to come out?
Yeah.
No.
So for you people on itunes just playing
a song and he's dancing and joey doing
joey ideas is doing the wave.
No joke.
And you could find me at five and some
weed to smoke.
Sorry for the fine right now.
I'm trying to turn it down because Jay
was going to kill all your ears.
Mute,
mute,
mute.
Mute your laptop.
Here we go.
Ladies and gentlemen,
that's not the most professional thing
in the world.
The point is.
Sorry about that.
Shouldn't that be pushing buttons over
here,
Brian?
I don't know what I'm saying.
It's me.
Shouldn't have.
I don't know what the fuck I'm doing.
The point is I forgotten a fucking good.
Donna summer was.
We were.
We were smoking a joint outside the
brain improv in the parking lot and joey
puts on hot stuff and and I wrote a song
about it.
I wrote,
I wrote a blog about it,
about Donna.
Summer was a bad ass.
It's amazing.
Somebody wrote a blog about that night
because it was so powerful.
I was listening to that music.
I'm like,
God damn,
that music was good.
That chick didn't give a fuck.
I had the opposite reaction happened to
me last week when I pit Donna summer on
a on a road trip and my girlfriend goes,
what are you a faggot?
I was like,
yeah,
this does sound pretty gay when you say
it like that.
She had some jamming songs were two p,
p,
p.
like I said,
she's a very intelligent girl.
Everyone's got their own taste.
Brian,
Donna summer is just totally
unnecessary,
but it's right every now and then you
got to respect that.
There's some shit that's not.
It's not like cool to like,
but it's fun.
Good.
I agree.
I was.
I was in a bar the other day and
journey.
Don't stop believing.
Started playing and I was like,
God damn,
that was good fucking song.
Oh my God.
Journey.
I listened to some of night will,
so it was ideal.
It was fucking great.
I'm like,
I forgot how good journey was.
The journey had some heads that guy had
a very unusual voice and God damn did he
connect with fat pitches.
Fat pitches will go crazy journey.
So Kenny,
the gambler and love that,
they love that chicken chicken company,
chicken company,
Kenny Rogers roasters and shit.
You know Jimmy Dean died.
Jimmy Dean,
sausage lead sources for 30.
That motherfucker was 81.
He just drank booze every day and
sausage and he lived to be 81.
Can you imagine the jokes and.
Haha.
Is he had with his wife at lunch.
You took my sausage,
you know,
Shit like that.
When that guy had so much money,
I bet he'd just mounted his wife's face.
Didn't even ask her questions.
Pull those pants.
I probably didn't even talk about it.
It's probably didn't say the thing.
He's so retched.
Polish sausage again,
bitch drinking whiskey.
Just fucking her mouth shoots a batch
town it's throat and walks out the door
and gets on a horse.
Can Be fucking Jimmy,
Jimmy Dean,
you know,
billion dollar sausage.
Empire.
And he started out as a musician,
right?
There wasn't.
It wasn't one of those fucking things.
Maybe it was.
You know what?
Good for him.
This episode is dedicated to you,
Jimmy Dean.
Good for you.
You motherfucker.
You met a living selling ground up
animals,
ground up pigs.
All right folks,
that's the end of this podcast.
Thank you for tuning in.
We will see you actually tomorrow.
We got to one tomorrow with bill burr.
Same Bat time,
same bat channel three PM.
Joey,
Coco Diaz,
ladies and gentleman,
a black baby brian red band.
Reichel laser.
Actually it was way.
No,
there we go.
Yeah,
we can't get to you.
Thanks everybody.
We'll see you next week or tomorrow.