I'm in a rush today.
Yes,
we live.
Gentlemen,
welcome back.
What's up Joe?
So I watched a documentary last night.
Holy Shit.
You Holy Shit.
Had me twice already.
Really Holy Shit at me with bigger,
stronger,
faster,
and now your holy shit at me with a
prescription.
Thugs.
It's kind of crazy,
right?
We have a $300,000,000,000 prescription
drug habit in this country,
yet we rank number 50 in life
expectancy.
It makes no sense.
Well,
it all came down to Ronald Reagan.
That's what's really crazy.
When they allowed people to allow
pharmaceutical companies to advertise on
television.
I can remember when those things first
started showing up.
Well,
it's,
well,
medicine turned into a business and when
it turned to a business that wasn't a
very good thing for the consumer.
No at all.
No,
it's terrible.
How much further do you think life
expectancy has changed over the last
hundred years?
A well over the last hundred years I
think it's changed dramatically,
but I think the last 50 years probably
not so much.
I mean,
from what I've seen,
it's about 20 years.
Not that much.
Well,
how much would you think it would be?
I don't know.
I just think it'd be more,
You hear about a modern medicine just
being such a big thing and it being able
to help you and.
But we also have a tainted food supply,
which we're talking about a little bit
that that's really hard to get healthy,
to be healthy.
Totally healthy.
Well,
it requires effort for sure.
It definitely requires you to pay
attention.
It definitely requires you to watch what
you eat and most people don't want to do
that.
But what's stunning to me,
I mean there was a lot of stunning
things in that documentary,
but the sheer numbers of prescription
pain pills that are prescribed in this
country every year,
that's staggering.
They said,
what was the actual quote that there was
enough pain pills to get every single
adult human in this country high for a
month,
for a month around the clock for a month
turned everybody zombies.
How fucking insane is that?
Kinda what we're doing.
I mean,
a lot of people are just walking around,
checked out and um,
you know,
one thing that I didn't know when I was
when I was addicted to painkillers was
actually ivy to Ibuprofen and Tylenol
has been clinically proven to be like
twice as effective as opiate
painkillers.
But if a doctor told me as a patient to
take Ibuprofen and tylenol together,
have like,
you're out of your mind,
give me the,
give me the good stuff that you wouldn't
feel he's doing enough for you.
Right.
I think that's a mentality that we have
and it's mentality that like I totally
admit to his family,
to a doctor I want,
I want to get a prescription,
but now I've changed that mentality.
But that's the mentality I did have.
Even if you go to a doctor and they give
you prescription Ibuprofen,
they give you 800 milligrams.
So two is four,
right?
It's 400 milligrams for two Ibuprofen
and then two tylenol,
which I don't know what the milligrams
of Tylenol is.
I don't usually take that,
but I have arthritis really bad.
My knees,
I had my hips replaced at 33 years old.
My ankles hurt everyday.
Everything and the advil and tylenol
combination has been knocking it out of
the park for me.
It actually learned that from doing
press for this movie.
I learned that from Dr drew of all
people.
Really?
Yeah.
That's incredible.
And how long you've been doing that?
Like two,
two advil in two Ibuprofen,
two months about.
And it makes a big difference.
It just helps me get through the day.
Helps me be pain free,
you know.
The other thing that a lot of people
talk about that I think just definitely
needs to be talked about is medical
marijuana because I'm an addict and I've
been through Rehab and everything.
I don't personally use it,
but I think for people that don't have a
problem with consuming everything,
I think it can be great.
So you have a problem too in the sense
that like even marijuana,
something that's not physically
addictive.
Once you start smoking that you'll want
other things.
And I'm only.
I've only been,
been sober about 22 months so I just
feel like I'm not ready to really take
that dive because I might smoke some
weed and then ended up,
you know,
taking some pills and drinking and
jumping in the pool naked and going to
jail.
You know,
what if you just get naked for jumping
in the pool naked if you get arrested
for that.
But that wouldn't be the end of it.
I would keep going.
He and I were talking the other day a
little bit about like,
you know,
everybody wants to justify their drug of
choice.
You know,
obviously I've been on performance
enhancing drugs for a long time and so
everybody wants to justify,
oh it's not addicting or it's not this
or not that.
It is addicting.
Any behavior that you practice over and
over again is going to become addicted
and like the side effects to it,
you know,
like some of the field to it.
So everybody,
I think a lot of times kind of kidding
themselves and they're saying,
oh,
pot doesn't do anything.
Or you know,
it's like,
well it does something.
It doesn't make you function the best
probably,
you know,
it certainly can be psychologically
addictive.
Certainly.
I mean,
it,
it helps her functioning in some ways.
That's one of the things that people
have gotten mad at me for a fucking bad
ass at video games,
that's for sure.
What else you at pool for sure helps of
music.
Like honestly,
I,
they're like God put everything if you
believe in God or whatever,
but we have a system like everything is
put on this earth for a reason and if,
you know,
they always say let medicine hypocrisy
said like let medicine be thy cure and
the cure be medicine,
food be medicine or whatever.
So like food as medicine is something
that tracy is like way back,
you know,
so things that are found on the earth
that we can use rather than
synthetically make.
And I think it just makes logical sense.
Well,
yeah.
Well it definitely is.
Probably a smarter way to do it is
healthy.
His name is hypocrisy,
right?
Isn't that awkward?
So
awkward.
You're onto something eponymous one of
them old dead Greek motherfuckers.
Yeah,
but the,
the,
the sheer numbers of oxycontins and pain
pills that are being prescribed in this
country.
It's a,
I was watching this television show
where they were talking about
Massachusetts and the problem.
Oh,
it was Anthony Bourdain show.
That's what it was.
And they were talking about all these
people that got hooked on pain pills
because they're good injured from some
job related or something,
or another doctor gives you a oxy
prescription,
your oxygen prescription runs out or
they changed the regulations and then
everybody turns to heroin.
And that's a big problem in this country
where they've changed the regulations.
Um,
and there was another that you talked
about on your,
on your documentary where they changed
the way Oxycontin's work or you can't
crush them up and smoke them anymore and
they lost 80 percent of their revenue
from that.
Yeah,
absolutely.
And that's something that just shows you
that people are using them
recreationally.
And how insane is that?
Yeah.
So that was one of the most staggering
facts of the whole movie I thought.
But we just came back from the Arnold
classic and we know there's some guys
dead lifting.
We went to this pro deadlift event and
these guys are pulling seven,
800 pounds.
One guy was kind of in an almost a 900
pound range,
but he ran into somebody backstage at
said he just,
he just saw the film and he lost his son
to what?
Heroin,
right.
It started as oxycotton.
It went to heroin where you go.
And he told me,
he said,
you know,
I wasn't gonna,
I wasn't gonna lift anymore.
I just gave up on everything.
I saw your movie like a couple months
ago.
And I said,
you know what,
I'm going to go,
I'm going to go dead lift at this
program thing.
And he said,
you're a movie.
Made it possible for me to get over what
happened to my son to realize like,
it wasn't so much his fault.
Right as he thought.
And so,
um,
I think just stuff like that,
like he told me that I was completely
fine talking to the guy.
I walked away,
just started bawling because I know that
you can even affect one person and
that's the power of film and
documentaries.
That's,
that's what we're trying to do.
Well in.
That guy's on the right track because he
said that now I feel it's my duty to
help other people and I think that's the
way people need to try to look at stuff
is to try to,
you know,
we're,
we're here as human beings to learn from
experiences and then I think we're all
put here to help each other.
Well can definitely help.
I mean for someone like that to reach
out and find other people who have also
lost people and you can help each other
and you can also maybe help someone who
is maybe thinking or would go down that
path and watches your documentary and
says,
well,
there's a real danger here.
Yeah.
The place that I went to cliffside
Malibu.
I have three people or three people
right now that are in Rehab there that
have contacted me from watching the film
and it's really hard to get into a lot
of rehabs because of insurance
companies.
And that's it,
that's another huge problem in this
country is the insurance companies don't
they want to pay for.
They expect somebody to be smoking,
drinking,
doing whatever for 30 years and on wine
that in 15 days.
And that's just not gonna happen.
You know,
people need 90 days of treatment.
If you're going to go to a drug rehab,
you need 90 days and so you need 90 days
where you're not working 90 days where
you're just staying in this place.
Why?
Why is it 90 days?
Think about this.
You're working right and you're a drug
addict.
What productive work are you doing?
Like let the guy go for 90 days,
he's going to come back a new person.
I think that that,
that we have to,
we have to unplug.
There's,
there's no other way.
I mean,
I think that it just leads to an early
death,
you know,
if we don't,
that's so hard for people to have work
that they need to get money now you can
get,
you can,
you can get out a little bit,
right?
Like wait,
like you did,
right?
Yeah,
yeah,
exactly.
I actually made this movie while I was
still in Rehab,
so there's definitely time to do things.
I think that,
um,
you know,
you've got to look at it this way.
Like,
okay,
I can like almost like killing people
find inside jail.
Yeah.
That's
pretty talented.
Take.
I can't take 90 days to like just
completely like fix my life,
you know,
I think I dunno.
I think time is more important to get to
give the time.
And you need like a full 60 though where
you're pretty much total isolation right
through the first 30 days or actually
lives pretty much totally kind of
unplugged from everybody.
You just stayed up there.
And what,
what do you do with your time?
You're in a lot of meetings,
you know,
it's all like peer groups,
you're basically like with other people
that are addicted to drugs.
And I would say like probably 80 percent
of the people that were in rehab or
prescription drug.
Do you know what one of the most
effective methods of stopping people
from doing drugs is Ibogaine.
It's a psychedelic ritual drug that they
do.
You can,
you can't do it in America,
it's illegal,
but they have clinics in Mexico.
My Buddy ed clay,
he got hooked on pills and he had a real
problem with same thing,
pain pills and was really despondent and
fucked up.
Went down there,
did a,
an Ibogaine ceremony and uh,
came back 100 percent clean and now he
runs a clinic down there.
Any idea what that does for you?
Like do something your brain,
we could google it,
but there's some sort of an effect that
it does.
We're literally shuts down addiction and
it's deeply troublingly introspective
too.
Like it explores the dark
site.
They're fucking crazy.
I don't know anything about it.
I'm hearing it for the first time,
but address from one,
this is the first time you've heard of
Ibogaine.
Haven't haven't really ventured into
that and to figuring that out.
But um,
wow.
I'd never heard of it.
You know,
that's the crazy thing about doing these
documentaries,
like you're going to meet other
interesting people like yourself and you
pick up more knowledge now.
That's something I was like,
okay,
well what is this,
you know,
and go look into that.
So,
but what you're saying makes a lot of
sense because it all,
it's all in the brain.
You create these pathways in your brain
that just basically you habituate and
you do the same thing that you like and
it's the same thing with lifting weights
or doing Jujitsu or do you tend to that?
That feels really good.
I like it.
I'm going to go to Jujitsu again,
I'm going to go to the gym again,
you know,
so it definitely makes sense that it's
something that will trigger some
than in the brain to fix it.
You know?
It also,
apparently I haven't done Ibogaine,
but the people that I know that have had
problems with pills and gone down there
and done it,
and also people that have also had other
problematic behavior that they wanted to
correct.
It allows you to look at yourself
literally for the first time in like a
deeply introspective of almost
abrasively way.
Not,
not almost,
but very abrasively in,
in,
in that it looks at every aspect of your
person
and that's part of Rehab.
You have to be honest with yourself.
If you're not honest with yourself,
you'll never get better.
No,
I'm sure.
I'm sure people that are bullshit and in
line and that's why one of the reasons
why it's so important to hit rock
bottom,
right?
Yeah.
I used to say I could stop any day.
My girlfriend said,
well stop.
And I said,
okay.
And I stopped for seven days and after
seven days I took pills and drank more
than I ever did in my entire building
up.
Yeah.
It was like,
yeah,
exactly.
I ended up in the hospital and my
girlfriend called my brother and he was
the one who was like,
Hey,
just get him here.
Like he was in Sacramento.
He said,
just get them here.
I actually just moved.
It was crazy just to get.
I got a random phone call in the middle
of the night.
I don't normally answer my phone all
that much.
Um,
and just,
you know,
I,
I just randomly picked it up for some
reason it was from a Philadelphia or
Pennsylvania right in the column there.
That's where she's from originally.
And she was just in a total panic.
I couldn't understand what she was even
talking about.
I didn't even know who it was.
She was like,
this is lauren.
And I'm like,
well,
I don't know any chicks.
I'm married.
So I'm like,
you know,
I,
I don't,
I don't know who it is.
And then it took me a while.
Then I finally heard her say,
you know,
Chris's girlfriend,
and I was like,
Oh shit,
you know,
what the fuck is this?
Like the second call my losing another
brother,
what the fuck's going on here?
And then she started to calm down and
she said,
well,
don't know you're,
you lost both of you guys lost your
older brother to drug abuse,
right?
Yeah.
Mad Dog.
It had a lot of people say,
uh,
after they see bigger,
stronger,
faster,
which was the first film that featured
my family and it,
everybody asks about mad dog because
everybody in that,
after watching that film worried about
him and a lot of concern,
they don't even know that he passed
away.
Some days you're fine handling it
because I feel like it's our obligation
to kind of talk about it to help other
people,
but sometimes you're just not ready for
the blind sides and it's just fucking
hurts.
Like a mother fucker.
This week at the Arnold Classic,
there was so many things that reminded
me of my brother because he grew up in
the wrestling,
bodybuilding at all.
Matt does that Shit.
He ain't eating that shit up.
And then.
And then his best friend Jeff lybolt
showed up at mark's booth.
Mark had a booth there selling all these
products and he shows up and it just
gives you like,
we love Jeff.
He's great,
but it gives you that feeling like,
man,
this was my brother's best friend and my
brother's not here to tugs,
tugs at your heart a little bit and it's
hard to talk to him about it,
you know,
if I bring up Mike's name,
uh,
you know,
Jeff gets upset and we don't know.
We just,
we will all wash.
I just trying to deal with this tragedy
and I was dealing with it in the wrong
way.
I was burying my feelings with drugs and
alcohol and his girlfriend saved his
life though.
She called me and she said,
you know,
I don't know what to do.
I don't know how I'm going to find them.
I'm outside his apartment now.
And I said,
well,
you're the only person there that he has
that's like,
you know,
that's kind of like family.
I was like,
you need to go inside the apartment,
make sure he doesn't have any keys and
just make sure he's alive,
you know,
checking on him.
So she did all that.
She made sure he was okay.
He was,
luckily he was okay,
but he was just passed out.
And uh,
then my wife and I came together and
just devise a plan to figure out how the
fuck do we get them to Sacramento,
you know,
how,
what are we going to do?
Like,
so we were talking about it and I was
like,
well if I just book a flight for him,
he's not going to fucking come.
Probably like tomorrow morning he's not
going to feel fine and be like,
all right,
got an 8:00 AM flight,
you know,
going through it.
I feel so fragile now.
Like I'm a completely different person
after going through that.
It humbles the shit out of you.
It
makes you just feel like,
like I feel really fragile.
I don't sometimes I don't know how to
deal with people or how to talk to
people because I'm just completely
different than I was before I went
through it.
So this is just in a couple of years?
About five years.
Yeah.
I've being on being on pills and
tractable when he felt invincible when I
was doing it.
And now I feel so vulnerable and I don't
know why that is,
but it's something that I think is
definitely a warning to anybody out
there that's thinking of getting on
prescription drugs or prescription drugs
pushed on them from their doctor.
Remember the advil and tylenol works
better than opiate painkillers and
people can look that up and you don't
walk away from it feeling like I feel
I know this guy who has a back injury
and he was always.
He always was weird.
I was always trying to figure out what,
what his deal was.
He always just seemed awkward,
awkward,
but socially like not like
inappropriate,
but like almost fearless,
like oblivious and clumsy.
And I was always like,
what the fuck is going on with this guy?
And we were trying to figure it out.
Like there's something,
there's something going on.
And then one day he goes,
hey,
um,
what's,
uh,
what's going on with this cryo therapy
thing?
Started asking me about cryotherapy.
I said,
well,
it's really good for reducing
inflammation.
Helps a lot with people with arthritis.
It's great for a,
it helps your body.
Rick kickstart.
It's a production of Collagen.
It's really good for a lot of things.
It's good.
I like it for the anti-inflammation
benefits,
like,
why would you,
uh,
what do you think am I said,
oh,
I got this back problem I've had for
years.
And then it clicked.
I go,
Oh,
you're on pills.
Pills all the time as a mother.
Because he would be like,
hey,
how are you guys doing?
What's going on over?
How's.
Everybody wasn't like that,
you know,
sometimes people are friendly,
but they're like,
are you okay with me being in front of
just like a little touch and go there,
figuring it out.
This guy was just falls
out loud.
He wasn't shit pilled up man.
It was,
um,
we were uh,
together with a bunch of other friends
that we know.
He was just,
it was,
it was odd.
We were trying to figure it out.
Like not a bad guy,
but just,
just this weird,
like almost like I was envious.
Like,
why is this guy so confidence?
He's like,
fucking outerspace.
I wish you guys go.
Was it good?
It looks good.
Looking at a good time.
All right.
I brought you over here.
It was weird.
I was always trying to figure out what
was going on with this guy.
And then once he approached me,
started asking me about the Cryo therapy
thing and how,
because I do it all the time.
Then he,
uh,
started slowly revealing that he's had a
pretty traumatic,
a back surgery or a back injury.
The thing that was great for me that
happened a doing bigger,
stronger,
faster and doing this movie is you
become almost like a priest where people
come to you and confess.
And so everybody comes out of the
woodwork.
You made a movie.
He said,
hey,
I do pills,
or hey,
I take steroids.
Big Deal,
you know,
and you talk about what happened and
what the effects were and what the
negative effects were.
And people just come to you and say,
Hey man,
I've
had a pill problem for 20 years,
you know,
and you're like,
that's,
that's how these people got into Rehab.
Are they called me?
Uh,
I actually,
uh,
a kid that worked on the movie,
he worked on the movie and he was
actually the president of the company's,
like a brother and he was the one that
called me and said,
hey,
look,
I know I've worked on.
You're moving everything.
I have a problem though,
you know,
after I saw the movie,
I just need to fix it.
What do I do?
Isn't it incredible?
These fucking people that are running
for president,
not a single one has brought any of this
shit up.
We're talking about a massive epidemic
where people are dropping like flies.
People were being addicted.
It's not sexy.
Probably things we'll talk about is a
dark thing to talk about.
Even watching a movie.
It's kind of a dark thing to get into,
not just that,
it's that they can't talk about it
because then they'll face repercussions
for pharmaceutical industry.
Trump is the only person that can talk
about it,
you know?
I hope he does.
I hope he does too.
I think it's donald trump's
responsibility.
Donald trump are calling you out right
here that we're calling you out,
Donald.
Goofy.
Fuck,
I swear I'll vote for you if you say
something about he's listening.
Bell Brothers,
Ronnie,
he's into it.
He's kind of busy,
but you know,
I think that that's,
that's a big problem is that one of the
biggest problems this country special
interest because it doesn't matter what
it is.
Like there's all these special interests
including the corn industry trying to
push high fructose corn syrup on it.
Yeah.
Anything you're looking at.
There's a sugar lobby,
there's the corn lobby,
there's lobby for everything and it just
twists the truth around and makes
people,
you know,
maybe you know,
vote for things that they maybe
wouldn't.
It's interesting though that that
statistic that when they changed the
Oxycontin,
when they changed the formula where you
couldn't crush it and smoking,
they lost 80 percent of their profit.
At least that tells us that some people
are looking out in the right direction
and absolutely they're doing so because
of things like your documentary and it's
one of the most important things about
doing a documentary like that.
It starts this conversation and people
start talking about it and you start
comparing notes and they start realizing
like,
wow,
these are people that I know people
around me.
It's just this is a giant issue.
I have to say,
like in my movie,
a lot of people wanted me to give more
answers.
What's the solution?
I'm like,
I don't really have a solution.
This is a giant problem that we need to
talk about and come up with bigger
solutions because I'm just a documentary
film maker.
I'm just telling you what happened in my
life.
I'm not trying to run for president.
I'm not trying to make a make a law
about this.
I'm just like,
hey man,
this is a big problem.
What are we supposed to do about it?
And that's what I think that's
collectively as a country,
we come up with what the solution is a
real problem in that these people that
sell these things are making ungodly
amounts of money.
When you showed that seminar that they
had where they were all talking about,
you know,
you guys are going to make insane
amounts of money and they were just
openly talking about how their drug
patch right here actually wrote this
down,
this drug it's called Avandia,
was for diabetes,
right?
And so they're given this drug to all
these people with diabetes and the
dropping dead.
One third of the people that were
prescribed
the drug were dying from it.
Right?
And so what it was was a drug for
diabetes that actually gave you a heart
attack.
And most of the people that have
diabetes,
that's the number one cause of death,
right?
So when you look at that,
you go,
okay,
well how did this company get away with
it?
Well,
when they made the drug,
they packed away $6,000,000,000 in an
account just to basically,
you know,
they,
they put $6,000,000,000.
Why?
Because they knew they were going to get
sued and they ended up getting,
getting sued only for 3 billion.
Like,
oh,
okay,
cool.
But they made like $20 million on the
drug.
It's,
it's ridiculous.
The things that are going on that are
getting covered up and nobody's talking
about like in the film,
I don't know if you saw that drug that
was made in the United States.
It was tainted with AIDS.
It was tainted with the AIDS virus and
they said,
you know what?
Well we can't lose this big batch of
drugs.
Let's send it to France.
What is.
I don't understand that though.
How does the AIDS virus get into this?
What is the AIDS virus?
You're talking about HIV.
I have no idea.
I have no idea,
but that's where the news report says
it.
Say the news report was all grainy and
it was from 1985.
They might not know what the fuck
they're talking about now.
It would definitely was something that I
was a head scratcher and I actually have
a guy.
There's a guy that works out at mark's.
Jim just got his phd and he was going to
go work for the company bear.
That was a company that sold.
They make their aspirin everything.
That's a company that did it and I was.
One of the things he was.
He was talking about,
he's like,
I don't know if I want to work for a
company like that.
Yeah,
we need to snopes snopes that before you
put it in the documentary.
Actually,
actually,
yes.
We have a big team.
Taste tastes a few of those.
When we do these documentaries,
we have.
Look at this,
we have a team of people.
Fact check everything.
The little larger police here it goes.
Recently,
unearth documents show that the drug
company beer sold millions of dollars
worth of injectable blood clotting
medicine factor eight,
concentrate intended for haemophiliacs
to Asian Latin American in some European
countries in the mid 19 eighties.
Although they knew it was tainted with
aids.
So yeah,
that's what I understand.
Like how so
tatum aids go together.
That makes sense.
Cool.
Ten years ago,
uh,
so as the company stopped selling the
drug in the United States in 1984,
but continue to sell it overseas for an
additional year,
the medicine was made using a combined.
Oh,
okay.
Plasma from large numbers of donors.
And at the time there was no screening
test for eight for the AIDS virus.
So a tiny number of donors with AIDS
could inadvertently contaminate a large
batch.
Whoa.
They continued to sell the medicine
overseas and attempt to avoid being left
with a large stock of a drug that was no
longer marketable in the United States.
Well,
you know,
that's what they also did with that aids
medication.
Um,
what does that stuff that was fucking
killing everybody act,
act,
uh,
act was initially a chemotherapy
medication,
but it was killing cancer patients
quicker than the cancer was.
And they push that through because the
aids epidemic was so huge.
They pushed that through so fast and
then they knew it wasn't
working and they kept pushing,
pushing,
and just not working.
It was fucking killing.
Yeah,
absolutely.
And they,
they used to call hades the gay cancer.
That's what they thought it was at one
point in time,
you know,
it's the whole thing is just disgusting.
It's so terrifying when you think of a
company that's valuing money in,
at such a high level that they're
willing to do something like that and
ship this tainted drugs to these other
kinds of.
I don't even know these people.
Right.
Just send it over there.
Fuck France.
Exactly.
Yeah.
It's crazy.
And they're still in business.
The thing is they market.
They market to the doctors so much that
they put,
they spend like $5 million on marketing
us and like 25 billion marketing to the
doctors.
So they're telling the doctors that to
like push these drugs and push these
treats treatments on people.
And if you look at the statistics of
like Medicare,
there's like 30,000 people every year
that die from treatments that they
didn't even need.
And that's a fact.
That's like a medicare fact.
It's like why are we,
how are we giving people medicine that
they don't need?
It's killing them.
It makes no sense.
You know,
it's like,
it's all because of money and they don't
really know what the medicines will do
to people and they just keep giving it
given,
uh,
given how harmful are some of the other
drugs,
like the restless leg syndrome.
And like I saw one the other day that
said they have a medication for if you
laugh too much or if he cries too much
or whatever.
But it gave me that she smoked pot,
take this truck,
they restless leg syndrome.
Is that bullshit?
Like what is that?
I actually have a experience that
because I've had like surgery,
I have like a weird circulation things
what I feel is right when they were
like,
what happens is like it's on days I had
too much caffeine or too much sugar.
It's,
I feel it's like something that's like
self induced.
But uh,
it actually is something that is rare,
you know,
it's very rare but it's something that
they advertise and you know,
so it only would happen if there was
external things involved for me.
Yeah,
I dunno.
I Dunno if,
if,
if it's completely like surgeries and
stuff.
And here's the thing though.
A lot of things aren't completely a
myth.
Like a lot of things.
Maybe a fact like point zero,
zero,
one percent of the population go,
how do I get that to effect,
you know,
30 percent of the population.
Well,
I advertise the shit out of it and make
people feel like they have restless leg
syndrome,
so I'll get all the caffeine addicts.
He'll get all the sugar addicts and you
know,
let's go.
Yeah.
It's marketed to those people,
you know,
another thing that's really
controversial that you touched on in
your documentary that I think is a
really important thing to discuss.
His depression,
you know,
depression,
depression is a big one,
man.
It's a big one because it's so hard to
lock down.
Whether or not this is a.
is it a medical condition or is it just
a state of your life right now?
Is it you reacting to all the doctor
itself to really hard as a friend going
through rehab and I feel great and I
turn on like,
how do you feel buddy?
You know,
I'm trying to help these people too and
we're all helping each other.
Right?
And like so good.
Oh,
I'm depressed about what we're,
we're in,
you know,
in a,
in Malibu or in a beautiful place and
they're just depressed and you don't,
you can't understand it.
I think it's something that we just
don't know enough enough about it,
enough how to treat it and I think we
treated with pills that make you a
Zombie so you just don't feel it and we
never faced stuff that causes more
depression.
Even like alcohol and stuff like that.
Also all sorts of other factors
involved,
like what are you doing with your life?
Like how much of your life is spent
doing productive,
enjoyable things will kind of support
group.
Do you have as far as your friends,
are your friends like really happy,
really healthy people?
Are you engaging in a lot of physical
activity?
Are you eating healthy?
Are you getting enough rest?
Are you drinking enough water?
All those things are a big factor.
Huge.
You are you doing what you want to do
with your life?
It's hard to explain.
I have a friend that has an awesome
family.
He's got a ton of money.
He's got everything that you could see
from the outside that we might want as a
human being.
Right?
Yeah.
That's really cool.
He's got.
He can do whatever he wants.
Right?
Beautiful Wife,
great kids,
but he's depressed and I'm like,
well I have no idea how to help that.
Like zero,
you know,
other than like he needs to go see a
therapist.
That's like Kinda the only way that you
can treat it because I think like us as
friends don't just don't understand it.
Well,
I think there's no one answer that works
with everybody.
Some people really suffer with any sort
of balance,
you know?
Sometimes people get these extreme highs
and extreme lows,
but it's hard for them to like ride it
out in the middle.
We've heard before,
we're like from our friends at like
wrestle a,
you know,
that they'll get this huge high,
much like yourself going out in front of
a big audience can be all fucking fired
up,
be funny as hell and then you got to go
home and your wife's like,
he didn't take out the garbage,
like hard to go back to being a dad and
have a normal,
a normal role in the household because
there's no like fans cheering for you.
So I think a lot of those guys were,
the ups and downs are so wild,
but,
but it's also,
you know,
it's,
it makes it 10 times worse because
they're doing a lot of drugs,
you know,
so the highs and lows or even amplified
even more.
Not only that,
but there's also a lot of trauma going
on with their body and their brain.
I think that plays a giant factor and a
really do.
I know a lot of people that have had a
lot of physical trauma and they have
almost all of them have a hard time with
depression.
But being happy as a choice.
I think,
you know,
he and I talk about this kind of stuff
all the time and I've seen people that
have their fucking legs blown off or
more and they got the biggest fucking
smile on their face.
We've seen some people in some pretty
shitty situations I have.
He has a guide as Jim.
This Guy Bryce.
He's trying to figure out how to dead
lift with one leg.
He doesn't have a prosthetic leg.
He's trying to figure out a deadlift any
days all the way up.
Yeah.
He's all the way up by the hip so he
can't.
A prosthetic can kind of work but not
really know,
but yeah,
we've seen people in all kinds of shitty
situations and they still got to.
They're still fucking smile and they're
still finding other things to live for,
whether it's lifting weights or doing,
you know,
fucking climbing rocks or whatever the
hell it is they're doing.
Does she,
like you said,
doing some productive shit.
Pursuing enjoyable activities is a big
one.
Pursuing something that you really have
a passion for,
like as a career is another big one.
I think there's a lot of people that
feel that soul sucking grind of day to
day nine to five doing something they
hate is just unbelievably taxing as like
being a filmmaker.
Every film I've done have done three of
them that I've directed and one of that
I produced it every time.
It's about raising the money and getting
going and it's just so hard and it's a.
I would get depressed in between
projects,
so I'd have like these great highest,
a bigger,
stronger,
faster.
Came out at Sundance Film Festival.
Everybody's talking about is 96 percent
on rotten tomatoes.
I'm up here.
Then I got to go get money to make the
next movie and I'm down here because I'm
broke.
I have no money.
You don't make a lot of money on these
things and it's just an up and down
business and then at least you're doing
it for you.
Sure.
And after,
but after all of it,
after all said and done,
because it's not about the money,
it's about for me doing something
awesome.
You know,
at the end of the day I talked to my
brother after I got sober and he said,
you know what man?
You're biggest problem is you don't need
anybody.
You've done it all yourself already.
Why do you need anybody?
You don't need anybody to help you just
keep doing what you're doing and that's
like,
that gave me so much confidence and
empower yourself to empower yourself and
build confidence.
Confidence is huge and in depression,
I'm not depressed anymore.
I don't feel,
I don't have a project right now and
money for practicing now,
but I don't care because it's like,
yeah,
we'll get it,
we'll do it.
We've done it before.
You know,
so I think that building your own
confidence is big in getting over the
depression.
Got To be a certain amount of depression
that's allowed to,
you know,
something terrible happens.
You gotTa,
you gotta allow for some of that.
Allow for some of that to come in and
just to happen.
Even not even terrible.
Like for me,
I'll fuck up one joke and a killer set
where I get a standing ovation at one
joke will fuck my head up man.
I will.
I'll just be driving home going,
fuck,
I'll just,
I'll sit at home.
I'll go over that.
Yeah.
What about Ronda Rousey?
You know,
after the law,
you know what she said on Ellen
degenerate.
That to me that was the coolest fucking
thing that woman has ever done.
That.
That was really neat to me.
Like I'm a huge fan of hers anyway.
I think she's amazing,
but that was fucking awesome to kind of
hear her.
Just lay it,
lay it all in a line.
That's a lot going on there.
On top of that,
there's also like head trauma.
There's like that.
You're going to be depressed.
It was just no way around it.
Not,
not just be the fact that she was the
highest of highs as far as celebrity sco
and then she just gets shit on all over
social media.
I mean I read just a few of the things
that he sold people,
all the memes and all the crazy shit
like people,
you know,
they're probably just not even thinking
and we all have fun with different
stuff,
but they're trying to be funny,
you know,
trying to be funny,
trying to be clever,
man can't.
You can't look at it if you're Rhonda.
I mean that's also part of what comes
with being that huge
project.
Mcgregor kind of handled it.
I thought I saw on your instagram you
said,
hey,
this is the best way that he handled it.
Like a fucking man.
He went out there,
he put a picture of him struggling with
a nice suit on and he said,
I went out there and I took a shot.
I will not apologize.
It will stop being me.
And then he wrote Dosantos,
you are a pussy,
although you are a pussy.
That great.
Great.
Back to talking to shit.
Yeah,
exactly.
It's what made him and he said he's
going right back to it,
you know,
and the thing is if he,
if he loses more fights or whatever,
that might get worse and it might go
away,
but if he,
what if he doesn't,
you know,
you become a legend forever,
so he can,
he'll get better,
he'll get better and he'll learn and you
know,
that's.
But that's beside the point.
I think I'm lowe's,
like you said,
are important because what a bad feeling
does for me,
someone who's really hard on themselves
when they screw up one thing and it
really drives me nuts that what that
does is that motivates me to be more
focused and more intense and pay more
attention to what I'm doing.
And if I don't do that,
I will feel that same thing again,
you know,
and there's like a certain amount of,
uh,
like those bad feelings where things go
wrong.
You just got to accept in your life,
you know,
like breakups,
breakups are devastating for people.
You know,
like when someone breaks up with you,
sometimes you feel like they stole a
part of you,
they stole some of your happiness.
It's a huge investment to be in a
relationship with somebody.
But you got to realize when that's over,
when that breakups over,
like,
hey man,
like this is,
this gives you an opportunity to move on
and to get your life in order better and
to,
to look at yourself,
give it to be by yourself for a while
and understand how much you value a
healthy relationship.
He's had a lot of good ones,
bad ones.
He had a girl call him up and say,
we can't date anymore because I have
cancer by that set.
And it was over and she actually have
cancer.
No big lie.
It's part of this whole guys got nothing
story.
I mean,
how is she going to get rid of,
you know,
what,
uh,
what else can you say?
Listen,
you're just not fun.
Yeah,
you're fat and ugly.
You got a small Dick,
you know,
I guess I have cancer pie.
It's not that bad,
but you know,
those,
those are important and you know,
you don't want to be with that person
anyway if that's how they feel about
you.
You got to find the person that really
likes you or you gotta figure out how to
become someone who people like.
And that's part of the struggle of
developing as a human being too.
And that's a Rut that some people never
get out of.
Some people they get into this Rut like
in high school,
like in dating in high school and
college and they fucking never get out
of that.
They're always in combative,
shitty relationships forever and they
never pause and reset.
They never have like a relationship.
Rehab was a lot.
It takes a lot of strength to walk away
from anything that you have invested
time in.
Right?
Yeah.
I mean even shitty relationships.
At least they have familiarity to them.
I think,
you know,
Ronda Rousey,
she said,
if I'm not this,
then what am I like?
To me that was a huge statement.
You know,
that people are always,
uh,
being defined by other people.
You got to be defined by yourself.
It's got to come,
it's got to come internally.
It's got to be hard for her because she
is such a mega star and she is known as
a fighter.
She knows,
you know,
the most dominant female fighter of all
time.
So it's got to be.
So it's also like that kind of success,
like that kind of love and notoriety is
so unnatural.
So that high is so unnatural.
It's strange.
It's like almost like the Oxycontin of
achievement.
You when you are,
you're achieving something athletically.
It's not as simple as like say like the
bench coach.
Hey,
a fight,
which was probably like her highlight.
She goes down to Brazil,
she gets cheered,
she fights his girl,
knocks her out in the first round,
struts around like a peacock.
The whole world's cheering for.
She's on top of the world.
Everything.
Well,
what actually really happened,
what would actually really happen was
there's two people and they're engaging
in an activity and one person is better
at that activity and the other person
and only better by a hair or a margin
like this.
One person is more of a brawler and
she's much more nervous and she makes
mistakes and then the other person is
better under pressure and she connects
with better shots and then the other
person gets hit on the button and it
goes down like the actual actual events
of what happened or not.
That big of a deal.
I mean it happens in gyms all across the
world,
but the fact that it's on this big
stage,
the fact that so many eyes are on that
moment gets magnified so the result gets
magnified,
so it becomes this really unnatural
state where everybody loves you for this
brief moment and you're walking around
glory,
glory.
The glory also comes with the potential.
Any high comes with the potential of a
corresponding low.
I mean there's just no way around.
It's exactly.
The thing that killed our brother was
was that he constantly wanted to be in
the wwe,
constantly wanted to be something and
when people told him like,
Hey,
you're,
you're getting too old for this or
you're not in shape enough for this.
Like he couldn't really handle that.
Now.
That was a big part of his depression
was he was trying to be defined by this,
a wrestling league that only gives very
few people a shot and those people have
either really earned it or they knew
somebody or whatever and got in and he
was always trying to get to that and my
dad says,
even if you did get to it,
I think he,
he still would've went the same way
because he wouldn't.
He would have went the other way.
We've been like crazy because he had
money and he had fame and whatever,
you know.
Well,
a lot of times it's the way you look at
life,
like the parameters that you set for
your life.
If those parameters are fucked up,
it's going to make your life fucked up
no matter what you get involved in.
And that's something that you find with
some people,
some people that are happy and they
become successful,
they can be happy and successful in
pretty much everything they do.
They have good parameters that they've
set up good behavior patterns and in the
people that have bad behavior patterns
are self destructive behavior patterns.
Those things repeat themselves over and
over again.
Even when they get on a roll,
like I have friends that I know they get
on a roll,
they,
everything's going good but I know
they're going to fuck up.
It's just a matter of time.
And then one day you'll see them and
they're drinking again.
Like I thought you quit drinking,
you know,
man,
my fucking my fucking mcgreal lift and
running out.
I want to hear it and I check your urine
in a business or comedy.
Right.
A lot of people are kind of like that.
I like Kinda kinda miserable.
Kind of like that's why they,
they make fun of things because I to
deal with that,
like kind of avoid maybe hanging out
with some of those people are.
Yeah,
my friends are all pretty happy.
I mean,
I've had friends that have had problems
with depression,
have helped some friends that had
problems.
I had a buddy who got depressed because
he was taking propecia.
Something you should be concerned with
folks if you're losing your hair,
first of all,
shaved your head.
It's greatest thing I ever did.
I love and had said,
oh,
it's glorious.
I love it.
I feel like anybody who won't fuck you
because your head shaved.
You wouldn't want to fuck them anyway
because you're awake.
You're barely getting them to fuck you.
Get in there,
you know,
they don't like you that much.
They only fuck you because you have the
right.
But uh,
but my friend was taken propecia and he
was getting seriously depressed and he
didn't connect the two of them together
and you know,
I got him to a psychiatrist and helped
him out.
And he actually was.
He benefited from psych drugs because
those psych drugs got him happy and
weaned him off and got him on on point.
God is life in order.
And then once his life got an order,
he weaned himself off those things.
And it's also the right way to use them.
Yeah.
You're not the press forever,
right?
I mean,
he also got off that fucking piece of
shit.
It's not for everybody.
I took her patient for awhile.
It didn't,
didn't make me depressed,
but a lot of people that makes them
impotent.
Like,
yes,
he definitely did.
That didn't,
didn't kill my Dick,
but it beat the shit out of it.
Yes,
that's
right.
Yeah,
you will.
It doesn't keep you from getting it up,
but it's definitely not the same.
And I didn't even realize it was her
pubes big and your dick smaller now my
prescription ran out and I was like,
ah,
I've got to get to the doctor and refill
my prescription.
All of a sudden I've got this raging
boner all the time,
like,
what's going on down here?
And then I.
and then I went,
oh my God,
it's the propecia.
Like this is what my dick supposed to be
like.
Ridiculous getting off.
This shit had went out and bought quit
propecia long before I shaved my head.
But it was,
um,
that,
that my friend going through that was
really scary because he was a,
you know,
he was really,
really depressed and it was like,
I was like shit,
like I got to figure out a way to help
this guy because this is not who we
normally is.
Normally he would be like happy and
joking.
Like comics are all kind of fucked up in
a way and that are performers.
They see things fucked up in the.
Usually.
Usually when you're getting on stage,
the reason why you do it in the first
place is you're compensating for
something that's missing,
like a lack of attention you got when
you were young or lack of self esteem
and you're trying to make up for it by
your performances on stage and you're
trying to get the audience to like you.
It's like almost like a hustle in a way.
And the reward,
if you can come up with jokes and
routines that are good enough to get the
people to the lab,
you get them to feel good.
And then that becomes your new self
esteem.
And just said it's a real tricky trap.
Do you think for yourself,
you,
you don't really fit the mold or do.
I definitely don't fit all the molds,
but I fit some of the molds,
you know,
I mean the same mold that got me into
martial arts was the same mold that got
me into comedy in the mold that got me
into martial arts was feeling like I was
a loser,
feeling like nobody gave a shit about me
and that everybody doubted me and then I
just didn't have anybody to count on and
I was always worried about getting my
ass kicked.
I'm like,
fuck,
I've got to figure out how to fight.
And I wasn't a big guy,
you know,
I'm only five eight,
so I was just like short kid and you
know,
in high school like when I started was
even shorter.
So it was like,
fuck man,
I got to learn how to fight.
And I just was tired of feeling scared,
but it was the same thing.
It was like I was looking for something
that I was good at to boost up my self
esteem.
How has the short kid and you know,
lifting for me,
like I bench pressed three slash 15 in
11th grade and then four or five by the
time I was a senior and I was blowing
people away and the same with mark.
He benched 300,
15 pounds in ninth grade and he was
dyslexic or learning disabled.
All these things.
So that gave us confidence.
You know,
sometimes the deficits that you,
you achieve and or that you experienced
in life,
they can help you if you can get through
them.
If you can get over that.
If you can get over those humps,
they can give you motivation and fuel.
That's why kids that are born rich and
privileged and live in a big ass house
and they get everything they want.
They very rarely have the drive to
accomplish great things because a lot of
times that drive comes from that feeling
of poverty or that feeling of loss or
that feeling of just being lonely and
depressed and like you get motivated to
go out there and make your mark like the
film.
He did a trophy.
Kids,
you know,
like there's a,
all these kids,
you know what,
these parents paying thousands of
dollars for these kids who go to these
special camps and stuff like that and
the best athletes in the world had their
parents just take a hike on.
I'm usually or die.
Yeah.
One of the other,
or sometimes there's divorced.
Mark was coaching football.
One time I'll never forget this,
and a parent came to him and said,
how do I make my kid great at football?
He said,
drop them off in the ghetto.
You know,
that's how you're gonna.
Make them good.
Is like he's to be mad.
Kids got to be some aggressiveness is
some.
My kids got to be angry and then also
too,
like you know when someone's coming to
you at like 16 or 17 years old and
they're talking about hey,
like it'd be great to see them get like
a division one scholarship.
It's like you would already,
you would already know.
We would've known that 17.
Yeah,
I would have known it.
11 probably.
You know like the kids just a mutant and
he's that much bigger and stronger than
everybody.
And he just stands out all the time on
every one of my wife's friends has a
five year old son in this little
motherfucker.
I pulled her aside,
he takes martial arts and I pulled her
aside and go,
that kid is an athlete.
He just,
he knows how to use his body.
Like if he stays with us,
if he's really interested in this,
he's going to be a bad motherfucker.
Like you could tell that that's crazy
five the way he does cartwheels way
balances himself.
The way he can shift shift positions.
I'm like,
if I had that little kid,
if I could coach that little kid,
I could make them a motherfucker.
You listen,
that's what happened with trophy kids is
it all starts with good intentions.
Like you get excited about this
five-year-old.
But what?
Uh,
what,
what about when he's eight?
And he says,
you know what,
Joe,
I don't want to do Jujitsu anymore.
I don't want to do martial arts center.
Then you gotta let them go.
Let them go is right.
But then a lot of parents don't let them
go.
Yeah.
But those people are crazy.
Well,
that's why it's good you did that
documentary.
Yeah,
those people are crazy.
You got cars.
That kid might be an awesome guitarist.
He might give up on Jujitsu and become
this amazing musician.
He might become a writer.
He might just decide that he loves
exercise just for fun,
but what he really enjoys doing is
something else.
He wants to be a doctor who the fuck
knows you,
but no one knows that there's so many
different people.
You've got to figure out what it is in
you that you like to express with what
you do for a living.
If you could figure that out,
man.
That is the fucking thing.
If you can find something you enjoy
doing.
It is the thing.
I always thought I want them to be in
front of the camera.
I just thought I wanted to be an actor
and I do whatever and I was always short
and fat and I was like,
well,
I'm not.
That's not gonna happen unless I'm in.
Got It.
Yeah,
so my Alfred Hitchcock was in front of
the camera.
He wasn't that pretty.
When you're in front of the camera to
document and somewhat and,
and that kind of happened by accident.
I wasn't trying to be in front of me.
What I like about you in front of the
camera though,
you're,
you,
you're wearing the same clothes you
wear,
you talk the way you talk,
you know,
like even my wife goes,
is that the guy who makes the
documentaries go with a backwards
baseball hat on.
That's weird,
right?
Why?
Why is he dressed like that?
I go because that's how he dresses all
the time.
I've gone to the gym.
Oh,
okay.
That makes sense.
Like that's who you are.
That's who you are.
That's how you dress.
It's good.
It's a good thing.
Yeah.
Same all the time.
You don't have to bullshit anybody.
I think there was a couple interviews in
bigger,
stronger,
faster where I went into like the
senator,
I'm wearing a suit,
you know,
I just figured like that's probably
appropriate,
but like other other times I was
interviewed a lawyer and I had dressed
up a little bit more and then I looked
back at him like why did I do that?
Like,
well,
I have a bad idea when you're
interviewing a senator or something like
that,
present yourself because the other
people don't take you a little more
seriously and they,
like,
I've had conversations with people on
the podcast like especially early on in
the career with a kind of like a little
dismissive of me because maybe I had
like a t shirt on that was stupid
tattoos and smelling it read like
whatever,
just assume that I'm an idiot,
you know,
until we have the would be dismissive
initially.
And I was like,
hmm,
approached you to set this up better.
Like if I had an office that looked real
nice and this desk was like,
this desk is a mess right now.
But if I was at in front of something
that looked more professional,
maybe they would approach this with a
little more professional attitude as
well.
So you showing up with a suit.
Not necessarily a bad idea.
I don't think it's a bad idea.
I have to say that like,
um,
some of the other interviews where I
wasn't,
you know,
wasn't being me.
And I knew it.
He felt it felt weird.
Natasha just been me know.
Well,
you know,
it's.
I guess it's,
there's only the only bad way to do it
when you're doing something like what
you're doing is to do something where
you don't like what you're doing because
it's your work.
You know,
like these documentaries are your
creation still.
Think that you don't go confront people.
He'd go ask all the right questions and
you give a,
give a person
enough rope to hang themselves.
That happens every single time.
Yeah.
Well,
especially if they're full of shit.
Yeah.
It's magical.
Now when you're acting yourself,
you'll probably get more out of one of
the best shows ever on television was
penn and teller bullshit.
Oh yeah.
They would just let people ramble and
talk and go,
and then they would be like,
okay,
boom.
And they're stopping it and say,
look at this bullshit.
You know?
That was amazing.
That was a great,
great show.
Yeah.
I wonder where they stopped doing that.
I guess they ran a nine seasons of it,
you know?
Yeah.
They did it for a pretty long time,
but it's the one on p to the other day.
I'm like,
oh my God,
it's amazing that we're working on
something like that.
We're trying to do it in a health and
fitness industry that.
Yeah,
you know,
we,
we just went to the Arnold sports
festival and there's,
you know,
thousands of booths of like 80 percent
of it is stuff that doesn't work
probably,
you know,
like supplements,
supplements,
and just like different things that
don't.
I just don't work well.
What's amazing is how many of those
supplements are steroids.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
There's,
yeah,
there's supposed to be steroids.
The summer ran for a little while until
they get caught on that for a supplement
says it's like testosterone on
testosterone and you're like,
why?
Why are you selling that to people like
that.
That's not a really good message to send
when you know little kids are buying it
or you know,
whatever.
What is it?
What is testosterone and testosterone
supplement?
I'll find out for you.
That sounds ridiculous.
But when we had jeff,
no Wicki in here,
who was the guy who busted Lance
Armstrong.
Great podcasts.
Yeah,
he's A.
He's a bad motherfucker when it comes to
chasing those people down.
But his website that you saw a website
where they show like all the different
stuff,
they'll,
you'll piss hot from that.
You can just buy at a regular vitamin
store.
It's fucking crazy.
And just just,
you get to the a,
you know,
it's listed alphabetically.
Just go through a and there's fucking
thousands of fucking things.
When he was on,
when he was on your,
when he was on your show,
Lance Armstrong tweeted me a private
message and said,
are you listening to this shit?
I said,
well,
what is he?
What is these top?
I said,
you should just go on there.
And then you had him on.
It was great.
You know,
lance was great,
but he was awesome.
He was awesome.
You know,
he's helping Dan Bilzerian trained for
that.
A bet.
He's got a bet Danville's area and is
going to drive the instagram guy or
whatever.
He's going to ride his bike from La to
vegas and he has like,
I think 36 hours to do it or something
like that.
And so they made a bet for a 600 grand.
Holy Shit.
So he's got a ride his bike and uh,
as soon as the bet was announced,
Lance Armstrong texted me and he's like,
do you know Dan Bilzerian?
I want to help them with those two guys
together.
And now lance is helping train them.
Actually never met.
I've never met Lance Armstrong.
Lance Armstrong has it always been cool
to me through like social media.
And I think that's really cool if you
can do something,
you know,
a one time between a bigger,
stronger,
faster.
Everybody should see this movie.
I was like,
wait,
was before everything happened,
you know?
And um,
but it was cool.
It's like a way before he got busted.
Yeah.
I can show you the tweet.
I like his,
I like his coach.
Like I was wild.
All the different shitty thought I have
to like try to get passed all the tests,
Ferrari and then he had like his
gardener or whatever,
like go way ahead of everybody and then
and then give him shit at like pit stops
and stuff.
I was like,
what are you.
Is this real well about the fact that
they were doing blood transfusions in
front of everybody on the bus?
That was great at the bus broke down
this weekend.
We were at this power lifting meet.
Some guy comes up to mark and says,
well,
I compete in the drug free division.
He said,
no drug tested.
There is no drug food and drug tested
you a little bit.
Is there a single power lifted?
It's not doing steroids.
There's.
There's a lot of guys that because
there's like,
let me pull it up better.
A single successful power lifter.
It's not.
The wild thing is the crazy part we were
talking about this also is that if you
just consistently do the right thing all
the time,
like if you're hydrated all the time,
you get the right amount of sleep,
you train hard,
you have a lot of motivation and
determination and you want to be better.
You can actually surpass a lot of the
guys that are on shit and and we see it
time and time again.
Whether those guys are actually 100
percent natural.
It's hard.
It's hard to fucking say.
It's hard to pinpoint,
but I'd have to say out of all the world
records that are broken in these drug
tested federation,
some of these guys have to be quoted at
what it blamed summary.
Know what I mean?
Some of these fucking guys got,
yeah,
there was a guy that just totally drug
tests and competition and 1100 pounds
squat add one bench and an eight,
15 dead lifts.
I mean he'd swaths
of 1100 pounds squat and check this out,
Blaine Sumner,
vanilla gorilla.
Mark sponsors the world's strongest man,
Brian Shaw,
and he bet Brian Shaw.
He couldn't pick up this 550 pounds
stone and throw it over.
What?
A 54 inch.
Yeah,
platform.
He's like,
it was a fucking baby.
It's on the Internet.
You can watch it.
So Brian brought up.
It's on a youtube baton rogue fitness as
youtube page Jesus.
So Brian did that and um,
and mark went over.
I said,
if you could do it,
I'll give you.
I'll give you five grand.
So the night before he said what?
He said,
hey,
are we still on with that bed or
whatever?
I said,
I said some bad.
It's a sponsorship first of all,
but yeah,
it's,
it's uh,
well I said that I actually changed my
mind.
I'm gonna make it 10 grand.
Oh my God.
This guy,
he throws it over that guy.
Six foot eight.
400.
And wait a minute,
wait a minute.
What am I looking at?
Here is a different event.
This is a kettle bell.
Oh my God.
Kettlebell 60 pounds.
I think Brian's show.
That's way more than 60 pounds unless
it's hollow.
Brian.
60 pound kettlebell.
But we'd win a whole lot back it up now.
It's probably more like 70 or 80,
but can't be.
Look how.
Look how big it is.
They have a special implements when.
No,
no,
no.
Look at the size of that Kettlebell.
The kettlebell,
the way he's walking with it might be
100.
That has to be hollow.
I don't,
I don't think that,
um,
I don't think there is heavy as he is
right there on the ground in front of
you.
Look over that Werewolf.
See that Werewolf in the far left.
It's made differently.
Those are different.
Those are specialty things or cast iron.
Those are specialty things that their
topics are bad ass.
Well,
the ones that he has,
the only way that they could be outside
on.
It's like a rogue fitness gone.
Rogue fitness.
His Youtube Channel.
God,
that guy's ridiculously strong.
But you mean even if it's fucking six,
he's six foot.
He's six foot eight,
420 pounds.
You get close to them and you're like,
I'm going to die.
This fucking guy.
Nicest guy in the world.
He is very nice,
but you still think he's going to kill
you just because he can fucking Robert
Oberst guy.
Yeah,
he's a great guy.
Down to the Ice House one night.
He's ridiculous.
None of his clothes that none of his
shirts have sleeves.
How the fuck are they going to cut off
his circulation?
His hands.
All these guys get on planes and like
that.
What happens?
Jesus Christ.
Look at this guy squatting a thousand
102 pounds of Seville.
Another girl right there.
Okay.
Now tell me he's clean.
He's in a drug test at federation,
so he gets me his blood tested.
Say,
uh,
that's insane.
I blame someone or you're lying.
There you go.
I mean,
I believe my guests can.
Hey,
this guy's a big hunter like yourself.
He's like,
he's into fishing and shit.
Like does he use his teeth?
Is he pulled out?
He probably
isn't the record.
Throws a 45 pound plate at their head.
Game of thrones,
actor half door Bjornsen.
He's on game of thrones.
He threw a 56 pound kettlebell over a 40
foot record.
So 50 foot six,
11,
six,
10 is retarded about being.
These guys are
world record of it.
So Oh my God,
it's heavy,
heaviest thing.
But if you try to throw a 30 pound
Kettlebell over that thing,
we would probably die doing it.
Here it is.
Here's the book,
here's the video,
look at this.
That's a one arm swing.
So that might be a little harder.
One 56 pounds.
But that's fine.
That was a world record when he did.
That was pretty cool.
Yeah.
This is actually a vice documentary.
There's a couple of thousand pound
deadlifts too in the world's strongest
man competition.
They.
There was A.
Eddie Hall did a thousand 26 and then
Brian Shaw that a thousand 21.
It was just fucking Brendan.
How many of these guys are doing
steroids?
Oh yeah.
No,
just the world's strongest man.
I mean that's part of the.
It's part of the sport.
It's 99 percent is part of the sport and
it's part of a bodybuilding,
you know,
as part of a lot of sports.
In a perfect world,
I think a lot of the athletes would say,
hey,
to perfect world there'd be nothing out
there that we could take to get better,
but that's just not the world we live
in.
Right.
So I think that's kind of the case with
a lot of art.
There are some guys that are just large
human beings that can handle big,
big amount of weights.
I mean you've probably seen it in mma
where people just have a different
structure.
You like,
I don't know what that guy is like five,
nine.
He has to cut weight to get the suit to
65 and he's just built like electronic.
Yeah,
it just doesn't just wrestle somebody
and you can't even grab the risks
because risk is all huge in hands and
feet are all.
But it's like what the John and Johnson
and Johnson that we've known him since
he was 22 years old and you know,
we were kind of instrumental in getting
him into wrestling and so when we met
him we're like,
dude,
you're a freak.
Your forearms or the size of my head.
He's got a double sized risks,
risks together and he wears a head band
around his biceps.
Were like,
hey.
And he got picked up by wwe,
like pretty much right away.
It was pretty,
pretty easy for him.
Well,
there's definitely some physical freaks.
There's definitely some physical for
expression.
Always wondered like when you see those
strong mankind's,
like there's,
I don't,
I can't imagine that any of them could
not be on steroids.
I doubt that any of them are probably
cleaned just due to the sheer amount of
weight that they have to weigh and the
sheer amount of weight that they have to
lift it just wouldn't really make sense
to do it without.
It doesn't make sense.
You don't want to go in and lose.
I mean,
that's not the purpose,
right?
I think,
uh,
you know,
we talked about this,
like I,
I'm on,
you know,
hormone replacement therapy and I think
it's like,
you know,
talking about prescription thugs and
whatever,
people like,
well you take hormone replacement
therapy,
but I think about it,
hormones is like,
it kind of balances me out and a lot of
other areas.
So I don't have to take pills,
you know,
I don't have to take other drugs.
40th three.
And when did you start taking hormones?
Comprise about.
Actually right after I had my hips done.
I was 30,
33 or 34 and it was because I had hip
replacement surgery.
So you started hormone replacement to
try to boost your body's recovery?
Absolutely.
Yeah.
I was doing growth hormone then too and
I felt like the growth hormone wasn't
really worth it.
I don't know.
I mean a lot of people financially you
mean?
Yeah,
they have a lot of people rave about it
yet.
But what you get bang for your buck or
whatever.
I,
if you're rich.
Yeah,
it might.
Maybe it'll help you a little bit,
but I don't know if you're trying to get
some crazy results.
Like what do you mean by like what were
you trying to do is a fan of growth
hormone.
It actually hurt my joints more than
anything.
Anybody hands fall asleep all the time.
A whole lot of water hands fall asleep.
Yeah.
Take it.
No,
I know everyone says that.
But uh,
it gives you a Dema and everything.
Yeah,
it makes you hold a little bit of water
I think.
I think at the time I've tried to.
I use a day and four.
I use a day that's,
that's not,
that's not much.
That's the big crazy bodybuilder guys
take like 10,
right?
I,
if you're using it in conjunction with
everything else,
like then you'd probably not optimizing
everything.
It makes sense that it would,
that it would be effective for you,
but a little bigger.
The major winner.
I think.
So some people take it and say,
oh my God,
I said,
growth hormone.
I got completely shredded.
And then it's like,
maybe it's just not the case.
Well,
you know,
it also could be the now are on growth
hormone.
They really stepped up their training.
They're all excited with her on growth
hormone.
Right.
There's a lot of factors involved.
We think suburbans do for the most part
to do with supplements.
A little bit of it.
It's going to help you a little bit,
some of them.
And then there's a little bit of placebo
effect if you're taking fish oil and
chugging down protein powder and stuff
like that,
you're probably not eating pizza and
drinking beer.
Well that's why double blind placebo
controlled studies are so important to
find out what actually does work and
what doesn't work.
What are the inflamed inflammation
markers in the blood and fish oil though
part about that.
Like with uh,
with certain things like fish oils,
like,
okay,
is it good for inflammation?
Yes,
probably.
But what people take it for is like,
there a lot of people take it for their
heart health and they realized like,
wow,
I got to take 12 pills a day for it to
actually be effective for my heart
health where you could get in
tablespoons to.
That's how I do it.
Sure.
Yeah.
But I'm saying like,
I guess it's not what I'm saying.
It's like it's not as effective as
people think.
Like,
oh I to take fish oil,
you know?
And then they go out and they buy pretty
effective,
you know,
a little bit over a really long period
of time is probably the most effective
thing.
So you've got to stick with it.
It's definitely bad for anybody,
but I just think that it's like,
you know,
it's something that uh,
it's just another thing like maybe you
don't need it,
you know,
well,
what is need,
you know,
it's your turn to optimize your life.
You've tried to optimize your body
officially it was a good choice.
But if you want to get the results these
guys are talking about in these studies
and taking 12 pills a day,
you don't really have to take pills.
You can just,
I take it,
I get it.
Um,
it's a company name.
Crawson's crossings and things.
Yeah.
They've been around forever.
They're in a bottle and just pour it
into a tablespoon.
I take a couple of tablespoons.
Yeah.
It's just so good for you.
It's like flavor,
like lemon or something that.
A little lemon flavor.
I think just really getting out and
talking about is a,
you're an addict,
you're just expecting it to help improve
your health,
which is great.
I think a lot of people expect us to do
something to have a heart attack.
If I take two of these a day and then
they realize,
oh,
the study was done with 12 a day,
you know?
Well,
they didn't take 12 bitch and step up
your game.
If you want to not have a heart attack,
take a couple of aspirin a day.
Right?
Isn't that what's supposed to be like
one of the best things in the world for
your.
For your heart?
It's supposed to help too.
Yeah.
Allegedly.
One,
one.
I one to a today.
This is so many different fucking
things.
You have to be on the same time.
Take some part and be 12 and working
well.
They get you all stressed out about it.
Then you've got to take something for
that.
What are you doing for Niacin?
What do I need to do?
What kind of Nice,
and then you forget to take everything
that you get depressed.
You ever get that shit?
You ever take that Flash Nice and flush?
I take that stuff every night.
It makes your fucking skin turn red and
you didn't take it at night.
Really good for you.
It makes you go to sleep or just really
that's when I take it,
but it's really good for your body.
You know?
It's one of those things that people
don't like taking because it gives you
that weird good for your blood
readings,
but just that effect is temporary.
Although
I take that,
I take it like a man.
You think that flush nice and doesn't.
Doesn't work.
Yeah.
What are you afraid of?
A little flush.
Yeah.
No,
I'm not scared.
I'm good.
That's what separates the men from the
boys.
All that weird feeling.
Afraid of looking like you have poison
ivy or some shit.
My eyes itch.
And did you find that stone at 5:55
stoning and pull that sucker up man.
I think that's unbelievably.
Is it?
It supplements that you were saying like
it depends on like what people are
expecting.
You know,
a lot of times certain things will rave
about testosterone,
testosterone.
There is no way.
Absolutely zero chance that that
someone's going to work as good as
injecting testosterone.
Well,
if it does,
if it works better than testosterone,
you're going to fuck your body up.
Yeah,
yeah.
Maybe it's going to have side effects.
If there was something out there that
was the cure that they like,
you wouldn't have to advertise.
People will just know about it.
Well,
here's the most important supplement.
The most important thing that you can
take is really healthy food and when did
you start throwing down all these
supplements,
but you're eating fucking big MACs.
Your,
you know,
you can't do that.
I got a friend was telling me like that
all the chemical components of all
really healthy food already exists in
vitamin,
so just eat whatever the fuck you want.
Take vitamins.
I was like,
man,
I don't think it works.
I just don't think it works.
It doesn't work like that for me.
That's the problem is people use it as a
safeguard.
Right?
Actually,
the first time I met you,
it was after one of your shows at the
ice house.
I don't even know if you remember.
We were outside in the back and you
said,
have you were talking to Brian Callan
and all these other guys and uh,
you were saying every time we go on the
road I got to go to a whole foods and I
thought that was so cool that you
actually take the time to go out and get
the,
even when you're on the road,
get the right food and like,
that was a,
that was actually inspirational for me
to hear because you don't have somebody
that struggled with my weight all the
time.
And like sometimes I think that stuff is
weird or people might think I'm weird if
I'm trying to.
I don't care if you're spending the
night,
you know,
and um,
it's just good to know that like other
people that are doing it,
why you traveled on the road for so many
years.
I know there's no.
Unless I stay in a place that has a
really good restaurant and I know they
have really healthy salads and real
healthy food options.
And,
and even if that's the case,
what am I going to drink?
I mean,
it's cool if they have,
you know,
bottled waters,
cool.
But I drink Kombucha a lot so I was
wanting to make sure that I have enough
probiotics and I want healthy snacks.
I don't want to have to go through the
fucking minibar and eat peanut m and m's
and all that bullshit.
Middle of the knife.
I'm hungry.
It makes you feel bad.
I think,
you know,
it makes you feel like a loser and I
just,
I mean there's nothing wrong with eating
shitty food every now and then,
but for the most part,
the base of your diet,
it's fucking gotta be healthy and stay
on top of it.
God vegetable for the years that I was
going through my addiction stuff,
I just didn't take care of myself at.
All I did was I was 260 pounds and I
right now the way I today I weighed like
$200 on a dot.
So that's great.
But that's a big difference.
You know,
there's a big difference.
I'm fat,
really,
really fat in that movie and I still
think I have a long way to go.
You know,
I used to weigh 3:30 and I kinda got up
there on purpose just to pluck and
gained strength and I went from like
$300.
Oh,
here we go.
Brian Shaw,
555.
World Records,
stone lift.
Oh my God.
So that's impossible to pick up.
I mean look how big his hands are.
Boy,
555 pounds.
And it's a ball,
like it's a size of a large medicine
ball.
An atlas stone.
Yeah.
It's an object not meant to be lifted,
you know,
it's not like a barbell or anything.
Not really interesting to put it up over
that platform.
Yeah.
How's he doing this?
Why is this in slow motion?
So the other way,
but that platform is about as tall as I
am.
Almost.
Jesus Christ.
That tub.
Is He that big?
He's six.
Eight.
Yeah,
he's huge.
He uses Christ.
Look at this.
That's probably up to my shoulders.
So it's a big boy right there.
That's an enormous human being.
Whereas slingshot elbow sleeves,
if you noticed the
harmful slingshot and what do you think
that guy eats in a day?
He eats like about 8,000 calories a day.
Yeah.
I,
uh,
I had,
um,
picked up.
I haven't picked up from the airport and
uh,
and,
and brought to my house by like a limo,
lamb shoulder,
and he took a picture in the limousine
of him,
uh,
with his wife and the limo and he's
eating salmon out of a fucking thing,
like container tupperware.
That thing.
The thing about that guy is everything
is so systematic.
It's amazing to be in his presence
because he talks about,
yeah,
like he doesn't,
he doesn't eat bad,
you know,
he doesn't.
He's on target to just be the world's
strongest man.
He's won it three times and he's going
for for this year,
right?
Yeah.
And usually he's like,
when are we eating?
And I was like,
probably like five.
He's like,
oh,
it's like,
he's like,
it's like almost four.
He's like,
I should probably sneak in a meal now.
So He ate before we ate.
But he brought meals already made and
everything was.
You know,
what's interesting,
if you look at his supplements,
he's got this thing,
a diet and supplements.
His meals are not that high in quantity
or in,
um,
like ounces of protein,
like when you look at what he's eating,
like 14 inch lean beef bodybuilding
magazine.
Okay.
But I mean this is what he's saying,
right?
Yeah.
Ten Ounces Tilapia.
So he's like,
these are normal size meals,
which you would think a guy that's that
big,
he'd be eating like,
you know,
56 ounce steak.
So you'd really look at it.
There's almost nine up there.
I think there's pre workout,
post workout,
which are kind of more like shakes,
but there's like a pudding in there.
Five,
six,
seven,
eight,
nine,
10.
It's like 10 different times he's eating
his entire life.
He,
he,
he's obsessed with his entire day is
driven towards,
you know,
continue to kick everybody's ass.
Yeah.
But even in that,
like you're,
you're looking at insane amounts of
calories even with the small,
smaller meals.
Right.
What's interesting about him too is that
it's four days of training week and
three days of full recovery.
So three days he's doing contrast baths
and he's like all the shit that you
always talk about he's doing.
He goes to,
he goes to a pet place and just as
physical therapy drills,
you know,
we saw him get on the floor and he was
doing all kinds of shit.
We were like,
what the hell?
How is he moves around like way better
than I do.
He's moves around.
Great Smart Guy,
man.
I mean,
that's really where it's at.
I think there's a lot of people that do
too much work and not enough recovery
and they just kinda mentally tough their
way through it instead of less work,
more recovery and probably better
results.
That's where I'm at right now.
I just fucked up my elbow.
They recommended a what does it.
PRP injections,
right?
Yeah.
My elbow has been bothering me for a
little while that's going on with it.
I,
I was training for a competition.
I was uh,
going after a 600 pound bench and I
fucked up my elbow midway through
training.
I did a 5:55 bench for a double.
That was a big pr for me.
And then,
um,
through our means personal record for
pb upns.
And so I,
uh,
got it banged up somehow.
I don't know if it was from that bench
exactly,
but two or three days later,
you know what,
it started to hurt.
Um,
I didn't think I was going to be able to
compete,
but I was still able to compete.
About five or six weeks later,
got a 22 pound bench pr in the meat but
missed a 600 pound bench.
I did bench five slash 78.
Um,
but when I went to bed 600,
I slightly toward my pack and I think I
tore my peck because my elbow was jacked
up.
So you just need some time off.
Yeah,
the pack,
clear it up.
Everything's all good with that,
but the elbow is still all jacked up and
so I just went and got an Mri yesterday,
which was fucking crazy.
They stuffed me in this little tiny
machine.
Never had one before.
No,
I've never had it before.
I've never had a surgery or nothing.
I was,
I was a Mris are weird.
Oh,
I was terrified.
I was in there for like half an hour.
Awesome.
Awesome hammering.
Oh my God.
After I got out,
I was like,
just,
I was just like a crazy noises,
so string,
so claustrophobic.
I was like,
holy fuck.
That was insane.
But yeah,
now I have to try to figure out.
I have kind of these,
uh,
they call them chronic tears,
which doesn't really help me at all and
it's all they told me what chronic tears
and tons of inflammation.
So I got to figure out ways to just get
it to heal up on its own basically.
Have you looked into stem cells?
I haven't tried anything yet.
So when we get out of the podcast,
I'll give you some stem cells in.
My doctor is actually one of the guys
like leading the way and in stem cells
and sounds amazing.
They're doing stem cells in Las Vegas
where they're taking them from woman's
placenta,
whether it's some into it,
because,
you know,
I can't get in trouble for my wife for.
No,
no,
no.
Women who have had some Syrian section.
Okay.
So a young girl who has a Sicilian
section,
they take her stem cells,
uh,
out of the placenta and they inject them
directly into your injuries and people
have had fucking spectacular sent into
my elbow.
I'll tell you about their adam done on
my shoulder.
It's amazing to hear about the
Wolverine.
Like how many of those do you think?
Hold on a second.
I'm telling you,
it is probably one of the most
spectacular healing methods you need
several shots of that.
Or like one shot,
one shot at.
There was a guy that I'm Arnold
Schwarzenegger I think gave an award to
last year,
maybe the year before had ocular cancer.
So he couldn't see.
And as I,
and one of his eyes and um,
they did stem cells,
stem cell thing on him and after like 10
weeks he had like full vision of that.
I don't,
I don't know how,
I don't know what it was,
but I remember all of the sorts and they
are giving them a warden talking about
that being,
you know,
I'm not surprised.
I mean,
I was fucking stunned at what it did to
my shoulder and I've since had my hip
done and my knee,
my hip was like barely bothering me.
I'm like,
fucking shoot it up.
Yeah,
you know,
it just bothered me after hard
kickboxing workouts,
but not,
not even to
the point where.
But I was like,
listen,
I wouldn't do a damage or is this a good
thing to do?
Preventative.
And he's like,
yeah,
probably be a good thing to do.
Preventative for weeks later,
not a fucking single pain no matter how
long.
Shadow over my whole body,
my knee was bothering me.
Well,
it's shown that they can regenerate
cartilage and Manila.
It's insane because it's literally the
building block kind of tissue can
regenerate any tissue,
like partial tears.
I know some of my meathead friends are
real fans of these like weird peptides.
There's like growth hormone.
Then there's igf one and now there's a
bunch of shit that I can't pronounce any
more,
but it makes your body develop more
growth hormone and testosterone.
And I tried some different things and I,
I didn't find any of those to be
effective.
So
you got to say it's a secret.
So yeah,
we need that guy's number because we're
both ganged up.
I'll help you out.
I'll help you out at the end of the
pocket.
His name is Dr Rodney Mcgee.
If anybody else is listening and he's in
Las Vegas and he's a great guy and
he'll,
he'll take care of you and tell you what
you can and cannot expect out of this.
But they're going to start doing this
all over the world.
But I believe right now in Vegas is the
only place we can get this stuff that
they're doing through placenta.
I might be wrong about that.
They actually,
they,
they got some to a doctor in New York
that was working on a UFC fighter.
Chris Weidman actually had to do as nice
to.
My doctor was telling me there's some
way that he was working on that day.
They could inject $200,
million stem cells and you at one time
and they basically do it once and it
works in your whole body.
I don't know how they think about it,
but bas rutten was saying boss route and
had it done.
Me Too.
I don't want to.
I don't want to get kicked up when
fucking great guy anyway.
But uh,
he had uh,
done intravenously and he was like,
it was like,
there was power coming off my fingers.
Like I seemed amazing.
He's a great guy.
He's a spectacular example of a human
being.
Um,
so when you're filming this documentary
and you're doing this and you know,
you're exposing yourself,
was that one of the harder parts of the
documentary because you know,
you had to show your car getting all
fucking banged up and I mean for me,
you know,
I,
I.
Did you take any heat for that because
you were driving around pilled up and I
got in trouble for that.
Like,
no,
I never,
I never once got pulled over.
I'd be hammered.
You emitting,
you essentially admitted to a felony.
It's weird.
You can't,
unless it's like murder,
you can't really get convicted of
anything.
You're saying like a documentary or a
movie?
Oh really?
Yeah,
like I could say I never paid my taxes
in 20 years and they can look into it.
It might be stupid to say it,
but him like,
because we had to check that out.
Like seriously when he was talking about
taking stuff away.
You're going to be in this fucking
movie.
What did you do?
What are we doing?
All of our attorneys and everything
like,
oh no,
like if he says it in documentary
entertainment way to see if ted Cruz
gets an office will fucking come after
your retroactive.
I think that it's important that you did
that though,
man.
It was,
it took a lot of balls.
Thank you.
You said you know,
some of the stuff I recall him saying
that he was most embarrassed about
was just like this.
The way he looked,
he cares about being fat and being
bloodshot eyes and like just looking
jacked up.
He was kind of like more depressed about
how,
how that came off,
but he doesn't like watching a movie
probably.
I mean that's kind of some of the stuff
he's told me.
Right.
I've watched it like maybe four or five
times in its completed form for me to
watch.
What were you eating that you gained so
much weight?
Did you just like try to like whatever
was kate yourself with food because your
pain and I actually thought it's funny.
I thought I was like getting bigger and
getting stronger.
Like I was really strong at that time,
like know,
so I was like fat,
but yeah,
I could still,
you know,
throw up four or five for like four reps
or whatever,
but then I tore my tricep and that led
to more depression,
lead to eating bad lead to less,
working out all sorts of Shit,
you know?
Well then drinking just causes waking
anyway.
Yeah,
drinking.
It's like the absolute worst thing for
you is not good.
One of the things that I've noticed from
this diet is I have very little alcohol
now.
Not that I drank a lot,
but now I'll limit myself to maybe a
glass of wine or two in a night.
At most.
Are you on?
No carbs,
very little carbs.
He's joined the war on carbs.
You joined the war on carbs,
carbs,
you guys,
you're going to do a documentary on
ketogenic diets and the owners of quest
nutrition to have 44 dogs at a farm in
Dallas that have a very,
had a very aggressive form of cancer to
now all cancer free and all they're
doing is a ketogenic diet.
70 dogs.
Yep.
Seventy percent,
Quito dogs,
70 percent fat,
30 percent protein turn into wolves.
They are dogs.
And so that,
the thing is like,
how can we look at that and say,
well,
will this work in humans or what is like
any,
I think any research we're doing on any
animals that are mammals,
you know,
like kind of have similarities so we can
start figuring things out through these
dogs,
you know,
because you're not going to experiment
on people really now.
So,
and the dog,
it's like,
Hey,
I'm just trying to save it's life,
you know?
So,
um,
what are,
what are their conclusions?
I think that ketogenetic diets,
I know they think that it's,
they know that it's very effective for
children that have epilepsy.
So here's what I've heard.
I've also heard the shot down,
so I'm just going to say what I've
heard,
I've heard that a,
the absence of carbohydrates that have
basically starves the cancer cell.
I'm not sure if it's that simple,
but that's what I've heard.
What carbohydrates do convert to sugar,
especially simple carbohydrates like
bread and pasta and sugar does fuel
cancer and I had inflammation in general
in general,
I feel fantastic.
I've only been doing this a month.
This diet is a primal blueprint.
Ketogenic Diet.
I've only been doing it for a month,
but my brain is the.
That's when we were talking about before
the podcast started.
That's probably the most interesting
aspect of it is the mental clarity.
He's got a book,
right?
Mark Sussan.
He's got a couple of books.
Yeah,
the primal blueprint and I think I
forget where are they in the other room?
Yeah,
I love.
I just love reading all that stuff.
You have read every ketogenic diet book.
There is,
so I'm gonna.
I'm gonna get that after we get off the
air.
I tried gluten free for awhile.
I did
that.
I lost weight and I got thinner,
like my face got thinner,
like my,
I'm one of those guys are like,
my fucking head gets fat.
And so the first thing that happens when
life,
my face gets round in big and this park
it's fact and have abs and have the
fattest face you ever seen the fat face
things a weird thing.
But uh,
that was the first thing that I noticed
when I did the gluten free.
My face shrank down to normal size and
this is even more so like gluten free is
very,
uh,
it's very controversial.
You know,
the guy who came up with the whole
gluten free thing,
published a letter,
published a retraction three years
later,
says that I lied.
I was wrong.
No gluten free.
Well,
here's what is definitely like a big
contract,
like big debate over it.
I guess so.
But here's what it is.
I mean,
this is why what I decided is one of the
reasons why I stopped being gluten free.
What it,
what it is,
is you're taking less sugar.
So that's what the benefit was.
The benefit was I wasn't even eating any
bread,
I wasn't eating any pasta,
so it was taking in less sugar.
It's really that simple.
So there's less inflammation,
so I felt better.
So it definitely worked.
Well.
You're adhering to a program that just
gets rid of some junk.
It's just not a huge.
What are you eating on the primal
blueprint?
I eat a lot of Avocados.
I'm meeting a lot of healthy fats.
I take,
you know,
mct oil of take these ketones that you
saw over here.
These things are mixed these into water.
Those are ketones.
I got a stuff,
a kito protein coming out pretty soon.
I'll send you some.
This is key to genic cream that you put
in coffee.
Mix It in coffee.
That's a good idea.
I could put exogenous ketones in coffee
and then there's this,
uh,
this new supplement.
Not a supplement,
but a snack called phat fudge.
P h a t fudge by.
Yeah.
I want some of that.
Eat,
play.
Crushed.com.
There's a woman.
I don't want to fuck up the spelling of
marriage.
Sounds like a great idea.
Oh my gosh.
Oh,
it's,
it's important to have stuff that's
convenient when you're doing these kinds
of diets.
You know what I mean?
Stuff that tastes good too,
and you don't want to always be cooking
up fucking pound of meat every five
minutes.
Exactly.
Well,
luckily I have a lot of meat in the
back.
I've got a lot of elk from the cup of
elks that are shot,
but you need fats on top of that and a
lot of that elk is like really a lean
fat to it,
correct?
Well,
no,
you don't add fat to it,
but I mean it's not the same as like say
if you get,
you know,
if you got to like a beef steak,
like a rib eye or something like that,
you're getting a lot of fat,
especially if it's a corn fed.
Beef steak is a lot of fat and so I take
different kinds of fats,
but avocado is one of the primary ones
that I like.
Ketogenic diets are amazing for a losing
weight,
for a weight class type stuff like
powerlifting,
weightlifting,
mma,
it works,
works fucking awesome.
You can drop a couple pounds pretty
quickly.
You've got to wet your body,
really get accustomed to it though,
because in the beginning people shy off
of it because they feel like losing that
weight makes them feel
weak and changing from a carbohydrate
consuming body to approach or to a body.
Yeah,
it does take time.
You know,
like any cheat day.
I haven't had anything.
No.
In the month I have done it.
Just just decide that I don't eat that
anymore.
Well,
I gave myself 60 days.
At the end of six days,
maybe we'll have some ice cream,
but I think I'm going right back on the
ice cream.
Right.
Did that improve ice cream?
Yeah.
Nice.
It's a.
They sell it at Erewhon bulletproof ice
cream and it's like I'm not buying any
bulletproof stuff.
I know that guy kind of carb
carbohydrates.
I want that guy's just too full of shit
about too many different things for me
to support it.
The one thing that carbohydrates do is
they help to hydrate carbohydrate,
helps hydrate the muscles.
So that's what's I think sometimes like
sometimes people will will say,
oh,
I don't like Kito Kito Diet because I
feel weak because I lose energy.
If you're doing a Keto diet properly,
you should not be losing any energy.
Your energy level should be fine.
However you're not gonna have as much
water through your muscles.
And if you're a strength athlete or
somebody that relies on the strength,
it can be compromised a little bit,
especially when you start to lose
anything like over like 10 pounds.
So there's going to be calm.
You lose a lot of weight,
your strengths can be compromised,
so you have to make sure that you're
hydrated.
You have to make sure that you're,
and you've got to make sure you get
enough,
need some carbohydrates here and there,
you know,
um,
Harbert's you don't want,
you don't want high.
That's it.
That's all it is.
And you look at like,
you know,
conor mcgregor going up a weight class
and I know there's different fighters
and different styles and all the
different things,
but it is hard to overcome,
uh,
someone just being being bigger than
you.
And so if you lose a bunch of weight,
you should expect to lose some strength.
Uh,
the girl's name is Marisha,
new to s,
h e n fact,
putting Paleo chef know phat fudge fat.
Paleo chef.com I think is a.
yeah,
that's a website.
And the,
uh,
the product's called phat fudge and
hopefully we're going to start selling
it on it.
It's just buy the whole company.
That sounds nice,
but it's,
uh,
it's really,
it's healthy.
It's good for you,
but it's a key to genic right?
The whole idea for me was just to just
give it a try,
just see,
see what it's really like it.
And so,
um,
it gets me in a mode where I feel like
everything come becomes an order or when
I'm on like a ketogenic diet for some
reason I'm like,
I'm not on it right now,
but when I get on it I'm like,
okay,
I know exactly what I need to do exactly
what I need to eat.
I kind of liked the structure of it,
you know?
And it's not bad.
I mean a lot of people are worried about
it.
No,
I'm not going to have it.
The only eat carbs.
And when people start panicking and then
they start coming up,
well I heard that it makes your Dick
fall off.
Come up with so many different.
So many lies about stupid thing.
Well,
it's not good for you.
It's a day where your brain runs on.
Carbohydrates are bad for me,
you know,
like it's not proven.
It's good for you.
I'm
guessing just armbar those people can't
do that.
Do you have a day where you throw in any
carbs are
not really?
No.
Just maybe vegetables and nuts and stuff
like that of that.
But my thought behind it was I just want
to try it,
see what it's like,
trying the exact way it's meant to be.
And what sits in is the idea behind is
not Paleo because that word Paleo
Lithic,
you know what's kind of messed up
because the Paleolithic era,
people eat breads,
they grains,
they did.
So this is,
he calls it primal and the ideas just
eat stuff that your body is just really
kind of designed to eat.
Your body's designed to eat fats,
your body's designed to eat vegetables.
And fats are important because when
people burn fat,
if you don't have those fats,
like if you're not consuming them and
your body starts burning hormone profile
is hugely.
You know,
by fats,
you know there's a difference between if
your body's designed to burn
carbohydrates,
if it doesn't have any carbohydrates,
you crash.
So that's the dish.
That's a big difference too.
Like the feeling that I get in between
meals,
like I don't get the same kind of
hungry,
like the hungry that I was getting when
I was eating a lot of carbs.
I'll get this off.
Fuck,
I got to eat now.
I've got to eat out.
I do not get that now.
I don't get that week crashed feeling
like I can get up in the morning after
not having eaten since like 8:00 at
night.
I'd get up at 9:00 in the morning and
I'll lift weights and I'm not.
I don't feel weak.
Right.
That's,
that's unusual.
That feels weird to not have the same
hunger cravings because your body's.
Your body regulates itself better as
burns off your fat.
I've been doing this for a long time,
so back in 1995 I moved to California to
go to USC,
started training at Gold's gym in Venice
and started trading with Michael Hern
and this other guy,
ron fed co who's getting his phd.
Right.
So go to the gym and these guys are a
lot stronger than me,
their squat and 7,800 pounds and I'm
around the 600 pound mark and they
basically said,
hey,
you're too fat.
You got to lose weight.
You got to be.
You can't be competitive.
You've got to drop to next class.
You need to be in the one nine,
eight weight class.
I'm like,
I have no idea how to do that and I'm
just a kid from poughkeepsie that moved
out here.
I have no idea what the bodybuilding
lifestyle is about.
Anything and he said,
look,
just eat red meat and water until your
account until what?
Red Meat and water shot.
I did that for.
I did that for,
I don't know,
whatever.
I can't.
When I came back from New York to go
back to school and lift with these guys
again after the summer,
I think I weighed one 96 and so I came
back.
It's like,
wow,
you did it.
And I was kind of stupid.
Says vegetables were fair game.
He said if you really die and you could
have like an apple here or there.
But yeah,
it was basically.
But I was naive.
I didn't know and that was kind of a
good thing for me because I just,
I just dove in headfirst and I didn't
take away your shit's like.
And how often they come out,
every four or five days he lift up a
manhole cover and just take a shit right
in there.
It's funny,
I was fine,
I was stronger and I went into me.
I think I squatted 6:59.
Why did you stop eating like that?
I just don't think it sustainable
forever.
You know,
I think that's one of the issues that
Quito guy as it gets to be hard to do
for really,
really long like yours,
I don't know,
it just gets to be tough.
You mean psychological and you just,
you just run into roadblocks here and
there and then you get,
you get triggers,
you know,
for food,
somebody has fucking birthday and then
they are eating birthday cake and it
just kind of snowball and you might end
up into something else or you know,
you might,
depending on what sport you're into,
maybe you have different goals at
different periods of time.
So sometimes you want to be small and
sometimes you want to be bigger.
So when you say roadblocks you don't
mean like you mean more psychological.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
No,
the Diet's fine,
you're not going to like have some sort
of weird blood issue or anything like
that.
I just think I'm going to give myself a
cheat day every couple of months.
That's how I think I'm going to do it
was one day you have an amazing,
uh,
iron will,
you know,
a lot of people don't have that.
It's not that hard,
man.
It's not.
There's kids in Ethiopia right now.
They don't have any feet,
you know what I mean?
Right now,
like,
how hard is it?
Elk steaks and sauteed Kale and fresh
eggs and Avocados.
It's all great.
You have your own chickens,
right?
It's all I feel great.
So I'm gonna stick with it.
I really think this might be the way I
eat.
People are so annoyed with me though
because I talk about it too much.
I think it's the best way to eat.
We've always,
we've always thought that,
you know,
we have a friend,
uh,
John Anderson who hasn't eaten
carbohydrates and years.
No cars,
no cars.
He's huge.
He has,
well not no carbs as he as he likes to
put it,
those little motherfuckers are
everywhere.
Carbohydrates are in everything,
but he pretty much despises the act of
like actually sitting down and eating
like rice or eating potatoes.
Really huge.
So good.
He used to do,
I know he used to do strong man
competitions and he said we did strong
man competitions.
The turnover rate from going from one
event to the next.
He had to eat carbohydrates,
you know,
but he,
he said that once he retired from strong
man,
he were strength wasn't his main focus
anymore.
He's like,
I get rid of all that shit and I just
basically just eat meat and vegetables
and like bodybuilding diet.
They have a lot of carbohydrates in it
and they stuffed themselves to put on
weight.
So.
And John Anderson continue to get bigger
and stronger.
You're not gonna you're not gonna.
I don't think you can win like Mr
Olympia without carbohydrates because I
think there's a whole thing to the,
the hormones of the insulation and
everything.
It's a whole thing is way too
complicated for me to understand,
but I just don't think you can.
I think you're limited whenever you
limit any macro macronutrient,
then you're going to have some
limitations probably,
you know?
Yeah.
It's interesting.
It's an interesting situation where
you're trying to figure out what's the
best stuff to put into your body to get
the best performance and the best
feeling out of it.
And then you factor in convenience,
you know,
social things,
customer things like someone actually
doing like a know mma,
like a competitor.
It,
it'd probably be a mistake to completely
get rid of the carbohydrates.
Just,
you know,
I guess the main question would be um,
if it's to lose weight to get to the
next weight class and it would be
something that you do for a period of
time,
but if other athletes are successful
with the carbohydrates in there,
why wouldn't you just utilize.
Some guys have gone
Vegan.
They try to go Vegan to lose weight.
Oh,
by the way,
all you vegan that keep telling me don't
say it.
Don't say it.
To keep tweeting me and instagram me
about Nate Diaz.
He's not Vegan,
so stop.
Just cut the shit.
Mercedes.
Vegan.
Yeah.
These vegans went crazy.
Does it feel to know a Vegan is the best
fighter in the world?
You got beat by a Vegan and the v.
they're all jumped on the Vegan bag.
He eats fish.
You Fox.
He eats eggs.
You need search.
He likes green plants.
It's good for you.
Look,
green plants are very good for you,
but you say that in your comedy cult
attached to these people.
They're so unbelievably proselytizing.
They're just ridiculous.
What they don't realize too is if I have
friends that are Vegan and they never
talk about it,
they never pushed it on me and I'm
actually interested in finding out why
they,
why they want to do that.
Right.
So I asked them about it.
I don't,
but they're not pushing it down my
throat.
You know,
most of what nate eats is raw.
He eats a lot of raw foods and you did
that for a long time and he tried raw
vegan for awhile,
but he felt like he needed to substitute
it with chicken or with a fish,
so he doesn't need any land animals.
But he does eat eggs,
I believe.
Pretty sure.
I know he eats breads.
I've seen him eat like tacos and shit.
So He's eating tortillas.
He was fucking awesome in that fight.
A bad motherfucker.
And the reason why he won,
by the way,
it's not because he's a fucking Vegan.
You assholes.
He's healthy and he's got very good
endurance,
got a really good endurance base and
he's a.
he's a really good boxer man.
His boxing is nasty and his Jujitsu is
top notch.
Nate Diaz has been around for a long
time.
He's 20 some odd fights in the UFC
motherfucker and all you vegan folks.
I'm not mad at you.
I'm not honestly.
It's just you got to understand that,
that,
that thing that you guys do where you go
after people and you,
you fucking insult them and it just
makes people more reluctant to associate
with you.
To want to be a Vegan,
it makes people more with locked and it
makes me peep people.
Let's think you're ridiculous.
You're in a cult.
They're looking to religion and they're
like trying to get other people to
actively join.
Why are you shooting deer?
Have a dog as a pet.
It's like,
well,
let's just fucking.
What's acceptable,
man?
I don't know.
Well,
it's not just that.
If you don't shoot deer,
you dummies.
They fucking overpopulate.
Unless you want to bring in wolves,
right?
There's nothing out there stopping deer
from fucking and making you guys.
You have this delusional fairytale,
Walt Disney i's view of wildlife and
it's been a really uncomfortable fucking
discussion that you guys don't want to
have because if you do have it,
you're gonna.
You're gonna wind up feeling really
fucking stupid because there's a reality
there.
They're killing hundreds of bison in
yellowstone park right now.
They're going to fucking shoot him.
You know why?
Because there's no hunting because
there's too many of them.
You know they're going to have to.
They're gonna Start Shooting grizzly
bears to.
Why?
Because there's too fucking many of
them.
They,
they,
you,
if something's got to kill them and it's
you gotta bring in Predators or you're
going to have overpopulation problem did
that.
People,
people with the most over populated
thing on the planet.
Well then don't fuck.
Stop fucking around.
Stop having babies.
Shut your mouth.
You know,
it's the whole thing is preposterous,
but it was amazing the next day,
the amount of fucking tweets from vegans
that were so excited that a Vegan one.
This auto stop them.
Stop on this speech.
No,
I'm kidding.
They're going to go extra hard.
That's hilarious.
It's amazing.
Well,
they're just,
they're,
they're in a cult.
It's a cult of vegetables and they think
that that had gone Vegan or vegetarian,
like a Rob Wolf who wrote that Paleo
Book and he does not Hardcore Paleo but
a,
he got very sick,
you know,
from it.
I,
I hear that all the time.
Like I went Vegan,
Vegan,
I got really sick and I actually,
when I was in Rehab,
there's a kid that was Vegan.
He was eating Oreos all the time.
I'm like,
that's so gross.
Like,
why are you going about their Vegan?
I'm like,
yeah,
but you're not a real vegan.
That's like bullshit Vegan,
you know?
Well,
it's Vegan,
but it's Shitty for you.
There's a lot of gummy bears.
Gummy bears are actually gelatin.
It's probably not Vegan,
but there's some gummy bears are great.
Just don't eat the whole thing.
Like you said in your set.
Oh that's,
that's a different kind of gummy bear.
That was true.
And you're like,
why do they fucking sell it that way?
Then dude,
only eat the head.
Why?
What's going to happen?
It's true story for me to hear that kind
of stuff.
I don't know anything about that world.
It's so cool for me to hear about that
kind of stuff because I don't know
anything about any of these kinds of
drugs,
so I'm just like amazing.
Edible pot is a motherfucker man.
Real careful.
But you can be healthy on a Vegan Diet.
You just have to be careful and you have
to supplement and you might have to
supplement with vitamin B 12,
which comes from animals.
Yeah,
and I know people that are on Vegan
diets that are also very healthy,
you know,
but yeah,
they're doing it the right way.
I guess it's got to be diligent and
there's also biodiversity where some
people works better than it does for
other people.
I know John fits try a Vegan diet for
awhile and it helped him for a little
while,
but then after awhile he just felt weak.
Like initially it helped him a lot.
Like you felt like you had more
endurance and he felt healthier but
slowly but surely he felt weaker and
weaker and then he just didn't feel like
he could compete at one 70 without
eating some sort of animal protein.
But you know,
you can get animal protein if you're
worried about the ethical consequences
of it.
You could,
you could get it from eggs and you don't
have to hurt anybody.
Like I have eggs,
these chickens there,
their pets.
I could walk up to them and pick them
up,
you know,
and they're not,
they're not going to harm.
They're not.
There's no factory farms situation.
If you have a backyard you can have
that.
And they free range,
they walk around,
you know you're going to have to deal
with the fact they eat bugs and if you
see something that says vegetarian fed
chickens with those poor fucking
chickens,
it's not their idea they want,
they want to eat everything.
Those are the motherfuckers really.
I fed him a mouse wants,
oh my God.
That episode where they're seeing my
kids weren't there for the finale.
Chicken sacrifice will.
So it was sort of highlights how crazy
people are when it comes to animals in
the hierarchy of what's okay to live and
what's okay to die.
We bought these pinkies for a hawk,
a hawk flew into a window and got
knocked the fuck out and hurt its wing.
And so we had to bring the Hawk to one
of those wildlife rescue places.
And so in the meantime,
this poor hawke was with us for a day
over the weekend.
We got to get some food.
So my family went to pet food,
stop and got these pinkies.
These mice,
they feed to snakes and they're like
basically the little babies,
it's kind of fucked up and you feed them
to the Hawk and that's what kept the
Hawk alive while we had them and
everybody's happy like,
oh,
the hawks still okie dokie amount,
but then there was this one mouse left.
My wife,
my daughter wanted to keep it as a pet.
I'm like,
you can't like this.
It's going to die like it doesn't have
its mom.
It needs to be fed.
And so I decided to feed to the chicken.
They were crying.
No,
don't do it like,
but you've fed it to a hawk regular.
Forgive you,
but the moment that thing touched down
those fucking chickens mold that.
Those little dinosaurs.
They're monsters.
Yeah.
My inlaws have chickens and yellow kind
of eat whatever.
Anything put in front of them.
Killed a mouse.
An actual mouse too.
Not a Pinky,
but in a mouse mouse that got into the
cage.
The amount.
They have a big chicken coop.
They get attacked by themselves.
You lose some of them here and there.
No,
they fuck each other up the package.
They fucking did decide to start chats
going on in their brains.
My dog killed a couple of them.
Unfortunately in a coyote got one.
One
that happens quite a bit.
It does happen.
But uh,
they fucking kill everything.
Just chickens.
They will fucking kill anything that's
small.
Like they packed my daughter and my wife
was like,
well,
they're just dumb.
They don't know any better.
I go,
no,
they're trying to eat her.
You just can't fucking eat.
Are you crazy?
She's little.
They're trying to figure out if she's a
little enough for them to eat the
fucking little dinosaurs.
After I saw after I heard that episode
and you talk about,
I had my girlfriend listening because
she loves chicken,
you know,
like the think it's so much healthier
cleaner than anything else.
And I'm like,
let's listen.
I listen to this shit.
Yeah,
Kinda messed her up a little bit.
Well,
chicken is healthy.
Just when you hear that you're kind of
like taken aback,
you know,
I just look factory farming,
I think everybody can agree is a monster
is side effect of civilization.
It's horrific and that's what's really
wrong with the way we get our food
stuffs so many.
I'm going to Keith and all that kind of
stuff.
He had a documentary food inc.
Have you seen it?
Yes.
Great documentary.
YeaH,
it's amazing.
It's amazing.
That's,
that's,
that's the darkness,
you know,
and if you feel better,
have not from not consuming animals,
good for you.
The problem is not those people.
The problem is those people that are
aggressively do she to anyone who eats
meat,
they just,
oh my god,
I get them on my troll them now.
I put hashtag vegan meat dishes when I
cook.
Anything that hasn't even started
hashtagging that.
Well,
you can just say you're vegan for
certain meals too,
because I see you post stuff on salad.
Write vegan meal.
Well,
most of my breakfast,
most of the time eating eggs.
I'm eating vegan.
That's not how they take it.
You're either you're either in or you're
out of the club.
Either you're in or in the way.
Now I understand their motivation.
I just think the way they go about it is
so wrong and it turns people off.
It's like the people that are against
for throwing paint on people with,
I guess not going to stop it.
It's going to make somebody mad.
That's it.
A lot of those animals that they get
from our clients about that.
Martin ever received the video.
We showed that video last week of the
martin chasing down the rabbit hole.
Just martin.
I didn't even know what a martin was
until I watched those shows.
You ever see those shows like the last
thing,
guys that live in the mountains for
trapping and shit.
A martin is like this little weasel and
it's not any bigger than a rabbit and
this rabbits running and the martins
running after it and they're filming it
on this snowy road and it's a long
chase.
I mean like hundreds and hundreds of
year.
I.
Here it is.
Look at this.
Look at that little fucker.
Shit.
Yeah.
He's hauling ass and he's chasing after
this rabbit rabbit is up ahead of them.
What is the name of this video?
If somebodY wants to watch,
if they're listening to this podcast,
it says martin chasing down rabbit.
I put it on my twitter a lonG time ago.
Whoa.
This shit.
And this is like halfway into the video.
Jamie did it in the middle.
What are they filming in iphone?
The rabbit goes off snowmobilers no was
a car.
A rabbit goes off into the side and they
go,
no,
motherfucker grabs them.
Damn.
But look,
they're the same size.
The rabbit is even actually bigger than
the martin,
but he jackson with his face then drags
them out loud and that's what they make
for coats out of those guys.
That's a big one for fur trappers.
Not that there's anYthing wrong with the
martin did.
That's what they do.
That's how they live.
Just a mean bastard.
That's all.
So we get by.
Yeah,
it's hard out there for a pimp.
Cold as fuck with a lift,
you know,
living up there in Alaska.
Um,
what,
what does the w.
Did you get any conclusions out of doing
this documentary?
I mean,
is there anything that you,
you got out of it where you,
like,
you think that it's important for people
to know?
Yeah,
I mean,
I,
I've learned a lot myself.
I think the number one thing that I've
learned,
it's very simple,
like I,
I'm not educated enough or have enough
experience to really save anybody.
I think anybody out there that has a
friend or a family member struggling
with drugs or alcohol,
that the number one thing that you can
constantly do is drive them towards
getting help,
whatever that is,
whether it's going to aa meetings,
whether it's going to get a rehab or
whatever,
just make them aware that they need
help.
They might not even know driving them
towards getting help because it's like
the most important thing that you can
do,
you know,
and I think that,
um,
you know,
a lot of people will talk shit about aaa
and say it doesn't work,
but I've seen it work.
I've seen every saturday morning in a,
down in the palisades,
there's a meeting,
there's like 200 guys in there and a lot
of people have been sober for 30 years,
you know,
so they're still going to meetings and
they're still helping people and it's a
community.
So,
uh,
that's kind of a part of it too,
right?
Not the money community of sober people,
you don't want to disappoint the other
people in the community.
The people I've met in a or some of my
best friends,
they're like the best,
you know,
like they're all,
everybody's trying to do good and you
know,
like they've maybe messed up in the past
and we feel bad about it now.
Everything we do is geared towards
trying to help people and do good.
Jimmy,
did you pull up anything on ibogaine or
ibogaine works?
Found a couple of stories but they
weren't really.
I didn't find like,
how do you spell it?
Ibo.
G I b o g a I n e I think I'm going to
say something to the court tomorrow and
I'll just say something.
Just to contrast them a little bit is
you don't need to be an expert to help
somebody,
you know,
you can help somebody,
like he's saying drive them towards,
you know,
making,
making sure they're getting help.
That was a kind of an issue with him.
And also an issue with my oldest brother
is a.
Especially with my oldest brother,
I kind of felt like I don't,
I don't know anything about like all
this addiction stuff,
I don't understand.
He's like bipolar,
but I don't know if he's bipolar and the
ups and downs or because of the drugs or
a combination thereof.
I don't know what the hell is going on,
so almost felt defeated in a way and
then anyone out there listening that has
dealt with addicts before.
You get burned by them so many times
that it just leaves you with a sour
taste in your mouth and you.
You don't even really want to help to a
certain point,
but you have to help.
You have to continue to reach out.
You have to realize that it's not the
person it is becoming a different person
over a period of time.
They're not the same person that they
once were and you have to try to help
them and you don't need to be an expert.
You don't need to know shIt about
addiction.
All you need to know is that they need
to get help and that a lot of the stuff
that's happening and you'll kind of hear
them say it over and over again.
They blame stuff on other people all the
time.
Um,
it's not really their fault.
They don't,
they literally don't have control
anymore and I don't want to make excuses
for people,
but that's the predicament that they get
and that's a predicament my oldest
brother was in and we weren't able to
pull him out of it.
And that's a predicament that he was in
and were able to,
are able to save his life.
It was one of the things you brought up
in the documentary is bipolar and the
diagnosis for bipolar and how many more
people are diagnosed at three percent in
10 years or something like that.
And what is the excuse of for that?
Is that they didn't know before or is it
just that they're trying to sell people
medicare?
Yeah,
they're trying to sell people on stuff
that happened with like adderall and
ritalin as well.
I think that like bipolar is definitely
a real thing and it's a lot.
I think it's like real bipolar is a lot
more rare than,
than is being diagnosed.
So when I say what is bipolar exactly
mean,
like what?
You're at different polls like,
uh,
you're,
you're a one one time,
you know,
you're really happy and hey,
it's so great to see it another time.
You're an asshole,
you know?
So it's,
it's just both opposite ends of the
spectrum.
We kind of ironic because that's how
we're addicts are.
Yeah.
And we all have that anyway.
Like we all have a little bit of like,
hey,
I'm really happy with the.
And I'm.
They wouldn't
treat our brother sometimes for certain
things because they wanted them to get
clean first,
but it's like shit hot,
you know,
he,
he's,
he's already an addict.
How the fuck did we get them clean so
they don't want to treat the bipolar.
It was,
you're right that there's similar
things.
Mark says something really important in
the documentary.
He said,
I talked to our older brother and the
one thing that he said to me is the only
time I felt normal was when I was in
jail because I was completely sober.
He had gotten thrown in jail for like,
yeah.
And I was like,
shit,
you're not bipolar,
you're not bipolar.
Maybe it's a,
maybe it's all the stuff via a lot.
Who knows?
Biggest part of it,
you know?
Wow.
So how long was he in jail for?
Three months.
Then that time he felt okay,
whoa.
Yeah,
I know.
That's was the craziest thing to me too.
That's nuts.
And then when he got out and just
started going back to his old ways and
he would go,
he would just go up and down,
you know.
And what did he get thrown in jail for?
Violating probation.
I mean like he was a bouncer at a bunch
of bars and he,
he got into so many fights and he town
bad ass beat up a lot of people.
If there was mma around back then he
might have,
he might have had a career,
but like he was kinda that,
that guy like he never was a bully.
He never boss anybody around,
but if he,
if he saw you and somebody was like,
choking you,
he'd go up and kick the guy's ass.
That's done.
It was never enough for him either to
just hit somebody.
He had to fucking throw a bar stool on
top of him or something afterward.
He was one of those guys.
So the bipolar diagnosis and the fact
that after he was in jail for three
months,
he felt totally normal.
Do you think that the,
that all the highs and lows are just
coming from the drugs in his system and
out of a system and the fluctuating
levels and just didn't know how to feel?
I think that's a big part of it.
I mean,
I can't really speak for him,
but I know for myself when I was trying
to get off of the drugs,
I went on a horrible drug called
suboxone,
which is a miracle drug for the time you
need it.
But the problem is I was on it for eight
months instead of for one week.
And that's a heroin drug,
right?
It's a,
it's an opiate that helps you get off of
other opiates.
So it's kind of a weird thing.
But if they.
Did that make you feel high when you're
on that stuff?
No,
they don't really feel high.
You just don't feel sick.
And so,
uh,
what happened to me,
I was,
I was on it for like a really long
extended period of time and I,
I felt completely out of whack all the
time.
I felt like,
like very up and down because if I
didn't have the drug in me,
I would have like anxiety,
oh my god,
I'm gonna get withdrawals.
You know,
if I didn't,
if I was running out of it,
I get anxiety.
I just had so many ups and downs from,
from that particular drug.
And I think also from,
from the opiate painkillers,
they always made me somebody that I
wasn't always like made me call my
girlfriend at the time and yell at her.
So do some asshole thing that wasn't
really,
you know,
they made you do that.
I felt compelled to do that in a way
that you would never feel compelled to
share if you were.
And you're always.
You always break it down to the truth.
Yeah,
they didn't.
They didn't force me to do it.
But while I was on those,
I exhibited behavior that I wouldn't
normally do.
The fucking girl in the movie lights
herself
on fire.
She's on that story.
It's so fucking sad that that story
killed me.
But yeah,
they,
they make you do some crazy shit like an
ice.
When I say make,
I think they,
they literally kind of make you do some
crazy stuff because I don't think you're
really not much control anymore.
Well your brain is a bunch of synopsis
and a bunch of neurochemicals reacting
and a bunch of shit going on.
And when you add some new shit in there
and you're throwing some massive opiates
in there and all of a sudden all the
signals are all fucking crossed and
everything's firing goofy.
It's literally not you.
And iT goes,
it goes to that same fact of like a,
I think therapy is really important for
people.
And I think therapy is something that
you get to do.
It's not something you have to do,
you know,
like you kind of get to do it.
It's like a,
some sort of,
you know,
it's like a luxury I think.
And the thing is that,
um,
people,
a lot of people will go to therapy and
then they want to get a drug with it,
you know,
like they want to go.
Like I said,
we have this drug seeking behavior where
we're like,
well,
a pill will fix me,
but talking to this guy's not gonna fix
me when actually talking to the guys,
what can fix you with?
What can be the cure?
It's like we have these things called
escape fires.
I don't know if you know what that is,
but like in firefighting,
you know,
there was this giant fire and it's,
and there was 30 15 firefighters on a
hill and a guy,
one of the guys said,
hey,
I'm going to light a fire to make the
fire jumped over this thing that people
like and I will be safe.
And everybody was like,
no,
That's not going to work.
And the guy lit a match and did it and
he was the only one that survived.
Everybody else was trying to get off the
mountain and they all died.
And like that's the problem with America
is how's that work?
I'm just saying,
well it's uk,
it's called the escape fire and so you
can light a fire to bake the fire,
sort of go around you.
I don't know exactly how that works,
but what I'm saying is like the answer a
lot.
The answer a lot of times can be right
in front of our face.
I can say,
you know what?
This person needs any therapy and the
person won't do it.
So that's a big problem with America and
our,
you know,
we want,
we want an answer,
we want a solution,
we want a pill,
we want a quick fix,
we want a pill to get you off pills.
But if I'm standing there I say,
you know what,
guys,
come with me,
I have the answer.
And he's like,
no,
you don't.
We already know that.
That's not a good answer,
you know.
So I think that's a problem.
It's like we have to open our eyes and
open our minds and start thinking of
different ways to heal.
Pain to cure pain.
Uh,
you know,
I mean,
you're never going to cure it.
You're gonna,
you're gonna hold it down for awhile.
You know,
I think the only way to fix something
really like surgery or like you said,
stem cells now and everything.
So progressive that I like,
I have a shoulder that I have a rotator
cuff surgery that I need to have and
I've just held off on getting the
surgery because I feel like it,
yOu know,
cutting my shoulder open and doing
whatever is going to do more damage.
And actually,
you know,
fix it,
which is maybe a stupid thinG to think,
but I'm actually trying to figure out
like,
hey,
stem cells or stem cells.
Good.
Is there another answer to this?
You know,
haven't found It yet,
but you know,
maybe I will.
And if I,
if I don't then I'll go get the surgery.
But I'm trying to explore other options.
Yeah.
It's not a bad idea to explore other
options,
but it really depends entirely upon
how badly your shoulders damaged,
how badly the structure of damaged in
the shoulder is a weird one because it
moves so weird.
It's got so many different ways it can
articulate.
It's a tear in the rotator cuff.
Super common.
Yeah.
You know,
one of the things that we talked about
before about these,
uh,
advertising,
the,
the ability to advertise for drugs.
I don't know if they're ever going to
take that down,
but I think that that is one of the more
disturbing aspects of the pharmaceutical
industry because we all know tHat
advertising gets people to buy shit and
it's not that big of a problem and it's
a car or when it's an iphone,
I don't haVe a problem with it.
You know what I mean?
People can say,
well,
it can.
You know,
it supports consumerism and materialism
and that's not bad.
That's not good for our culture.
You can just.
You could be strong enough to get past
that and I think you're going to be all
right,
but the pill thing,
well,
it's different.
We trust doctors like you don't go to a
car dealership,
trust in the car dealer to be like a
bargain,
right?
Take care of.
Take care of your life.
Let's also,
they suggest that you ask your doctor,
shouldn't your fucking doctor tell you
what medications do you know that people
that ask their doctor,
when I go into stat,
say,
when you go in and ask your doctor for a
pill,
75 percent of the people will get that
pill.
So that's,
that's crazy because here's what happens
wIth doctors.
The doctors are overprescribing for
sure,
but their hands are tied because if I go
into a doctor and I tell them I'm in
pain,
their job,
according to the medical industry,
their job is getting out of pain.
So how did they get out of pain?
They gave me an opiate,
painkillers.
They give me All these different things
to get me out of pain.
Now if they don't get me out of pain and
I fill out a doctor survey,
so you know what?
My doctor didn't get me out of pain.
That doctor gets a bad rating.
They get enough bad ratings,
they can lose their license.
So there's a lot of pressure on doctors
also.
How the hell is anybody know how much
pain you're in?
Yeah,
that's a big one,
right?
Neck pain or back pain really hurts,
like on a scale of one to 10,
say yeah,
anybody can say that they've got
something wrong with her back.
And I talk about painkiller.
Painkiller is actually a great thing for
acute pain.
So you get in a car accident,
you have a broken leg,
whatever it takes some oxycontin,
you don't feel it and it take that for
what,
two or three days,
you know,
you don't take that for four months
because then you become a drug addict.
So I think that if a also like the
prescribing and uh,
the,
the number of,
of actual pills we give people needs to
come down.
We just make to way too many drugs.
Is it,
is it all just money driven you think?
Because uh,
you know,
like if you get a ticket,
you get a speeding ticket that's like on
your record and you get noticed,
speeding ticket shows up,
right?
How come they don't have something
similar with,
with drugs?
You know,
when you,
when you get prescribed a drug,
like how come you don't have like a
record?
Well,
there is at least,
at least within the state,
in California there is a.
There is a thing,
but the problem is not everybody's
required to use it.
It's not mandatory.
So When when that kind of stuff becomes
mandatory,
it should be fun because a lot of people
say,
well,
it's my privacy.
Like if I go,
if I go to costco,
costco shouldn't be able to know what I
get at walgreens and I'm like,
you know what?
At some point we have to lose
that privacy issue because it's killing
people or to protect people.
Yeah.
We're.
We're to protect people.
I think sometimes in society we need
laws that protect people from
themselves.
That's what caused the whole oxycontin
industry in Florida was that they didn't
have a database where you could go to a
doctor,
get a prescription,
then go down the road,
get another prescription from another
doctor.
When the vanguard released that,
that piece of the oxycontin express,
which a really kind of highlighted that
and it showed a bunch of people and that
people that eventually wound up dying of
overdoses,
but when they followed them around and
found out how easy it is to go to these
pain management centers,
that's what changed the industry and
that's what also changed the pills,
the be able to crush them up and smoke
them.
We can't do that anymore.
Do they call those pill mills?
Pill mills and people just go.
And those people at West Virginia,
there's a movie called oxycontin.
I've pretty much seen every drug movie
now.
So oxycontin was a pretty interesting
movie where it was just about one single
town in West Virginia and that's like
the nickname of the town and these
people drive from west Virginia down to
Florida,
get like a thousand pills,
come back and sell them on.
It's like that's what they do.
And for West Virginia they got a lot of
money doing it and stuff like that,
you know,
because everything's cheaper there.
But uh,
they've caused an epidemic there.
There's,
there's a,
you know,
a couple of hundred people that live in
that town there and there's a couple
people that are trafficking all these
drugs in and making this huge problem.
Yeah.
Those depression commercials are
particularly problematic,
man,
where everybody's smiling.
There's butterflies and flowers and you
see the sun coming up on the person's
face and all of a sudden they're smiling
again and you want that.
Like it's.
It's really dangerous because it's so
influential.
You watch a commercial and those
commercials,
like it's visual,
there's music playing.
There's a pretty girl.
The sunset in so influential.
Yeah,
those little sad,
like a,
not like stick figures,
but a little fat chubby faces like round
moon.
Yay.
Little,
right.
The zoloft point of the advertisement Is
really is to sell it.
They have to list the side effects,
right.
That's part of it,
blah that real quick.
But the thing is the whole rest of the
commercials,
just to distract you from the side
effects.
One of this,
one of the commercials is showing a
woman,
which I,
you know,
that's fine.
I can take any,
but it just seems random.
They show this woman getting like this,
like a backhoe and she's operating as
bacco and ashley ashley's operated back
on,
they say don't operate heavy machinery
while using this product and you're
like,
this is so backwards.
She's operating a,
some sort of like a crane or a backhoe
and she's like in like a business outfit
and they don't have the machinery and
you're like,
where are these people getting,
you know,
who are the ad wizards behind this one?
And then the.
Then the other thing was the saying that
medication for depression didn't do any
better,
didn't get people any less depressed
than any other method of treating it.
Yeah.
And like you said,
you had a friend that he did some
antidepressants and it helped them and I
Was,
if he just got off fucking propecia,
it might have cut it off right there.
And also though I don't know enough
about it to say like shouldn't take this
or shouldn't take that.
What I'd say is like look into it more.
You know,
you haVe to become your own doctor,
you know.
And if I say like,
look,
I know how effective antidepressants
are,
how effective they are not,
but if I say it people to slam me for
it,
they're like,
oh,
this guy,
you know,
he's not a doctor or whatever.
So what I'm saying to you is go out and
do your research on it,
you know,
and find out how effective or
noneffective your drug is.
It just seemed crazy that they're
allowed to advertise and that seems like
something we have to stop.
But the amount of money that they have,
the amount.
I mean the Woman,
the woman in the documentary whose niece
burned herself to death,
she said it best,
the,
they're drug pushers,
they're illegal drug.
It was hurt right there.
Illegal drug pushers.
And the fact that we allow them to
advertise on television like that.
That's gotta stop.
It's gotta stop.
It's one of the most difficult temescal
yeah.
And we took tobacco off tv and you know,
we still have,
we still have a huge,
uh,
there's still a large amount of people
that die from smoking cigarettes or
whatever,
but like,
it's sort of their freedom now.
It's like their choice,
like they know it's bad,
it has a warning on it says this could
kill you if used as directed.
This could kill you.
And uh,
these pills aren't saying that.
No,
they're not saying that,
but documentaries like yours are,
and I think we need more stuff like
that.
Me need more things like what you did,
where people get ahold of it and they
watch it and they,
they listened to the message and they
go,
you know what?
There's this.
Is this something that,
this is something that needs to be
talked about.
This is something that you're not
hearing.
You're not hearing our leaders talk
about.
You're not hearing our politicians talk
about who are running for office,
are not talking about this massive
epidemic that's killing more people than
car accidents.
That was another interesting statistic
from your movie that pill overdose and
kill more people every year than car
accidents.
I'm lucky I came out the other side and
my brother didn't know our brother,
mad dog.
He didn't make it.
Make it out the other side.
And now my friends have lost two friends
to oxicon.
We lost an uncle as well.
Yeah,
and my goal is just to help people not
be in the predicament I was in.
It's terrible.
You know,
it's terrible.
I have people email me on facebook and I
encourage people tweet me or email me,
ask me questions.
I'm not.
I'm not too busy to help somebody in
need so so many people out here
listening to you that are listening to
this podcast that are just like us,
that know people that haVe died.
There's so many.
It's such a fucking,
like you said,
a one guy acting really weird.
If he have a friend That's acting
strange,
it's not showing up on time to certain
things that's avoiding you when you call
them and just not communicating with you
anymore.
You're going to have to try to figure
out a way to reach out to that person
because something's probably up.
You know,
rehab is very expensive and I want to
tell people,
don't use that as an excuse.
Don't use like,
it's too expensive.
I can't afford it.
Excuse,
hit me up and we'll figure out how to
get it done.
There's a free.
There's a lot of,
there's waYs to do these programs too,
I'd imagine.
Yeah.
There's ways to approach this.
There's government programs,
there's a certain insurance you can get,
like there's a lot of things that a lot
of people don't know and they should
know.
So if somebody out there struggling
like,
you know,
feel free to hit me up and I'll help as
people as I can.
What else do you think that people need
to know about the prescription drug
industry that you think is like a not,
not being talked about on a daily basis?
They're just being lied to.
A lot of people are being lied to.
These studies that they do.
They only have to do two studies.
They only have to show the fda to
studies that are effective and biased.
When I say effective,
they just mean they have to be slightly
more effective than a sugar pill,
which means it could be just some crappy
drug and that could be the placebo
effects.
Somebody said,
I feel better because I'm taking this.
right,
so that's.
That doesn't seem like as much of a
hurdle as a drug companies make it out
to be.
Yes,
it costs a lot of money to get a drug to
market,
like they say,
almost like a billion dollar sometimes
just to get a drug to the market,
but they're going to make so much more
money off that and profit off of that.
And then part of that money that the in
the research and development.
Well just put it this way,
last year,
I think it was last year,
and John Oliver oliver said this,
John Oliver did a great piece on this on
his show and he says,
uh,
I think last year that nine out of the
top 10 drug companies spent more money
on advertising than they did on research
and development.
That's a big fuck you to all of us a big
fuck you right in all of our faces are
they save a lot of money for lawsuits
too.
That's likE the price is the price of
businesses is them to save a lot of
money,
put a lot of money away for.
But then they do the calculations.
They run the numbers and I'm like,
okay,
well if this many people try to sue us
for death or whatever the fuck it is,
their problem we're still going to make
out with with $4,000,000,000 or whatever
it is.
There's all kinds of crazy shit factored
into the,
to the profit margin.
You know,
if I sell a standard business practice,
like gm does that and stuff.
Like a lot of companies,
you know,
it's just the way people do stuff.
If I make eight billioN dollars and I
lost two bIllion in a lawsuit,
who cares?
It's $6,000,000,000 on top,
right?
Yeah.
The studies,
the way you showed how they do their
studies too.
That was really an eye opening thing.
Hundreds of studies and they don't have
to show you the results there.
Listen,
if there's nothing wrong with this,
if,
if I'm not being lied to,
then why the fuck did the fda not do an
interview with me?
Why did the dea you do it?
No,
they were.
They're like,
well,
you can just look on our website.
All her shIt's on our website.
Are you fucking kidding me?
I want to do an interview with you,
I want to talk to you,
I want to ask your questions.
I want to ask the dea was responsible
for how many drugs are made each year,
what the hell,
what's going on here?
And they won't.
These people are public servants.
They work for us and they won't do
interviews.
And that's bullshit.
You know,
like that's something that makes me
angry because like,
I had all these ideas for the movie.
I'm going to ask this guy,
I'm going to ask this guy and they just
don't want to talk to you.
Whoa,
that's,
that's disturbing.
Because you would feel like someone
who's a public servant like that,
that they have an obligation to,
they should have some sort of a pr
representative that has an obligation to
state their policy.
And the pr representative told me,
uh,
like basically like,
um,
you know,
I'm not nbc and cbs.
I'm not hbo.
I'm,
I'm always
do all my movies independently and then
he'll bring them to somebody afterwards.
And so that's kind of a tough thing too,
is like not calling up and have the
credentials.
You have to establish documentaries that
have done very well.
I think that,
uh,
I also think that people might have seen
those documentary and say,
we're not coming in our doors,
you know,
fucking troublemaker.
Throw us under the bus,
man.
Just bizarre,
bizarre,
bizarre world we live in where this is
the norm there,
these,
these pills that people are taking these
consciousness altering pills that
they're trying to force down people's
throats.
That was the other thing that I wanted
to talk about,
the connection between statens and like
how little statents work and the fact
that statens,
the people that sell them also sell
viagra will make you impotent.
They sell viagra to give you a bone or
afterward there's a new commercial too
with the constipation.
If you're taking opiate pills and
they're in and you're getting
constipated and you constantly have
another pill for you,
it's probably the same goddamn company.
If you're taking a,
taking a psych bed,
it's not working.
You gotta throw abilify on top of not.
I'll build a phi.
Supposed to be like really scary for
people to like.
It's all scary what the abilify's like.
One of those ones that really gives you
a rabid suicide wait a second.
Our doctors really telling me,
telling us,
you and me that we need to take an
antidepressant and if it doesn't work,
if it doesn't work,
take another antidepressant top of it.
But you know what,
don't smoke weed.
That would be bad.
it's bad for you.
It seems like marijuana would fix.
Could fix those problems with anxiety
and stress and confused,
you know,
whatever.
Is marijuana fixing anxiety because it
makes me anxious as fuck.
Makes you paranoid a little bit.
Yeah.
Well it makes me aware.
I mean I think that paranoia is just be
you being aware of how vulnerable you
really are and how crazy the world.
We started thinking of weird shit and
start thinking about it as you know what
it is,
but staten.
So statens don't really help you.
Well look at that low.
If you lower cholesterol,
what's that gonna do for you?
Well,
there's good cholesterol and bad
cholesterol.
We have this idea in our head that we
have to get rid of cholesterol,
but I think getting like lowering your
cholesterol they say really doesn't have
much of an effect on like whether or not
you're going to have a heart attack.
It's not like one of the markers
anymore.
Like I think that the problem is not as
big of a factor as they once thought.
The problem is.
Like,
do you really need to lower your
cholesterol?
Do you really need to.
Like he'll fix your diet and do it
through other ways that's responsible
for a lot of brain function is
responsible for all testosterone cream.
Yeah.
I think,
uh,
you know,
people's cholesterol and trIglycerides,
it's of go through the roof just because
poor eating habits,
not necessarily because they eat
saturated fats,
saturated fats.
That's another thing that people keep
saying,
saturated fats are bad for you.
The parent old studies,
no,
they're not bad for you.
Saturated fats are,
it depends entirely on what your eating,
what your body requirements are.
If you eat too much of anything,
you're going to get fat and that's not
healthy.
Your saturated fats from pizza,
it's probably not the best option
because we're eating like four or five
times a day or something that I love
pizza.
Well,
we're all adults,
right?
But we're all learning from other adults
that,
you know,
our parents and our parent's parents
that didn't have much fucking
information.
So we're growing up with these people
that really didn't know what they were
talking about.
They really didn't have any idea where
we're eating sugary cereal for breakfast
and we just didn't know studies that our
parents had in the 19 sixties in the 19
seventies.
What they had to go on,
the information that they were they were
given.
It's just so poor in comparison to what
we know now have was up.
They want to do.
I was saying I have a projecT I want to
do that basically,
you know,
one day you'll read in the newspaper
that you should drink coffee.
It has all these health benefits and the
next day you'll read it as bad for you.
Right?
So you hAve all these conflicting things
all the time.
Go vegan and don't go vegan,
do keto,
don't know.
And nobody really knows the truth that I
don't know the truth.
So like that's what I want to do is go
out and seek a basis basically do
mythbusters in the world of health and
fitness because there are people out
there that no,
we just have to go find them and expose
them to the world so other people can
know.
There are a few people out there that
have a really good understanding of most
of what they're talking about.
But the problem is when it comes to the
human body,
there's so many fucking variables.
And then there's also so many different
types of people.
There's some people that just,
they need different nutritional,
they have different nutritional
requirements that maybe you do or I do.
There's just no getting around that.
We always talk about our friend dr.
Lane norton who uh,
kinda brought flexible dieting to the
forefront of most sure how familiar you
are with it.
But basically it's almost like
weightwatchers in a way where it's like
you can have all kinds of things.
You can eat some pizza,
you can have some ice cream,
you can eat steak,
you eat chicken,
you can eat all over the map as long as
you're kind of fitting within a calorie
macros as long as.
Yeah,
as long as it fits your macros,
as long as it fits your caloric intake
for the day and let's not be stupid
about it.
You can't be eating junk everyday all
the time.
Well,
people take his stuff out of context,
right,
and they'll say,
well,
they post pictures of pop tarts and say
I'm on flexible dieting,
and it's like,
well,
you didn't post a 95 percent of the
stuff that you ate that was healthy
chicken and rice or whatever,
or like vegan oreos.
I don't even think though that there's a
trend that people kind of understanding
this a little bit More now.
at least it's starting to gain momentum.
You've seen people that are
concentrating on organic vegetables.
I mean,
even just like the seminar that I did
where there was,
I don't know how many people there.
There's a bunch of people,
a shitload of people there.
I mean,
years ago,
if I did a power thing seminar,
I couldn't,
I couldn't beg people to go to it.
There's,
there's women there now.
There's girls,
you know.
It's like weird.
It's like I figured out the way to get
that big juicy ass.
Yeah.
There's not a whole lot of teenagers,
white women are evolving.
We would go into these power lifting
meets again that ass.
But yeah,
it's,
it's changing.
You know,
people are starting to learn that
strength is important.
Even as you get older,
as you get into their forties and
fifties and sixties,
more important because you need
to keep your bone density and keep your
muscle mass and it's important for
women,
you know,
they have osteoporosis and stuff like
that.
Eyes When you go on vacation and you go
by the pool and their bodies are just
gone.
Shoulders don't exist.
It's like old women.
I just want to run up to him and put
them in an americano and just ripped her
shoulder apart because it's just,
it's not attached to anything.
Yeah.
It just seems like it's like loosely.
You just feel like you're not together.
If you do that,
never do that.
I don't,
I'm just kidding.
Come on.
But I mean you look at their bodies,
you know,
like my god,
if this guy has to pick up anything,
his body's going to break and this is a
guy who at one point in time was a
teenager who was a young,
happy,
vibrant kid parking on the railroad or
doing some bass and maybe it's just been
gross as whole life,
but you see people as they get older.
My point is that if you live that
sedentary lifestyle and you sitting in
an office all day and if you're not
making your body work,
it's going to fucking atrophy and it's
gonna break down and pick some stuff up.
Do some squats,
airport.
When you go to the airport,
you realize how unhealthy this country
is because people are coming from
everywhere.
I go to the air like what was just in
the airport in Ohio and I'm like,
I'm.
There's not a lot of healthy.
Ohio's awesome.
How about disneyland?
And it's sad because you're only making
up one percent of the people.
If you see somebody who's kind of jackie
like,
hey,
what's up man?
Because it's rarely,
only ones.
Well,
how about when you go to disneyland?
It seems like a scooter festival.
Now.
Everyone's on scooters.
These people,
there's so many people that have eaten
their way out of walking.
They don't walk anymore.
They're oozing over the side.
It's what it is,
and you could say all day that it's a
disease.
You could say all but this.
It's real simple.
You're putting too much food in your
body.
Your body is getting too big.
It's really simple.
Well getting so big that like fat is now
growing in some odd places and stuff.
I mean people's bodies are or not even
no longer in the shape of a of a normal
human being,
and I'm not trying to fat shame people,
but that's.
That's the truth.
Don't even say that word because it's
not shaming.
It's so dumb.
If you shame them into losing weight,
that's probably beneficial to their
health.
That's not the way to do the best way to
do it necessarily,
but I think people,
because they're lazy,
fit shame people,
like they'll see him walking down the
street.
They'll the first day that they'll
discount all the work,
like all the steroids are now.
They'll say like,
you know,
that's not healthy.
Look at that guy or anybody that's
leading.
They're like,
oh,
he cares about it as a gym.
Well,
not only that,
they think you're dumb because you
weren't going to meet him.
You must be dumb.
You know?
I know this guy is a bodybuilder,
but he's also.
He has a phd.
Right?
And people will think he's dumb and
they're like,
oh my god,
we Just shut the fuck up.
You know,
you just,
everybody wants everybody else to have
soMe sort of a deficit.
Like this guy's rich yet,
but I heard he's got no dick.
You.
Yeah,
exactly.
Always,
always have to play when they can't fInd
a flaw.
What do they say?
Dump con.
She's a bitch.
She's a whore.
It's always going to be there.
It's always going to be that.
But just I feel like people are more
conscious about their diet now than
they've ever been before and they're
more conscious about it because it's
kind of been
getting out there in the public where it
didn't before,
you know,
it was like,
no,
it is very important and it is hard to
go to a grocery store and find the
actual things.
Indeed,
you know,
like you want to get things that are,
they don't have preservatives or
whatever and you have to like look for
it,
you know?
So you're kind of a hunter gatherer
again,
trying to hunt in the grocery store for
the shit that's good.
It's exciting for us because we've been
involved in this for over 20 years.
And then finally people are starting to,
we're like,
oh shit,
they're talking about stuff.
We were talking about two decades ago.
How coMe?
How come it's not mandatory to be taken
nutrition all through school?
Like it's just like ridiculous.
Like oh there's no time for that.
we have to teach you who the presidents
were and we got to teach you all this
other things that you're never going to
use and why not nutrition from a
documentary on sugar,
sugar,
sugar.
Yeah.
I watched it with my kids were lIke,
what?
My sugar film at the same company,
samuel goldwyn that did prescription
thugs put that out and it's cool because
that company is just looking for
important things to put out.
It's very,
very important.
The sugars are crazy.
My kids,
when they were really young that you
know,
certain amount of food and excess,
you know,
junk food is gonna make you fat.
I kept saYing that over and over again.
Now they're older,
so I don't say it because I don't want
them to have some sort of weird complex
about it anymore,
but they know they got the information.
They get the message got across.
They're eight and 12 now and so we're
kind of just put it in their head.
That feeling that you get,
that feels good when you take it in
healthy versus getting sick and so on,
but the feeling that you get that feels
good.
when you eat sugary foods like that
corresponds with a crash and that
crashes really bad for you.
Right?
so like now think about that.
Next time you eat ice cream,
I can enjoy it,
but understand that you're doing
something bad to your body because most
kids don't know.
They just,
they just the good part and then they
have to realize one day that there's a
bad part to it,
to the.
You have to teach them that if you mix
it with painkillers,
it feels great.
That was the other thing in your
documentary,
they're showing the kids,
you know how quickly they get kids on
like children's claraton
disapprove,
approve oxycontin for like 11 to 16 year
olds.
Yeah.
Well here's what the problem is,
here's what people are saying and it's
bullshit.
They're like,
oh well,
it just makes it easier for a doctor to
prescribe oxycontin to a cancer patient.
Like you're telling me that the fda is
going to come down and a doctor for
prescribing oxycontin to,
as you know,
he's going to die from cancer.
Like I don't think so.
Like,
I don't know,
maybe maybe they are,
but like,
it's so crazy because all that's going
to do is create a bigger epidemic.
Yeah.
They're very aware of them for sales.
I think they're very aware of that.
I don't think that's something that
needed to happen.
I think that,
you know,
these kids that we've been thought of
that.
Yeah,
some fucking monster to somebody that
makes.
That makes the drug right.
No one else hAs.
The lobbies are the Most powerful thing
in the world.
and that's what's.
Was there anything,
anything surprising when you were doing
this documentary?
Was there anything that really,
really took you by surprise?
Yeah,
I think,
uh,
what took me by surprise,
I relapsed during the documentary.
That was something that I didn't think
would happen.
But,
um,
that was,
that was the trigger.
What start,
what was it?
The hip replacement know what happened
was,
uh,
I.
Okay.
So I was taking a lot of prescription
painkillers right from my hip
replacement surgery.
Fast forward about five years.
I'm on them for a pretty long time.
actually.
Had to get my right hip replaced again.
So I had three hip surgeries,
not just to have both hips done and then
another,
you know,
another hip two years later.
So it was constantly painkiller,
painkiller,
painkiller because dr after the first
hip surgery,
never knew what was wrong with me.
There's just this perpetual cycle,
oh,
hey,
your hip is.
Two years later,
my doctor called me,
said,
oh,
you know what,
we screwed that up.
I'm sorry.
There's actually you're the socket never
grew in properly and it's moving and
that's why you're having so much pain.
I felt like I felt like I was on fire
for two years,
you know,
like my,
my hip was on fire.
So,
um,
that was a big part of the drug
addiction.
And then I basically,
by my best friend,
leland was,
uh,
a guy who,
he,
uh,
he was,
you know,
he was prescribed painkillers to and he
knew what he was doing.
He knew it was never wanting to overdo
it,
you know.
Um,
but I just remember one day,
uh,
I told him like,
I need to quit these.
I'm going to die,
you know,
and he,
he would get prescribed painkillers.
So I would try to get them from him and
he would say,
no,
I've,
I've cut you off,
you know,
you're done.
and I just realized I needed to get off
those painkillers.
I was going to die.
So I went on suboxone and that was like
another year on suboxone and then while
I was on suboxone that doctor put me on
like eight other drugs,
like a columbia pan and all these other
powerful crazy drugs where I banged up
my car,
you know,
driving around.
So it was like a constant,
perpetual mixed of these prescription
drugs.
And then I decided to get off everything
and get clean and I felt like when I did
get clean I felt like I could never
sleep.
So I started drinking like a fish,
you know,
I was drinking vodka full thing of vodka
every day to sleep.
He had to go to sleep and stop My mind
from racing.
Yeah.
Did that to work and that didn't work.
so I'm.
So it became a very heavy.
I became a very heavy drinker and um,
I would get these crazy hangovers and
that's what I just said,
you know,
what cures the hangover?
Xanax.
Wow.
That's,
that really works for me.
And um,
I would go on craigslist and I would buy
xanax from a kid in sun valley,
which is like way the fuck out from
venice.
You can buy xanax on craigslist.
Has that x oxycontin.
I showed,
I showed that in my documentary that
that was something that does.
The congressman was like,
whoa,
in the movie.
Yeah.
And then they stopped doing it.
But you were like,
I knew about it because I was doing it.
Yeah.
And what happened was I lied to him.
I said,
you know,
I used to do that like three years ago.
I just did it three days ago.
And you'll become a good liar,
you know,
when you're addicted to drugs.
And I was trying,
it was weird.
It was a weird thing.
I was trying to make a difference,
but I was still doing shit,
you know,
I didn't know how to stop.
That just seems so crazy that you could
buy drugs on craigslist.
That's insane.
Yeah.
I say in the movie,
like they,
they had shut down the whole
prostitution thing on craigslist.
Why don't they just shut down selling
drugs,
you know?
Why did they shut down the prostitution
thing?
I don't know.
Seemed like a great idea.
It just went over to backpage.com now.
yeah.
Now you,
you let everybody know,
hey,
there's a service.
Was there anything else that was
surprising?
We were doing it.
I mean,
I just,
I think a lot of it was surprising like
that the woman,
glen olsen,
who was the pharma rep who basically,
uh,
yeah,
there was,
there was so many things that like,
I always thought that a lot of the stuff
I was going to present in the movie was
a conspiracy theory.
You know,
like people are gonna think I'm crazy,
but then you find so much proof that
like you're being lied to that it's
crazy that the proof keeps mounting.
And that was,
that was always surprising to me.
How,
uh,
every sort of corner I would turn in the
movie,
I'd be like,
well,
this is something else that's messed up.
And then trying to get people to be in a
movie and talk about their,
uh,
their drug use isn't,
is that isn't ever easy.
You know,
that's always a problem.
Yeah.
That woman was really,
really.
It was really profound.
It was really intense.
But one of the things that she said,
what she was talking about,
are you worried that they're going to
kill you?
She goes,
no,
I'm worried that they're gonna kill you
and you and you and you,
and I'm going to be screaming from the
rooftops and no one's going to care.
Yeah.
That sounds crazy.
But It,
the whole time people were saying,
aren't you afraid they're going to kill
you?
And I said,
if they kill me because I made a movie
about prescription drugs,
that just proves the point,
you know,
like,
I'm not afraid.
I'm not gonna live my life and I'm not
going to live my life in fear because of
I'm going to make something and tell the
truth and somebody's going to kill me.
That'd be like the worst way to live
your life.
not only that,
it's not like they have a team of
assassins working for a pharmaceutical
company.
They don't.
They don't have to kill you because
there's going to keep making billions of
data.
We don't care like your.
Your documentary is profound as it is.
It's only going to put a dent and maybe
one percent of the people that would be
thinking about taking those drugs.
Exactly.
I mean,
that's the problem.
YeaH.
Well we can hope is that one percent
will be 10 percent in a few years and 20
percent in a decade or more and maybe
other people continue to make these
documentaries and I've covered,
you know,
new information in it.
The thing is Like,
you know,
yeah.
Like you said,
they're going to keep making money.
They're going to keep their basically
printing money anyway.
You know,
they're going to just keep doing it.
It's scary shit,
man.
It's scary shit to watch scary shit to,
to see peopLe that,
you know,
get hooked on these things,
and it's scary shit too.
Like that.
The guy that I was talking about where
I'm like,
what is going on with this guy?
And then one day he tells me about his
back.
I'm Like,
oh,
how many people are walking around like
that?
And when people are driving their cars
like that,
I mean you'll see out of their head.
I,
you know,
when I'm,
like I said,
when people,
when you do a movie like this,
it becomes a confessional and you will
be shocked at the people who were doing
the same exact thing as I was doing that
like would look down on me for.
BecauSe it was,
oh well you were a drug addict.
Like I'm not addicted to it.
Like I hear people saY that all the
time.
Like I'm not addicted though.
I'm like,
yeaH,
but that's what you're going to.
Something that was prescribed by a
doctor.
Maybe you don't feel like a drug addict
on the streets,
man.
Yes.
I know a lady who thinks she looks down
on marijuana,
like in a big way and she just talks
trash about it,
but she takes a xanax every night when I
can't go to.
When I started the movie,
I was exact same
way.
I always thought we always thought,
uh,
in our high school,
marijuana was for all the dirt bags.
Like I felt.
I thought that for so long and now I
look at him like,
did I miss the boat on that?
Like maybe what was I doing,
drinking and taking all these pills when
something was there,
you didn't want to be a loser.
And that's what we're,
it was drilled into our head when we
were kids.
People who smoke pot or losers and I
think,
um,
I think marijuana,
there's a slippery slope with marijuana
because now that it's become more
accepted,
medical marijuana,
in some states it's legal,
now they're just ramping it up and make
it stronger and stronger and stronger.
You know,
anything that alters your,
your consciousness can be problematic.
Yeah.
It'd be beneficial or it can be
problematic.
Yeah.
The only good thing about marijuana,
it doesn't have a physical addictive
property to it.
Will your body desires it in a way where
you're going to start sucking dicks and
robin people for it,
but it's certainly become problem.
Wasn't that in like half baked,
half baked.
I think that anything can be addictive.
Gambling can be addictive,
you know,
food,
porn,
you know,
when people get obsessed with things
that's addiction in a way,
you know,
you can get obsessed with all kinds of
healthy or unhealthy things.
And uh,
you know,
I think that what,
what we're seeing with this documentary
is a world that has been growing.
Um,
it's a,
it's an epidemic that's been growing
that we're just not getting that much
exposure to in the mainstream.
We're not hearing these numbers.
We're not hearing these statistics that
you presented in this movie.
The statistics about the $250 million
prescriptions a year.
Just that.
And what's sad is like they put people
on this endless cycle all the time.
Like chris liebing Who's in the movie
ufc,
you know,
uh,
he was,
he was awesome to talk to is great.
And then I talked to him like not that
long ago,
you've gotten in some trouble.
So I called them and to see how he's
doing and like,
it sucks because he's still on suboxone
and I'm like,
eh,
you don't like that's a drug that,
you know,
he's on it now.
He said he told him he was still on it
and he's still drinking once in a while
until it's taking that.
And it sucks because he's,
he's a cool guy,
you know,
he's a great guy,
a little reckless here and there,
but he was,
he was so awesome to talk to.
You actually became a friend through
doing the movie.
And I always worry about my friends,
like I don't want them to still be on
stuff or still be taking stuff,
you know?
Yeah.
I wanted to add that the reason why he
relapsed was because he tried to stop
everything cold Turkey on his own and he
stopped for seven days.
Right.
And then that's when he,
that's when he relapsed.
So those people out there that think
they can do it by themselves,
he probably can't.
You probably need to try to seek some
help.
It was a lot of people that are very
strong willed and they feel like I can
do it like some other pussies camp,
but I'm going to be able to do it and
you know,
I went through 90 days of rehab and I
came out and I've been sober for like 22
months and people in,
you know,
in my circle say that's a miracle
because a lot of people don't even make
it that far,
so I'm just like,
I'm just trying to keep going and trying
to get healthier because I think it's
all a snowball effect.
You can go snowball effect downhill or
you can go snowball effect and you know,
beyond the rise and started doing
everything right and eating like you're
eating and using people like you,
like you're a big inspiration to me.
I listen to the show all the time.
I think it's awesome.
It's a great source of information.
I have a bunch of different things I do
every day and listen to and watch and
try to gain information from everybody,
you know,
become a better personal.
Thanks.
I appreciate it and I do too.
I have a bunch of different podcasts
that I listen to and new sources that I
find and I think this is a cool time for
that,
you know,
and it's a cool time for like a guy like
you can come on a podcast and just talk
for a few hours and explain everything
and be open and people hear this more
than a million people will hear this and
it'll open their eyes to what this is
all about.
I felt obligated to be open because I
felt like I did so much bad shit.
Like,
like man,
I got to tell people about this and a
lot of people are afraid to be an open
book and I understand that the luxury I
have is I'm a nobody.
It doesn't matter.
You know?
I can tell you everything.
I have nothing to lose.
Well,
you're not a nobody.
I mean you're a well known documentary
film maker,
but I think that it takes balls no
matter who you are to do what you did.
So thanks.
Thanks for the documentary.
Thanks for making two awesome
documentaries that I've seen.
I still haven't seen trophy trophy kids
because I have kids.
I don't know.
The other thing too is it's not over,
you know,
he's still,
he's still working on his life,
still working on rebuilding and you
know,
I was a financial disaster.
We decided as a family,
you've had,
you know,
family meetings to figure out how the
fuck do we help him,
you know,
so we all got together and now they
actually moved him out of this pit of la
and moved him to sacramento.
He lives in sacramento now and davis,
he lives down the street from me and he
works for me now.
So we're just producing content for my
youtube channel and just cranking out
awesome information.
We'll probably do some documentary style
things as well.
It's funny because I inspired him to
start working out when he was 12 years
old and um,
and now he inspires me.
I mean,
he was a dyslexic kid.
He was,
you know,
his car.
He's worth millions of dollars now.
It's crazy because he was always told he
couldn't do it.
He wasn't smart enough and you're not
gonna make it and all that bullshit,
right that they tell you in school.
They put you in a class with the kids
that are eating glue and he invented
sundance gunfire.
It's almost like,
yeah,
it's almost like a meat head version of,
uh,
of the jerk,
the movie,
the jerk.
He invented a thing that helps you bench
press More weight without getting hurt
and boom.
And I think that it's an important
message for people to follow what
they're passionate about.
Not always worry so much about money
because money came because he followed
what he loved to do that don't give up
on shit.
Don't give up on the people that you
love.
don't give up on the people that you
care about.
we lost one.
I'm lucky to still have him here.
He's my hero.
My other brother was my hero as well.
Just you got to take value in the people
that are around you.
And there's,
there's inspiration and motivation to be
found all over the fucking place.
Stop being so god damn grumpy and
getting on youtube and talking shit.
I saw your bid that made me fucking
almost cries laughing so hard because
you're like,
all you gotta do is close your
motherfucking laptop,
bitch.
Yeah,
that's right.
But you know.
Anyway.
Yeah.
Just just try to be positive and a lot
of great things surrounding you.
Open your fucking eyes.
He went to your show for his birthday
and his,
him and his wife,
they love it.
They're laughing their asses off.
Julie diaz killed me.
Killed that,
that fucking guy.
So he's like,
hey,
she.
The day that we come,
because his wife got an argument.
He's like,
we got the day.
I come back from they arnold enough for
a week.
Yeah.
The day I come back,
I'm going to go to joe to joe rogan's
show.
Ah.
I don't really think it's that important
to go to.
Joe rogan is all through tech show.
A lot of miscommunication like in la,
like Why is that so important?
He's like,
well,
I'm going to go to a show and it'll be
awesome.
Like,
yeah,
well I Think it'd be good for us.
My brother.
Yeah,
you need to be with the kids and she,
she,
she thought he was going to go to your
comedy shall not be on your show
was upset.
I wAs like,
no,
honey,
I'm going to be on his podcast.
he was like,
oh,
okay.
That makes sense.
You know?
Oh,
well I thought it was like I'm flying
in.
We just went and a couple of weeks ago
she thought you were coming to see
standup.
Right,
right,
right.
Yeah,
we fucking idiot.
Why are you doing that?
Miscommunication through text and I'll
listen man.
Thank you so much.
Thank you both.
You guys a mb slingshot,
right?
That is a.
That's one of the instagrams.
The other one is at mark smelly bell.
That's my official instagram and if I
can plug my youtube is youtube.com
backslash super training.
I was six and to celebrate being on the
show,
we put on a coat up,
go to how much you bench.net and how
much you bench.net and type in rogan and
get 20 percent off.
Bam,
bam and prescription thugs.
It's available right now on itunes.
That's how I watched him is on amazon
through all that stuff.
Roku.
Shit on demand,
on your television and cable.
Anything you've got going on,
man.
Always got an open invite later.
Some awesome stuff coming up,
man.
Yeah,
shout out to all and bitches are
bitches.
I don't know what that means and cons.
All right.
Thank you guys.
Let's appreciate it.
Thank you.
Stem cells.