And boom,
we're live.
Before you take any,
uh,
Dr Gordon's advice,
I just want you to know folks.
He's scared of shrimp,
shellfish,
pork.
He's never had wild game and he refuses
to eat outside of a very narrowed
dietary discipline.
He's got like a very.
What is it?
You really do?
You really eat?
I don't eat pork.
You don't eat pork?
No pork.
That's.
But you know about Bacon,
right?
When was the last time you've had it in
Turkey?
Bacon?
A day?
Yeah.
I had Turkey Bacon.
Absolutely.
That's just pathetic.
Turkey sausage.
Turkey sex with two condoms on a totally
unnecessary.
Well,
some of us don't even use that,
but how could you eat Turkey bacon and
not eat the real Bacon Bacon?
I used to eat it,
but after getting sick and no one got
sick ever in the history of the world
from Bacon.
Do you eat bread?
Yes.
You have no problems with gluten?
Well,
I don't have a problem with gluten.
Okay.
There's a lot of people that do have a
problem with gluten.
Well,
I have a problem with pig.
You don't have any problems with pig.
How sure are you?
My school doesn't look as good as it
does when I'm not on it.
What are you doing?
Go look over your stool with a fine
tooth comb.
Every morning.
We're here.
We're with
Dr.
Mark Gordon,
my good friend and his friend Andrew
Marr,
who is what,
what is your position in the Warrior
Angels Foundation?
I found it,
uh,
Joe,
so,
uh,
founder and former Greenberg and tell us
all about what it's about and what the
mission is.
Yeah,
absolutely.
Um,
our mission is to get no cost,
a traumatic brain injury treatment to
veterans who need it,
so it's an alternative means for to get
guys treatment outside of the medical
model,
which is predicated on a medication and
psychotherapy,
which it does not improve quality of
life.
Is that changing at all because of,
you know,
all the work that Dr Gordon has been
doing and there's been a lot of.
I've heard outside of you even mention
of your name,
people bring up your therapies and
things that you've been promoting for
several years.
Has,
is that changing in the community at
all?
We're working to change it actively,
so,
uh,
we're,
we're going to have a meeting next month
with some,
uh,
some top people and the active duty side
of the house.
We're also meeting with our and,
and works of getting with the Veterans
Administration and working that.
So we're going,
they're going to know everything across
the board about these protocols,
why they work,
why they're better,
how they're cost efficient,
how they're time efficient,
how this can not only improve as
soldier's life,
but the life of the family child.
Second order effects go on and on and
on.
So the evidence is out there,
the science is behind it.
This isn't false hope we're not offering
any false hope.
Everything is science,
evidence based,
uh,
reporting that we're doing and based off
Dr Gordon's clinical application of
years and years of doing it.
So the short answer is yes,
they're hearing about it and we have a
five year plan to overtake the system
and have them implement these on both
sides of the house.
So to speak.
Now,
for people who haven't heard any of our
podcasts before,
haven't heard your discussion
about it.
The one of the biggest issues that we're
experiencing with soldiers coming back
from Afghanistan and Iraq is if you hear
my voice,
I've got a little bit of a cold ladies
and gentlemen,
a traumatic brain injury elk a lot.
How dare you,
it's big bacon,
Bacon,
and a clam.
Um,
a lot of soldiers are coming back from
these,
these wars with injuries that may have
been fatal in the past.
They're no longer because of all these
advancements in medical technology,
but they're still still dealing with the
ongoing effects of the war,
the traumatic brain injury.
Now,
what you have found and many others have
supported this,
is that a lot of this is there's damage
to the pituitary gland.
It stops the production of hormones.
This leads to deep depression and leads
to some pretty significant issues that
soldiers are facing.
So if you could just fill people in on
that.
Well,
what we found is that,
um,
because of the body armor being so
efficient,
a lot of the blast damage,
instead of killing someone is leaving
them with trauma to the brain in any
form of trauma to the brain,
whether or not it's a blast trauma being
hit on the head,
slip and fall,
a automobile accident,
turning upside down or whatever the
situation might be.
A,
the brain changes its chemistry because
of inflammation and that's from tearing
of little nerves.
It's not only the pituitary and that's
been some of the problem that we've had
is focusing as I focus on narrow kind of
diet,
focusing in on just the pituitary,
but what we found is a group of
chemistry in the brain called neuro
steroids,
which regulate our personality in some
of those neuro steroids have names like
to stasia drone or dihydrotestosterone,
estrogen,
pregnenolone and the literature has been
around since about 1986 showing that
these regulate our brain function.
So head trauma of any sort can cause it
to decrease number one.
Number two,
with any form of damage to the brain,
you get inflammation and that
inflammation expands.
Let's say if there was a small area of
tear in the brain or a bullet that
penetrate a penetrating injury to the
head,
that area where the bullet or the
foreign object a diminished amount of
brain tissue,
it grows larger because of inflammation.
It destroys more and more neurons in the
more cells in the brain that are called
neurons are destroyed.
The greater the onset of cognitive
impairment,
your ability to use your brain in a
function and then emotionality changes.
No.
How did you get involved in this and how
did you figure out what so many people
hadn't figured out what this the with
the emphasis on therapy and pain
medication,
antidepressants.
How did you see through that?
Yeah.
Well,
I really didn't discover anything.
All I did was in reading the literature,
as much as I read it,
saw that people had already laid the
pathway for me to follow and I've
followed it intensely for the past 21
years doing endocrinology in the past 10
years doing specifically
neuroendocrinology,
which deals the brain and it's in my
population of patients.
I used to see them for hormone
deficiency and then started going back
asking them those were the hormone
deficiency,
if they've had any kind of head trauma
in the first book that I wrote,
which had the first introduction for me
to write about traumatic brain injury
and hormone deficiency was the young kid
by the name Michael,
who had been in a um,
who had come to me.
His parents brought him in and he had
hormone deficiency and we correct it,
is personality,
improved his quality of life,
improve,
and then read an article which I've
shared with you in the past which came
out of a Turkey about pugilists who had
the specific growth hormone deficiency.
And that was my epiphany article where I
started looking further and further into
literature and Moo,
moo tie.
They had a hormone deficiency and then
boom,
all the hormone deficiencies.
So this kid,
I went back to him and said,
have you ever had any trauma of any
kind?
He said,
well,
when he was 17,
he was 21 at the time when he was 17.
He was in a motorcycle accident,
was in a coma for three days,
came out of the coma,
and his neurologist said,
oh,
you'll be fine.
He progressively got worse.
So that set the stage for me to start
looking at this relationship between any
kind of head trauma.
And then 2007.
Uh,
my first military was a green baret.
I met the wife who was a emergency room
doc in North Carolina and she called me
and told me about her husband who was
six towards the duty was having some
problems.
We ran.
We donated the money for him to get the
full testing and turn out who's hormone
deficient when we correct it is
hormones.
He was back in the good.
A good light with the military was
getting ready to get kicked out for
insubordination.
And that progressed on 2009,
uh,
with opening up our practice to
military.
And it just kept on repeating itself the
same pattern,
the same head trauma blast,
a blast injury and hormone deficiency.
And now,
how's this being received?
Like the rest of the medical community?
Because,
well,
this is an uphill battle because the way
it's being treated presently,
um,
if you look at the literature from 2012,
410,000
service servicemen came back as veterans
and,
um,
were diagnosed with ptsd.
Now a posttraumatic stress disorder is
usually perceived as being a
psychological psychologically
precipitated event where they witnessed
something that was horrifying to them,
a death of a friend,
loss of a limb or whatever the situation
might have been to stimulate it.
And that immediately opened him up to
simple treatment here,
take this packet of antidepressants and
you'll get better.
Well,
they didn't get better,
so they didn't get better because they
were having what's called treatment
resistant depression,
which now we find is due to hormonal
deficiency.
If you look at the civilian population,
people with hormone to,
with treatment resistant depression,
you check them out and the testosterone
deficient or estrogen overdose,
or low progesterone or low pregnenolone,
other chemicals that are in our brain.
And,
um,
these individuals have been the,
the foundation of what I do in trying to
find a simple way to replenish them.
What you have to do is test them and
that's not being done.
It's so much easier just to hand a
packet and say you have ptsd when the
majority of them are traumatic brain
injury,
and I was on Dr drew show with one of
our patients who was a army corpsman and
he didn't have a single scratch on his
body,
but within two years of leaving a
separating from the service,
he started developing depression,
mood swings,
explosive personality.
He ends up coming into our program and
we find out he has two and a half
hormone deficiencies and the pattern is
indicative of having had head trauma.
Well turned out he would walk behind
Abramson tanks as they were just
charging their shells and he said,
man,
my body would shut her,
and he was around javelin missiles.
He was around repetitive gunfire.
He personally didn't have a scratch on
him.
That's incredible that just the recoil,
just a boom,
Christa,
the sonic boom,
the impact that that,
you know,
shocking.
His body can do that too,
right?
There are books out and the government
has lots of books out on blast trauma.
In fact,
one of the amazing things for me to have
read was the army did a study on
individuals who had had blast damage,
blast trauma,
no physical Amma just blast,
and they put them on a simple product
called NSC assisting Nac and those that
were on it got better,
but how come we're not hearing about
what is that stuff in a sealed system?
It's a precursor to glutathione,
which is the number one
anti-inflammatory,
excuse me,
anti free radical,
a antioxidant system in our brain and
it's a becomes deficient.
It's indogenous within our system of
glutathione is the same stuff that you.
You recommend taking booze it well,
yet glutathione helps with metabolism in
the liver to detoxify.
Okay.
Here's the thing about Nac though also
that mark told me and I'm on that
product,
but if if I was be a.
If I was taking that while I was still
operating and the problems that I had
never would have happened,
they would have cut it off so we can
essentially cut off these problems just
by being proactive and preventative in
this way.
So if we were right now today to
administer to all special operations
soldiers in AC,
a lot of the problems that we're having
out the window,
that's crazy.
That's crazy,
right?
It's true medicine,
you know,
what's going on is all,
trying to catch up,
always trying to catch up with what we
do is proactive.
We see patterns in the blood that if we
let them keep on sliding until they're
sick,
they'll get even,
you know,
absolutely sick in the medical model
right now is right this second.
You're
not sick.
Let's wait until you get sick before we
do something.
One of the more shocking things in
working with the UFC is we got involved
with.
We do these events called fight for the
troops.
We do them on basis.
And uh,
we uh,
we got involved with the intrepid
foundation for Intrepid Foundation for
excellent.
You find out how,
how little money the government gives
them and how much they have to raise
outside and,
and,
and doing functions like these big UFC
events.
And that to me was one of the most
disturbing things about those events.
I'm like,
how is it possible that we can have all
this money for all these different
missions,
all this money for all these different
things,
but we don't have money to take care of
these guys when they come back home.
That seems.
That seems criminal.
Well in unethical.
Yeah,
at a minimum,
at a minimum.
What is the highest level?
I mean this is if you,
if,
if you count on soldiers to do what you
ask of them and put their body on the
line to,
to complete missions and then you don't
take take care of them when they come
back.
How do you ever expect anybody to be
patriotic?
Well,
here's the thing,
Joe,
like there was millions of dollars spent
on me personally on my training and then
you can't put a number on that
experience,
right?
So to,
to produce a special operations soldier,
millions of dollars.
So it makes sense to put in proper
preventative programs to make sure those
guys are forming,
performing at elite levels.
Right?
We're going to do that for our weapons
systems.
We're going to do that for our vehicles,
for aircraft.
Why would we not do that for the same
thing as our guys,
but you know what,
we're not waiting for anybody else to
come up and say,
okay,
we're going to do this.
We,
uh,
I'm following Dr Gordon's lead started
the foundation and we're doing it and
uh,
we're gonna we're changing it from the
inside out,
from top to bottom,
bottom to top.
Well,
I think maybe it takes guys like you
that are on the inside to do that.
I feel like the bureaucrats,
the people that are in the air
conditioned offices that are deciding
where money goes,
if they don't,
they don't have a stake in it.
They're disconnected.
So they don't,
they don't feel it and they don't
understand it,
but it,
it's,
it's simple because we're providing
science,
evidence based solutions,
not,
not bitching.
Are Griping,
complaining,
offering solutions based on science.
And how long have you been involved in
with this foundation?
Uh,
we started January one of this year.
Yep.
So just taking off just get.
Yeah,
I was just medically retired and in
June,
so I started up.
I was actually,
I had to go outside of the military
medical system to get alternative
treatment,
alternative being not medication,
not psychotherapy and medication.
Very similar to when magazine was on
here,
the navy seal.
I was on 13 different meds and for you
know,
it,
you're just,
you're,
you're not the person that you used to
be,
you know,
I was uh,
on elite up capable of performing at an
elite level in situations of life,
death consistently and reliably.
And then all of sudden I have a problem,
you know,
handling things that just don't add up.
You know,
your behavior is not right.
I can't remember things driving home,
I don't know where I'm at.
Five years,
I've driven that route every day.
All of a sudden they look up,
you don't know where you're at.
Writing a sentence in the middle,
in the middle of it.
I can't,
I don't know what I'm writing about,
you know what I mean?
So those kinds of things.
So it was easy for me to put my hand up
and say,
Hey,
this is,
this is psalms going on here,
this is not right.
And that was basically saying,
Hey,
I'm on fire,
somebody has put this fire out and this
kept throwing medication and medication,
medication,
and then you start having anxiety
attacks,
which was completely foreign to me.
Right.
That was something that some other
person a week person's problem as I
perceived it.
And now I'm having these anxiety attacks
where I'm breaking down emotionally and
crying in public and I,
I can't,
I have no control over it.
And uh,
and happening in front of my family,
my wife and my kids,
and I was just like,
hey,
enough is enough.
And going out,
trying to find different things led me
to let me demark Dr Gordon.
And He,
uh,
he introduced me to his protocols.
He actually sent me an email and the
first line he says,
Hey Andrew,
you know,
I'm this and we're doing this and I'm
not a coop by the way.
And I was like,
okay.
I liked that,
I liked that.
I liked that guy.
Yeah.
Very debatable introduction.
I'm not a cook.
I'm,
I'm interested in what he's doing.
Kooks will always tell you they're not
kooks.
Yeah.
No.
So that's why I was drawn to him,
by the way.
Crazy.
Yeah.
So do you,
do you have a specific injury or a
specific moment where things changed
for,
you know,
I was an explosive breacher so I was in
around explosions for my entire career.
You know what I mean?
I was only knocked unconscious one time
in combat.
But the thing that mark was saying,
and this is just,
this goes outside the veteran
population,
this goes with anybody.
But,
um,
the symptoms can come in months,
weeks,
years,
days,
whatever,
later,
right?
So it wasn't attributed to any one
thing.
So six months later after my last
deployment,
I'm starting to have these problems.
They're starting to manifest and when
I'm,
when I'm bringing this up to the
attention,
you know,
it's like,
okay,
well this is a psychological issue.
And I'm like,
well,
I've been doing this for a long time.
This is what I want to be doing.
That's bullshit.
It's not a psychological issue and
here's why I wouldn't be able to perform
like this and all of a sudden I just
can't do it.
And,
and,
um,
so that,
that was just very frustrating,
you know,
in that regard,
trying,
trying to,
to come out and try to find some,
some real answers and only like mark
said,
what it takes is an individualized
approach,
right.
And uh,
and that uses evidence based diagnostics
to pinpoint and treat the underlying
condition.
But nobody was trying to figure out my
whole story.
Um,
and,
and when you don't do that,
you just take,
find out what the symptoms are and you
treat those symptoms with medication,
then you're not,
you're not doing anything to fix it.
But um,
so that's,
that's kind of why it's hard to,
for,
for I think,
uh,
the medical community understand it
right now because if you a problem
and you can't necessarily attribute that
to a major accident or a major injury or
a major explosion,
then it's like,
okay,
well we don't know what it is.
It's a psychological problem.
We're going to put them on packet a and
we'll see how he is in two weeks.
Yeah,
that expression psychological issue is a
real tricky one,
isn't it?
Because your psychological makeup a lot
of times is dependent upon your physical
health and what's going on in your body
can greatly affect your mind,
but when someone says psychological
issue,
especially for a guy like you,
what they're trying to say is that
you're weak,
right?
They're trying to say that you can't
handle the pressure salute and that
you're cracking and this is what it is,
the integrity of it.
It's called Comorbid and this is an
argument that's going back between the
psychiatric world and the non
psychiatric world.
We're in Comorbid,
which came first,
the situation that precipitated
depression with the depression that's
develops the situation in this
particular instance relative to Andrew
is his chemistry of his body was doing
great until he had that group of insults
to them.
Whether or not it was that huge trump
that got blown up 100 feet in the air
and you've got the shockwave that
knocked you out,
um,
or the repetitive gunfire that you had
or the breaching.
How many licks does it take to get to
the center of a tootsie roll?
Pop.
It's different for everybody.
Everybody is so different.
So what happens is as you start losing
these hormones,
I mean one of the hormones that I've
repeated a number of times in our repeat
again,
pregnenolone has been found to control
the anxiety affect in the body,
in the brain.
So morning anxiety or pregnenolone or
social anxiety,
uh,
can be affected.
And you know,
I have patients who have been in auto
accidents who never had anxiety attacks
or panic attacks,
and they wake up six months after the
injury and they've got morning anxiety.
They are pregnenolone levels.
Instead of being average about 110 are
down at six or seven.
You correct them back 110,
their anxiety disappeared.
What is pregnant?
Pregnenolone is called the mother of all
hormones.
It comes from cholesterol.
It's the first hormone or steroid
hormone,
official steroid hormone that comes off
of cholesterol.
So if we interrupt cholesterol in our
body,
we lose pregnenolone,
which becomes the precursor to the Aga
and testosterone on one side and pro
progesterone and cortisol and another
side.
So with low pregnenolone,
it can lead to all the hormones that
help to regulate our brain function and
our life.
Cortisol,
if you don't have cortisol,
you get a syndrome called Addison's
disease and you can die and most people
associate cortisol with high levels of
it being problematic,
right?
Stress,
stress,
stress related,
and you know,
everybody thinks it's emotional stress,
but there are five stressors.
You know there's emotional or
intellectual,
emotional stress,
physical stress,
nutritional stress can precipitate high
amount of cortisol.
If you're fasting,
cortisol goes up and then there's
chemical stress like a chemotherapy or
certain medication that you take alcohol
to.
Certain drugs can do it and they can
influence the adrenal glands.
Production of Cortisol,
which is called an adaptogen,
which allows you to go from one level of
physical functioning,
mental functioning to another.
It adapts,
helps you to adapt,
you know?
Wow.
I gotta tell you when I have these
conversations with you about this issue,
it's kind of frustrating to me because
it seems like you're.
You're making all this sense and you're
talking about this.
This is broad spectrum of different
hormones and all these different
variables that exist in the human mind
and how importantly are to maintain
proper levels of them for how for
function.
But you're just not a lot of people like
you out there.
They're talking about this like,
this is what you're saying is,
is a fairly controversial treatment.
Dr Gordon to me like this,
he's like,
this is like 1960 and we're saying we're
going to put a man on the moon by 1969
and everybody says you guys are bat shit
crazy.
You know what I mean?
That that's.
That's where we're at.
It's it seems like.
Is it because there's not a lot of
motivation for innovation when it comes
to treatment or is it a.
is it.
What's the resistance to understanding
all these different variables?
If for 30 years
plus years you've been told that you
treat depression by giving this pill,
that's either an Ssri or an Abcd or
whatever it is you're going to give that
pill and if someone comes in,
a coupe comes in and says,
look at the literature for the past 35
years,
even as far back as 1958 with Dah da Dah
da,
his antidepressant.
You come in with these natural products
that have no patents on it,
that you can walk into a GNC,
you can get it from onnit,
you can get it from any of these
companies and take it natural,
100 percent natural coming from Mexican
wild yams and it fixes your depression
and it costs you three cents a day,
five cents a day,
ten cents a day as opposed to the cost
for some of these other medication.
Who are you going to believe?
This Kook who talks about over the
counter product or the pharmaceutical
rep who talks about this prescription
medication.
That is the problem,
right?
Official sounding names and designations
and correct.
I got it and it's an uphill battle in
the way that I approach it with my
science background.
Not just medical,
but the science research I did in the
beginning is to line up all the
information,
irrefutable information and hand it to
someone and read it.
See,
for a dummy like me who's obviously in
the outside of all this,
how do I get you in trouble?
You got me in trouble.
You put that picture.
Will you have lunch together and you
split here with the brilliant Dr Gordon.
I got a lot of shit from your people.
Why?
Because they said that you know you're.
You're a smart guy,
and I said,
you're absolutely brilliant.
Trust me,
I'm a dummy dummy.
They think I'm smart.
It's because if they think I'm smart
because they're done with the,
call me dumb please.
But what I'm saying is like for someone
like me that has zero science
backgrounds,
what I always assume is that the way
things got better and the way people
figure things out is that they just
looked at the facts and then when new
facts came in,
they adjusted accordingly,
but it seems like there's resistance
against that.
Correct.
The status quo is very clearly.
We hand everybody this antidepressant.
We're not gonna hand them this natural
product that's been shown since 1986,
1958 on another large group of research
to be beneficial blind washout studies
for benefit and depression,
natural product.
They don't want to use natural products
because it's in.
It's in essence,
as I see it stating that,
well,
you don't really need the
pharmaceutical.
You can just get a natural product,
so do you think there's just so much
money involved in pushing the
pharmaceutical drugs that these doctors
are reluctant to go against it or not
prescribe it or step out on a limb?
Well,
you know the the medical community,
the medical boards of every state.
It's the standard of care in your
community,
which means that if there are 100
doctors in a community of physicians and
the standard for 99 percent of them is
to use a SSRI.
The one doctor who uses a non ssr are I
can be pulled into the medical board,
has practicing outside the scope of the
medical community as well as doctors in
general don't want to be looked at as
being that one person who is trying to
introduce something new,
revolutionary,
something that's worth something.
They worked very diligently at for 21
years to show the science and the
clinical cases that it works.
It's a maverick and our medical society
doesn't work with Mavericks.
It works with mass.
There's a lot of forces that are kind of
stacked up against it,
but that doesn't mean that that's a
reason to cower and not stand up to it.
Right?
I mean it's either it's either right or
it isn't right and we're saying Dr
Gordon is right and we're going to.
We're gonna fight it to do our last
breath to change it into 300 million
people in America on antidepressants.
And if,
if you're on an antidepressant and
you're still depressed,
guess what?
It's probably not.
That's probably not the underlying
condition.
It's what science has shown us.
Its a hormonal imbalance or able to
interdict that and effectively treat it.
And the problem is,
you know,
using the term hormone,
I've been slowly getting away from the
neuroactive steroids,
steroids,
these neuro active neuroactive steroids
are,
we'll say neuro steroids.
It was
found in 1986 by a Dr blue out of bay
loop out of Paris,
France,
that the brain has the chemistry to take
cholesterol and to make it into
testosterone,
make it into pregnenolone,
make it into progesterone in the brain.
For many,
many years,
biopsies of the brain would find
testosterone it and they thought it came
from,
you know your testicles or thyroid in
the that came from your thyroid gland in
the neck.
What we're finding is neuro steroids are
made what we called the Nova within the
brain itself,
and when you have trauma or
inflammation,
you lose that,
and that's why I believe based on
reading the literature and my
interpretation,
that's what can be faulted.
How I interpret it is that that is the
cause for all the transitions in the
brain,
but there are receptors in the brain
that regulate how nerves conduct and
what they found is these nerves have not
only magnesium.
Zinc is a volume receptor,
and they found a pregnenolone receptor,
so they found a receptor which
pregnenolone works to regulate,
to smooth out,
to calm you down so that you're not
having panic attacks or emotional
turpitude and yelling,
screaming,
and picking up a gun and shooting
someone or throwing something or yelling
or beating someone up,
getting assaulted.
Her sympathetic nervous system has just
gone crazy.
The whole,
the entire nervous system goes off,
so in a sense,
what you're saying is there's different
types of testosterone,
different types of hormones that are
produced in different areas of the body
that it's not just your testicles that
are doing it.
Correct.
It's the same testosterone.
You know,
people talk about bio equivalent bio.
What is it?
Bio identical hormones,
testosterone.
To be testosterone has to be equal
bioequivalent,
so the brain produces the same
testosterone as the testicles.
The brain produces same pregnenolone as
the cholesterol elsewhere in the city.
When the brain is injured,
it no longer produces it at the correct
levels,
correct.
You lose it.
In studies that are done in Alzheimer's
patients,
they found the frontal lobes of the
brain,
which regulates executive function,
making sure that you make the right
decision.
You're able to make the coffee in the
right sequence,
making sure the butters at the end is
all regulated by the frontal part of the
brain,
which is the most common area that is
damaged in to and fro kind of auto
accidents or explosions throw you back,
so they found pregnenolone.
Pregnenolone deficiency,
the same thing.
We're finding in boxers,
in pugilists,
in MMA and everybody,
there's a deficiency,
and I think I shared with you a nfl did
a study where they found that 19 times
faster box of nfl players are 19 times
more prone to develop Alzheimer's
disease between 30 and 50 years of age.
What else?
Wait a second.
Thirty years of age developing
Alzheimer's.
Did you see that recent study that said
96 percent of all former players have a
gte?
Yep.
Ninety six percent.
That's incredible.
Let's see.
Uh,
it was 97 out of 98.
People have brains that were tested,
had cte,
which I guess is 96 percent phenomenal.
And why don't they do the same testing
for military and soldiers?
Yeah.
What Dr Gordon was saying about all the
different neuro steroids,
for instance,
like cholesterol,
he's saying as a precursor to
testosterone.
So,
but if you take a stat and drug that
lowers your cholesterol,
guess what?
The byproduct that is,
it messes up your testosterone.
So what,
what we're understanding is our
chemistry is all linked,
man.
It's all together.
If you do,
you can't just treat testosterone.
If the stuff above it isn't as affected
and you're not treating that well,
guess what?
The military model doesn't even test for
that and if you're not treating things
below testosterone that,
that produces,
I'm at that level with it.
If it's deficient or insufficient,
then you're not going to get what you
need.
So until you look at your body,
your chemistry as a whole and you
interdicted accordingly,
you're going to continue to have this,
these mass problems across the board and
the ones that are manifesting and uh,
with soldiers,
with fighters,
with football players.
But you know,
at the end if you take these drugs,
alter it then with the civilian
population as well.
So it's not just a,
like a niche market here,
it's everybody is affected by this.
So this is the,
what's amazing about what Dr Warren's
doing.
It could fix a lot of things.
One of the,
the things that has just come up on the
table is looking back at the thousand
plus people that we've put on a program.
Unfortunately we only have about 50
veterans on program.
The rest are civilians.
What we're seeing is those that are
addicted to opioids or narcotics or
alcohol addiction are able to get off at
rapidly.
When Matthew was on here,
Matthew was on 15 different drugs of
that grouping.
He was on eight oxycotton a day and I
spoke to him recently specifically about
this.
He was taking it for 18 months.
He was on morphine 40 tablets.
It's either 40 or 60 milligrams per
tablet and then fentanyl,
fentanyl patch,
which is a pain patch,
and in six weeks he was off of 14 of the
15 medications,
a pain patch on top of all those pills,
but he had.
He had surgery on his jaw with six pins.
He had treadmill pulled out of his list,
left Occiput,
and he had his left leg.
I think it was shot out and he had
chronic pain.
That's why he was on all these pain
medications.
He's off all of that now.
Wow.
Because you know,
vitamin D deficiency has been found to
be a cause for inflammation.
It also low vitamin D,
You have a very low pain threshold.
Increasing vitamin D improves that
testosterone changes how we perceive
pain.
I'm stabilizing the pregnenolone and all
those hormones in the brain changes how
we perceive life.
When you're depressed,
you perceive pain,
very little pain as big pain when you're
not depressed.
Oh,
okay.
Bump yourself,
get better.
Wow.
No.
When we were having this conversation at
lunch,
when we're talking about this,
you were bringing up stem cells and the,
the effect that stem cells are having
and stem cell injections on,
on people that have all sorts
of serious traumatic injuries,
is that with the brain as well?
Um,
have they figured out how to squirt that
shit into your dome in,
let's see,
19,
2012.
I went to Germany to Dusseldorf,
Germany to work for the doctors who was
taking autologous stem cells.
He take out of the patient's stem cells,
send them to Israel to get an augmented,
to increase the amount and get them back
in 48 hours.
And then this absolutely incredible
three dimensional positioning needle
that use three dimension,
three axis,
these x,
y,
and Z.
and was able to go.
We drilled a hole in the skull and we
put a needle in directly into the fourth
ventricle,
which is that fluid compartment in the
brain and injected the stem cells and
it's spread out to the brain to the
brain stem,
because this gentleman had a brainstem
hemorrhage,
and within 48 hours to 72 hours,
he started having these improvements,
hearing improved physical functioning.
He was in a wheelchair with a belt to
hold them in place.
Three days later,
he's not using a belt for 12 years since
he had his stroke.
He wasn't able to pick up a coffee cup,
a coffee Mug,
and hold it.
He can only use a straw.
He was picking up his Coffee Cup and
drinking it.
So there,
there are places around the planet that
are using stem cells and people with
Alzheimer's,
with als,
with traumatic brain injury.
And it's getting benefits.
There are benefits in my projects in
Beijing,
China,
the stem cells called Mesenchymal stem
cells,
which are the ones that loved the organs
come from,
uh,
in diabetics injecting one injection of
10 million mesenchymal cells into the
patient through an IV,
30 percent of them lost their diabetes,
a 45 percent and had a decrease in their
insulin requirement and 25 percent of
them didn't have any effect.
And this is a center with 26 md phds in
Beijing that tops in their field.
So there's a lot of hope in that as
well.
Correct.
That seems like something that would,
if you're injecting it directly into the
traumatic,
the area has experienced trauma.
Yeah.
There's a,
uh,
orthopedic,
a buddy of mine,
a sentinel sentinel who's,
um,
was using autologous stem cells that he
pulled out a patient and injected into
the knees and get rebuild of the knees
without needing surgery.
What I'm hearing too is about rebuilding
cartloads that people have had bone on
bone cartilage.
They're rebuilding it.
Correct.
There are a couple of protocols.
There was one by a Dr Allen are done out
of Miami orthopedic surgeon who showed
that if you go in with the arthroscopic
scope and you use a bird,
which is like a,
a sandpaper device and you rubbed the
bone and then injected with growth
hormone that he was able to get five to
millimeters of regeneration of cartilage
in our office.
We use prolific,
huge significant,
and he did a Harvard study that is
publication Kane at Harvard.
He patented the toe thick,
10 millimeters.
That's incredible.
Not Ten centimeters.
Ten millimeter.
Twenty $5 a.
that's a pad.
Yeah.
It's a nice thickness that developed.
So um,
but no one's doing that because it's
illegal to use growth hormone in that
fashion.
A growth hormone has a very restricted
use parameters on it.
Why is that?
Because like baseball players and shit.
Well,
I think that had a lot to do with it.
Public Impressions of it.
This stuff works.
It works phenomenally well.
That's so frustrating to me when
something that's really,
really effective gets illegal because
athletes are using it and becoming more
effective.
It's just,
it's so silly.
It's a complete misconception.
It's ludicrous.
If the goal is,
if the true altruistic goal in medicine
is to fix people,
then why are we being restricted in
using the things that we see fixing
people?
Well,
the stem cell stuff was everybody was
always worried that people were going to
get it from fetuses and then somehow
it's going to encourage abortions until
they figured out how to get it from
other means and once they figured out
how to like get it from.
And then now that,
that debates off the table,
but for the longest time that was the
big issue.
Like during the Bush administration.
Yeah.
They held back stem cell research
because of the right wing Christians.
Right.
I think there's one cell,
single cell,
single cell.
Yeah.
Uh,
I think it's what,
10 years that they put the moratorium on
doing any research in stem cells,
which is giving Switzerland is giving
China,
is giving Russia,
you know,
massive advantage to be,
to be diagnosed clinically as dead,
you have to be brain dead.
So if there's not even a brain in there,
how,
how can you say that?
Taking a single cell,
I mean picking your nose is going to
kill more single cells then doing that
for stem cell research,
but the reaper cut real quick killing
your single cells.
But the repercussion of that could be a
game changer across the for everything.
Yeah.
I,
you know,
I used to think of stem cells as well.
That's kind of interesting.
Uh,
some future therapy that's going to be
cool until I got a shot into my shoulder
and I'm like,
holy fuck.
Like this is nuts.
Like this shoulder is bothering me for a
year.
Not Bothering me at all anymore.
How quick turnaround is that?
A couple of weeks.
Within a couple of weeks I started
feeling great.
Now it's two months out.
Now it's been two months out.
I don't have any pain.
PRP or stem cells,
stem cells where they get the stem,
placenta,
they have a technique which is prp,
which is platelet rich plasma,
which is similar to.
Right.
It gets a of cope.
Well,
it's similar to a Regena cane,
right?
Except that they don't,
they don't.
Regeneca is that stuff that Dr Peter
Welling figured out in Germany,
that's the blood spinning procedure that
heat up the blood,
like a more advanced version of platelet
rich plasma and what they do and I think
it Australia,
they expose it to a specials frequency
of ultraviolet light to take care of any
of the inflammatory chemistry that's in
there through a photo of the activation
and the PRP works very well seen as
something that's more acceptable than
doing autologous stem cell,
which there's a number of ways to do it
though,
is the point.
There's a number of different ways to
get stem cells.
Yeah,
well a lot of UFC fighters getting it
now and what they're doing,
a good percentage of them or they get
their fat sucked out of their body out
opposed.
They're turning that into stem cells.
Then shooting into their knees and their
shoulders and what have you,
and having incredible results.
A lot of MMA fight.
A lot of grapplers are doing it.
I need to get that done.
Yeah,
dude,
I'm telling you man,
I,
I mean I don't know if mine's an
isolated incident,
but I'm,
I'm just so blown away.
I was on the verge of surgery.
I was thinking,
okay,
I'll be out for three months.
We'll be in a sling for eight weeks.
Baba,
I was going over my head how much
downtime,
what can I do during that downtime?
And I was,
I was preparing to have a useless
shoulder.
Now all of a sudden I'm doing
everything.
I mean with zero pain,
it's just,
it.
Some weird noise is still,
it's kind of right,
but there's no pain and no limit,
no restriction in movement.
Like there's no it doesn't,
there's no impingements no,
no.
Jerking off is no problem.
I have a.
yeah,
that's crazy.
Mark.
I have a non union,
my left Fibula,
so it's,
it's broken and I would love to do that.
Non Union and your fibula.
Fibula is a small bowl or non white non
weight bearing bone in two.
I have a metal,
a titanium plate and it got broken to
pieces on my first deployment and I just
never had it fixed.
So the plates broken to place broken and
uh,
so I've been,
they've wanted to fix it but they're
like nine month rehab and I was like,
no way.
Nine months.
Yeah,
yeah,
absolutely.
It doesn't work now.
Right,
right.
So they would take the titanium plate
out a re a graph.
It had the graph,
the graph it take stuff for my hip
apparently.
And I was just like,
it's not worth it.
I'm just going to keep on,
keep on keeping on.
But uh,
and then I knew I found out about stem
cells and I'm,
I'm just gonna wait till I can do that.
We'll be back next week.
And can the stem cells fix that?
They can help with the bones that are
non.
If they're close enough help with
nonunion fusion.
Helped with fusion.
Well,
yeah,
it could help regenerate.
And then the speed up,
the,
the therapy time,
the turnaround time for your.
Well again,
you know.
Right.
So if it's,
know if it's nine months now,
maybe it's three months.
It's just so frustrating when you hear
about how much time they spent
banning stem cell research because of
the new research that they're doing now
and regenerating things.
I mean,
they,
they've just,
they've sequenced the gene of the
flatworm and they think they're going to
be able to figure out within x amount of
years how to regenerate limbs.
Like,
what the fuck,
man,
we're,
we're getting into some really crazy
area with state of science and medicine.
So what do we do?
We stop using all the technology that
can help people today waiting for the
technology decade
from now on.
That's even sillier.
Definitely.
That's what's happened.
It's so fast.
No reasons being applied this problem.
Yeah.
Well,
it seems to me that,
that,
that stem cells would be a really good
one for people with traumatic brain
injury.
I mean,
when you think about that,
no,
I think stem cells is a good option.
Um,
you know,
but what is it that you're looking at?
You look at someone who has had a loss
of a segment of their brain,
you want to try and regenerate it.
Um,
we know that possible.
Well,
we know from studies that were done back
in 1911,
uh,
there was a Dr Kegel.
Nineteen,
28 is a doc up in mcgill university,
a guru,
a total girl who's does regenerative
research.
The only reason why nerves can
regenerate is because they're in a non
permissive environment is what I call it
lecture.
I give on this specific topic,
is that there are so many chemicals in
the brain that are trying to foster
regeneration of nerves.
Like for instance,
usually I just doing a study on a
byproduct of progesterone called Aloe
pregnenolone,
which is neuro regenerative,
a snapped agentic,
which means that the connection from one
nerve to another nerve is a synapse.
If it's damaged,
it can regenerate.
It also pray.
Allopregnanolone is a free radical
scavenger.
As we age,
as our biochemistry changes in the
energy production in our brain,
through mitochondria changes,
a lot more of oxidation occurs or free
radicals,
and that's called oxidative stress and
it's believed,
especially in great articles by a
gentleman at USC,
a caliphate.
Finch talks about aging of the brain and
loss of our functioning due to this
oxidative stress,
and he believes that oxidative stress
leads to hormone deficiency,
leads to physical deficiency and death
and recent group of articles showed,
uh,
we're seeing a lot of a type of diabetes
called insulin resistant diabetes.
Were you making too much insulin because
it's not being recognized by the cells.
So they found in these group of articles
came out that if there's inflammation of
an area of the brain called the
hypothalamus,
which regulates our energy use,
that it can predispose you to developing
this situation called insulin resistant
diabetes or the Metabolic Syndrome.
So we've been tracking our patient
population who have had significant head
trauma,
whether or not it's blast with physical
injury or blunt head injury.
Someone who fell off a second story and
hit their head was unconscious for a
month.
Uh,
they're developed,
they've developed or they came into the
office already with this insulin
resistance and it's easy to fix,
correct their hormones given chromate
and monitor them.
What's chromium?
Chromium is a mineral metal which is
important for insulin recognition at the
cell wall.
And it was called by c Everett Koop,
the,
um,
the insulin tolerant factor back in the
late nineties.
So this chromium hooked up to a nice and
called chromium poly.
Nakota donated.
The trade name is called chromate.
I,
we use it for our patients with type two
diabetes called insulin resistance.
And they all reverse.
They all get better,
their blood sugar stabilized,
the fats get better and their insulin
comes down.
So we had,
in fact one of our neighbors had an
insulin level,
a hundred 17.
It should be less than 25 once we
correct it,
is two stops.
Drone and his chromium,
his levels dropped down below 30,
which is where you'd like to have it.
You know,
I was listening to this radio lab
podcast recently and they were talking
about lithium.
There was a woman who takes lithium
because she's a,
I guess it's bipolar and uh,
I didn't know lithium is just a salt
lithium chloride sodium.
Yeah.
It's just an element.
And coordinate takes this and she's fun.
Yeah.
I haven't looked at it,
but there are people,
you can buy it over the counter now,
but very low.
Yeah,
lithium,
you can buy over the counter ended.
I haven't.
For what?
That's what I need to go learn lithium.
Yeah,
because it seems like for me,
ignorantly when I heard that,
I was like,
well,
I thought lithium was some hardcore
Prozac type drug that they put people on
when they're out of their fucking mind.
I didn't think it was just a salt,
so it's metal or was it beneficial Dr
Gordon or cannot be used for official.
Starting to what started it was I would
see patients coming in with bipolar and
being on lithium and then started seeing
patients who are coming in on it,
you know,
just taking it as because of articles
and life extension magazine or one of
those other science based journals or
magazines.
But I haven't had a chance to go and
look at it closely,
but it's very impressive.
It's the metals,
you know,
it's like a magnesium works on one of
the brain receptors that if you take
magnesium,
it'll make you calm.
Magnesium metal,
you're talking about a solid magnesium
carbonate magnesium.
Zinc makes your testosterone goes up,
right?
Correct.
Zincs involved in 300 processes in the
body,
it's anti viral and anti cancer and it's
anti Alzheimer's and 300 processes in
the body.
One of them is a natural Roman tastes
inhibitor,
so I've never used the idexx in my
practice or an astros salt in my
practice.
What does that mean?
Aromatase inhibitor,
aromatase swelled.
Testosterone converts to Estradiol
naturally and it's the body adapts to
what we do to it.
If you give an overwhelming amount of
testosterone to the body,
the body says,
oh,
now what am I going to do with this?
So it will either send it down to
estrogen,
Estradiol,
or it'll send it to another thing called
dihydrotestosterone.
Estrodial obviously get man boobs.
She got crying,
whipping and so forth.
And dht causes hair loss,
causes testicles to show how you looked
at my head when you said that.
Well,
saddleback back.
So,
um,
there are side effects.
So,
um,
in,
in replenishing testosterone,
you have to be careful with the balance
you use.
Otherwise you start throwing things in
like an astro which blocks Esta dial,
which is extremely important for
generating growth hormone in the brain,
helping blood flow and keeping the
immune system unique to the brain
functional.
So you know,
everything we do,
there's always a risk to benefit factor
that needs to be looked at.
And I think that some of the risk
factors are being ignored.
This woman in this,
uh,
this radiolab podcast,
he was having an issue with kidney
failure and they were going to make her
get off of the lithium.
The lithium has a negative publicity,
well,
it has toxicity and it's dose dependent
toxicity.
And then the uniqueness of the person's
biochemistry,
you can make a very low amount toxic for
you or another person and it's
meaningless
to silver.
This woman who was this massive conflict
because this,
this stuff was saving her when she had
allowed her to be herself and now all of
a sudden they were telling her,
you're going to have to get off of it.
And she had been off of it before and
just lost her marbles,
saving her and killing her at the same
time.
Yeah.
It's crazy.
It's A.
is there another way that people can
avoid that?
Is there,
is,
there is another way that it could have.
They could avoid the effects of being
bipolar,
exercise,
diet,
anything.
Well,
do you want to say anything about that
Andrew?
Um,
we,
we think that you can treat that by
treating a neuroactive steroids in the
brain.
And,
uh,
it's,
it's been shown that it's been backed up
by evidence and proof and his clinical
application as well.
But that's very much the case.
So how does that work?
I'm testosterone is a generally
perceived as being a sex hormone or
being a reproductive hormone.
What we're finding is that it's involved
in an incredible array of different
processes in the body,
uh,
studies on the emotional center of the
brain.
The limbic system found that it helps to
stabilize a panic and also anger and
aggression in reactiveness to our
environment.
If it's slow,
you're hyper reactive.
They're finding that in a Anorexia
Nervosa,
uh,
women who are starving themselves,
who do have a psychological issues to
it,
if they don't respond to treatment,
giving them testosterone improves it.
So what we're starting to see is these,
a neuro steroids and neuroactive
steroids have influence on an array of,
um,
psychological or mood disorders and one
of them is in bipolar in the case that
we're just touching on,
um,
gentleman who was diagnosed with bipolar
by the military and was put onto lithium
and also add at the same time.
So,
and then what happened was he was given
a challenge test with a low dose of
testosterone and within 32 hours or so,
Dana has symptoms disappeared.
That's incredible.
The,
the,
the combination of things working
together synergistically.
It was one of the most incredible parts
of it.
Correct it.
And this is something that,
it just seems that a lot of people just
simply not aware of.
Correct.
The analogy that I use is,
you know,
brand new corvettes,
absolutely bitch and cars,
and it's like having a corvette with
four flat tires.
Now all we're going to do is going to
fill up one of the tires with air and
you're going to try and drive the car.
You're not going to be able to drive the
car.
Let's fill up the front two tires and
drive.
Okay,
let's go and fill up three and a half
tires and you going to drive.
It's not going to happen.
The synergy is in all the hormones that
we have in our body,
all the chemistry together to give us a
level of benefit of function that one by
itself cannot do,
and if you look at the failure reports
that are in traumatic brain injuries
since 1959,
it's called a futility failure where
these big pharmaceutical companies took
these great drugs and gave one product
to an individual which Madec brain
injury and they didn't get any benefit
greater than 10 percent.
That's called failure or futility
failure,
and it's because in other people are
writing the because is because our
system is so complex.
How do you expect one product to fix it?
It can't
and everything's got to be balanced.
It's all got to be balanced.
There's such an issue in this country
when it comes to mental health that
mental health doesn't get looked at like
the health of a bone or the health of a
muscle.
You know,
if you have a torn muscle,
you have to get an emergency operation
to reattach it.
Right.
But if your brain is fucked,
it's like,
come on,
don't be a pussy.
Yeah.
You know,
toughen up or,
you know,
stop.
Stop being so down on yourself.
We're this.
We're the sum of our chemistry.
I mean that,
that,
that's the deal.
When that's affected,
that's when you have these,
uh,
these different things that manifest
why we're seeing so many of the vets
coming back and committing suicide
because they've been instilled with
exactly what you say.
Don't be a pussy,
you know,
man up and do it.
That's what.
Yeah,
it was then.
And that's why it was easy for me to
say,
well,
I can speak to my credibility that
that's not the case.
So let's find,
let's find some damn answer,
right?
Because we're flying,
falling off the crazy train.
Right,
right,
right.
Yeah.
For a guy like you,
that's where it's so clear.
It's like,
you know,
you're not a pussy,
so what the hell's going on?
For example,
that have self doubt.
It's like,
well maybe they're right and maybe with
that psychologist says is right,
maybe I should take this medication and
now that's compounding a problem and
making it even bigger and that's why
we're having these suicides.
And also,
you know,
one of the things that's been
fascinating to me over the last couple
of years is finding out all the
different things that we do that change
a hormone levels of our body.
Like all the different things you could
do during the day that up your
testosterone,
including like just drop what they
called peacocking driving a nice car
around a bunch of young ladies actually
rises,
raises your testosterone like,
ah,
what the fuck is going on with our
bodies?
Like weird.
Is it
that there's like moods,
the changing and mood,
like happy moments?
Correct.
Like literally will change the chemical
evolution,
makeup
evolution of man,
you know what I mean?
And that was a natural selection that
when women were around,
I was gonna you know,
you're going to perk up and down,
got to get ready to party when a woman
opulate said they,
you know,
14,
15,
16,
there's a spike in testosterone.
So she's oblating.
She has a spike in her testosterone.
What does she want to do?
Get Our party on,
get up,
party on.
She wants to get that fertilization,
dance,
going to dance.
That's happened.
That happens also to a lot of women that
get older when they put them on hormone
replacement,
once they experience menopause,
they,
they have more testosterone.
They get hornier correct.
If you just follow,
I'm aging,
uh,
men and women as men who had
testosterone based age,
they lose their testosterone and they
have more estrogen.
That's why we become clear stages as we
get older.
Women on the other hand lose their
estrogen and gain more testosterone.
That's why you start seeing facial hair
and they start taking the command
position in the relationship as they get
older.
And it's this flipping of the,
the hormones.
Hey Doctor Gordon,
I wanted to touch on the a and Joe,
you asked about the,
uh,
able to regrow anything in the brain.
It's called neuroplasticity,
you know,
right.
Doctor Gordon,
and I wanted to dumb it down for the
listeners are guys that maybe are like
me that are listening,
so are,
are we able to fix our brains?
And Science has said yes.
And I found this out before I met Dr
Gordon and I was hearing about some of
these things and treatments I was at
about neuroplasticity and basically
being able to regenerate the neuronal
pathways.
Okay,
so we have shearing a shearing of the
neurons and a traumatic brain injury
and,
and that's causing some of the issues
that we have,
but when,
what we now know is we can form new
neuronal pathways in the brain and we
can stimulate stimulate that through a
number of ways.
Learning something that you've never
learned will stimulate that.
I'm treating it with what you're
deficient in,
new oral steroids steroid wise.
We'll fix that.
So we thought like,
can't you,
can you treat a.
can you teach a old dog new tricks?
We thought the answer was no,
but now we know that that's not correct.
We can regenerate neuronal pathways in
the brain.
Anybody can do it,
and you can keep yourself.
You can continue to get sharper as your
age through these treatments.
I think people get sharper to when they
try new things.
Absolutely.
That's part of the.
That's part of the science behind.
Okay,
well that,
that builds new neural pathways and we
didn't think that that was possible.
I don't know how long we just figured
that out,
but when I heard that two years ago and
people were telling me,
hey,
this is the new.
You just accept it.
And I was like,
well this is the last class.
I was not told me about neuroplasticity.
So which one is it can regenerate and
renew or you can't.
I think it was Fort Collins and a doctor
twilley twilley who was doing just that.
Introducing two vets who had traumatic
brain injury,
would nintendo with certain types of
gains to get the visual manual dexterity
which would help to improve their
cognitive ability because of doing just
that,
using learning something new.
Uh,
what's that thing called?
[inaudible].
So Dakota.
Yeah,
so do Duke,
which,
uh,
forces you to do a intense thinking
which can help build a new pathways in
literature that I used to read in
Alzheimer's.
I have a lecture on it.
There's,
um,
they found that if you looked at the
academic,
uh,
the academic experience of an individual
when they get Alzheimer's,
the people have the highest academic
achievements,
meaning mds,
phds,
and so forth compared to people who just
have a high school diploma,
that those people with the higher
education have a slower progression of
Alzheimer's disease.
And that's because they've built
parallel pathways,
a lot of pathways.
So if you lose this pathway,
you've got this one is an alternative
backdoor,
backdoor backup side of the door.
Yeah.
So,
you know,
well,
it also makes sense in relation to
exercise.
The more exercise that when people don't
actually.
Absolutely.
They experience atrophy,
right?
When you know,
when your,
your,
your life has exact same path every day,
the exact same stimuli.
Nothing varies when that,
when that happens,
it's a very easy for your mind did just
atrophy your,
you're correct.
Your process.
You don't challenge yourself in life,
then you're going to atrophy in every
area so that that's the onus on the
individual.
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
That's also by people that are sort of
adrenaline junkies,
they,
they kind of ramp it up all the time.
More and more and more to the other
people around them.
Like,
you're fucking getting a little crazy
here,
buddy,
but it's because it,
it takes more for them to get that
juice.
Right.
They don't get it from the original.
Their baseline is pushed higher.
Yeah,
fine.
You know,
I have patients who get onto a program
and after for six months they say,
doc,
I don't feel the same as I did at the
beginning.
I said,
well,
at the beginning you were at zero,
now you're at 100.
We're at the top.
What more?
You've already had that contrast from
zero to 100 and the analogy I use is,
you know,
it's 100 degrees outside and you've got
to pull the.
It's 86 degrees when you jump into the
pool,
it's initially cold and then your body
adapts and you don't feel that
temperature difference.
Is the temperature any different?
No,
it's the same thing.
You've adapted.
So what happens is we adapt to not
feeling the contrast because there's no
contrast.
You're already at the top.
Does that make any sense?
Yeah,
totally makes sense.
Yeah.
So this is what people have to
understand and you know,
every week I get one or two patients,
you know,
call up and say,
doc,
I just don't feel as good as I did in
the beginning.
Have you changed?
Have you dropped in your functionality?
No.
In fact,
I'm going to be running a,
you know,
a marathon.
Well,
were you able to do that last time?
No,
I'm not.
Now I'm in the gym six days a week
instead of once a week or once a month.
I said,
your entire lifestyle is updated,
but you're not feeling as good and I
just can't get a full understanding.
Their level of function is up here,
but they are telling me that they're not
doing as well.
And is it just because they're just,
they're used to it?
Is that what it is?
It's a massive improvement.
They had in the beginning it was like
this new state.
It's almost like getting water in your
ear and it.
Yeah.
And then the water comes out.
It's a contrast.
Hormones always give the body a contrast
beef between low level and that higher
level,
not excessive but higher level.
And you adapt to it and you think it's.
You know what happens with heroin
addicts,
it's a bad example,
but the same thing,
they get what's called techie flax.
They don't feel the same.
Hi,
everybody chases that first high and
you're never going to have that first
high because that was the first time
that you just whacked all your neurons
in your brain with this new drug.
Heroin or chasing the Dragon,
chasing the dragon.
Correct.
But it makes sense.
I mean,
when something is unique in the,
in the beginning and special and
fantastic.
He gives you this.
But then when that's a normal thing,
right?
Then you go,
you know,
what worked for me in the beginning and
then it stopped working for them.
It hasn't changed and you'd show them
their blood levels,
like at a,
um,
in fact it was a,
I think it was Jordan who,
uh,
was very,
very low in testosterone.
I think it was like a two when it should
be a 14 and his total was like two,
uh,
220 and should be about 700 and he
complains that he's not feeling as well.
We did his blood work and his free
testosterone was like 14,
13 point nine,
nine in total was 801,
so it was like four times above where he
was before.
And he's saying he doesn't feel any
better.
That's crazy.
So he just got used to this elevated
state.
He's at functioning at a higher level,
you know,
I've been on treat happens.
The rich people too,
right?
Is that right?
Yeah,
that's what they say.
Using a ball,
you,
uh,
you start to crave different things,
right?
And,
but the problem with that is we lose
focus and the clarity of the present
moment.
That's the problem,
man.
I crave a different emotion when you
need to be experiencing the most that
you're having right now.
Living,
living in that part of it.
The problem of being a fucking person is
because we're always striving for the
new thing.
We're always striving for improvement.
We always want a better time at our run.
We always want a better this better
that.
The newest car,
the fucking uptight to the house,
all that shit when we're constantly,
when no one has ever like,
hey,
that's pretty good.
Yeah.
I think that apathy,
I think it's chasing certain emotions
and trying to run away from other ones
when,
when there's,
there's opportunity for growth and
development and ultimately contribution
and all of them and they're all,
they all can produce that.
If you're able to instead of run from
it,
maybe look at it and see what that can
provide you and what can,
what can you do that to provide that to
somebody else.
Yeah.
It makes sense.
Totally makes sense.
It just seems to me that,
um,
the way you approach life and the
philosophy that you have,
that you take through life can either
they can even contribute
or take away from your happiness and
that it's,
it's not,
it's all these things.
It's not just the hormonal balance,
it's not just the health of the physical
body,
but it's also the approach that you have
to live,
the way you look at things can sort of
affect and,
and,
and balance all that stuff out in a way.
Meaning that you need everything.
You need the big
picture.
Absolutely.
I think if you wrap your happiness
around passion or our pleasure,
those are,
those are fleeting.
You know what I mean?
So if you could been instead wrapping
around purpose or meaning,
then you're going to be a longterm
happy,
uh,
but pleasure,
passion,
things like that,
that,
that short term people chasing pleasure,
man.
And that,
that doesn't make you happy in the end.
No.
You know,
my friend Steve Reno has a really funny
way of.
He talks about things that are really
fun when you're doing them.
And then things are that are really fun
after they're done,
he's like,
some things are really fun while you're
doing them,
but after they're done,
they don't give you any.
Like a rollercoaster rollercoaster
doesn't give you anything after it's
over.
But like there's some miserable trips
that you go on.
Well afterwards,
just spend hours and hours laugh with
your friends.
Like,
dude,
that sucks so hard.
Absolutely.
He'd be laughing about how fucking cold
you were and you're camping and you're
freezing your dick off.
We want to blow my nose.
But you know,
remembering a perceived negative time
and putting a positive light on it.
You know what I mean?
Absolutely.
It's also understanding that a lot of
like what is good is very difficult to
do and it becomes like your goal setting
and then achieving those goals becomes
this,
this feeling of of pleasure and a good
thing.
Whereas opposed to so many people just
want comfort and quiet and peace,
but with none of the hard work and that
you don't appreciate it then absolutely.
You like a spoiled child,
like spoiled kids don't appreciate what
they have in their life.
Somebody works really hard and you know
they've gone through hard times.
Then when things turned well,
they're like,
God,
this is so good to not have to worry
about money now,
to not have to worry about where my next
meal's coming from,
to have a nice home and a nice bed to
sleep in.
Yeah.
If you look at the Richard Bransons and
the job's and so forth that came from
nothing and they built something.
They worked.
They were hungry and develop something
or had a world that was fulfilled.
Everything that they could think of a
they had the desire to achieve that goal
as opposed to people who are given
everything on a silver platter.
They don't have aspirations.
They don't have the drive.
I think you achieved that goal.
That is kind of pleasure.
You're talking about Joe,
but like the we look back and look at
the journey that it took from where you
started to get to that goal.
That's where you can feel purposeful and
proud of proud of it.
That last longer than the feeling of
accomplishing that goal.
The journey.
Yeah.
It's what a weird world we live in,
isn't it,
you know,
trying to manage all this stuff and
trying to figure out what,
what's the most,
what's the optimum way to get through
life,
what's the best way to approach it,
how much emphasis to put
on the mind,
how much emphasis to put on the body,
the relationships that you have with the
people in your life greatly affect how,
how you feel about life in the people in
your life could,
they,
can affect your hormone levels.
They can affect your,
your cortisol levels.
They can affect all those things.
He has his daughter having a,
you know,
someone said that I talk a lot and I
tell them that because of having four
women in home,
three daughters and a wife,
that the uh,
Opportunity that I have to speak is
always outside because inside the house,
you know,
he just listened.
I just listened.
Just trying to sort out these aliens
that you live with and other especially
matched you.
I got three daughters.
I have two on the same package.
Yeah.
I also got two boys,
so commiserate later.
Full House.
You got chaos.
That's how we live,
like I said,
in feces,
urine and nonstop,
but as they get older,
they mature into this delight as my
daughter over there and the other two
daughters that are in here.
Just a delight and that journey you were
talking about and the effect of the
environment on your psychological
wellbeing.
You know,
it's a.
it's a rollercoaster that I've gone
through a rollercoaster with each one of
the daughters and I've come to that
landing.
You know,
where you get off the rollercoaster
finally at this age and you look back
and you start laughing on some of the
silly things that happened and my
daughter came to me a couple of weeks
ago and basically said,
yeah,
we went through some silly time.
Let's have some great time.
And it was one of the most revelator ing
kind of nights I could have had.
It was the best night and going out and
having a good,
you know,
40 year old scotch or something.
But you owe me that.
This,
this last year,
I read a Victor Frankel's man's search
for meaning and it just changed my
outlook on everything and he went
through the Holocaust and that basically
the book was the premise of some people
survived the Holocaust and they like the
Holocaust.
That's the text,
that's a text and then me Holocaust.
Some people survived,
right,
and we're able able to to have meaning
while others just gave up and died and
what was.
What was the reasoning behind that?
Was kind of how the book looked at it
and it was the people who survived that
nine percent was the commonality was
his.
Everybody had some kind of a meaning,
right?
Some somebody has some kind of purpose
outside of themselves that was wrapped
in a how they could better,
better somebody else's life in some form
or fashion and that purpose,
that meaning to their life allow them to
be able to endure whatever came their
way because they had a purpose to endure
it.
The person that didn't have a meaning a
put on their life for whatever reason,
just at the end,
that was too much.
They just gave in and said,
I give up and eventually died and that
was the difference.
You know what I mean?
And we can replicate that in our own
life.
I mean you can wrap your life around
meaning and purpose and
tie that to how you can contribute to,
to put value into somebody else's life.
I found that puts value into you.
You know what I mean?
So I think the,
you know,
the purpose of life is to live a life of
purpose.
That's a very good way of putting it and
it makes you feel better about your life
too.
And like cynical people will say,
well,
there is no purpose in the end.
You know,
you're going to take a dirt nap and
that's all the time that you have here
is just bullshit.
But the reality is that bullshit is way
better when you believe that you have a
purpose and when you live for a purpose
and when you work hard and you achieve
things like goal setting,
they say that one of the most important
things for people to achieve happiness
is this setting and achieving of goals.
It's setting and achieving of goals,
whether it's simple like completing a
project,
I want to start a garden in my yard,
you know,
and you want to put up posts and grow
plants and then when you eat a salad
from those plants you go,
I fucking did it.
Like you get a feeling,
a natural feeling of accomplishment from
an art project,
from anything you want to do,
fixing the shed,
what,
whatever it is.
Like when you set a goal and you do your
best and you achieve.
That's part of what made human beings
what we are today in 2015.
Those,
those natural reward systems are in our
DNA.
And if you follow those and you live by
those,
you will have a more fulfilled life,
a happier life.
I agree.
And it's,
it's a fulfillment.
It's a joy that you get that you don't
have need anybody else to say to you,
good job [inaudible] because it's self
generated.
It's your own self reward as opposed to
people's search for other ones.
Someone else to tap them on the back.
You know,
people come up to me and you know,
I'm very sensitive about the fact that
people say,
what a great job I'm doing whatever I'm
doing,
I know I'm doing a good job because
that's my purpose.
That's my purpose.
I don't need to have someone to tell me
to,
you know,
I've been doing a good job.
You're not a slack.
Like if you weren't doing your best,
you'd be,
you'd be going against yourself.
Right?
So you don't need anybody very
hypercritical about myself because you
know,
you look around the planet,
how many people are putting in effort
for helping other people?
I mean really truly helping without
helping them.
Not that I do 100 percent because I'm
selfish.
I need to have my couch in my car and
whatever else.
Trying to improve wellbeing,
improved wellbeing across the board.
Yeah.
There's really no good manual on how to
live life.
And even if there was,
it might not apply to you,
you know?
I mean,
nobody can tell you what's going to make
one person happy.
It's not necessarily gonna make another
person happy.
You know,
we're,
we're here talking about goal setting
and working hard and trying for some
people,
that's actually not it for some,
for some people,
what do they want to do?
They just want to have a good group of
friends and be around them and have nice
meals and good conversations and that's
it.
They literally don't have a desire for
these other things.
But for people like you that have this
burning desire to know things and
improve upon things and to do good work
for,
that's
your path.
That's it.
I think some people just get so wrapped
up in the day to day rat race of life
that they don't put the pick their head
up and say,
man,
I,
I'm totally missing the boat.
And there,
there is no meaning.
There is no purpose to how I'm doing
anything.
I would think people really thought
about it.
They might not be do what I,
you know,
Joe Rogan Westview or Mark Gordon wants
to do,
but they're,
they're going to like,
hey,
I want to do something.
If it's not just tied around,
totally doing,
you know,
I just want to hang out and not give
anything out to anybody.
You're not gonna get anything in return.
I don't think anybody wants to do that
and in their right mind,
you know,
it's so hard for people to find out what
it is that they want to do and then how
do I go about pursuing that and how do I
go about pursuing that while avoiding
the idea of choosing just a job that's
going to give you security,
you know,
a job that you don't want to do,
but hey,
you know it's going to give me dental
there.
That's a.
that's a big factor in a lot of people's
lives.
The non pursuing of dreams that somehow
and you to go streams or danger,
you got to go after it with your,
with no fear of failure.
If that didn't,
don't even let failure enter into the
equation.
What would you do if you knew you
couldn't fail at it?
That's what I would tell people to do.
That's what I tell my kids.
Whatever you're passionate about,
that's where you need to start.
You know what I mean?
That's where you need to go and get
dental.
You're going to have failure.
But failure is important for growth and
learning.
Uh,
you know,
I have it all the time.
It's,
it's,
it's good.
It's like a vitamin.
You gotta take it,
fill fuel yourself with the fuck up.
So that's what I always say,
talking about failure.
One of the stories I keep on repeating
and using as a goal for myself is it was
a reporter that interviewed Thomas
Jefferson,
Thomas Jefferson,
Thomas Edison,
before he passed away.
And he said to him,
you know,
Mr Edison and your development of the
incandescent bulb was what revolution I
took us from the stone ages to modern
living and you know,
but how do you feel about these over
1,108
failures that they said that you had
with the bulbs?
And Thomas Edison says,
well,
sunny,
I don't look at them as being failures,
justice,
things that didn't work.
And it's by having that attitude of
looking at what we do in our daily life
is not failures.
Meaning that you're worthless and you're
incapable and therefore you should stop
what you're doing,
but look at it.
It's just something that didn't work.
Find another pathway.
The data.
Great.
Thomas Edison impression,
by the way,
you very much is a southern.
When did he become from Alabama?
Where was he called?
The Ohio.
Well,
not only that,
he ripped off Tesla,
me know.
That was really how he got ahead.
That guy was just.
He hated the alternate current lecture,
shooting fucking elephants and shit.
DC.
Remember that?
He liked you,
but that Alpha is all about direct.
Current.
Yeah.
He fucked up.
That was a dumb ass.
It was just lucky.
There was a super genius around that he
could steal from.
Well,
I'm sure he was smart.
Yeah,
don't get me wrong,
but we kind of helped.
Helped being around Tesla.
I mean that's that Michael Jordan
commercial,
you know,
like about how many times you've failed,
failed over and over and over again,
and that's why it's succeeded.
Like he said,
man,
it makes that,
that spurs growth.
You know,
you have to be able to fail.
I look at it as data,
you know what I mean?
That just,
that gives me readings about where I was
and how I need to self correct the
course I'm at.
Without it,
you can't get a good true measurement
and that feeling that you get from
failure is awesome.
It sucks at the time,
but it's like the like we were talking
about things that are fun while you're
doing them and then things that are
great years later,
when you fail at something,
that feeling that you have afterwards,
it's fucking horrible,
but that feeling will fuel you.
That feeling will get you to avoid that,
so that's what it's there for,
but you got to rearrange the way you
look at it.
People look at it like,
Oh,
I'm a failure.
You can't define yourself by mistakes.
You what you who you are is you are the
thinking thing.
You are the thing that can figure out
what the problem is,
how to,
how to form a solution.
You're not the results like you're not
the failures and that's what a lot of
people run into.
They define themselves by failures and
people try to define you by failures,
like how many times you run into someone
from higher.
Remember that time when you're in high
school,
you did this.
Not like,
Hey Dickhead,
that was 20 years ago.
You're still living there.
You know,
I learned from that and I moved past it.
That happens with a lot of people,
right?
That people will try to drag you into.
Like I had a friend of mine who,
uh,
he had to get up.
He had a breakup with this girl because
he was dating her.
When they would talk about things,
they would have a disagreement about
something that she did and she would
bring up something that happened like
fucking two years ago that had nothing
to do with it.
Like you did they give you.
And then you said that he was like,
it was too fucking years ago.
What do you,
what are you talking about?
Has No bearing on who we are right now?
None.
Zero.
She's not being rational.
You.
She was trying to define him by,
uh,
an argument that they had,
you know,
two years ago or whatever comments like,
you know what I mean when people are
doing that,
they're trying to define them based on a
failure as a team guy,
man,
anybody on the guy I want on my team is
a guy who's failed and failed and failed
and every time he got back up and he
said,
I don't,
I don't give a shit.
I'm going to keep going because I know
when,
when the bullets start flying and the
day gets tough,
we're going to keep moving.
Show me somebody who's never failed ours
one every time.
And as soon as they have a perceived
adversity or difficult situation,
they don't know how to act.
I don't want that guy on my team,
especially when it's life and death.
You know what?
That's a big issue with fighters.
Yeah,
with fighters,
that's a giant issue.
It's called being a front runner and
there's some guys that just,
they don't do well when they're the the
nail.
They're great when they're the hammer,
but when then all of a sudden they're
the nail.
They don't know what the fuck to do and
they fall apart.
There's certain guys that if they're
dominating a fight to the most
terrifying fighter in the world,
but the moment things start going the
way you start seeing cracks in their arm
or you start seeing mental weaknesses
and they fold and they perform at a
drastically reduced level with no
reason,
well the reason it's psychological,
all of a sudden they're confronting it.
Adversity.
They're confronted,
they don't know what to do,
and then when you see a fighter that's
able to cable,
able capable of being hurt and on the
brink of failure and then coming back
and winning a fight,
then you see a person with character and
then there's other people that they're
great when everything's going their way,
but the moment things aren't going their
way.
They just fucking pack up their bags and
go home.
That's what I love to watch is the guy
that those fights were.
The guy was down and he didn't.
He didn't stop pain.
You learn a lot about God.
You said Joe,
their character.
That's where he learned about somebody's
character is this kid that fights in the
UFC right now.
His name is Thomas Almeda is very,
very,
very highly hyped up fighter and he had
a real tough fight recently with this
guy named Brad picket.
Brad pickets,
a tough veterans.
Been around for a long time.
This kid I'll made has been beating
everybody up and then all of a sudden he
gets in this fight with his veteran and
he gets cracked.
His nose gets broken.
He gets rocked really hard,
came back the next round and knocked
out,
knocked pick it out.
It hit him with a flying knee and
knocked him out.
But the point being that this kid got
pushed to the brink,
never lost composure,
and then you go,
okay,
the hypes real this kids a real deal,
and you got to see that.
You've got to see that to know because
otherwise you don't know what happens
when they get in trouble.
Absolutely getting in trouble,
like being able to operate while under
that kind of intense pressure of being
in trouble is what makes champions,
hey,
how do you replicate that in the fight
world and and training for a guy to be
able to be in that situation to where,
hey,
this is what's going to feel like and
this is how you need to respond or can
you replicate that?
You almost can't.
I mean,
I think that that kind of mental
training,
it's,
it's so difficult to try to replicate
that.
There's certain drills you can do like
you do.
I'm a drill.
We take five fresh guys and you go in
and you spar one guy for one round and
then that guy goes out and you bring a
new fresh guy and you're tired.
That guys,
they,
they try to break you.
They try,
but there's also people that don't agree
with that because they think that that
kind of like experiencing failure like
that in the gym is actually a bad thing
because then you become comfortable with
failure and you understand it and some
people think that it's just an attribute
that's a psychological attribute.
Either you're in shape and you're
prepared and you're ready and when
adversity comes you're going to be able
to handle it or you're not.
You know,
it's,
it's really tough to put an answer to
that because it's really tough.
Like think about like buds training or
think about like how many people go
through that,
that kind of training and just get to
the point where everybody's
uncomfortable,
everybody's miserable,
but they get up and they quit and who
doesn't quit?
The people that don't quit at the people
that you're going to count on,
like why?
Why,
why this is their first time doing
because they made the decision
beforehand.
I can tell you they made the decision
beforehand like I don't care what
happens and how much it's going to suck.
In my mind.
I have now embraced it and I've told
myself that I'm an enjoy it and no
matter what,
I'm not quitting it.
I'll lose a leg before I quit,
but if you have even the slightest
inkling of this sucks,
I can't believe I have to do another 20
miles and hump 100 pounds.
Then you're thinking it's easy to step
off to the side over there and be done,
but if you have a mental mind frame and
you can train it,
if you had that mental mind frame of I
will not they they're,
they might not take me,
but it won't be because I didn't finish
this damn thing.
It won't be because I'm not physically
and mentally here doing everything
that's asked of me.
Well,
when you say you can train it,
they don't try to trade it in you though
before they prepare you?
No,
absolutely not.
They want the person who does it on
their own.
Innate.
I think it's the same with fighters.
Yeah,
I really do.
Either you have it or you don't.
Yeah,
and that's why similarly,
there's just a small percentage of
people that ever get through that kind
of training.
There's similarly a small percentage of
people that ever get to the elite level
of competition.
I think in any form,
in any sport,
in anything where you're trying to push
yourself,
anything that's difficult,
not really difficult.
Endeavor reveals character.
Yeah,
it's beautiful.
It's a beautiful process is,
it's amazing and it's amazing to see in
yourself and even,
you know,
the people that experience it would,
they quit even that can be a lesson,
you know,
you can learn from that lesson and
rebuild and,
and never,
never experienced that.
Again,
have a curiosity in your training.
What percentage of people actually
complete the training?
Um,
so through our initial special forces
assessment and selection,
only about 33 percent get through that.
Then you go through the training
pipeline,
which is anymore for about a year and a
half to two,
two and a half years.
And that's about 50 percent of the
people I think,
you know,
so you get 16 percent will get through.
It's,
yeah,
it's a very small percentage and that's
people that have the courage to join.
Right.
So you know,
you think about how many people were
willing to sign up.
I mean that's a small percentage to,
so a small percentage of a small
percentage of a small percentage.
Everybody wants to be a cool guy and
until things go wrong,
oh yeah,
man,
nobody wants to be anymore what it is
with the seals.
And so it's,
it's,
it's very similar.
Similar to it.
Yeah.
It's kind of be,
it's almost all very,
very small percentage.
So the question is if it's 16 percent in
that arena,
what is it in,
in,
in boxing,
MMA or fighting mma?
There's also,
there's a lot of physical gifts that
come into play.
Like we're talking about guys that quit,
there's guys that quit that are at the
elite level and they just,
they just don't run into anybody as good
as them.
And as long as they keep training,
they keep pushing ahead,
they'll,
they'll bulldoze and bum rush.
All these guys that are in there with
them.
But there's guys,
you know,
I don't want to mention names,
I don't wanna hurt anybody's feelings.
This guys have won world titles that are
quitters.
Yeah,
it's a fact.
They're just really good or they've been
cheating.
It's been a lot of steroid use epo,
a lot of different things.
But even then they have to fine tune
those skills.
I mean,
any anybody can do,
do those drugs and they can't hit a home
run or they can't put somebody in a rear
naked choke.
They're not entirely week.
See,
you know,
they might,
they might.
Like,
some people can run a marathon,
can run an ultra marathon.
Can you do 100 miles in 24 hours?
A lot of people can't,
but some people can.
So the people that run that ultra
marathon,
they'll look at other people that can't
run a marathon.
Or the people that run a regular
marathon will look at people that can't
run a marathon,
that will quit at Mile Sixteen or
whatever.
And they'll go,
wow,
you just fucking don't have the mental
toughness.
Maybe they don't have the mental
toughness to go 100 miles.
There's levels to everything in this
life and there's people that are at the
elite level of MMA that I know.
I know that if they get in a bad spot,
they're going to quit.
They're going to breaking point.
I can tell you that for a fact.
Every,
every,
every human has a breaking point,
so there's no.
There's no unbreakable dude walking
around today.
No.
Even though he my thanks.
So yeah,
a lot of people think so.
A lot of people think so without ever
being tested and I don't even think they
think it.
I think they're just saying it so that
they think that they can convince you
and maybe somehow know that will
convince themselves if you believe it.
Yeah.
Is it nurture?
Is it nature?
Is it just good question?
What they want to do?
Is it a psychological decision to do it
or is it their matrix of how they're put
together?
This is the limit of their capacity.
I had this puppy,
and this is obviously a dog,
another person,
but I had this dog.
His name was Frank Sinatra.
Craziest fucking dog I've ever had who's
nuts.
His mother was a wild boar hunting dog
from Hawaii.
His dog was fucking crazy.
He was crazy.
But uh,
when he was a puppy,
one of the reasons I realized he was
crazy.
He was a,
he would always like to play bite and
stuff.
He was really little.
It was only two months old.
I,
uh,
you know,
he would come up to me and bite my hands
and I'd push him away and he'd run up a
bite my hand again and I pushed him away
and I'm like,
how many fucking times can I do this?
I pushed him away 80 times before I got
tired of doing it.
I go,
one,
two,
three,
four.
I'm a fucking human.
Okay.
I'm a grown man and he's a baby dog and
I'm pushing him away from me and he
never got discouraged.
Not once at,
at number 80.
I'm like,
all right buddy,
bye my hand.
Let's just,
let's just call this a lot.
But like,
that was 100 percent nature,
not nurture and dog that I've taught
them to do is get pat and given dog
food,
give him kisses.
But in his hitting his makeup and
there's that question of epigenetics,
like what,
how much of your character do you get
from your parents?
Like just in your DNA,
how much can you mold on your own?
I mean,
I think there are.
There's an untold number of variables
and nature and nurture.
It's neither or it's all the above.
Absolutely environment.
There's so many different things that
are.
So,
you know,
you can't really,
put these people down for not being able
to succeed at the level that you've like
to.
You did with this super marathon or the
marathon reimbursement.
It does.
Like I do a five k and I'm wasted.
I'm not a runner or a swimmer.
But if you decided you were a runner and
then put in the work,
you would be a runner given any mean
whether your knees hold up or ankle
problems or all that jazz.
If you decided to,
you can do.
It's not outside the realm of
possibility.
It's not like you can't fly.
Well,
I can't fly either.
You know,
I don't have wings.
You know what I mean?
Like we're talking about nonphysical
limitations.
It's a simple thing like running,
not saying,
well,
you beat Usain bolt in a hundred yard
dash.
No you won't,
you know,
but we're talking about some simple
stuff,
making the commitment to do it and keep
it and just keep them commitment and you
have the physical and mental capacity
and then just whether you're going to be
committed and whether or not you're
going to embrace the suck.
I've been committed before.
That's the difference,
Joe,
instead of turning from whatever you're
doing,
embrace it,
man.
You have to truly embrace it.
Embrace the suck.
Then it's not something that you're
trying to get out of you.
You're trying to live in that moment
and,
and truly thrive in it.
And that's the difference.
But the elite performer and anomaly,
yeah,
I mean even like simple things like tell
yourself you're going to do an hour and
a half on an elliptical machine.
What seems real easy for five minutes
and then 10 minutes and you're like,
fuck,
I got an hour and 20 more minutes this
bullshit.
And then you know as you're going and
not reduce the level,
keep the level at the same.
And just force yourself to do it.
That's not easy to do,
but that ain't shit compared to an ultra
marathon.
So there's levels to everything.
And then how about these crazy fucks
that do like there's people that do to
ultra marathons in a row,
like they'll do an ultra marathon and
they'll do an ultra marathon back
because a regular ultra marathon is not
fucking crazy enough for these people
because they did want to find the edge.
What?
When's the edge?
Or I hit it.
Nope,
I think I can go further.
I think I'm building up more endurance.
I think I'm building the goal more
mental toughness.
I can go further.
Have you ever heard of Wynn Hoff?
I've heard that.
What does the iceman?
Yes.
That crazy.
That good.
Ran a marathon in the,
uh,
in the desert without drinking water.
Yeah.
He goes and does his crease craziest
immersions and,
and like freezing temperatures and he
can keep his core temperature without
changing.
He holds the world record like two
hours.
So he's saying that he's come up with a
method that he can teach you how to
change your physiology to be able to
adapt to these things.
And it's with breathing techniques,
um,
commitment and a cold water immersion.
Wim Hoff.
Fucking alien.
That guy,
Hey,
I did is uh,
I bought his thing the other day and me
and becky did the breathing thing.
Um,
my wife and the first day I did it,
I hold my breath for two minutes and 41
seconds.
My wife held it for two minutes and 30
seconds after,
after 15 minutes doing this breathing
stuff.
And you held it for five minutes before
we.
Because that guy is somebody who is a 41
second.
Yeah.
In short.
In short shorts and no shirt.
Yeah.
Summited everest.
It took 26 people up to Kilimanjaro.
Uh,
they submitted it and they all had a
cancers or ailments or whatever,
trained them for three months.
16 of them submitted.
They did it in 20,
36 hours and they did it in shorts.
You know what I mean?
His whole thing is I can train you to
take,
take over your and
your autonomic nervous system.
Well,
a guy like that seeing,
you know,
like people talk about mental training,
like cowboy cerrone on the other day and
uh,
I asked him if he's involved in,
you know,
he's talking about like Mindfox and
things that go wrong and fights.
I'm like,
have you ever done any mentor training
at all?
And he's like never fucked with any of
that stuff,
but I think you get a guy who was as
tough as like a cowboy cerrone and you
teach him some shit like this.
Absolutely.
It's all next level.
This is the elite of the elite.
You know what I mean?
So if you can get your physical,
your physical performance up to the top
level,
then you're selling yourself short.
If you're not only also having a mental
aspect to your game,
you have to have a mental aspect to your
game.
You have to be mentally draining.
I think also like people get used to
shit,
you get used to stuff and you get used
to stuff like where it's not that bad
anymore.
Like,
you know,
I do this.
Have you done the Cryo therapy yet?
Have you done any of that?
No.
What are you doing after this?
You want to go do it?
Two hundred 70 degrees below zero for
three minutes.
Fucking awesome.
My mom did it.
She says amazing.
Amazing.
You get out of there,
you feel like a fucking Werewolf,
like you're going to run through
buildings.
Oh,
sign.
So the point is though,
like I do it so often it's nothing but
the first time I did I was like,
Oh shit,
now I do it.
I just stand there.
Like I literally like the timer goes off
at three minutes online.
I can keep going.
I could just keep going.
My body body's so.
It's so normal to me.
I get used to it.
I wonder if that's what's going on with
his wind Hoff guy too.
It's like his mind has a category for
these states and he puts himself in
these antique and slowly but surely
increase the duration of these states
and the suffering and the in his body
understands how to mitigate whatever
issues might come up from.
It's got a documentary on Vice Joe,
check it out.
It's like 39 slash 40 minutes.
I keep hearing about it.
I and I haven't looked into it enough.
I want to read the facts machine I
bought.
I bought the programs like a 10 week
program for 200 bucks.
I was like,
I'm getting it.
That's awesome.
I want to do that.
Yeah,
I need to get that guy in here.
Those people that are like that,
those outliers,
those are real outliers.
So it's people that like,
like I said,
when you talk about doing an ultra
marathon or something along those lines,
like for most people like God,
that's the develop mental toughness is
involved in that is insane.
And then you hear about this guy and
roller bolt,
fuck.
Well there's always going to be someone
who's taking it to the next place.
Next Guy's going to do it fucking
barefoot,
you know?
I mean it's just,
he's cool because he,
he hooks up with scientists and they
regulate everything.
They take the blood before and during,
after he's looked up to the machine.
So he's like,
he can prove now it's,
you know,
it's proven evidence proven that what
he's doing,
you know,
that's,
that's really cool about it.
That's from being different.
Some like some religious cuc or whatever
to hey this is how I'm doing it,
this is why this time effecting my
autonomic nervous system and now I got
the science to back it up.
Right.
So a lot of people,
they look at that and they think of it
as like walking on coals,
which is really just kind of a horseshit
trick.
You just walk fast and it gets fucked
up,
but you're fine,
you know.
Whereas this guy,
I love that too,
that he has brought in scientists to
make sure,
like there's zero fuckery involved here.
This is a guy that really understands
how to regulate his body temperature and
his breathing and no,
no
false hope and.
But that's exactly what we're doing with
Dr Gordon and the foundation.
Hey,
there's no false hope here.
You know what I mean?
So what he's doing,
when I love about him,
he was like,
hey,
no false hope.
What we're putting out to the guys out
here,
if you're listening,
there's no false hope and Dr Gordon's
program and through the were angels
foundation,
it's all science evidence based and
we've set up a system that's so advanced
that you don't even have to go to a
doctor's office,
be able to see Dr Gordon.
Everything is paperless,
done through skype.
So we've got personalized
individualized,
uh,
methods for medicine to see one of the
world's most renowned people to treat
traumatic brain injuries.
We're now bringing that to every veteran
that signs up through our program.
Did you brought the whole thing full
circle?
Okay.
Did that fucking.
You've been doing media do it.
You know how to bring it back.
Now I'm the Warrior Angels Foundation.
What does anybody have to do if they
want to get involved in this?
Like say someone's listening to this and
they say,
you know,
they're thinking themselves.
This,
this applies to me,
right?
Like,
I know,
I know this could help me.
I know I have this issue.
All you gotta to do is go to our
website,
go to our treatment page and start
filling in your information.
And the website is warrior Angel
Foundation.
We are angels with the angels,
Angels Foundation Dot Org.
So you go through,
you fill out your initial information,
then you get started in our automated
process.
What you'll get Dr [inaudible],
Dr Gordon's a patient patient intake
form,
you know the,
the long one and you'll fill that out,
get it back to us through email,
never had to print out anything,
no printing,
no nothing,
man.
It's all digitalized,
uh,
all done through the cloud.
So we get all that information.
Once we get all your information in,
Dr Gordon in his office,
check it.
They make sure you're a good candidate.
Once that's been decided,
we'll go ahead and we'll start with
funding you.
And um,
when we make the funds go through,
you'll get your blood test,
we'll send a.
We have access labs and Florida.
All right,
so they'll do your labs.
So they send the labs to you,
to you wherever you're at,
and they will make plans for you to go
to a lab that's the closest to your
geographical location.
So that's the only time you're gonna
have to leave your house to do this
thing.
So you'll go,
you'll go to leave your house to go get
your labs drawn.
They'll ticket,
they'll take the labs,
they'll send that back to Florida,
Florida.
We'll get it there,
analyze the results they're seeing the
results to Dr Gordon.
Dr Gordon gets it,
he gets the results,
makes a,
a,
uh,
they schedule an appointment with you to
do a one on one consultation and he'll
go over everything in complete detail
and answer all your questions there and
then go over what your protocols,
what do thinks your protocol should be
before we actually do a skype,
I write a four page report which gets
sent by email to the patient and it has
English in it,
not just medical leaves in an explains
some of the results and it gives them a
chart of what the suggested first group
of products or the first approach will
be.
And then through Fedex we send a very
comprehensive patient that's a put
together
specifically based upon their lab
results.
It's about 80 pages in total and
explains why we did every single one of
the tests and how they interpret out and
then supportive documentation from the
general medical literature that's out
there.
Um,
and then through the skype,
which is 45 minutes to an hour,
we go through every single one of the
lab tests and how it pertains to them
after we discuss their traumas or
whatever their accident that they had or
if they're a civilian in the lack of any
accident.
But here's what your results are.
And then we make arrangements for either
their doctor to participate with us or
one of our doctors,
you know,
since November twelfth when I saw you
last year,
um,
my new book on traumatic brain injury
came out and I'm a new lecture series
came out and we did that in San Diego.
And part of the reason why there are now
more doctors aware of what we,
what we do is because we trained 45 docs
from five different countries in the
protocols that we've developed over the
past 10 years.
And the results we had.
Andrew was there and spoke to them.
We had a night of Friday night,
which was for military night since we
were so close to coordinate island and
invited the military.
Anyone active war.
Presently I'm a veteran to come to the
meeting and to hear Andrew talk about
his own life's experience.
You know,
I can be the egg head and tell you about
the science that's behind it,
but what's really impacting on both the
psychological,
emotional level is listening to someone
as you did to Matthew Gazani when he was
on the show and Andrew telling his story
of how he transitioned from this
phenomenal life to this great military
life,
that then the injuries and then what
happened after it and then having all
these standardized medical procedures
done,
which really didn't help to bring them
to the level that he's at right now,
which is according to his mother,
father,
sister,
brother.
Your dog also said that you were acting
much better than you were in the past
ever.
Right,
and his life is transition.
The emails he sends me about the quality
that he's experienced,
that's what it's about.
Regardless of what we do,
it's always about,
unfortunately the end point of the
journey that we're taking right now is
that bringing you back to a
functionality where you're enjoying
life.
How's your life?
Yeah.
Couldn't be any better,
I couldn't be any better.
And,
and that's what we're,
that's what we're saying.
Hey,
we want to bring this to everybody out
there who's been told,
like I was told,
this is the new you take a notebook
around with you because you're gonna
have to write stuff down because you're
not going to be able to remember it.
And here's an important thing.
There's a donate link and the donate
link at a warrior,
Angels Foundation Dot Org.
The donate link is really important
because there's a lot of guys that just
didn't have the funds.
They don't have funds for this kind of
treatment.
And it's not covered by insurance
companies.
Correct.
I mean,
there's any insurance covering this all.
What happened?
Um,
let's see how Matthew Gosney got in as I
take a,
a,
of my practice and put it into a
separate fund.
And that's how I think,
uh,
started funding the military is through
our practice because it's,
you know,
for a year,
the first year it's $5,000
all inclusive.
Everything.
Because we've gotten donations from our
laboratory,
the laboratory that we use,
access medical lab has given us a lot of
money to help offset the costs for the
labs are compounding pharmacy
university.
Compounding pharmacy gave us $100,000
grant so that testosterone is for free.
Any of the compounded products free.
Another pharmacy pharmacy gives us all
our clomid so that the first three
months of product for the,
the less than 40 year old veterans,
they get clomid,
which helps stimulate their own body to
make testosterone.
We just got a $10,000
grant from a pure encapsulations for the
key antioxidants that we use for brain
health and a lot of help streamlining
those costs coming in and get this joe
the 5,000
in year one is compared to what the va
spins,
which is $15,000
and the Congressional Budget Office
report in 2012 for Tbi and PTSD,
15 to $16,000
to treat that and all they use is
medication and psychotherapy.
So it gets more as the years goes on.
Whereas we're fixing an underlying
condition.
We're fixing the problem,
$5,000
for the first year,
about 3,500,
2,535
the second year,
and then every year thereafter the cost
is about $1,500.
The same cop was,
it had a $66 billion dollars is what
they're paying for all the medical care
in 2012 slash $66,000,000,000.
That's why we're getting listened to
because we're were like,
look at the difference and variations of
these prices of what you guys are
spending and result and the end,
the end result don't.
But nobody cared about the end result.
They cared about numbers from that
crazy.
Yeah.
And let me just tell anybody who's
listening.
If I made.
My daughter has a jewelry company and
she's volunteered to,
um,
to gift to anyone who gives $5,000
a coin,
which is a 1800 years of age silver coin
from a roam.
All authentic.
They look brand new coins,
um,
as a gift.
Anyone who helps us with $5,000,
uh,
Eric coins or era,
if I can say her website.
Sure.
Okay.
It's e R A,
B Y R,
g.com,
and on there you'll see giving,
it actually shows what she's a producing
in her jewelry company and donating to a
warrior angels foundation so they can
hand it out to people who are donating
money.
Now,
is there any resistance to this,
this type of training?
Is there a,
are there any detractors,
a training insensitive over the seven
training treatment rather?
Uh,
no.
Um,
in fact,
um,
everything is FDA approved.
Everything is being used at
physiological levels.
I think I shared with you on past show
that we use a blended testosterone,
a injectable that we developed about 14
years ago,
which gets into the brain a lot faster
than the cip yonatan the Atlantic that's
out there,
different types of testosterone and we
use a very low dose,
40 milligrams,
which is the amount that a healthy 25 to
35 year old makes in a week's time.
So we're using everything physiologic
and it's not just about hormone
replenishment,
it's about the micronutrients that we're
using to help with the hormone so that
they work.
I mean,
you need to have a well balanced
machinery in the brain in order to get
all the benefits and you,
no one is addressing the inflammatory
aspect to brain trauma and without
addressing that,
you can't get improvement.
Now I know there's sustained improvement
that they're developing new testosterone
that's animal based.
Instead of using yams,
the,
they're using animals somehow or
another,
and they're avoiding detection with,
uh,
these,
drug testing when they're doing these,
um,
carbon isotope tests,
right?
This is new.
This is the new thing that,
that,
uh,
the,
the people on the fringe of the cheating
movement.
Yeah.
Well,
if you can get the testosterone more so
into the brain because we're just
testosterone from really work.
Yeah,
it does work to help build muscle,
but what controls the muscle?
The brain.
We were just talking about how people
succeed in freezing and Eisman and
Kilimanjaro.
It's all the brain.
So if you can increase the brain's
ability to be resistant to failure,
meaning that you've got a mindset,
you're going to do it regardless of hell
or high water,
you're going to do it.
That's really where the benefits are,
so the testosterone increases those
benefits.
Correct,
and low dose,
a very well absorbed,
both like two stops from appropriate,
gets into the system,
into the cells and three to four hours
and it's out of the blood so you don't
detect it appropriate.
What about that?
You were.
You developed drops.
Little light bulbs.
SOMOS Nana live too.
So mit's a compounded product.
We developed the vehicle that the
compounding pharmacies can legal legally
put testosterone into this liquid and
the liquid is put under.
The tongue was put into the mouth and
washed around and gets absorbed because
the particle size is so small,
it gets absorbed rapidly,
but there's a different world.
This is something you have to do every
day,
right?
This is one that,
yeah,
our testing showed that either once a
day,
ideally once a day is the best,
but uh,
you get to regulate the responsiveness
that you have the response.
So if you want to have a nice easy day,
take one squirt on the tongue.
If you want to have really energetic
day,
you'd take two.
If you want to have a fun night for many
hours,
you take four.
That
sounds like you're encouraging people to
get fucking crazy.
I educate everybody.
It's prescription only.
And with all the great doctors out
there,
they'll regulate it and it,
and it's not,
it's not a magic pill,
but what it'll do is it'll allow you to
live life the way it was intended to be.
You know what I mean?
So before,
if you couldn't react to something,
now you'll be able to react to things
appropriately.
You'll be able to do things
appropriately towards.
If you're,
if you're have a,
your neurochemistry is not in balance,
then you can't.
So this will give you the opportunity to
do that.
So in closing,
is there anything else you guys want to
say?
Warrior Angels Foundation Dot Org is
where you can go to learn more about
this.
We got it
crowdfunding campaign that you can get
to through our website.
Um,
we got awesome perks on there,
like a range day with me shooting at the
range.
You got videos on there for that.
I'm cool mugs or whatever.
So some incentives to give.
And uh,
and anything you want to find out about
Dr Gordon or also his daughter will be
on our website as well.
I will say that a life extension
magazine that in 2012 did the article on
hormones to heal the brain in the
military is doing a followup,
a followup article where they've gone to
six or eight of our patients for I think
military and two are for non nonmilitary
and interviewed them to get their
experience over the past few years that,
uh,
since the 2012 article.
And I think it'll be important for those
people who are thinking about maybe
getting involved in what we're doing to
read that.
I think it's coming out a the end of the
year to read it and listen to the
experience.
Where else go back to the,
uh,
Matthew Gazani Jason Hall,
November Twelfth of last year.
And listen to the podcast that was done
because I get a lot of calls of how many
people exactly what he said was what I'm
going through.
And I think listening to those that are
injured and get onto the program more
important than anything I can say.
And also Joe,
because we're on here today,
lives will be changed,
man.
I,
it's probably hard to comprehend that,
but thank you for this opportunity
because it's going to have a ripple
effect that you probably aren't gonna be
able to understand,
but my being on here,
things were things that were going to
affect people's lives in a positive,
positive way.
That's you.
That's what I hope.
And thank you.
Thank you for starting this foundation.
Thank you for being so active with it.
Dark Dot Gordon.
I mean this is all amazing stuff and
whenever you hear about people getting
help like this and how effective it is,
it's just a beautiful thing is really
awesome.
All right folks,
so warrior angels,
Foundation Dot Org.
Go there,
check out the crowd,
fund a link,
check out the donate button and become a
part of this folks,
you can help.
All right,
thank you everybody.
That's it for this week.
We'll see you soon.
Bye.
Thanks.