Tell me,
what are you drawn?
I just write it down like a Pisco
chairs.
Burgo depot.
Oh,
that's me.
How rude of me.
Ergo depot.com.
Ergo depot is the company that provided
us with Isa.
I fucking love these chairs.
I'm not getting paid for this ad.
This isn't even an ad.
I just tell people with if you have back
issues,
get a really good ergonomic chair.
It makes a fucking giant difference
because for me,
I'm sitting in this thing when I do
podcasts for three hours in a setting
and my back doesn't bother me.
When I would use a regular office chair,
I would sit in it for an hour and I'd
start getting.
I started getting not adopt on the
podcast was over.
I'd have to grab like a ball and rubbed
my back out.
Now with these I think,
and I think it's better for my back,
I think it acts when you force yourself
to sit in a good posture.
I think it's like an exercise for your
back and the more you do it,
like I'm super conscious of it now
because I've always had super bad
posture.
I used to slump and then lean my head
forward to terrible things to do during
our show.
So bad it looks terrible tale,
you know,
it doesn't do it when I would write to
and it would bind up on the top of my
back.
So if I write for a few hours I'd be
like,
oh,
but ever since I got these things,
man,
he's really good ball.
Just one of those blow up balls.
Just sit on those.
Yeah.
Those workout balls.
You find that it carries over to like
when you sit somewhere else now you have
better posture.
Totally.
Yeah.
This is how I said no.
I try to at least except when I'm.
For whatever reason,
I don't enjoy television like this.
You got to slouch feet up.
I got to be kicked back.
It isn't too so good.
God,
it's so good.
There's rumors about the next three or
four seasons with them.
They do that because supposedly as you
would say,
they're supposed to do the.
The rumor was that they're going to go
do at Miami season because now the whole
cartel battle goes to Miami,
Griselda Blanco and stuff.
And then,
and then a season,
a four or five would be how the Mexican
cartels took over.
Oh my God.
And like El Chapo.
And so of course,
yeah.
Um,
my uncle Billy Corbin,
um,
my friend who's been on this podcast
before,
is it going,
you know,
cocaine,
cowboys one and two.
If you haven't seen them to stop what
you're doing.
Amazing.
You Watch that documentary,
you just go,
what the fuck?
Unfortunately,
he's a Miami graduate,
but he's a nice,
nice kid.
Is this a Florida rivalry force?
He got y'all guys got course toxic shit.
A mother.
He's lucky they're,
they're good.
This year we'll say no idea what you're
doing.
And her suitor?
Yes.
Number two?
Jamie cosby or something like that.
His name was cosby.
Really?
Yeah.
The guy that that ends up like falling,
you know,
whatever.
Seeing her while she's locked up in
cocaine.
Cowboys
to his last name's cosby.
I remember that.
Oh,
that's right.
He was the guy that was like her
boyfriend,
but she found out he was banging other
checks and she got real pest and when he
started seeing her he was like,
I just want to make money and I'm trying
to move weight,
and she was like,
what do you want?
And he's like,
Oh Hilo.
And she like had someone drop off like
five kilos.
We started off when he was like,
oh my God.
And then the dude was really trafficking
a beautiful.
We'll get there.
Is Charles cosby sleeping that good?
How,
how much to bang?
Griselda?
He must listen for that guy.
That's the God damn lottery.
Yeah,
it was.
It was.
You get hard for her.
You'll figure out a what?
This is all pre viagara too and they're
doing coke vacant out there.
Ooh,
good for her.
Zelda was so fucking crazy.
I never heard that story until there's
so many pictures until a cocaine
cowboys.
I had never heard of.
Never heard of it either.
So good.
So she got a documentary.
She got killed just a couple years after
she got out.
She went back to Columbia.
She went back and they had pictures of
her,
I don't know street.
That's perfect player.
She looks exactly like her.
What?
J Lo has a perfect face.
She really no wonder why she's so needy.
She's carrying around the Willy Wonka
golden ticket.
Like you better listen bitch.
Look at that face.
Look at his ass.
It's kind of crazy.
Like to have that much power.
I was.
That girl has like a.
she's.
She's like,
yeah,
if she stares at me and my boyfriend get
along.
All right.
Yeah,
I mean,
come on man.
Yeah,
and she's been doing it for a minute
too.
She's like 50 years old.
She's in her forties.
Got to be a dime piece.
You know,
I just remembered about Chris from that
documentary is that she named her son
Michael Corleone.
Wow.
That's a really good name for.
I can't think of naming our next child.
Carl's Jr.
That'd be kind of a good.
I don'T know if this is true or if it's
just a rumor,
but the rumor was that j lo's boyfriend
who's as 20,
28 year old,
handsome dancer fellow,
he wanted to go to the ufc and she told
him that he had to come with her to some
charity thing and uh,
in New York and he said,
no,
I'm going to the fights.
And she broke up with him.
Whoa.
Wow.
She tells you what to do.
You've got to go with her.
Yeah,
of course.
You have to go with her little dance.
That's his,
that's her little,
you know.
Yeah,
exactly.
Lapdog backed out.
Backup dancer.
You here.
Fuck me.
Look good.
And you come to charity event.
Yeah,
that's the deal.
Those,
those relationships get super weird in
the sixties,
like once you get to this age,
that's one of those relationships.
get real windows.
That woman,
you're a woman.
No longer as hot.
Your life falls apart if that's all
you've banked on your whole life.
You don't know If someone's 20 slash 30
years younger than you.
Well,
it's not just that,
right?
I mean,
if your entire thing is based on what
you look like,
if that's all you've really paid
attention to and that's what you really
rock is just that,
not your personality,
not not your,
your enjoyment or your hobbies or
anything like that.
Not only does it taken away from you,
but you've had it your whole life,
so you accustom to people approaching
you in communicating you with like
extreme,
like niceness and kindness and desire
and men are just tripping over
themselves to be with you.
Like you have a magic potion that you
put up.
Not only does that go away,
but you become repulsive,
right?
Yeah.
As it all starts gets weird,
and if you.
if you can't buy into it,
if you want to extend your ears,
then you start hitting your face cut
open.
You start getting weird shit done.
You start getting your lips done.
You have a mouth that goes ear to ear to
keep pulling them back into the mouth.
Keeps crawling,
surrendering your age.
Right?
It's far better alternative to be the
dignified older woman who has never
faced fucked up older woman.
Yeah,
that's what I'll be answering some.
It's just a thing that we haven't.
Even if you've been,
I guess they've probably been doing
surgery on people's faces for like 20
years or 30 years.
Right?
How long?
How long ago do you think they started?
I think probably in the between 30 and
48.
And you're still an early adopter?
Oh yeah.
What do you see?
Like now the move is if you're going to
do that,
it's the mild,
right?
It's,
it's the type of the face lift or the
nose job where you go,
oh,
something looks different,
but you can't tell.
That's a.
That's a primo job.
Yeah.
When you see somebody and you're like,
jesus christ,
that's,
oh my god,
look at this.
Oh,
that was Egypt.
3,000
bcc or close to two years before we get.
I don't trust botox and shit.
I now they're like,
it's fine.
You can inject botulism in your face
with no repercussions.
Don't.
It's not.
It can't be.
It's got to be toxic.
It's going to melt your face off.
We're gonna have a bunch of women with
melted faces in a few years right now
that are mad at us because we don't know
what we're talking about course,
but I gotta I gotta assume.
just assume that if you're paraLyzed in
your fucking face to.
That's weird to you.
Talk to people who can't do that.
You know,
like a little too shiny.
Something happens there.
Waxy,
shiny.
Like where's your head so shiny.
It doesn't move in.
It's shiny.
You know,
there's a time and a season to be the
hot chick.
Like I love.
I love Pamela Anderson.
We,
we all did do.
But like I know there was a time where
she didn't surrender like you're the hot
chick for a minute and then you're,
you're just not.
It's gotta be no,
it's got to be tough.
Yeah.
Logically that,
that rush you get from all that
attention as that you don't get that
feeling anymore.
That's got to be really hard to deal
with.
You know?
Oh yeah.
I can only imagine.
I mean,
how could you.
I don't think there's probably very few
things in life that are like that where
they just don't get back.
you know,
it's probably similar to an aging,
a rocker where you play out,
you know,
you're,
you're playing stadiums and people are
like,
you get that out of a ration of everyone
coming to your shows and it's like,
huh?
Like maybe you don't,
you don't move the tickets anymore.
or you just stopped touring.
like there's gonna be an adjustment.
It's not just stadiums to,
okay,
I just don't do that anymore because
it's too much of a rush.
Yeah,
for sure.
Pick up heroin but see some aging rock
for some reason or another,
they still pull it off like,
like mick jagger can still pull it off,
but I think that's,
it's not just that he can,
like he,
first of all it goes out and still does.
It puts on a great show,
but I think the reason that he does is
because you don't want to give up that,
that rush,
that feeling of playing the stadiums
probably.
And it's also probably fun,
really fun,
right?
How do,
how is it not fun to be mick jagger?
Apparently he works out like twice a
day.
really?
Currently.
He's a freak.
He's super disciplined.
He does yoga and push ups and sit ups
and all kinds of crazy shit runs.
wow.
Yeah.
Apparently he's 70 something years old
as fuck as apparently he's super
dedicated to exercise.
Does you think keith has the same
workout regimen and 100 percent?
Yeah.
It's probably not doing heroin anymore.
Probably not.
They don't live that long.
Maybe they can get that good heroin.
So here he's doing sit ups and
apparently like look at all his dance
moves.
I mean what fucking seven year olds can
dance like that?
There are men look at them and know
there's also like a flexibility to his
spine that you rarely see.
Like how old is mick jagger?
Let's guess.
Let's get,
I'm guessing 74.
Seventy three.
Sixty eight.
[inaudible] 68?
I think so,
yeah.
Seventy three.
Nailed it.
Beautiful.
You used my guests.
How many 73 year olds move like that?
Come on man.
When you're 73,
that shit is done and he's like,
he's like slinky now.
Like he's got like a got like a little
thing to
James Brown was moving real crazy like
it was from drUgs,
but he was doing shit.
Yoga,
somebody 20 Five Can't pull off half of
this shit.
You know what?
He was a freak.
Yeah.
He's a freak and he probably just did
it.
he probably tore his hips apart.
Well,
so did he was still doing those little
toes were moving around all the time.
Well prince will you still crazy dance
stuff.
We would spin around.
Do the splits.
Is this James Brown?
James brown gives you dancing.
Are you playing with this guy?
okay.
There's no volume.
So we just watched them christ.
oh well he had some crazy moves too.
But this is a different style of dance
that existed in 19 sixties.
Black America.
And he was the fucking man.
Do you ever see him in africa when he,
uh,
he played the concert and zaire before
muhammad ali fought joel foreman.
George foreman.
Dude.
Yeah,
it's him in zaire.
James brown was one of the baddest
motherfuckers of all time for sure.
Just a freak of freaks us out of his
mind.
People are just basically,
you know,
all soul r and b artists are just trying
to do a version of what he did for.
There was nobody before him like that.
Like you,
you have to put it into context.
You know,
when he would come out with those capes
on and shit like that.
Yeah.
This is,
yeah.
Just say sex on here because I've seen
one and look at the size of his ass.
I didn't know he had such an ass.
get the fuck out of here.
This is 76.
How will do you think he was back then?
He's probably 40 man.
He was a bad motherfucker.
Look at that mustache.
Look at his hair.
Everything they had at the rock and roll
hall of fame,
but they have a basically the same
outfit he has on there,
but the bit dazzled word is just sex aNd
he used to wear something,
saYs stomach.
right now it says g,
f o s what does that mean?
What does that mean?
Is that George Foreman,
foreman grill the originals?
Probably the first one like,
you know,
like a lot of black guys love acronyms
like that.
I've heard like people do like that are
like really into like positive thinking.
They do like,
uh,
like fame,
you know,
anyone mentioning everglades,
like some ridiculous one cfo has a soul.
Your soul fear is false evidence
appearing real.
That's all.
It was weird.
I was on instagram that post the
inspiration on harsh aggressive shit.
Keep pushing,
stay
from the traIn into the wrapping.
Appreciate the sentiment.
But it is corny,
you know,
it was a really funny bit about that.
So crystal,
leah,
he's got a really funny bit about,
about how you know about those hashtag
motivation people.
It's funny.
It's a good bit,
man.
I got to see it.
I haven't seen that.
It's funny bit,
but it's,
it's,
it's a double edged sword because on one
hand I appreciate people that are
exercising and taking care of
themselves.
I Appreciate people that are motivating
people,
but it's fucking still cheesy.
do still silly.
I had this lady one time come to a show
that I did in cleveland and she was in a
wheelchair and she started to,
oh,
she bought,
I was selling cds,
this is like seven years ago.
And she'd be like,
let me get 10.
And I was like,
you went 10.
I was like,
alright.
And I sold them to her and then the next
day she comes and she buys 10 more and I
go,
all right,
I can't,
I can't let you keep buying it.
It's like,
I'll just give them to you now.
I want to support you.
And then she would start to write like
she did that to open up the email
exchange and then started the email me
like ask me questions and then download
about just everything that was bothering
her and things that are bad in her life.
And then I'm going to have this
procedure done.
Ali's remember I Was like,
I'd be like,
alright,
you know,
I communicate with her and then I go
back and she comes again to the first
show.
And I go,
uh,
Well,
you know,
I just,
I'm glad that,
um,
you,
you look like you're all right.
And um,
you know,
the other thing I like about you iS
you're not into all those inspirational
quotes.
I just told her that and she goes,
I love inspirational quotes.
And I was like,
oh,
why don't you bring that up?
I don't know,
I think because I hate it,
I hate it.
And I was just thinking about like,
she doesn't do like keep your head up
stuff.
Like she didn't do that.
I was like,
You know,
you,
you're positive without having to remind
everybody about it.
And she's like,
no,
I love that stuff.
And I was like,
ooh,
uh,
was that it?
Now she was like,
I'm getting my leg removed next week.
And then she was like,
uh,
I have,
one of my kidneys.
they already took out.
My son is Afghanistan,
he got shot.
I'm like,
oh,
I don't know.
I'll tell you like you want to see the.
I was talking to a dude this weekend who
was a doctor.
He was telling us about a surgerY that
they had to perform on this woman.
She had to get her leg removed so they
had to cut through bone and meat and
hack this woman's leg off for some
medical reason.
I don't know what the reason was.
So they're in the middle of doing this
procedure.
They remove her leg and he turns around
and the doctor that is with has the leg
over his head like this,
like
some crazy caveman joe in the operating
room.
Just remove this lady's leg over his
head.
He's going,
he's going to eat or something like it's
fucking.
It's hilarious,
but super disturbing.
But I guess,
I mean,
you're just over it.
When You do it enough.
Look at him joking around about it.
It's not going to make her leg like.
I mean,
she's already witnessed,
witnessed surgery.
You were going in and observe surgery.
I saw my own surgery.
Surgery might.
Yeah,
my knee done.
My first knee operation.
I wanted to watch it.
So they,
um,
they gave me an epidural and I've
watched it.
What do you think was interesting early
though,
right?
It's interesting to look at your body
like,
um,
like the joints.
They seem like when,
when you're getting operated on,
they're fixing something.
The joint seemed like a,
like a hinge instead of like a part of
your body,
like you see it as um,
you know,
you see what would a joint actually is
when you see the tissue in there because
it's,
it was a complicated procedure.
IT's called a patella tendon graft.
They open up your knee like a fish and
then they take a chunk of your patella
tendon,
which is your big thick.
This one that's on the front,
it's pretty thick and you don't need all
of that.
So they take like a third of it and then
they open you up and then they screw it
into the bone and the top and screwed
into the bone and the bottom.
And then they stitch it all up and it
was so weird to watch them do that.
And it was so much better after that
surgery.
What was,
it was fucked before the surgery.
It was too,
it was
wobbly.
Wait a minute.
So there,
but you're watching and they're cutting
into you and you know,
feelings of when I was birthing our son,
she's like,
do you want a mirror to see his head?
I was like,
no,
fuck no.
So I mean that's pretty amazed that you
were able to look at
your own body.
wanted to see it.
Yeah.
I was hoping I was never going to do
this again.
I'm like,
well,
if I'm going to do this,
I want to watch it.
I observed
the food day of surgery an entire day.
Like I saw eight operations when I was a
freshman in high school.
I had the illusion that I would be a
doctor,
I want to be a doctor.
And then my uncle was
dr.
He set me up at the mayo clinic in
jacksonville and so I meet this guy and
I was pretty big kid.
So they're like,
what college do you go to?
It was like,
no,
I'm at school.
And they're like,
okay,
you ready to see this?
Like they thought it was a little more.
And the first one we see is a woman who
spread eagle.
She's 80 and they were moving assist
from her vagina and here's the thing.
He goes,
so he comes over it,
he comes over to me and I'm with my dad,
and he goes,
hey,
don't make any like jokes while you're
in here.
And I go,
what are you talking about?
He goes,
she's awake.
So if you're like,
oh,
look at her old policy.
Okay
pussy though.
But the best way they go in gnarly,
they fucking open up the cyst is the
size of a softball.
Oh my god.
So the guy's like,
this is the biggest cyst we've ever
seen.
Has the.
Has another nurse go get a camera,
starts documentaries like this is going
to be in a journal.
This is incredible.
Then they rupture it and it's shooting
out of there.
Have you ever gone to dr pimple
popper.com
headphones,
headphones to the dr pepper lady on
instagram and I'm obsessed with her page
and she's got like millions of followers
to because she.
All she does is show or youtube videos
and our instagram videos are all just
her popping cysts and it is strangely
strangely.
So she cut Dr.
Sandra Lee.
Hello,
sandra.
Um,
millions of millions of views on
instagram,
millions of views on youtube.
Oh no,
not yet.
Wait,
wait till you see it.
You're not going to bark yet.
So right now she's cutting into this
woman's back who has what looks like
click a small frog growing her back.
So she's like cutting the top of it off.
Cutting a chunk of the meeting was
really good at cutting it yet,
right?
Yeah,
because she wants to remove it in one
chunk.
Like sometimes she can get them.
She's opening it up right now with these
scissors.
This is not the most satisfying because
this right now we're just looking at
surgery.
You okay?
Christina just said she's snipping.
Oh wait,
gotta be so nasty.
Joe.
Um,
I have seen so many people get cut and
knocked unconscious and beat up.
I'm not averse to looking at a ces.
Now look how nasty this is.
Once you start scoring.
And here we go.
Here we go.
Come on,
come on.
Oh.
Oh god.
What?
That's rough enemy person's body vomit.
That's a back.
Is that a back?
What is that?
Started to tell what is the,
what is assist.
It's just nasty.
I dunno.
Just nasty shit.
I dunno what assistance that was.
Huh?
I think it's dead skin.
I read about one of these recently
because they're always watching,
but why don't you just google it?
I did.
Oh,
I can't.
well we'll find out.
We did so much speculation.
We did a podcast this weekend without,
without jamie on the,
uh,
the computer and we were asking
questions and no one ever answered the
questions we just said it was like a 100
percent misinformation.
I heard.
I heard it was like this.
Do you want to look?
I'm hey jamie.
I think we're all good.
That was great.
Thanks.
I just going to get to the end of it.
Some of them are fucking unbelievable.
Push them now.
That's like trash.
Trash in your body.
Five minutes left on this video.
I'm going to throw up.
I just do it to me.
You just had a baby.
Should be like durable now.
But this,
it's like the whole.
Yeah,
it's crazy how big that hole is.
Like that's a goddamn gaping holes.
That's fine.
I don't like the stuff coming out.
That's the gnarly parts.
Wonder why she had to do it.
That obviously I'm not a doctor,
I'm not criticizing or technique,
but I wonder why you have to take a
chunk out of the skin and less instead
of like making like a little hatch.
Like you remember those old schools?
Pajamas scape.
Dude,
that's a small fish.
Oh,
for the love of mommy.
You got to get that last part out.
That sack that it's all holding in and
then what's left over after I heard that
they don't actually know what causes
cysts.
Oh,
how comforting.
Yeah.
They don't know anything.
You just growing up.
Golf ball sized bag of pus on,
you know,
we don't know if people grow in weird
spots too.
They don't even know why.
Yeah,
go weird spots are going to top your
head and shit.
Like they over grow and they're not
cancer.
It's a member.
Ooh.
Membrane the membrane.
This membrane,
the membrane in the body.
A membranous sack or cab cavity of
abnormal character containing fluid at
tough protective capsule.
And closing the larva of parasitic worm.
No.
So yeah,
I guess it's a cavity containing fluid
and they use the word fluid super
loosely.
Fluid pus.
It's fluid.
It's like a whipped cream,
like pissy nastiness.
That's not good.
Nah,
no,
on vagina too.
That's.
I imagine this ladies,
I still remember it.
It was her badge on the outer part so
everybody could see or inside it was
inside.
But then they,
they,
they had her in some way where they
could push back and you could see it
coming out of the side,
you know,
coming like on the wall in a speculum.
Like they opened her up.
Wow.
I wonder if it really had fluid though.
I do remember that.
It wasn't like this.
It really was like a stream coming.
I hate.
I hate to be disrespectful,
but do you think it made her pussy
tighter?
I think so.
It seems like a really good question.
I don't see how you had it in your
mouth.
Would be sure.
Tough to swallow.
So imagine if you got it in your box.
I think that's how they fit.
Snug it up there.
Discovered it because her husband was
for tight.
He's like,
oh shit,
maybe 85 guys.
Do you guys remember James Brown went on
a shooting spree because someone uses
toiLet.
Someone took a shit and it's personal
bathroom.
You don't remember this.
He got in a shootout with the cops.
He uh,
he drove off with a shotgun.
He threatened someone with a gun in the
office for shitting in his toilet.
And then he,
he got in a car,
a high speed chase the cops,
the cops shot his tire out,
kept driving really fast.
That's what it is.
Last mug shot.
How many times you've been arrested?
He got arrested a few times.
His last one,
he and mike.
Mike epps has the job.
Remember that the year after year that
that happened,
mike epps put out a special.
He's like,
band looked like a thunder cat.
That's the Best description of that
because he did.
He had like this straight and he had
that ridiculous smile in that I
remember.
Do you remember the James Brown super
coked out interview?
He did.
So I was just thinking about that one.
What was that interview on?
It was on cnn.
This,
this looks like it get to shoot that
police on pcp.
It says,
oh yes,
I do remember this.
CrazY glass.
Give us some volume,
jamie.
his job is going crazy.
I miss pcp.
Yeah.
It was just saying living in America,
nothing wrong.
Nothing wrong at all.
You're not in any difficulty,
but you're out on bond.
No,
not all.
The charges been dropped.
A lot oF love.
You out on lumber out of love,
which is it I don't love.
From tonight.
You'll find me now at the time you and
your wife had had a problem while the
two of you going to be able to work this
out about the music to talk about what
happened.
WeLl,
let's talk about your tour.
When are you leaving tomorrow and where
are you going?
Rio,
rio de janeiro,
and sao paolo.
But your fans will have heard all about
this.
James,
aren't you concerned about a emojis?
Because nothing wrong and when they ask
you to think about.
got a brand new bag world.
Oh my god.
Time.
We've heArd that in two days.
That's great.
Stay right there.
I'll have to talk about.
Well,
tell us a little bit about what you just
listened.
That's crazy.
What are you going to be doing on this
tour?
I'm going to be doing.
Papa got a brand new bag,
a little bit of sex,
but she didn't get above that feel good.
Wouldn't have radio shows.
Would call someone up and then we got
more.
Oh yeah.
Cause he tells her that he smells good
and he makes love.
Good go.
No,
you want to mingle now,
but when you get out there,
why do you think that is?
What is that?
The women loved you when you get out
there was that lady.
Well,
I'm asking You.
You feel good and you sing good and meg
love.
Good.
Well now we are.
We don't have to ask anybody else.
We got back from
now you're involved in the magazine.
Tell us a little bit about possible
magazine.
That's a crazy.
Rogers angelo was a pianist and james
advised,
and we're doing a fantastic job.
The second coming on this week.
I said,
we have the pope and I believe william.
He's losing.
Yeah,
he looks like Michael Jackson.
We turn into a werewolf and thriller his
eyes nailed it.
Look at those glasses it looks like.
Yeah,
yeah,
yep.
Did you ever see The short movie like
that short film I made a few years ago
about him?
No.
You made a film about James Brown made a
film with ryan sickler,
a comedian about a real story about him
that it's called nine inches and it's on
my youtube page.
And what it's about is that there's a
real story about two guys who shot each
other in an argument over james brown's
height.
What?
Yeah.
So we made a short about it.
This is all about James Brown.
No,
how did I not know about this?
But it happened in Alabama and.
Oh,
here it is.
Yeah.
He just pulled it up.
But,
but based on a real story,
two guys got in an argument about how
tall he is and basically one guy was
like,
you know,
james brown's five,
five or whatever,
and that dude,
he's six feet motherfucker.
And they got,
he got,
they got so heated,
they shot each other over his height.
So that's why it's called fiverr.
It's because of the discrepancy in area,
but it's a real story that,
that these guys were friends,
like good friends.
People get mad about nothing.
Oh yeah.
People get mad about shit that doesn't
make any sense.
Wind up killing each other because
nobody wants it back down.
Then escalates.
You got to be right.
Yeah.
I'm more concerned about pcp.
Where did it go?
Because remember there was a lot of cool
stuff in the eighties that happened
because of angel dust.
People lifted cars and we're where it's
pcp.
My old boxing coach had his finger
bitten off any of our pieces of really
getting off on pcp and he had it
replaced with his toe.
He had his,
his not as big toe,
but as two biggest
toe put in right here.
And you being us.
No 100 percent serious.
Joe lake.
I love that guy to death.
He's my boxing coach.
When I was kid,
he had his finger permanently bent so he
could throw a right hook.
He's a southpaw and a very good right
hook.
He didn't want to give it up.
So,
uh,
when you would shake his hand,
shake it like that.
He has like a little,
little baby finger.
Yeah,
constantly.
That was the toe that was a toe.
It's toe,
but now it's his index finger.
And he had his toe.
yeah.
Yeah,
his foot,
his foot only.
It was four toes as a toe,
big toe.
And then three handlers and somebody hit
it off and say,
oh,
that reminds me,
that reminds me so much fun that I was
with diaz for three days and I'll tell
you why because this is so perfect.
So,
um,
with the,
as we're leaving the shoreline
amphitheater,
we did the odd ball tour.
So we're leaving this shoreline
amphitheater.
He just,
he massacred,
he,
it was like close to 10,000
people we get in the shuttle because
there's intermission and joey and I were
before intermission.
So we tell the driver we want to go back
to the hotel.
There's still another half of show to
go.
So it was just joey,
myself,
and the driver.
And we get in the car,
there's no music on.
We're just talking and we just hit one
of those moments.
You know when you're on a highway at
night and you kind of hit that thing
where it's like you just,
everyone stopped talking for a minute
and you're looking out the window and
you can feel like I'm just kind of
staring off.
No one's talkinG and then after like 15
seconds of silence,
julia goes,
that would tell you.
By the time I saw a guy cut open at the
tenderloin in 1979,
stomach split wide open and I was like,
what?
And I just see the driver's eyes
widened.
And I was like,
no.
He goes,
yeah,
iT's blood was brown because he was
bleeding for so long.
People just stepped over him and I saw
two guys stab each other.
Fucking street,
1980 just over.
Nothing.
They just stab each other.
I didn't almost shit my pants,
but then I got used to it and then you
just see the was just crazy.
I got used to it.
Just look over like who's this guy
sitting next to?
Which is all you saw from like,
uh,
he was,
he's such a,
like a rocket ship of a personality that
you get used to like all the people on
this tour because I did all the dates
and then you can,
you should see like the first night he
came out I'd see the,
like the oddball staff,
like turning,
like what the fuck is going on because
his,
he's just so out of left field,
you know,
you can't prepare for it.
And he's just like,
he's got not a fucking his tank zero.
There's nothing just calls people cock
suckers.
Like the audience was up cock suckers.
They're like,
who the
f you did it to 8,000
people last night.
It's so great up you fucking cock
sucker.
It's endearing to see him live.
Yeah.
He,
he has like some reference to it.
Like he kNew he,
he,
he would throw people off.
Right.
You can tell that.
Some people knew.
They'd be like,
oh my god.
And then he goes,
yeah,
I say some fucked up shit.
And then,
and then he goes,
but I'm your uncle joey.
You know,
everyone's got an uncle joe,
he liked me.
It's a little uncomfortable at first,
like a finger in your ass and then they
just like laughing again right away.
He gets how he hits people,
you know?
Yeah.
He something odd.
There's no,
I've never been anYbody like him for so
force of nature.
It's like a rare occurrence really owns
his farts in public,
but he was just like,
you got to tell you something else in a
bar.
And I was like so loud and it smelled so
sour and he goes,
wait till it hits that motherfucker.
Right.
Points that the guy.
Yeah.
I mean it's crazy,
man.
Crazy.
He's married.
He's fired once on a point that was so
bad that I headphones on and I smelled.
I was in the middle of writing and I
smelled it and I just go,
I start to make this face and then I go
and I put my shirt on my nose.
Terrible.
and then it hits the woman behind us
with the headphones on,
listening to music.
I hear,
oh my god,
oh my god.
He's got his hands rested on his gut.
He's a credit for it,
definitely do it on planes,
but I keep it private credit and no one
assumes I would.
So I liked to plus the sound.
It's so much on the plane that you can
fart and you can just let it rip.
No one's gonna hear it.
Yes.
Good quality.
He also says things that don't add up
for that.
Like he like,
he,
I'm like,
come on.
He goes,
you don't meet dog.
It's like my favorite thing about his
periscopes,
periscopes.
He'll smoke,
you know,
crazy amounts of weed.
He was like,
at 6:00
in the morning,
I've really like rolled two joints.
Smoked him.
Fuck.
Are you doing with your life?
And I'm like,
go,
you're implying that that's the
accomplished,
like I'm doing something.
what are you doing?
He's always said I got high when I have
to do shit early in the morning.
I always call him because he's always
awake.
He's always awake.
Yeah,
he's a,
he's a maniac.
He told me that 4:30.
So like sometimes he's like,
you know,
it just hits me like a thought.
I just get up.
I'm like,
funnY,
4:30
just wants to get up.
Yeah,
not really.
It's,
it's crazy,
right?
You think that he would just be passed
out,
but no,
keep up.
Hold on.
I need to sleep.
If I get up to pee and it's like 4:00
in the morning.
The problem is sometimes
I'll have an idea if I have an idea,
I've gone back to sleep.
I'm like,
oh,
I'll remember it and I never remember
it.
Yeah,
so now if I have any kind of an idea or
a think like it might be an idea,
I have to sit down and then I have to
write something out or talking to my
phone.
I'm talking to my phone a little bit
just to try to capture it.
Gotta write it down.
that's key.
If I don't,
I'm fucked because if I don't I'm not
getting any sleep because then I'll be
sitting there thinking like,
gosh,
I just got up.
It's always that thing where you go.
It could be like when you were about to
fall asleep or about to wake up and you
go,
oh,
I got that though.
That'll that'll come to me,
you know,
when I find like I had to do this thing
for espn today,
so I had to get up early and I'd drive
on the highway and traffic and all that
shit.
But when I was,
I got up early,
you know,
woke up,
had a cup of coffee,
I'm out the door in the hustle and
bustle and there's something about like
getting up early,
forcing yourself to get up and then
having a cup of coffee and going out and
do something.
It gives you,
like,
you got to look a little momentum going.
You knoW,
I'm like,
I'm up early.
there's something to get up early to
really resent people that would brag
about it.
Like,
well I've been up since 5:30.
Well fuck why'd good for you?
It's a little can dredge or tori.
Thank you.
I agree.
Like look at,
look how,
how disciplined I am,
but now we're going to bed late or early
were up earlier,
but now the kids up at the crack of
dawn,
so we got to be up to and now I'm used
to it.
Now I'm one of those people,
you're just sending emails at 6:00
AM and I actually do like it more.
It doesn't make any sense,
but I feel like when I forced myself to
wake up in the morning,
I get a better feeling about the day.
Starting off in a good way.
Like,
all right,
we're up to scale.
I can't just young 11.
Just jerk off.
Yeah.
Wake up at 1230.
Hit the gym by three.
That'd be fine.
One thing I don't know.
I don't like morning workouts.
No.
I like afternoon workouts.
Workout.
First thing you do?
Yup.
Yeah.
I'd like to do something with no food
on,
to do one workout in the morning,
like something,
chin ups,
body weight squats,
something like that.
Sometimes I hit the bag,
no food.
I like to do that several times a week,
but I always feel stronger and I have
more energy if I workout late in the
afternoon.
Late afternoon.
Yeah.
Do you overeat though after you work out
on an empty stomach afterwards?
No.
No,
no.
Um,
I mean I'm gonna be hungry,
but I'm always.
You have to work out.
That's not,
I don't eat much more.
I see what you eat on instagram.
I put my food on instagram.
One of those annoying folks.
I have a lot of meat.
You guys want to meet.
I'll give you some elk.
Show you how to cook it.
Yeah.
Super good for you.
Do you want me?
because you do a lot of veggies and
meat.
I noticed no carbs.
I very little carbs.
I eat a lot of avocados,
a lot of coconut oil.
That's what I'm.
That's what he's doing right now.
you're not fat.
low carb.
Yeah.
You know when you to get ahold of dude,
you got to get a hold of some ketones.
We have them here.
Hold on.
Oh shit.
Yeah.
Somebody if you're on a key to genic
diet.
Yeah.
Try a few of these and tell me what you
think.
What is this?
It's called key genics.
This is the stuff that I use,
but this is made by this guy dom
d'agostino,
who's a.
He's a research scientist from a
university in Florida,
by the way.
He's in Florida and he's one of the
foremost specialists on a ketogenic
diets.
The benefits of key to genic died and
reading a lot about it.
He's super scientific on the best
resource,
if you want to listen to.
This is the tim ferriss show,
tim ferriss,
his podcast.
He had three different podcasts with dom
d'agostino and the first one was one of
the things that got me super excited
about trying to work on a fat based
diet.
Yeah,
just listen to all the benefits this guy
was talking about like all the,
like there's a whole series of benefits
that and intermittent intermittent
fasting,
like getting your body into a state
where it's burning fat.
The big one.
Now,
the real big one though is the hunger
thing.
There's two big ones,
like one I know I have energy all
throughout the day.
I know people right now listening to
this going,
oh my god,
he's talking about a ketogenic diet.
Again,
jesus fucking christ,
because I talk about it too much really?
But just for just for you guys,
um,
you,
you don't have as much hunger,
like in between meals.
You don't have that.
I'm a month into it and really?
Yeah.
I'm down almost 18 pounds.
That's incredible.
I uh,
I basically have,
have felt that way where I'm not just
like feeling that satisfaction more.
I'm also eating overall less food,
you know what I mean?
Like I used to eat just a more of a
higher volume of food,
you know,
like every meal was much bigger than it
was because that fat satisfies you.
Yeah.
Much quicker.
You know,
we'll definitely satisfies you longer
to.
And it just like the craving for carbs.
Like uh,
I got off of it when I went on this
trip.
I went on a trip and I was with these
guys camping for six days and there just
wasn't,
there's no way.
I mean it was just so much food that
wasn't key to genic yeah.
And that's all we had was that food.
So I got off it and the first thing I
noticed is like how hungry would get in
between meals.
Sugar spikes.
Yeah.
Like you get like,
god damn it,
I got to eat.
And I realized like,
wow,
I don't get that when I'm on the fat
based diet and as soon as I got on the
fat based diet again,
it went away.
My son,
you know,
what are my second day of cutting the
sugar and stuff was when we did that
live podcast and I was snapping at.
Everybody was so grumpy.
Oh,
did you get like heroin?
Like,
dude,
I didn't mean I didn't realize how much
sugar I was consuming regularly.
But the first 48 to 72
hours when I was about to be on the
first 48,
I was fucking.
I was really snapping at me.
Yeah man.
I know.
It was just,
I couldn't control it.
I also had a really hard time focusing,
you know,
for those first couple of days.
Yeah.
They,
they called the keto flu.
really?
Yeah.
You feel like you have the flu?
I had a buddy of mine,
my friend brendan tried it,
not brenda chubb and other brendan.
Um,
and um,
when he tried it,
he was like,
he sent me a text message.
It's like,
do you feel shitty?
Like,
do you feel like tired?
Uh,
when you're,
when you're first doing this,
like some people it hits him like really
bad.
I was just really irritable.
Yeah.
Really irritable.
You're jonesing.
Yeah,
I wanted it bad,
man.
Yeah.
So bad.
And you forget all the stuff that has
sugar in it.
That's everything for anything.
Does it.
Actually the cool other cool part about
it besides the health benefits me,
you know,
from what I've read,
a lot of people's,
all their cholesterol goes down,
all that stuff goes down.
It's a good exercise in discipline and
in being focused and mindful in
something that's the cool part.
If you're not,
like,
I'm not a super disciplined person about
a lot of things,
you know,
I'm disciplined about work,
but like I don't find myself to be super
disciplined and all sudden you're going,
all right,
I have to look at what's in this.
And then you're starting to catch
things.
It makes you more focused overall
because you're focused on trying to do
this one.
Like I want to eliminate sugar,
which he secretly in everything you
know,
I think a lot of addictions,
they,
they're all almost the same thing.
It's the same pattern and that pattern
is you're just doing something and you
can't even believe you're doing it while
you're doing it.
And I'm betting all on black,
like whether it's gambling or whether
it's sex or whether it's drugs or
whether it's a.
I mean,
people are addicted to a bunch of
different weird shit.
yeah.
And food is a big one.
It's a big one,
man.
It's kinda the same thing.
They're just caught up in it.
And then after you're done,
you're like,
what the fuck did I do?
What did I do before I had a baby?
I had so much free time and I didn't
realize how much of that time I just
spent eating,
just snacking on shit that I did not.
And now I don't have the time to,
you know,
you lose the baby weight gradually.
It wasn't an effort because it's,
I don't have fucking time.
I used to graze out of boredom or
depression or on the road or whatever.
And then,
you know,
you don't need to eat half the shit.
I don't need you to have the shit I was
eating.
It's simple mouth poser.
And that's when you got to look at it.
There's two,
two different things going on at the
same time.
One,
there's a simple mouth pleasure that
like when you eat lasagna or something
like that.
Oh I couldN't even do it last week.
It was too many carbs.
I felt like it was so heavy though.
I miss pasta.
So good.
You know what I broke on for
a day and i just had a little bit.
I love like a.
Oh really?
Like
the proper really made way rice,
like a,
like a rice that's made,
you know,
not like quick rice but like boiled and
so what makes rice perfect?
Our guatemalan nanny did it?
Yeah.
Had.
Yeah,
I had to.
I was like I got to have cheese steak in
philly on saturday night.
Catch her life.
How was,
that was awesome.
Go.
Are you gonna?
Give him a plug.
I think it was jim's jim.
Jim's jim steak.
yeah,
it's good.
Me and tony found like the place that
had the most authentic reviews.
That's a from my instagram with them
cooking it in front of you.
Come on,
son.
Put cheese was on it,
which in retrospect was a mistake.
I should have gone with provolone and
the guy who was like,
do you want to try wiz?
Like what does that?
He goes,
cheez whiz.
I go,
really?
He goes,
that's how we use.
That's how we originally.
Jeanne moves.
Yeah.
I always thought that was disgusting.
Processed cheese.
I'm real white trash though.
I like all that stuff.
I like shaky cheese.
It just doesn't taste as good.
Prevalent tastes better.
Way about daycare,
chopped onions,
onions,
peppers,
mushrooms to jeff over skippy or I liked
that.
No sugar.
Peanut butter that you have to stick the
knife in and make your countertop oil.
Do it yourself.
I liked that stuff we had to go to.
If you had to go skippy or jeff is kind
of a battle for it.
Who'd you go with?
Skippy?
Skippy.
Peanut.
Dear.
Miss jiffy is like a little bit more
sugary,
but jeff is more peanutty be.
Maybe I got those reversed,
but skippy does taste more process,
but I like the taste.
Yeah,
it does taste more product,
right?
yes,
that's right.
So now you're correcting yourself.
I got it.
So your team.
I'm just keeping it because it's like
candy.
I'm eating candy.
No,
I'm not really eating peanut butter,
peanut butter,
but it's like peanut butter cups and for
like 20 years we never knew basically
that that's not really whipping.
It tastes like,
you know,
having it and you're like this is candy.
Peanut butter is candy is like,
no,
it's not supposed to taste like as a kid
and your lunch and it was just sugar
layer and then a sugar layer.
Well when I was a kid,
my parents.
Yeah,
my parents,
my parents were hippies when I was kid
and they may be healthy and so really?
Yeah.
My stepdad was a total hippie.
Like you had hair down to his ass.
Oh.
And my mom was a hippie too.
We lived in san francisco the whole deal
and we ate wheat bread with that fucking
nasty peanut butter that you have to
start with a knife and when you're a
little kid you're so pumped.
Products white bread with jelly goes
into the bread and like it turns like
it's like you ever see like a nice
smoked meat where it,
that layer on the
outside of the darkness and it's like a
ring,
like a smoke wing but a peanut butter
and jelly sandwich on like wonder bread.
That jelly starts to leak into the
bread.
Yeah.
But those will melt in your mouth.
You wouldn't eat a peanut butter and
jelly sandwich on jeff with willows with
on the less with wonderbread rather on,
with a glass of milk.
So she had like cold war lunches from
her to tell him what you had for lunch.
So my parents,
my parents split.
I live with my dad for a few years and
like he would make me lunch.
It was a cut piece of bread off of like
a low of some eastern european rye with
no seat and then butter and then salami
on butter.
Which is just grease on greased,
like my stomach would hurt a kid to go
to lunch.
Just have these cold like this,
this with butter,
butter,
jelly and butter daily.
He just says you should eat the way he
eats.
He.
He's like,
he looks great,
looks great.
He has cold boss again,
like you know,
basically super fatty sausage and then
like he's like onions,
beer.
Where's he get his bread?
These loaves of bread while there's a
place here in woodland hills.
It's called the german cold cuts.
It's on topanga canyon.
I grew up going there.
It's a tiny little german place and it's
rye with no seeds.
Then there's another one,
a burbank.
It's another german slash hungarian.
They got all the treats and my dad is he
like,
we have cockroach dna,
like we're eastern blockers.
My,
I have relatives who one guy drives a
cab,
80 years old,
never exercised.
Drinks a liter of vodka every day.
Small like it's just our family.
I do think that was because she never
gets sick.
now I'll get like a fucking flew and go
to the hospital and she's like,
like sniffs for a couple of days.
She's like,
I bet your people survive strong.
Like bull zilliant.
Think about like,
like eastern block people.
Some of the hardiest people will you
think like hardy white system most
tender,
the sweetest and the most kind and
affectionate pupil.
That's the thing I don't like though is
that my parents are just so cold.
Like my step mom used to get offended
when waiters would come to the table at
a restaurant and be like,
what's up folks?
For like,
what the fuck?
You folks like,
they're,
they think that it's weakness to be
friendly.
Hi,
how are you?
They just think you're dumb.
Wow.
They went through many wars.
People went through too much chaos,
too much,
too much trauma.
How to be hard for a lot of cold stares.
It's my step,
my step mom he didn't like.
Or do you think that's.
Why do you think russians admire putin?
Because.
But do think they admire him
because,
uh,
they're scared.
Do you think they admire them because
they,
they actually admire that hard ass
motherfucker.
It's a cultural thing.
He'd be seen as a pussy if he were to be
like our obama.
Hey,
that stuff is considered like,
what are you are scared to come on?
Well,
he,
he like jackson.
No,
he checks these guys that are
billionaires like he takes over the
companies and puts them in jail.
There's no reason to be scared that
they'd been scared for so many leaders.
I mean,
look,
they've been through communism.
And how did you guys see you gotta
remember this?
Did you go see the assassination attempt
on him recently?
No,
no,
no.
Oh my god.
It's crazy.
I'm prudent.
Somebody did a suicide assassination
attempt on putin and the way they did it
is they were driving on the opposite
side of the highway and they drove head
on into his car.
Wow.
He's on one side.
Then on the other side,
and they had a median and this guy
drives in the center of the median,
like before the putin's car comes.
And when he sees putin's car turns right
into it.
So he knew it was that car and putin
wasn't in the car,
but his driver,
his driver was and his driver was
killed.
Oh wow.
Yeah,
that's crazy.
Is there a video of this was a couple of
videos from a couple of different
angles.
It's crazy because dashboard cameras
they have over there.
No,
no,
no.
This is like a street cameras so you can
see the cars.
You could see the cars and they see them
slamming each other.
I mean they're going like 80 miles an
hour,
both sides and is uh,
uh,
putin's.
But it is this vehicle like lead and
trailed by escort,
you know,
by security or.
No,
that's a good question.
I don't know because putting wasn't in
the car.
Maybe they thought he was in the car,
maybe that maybe they had a heads up and
they knew something was going on.
I mean,
who the fuck knows,
I dunno.
Maybe they put them in a bunch of
different,
you know,
had a bunch of different cars,
but you could see here here,
roll it back and he watched this.
Boom,
that guy did that on purpose.
Roll it back again,
jamie,
why does that thing keeps shutting off
something wrong with the connector.
Boom.
See that?
Oh yeah.
It's crazy.
So there's a couple different angles of
it,
but the guy leg literally just drove
right into the other lane,
so that was new for sure.
That was,
I mean obviously to target that.
Wow.
New for sure.
To target it and knew for sure he was
going to die.
Watch this.
Boom.
Wow.
Yeah,
they're both dead.
I'm pretty sure.
I mean the also just the precision of
knowing jesus christ and the timing that
I really get your timing right.
How did they know?
I mean there must've been other people
involved.
What am I seeing?
Yeah.
Wow.
Scary.
He's a.
He's a fascinating figure.
It's the when those people exist in this
day and age,
like kim jong wound,
like when that guy exists in 2016,
it makes you really stop and think like,
wow,
he's a dictator of a whole country.
They're all terrified of him.
Did you see when North Korea
accidentally let all of its websites
have become available for a brief moment
of time?
They have 28 websites,
there's only 28 websites and the
internet in North Korea.
Yeah,
so the people that live in North Korea,
they think that's the internet.
It's got to be there.
All state run websites.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
There's a list of them,
but they made a list of the websites
that are.
They like a kingdom on his handsome.com
because I know is super fast runner.com.
You meant that it became free for a
minute and I was like,
oh,
I wonder how much porn was downloaded.
Like could you imagine?
It would be insane.
I think it was.
They just fucked up and let the rest of
the world look at it.
Wow.
I saw that documentary were like this
big thing is that the south koreans will
put films on flash drives films.
Yeah.
Movies on flash drives and then sneak
flashdrives oh,
over in North Korea.
And so that they can see like other,
you know,
others countries like landscapes,
movies,
like just.
And it just blows their minds.
I want to see what the websites were.
Did you find what the websites where?
This wasn't a great list on here.
I was going.
Oh,
okay.
Yeah.
They have 28 websites,
man.
Wow.
Bananas.
It is all came.
There was that.
There was a cooking one showed up and
then korean films.
Wow.
It's really strange.
Young guns,
super long.
Dick.com.
Rudimentary.
Why the mentoree web design skills that
are a hallmark of north korea's online
presence.
Yeah.
In fact,
many of the websites appeared to have
stopped functioning at all by wednesday
morning.
Wow.
What an insane world we live in.
That really is the most.
It's so sad when you think about that.
That's someone's whole existence to live
there.
What did you see when kim jong il died?
How fucking crazy that was.
They would go to jail.
You'd be sentenced to jail if you didn't
cry enough [inaudible].
They felt like you weren't crying
enough.
they would throw you in jail.
So it was to see if you can find this in
the morning.
It's insane.
FaLling down on the streets.
What is amazing about North Korea is how
they contain it like that.
Because my father grew up in communism
in Hungary,
but they could still hear like the
beatles and shit,
you know,
they still had access this way here.
This is so crazy watching all these
people lined up crying and they have to
cry for like long periods of time.
Like if you stopped crying too early,
they'll put you in jail.
People were arrested at these events for
not crying enough.
God damn it,
man.
Yeah.
It's so scary.
It's going to get arrested on the end
there for crying.
I didn't see him crying up.
No.
Yeah dude.
Because blowing his nose on the show.
A little emotion guys.
that's a good one.
That's an exemplary [inaudible] like a
pentecostal guy in tongues.
Oh my god.
Yeah.
Wow.
You know,
North Korea has allegedly,
this might all be us propaganda.
No,
the,
uh,
allegedly have these prison camps where
people are born.
They're born into it.
And this one guy got free and gave all
this testimony,
explained like what it was like in those
camps.
Now he turned his own mother in for
something that she had done and they
showed like how um,
different jobs are given to different
people depending on what level of
decrepitude nis there is.
That a word.
Sure.
To credit precedent,
decrepit,
decrepit to take the lead on that one.
A fucked up at nus.
That's the word.
How much you've,
you know,
decayed.
I mean they're not starving people out
and then they would feed them to dogs.
Oh my god.
this guy was showing the levels,
like he drew pictures of like what
people looked like when they would do
certain jobs and once you couldn't do
physical labor anymore,
they would just fucking fed to animals.
It's really,
they also do this thing where like if
you fuck up or let's say you escape,
you were a north korean citizen,
you escape,
they would go round up your family and
put them in jail and they have a two
generation policy there so that your
kids and their kids will live in the
labor camps.
Jesus,
during communism,
my dad said that they would encourage
the children at school to rat out their
parents if they heard,
if you hear your parents saying anything
against the government,
you're supposed to write your parents
out and that kids would end up doing
that and then they come to your door and
take.
I think that thing is called escape from
camp 19 or escape from camp 14 that that
guy got free and then he was still
living as though he was in North Korea.
He preferred I'm sleeping on the floor
because he slept on the floor for like
25 years,
you know,
and he couldn't adapt.
He just couldn't escape from something
came out about him later that he had
made up some things.
Not that his whole story was made up,
but he fabricated something.
I would imagine that if you lived in a
prison camp your whole life,
you have some serious mental illness.
Oh yeah.
The idea that we could think that this
guy is going to be saying that we hold
them up to some sort of standard.
Well,
you can't even buy what he said.
Don't you know,
he said his biggest fantasy was in that
month eating meat.
Whoa.
Like that's what he would dream about.
Going to get a steak.
Oh my god.
Yeah.
2016.
They still doing that to people right
now.
It's crazy.
Yeah.
Well,
you know,
I had George Perez on,
you know George Perez is dynamic.
Yeah.
Jordan did some time in jail.
He did a long time ago.
Yeah,
a few years back.
Early two thousands for a fight at a
basketball game.
Wow.
Some street basketball game beat some
dude up and then years later he was on
mtv and the dude saw him on tv and heard
about that and that's how he got
arrested.
He got arrested and then he did.
He did prison time.
I did three years.
Shit.
He's fucking hilarious by the way.
And it stories are hilarious.
He's just a funny,
funny dude.
But um,
when he was talking about prison,
it got me thinking like he was talking
about how much people make and he was
talking like thirty eight cents an hour
or something like that.
Like there's not one of them.
One of the things that he said something
ridiculously low and then I'm like,
okay,
how is that not slavery?
Like how were You like you not only are
you putting someone in jail where they
can't go anywhere,
but you are forcing them to work at this
insanely low rate that no one would ever
worked for.
ThAt's true.
Like when you look at the definition of
slavery,
if you say,
well,
slavery ended in 18,
65.
How has slavery done in 18,
65 when you have men literally in chain
gangs breaking,
right?
While we wrote it down on paper,
so you know,
well this guy robbed a purse or whatever
reason.
You put those people in.
Yeah,
I mean either killed them or you know,
like you can't.
You can't force someone to break rocks.
Right?
you can't force them to work for thirty
cents an hour,
whatever it is that still in places some
places.
I think that the law,
one of the last places that still,
or I don't know if they're still doing,
wasn't Louisiana,
was that Louisiana prison that's really
famous.
They had chain gangs.
They made the inmates were pink and
stuff.
No,
that's in an Arizona.
that's just joe our pio,
right?
Yeah.
That guy's crazy.
Chef joe.
That's where Mike Tyson had to go.
He went there.
Mike tyson.
That'll wear pink.
And you got caught with cocaine.
Was it coke?
Yeah.
Pink pink.
How to do a couple of days,
but it was,
you know,
one of those approval point type things.
Wow.
That even Mike Tyson has to wear the
pink.
This is stupid,
but their commissaries cheaper.
Right?
Like maybe it's all adjusted for
prisoners like that.
America is only female.
What chain?
Gang.
The women who pull weeds and barry
unclaimed bodies and at what burry
unclaimed bodies that come up.
That's number to pull weeds.
Number one.
Barry unclaimed bodies number two.
Number three,
pick up cans back in the Arizona desert
to avoid 23 hours of lockdown and
country's toughest jail.
Wow.
They're all chained up.
Just you gotta wonder like at what?
At what point is it slavery?
I'm wondering which one of these girls
would be my prison girlfriend thing.
Tom body body.
So this is probably the glasses I'd hook
up with that shakes.
This is probably like people that are
border crossing and the lineups are
dying out there.
That's got to be so brutal.
Oh my god.
Through Arizona in the summer.
You ever go to phoenix in the summer and
you're like,
oh okay,
I'm going to kill 140.
It's like the middle east dude.
One hundred and 40 degrees and they're
working outside.
Packing weeds.
Holy shit.
That's your life.
Do you think you can get sunblock?
Can you request that you think in jail
like that for some people.
If you were an irish guy with red hair,
I mean I'm really a.
I'll burn.
Excuse me.
It would catch you talk in spanish
though,
and they'd go,
fuck that guy.
That guy knows how to get tan because
you speak fluent spanish.
I've seen people talk shit and spanish
around.
tommy.
Tommy will say something in spanish to
them and they'll go,
oh,
the white guy knows track doing a
spanish talk show on monday.
I'm doing not just going to let that
nita on monday.
See that when he starts doing it in
spanish,
spanish like,
oh,
this is legit spade.
Scary.
A little,
right.
It's a little alarming.
You're like,
it's a host is a clown.
You know?
It's like a guy in full clown makeup.
Are you going to go on as a rapper?
I don't know.
I thought about it.
Is the rapper's name again?
Dj dad mouth and if you haven't seen it
folks,
dj dad.
Math is how tom gets to everybody.
Just one thing that everybody hates.
Everybody hated them.
Not everybody,
but most comics do not like doing
morning tv shows.
They're.
They're probably the most watered down.
It's like pretending that a glass that's
one quarter,
low fat milk and three quarters water
that tastes good.
That's a good way to drink it.
It's not going to give you any pain,
but it's not good.
You're not enjoying it.
It's the worst.
I don't know.
It's a hard gig to have.
That'll be monday.
What does that mean?
Tom?
One book that neato nights with the
plantation,
his name,
but they need those like little banana
nights with little banana man.
I want you to go on sabado domingo,
that shell,
you know,
so he got this saturday for like 30
years or something.
Shell the latin show and we were in
Florida once in miami in a hotel room.
He was sick and we were watching just
hours of it because it'll,
I think it ended.
I think that guy,
that guy,
that guy's been comedy sketches,
they have paternity testing.
TheY have just every slots.
You just slept chain.
How dare you?
Slut shame.
Isn't that funny that that's a real
expression.
Shaming and slut shaming
now.
Saigon site and pronoun shaming.
What's your pronoun?
Joe referred to c,
c h n t dot.dot.
That's my pronoun or gender,
his majesty thing.
Right.
You saw that,
saw you haven't seen this?
Yes.
So university of Michigan,
like a lot of universities now doing
this,
uh,
you know,
like you sign up for class,
your professor sends out an email to the
entire class and professor joe rogan,
my preferred pronouns are he him?
And then this one kid was able to
[inaudible] you can voluntarily choose
your pronoun.
He was like,
mine is his majestY of it.
What a good kid.
His whole thing was to point out the
absurdity of it.
But then people are like,
you're a fucking asshole.
Like they're all mad at him now.
[inaudible] name is grant strobel,
chairman of the young americans
foundation to use the new policy to
update his preferred pronoun to his
majesty.
How could they be mad at him?
That is.
That is no more ridiculous than h I r,
of course there's like 18 different
gender pronouns now been identified and
we also know there's astral gendered.
If you're feeling like you're part of
the cosmos or you polly polly and by.
Yeah,
you put it on your pot.
He put it on his podcast or he's a
twitter page and like it was like by
awareness day and then.
And then some,
some guY,
a real professor was tweeting and he
retweeted.
It was something that was so close to
parody.
What the fuck did he say?
He was just like.
It was the wording of it was too absurd
to even recall,
but it was like remember when you're the
teacher today on by awareness day,
your gender and your to be by is not to
be gender specific,
but specific to city of your gender can
also dictate what your sexuality might
be like.
What?
Like something like that.
Something I don't know.
Using.
Yeah.
And then it was like happy by awareness.
You know?
I finally used an all gender restroom in
portland and it was at a gay bar and I
got like,
I didn't enjoy it and it's not because
of the whole pronoun thing.
It's because you've got like dudes
taking gnarly shits next to you don't
need it.
Yeah.
I don't need,
it dims thursdays I'm poly and by and
I'm also fluid gender.
My favorite thing is to be fluid gender
because you can go however you're
feeling in the moment,
but you have to.
People have to know what to call you so
you have to.
That's my favorite.
Announced constantly.
I,
we went,
we saw this video of this guy who was
like,
he was like,
you know,
you should really respect people's
pronouns,
which,
which I am like,
okay.
then he goes,
and if you see somebody and you're not
sure,
just ask them.
Be liKe,
hey,
what's your pronoun?
To which I say,
no,
you fucking don't.
Like,
you're not going to just see somebody
and be like,
hey,
I'm just wondering just a pronoun.
I think the onus should be on the person
crowder.
Steven crowder has a fucking hilarious
video where he actually does this and
go,
yeah.
He goes out and asks people what their
preferred gender pronouns are and they
just the looks they give him like he
goes to like grown adults,
goes up to them on the street and just
talks to them and just wonders what
their preferred gender pronoun is.
Nobody knows what the fuck you're
talking about.
Preposterous.
I can't wait foR the backlash.
What's that video?
That guy dustin.
Dakota.
Yeah.
We have to show that one to code is
amazing.
Did you see the thing?
Yeah,
to code Is incredible.
this is zoom,
zoom,
zoom.
Oh,
for the different gender pronouns.
Why is it so hard?
Why can't you just do what they asked
for?
My pronouns are not preferred thing is
like,
I feel like there's enough people going,
okay,
really that it's kind of a legitimate
thing to not be 100 percent on board
with us,
you know,
because I feel a little like,
oh,
am I on the wrong end of history?
Pronouns are not preferred.
Ask a gender terrorist areas.
Whoa.
This is the newest video on my ask a
ginger terrorist playlists on my
channel.
Are we allowed to play this without?
You can't.
You can't just play it.
Well,
we're not showing it on youtube are we
haven't like picture in picture.
I'll take it off.
Take it off.
I know it's this dude's dude.
Whatever it is that's got a beard.
Not.
I know it doesn't have a preferred
gender pronoun.
Well that's what you're work at.
We're going to get to.
So that's the thing now,
right?
You can kind of be whatever you want to
be.
Yeah.
Which is fine.
I guess.
I just think it's funny that some people
are saying that you should see this
individual and lead with like,
it's almost like it's rude for you to
assume,
which I think is absurd that you're
going to do that.
It's rude to assume like if you,
if you're going to dictate a different
pronoun,
I think that should be on you like a
status.
Like you should just show people or some
people do have these little stickers
that they put on my preferred gender
pronoun is.
That's cool.
Well,
here's a radio lab and this is one of my
all time favorite ones.
There's a radio,
a podcast.
They take it so seriously because it's
radio lab and uh,
there's a guy on it who's clearly out of
his fucking mind and he goes back and
forth between male and female during
switches while he's talking to you.
Because I just switched.
I just switched from the man.
Now you're like,
well,
okay.
When do you get to be a dragon?
Do you get to read minds in the future?
Then we're supposed to respect this.
You have to because it's,
it has to do with gender.
So if this guy was telling you about his
past lives,
you know,
as a roman gladiator
or if he was telling you about the
future when the star ships land,
you would think that he's a crazy
person.
Right?
Right.
But right now.
But when you talk about gender,
as soon as you start talking about
gender,
you really,
you're supposed to like give people the
benefit of all doubt.
Like even if you think you're switching
gender back and forth as you're talking,
like the idea that you're,
your genders,
like some sort of a seesaw,
you're on the precipice and you can just
go left or right to left or right.
And it is close minded asshole.
You just decide you don't understand.
But here's the thing,
are we different a lot of the time?
Why can't I be that difference be
expressed in gender like you the other
day when you were cranky because you
didn't get your sugar.
Yeah,
right?
Yeah.
Like what?
That's be.
You have a dIfferent personality trait.
You fell into this bitchy but doesn't
like that feeling like going back to
like sexist and fire.
Join up gender folk phobic.
Nervous,
well I'm looking forward,
I'm looking forward to ignoring so many
emails that are going to come into my
inbox about this conversation,
but people get mad.
Oh,
I know they're going to get so mad.
My point is like,
we've talked about this,
like if you're feeling particularly
lovie dovie,
right?
Your patent kittens and you're.
You're putting your daughter's hair and
ponytails.
You're more feminine feeling.
So did you switch genders at that
moment?
No.
You still specifically this guy wanted
to go back and forth to being recognized
as a man and then recommend the middle
of the conversation.
Then as he goes back and forth,
he becomes a totally different person.
Like yes,
like he's not going to tolerate any
bullshit.
I think usually in the military too,
it was like it was like there's a lot of
weirdness to the story and he's under
the care of a psychiatrist though,
right?
No,
no,
no.
He's wondering around getting government
grants and.
Great.
I have no idea.
I have no idea what he's doing,
but I just.
You never go.
Like if someone goes back and forth and
pretends to be hungarian,
I'm hungarian now.
No,
no.
Now I'm from Ireland,
but I feel today I'm now I'm hungarian
again.
Wait,
I'm identifying that way,
but that's fine.
Like here's the thing.
If you want to identify throughout the
day,
sometimes I am more masculine.
When I'm at the comedy store performing,
I am very alpha male.
I'm very macho,
but I do.
I have to demand that people know what
to call me at every given moment.
That's a little unrealistic.
What's a nEw thing?
It's really weird.
I mean it's so presumptuous and
narcissistic that you should know what
to call it.
You at least say like right now,
address me as her shoe.
Different names.
He looks and he just snatched it out of
them.
Depending on who I'm.
I might be mis-gendering or not,
depending on how he here or she hears it
at the moment.
When you did point,
if you're in a conversation with that
person,
would you like feel like that's a
respect?
Like something that you'd be like,
oh,
okay,
I'll respect your wishes.
I'm not changing your gender.
You gotta to pick one?
Yeah.
If you say,
girl,
you're a girl.
I'm cool with that.
I don't have any problem with that,
but you can't go back and forth.
Yeah,
or I can't talk to you.
It's too much work.
That's the whole thing.
It's too much fucking work.
And if you're an adult that's got a full
life,
how the fuck a room In your head for
[inaudible] every second changing.
Not only that,
that's somebody else's issue,
right?
What about yourself?
You know,
I don't have any.
I don't have a room to communicate with
you because you're concentrating on
yourself so much.
You want people to change how they
address you.
Can you just change how you feel
occasionally and not have a new fucking
name that someones 3:00
in the afternoon.
I'm bob,
why did we have to label it every moment
of every.
Well,
is he super self indulgent thing and
that's what you're getting out of this
and that's what like the people that
are,
you know,
they're being labeled as insensitive.
Like that's kind of the point.
The point is like,
yeah,
you're supposed to be insensitive of
nonsense.
This deserves a fair amount of mockery,
afraid to,
in part because we're going to get
shamed on twitter.
People are going to call us phobic of
this and that.
Even if you say something remotely,
your gender unpolitically correct or
whatever.
Yeah,
look,
there's a bunch of people out there that
are just not happy and they might not be
happy with the gender.
They might not be happy with the way
they look.
They might not be happy with how old
they are.
They might not be happy with a bunch of
different things,
but we have like rules as far as like
what you can change and what you can't
change and we're allowing people now.
This is like a really reason thing to
just decide to change your gender,
which doesn't affect me.
I want people to have freedom.
Doesn't bother me,
but what,
what is this?
Uh,
there's an addendum to the radio lab
story.
She made them edit out the references to
her actually changing her identity.
I guess she stopped.
She stopped switching after all this is
right here.
And she no longer flips.
Interesting woman.
She now remains comfortable as a queer
trans woman.
What does,
what does that mean?
What's a queer?
There's not gay though.
No,
I thought it meant that queer is like
weird.
Like you can do both,
right?
Isn't it?
what is queer?
And then let.
How do you know gay is gay?
Queer is not gay.
Queer is like non defined.
Okay.
So not a non defined trail on binary.
tom's domain.
Tom,
can you explain this?
Yeah,
I mean basically.
Well you guys,
you fall on the binary spectrum.
Cisgender and privileged.
Okay.
Here we go.
Shoot a queer feeling.
Nope.
That's not it.
A homosexual.
No.
See they're using a different.
Now see it used to be homosexual,
but it's not just a homosexual anymore.
Okay.
TeRms and definitions.
Lbgt right there.
Click on that one.
Lgbtq now.
Oh no,
there's an I in an a in there to look at
that.
See,
look at that.
Make that largest fucking shitty.
I ask you to read it.
Bisexual,
transgender,
queer.
Yeah.
Look at it.
But look it above.
Above.
Go up to the top.
Look,
lg lgbtqa.
What is tb,
lg queer,
asexual,
queer,
or a sexual history.
Questions or questioning and a sexual,
but there's intersexual to.
There's I.
Some people choose.
I wait.
What site?
WHat does that mean?
No,
let's get to q,
queer,
intersex,
intersex as jamie,
an umbrella term used by l,
g,
b t q,
a people to revert to the entire lgbt
community and alternative that some
people used to.
Queer is the idea that labels and
categories such as lesbian,
gay,
bisexual,
etc.
Similar to the concept of queer,
of gender queer.
Oh,
okay.
Gender queer is different.
what's gender queer?
I think that'd be like me,
like nonbinary where I don't fall under
the spectrum of male or female.
gender.
Queer is a term which refers to
individuals or groups who are queer or
problematize what for making a fake
words,
hegemonic notions of sex,
gender,
and desire.
In a given society,
gender queer people possess identities
which fall outside of the widely
accepted sexual binary.
You're not buying your area,
your gender queer,
row,
gender queer.
Gender may also refer to people who
identify as both transgendered and queer
eye individuals who
this a lot of work.
Man,
that's a lot of work time.
This is what you do when you don't chop
firewood.
Yeah,
fucking easy to get water.
To get bottled water,
easy society.
We have to invent all these things.
Now what happened?
I just be in Here.
Why is everybody has to be defined?
I don't know.
Why do we have to check each other to
make sure that everyone's on the same
fucking agenda?
Do you know how much I'm dreading my
son,
our son?
Sorry.
Going to school.
Do you know that there are schools that
don't have grades first grade,
second grade,
third grade,
so that the kids don't feel bad.
There was no hierarchy.
Group one,
group two,
group three,
shit like that.
Soft.
People are trying to eliminate all forms
of competition and scrutiny and they're
calling.
Any criticism of you at all?
Bullying,
bullying.
It's all bull.
Yeah.
There's.
There's a lot of leagues with no.
No score.
It's crazy.
It's weird.
That is really weird.
I think loss has really helped you as a
kid.
I think shame helps you.
Loss,
anxiety,
fear.
those were all my primary motivations as
a young woman and it carried me very
far.
I'm not a fucking loser and because of
these things,
I'm sure like the people that do it,
that,
that do mean shit or say mean shit.
The kids,
they realized after they do it,
how shitty it feels.
Like it's a learning experience even for
them,
like they should absolutely be
corrected,
but this idea that somehow or another
you're going to wipe all that stuff out.
That's part of being a person,
right?
It's a weird part of being a person.
Like people liked the fact that they can
affect people by saying shit.
You know,
they absolutely.
Yeah.
The idea that we're going to sanitize
out everything so that your kids will
never have to feel a bad feeling ever
again.
No one.
Everything's going to be perfect,
right?
To make a whole new bathroom,
to make a whole,
uh,
an asexual bathroom because some people
just,
they're not sure.
Some people,
people are just gonna start shooting
outside.
I can't wait for the,
what is this one?
Half a skirt is this new form someone
just posted.
Oh my god.
Is that new?
Is that real?
That's a college.
That's where your tax dollars are going.
It's a high school somewhere.
Come on man.
How many people this,
how big of an issue is this?
You know,
because there's people that have all
sorts of very strange,
uh,
identity disorders.
There's a guy in england that thinks
he's a six year old girl and he
identifies a six year old girl and he
wears pigtails the whole deal.
He sits down with his kids and his own
parents,
kids.
He kids.
Wow.
He identifies as being a six year old
girl.
Hey,
we have to accept this.
As long as you change gender,
they uh,
his family.
As long as you change the gender,
everybody's cool with it.
Meet the 52 yeAr old father that if he
thought he was 13,
he tried fucking 13 year olds.
13 to know.
Maybe everybody goes,
no,
you're out of your mind.
Dude.
she is gorgeous.
Look at this.
He's living as a six year old girl,
abandoned his wife and kid,
but let's be for seven kids.
He has seven munchies.
She has seven kids.
Do you want her to be a daddy?
Well,
it's too late.
Already a daddy better those kids.
But the kids are better off without her
shoes.
So he was living as an adult.
He has a,
you know,
a family,
the whole deal and then just decides
that he's not just a woman,
but he's a small young six year old
girl.
There's something else called again,
psychiatrists need to get involved in
the volume on this young jamie
and as well the tv show.
Boy,
am I a boy or a girl decide to go public
with your short.
Um,
I paid a pretty heavy price for
transitioning.
And so at a certain point I've already
lost everything and everything has
happened.
I'm going to be me and I'm going to show
other people that it's okay to be.
She looks like most middle aged women,
Wisconsin coming out of the closet just
liberated like my friends' moms when I
was a kid in milwaukee.
They all look like that.
Transgendered,
six-year-olds,
I'm torn about because I don't give a
shit if he wants to be a woman,
but I just can't see this.
There's a line that's being pushed by.
These fucks keep going further further
and they keep taking advantage of your
acceptance and they want nonsense to get
through.
This is fucking nonsense.
Nonsense.
This is a person who just wants
nonsense.
The world didn't work out for them.
The regular world of having a short
haircut and wearing t shirts,
he's like,
no,
I'm going to wear a little girl's
dresses.
I'm going to be a six year old.
Hey,
how about you?
HOw about fuck you man?
Well enough.
Now here's the thing.
Twenty years ago,
maybe even less the answer to like six
years and be like,
hey,
go fuck yourself.
Because all these shutting sterl online
and they're ganging up and attacking
universities,
right?
And attacking anybody Who sees anything
any differently.
This is not accepted.
It's folks.
Acceptance is 100 percent fine.
you should be able to do whatever you
want,
but you want to pretend that's not
crazy.
We got a problem or a 52 year old man.
You pretend to be a six year old boy.
You're out at your fucking mind.
Well,
guess what?
If you're a 52 year oLd man,
you want to be a six year old girl,
you're still out of your fucking mind.
You've been alive for 52 years.
We're supposed to pretend that your life
experiences is nothing.
Your records you enjoyed that stage of
life.
You're given so much credibility to this
idea.
I feel like this is because of the
gender switch because you're in weight
loss.
Especially if you're like me.
If you're a man and a meathead like me,
asshole insensitive asshole.
This is nonsense.
That's for the record.
I'm a woman and I think this is complete
horseshit to 100 percent horseshoe and
also there's something good about the
conformity of the 19 fifties and before
because I feel like we've got a rug.
Of course.
No,
I'm telling you,
that's a.
You know,
that was a time when you couldn't.
He's got fucking seven kids brawling.
Don't you think that outweighs your duty
to your family outweighs your need to be
a six year old?
Gets drawn to.
I'm drawn to it.
To the people that are really direct,
like no bullshit.
Like dance,
like the,
the,
the business coach.
Oh,
the $50,000,000,000
man.
Holy food.
Love this guy.
I thought you're going to say jody as
well.
If you do.
If you look up dan pena.
this is why you're poor.
And you scroll.
Scroll to a minute.
40.
That guy.
Yes.
He just fucking dirty.
And so it's so funny.
He doesn't give a shit though.
That's what he's almost dead.
Well,
donald trump's going to rock the planet.
He's a trump supporter.
Yeah.
He's out of his mind.
Yeah,
I think so.
But friends,
I think he knows him.
I don't think we could play stuff
without getting sued.
Jamie,
can you hear the audio?
Yeah,
I don't think so.
No.
Yeah,
I highly doubt he'll let you play your
stuff without you heal yankee offline.
We put a match.
Yeah.
They're going to find you think so?
Matter time.
Shit.
I don't know.
I just think this is his property,
like his,
his lectures and all that stuff.
This is where fair use argument could be
a player.
That fair use argument is not.
It's.
It's a weird argument.
We play shit all the time and talk about
it and it gets jacked.
Whom?
Well did you see the guy,
the video today?
The guy who got attacked by a grizzly
bear?
Holy shit.
No,
it wasn't even hunting.
Was scouting scouting for an upcoming
client and he came across a mama bear
and her cubs.
That's what's up.
Yeah,
and he even sprayed it with bear spray.
He said dead on 25 yards,
like unloaded in the bear.
Just ran.
Ran right through it.
You don't.
I mean you don't.
You don't know what they're going to do
until they do it.
That bear spray might work sometimes.
It didn't work this time.
Yeah.
Look,
it's hard to tell here,
but his skin is hanging off of his head
above his ear and he the bear bit
through his arms to.
His name's todd or he's lucky he got
away on my face and protected the back
of my neck.
Oh my god,
I don't know what's under my hat,
my arm,
his arm's broken.
look at that stuff.
Hanging out.
This whole just twitched.
You couldn't imagine a fucking bear
female grizzly bear protecting her cubs.
Tough.
This guy is holding back that up there
for a second there.
Back it up.
Look at it.
Listen to this.
Internal organs are good.
Eyes are good.
I just walked out three miles.
Now you go to the hospital,
so nobody stopped to make a video,
but listen to that pragmatic way of
looking at her legs are good.
Internal organs are good.
Like that is the fear.
Like that guy just came in contact with
a real live monster,
a fucking grizzly bear twice,
twice in a day.
A real live.
After that three mile hike got in his
truck and drove 20 miles to a hospital
for then.
You should probably so happy.
Just he's alive.
I mean,
you see the photos,
the scar.
Yeah.
oh my god.
the photos that headscarf.
Yeah.
That's really,
really big.
Yeah.
I wonder if that was a claw was probably
a claw.
Sorry.
He's so.
He's scouting for alex,
so this is like a public,
but is it a,
I don't know where,
where,
where do people have some kind of a
hunting area?
Yeah.
He's said he could be on private land,
but most likely is on public land.
And um,
you know,
they have a,
they don't,
I don't believe Montana has a grizzly
bear season.
They do have grizzly bears,
so he just wasn't.
He just walked over and then I.
Yeah,
I think the only place you can hunt
grizzly bears in north America as
Alaska,
I think.
I think there's grizzly bears in Alaska
and then I don't think you even hunt
grizzly bears in Canada.
He had imagined the diarrhea in Canada.
They hunt them in british columbia.
What am I talking about?
Like when you,
when you walk over and then 80 yards was
a bear and you'd be like,
oh god.
And then you just,
you got his spread.
He knows if you're around here,
like you can't book it,
you're not going to run.
He sprayed it.
We know that that's one photo of his
arm,
but check out the other ones just has
one of his head or pull them up because
I'm not logged into facebook.
Oh,
okay.
I'm just see if we could find it outside
of a,
but oh my god.
So my buddy Adam Green tree who is on
the podcast last week,
he's a bow hunter.
There it is.
Look at his head.
Look at the giant scar that goes from
his temple.
Although first of all,
if you wanted a scar on the back of your
head,
that's the spot.
Like it doesn't rip his ear off.
Doesn't you know?
It's got a nice line on his head,
but it seems like it will stitch back
together as long as he doesn't have an
infection from the bear bite.
And a guy's goT a good story too for
awhile now.
One bite on my farm went through to the
bone and I heard a crunch.
Yeah,
think you're dead,
right?
You're like,
this is it.
This guy's really good about social
media.
this.
He's like,
hey everyone.
I got to tell you this video.
He did a couple of,
well,
this guy's a hunting guide.
Do you know how like in tune with the
wilderness and this kind of sPeed and
the Montana montana's the woods man.
Yeah,
I mean it's beautiful,
but I mean it is a wild state.
They have a lot of grizzly bears here,
man.
Lot of a lot of like free roaming
animals everywhere,
right?
Because we went there in the summer and
we went to bozeman and we drove down
this road and we pulled up.
We saw 100 elk just sitting in this
field like right off the side of the
road.
We're like,
this is crazy.
You just get out of the car and look at
them on a hunting trip or with my family
we went to.
We did the yellowstone thing,
but just looking out and looking at all
these animals like whoa.
And apparentlY,
but we saw grizzlies there but we saw
them at a grizzly sanctuary,
but apparently people just run into them
all the time.
Yeah,
you just,
you could fuck up like this guy and just
accidentally be in the Wrong place at
the wrong time.
And the female has her cubs.
I remember going there once and having
the guide tells,
you know,
if you run into a bear and like do these
things in the whole time.
Your brains,
like you just got to die,
you know,
like he's like,
cover your ears and crowds.
But like,
play limp,
don't fight back,
don't run my life.
And this guy actually did it,
which is the crazy part.
Yeah.
He actually did it and he played dead on
that second one.
He said,
yeah,
he just went limp.
It's the only way.
Imagine going limp on that thing is
biting you.
Jesus christ,
they're so big.
It's such a terrifying.
It's,
it's crazy that it's a real thing that
there's a real animal that's 11 feet
tall.
It weighs a thousand pounds.
So my friend adam,
he went on an elk by himself in Montana.
He was in Montana,
shot an elk and uh,
he's,
he has to pack it off the mountain and
he's like 14 miles in.
So he's got to pack this thousand pound
animal and he's going to do it in 150
200 pound chunks.
So he's going to and each one of them is
going to take a day.
So he's doing it essentially four days
of just packing out meat.
So the first day when he goes back,
a grizzly was sleeping on the carcass.
A giant grizzly bear,
11 foot grizzly bears sleeping on the
dead.
Elk chase it off and scare it.
Has to yell at it to try to get it out
of there.
He has a pistol with him by himself.
I don't think I would have taken that
route by himself.
He had no,
that's nuts.
No,
he can have the elk.
Dude.
The bear ran off really well.
Is that the approach you would have done
without knowing this?
Have you been like,
man,
I don't know.
I mean,
you post to do that.
You say you're supposed to yell at me if
you want it to leave,
but you might want to Just give it to
meat.
Get the fuck out of there.
Just get the fuck out of there.
That's not true anymore.
Did he?
Doesn't.
He didn't want to do that beCause he.
He worked hard for that elk can you
shine,
right?
It's a tough fucking call.
I wouldn't want to be the one to make
it.
No,
of course not.
No.
See goes one hand.
You would say,
well look,
the bad news is I don't get to meet.
The good news is the of big and see
because I really liked paris.
I had a teddy bear when I was a kid.
That's my friend cameron hanes.
That's one he killed in Alaska.
Is he the guy that also does those crazy
marathon run ran 200 miles this summer
in a day.
Seventy eight hours.
He ran three days,
slept three hOurs and three days.
How do you,
how does your system keep going until
you have to build up to it?
He was runninG a half a marathon a day.
Every day was running 13 miles.
That's insane.
And then he ran a hundred miles in like
june to prepare for the 205 miles in
august.
Wow.
It's insane.
I mean there's the mental part,
which is its own thing,
but then physically doesn't that just,
he looks tired,
they're tired.
Well,
he didn't just do it.
He's kind of crazy.
I mean he's a good friend of mine.
I love him to death,
but he's crazy.
And this is one of the things he did.
He uh,
he lOst a ton of weight.
He went from 180 pounds down to below
one slash 60 just by starving himself.
So he had his body eat itself.
So.
And because he was already lean,
like he didn't have any fat to lose.
So the only way for him to losE weight
burn 3000 calories,
eat 2000.
So he did that for months until his body
looked shriveled away,
down to a,
like,
I think he got under 160 before he could
do this.
Like the other day he put a picture on
his instagram.
He weighed 100 fifTy eight.
When I met him he weighed 180 and he was
built like you lift weights but he did
one of these at 180.
And it was too hard,
so he decided to lose the weight.
So that's how we kind of discipline.
You have to just make your Body eat
itself.
Like you don't have any faCts,
even at sub one 60 to run that that muCh
like to your knees,
your joints.
It's got to be brutal.
Right?
It's not good will.
That's what he said.
He said it's really like you could do
performance enhancing drugs,
but it's really not necessarily going to
help you,
but really they're not going to help you
not feel pain or be able to be tough.
Like it's.
A lot of it is just being tough.
Yeah.
He's a tough son of man suffering.
He's a maniac.
He's got issues,
but he's also like one of the most
successful bowhunters ever.
Really hasn't.
Bowhunting is the hardest thing in the
world to do when it comes to acquisition
of meat.
Like there's no harder way to.
What state does he live?
In?
Oregon,
there's no harder way to get an animal
than with a bow and arrow because you
have to get within a certain distance.
You have to practice every day.
You have to,
and he hasn't had an unsuccessful
bowhunt since 2009 and he goes every
year and it kills multiple elk every
year.
That's like unheard of.
Nobody does that.
Like everybody has dud dud trips like
you go and you struck out,
you just don't see the right animals.
You don't get him.
He,
he's just.
I mean this one is designed for,
so he does and he just excels at it and
if he doesn't find somebody just like
runs 100 miles to the next spot,
I've hunted with them and the thing
that's crazy is how he doesn't get
tired.
LIke I'm in pretty good shape.
That's what I follow him up the hills.
I'm like,
fuck that.
Some people are wired like his sister
maria is a similar level of lunacy.
Does she do marathons and shows you guys
like a.
She's done like trial half triathlons
and uh,
she uh,
she did five point eight miles a day
before she gave birth.
Whoa.
Oh my god.
And her uterus was falling out of her
vagina from doing all that.
And the doctor said,
you gotta stop.
Dr.
Said he needed a nice system,
things up,
tighten it up unless ball size,
a nice little sister and she is one of
those people that is always like,
do.
She's really athletic.
She was in the navy and she beat out all
the guys doing pushups.
Right?
She did the whole.
They have a pt test.
She beat all the women and all but one
guy,
jesus christ.
Animal.
Just like a brother.
Hardcore guys like her brother.
Does she do those tough mudders?
Those are the weirdest mud.
People get sick as fuck.
They get diarrhea because for real.
What is this?
I don't know what the auditors are.
These crazy races where you have to go
through.
You're literally running a lot of it
through mugs that they're totally
covered with mud,
but the problem with that is mud as
water and still water is super bad.
People get that mud in their mouth and
they get the pathogens shouldn't mud and
they just get a broken fire hydrant for
an asshole.
Okay.
Bodies like just.
We're just getting rid of this whole
machinery out.
It's like spring cleaning with a carpet
cleaner.
It does look fun like the I think the
running and you know what I mean,
like this is the month.
Oh these people are fucking maniac.
Told them this diarrhea.
Well they learn.
They learn.
I mean some people just really into it
and they keep their mouth shut.
They know how to do it or keep their
mouth closed and they don't.
They don't breathe it in,
but when they,
when you see them running through it,
it's like,
like they have all the.
What do you.
Yeah,
this is just people waiting dude.
But yeah,
I think this is an actual.
This is just people walking.
There's,
there's some where you see them running
and doing all this stuff.
This is just a bunch of people walking
through a swamp,
get your life,
but if you do that crawl like sometimes
you have to crawl under stuff too.
I guess that's when you can get it in
your mouth.
The stupid sorry kind of things people
do when it's so easy to get food.
That's what's that disease or he heard
from him.
18 gender pronouns in Somalia and
guarantee fucking races.
Gender phobic.
Look at this fucking maniacs.
Yep.
Waiting for.
Or most of these,
you know that question.
A tough couple of miles.
Some of them are about a mile in,
but tweak some of these obstacles so
it's like six,
seven miles,
six,
seven miles.
They're literally,
they made mud for them to play in like
33,
but this is a setup like they make all
this.
This is so goofy.
Sorry folks.
If you're listening,
you want to try it.
Maybe I.
Maybe I don't want fucking pathogens.
The giardia and they didn't take.
Take that muskrat shIt.
This is real.
This is a real hate mail episode.
We always bring the gender stuff this
time.
Not real gender stuff though.
No,
no,
no fake stuff.
No,
not the legit people.
They're like,
dude,
I'm a.
I'm a man.
Trapped in a woman's body obviously.
Right?
But just keep yourself.
Keep your weird shit.
That shit some persons good.
I'm telling you the 19 fifties.
Not all bad.
No,
but you know there was a transgender
people pour in the turn of the century.
Turn of the 20th century.
There's a lot of photos of transgender
people from back then.
it's always been a thing.
I used to see more in hollywood when I
lived there 15 years ago.
I just don't buy the going back and
forth.
Sorry.
I don't think most people do.
I think it's an attention seeking,
uh,
some,
something,
something else is going on there.
I think not all your feelings should be
acknowledged by.
That's important.
I agree.
You like this guy wants to be the six
year old girl.
I mean they have specials on him and now
he's 57 years old.
I can't,
I can't.
TheY don't have specials on him because
her extraordinary story,
they have specials on him because you
know,
it's ridiculous and you're going to
watch it.
Yeah.
It's funny.
It's weird.
Yeah.
You'll look.
You can't go back in time,
right?
You lived a long time.
You have to be responsible.
They have a special on him.
The same reason they have a special and
a lady who doesn't cut her toenails.
Look,
these are my special name.
It's so true and I can't get a job.
They could never get a job.
That's the.
These people are employed.
that is the one common denominator.
What is your,
what do you do for living?
Not anymore.
That's discrimination by the way.
You're discriminating against her guys.
Well,
I've heard people discuss the merits of
the sacred argument where you're not
allowed to cut your hair because of your
religion.
Right?
And I'm like,
well listen,
at the end of the day,
it's just your fucking hair.
And if your religion is about cutting
your hair or not cutting your hair,
I'm sorry,
but it might be bullshit.
Yeah.
Yeah,
you can't.
So if you can't,
you can't just say,
hey,
my hair is getting in the way.
I'm just gonna cut it.
Who says that?
Who says you can.
I know you're talking about your swami
tells you you can't do it.
Is it written somewhere?
What's happening?
You can't just cut your hair and for the
same guy.
No ma'am.
Sacred.
God's going to punish you.
If you eat meat on friday.
Older you get the more absurd,
the religious,
um,
you know,
customs and,
and yamaka.
So all the,
all the,
all the prints off the meeting,
that meat eating anD the wash stuff over
here,
like all that we have in our rental
house.
Not because we have some.
A couple of shoots.
Yeah,
it's all.
It's all kosher kitchen.
It's fine.
I support fully that if you don't want
to ever cut your hair again,
you should be able to not cut your hair
again.
If you want to grow your hair crazy law
and grow your beard crazy long.
Yeah.
My problem is if you think a dad wants
you to do that,
I think that there's some mystical guy.
If you just say,
you know what?
I just like it getting crazy,
crazy,
crazy asshole hair.
I just liked being hairy,
man.
I liked the feeling like,
okay,
upset.
Nobody fucks with rick rubin.
Right,
right.
Rick rubin,
just let's go.
Let's all go to the hair on top.
All,
all fucked up.
The beards all fucked up for jag.
A rolls royce crazier.
You look and then you have like a
fucking car and he's a handsome fella.
And he thought that shit just decides
that says,
look,
his fucking full on crazy hair.
You're not so far.
I feel like you're almost there.
You could let that go.
Why don't you see if,
um,
I think though as a comic,
you're better off without that kind of
thing.
So.
And you're marrIed to that look,
right?
Well,
what's that guy's name?
He's at the store though sometimes he
has quite a look.
You know,
I'm talking about.
He's like,
he was a cab driver.
He holds his coat over his,
over his arm or his.
No.
And he's got all the notes.
Triply london.
J.london.
Yeah.
Look,
that's a look.
I know what I'm saying.
Like rick rubin,
rick rubin,
and a rolls royce.
Because I've seen several.
It's just funny thing.
Funny about a guy who looks like a
homeless guy or like crazy la street guy
favorite and they're just gazillionaires
and you'd never know it.
And the nla,
anybody that walks into a store or
restaurant that looks fucking homeless
could be worth $500,000,000,
I think.
Like she would.
Sikhs.
Sikhs aren't allowed to cut their hair.
Remarkably cool people.
I've met a lot of them,
especially in toronto.
There's a big sikh population in
toronto.
Sure,
some of the nicest,
coolest people,
but they just have that thing that's so
you could say,
well,
yeah,
I mean he believes that a dad wants him
to do,
but another thing you would say,
well maybe it identifies you with this
group of people and you feel like
outsiders and you feel like if you grow
your hair and wear it wrapped up like
that,
like you feel like you fit in with that
group with your group.
Since I grew up in la with a bunch of
seed kids,
made fun of them.
Just call them onion heads or whatever
and it was fucked up for them is what
I'm saying,
because then you get singled out and
fucked with by.
Your wife doesn't want you to,
you know,
get teased.
Relentless.
That's your point.
That's my point.
He didn't want you to be bullied.
Look at that article.
The white and jewish men that run rap.
Oh,
that's hilarious.
The one major record companies.
Yeah.
Well,
no,
but he's dressed like a dude who lives
in seattle,
jacl.
What's what's in his hand?
It looks like a.
So that is weird bro.
That's a very weird look.
Those prayer beads in front of a private
jet with jay z.
Tracy's got a $25,000
suit on.
Who is that with them seal.
What happened to that dude?
Well,
funny you should ask key member when he
sang recently in public for the first
time in like a million years and it was
really bad.
Oh no,
no.
It wasn't the first time in a million
years.
No,
it wasn't.
I know,
but it wasn't the first time in a
million years.
No,
no,
he just sang.
He sang on the super bowl pregame show.
It wasn't good.
It was terrific.
He's,
he's been.
He didn't,
he never went away.
He left the game.
Not at all.
He's,
he's banging.
What's her name?
Hide the clue to know all your facts on
this or not.
Right.
I don't know shit about celebrities come
on,
but it was a terrible performance.
Do you know like certain songs or
certain musicians like bring you back to
a time in your life with seals?
The first time ever bought a stereo
stereo,
had a buy and I was dating this girl who
was really into music and she told me
you have to get this seal out my work.
Really?
Yeah.
And I had it set up.
I bought an actual stereo for the first
time in my life and I had a one big
speaker to the like I had speakers that
were on stands that got off the floor.
Those are great.
I didn't even have a couch yet and I had
this uh,
this stereo that sounded really good and
I played the cd,
set it all up myself.
I put the wires in the right holes and
pinch them down.
And then,
uh,
I played that cd and where you have like
one big speaker over here,
one over there and you could hear the
sound like moving around back and forth.
And I really appreciated what he was
doing.
Like,
I'd never heard it before and anything
but like shitty car stereos with like
blown speakers,
you know,
talented dude for sure.
And when we were talking about earlier,
you made a good point about that song
whenever I got like,
dad's like that song.
Yeah.
Everyone likes that song.
There's dads even with their fat gut,
we're driving electric golf course or
they want to pretend they're still going
to get a little crazy.
My whole family with everybody and mike
can just go to this place.
Just I have a switch that switch goes.
I don't even know.
You know,
you have to wake me up after it's over,
you know,
a free.
My dad definitely probably just had that
on a loop,
you know,
just like,
of course your dad liked it.
No,
my dad liked prodigy a lot.
Like he would get ripped and just play
that through the house,
like on the file.
So horrible.
Oh yeah.
I hated it.
You remember that one?
Drank too much.
Crazy song.
That was like a big one too that
everybody would crank in their car was a
seal one.
No,
no,
no dad's song.
You mean to go there?
Isn't lost my mind.
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Hold on that special time.
How's that go kind of thing.
Cielo cielo.
Before the ecstasy charge.
Charles barkley cielo is.
Fuck you barkley with swift danger
mouse.
It's like a.
Alright,
so cielo is a singer.
Oh,
he's in.
It was a dude that is a universally
loved song till people love to think I'm
just crazy.
The andre andre 3000 song.
What was that?
Hey,
a lot of dads can get into it.
You know,
it's not just for the kids,
right?
Yeah,
that's true.
Like outcast.
That's for the kids,
but that song that's going to listen to
ads only.
It's like jazz sophisticated.
Yeah.
It's like,
no,
I like black kids music.
Kids listening to.
I was listening to this rap song where
they were talking.
This guy was trying to romance this
girl.
He was talking about playing chess with
her and eating organic food and
listening to jazz in the song.
Yeah.
In a rap song trying to romance this
girl organic vegan.
You know what song I was listening?
I was watching an episode of glee.
I don't know why.
No,
I know I'm becoming horribly lame.
And they played that song.
The thong song she had dumped like a
tribe track track.
She took dumps like a truck.
No dumps like a truck.
Like her ass is like a dump truck.
Dumper.
Dumps like a truck.
I know that her dumps or her just trying
to make things run more.
You look into it,
they'll fuck you up.
Cisco,
we can't go down the rabbit hole.
There's the thong song.
Cisco.
How long ago was this made that James
Brown was a baby?
Yeah.
Cisco had a gang of buses.
What's he doing now?
Look at these gullies buses.
He says five buses pull up.
They say cisco on them.
I want everything.
White dong.
Dong dong.
There you go.
Yeah,
he's still there.
You go.
Hey tommy,
you fucking got me on the gucci mane.
You son of a bitch.
I was listening to gucci mane,
some new gucci mane thing the other
night.
I'm like,
he wrote that five minutes ago.
He wrote that on cough syrup five
minutes ago,
straight out the fed.
Met first day of the fence.
You got a new app,
new album.
He lost a lot of weight in prison.
You notice that?
Yeah.
He's got a six pack now.
He really lost a lot.
Yeah.
He has a ice cream cone on his face.
Burn burn wIth a lightning bolts.
That's hilarious.
She doesn't play man.
Young thug and gucci mane.
His young protege.
Young thug.
He's a little bit of.
I don't know.
I wouldn't call them fluid gender.
I'm not going to say that,
but he's a fashion designer.
He was first of all,
gender fluid.
God,
you are going to miss gender.
Gender id on my jeans were a little
whack.
Tommy likes standing out.
Let's not.
Let's not light denim.
Denim with you.
Would like though from from before,
before he got locked up the lemonade
song.
Oh,
I've heard that.
Be like,
yeah,
that's a catchy.
So I mean dad's can listen to it.
How'd it go?
How can,
how does it go?
We're being invaded.
How's it going?
It goes next door.
Neighbors alarms going off.
Oh,
is it called the purge?
Yes.
The purge have a sandWich.
Sorry.
How does that song go?
Sing your lemonade lemonade.
Yellow,
yellow,
yellow birds.
Yellow diamonds in my head.
Yellow,
yellow,
yellow.
That's good.
That's how it starts.
So I think maybe he makes things.
Dun dun dun dun dun dun dun.
You like it negative?
no.
alright,
I'll play it for you.
That somebody likes it though.
Lots of people.
That song's catchy.
Actually.
I'm the minority here.
I cut it from youtube.
Yeah,
he's cutting it off of youtube so we
won't get pulled from youtube so people
can hear this on.
So you get a yellow,
yellow like gold,
right?
Like money for awhile.
Yeah.
Okay.
It's the melody.
Yeah.
It sounds good though.
It seems like he's having a good time.
How big he is there?
He definitely had more body fat.
Probably do our pushups in the house.
Yeah.
Then you got to eat and up focused.
Probably wrote some good shit.
And this is all pre tattoo to.
Yeah,
we had a few then though,
but not on the face baby.
He's got my favorite all time saying to
a judge,
mr jermaine,
are you guilty?
He goes,
bitch,
I might be right.
He said that.
No,
he said that.
I thought that was funny.
Gucci mane did not want him.
Might be it's hoax.
Why did you ruin it for me?
Dark.
Damn dude.
I'm sorry.
I know jamie.
Keeping the dark.
Keeping in the dark on things that are
too good,
bitch.
I might be his greatest thing ever.
Say that to a judge.
Gender.
No fucker.
Sorry.
I was talking to jamie privileged.
Jamie,
you are so privileged.
Guilty bitch.
I might be.
Come on.
Be one of the greatest things that
anybody could say ever.
Disrespect guys.
Nineteen fifties.
There's some great videos.
By the way,
if you're ever bored.
I don't know if you ever looked up on
youtube.
Judges handling,
um,
people acting out of line at sentencing
thing.
It's incredible.
Yeah.
Have you ever seen the one where the
girl.
Yeah.
Is like a.
She said something in spanish to this
cuban
judge in miami.
He's like,
he has a really heavy accent.
oh,
I remember you ever seen that?
It's unbelievable.
This is it.
That's it right there.
It's unbelievable,
man.
And you flipped.
She flipped the bird to the judge.
She,
unless she says something in spanish to
be cheeky to him.
And then he's like,
going back here.
what did you say?
And she's like,
oh,
I said like one of the ears.
And he gives her like an extra 30 days
and then she's like,
gives flicks them off walk.
He's like,
come back again.
And he gives her like an extra 90 days.
Whoa.
She thinks she cute.
That's why,
you know what I'm saying?
She was pretty.
She was like laughing and stuff.
Yeah.
He,
he fucking rushes her.
Isn't that interesting?
That it's a,
the judge's discretion?
Yeah.
Can do that.
How weird is that?
That shouldn't be the case.
Shouldn't be like you're punishing her
because she's being disrespectful to you
or to the court itself.
To both.
I think that you have to respect the
court.
Did you see what they did to that
Alabama judge know he.
There was.
Oh yeah.
Here we will get yanked yogi.
Want to hear what he says to say to her?
It has no sound.
Oh really?
Oh,
oh.
It was probably like the courtroom
camera.
St.
Actual courtroom can come back.
Tomal did the backyard.
She's laughing and smiling.
Funny how people when they're in a
position like that,
you're caught like you're in court and
they have all the power.
You want to pretend like you don't give
a fuck.
No,
I'd give a lot of fuck.
If I were in front of a judge,
I'd be very,
very respectful and scared.
She just flipped him off.
Yeah.
Now he's angry.
Oh yeah.
that's amazing that he can just do that.
It's kind of amazing because that's
almost too much power.
Like I understand that you are violating
the court,
but should it really be up to the judge
to arbitrarily decide to give you 30
more days or 90 more days or whatever
they give you shouldn't really be up to
him.
I mean maybe there's a rule,
like if you say the f word or if you
give someone the finger,
you get an automatic,
like whatever.
Oh,
but then they'd be able to pick rule.
I don't know.
Maybe it is.
Maybe that's contempt of court,
isn't it?
Guys?
I went to law school for two weeks and
contempt of court to,
uh,
to be disrespectful.
Right?
Yeah,
for sure.
You're not supposed to flIp off a judge.
You're supposed to dress a certaIn way.
I mean,
obviously the jumpsuit thing is its own
thing,
but like,
yeah,
you're supposed to respect the court.
The judge was,
she had to wear the jumpsuit,
but do you,
um,
do you think that the judge can just
decide how many days he gives you?
I mean,
there's got to be a limit to it.
Like you can't be set to for contempt,
but shit,
he look at that curses.
Judge gets a year.
Wow.
Chris judge judges 364 days in jail for
contempt.
Oh,
well he's domestic violence asshole.
I just don't know what the rules
are.
Like what a judge can do and I don't
know either,
but the sentencing is sending sings a
weird thing.
They have minimums were certain things
like murder and armed robbery crimes.
there's probably,
there's got to be parameters for.
They're always like,
oh,
this judge particularly is lenient on
this and that matter.
Like you,
you almost want to choose your judge and
you choose your jurors.
The attorneys do based on.
Okay,
so I didn't really go to law school for
two weeks and we did learn about jury
selection and the key is you do want to
get,
and this is horrible,
but usually like the dumbest people,
like you want to have people that are
really,
you know,
I'm easily persuaded to whatever your
cause and a judge to that is favorable
for liberal if they're whatever,
you know,
you could guess based on their,
the precedence.
Yeah,
man.
Yeah.
It's very fluid.
Geez,
tom.
She's doing all right.
I mean freaking us out so quick.
A lot of water.
No,
no you don't.
That's the first time you've cracked it
open.
What are you guys fighting?
I hydrate a lot more than he does.
Oh,
is this an issue?
It's not close.
You hydrate more than.
Of course I've been hydrating this whole
time.
Interesting.
Uh,
but he has that drink too.
That's not this hydration.
Much smaller.
Smaller being.
I weigh like a fraction of when he was
very tiny and petite.
Oh geez.
Look at my uh,
moniker,
dad mouth,
but look at water.
Use the water champion.
Is that what you tell people that I'm
clearly the water champion.
We decided this.
I got,
I got to do a full new show.
A lot of times you have to go.
You're doing like eight minutes.
I did the entire blog.
I did the weather and everything.
All his dj dad mouth.
Every what?
What city was this in?
Des moines.
Really happy were there.
They were just,
oh my god.
What are you doing in des moines?
I was,
I was there.
I did two nights.
Just said the funny bone.
Is it fun?
Yeah.
I had a really good time.
Really good time.
Did you come up with this dj dad mouth
thing?
Just like it was at a specific,
like,
like a plan or did you do it like for
fun?
For fun?
Totally for fun.
Just to shoot one day and then we just
tell joe the whole story when I was
eight months pregnant and he's like,
I'm going to buy like a ton of dj
equipment.
I'm like,
wait,
what are you doing?
He's like,
I'm buy like $10,000
where the shit in our house,
and I was like,
all right,
this is your.
I clearly knew this is his last hurrah
as a free person,
so I try not to give them too much
static and then sure enough all was
deejaying stuff shows up.
NoT 10 grand.
You got decks and fucking lights and
lasers and peter.
Yeah,
he's got a lot.
He's,
well,
he's a real dj.
He does.
He goes to clubs.
You can do it.
He doesn't know.
He does.
Yes he does.
Yes.
What's her face?
Because I was like,
I'll get good enough at this to do after
parties after my shows.
Were you serious?
I was half serious.
Yeah,
because I was like,
you know whaT,
like,
because I,
you know,
I,
I've,
I love hip hop.
I've always grown up and I always wanted
to do it.
So I got the,
I got like,
you know,
internet.
I'm not,
not tent that.
Not even 5,000,
like,
not even close to that.
I just bought turntables and got her
jacket.
It's gold chains.
No,
but come on.
That shit was just silly to get,
you know,
you were a dj today and you were trying
to spend turntables,
don't you think people would be asking
to take selfies in the middle of it and
it would fuck up your flow if I was
deejaying and if you were like doing an
after party,
people have tried to take selfies with
you.
I'm in the middle.
I'd be up there on facebook.
You've probably right?
Yeah,
for sure.
They would have to be honest,
who really gave me the idea idea where I
was like,
oh,
like this is actually possible was
hannibal,
because I was in cleveland earlier this
year and I saw him tweet that he was in
cleveland doing a pop up show.
Right.
He just tweeted out and doing like a
whatever,
like a rock club pop up show.
No advanced notice.
So I texted him.
I was like,
I'm over at hilaritY that great club in
cleveland.
Uh,
when is your show?
He said,
like,
nine.
I go,
mine's at eight.
You want to do a guest spot?
And he goes,
yeah.
So then afterwards he had an after party
at the uh,
and I,
and that's me basically geeking out on
the decks.
Yeah.
So,
and then tony trim,
which is a dj that travels with him was
like,
oh,
did you can just get this and you can
just buy this stuff.
And,
and,
and that's what really got me to do it
was cro one up,
let's look at that white guy dance,
move that move.
you're doing there.
You're doing thiS.
Yeah,
that's true.
That's what really geeked me out was the
dj dad math came because he was becoming
a father at the time and was a dad and
then it kind of morphed into dj dan.
That's true.
All that's true.
But taking it onto morning news was like
a one time goof.
Funny.
That was so fun and I was like all the
time,
you know.
So when you went on as a onetime goof,
did you have a plan or did you just
really.
What'd you do?
I was just like,
the fun thing was to go was because I,
the thing that I hate the most when you
do that,
they're like,
what can audiences expect this weekend?
They always say that,
oh,
I hate that.
And I'm like,
oh,
fucking show jokes.
Um,
what do you talk about?
Yeah.
What's,
what's,
what's bothering you right now?
Tom?
Yeah,
that's the setup.
Tell What's going on in your life and
they think you're going to like.
And then they go,
just do whatever you want.
Like just have fun with it.
So when they do that,
I was just like,
it's not really,
I don't really give a fuck about comedy.
And then they're like,
what?
I'm like,
it's about the after party,
you know,
I'm going to be deejaying here just to
goof off because it was fun to have
around and be like,
all right,
you are at the funny bone.
Right?
I'm like,
I mean for a minute,
I don't even really care about it.
The funny bone.
And then you have the funny bone sitting
right there off camera.
Like who cares?
Like the best part is when he sets up
like the really cheesy anchors to ask
him stupid questions.
Like,
did you,
oh,
you had someone do the bird is fat
thing.
That was the best one because you know,
if you ever add sometimes when you go,
hey,
um,
you know,
asked me about farts or something,
they'll be like,
like,
so they,
they know not to.
They check themselves on asking
something provocative or that's not 100
percent pg.
So I didn't know how it go,
but I go,
oh,
ask me what bird.
So fat.
And the lady goes,
okay,
and then so we just are in the middle of
this interview.
She goes,
white bird,
so fat.
Then I was asked a good question and I'm
like,
I just rolled with it,
you know,
and then it grew.
And then a hot dog eating champion,
a guy that was in scotland,
she placed tinny place.
Yeah.
He's like one of the.
He was like a super competitive eater,
like a kobiashi dude.
This guy was probably the audio on this.
It's incredible
life changing stuff dropped about 100
pounds in eight months.
He dropped 100 pounds my cheat day for
the year,
but prepping just this amazing water to
giant inspiration.
So first my wife,
it's our second anniversary today,
so I want to say hi to her.
And um,
there's a comedian I love.
He's a big,
giant,
fat guy just like me.
Bert chrysler,
he's still way bigger than I am.
Maybe I can inspire him.
There you go.
Now are is funny.
This is why it's funny.
Tom and bert had been doing this thing
for a fucking year.
Now tom will write to the hashtag burn
fat and then bert will right thomas fat.
And then they'll argue they make videos
with their shirts off,
arguing who's fatter.
Yeah,
it was fun.
It's actually,
you know,
it's died down a lot,
but like the fact that that guy did,
he did it on his own,
which is a picture of you up.
Yeah.
I see.
Hashtag burn as fast talk about you.
If I tweet about you hashtag birds that
took off.
We didn't,
like we talked about on your mom's
house,
but we never thought we'd do all kinds
of silly stuff,
but this one really resonated with the
audience.
Why did that one really resonate?
Um,
you know what?
There was,
there was great theories about this and
I think it was this.
I think matt full trump pointed out to
me the full charge said,
um,
you gave them the formula,
you gave audiences a joke formula.
Here's a person.
It's a fat joke.
Go,
go ahead.
And I think that was what was fun for
people to jump in on something that it's
all,
like the formula is there to pick a
side.
That's the
competitive nature of it.
Yeah.
And they know that you guys really are
good friends.
Some did,
some did not.
I would say most,
most people did.
Most people did.
Some people get mad.
Oh yeah.
Some people were like really fucking
really harsh and really like,
fuck,
I've always fucking hated burgs a piece
of like,
you're like,
whoa,
like shit like that.
But it wasn't the majority.
Some people were like that though.
Yeah.
Same thing to me.
I'll tape some people were like,
you know,
it's one of my theories about this trump
thing.
I think people just pick a fucking side
and that side represents the battle.
Yeah.
And it doesn't have to make any sense,
right?
If you like,
whatever fact you bring about like,
I don't care.
One of the things that I like,
if I post something about hillary,
like some,
I get so many people just get so fucking
upset.
I'm like,
look,
it doesn't take away from like one guy
was saying that,
um,
that uh,
the,
uh,
there's a bunch of different ones,
but there was one recently.
I'm a wiki leaks,
one that came out today.
We're a wiki.
Leaks is saying that she,
uh,
she said she asked about julian assange
whether they could just drone this guy.
She's like,
which is kind of funny.
Like I get it.
She's saying he's just thumbing his nose
up in America.
I can't,
we just drone this guy.
Who knows where she really centered.
Right,
right.
But the problem is if,
if somebody tweets it,
the people that support hillary don't
go,
whoa,
that's kind of interesting.
They go,
oh,
you fucking.
You think that you really mean that.
Where's your.
Where's your proof?
Like we're like,
all of a sudden they're defending their
side.
They're defending that person like
they're so emotionally invested in her
winning over trump that instead of
going,
whoa,
did she really say that?
Right?
Let's check the story out or in as a
human being just going,
what do you think she meant?
Do you think is a joke or crazy,
or do you think this is what they really
do?
And then it starts.
You start thinking about some of the
things that have taken place like that
fucking kid who leaked the emails to the
dnc and wound up getting shot at 4:00
in the morning and the back in front of
his house.
You know that story,
right?
I don't know.
No,
no.
This is a kid who,
4:00
in the morning,
this is a guy who leaked the emails that
showed that they collaborated to get
hillary elected over.
Bernie sanders makes sure that she got
the nomination.
I mean,
they literally distorted they distorted
democracy,
like the democratic national campaign
was working to try to get hillary
elected over him because bernie sanders
is not really a democrat.
He's like more of an independent,
you know,
and like he doesn't play like party line
games and they had decided pretty early
on they were going to support her.
So it's not like the democratic national
committee has just,
just being completely objective and just
doing their best.
He was murdered,
hence murdered dc staffer was email
leaker offers $20,000
reward for info.
Yeah.
This is a crazy story.
It's a crazy story.
I mean if that is what happened and they
decided to have someone kill that kid,
that kid is the one that leaked that.
Exactly.
But here's the thing,
it worked.
It not only he's that he's,
but no one's talking about it anymore.
It's just one of those things you just
kind of went away.
I don't know what happened.
I mean,
he might have just been kiLled in some
random act of violence because he was in
a bad place at the wrong time,
or some of them have fucking killed him
like that might've happened to if he
really did leak.
Those emails like that is nuts.
It's a movie a movie.
Sure is,
and in this case,
create crazy chaotic election.
Nobody has any time for that.
There's too many other things you have
to be thinking about is a million
different things going on at the same
time.
Yeah.
It really makes you like those picking
sides.
Things to always makes you realize.
I think that that elections are decided
by either side.
It really is decided by that person that
can be swayed.
It's such a small,
weird thing.
you know,
you're never going to sway the left.
The far left or the far right.
It's all about the person who was like,
who is the undecided?
Like are you really?
Those are two polar,
in my opinion,
opposite people,
trump and hillary.
It's like,
how are you on the fence if they're
don't understand the way they're
thinking.
They're so polar.
It's a joke,
it's a cartoon they have male and
feminine,
nor the noise of all the news stuff and
the conversations you really got to be
like,
what's the policy on this?
And then I guess some people are,
are actually caught up,
you know,
thinking like an actual,
like the drama of it all and the
personality,
the drama.
If you're,
if you're one of those people that's
actually going back and forth,
right.
You have just eat neither or
our ideal.
And anybody who pretends that either or
are our ideal is crazy.
Yeah.
No.
So I get you want to stop trump because
you think he represents everything
that's wrong in the world.
Well,
to some people,
hillary represents everything that's
wrong in politics.
Some people have a problem with that
too,
right?
It's just the whole thing is,
it's just,
it's a weird sort of a social studY as
much as it is an election year.
You're watching this team thing play out
is very strange way.
Yeah.
Oh,
I don't know.
I,
I don't know either.
And I mean there are,
who do you think's gonna win.
that's the thing.
See,
that's the thing,
it's like,
who do you think's gonna win?
I don't know.
I'm thinking.
I think people will pick a side,
they'll pick a side,
whether it's democrat or republican,
they'll pick aside at some point in
their life and then just start accepting
stuff to stay on the team going with
stuff that goes that way and you know,
I mean there's like some ridiculous like
super ultra sensitive leftwing stuff
that I think is preposterous and then
there's some ridiculous,
right?
We're super conservative,
ultra religious stuff that I think is
preposterous and you could only be one
or the other.
Like if you're a republican,
you have to believe in god and you have
to be conservative and you have to
right.
The party.
What the party is now is completely
different than what it was the eighties
when reagan was chillin and everyone was
happy.
The eighties is when they courted the
religious right.
That's how they made it.
The religious right in the eighties.
Those religious people are a big part of
the reason why reagan got elected in the
first place because they organize those
church people organized like they all
supported him because you know he was
supporting christian values.
There was much more of a separation of
church and state in the earLier years of
the government.
Yeah.
I feel well,
I feel like thIs year's election is in
our lifetime or my lifetime is the most.
Like the votes are based on the.
The hatred of the other candIdate,
more so than supporting the candidate in
some ways,
but some peopLe love trumP.
They fucking love a man.
They love the idea thAt this guy is
gonna.
Come in and just shake it up,
shake it up,
shake it up with all kinds of stupid.
That's the dumbest fucking guy.
It's absurd.
That debate the other night was insane.
I saw people that I like who said that
he won the debate,
so yeah,
dave rubin said it.
Dave ruben said he thinks that he thinks
that overall trump Won.
Maybe the beginning was just brutal.
I missed the beginning.
Yeah.
Did you see the beginning?
No,
not either.
I only saw the end when he was just
stumbling.
Said he has a winning temperament and
she found him.
She's called the winning temperament
thing,
was such a like a childish temper
tantrum.
While it's so weird because he turns it
around like the question was,
did you say that hillary doesn't have
the right look to be president,
and he was the look,
the stamina.
She doesn't have a winning temperament.
I have a winning temperament.
He turns it around on himself Because he
knows that the big knock,
so he's getting defensive that that was,
that was,
that was bait,
but that he couldn't ignore because the
big knock had been.
Well,
one of the bIg knocks was like,
well,
you don't have the temperament because
he's.
He's very thin skinned.
Right?
Like anybody tweet something,
adam,
he fights,
you know,
you guys,
all the insults.
That's because his temperament,
that doesn't seem presidential,
but he's a winning temperament.
That's the spin spin,
but it just shows how much he absorbed
all that stuff and was defensive about
it.
Yeah,
yeah.
No,
it was very defensive.
Also the presidential,
yet he gets very,
like,
doesn't really get away,
but it's one of those things that his
supporters ignore was how often,
you know,
he just goes like bronc,
like he was wrong.
That's not never said that.
And it's all stuff that he did say.
Yeah.
And they just go like,
well who cares?
You just some part of the tax thing came
out that he put how much money?
Nine hundred and $15,000,000
in losses.
So they didn't have to pay taxes for a
long time.
Eighteen years,
18 years,
no taxes really.
Well,
he said that he basically,
it's legal.
What you,
what they're saying might be the reason
why he hasn't wanted to release his tax
returns is that that level of loss would
allow him to not taxes on
essentially $50 million in income.
No federal taxes for about 20 years.
But they're saying,
you know,
that's why the reluctance to probably
cause once that's out there,
even though you didn't break a law,
that's,
you know.
Well it also crushes the illusion that
he's a successful businessman of course
course.
Yeah.
That you don't lose $950,
million dollars or whatever it was.
If you're doing great.
Yeah,
that's just a fact.
He's filed bankruptcy,
personal bankruptcy,
but a couple of times.
A few times.
Yeah,
but it was weird when he was talking on
the debate and hillary brought that up
and he goes,
it's because I'm smart.
Yeah.
Like,
I'm smart.
I don't pay taxes because I'm smart.
You're running for our phone.
Like people who have paid taxes only
make like 40 grand a year.
they're not going to want to hear that.
Right.
President camacho,
man.
We might get them to the prophecy of
idiocracy ways that you think is going
to happen next because this is what's
fascinating to me.
It's like once we get through him.
Okay.
And whether or not he.
I don't think he can win at this point,
but I've been wrong before.
yeah.
People,
no trump fans are getting better.
Again,
this is the hate mail episodes.
It was,
hey,
let's say if he wins,
it's going to be very fascinating for
us.
Yeah.
Which is going to be mad.
You know what it's going to be like.
It's like,
have you ever done like a um,
when I was living in New York,
there was an inside joke with comedians
that like,
if you were all a bunch of starters,
you just started out and there was a
black comic that plot,
that comic would always want to go on
last.
LIke,
no man,
I was told I was supposed to headline,
but if it was a black guy with two other
black guys,
he always wanted to go on first.
Oh,
right,
right.
You do all the white people since my
trial.
A bunch at hacky shit.
Like when auction auction jokes.
Yeah.
If trump becomes president,
we will all be that hacky urban.
Right.
We're just,
you'll be so much shoes.
You will,
you want to go on stage early because
you don't want to go on after everybody
beats the trump material in the ground.
It's so true.
You hair stuff,
your hair jokes,
all the crazy shit he's going to say,
yeah.
All the dumb shit he's going to do it.
You know,
I get the feeling that he doesn't really
want to be president.
I don't think so either.
He just likes the attention.
He's a bit of a megalomaniac.
he likes people talking about him,
but it's so well,
okay.
Let's saY he gets elected.
I really don't see him doing.
What's the motivation?
So was just going to be in the headLines
now and he wants to be referred to as
mr.
President.
I think he's.
Do you think that once you get in
though,
I mean once,
once he's in there,
maybe he's not going to want to let it
go though.
Maybe he's going to actually try to make
a mark,
you know,
make,
do some stupid shit.
I feel like that his,
his favorite,
his perfect scenario.
I don't think you would ever want to
give up running his businesses.
I think he loves it.
He loves his lifestyle.
I don't think he wants to be tied to the
white house.
I think his dream scenario is that this
is a close race and then he goes like,
I basically should have won.
this was pretty much rigged and it
should be another vote count.
Well,
he was saying that about the debate.
Yeah.
He was a real deal.
Rigged deal.
He said that about one of the.
I'm one of those,
uh,
what's it called during when there were
more candidates in the republican
primaries?
He lost one state and like the day or
two after he was like,
I think I won.
He lost like Iowa or something.
He was mad.
they got one that didn't want to give it
to even do like,
what does he want?
It's just so amazing that he's this
close.
It's so amazing and he's the nominee.
It's so embarrassing.
Republican's embarrassing for all of
this stuff.
Columbus,
where this happened,
where as we were leaving a somewhat
random janitor found all these black
ballot boxes in a warehouse.
They're already filled out for a bunch
of franklin county,
like different places in hillary
clinton's marked and all of them was
just came out yesterday and I was
looking at.
I was like,
ah,
I don't know how,
but I'm seeing it on a bunch of news
sites right now being looked into right
now.
What?
What website is this ad from?
Pamela geller.com,
but when I was pamela geller,
I have no idea.
I just clicked on the one.
The first one I saw,
but this was like the local nbc station
was reported as donald trump's nice
snopes reporters.
It was false,
but it's on a bunch of sites right now,
so it might not be true.
Yeah,
sorry,
I brought that up.
Just the damage.
Origin.
See there,
look at this be weird christian times
newspaper and article reporting.
Tens of thousand.
It's fake dude.
How dare you.
Jamie?
Ballot box.
Yeah.
Clinton ballot boxes.
I know.
It's like.
It's not only that,
it's not.
If you look at some of them,
the way it was looked like there was
photo shopped on parallel with the box
itself.
Okay,
leT's get rid of this chair.
this is fake,
but it's happened.
I'm sure they've done it before.
You know,
I'm sure someone has written.
You ever see hacking democracy?
No.
Hacking democracy's great.
It's a,
it was an hbo documentary on those
machines.
The diebold machines.
This is the hanging Chad.
No,
they rig the machines.
The machines were rigged so that they
could have a third party enter data,
so like not just you,
not the person who counts,
but a third person enters data to
change,
change the votes,
the machines,
the machines.
Machines were 100 percent hackable and
they had designed them to be savable.
They designed them to have third party
input and they showed on the,
in the hacking democracy.
The guY got into the thing and changed
the vote.
He like changed a vote,
like a demonstrated it to them and then
they were sitting there going,
what the fuck?
Like why did and not only that,
the guy who made those machines or the
company who made those machines was a
gigantic supporter of the republican
party.
And this is when during the bush
administration.
Yeah,
I mean they changed their name.
The company diebold,
they have this.
They had a switch their name.
They switched their name.
They don't.
They also make atm.
Now I'm now just getting people elected.
You make it payments.
It's crazy.
It's crazy how many high ranking
republicans like renounced their.
You know,
their cards and announced that they were
done.
It's a lot.
Well,
here's one I forgot I wanted to bring up
that guy hastert.
I think that's his name.
Who got convicted?
He was sOme big time judge who got
convicted of child molestation.
Oh,
old dennis?
yes.
Dennis hastert,
right?
Wasn't he a senator or congress?
What was he sentenced to?
Fifteen months.
That's It.
Oh my gosh.
Fifteen months.
That's all you get for that.
Yeah,
it was drake structuring bank
transaction.
Scroll back down please.
Illegally structuring bank transactions
and effort to cover up his sexual abuse
of young members of the wrestling team
that he coached decades ago.
What the fuck?
How you only get 15 months for that.
How do you.
How do you view as speaker that?
Yeah.
He was speaker of the house,
rIght?
Yeah.
How the fuck is he?
Old habits.
That might be a part of it.
He's so old.
Shoot him.
He was dead.
Eleven years with those kids all line
up.
Hey look,
go back.
Please listen.
Read this here,
mr hasford 74 who made an unlikely rise
from beloved small town wrestling coach
in Illinois to speaker of the house in
Washington,
sat,
slouched in a wheelchair in a federal
courtroom here as judge announced that
he would be rejecting please for
probation.
He's got to play it hard on mr.
Hazard as well as the prosecutors
endorsement of a shorter prison state.
What do shorter than fIfteen months?
He said,
look at the judge said the defendant is
a serial child molester.
Wow.
Look at this.
Some actions can obliterate a lifetime
of good works.
Nothing is more stunning than having
serial child molester and speaker of the
house in the same sentence that the
judge 15 months is the is the full
sentence for that.
Any ordered him to pay $250,000
in fines.
Even if you paid those kids a thousand
bucks every time you fuck them.
Do you think it was 250 times?
No.
You got off cheap,
you know a job or you fan fan publishers
series of illnesses including his
stroke,
blood stream infection.
So he's sickly and old,
which is,
I bet why they're not giving him the
whole thing.
So I think they should cut his balls off
publicly.
He used a walker to rise to his feet,
but is cox did as he recounted the days
when he would molest young wrestlers as
a high school wrestler.
I looked up to coach hastert.
He was a key figure in my life.
Said mr.
Cross now 53 and a businessman who works
in the financial services in the chicago
area from a podium just feet from mr
hasford wheelchair.
Mr krause recalled abuse that occurred
on a locker room training table when he
was 17.
I felt intense shame and guilt.
Holy shit.
Let a piece of shit.
This guy got away with it for so long.
Raping little kids.
Wow.
It's just amazing that that relationship
that he had as a speaker of the house
allowed them knowing it.
Fifteen months should be in jail for
life.
And he got,
by the way,
so many.
The judge received so many letters about
what an awesome guy and all the awesome
things that he did.
Oh my people.
Just wanting,
everybody was,
you know,
I mean high ranking people were like,
he's done amazing work.
That must mean that he knows something.
They must have helped him because he
knows something.
They must have been one of those things
where I look,
if I go to jail fucked.
You write that fucking letter.
Yeah.
Who else stands up ever paternal.
Right.
That whole shit was going down with san
dusty.
Even paternal was like,
ah,
I don't know shit.
What the fuck?
everybody backed away from sandusky.
Nobody's stood up first.
Of course.
Wow.
Right now I heard on the news this week
and there's someone,
a doctor who used to work for the usa
olympic team and like the gymnast.
Yeah.
He's been accused of.
I don't want to like I can tell you what
their sexual abuse allegations digitally
inserting girls to no gloves on and
thought,
oh jesus,
he's going in their pussy to correct
their back.
That's what he was saying he was doing
on trips with no parents around and
whatnot.
Oh my god.
I learned that technique years ago,
but I didn't know that it was the wife
of a straight posture.
I did notice that maybe the three digit
technique it's held.
Yeah.
just threatened with the pinky,
right?
Yup.
Shoulders back.
What the fuck man?
Oh my god.
Dude.
That's scary stuff.
Did you hear about kim kardashian
getting held up at like tied up and tied
up?
Gagged.
Terrible.
Man.
That is terrible.
Scary shit.
And the guys were dressed up as cop.
This is a really well planned robbery.
That's terrifying.
Yeah.
$9,000,000
in jewelry.
They had $9,000,000
in jewelry on them.
Jewelry.
That's incredible.
Yeah.
I heard that he was performing in the
middle of a song.
Cut is somebody ran on stage and told
him.
He said there was a family emergency and
took off.
When You say him,
you mean kanye west?
Yes.
Most people don't know yeezy is who I
was talking about.
What the fuck?
Jesus.
How scary.
That must be someone robbing you.
Imagine how $9,000,000
of jewelry on youtube you have flew
internationally with.
Yeah.
You have a dope house on you.
No,
that's a dope house.
And you're flossing it everywhere you
go.
Yeah.
9 million.
The amount of money they make the.
I read something about her,
her app,
the amount of money that she makes us
some app.
It's absurd.
It's like $50,000,000
a month or something.
Something?
Yeah,
50 or $80 million a year as what I saw.
Yeah.
Well I might've made up some numbers,
but that's still an outrageous amount of
money.
It's incredible for to play a game where
you're like,
I'm kim and buying a purse or something.
She got robbed at gunpoint.
Paris.
Paris seems like a dangerous functions
part.
Shit keeps going down in paris.
yeah.
It keeps going down.
Charlie hebdo and the nightclub shooting
thing.
Yeah.
Nice.
France like France itself.
France was the,
the,
the truck that drove over all those
peoples.
Kk got robbed.
magical.
Went up a kid today.
These your.
Yeah.
Brought in $100,000,000
since the launch.
Jesus.
I think what she went through is
absolutely terrifying.
That's got to be really,
really horrible.
100 percent.
Do you want to predict what kind of guy
angelina jolie hooks up with?
This is what I do.
This long hair wouldn't beads for sure.
Probably does yoga.
Maybe in the peace corps he's going to
be really poor and um,
and it doesn't care about money and um,
he's like a,
he's more of an activist than,
and it doesn't even act right,
but then she's going to dump him after
he wants to act because once they're
together for awhile it was going to get
some offers to do some stuff.
She's gonna want him to go to a
basketball game.
He has won a couple of public
appearances.
yeah.
That is really spot on.
I think you're,
I think you're really right here and
someone not in the public eye.
Yeah.
Just an unknown guy.
You're like an earthy kind of like raw
cotton shirt.
He sows his own clothing,
you know,
that kind of thing.
yeah.
Kudler did you know that there are
people that are,
they're called cuddle lists and they
cuddle you for money.
He's that guy.
Yeah.
I've heard of that,
but I don't.
I can just come here.
Can you get hard?
What happens?
You got to deal with that.
You used that bomb.
There's just a lot.
Yeah.
Tickling and she does fluctuate though.
So before brad didn't,
wasn't she with billy?
Bob thornton and she used to carry his
blood around in a violent.
Her neck.
Crazy.
She must be in bed.
Oh,
she might go weird again because brad
seemed real normal.
Right.
But go weird again.
She could control that hot guy just
saying which she could control billy bob
shaw.
Like I like this better.
The hot one.
Look at the two of them.
Yeah.
He had a bra.
I like the sunglasses.
It's not like it's night or anything.
Yeah,
keep those on billy.
For sure.
Yeah.
yeah.
She's eaten butthole for sure.
Sure.
Everybody's.
Yeah.
Everybody's should mates.
That's
actually greets you.
She got billy bob tattooed on her way
into that guy.
He's grabbing her tits right there in
front of America.
Probably a whole lot of fun.
Whole lot of crazy.
Yeah.
Next guy.
Yogi like probably wears flip flops a
lot.
Yeah,
totally.
It's got to have some edge to them.
That's what's going to excite or kind of
a little edge and I think she's going to
want to control the guy.
Plus there's the kids,
there's a lot of kids where he's got to
be real into being stepdaddy.
She's like,
what do you,
how you feel about seven kids or with
the crazier move p to never have a
relationship again,
just to dedicate herself to children
from now on,
a character that could be the move that
she might be the move.
Yeah,
and then she goes,
j lo style just gets a bunch of little
boys so fox kicks him out the fuck out
of my house,
but you know,
maybe that's the move.
If I divorced tom,
I might do that.
Why get married again?
You can't.
He's the love of my life.
This would be wham song.
Never gonna dance again.
Just started playing on my speculation
is always fun.
Would you go for the young pretty young,
young things,
the pyt she would go for the big black
guys.
No,
I'm not into the black guys.
You would be after tom.
You guys.
The one thing you'd be like,
I heard that music for so many years,
I want to give it a shot and try them
and then you would like it.
Walk me through the logic though.
Give me the backstory.
Toms was terrified of is just a football
player with a giant hog.
Yeah.
But I kinda,
you know,
I kinda fantasize about it til.
Well that's the thing.
I'm kind of,
I feel like I'm kind of in the room and
I'm like go get it,
get it,
get it man.
Like I'm kinda like,
what'd you want to be in the room?
Like an invisible bubble where they
couldn't hear you and you can just yell
out and,
and he would just jerk off freely and,
or would you want them to know you were
there and just kinda whimper a little
bit.
I kind of fell inside him in the balls
at the same time.
The invisible part would be cool.
But also like if I'm like,
yeah trey like kinda like kind of behind
them,
you know?
And he's like shut up white boy.
Like he's talked some shit and I'm
sorry.
He's like,
does he make you suck his dick or
sometimes they do not make the
motherfucker,
I don't want to go back to fucking the
girl,
but I want a cuckold is that's extreme
cuckold with a racial bias.
I want to do that.
I want to walk up behind like when he's
done and you're like,
oh my god,
you know,
he's like,
he like,
he shakes it off.
He's like,
oh,
like that.
And he's like,
I go,
oh,
I guess it's my turn.
And then he's
like,
nah,
hold on.
And then he's like,
yo.
And then like six guys come in and he's
like,
they got to go first and then like,
what's the,
what's the tagline?
You know how they need a funny line to
wrap up the scene?
Like shaking a paintbrush.
Yeah,
yeah.
I think that moves getting more popular
st.
That's the equivalent of dropping the
mic and for now,
but then he's like in took your wife or
what's the,
wHat's the seal to the button to the
scene and through your writing,
that's what they call black.
Imagine that painter that does that.
What's jackson pollock?
Jackson poLlock.
Bob ross,
no,
jackson pollock's the guy that throws
the pain all over the place.
That's what it would be.
Then he'd be like,
that's my jackson pollock,
the line.
They all do it.
Plop and some dudes have yellow color.
Who's coming as yo.
What the fuck he.
He,
he,
he drops like that.
He goes,
they put that in the getty.
Nailed it.
That's the line.
They definitely could put it in lacma.
Yeah,
that's right.
We saw the robert maplethorpe exhibit at
the getty see piss christ.
No,
no,
but that was like.
I liked the way you said you really.
The definitive maplethorpe work was
christ or guys getting fisted and
assholes and cox.
None of that was on the walls and I was
so upset.
All.
Yeah,
some,
some nice portraits.
Maybe one dick.
I saw the exhibit when I was living in
boston.
That's piss christ the crucifix.
Dunked in a bucket of pis or ullico jar.
Plastic piss.
Christ glass jar of pis.
Yeah,
and it,
it became a huge thing in the eighties.
Really?
Yeah,
because people felt like it was
blasphemous and the religious people are
super upset because I just,
I might be wrong,
but I feel like he might have gotten
some public funding like for,
for his art.
I feel like you might have gotten grants
or something for his art,
so we're in the wrong business.
Be fun just to see my parents have an
aneurism.
We can show him that.
See their heads.
What's her mom's name?
You got to understand.
This was pre internet.
I was.
I went to his exhibit really 80.
I want to say that.
80 eight or 89.
I want to say it might've been earlier.
It might been [inaudible] 87.
it might have been before I did stand
up.
Wow.
Okay.
Did look at that.
Oh my god.
From the taxpayer funded national
endowment for the arts.
She received $15,000
for the work and $5,000
in 1986 for piss.
Christ is a different guy though.
maplethorpe's the.
Oh,
this is serrano is piss christ.
Yeah.
oh,
you got serrano,
dude.
Different one.
Yeah.
Maplethorpe's piss christ multiple ones.
Maybe it's serrano's.
Piss.
Christ is,
is it maplethorpe's piss christ.
Is that the same guy that doesn't
involve balls and cox and my wrong.
I feel like I'm,
I feel like that was who made it was
maple thorp,
right?
Piss christ.
Maybe I'm wrong.
Maybe I can flag elated.
Did I,
did maplethorpe have one,
two,
or did I make it up?
If you take a picture of it,
he could have is that it will find out
or tag or for photographs for a brief
history of piss.
Christ is maplethorpe to do with it.
Anything with it?
It's in there.
There it is.
Okay.
As maple thought.
Oh,
it's just that he was also granted
money.
It looks like a punishment for its role
in supporting the work of an artist at
nea.
Saw it's funding for the next year.
Cut by $45,000
because of that.
Oh,
okay.
Here it goes.
Uh,
funded to given to serrano made piss.
Christ by the way,
have an nea supported,
see a feLlowship and another $30,000
to atone for the sum given and support
of a robert maplethorpe show at the
philadelphia institute of contemporary
art.
Okay.
So he didn't do it,
it was somebody else.
So maplethorpe was just all the fists
and buttholes and stuff.
Yeah.
But really was upsetting that they
wouldn't show that stuff.
Like that's what the guy is known for it
don't give me this,
that we're looking at patty smith
portraits the whole time.
but he did that too,
right?
Like,
why is it,
why,
why do we have such a hard time with
sex?
Like that kind of stuff,
but not a hard time with violence.
Like we were talking about.
We're talking about um,
uh,
narcos,
so violent,
so crazy violent,
you know,
but it's a lot of sex in that show too.
But we're.
So it's okay.
Like we don't,
we don't have nearly as much,
like I don't want to give away any
spoiler alerts,
but there was a,
there's a scene where a kid gets shot.
I don't want to say when,
when it happens,
but when it happens,
it's so graphic and I was thinking that
is so crazy that they can show that kind
of violence like violence and adult
versus against a kid.
But you could never show like actual
sex.
Do you remember,
um,
that vince gallo movie brown bunny,
where chloe sevigny ne blows in the
saving seven.
Yay.
Isn't that?
That's not the movie.
Attend.
They'll write down bunny.
She blows me.
Comes on her face.
She said that really,
really,
you know,
fucked up her career.
It should be smart.
Well,
what does he think?
I mean,
I guess he was making the same argument,
right?
He was making the argument like,
why is it okay to have violence?
Why is it okay to have all these aspects
of people kissing and grabbing each
other's asses?
We can have actual sex.
He also just wanted a blow job.
Probably.
I don't know if he,
maybe the body,
you have to look at it that way.
But then the irony too is on mainstream
television shows,
it's all tna.
I can't watch glee.
I told you on netflix and that's really
just
eye candy.
It's a bunch of high school girl
cheerleader outfits.
You know about fox news,
right?
What they're doing with their legs to
pageants.
They're all just slipped up and shave
down and scissoring crossing the legs.
It's amazing.
Yeah.
Imagine if men could read the news and a
tank top of you can be in a top in
bikini underwear,
just reading the news,
just shredded,
shaved down,
oiled up.
Such a great world.
Lips your lips done.
Big fucking pirate hoop earrings,
right?
Just let people know you're ready.
I mean,
look,
tom watches these espn for hour after
football shows where they called fucking
sport sash or whatever,
and these guys that are working on these
shows,
they're fucking basset hounds,
man.
They're mostly older,
unattractIve,
and there's no way a woman would be able
to get away with looking like shit on tv
the way these dudes do,
but their football experts.
Right?
That's true.
I mean,
okay,
but there's no attractive.
It's not the news,
but even show on news though,
the standards.
It's true that for,
for men.
Oh yeah.
Way different.
There's some real fucking dogs.
Yeah.
The women can't.
They either had to be really old,
like Barbara Walters.
Stateswoman.
Yes.
But what's interesting is they have
these like really like ridiculously hot
women and they're reading the news,
but they don't have to know shit about
the news.
They just have to read off a
teleprompter.
It's the comparison with the football
guys is worth because football is one of
those things like,
I don't know shit about football,
but there's some dudes who knows
everything about fulbright and they can
recall games from the 19 sixties and the
play that was news to win super bowl 44
and those fucking guys like that.
They essentially to.
They do what you do in that they can
look at a play that took seven seconds
and tell you everything that happened
the same way you can tell.
You know how a guy got beat like in your
gut.
Well,
his arm drop there.
The guy saw an opportunity to put him in
a chokehold like you see that fast.
These guys go,
they watch the play in right away.
They go,
well what happened was that linebacker
he got,
he got tricked into thinking he,
he,
he bit for the fake.
So he came up.
It opened up this guy to run across the
middle.
Like they do that in two seconds,
but you know what I mean.
They should be hot.
I get that.
The thing is,
look at 60 minutes,
that fucking dead.
Is he dead?
Let him on tv,
morley safer and andy rooney is
definitely couldn't even towards the end
of his life and they're letting that guy
on tv and they're complaining that
Barbara Walters is too old.
What are you talking about?
This guy can barely get through a
fucking set.
That's true.
Yeah,
that's true.
Yeah.
I mean he was definitelY old and not tv,
not camera ready and as they would say
like diane soria,
she's like,
she's still hanging in there,
right?
Yeah.
You're still strong,
but that's like another state's woman,
a woman who's established,
respected,
and is very smart.
She's not fuckable as long as she's of
the age where she's unbelievable.
She was though she was hot,
beautiful like that back in the day,
but she never did like meghan kelly
stuff like see Megan Kelly from fox's
sexy sexy photo shoots and stuff like,
oh,
did you do photo shoots?
But I think a sawyer or one of leslie
stall,
leslie stall or sawyer shirts hanging
off the shoulder photo spread out.
Why do you do that?
Why?
Because it's hot as fuck.
She taught us the son go to the full
body.
One uP there,
up left,
left,
left.
She's hot as the sun.
That's why she's doing that.
Because every guy is like,
oh,
I give up.
Touch me.
Please not even say.
I mean,
one day she had a real fun.
Trump battled.
Yeah.
But she gave in.
She gave in.
Yeah.
She had a meeting with.
Wait,
whoa,
whoa blah.
Whoa,
whoa.
That's not really the lingerie one's not
real is it?
Don't even click on it.
Don't get my hopes up.
Um,
yeah.
She,
she gave in and sat down with them and
was like a,
they had like a friendly conversation
and she was like really forgiving what?
Not just forgiving but like,
she backed off like a lot,
like she backed up and it was just.
I mean,
I get it.
That's your job,
you know,
if you want to be the conservative,
he's a conservative icon,
right?
I mean he's in that.
Is that her?
No,
that's not her.
Who is that?
Who's that?
That might be another one of the.
Here's a bunch of them.
That's not her though.
No,
unless it was her,
which was nice young lady.
It might be her.
That might be her when she was younger.
Yeah.
Might be entirely possible,
but yeah,
guys don't do that.
Like what fucking fox news anchors can
have his shirt off,
shaved down and like,
like laying back like sensual with his
mouth open.
Like for the strawberry in his mouth.
You know,
anderson wants to though.
Here's the thing,
and you can say that and that makes
sense,
but I'm supposed to be down with like
the women's movement that says that
that's an expression.
That's her expression of her.
But leonard and it is.
Yes.
But again,
if you're a professional news caster,
is that really what you want to be
presenting?
Well,
the thing is it didn't exist.
Yeah.
What hot news caster.
Well they figured out they can get
ratings.
Yeah.
They could get men to pay attention
because here's the thing,
the ratings to men that are really into
politics are almost entirely unfuckable.
That's why they get really into
politics.
Usually they're married and they're
like,
I'm giving up.
And they just stay around out and
they're fucking chin starts dropping and
they remember the good old days and they
watched that fox news and they see
these.
They're so hot,
they treat.
Their wife is yelling at them and shit.
They just ice queens on fox and was a
publican.
Yeah,
that's funny.
They're all the same.
If you go to that image on the left
there,
those have all been women that have done
news on on.
It's amazing.
The robots a robot.
It's like it's a real doll factory.
It's really fun and super hot,
but I get it.
look,
it's a smart move.
It makes total sense.
They crushed it.
They crush the ratings Man.
That I don't know if they do anymore
really.
As far as the of the cable news,
I think they're.
I think they dominate sumner.
I Just read recently that they weren't
doing so well anymore.
Really?
I don't think cable news is doing so
well anymore.
Well maybe in the grand scheme of
things,
but within the cable news competition,
I think they.
They dominate.
They find out who got my cable news,
cable ratings,
fox beat cnn and msnbc combined method
guys.
Wow.
That's the way to do it.
Maybe I should be wearing a laundry
during your mom's house.
I wonder if that goes up or down
depending on who's president.
Like a wonder is when you have a
republican president of cnn gets a bump.
Right?
Because people are pissed.
Yeah.
that's probably.
That is probably how it works because
people,
fox news thrives on every obama story
for sure.
You know.
But to cnn go deep to do they go with
the,
a scantily clad beautIful ladies as
well.
No,
I don't watch cnn.
They have pretty ladies.
They're pretty,
but it's not like that.
And they have more diverse.
A couple of basset hounds tooth but they
have a couple of cuties.
Well we don't have to go over each one.
Yeah.
But the,
um,
the thing,
the thing that's odd about it is that
had never existed before.
And then they,
once they figured that formula,
yeah,
we got,
this is what we do now.
Yeah.
Ladies and football,
they're reporting from the ground or
what exactly.
super hot and it's kinda like that one
of the guys.
There are some really good ones though.
There's some really good reporters.
Female reporters.
Yeah.
There isn't an mma to.
And your and your cameras.
Great.
Um,
gender trainers.
Trying to think.
Uh,
there's a,
there's a few really good ones.
People they got the hot thing was when.
Uh,
what's your name?
Aaron andrews.
She got her.
They peeped her fucking creeps.
They cut a hole in her fucking hotel
room.
Her and like recorded her fucking gross.
Yeah,
I really fucking.
She knows her shit though.
She doesn't know.
She knows her sport.
She knows football.
It is funny though because when we're
not football,
but if you think about politics,
when I said the most people guys that
are into politics or unfuckable,
what I mean by that honestly is what
they're usually like guys who are
married and have families have their
dads and they worry about their income.
They worried about where their money's
going.
It's not like a giant subject of the
young single man until trump came along.
Yeah.
Trump was like one of the first ones I
noticed like a lot of like young,
single guys that were really into it.
Yeah.
What the fuck is that?
What happened there?
Maybe they grew up with him.
Name recognition.
He's on that reality show.
No,
I'm serious.
He's on tv.
That guy's a reality star.
I think it's just that he was so outside
of the the the political speak and he
was like,
this is ridiculous.
Shit keeps happening.
I'm going to fucking do just chicks
love.
Do you see him mock her?
Falling down?
Great.
It is pretty hilarious.
It is,
yeah.
He even insinuated that she probably
wasn't faithful either.
Yeah.
He just.
He goes for it and that's why he's got
the fan trumpeter.
Imitates hillary clinton for stumbling
at nine slash 11 memorial questions for
loyalty to bill.
Oh my god.
It's so crazy.
Yeah,
but look at the people behind them
clapping.
Actually they're holding up cameras.
That's a strange thing,
man.
The device age.
Everyone with the device in their hand
and if you look back at photos from the
19 fifties or sixties,
like watch the nixon debates with
kennedy and you look into the audience,
people are standing there.
You see these people now.
Everyone has a devIce.
Everyone's capturing in their own
device.
I was there.
I saw when he said that.
He said that outrageous.
Sure,
but then you're going to back up that
video you took on a hard drive,
right?
To preserve it for the rest of your
life.
Like,
no,
you're just going to delete that video.
Send it,
send a cnn need to see this.
Cnn needs to see a video from the source
like no one knows.
You know?
You never know.
You never know when like some black
lives matter.
People might rush the stage and try to
take them out yet.
Right?
Remember that happened.
There's a bunch of people are screaming
and yelling at one of his rallies on
video.
Yeah.
It's been so many altercations.
That's why they're doing it.
I got to see him look without holding
something up anymore.
What the fuck do you think happens next?
That's what we're getting at earlier,
like after these two?
Yeah,
like what do you got left?
This is the deep end we're in right now.
Is the deepest deep never sure.
Right.
For sure.
The only.
The only good out of it,
and I'm not being patronizing,
but the only good out of It honestly is
we get to see a woman be president.
That's it.
Yeah.
She's like,
if she was a man,
she would be thought of as someone
deeply entrenched in the system that's
been proven to be full of shit,
has been proven to be somewhat option
and corruption,
capitalizing on their position to make
ridiculous amounts of money and there's
so much going on there.
Everything that you basically criticize
about politicians,
she would fit the bill for that.
I know you guys.
The next president's going to be
nonbinary.
What do you think?
Well,
I mean we got the black guy.
We had obama,
now it's the woman's turn.
Did you see pansexual?
Pansexual,
and some woman came out as pansexual.
She was the first politician to come out
as.
See.
That's my point.
Next is the pan sexual president could
be like a gender thing,
pansexual,
trans president.
I forget what it means.
All right.
I'll just fucks the whole house.
Oh,
wow.
Mary gonzales,
tate's tx,
Texas state representative identifies as
pansexual in new interview.
Can we get a look at her?
Look at that.
And you went with the gender binary.
Hold on.
I'm looking at right there.
There are many might describe gonzalez
orientation as bisexual.
Pansexual.
Pansexual is.
Don't believe in a gender binary and
hence can be attracted to all gender
identities.
Let's get a look at Mary Gonzalez.
Nope,
let's not.
No,
nope.
No pictures,
no pictures.
No.
You don't want to say her name.
Should have.
Just call her.
She z.
We don't know.
We don't know what to call they.
It just.
If you could get someone from the 19
sixties and show them the world that we
live in today,
the things that people are upset about
and the restroom issues.
I feel like I'm that person.
Like I feel like I'm 40 years old and I,
I.
the world is so different than the world
I grew up in in the 19 eighties.
I feel like I'm that old person that's
like,
I don't get it.
I don't get any of this.
Did you know the differences in this
age?
This is the first time where people who
are sensitive and open minded and
progressive are going,
what the fuck are you talking about 30
now it's gone so far that people who
were 100 percent pro gay marriage,
100 percent pro,
racially quality,
gender equality all across the board.
Check off the things.
As long as you're not hurting anybody.
I'm 100 percent and you doing whatever
you want to do,
but it's gone so far that like there's
just so much nonsense.
Yeah,
I agree.
Meanwhile,
there's homelessness,
joblessness,
like all the real issues,
war,
asteroids,
cancer,
all this shit that's been around the
human plagues and.
And that's
being resolved.
North Korea has nukes,
right?
Yeah.
Guys,
we can all use the same bathroom,
so we saw that one.
It's really important.
They're close to neutral,
right?
Do they have nukes or they have nukes?
Just oh right,
that it registered.
I was like an earthquake or something.
Cool.
They fucking detonated in nuke.
They can do nukes.
Great.
Homeboys got some swag.
How long before they killed him?
How are they going to kill him?
That mentality doesn't.
Does it exist over there?
Rebellion?
I don't know.
I think somebody else does it,
but the,
the,
the question thAt they kill you,
he'll kill you if there's even a murmur.
Oh yeah.
Kill his uncle killed his uncle right
away.
Told his uncle and his uncle's sons.
So he killed his nephews.
Cousins,
cousins.
Yeah.
You don't fuck around dude.
How crazy is that?
That's today.
I mean that he's got a whole country
like that gripped.
But the thing about a guy like that,
if you killed him,
what happens next?
Like how do you get those people are
there.
So program.
Well that's the best part.
C,
we go there and we open up and all of
garden and we show them coca cola,
mcdonald's
and we get to rebuild North Korea.
What do you think?
We left the south koreans figured out.
Yeah,
they just take one in to each house and
separate them from their family.
North Korea come in like a dog man
fucked.
yeah,
take them in.
Like someone's got to train someone from
another country to whatever.
Deprogram them like a cult.
Train them from like a puppy.
Oh yeah.
Did you realize that you could be 40 in
North Korea,
come into,
you know,
sneak into China or something and you
don't know anything in this whole world.
You're like a 40 year old infant
basically.
You don't know the rest of the world.
Anything.
Nothing but saying dan,
why don't we call them like we did the
middle east,
like Iraq.
They're so volatile because they have
weapons in South Korea.
Like we really like South Korea.
They make samsung first on cnn,
North Korea may planning october.
Surprise what?
WHat does that said today?
Oh jesus,
god,
what is october surprise?
Like to fuck with our elections?
I mean,
it's so strange.
Yeah.
And then you know what?
It also disturbs me.
So they were so calm about all the
conflict and the rest of the world
because there's not really that much
over here,
so we've kind of minimalize it and we
concentrate on some other nonsense and
we fill our face with sugar and the rest
of the world is embroiled in all these
battles.
Like indian Pakistan are right next to
each other and they fucking hate each
other and russia's invading the Ukraine
and there's all this crazy shit that's
going on with them.
And then this putin's almost getting
assassinated and,
and we're like,
I want a latte.
Angelina broke up yet,
but it's good.
Were isolated geographically till
Australia,
Mexico,
Canada.
That's isolated.
Australia is the move.
God,
what we call,
they're going to learn how to talk
different though and driving the other
side of the road.
That's a really hard.
Yeah.
They need to fix that in order for us to
colonize.
Yeah.
Why are you guys on that side?
Stupid.
It is counter.
Is there a reason for that?
I mean,
the logical reason that we don't see as
americans,
like the metric system.
Well,
they got it from england,
england had it because england is so
fucking old that back in the day they
used to ride horses and when you would
be like riding,
you would want people that were opposing
you on your right hand side so you could
hack it them with your sword.
How the fuck did you know that?
That was really impressive.
It's not that impressive.
You've looked at up though,
because most people were right handed or
right handed,
so you'd want to be on the left hand
side so you could chop someone's head
off for the sword.
That's really good.
Good.
Yeah,
makes sense.
Makes sense.
Over here we grew up,
we realized,
yeah,
you could Just shoot someone chopped
away with a fucking sword.
Throw me back on the right.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
They were like pre arrows.
They figured that out.
That's pretty nice.
He's figured out arrows yet.
They just had long,
sharp things.
They hadn't figured out that you could
throw things to the air yet.
Crazy.
Back in the jousting days.
How about catapults?
Oh,
those Are neat.
Yeah,
a giant rock and just pull it back and
just launch it at peak.
Well,
you know,
we watched some documentary on Saudi
Arabia,
you know,
are they still crucify people?
We've seen that one on netflix.
What's it called?
Genes.
I think it's called Saudi Arabia,
I think it is.
yeah,
it's fucked up.
Brutal.
But they take cameras in and they show
you what's up and people getting
crucified.
Yeah,
we watched it.
They show you.
You saw that.
You saw the people getting crazy hang
'em up.
Yeah.
You see,
um,
uh,
they,
they censor stuff but you guys about to
get to capitate and they blur,
you know,
guy with a sword just chops his fucking
head off.
It's now.
It's weird.
They were like,
there's certain parts of those images we
don't want people to see because we know
they're too disturbing.
It's.
Yeah,
yeah.
Do you ever see those isis videos that
they don't catch on youtube?
There'll be up for like a couple days
for someone catches it and I haven't
looked in a while,
man.
I don't like seeing it.
I don't like seeing the Real
decapitations and murders as fucking
disturbing as shit to me.
Why?
Yeah.
I saw a few years ago I didn't like
horrible.
God did it with a small knife.
Cut this guy's head off a small knife.
I'm like,
oh yeah,
but that stays in your head.
That's why I don't like it.
Yeah.
That's why they want to do it in the
first place.
Yeah.
Just a strange,
strange thing.
We are people
drawing and quartering.
Did you ever hear.
I mean,
you know it goes into that one that's
kind of creepy to meet.
It's where they.
They tie a every year,
arms and your legs,
right?
They tie them to a horse.
One horse per limb and I don't think Cut
your intestines like cut your stomach or
your intestines are open and then they
send the horses off in all directions.
There it is,
and then you get ripped limb by limb and
your intestines get cut out.
Isn't tHat amazing?
Yeah.
There's a guy in the middle with an ax
or a big sore.
Just cut you open while the horses pull
you holding
and this is how they would publicly,
um,
you know,
the,
this is a criminal,
so they're,
they're showing the masses.
This is going to happen,
happened
to you if you steal this thing.
I was listening to the other day about
the inquisition.
It was fascinating man,
and it was talking about how everything
had gotten so crazy that they would try
to dig through any means.
THey would try to elicit a confession
out of you that you had done something
that was blasphemous or done something
against the lord and they could torture
you in order to do that.
They could torture you in order to get
that confession out of you.
And they just start torturing people
just like everybody was guilty and they
were just killing people like crazy
jesus.
And just listening the accounts of like
how it all went wrong and how they
started doing this.
It was like,
wow.
Like you could see we want to think that
in today's day and age that this can
never happen.
Like we're past that,
you know,
we're just too much.
We have too much information.
We were to evolve or to our culture and
our civilizations move far too fast,
but there's spots on earth where it
hasn't like North Korea,
you know what their spots on earth where
it hasn't moved past that.
Like Saudi Arabia,
what you're talking about.
Well,
it goes well and we still punish people.
We still kill people.
We just do it behind closed doors in the
United States.
We may get magnified quite dignified.
We're still murder.
Yeah,
and if you.
I rob somebody.
We make you a slave,
right?
You're asleep,
It's just dignified because it's,
it's in a building that's clean and we
don't see it.
You don't Have to see it so it doesn't
exist.
Right.
It's still horrific
though.
We're just,
we like to think because we can send a
video through the sky and it arrives on
your phone from 50 miles away.
We'd like to think that we're way more
advanced.
We really are.
We're so close to monkeys were so
goddamn.
Oh yeah.
I know.
And you know,
we're on the verge of death all the
time.
I had this girl right to me.
She works separately,
all these jobs around the country,
around the world to make money like job
to job.
And she goes,
I worked in,
um,
what is it?
Yellowstone national park.
she goes,
yeah.
Yesterday somebody fell into a geyser
than just disintegrated.
Another person just fell off a cliff.
They died.
She goes,
life is so fragile.
That guy got drunk,
drunk,
don't want a hundred yards off the trail
and slipped into one of those puddles.
and they,
they're like,
dude,
there ain't nothing left like lava and
boiling water like happens.
Think about how close to that dude was
the dying today that I guy with a beer.
Oh yeah.
Poof.
Yeah.
And people are like,
we have to save the barrier is really
important.
We'll keep him around to kill more
people.
Maybe he shouldn't have been around the
baron.
His baby mama bear protects her babies.
Is there a.
Is there a problem?
Do we have like a big event?
There's an issue with grizzly bears in
the greater yellowstone ecosystem that a
lot of people think that there are too
many bears and they want them to see
classified.
The environmentalist disagree and they
say that the bears were brought to the
brink of extinction and only through
diligent work,
have they been brought back to the
position where they're at now where
they're thriving.
The problem is super hard to accurately
estimate hoW many bears there are.
It's,
it's,
but you see a lot of them and the people
that are out there all the time,
the hikers,
the sportsmen,
meaning the hunters and the fishermen,
they see a lot of them and they're
seeing more of them than ever before.
And they're seeing actually less black
bears and more grizzly bears,
which is,
it used to be the opposite.
It's,
it's a crazY animal man.
We ha.
I mean,
and brown bears are like the real
motherfuckers,
right?
Aren't they even bigger?
There are super aggressive.
They're super,
super,
super Aggressive sometimes.
Sometimes they don't give a fuck.
Like there's this area,
it's a really spot where there's this,
um,
this river that runs through Alaska and
it's an incredibly common place to see
grizzly bears to the point where there's
a video of it where there's like,
jamie,
how many bears were in it?
Like 15 bears is like 15 grizzly bears
in this one area because there's so many
salmon,
so much salmon,
and these people are standing around
filming these grizzly bears because
there's so much food for the bears.
The bears never killed people and it's
like one of the safest places to observe
bears in Alaska.
yeah.
They've never had a fatal incident.
They're like,
bears wander up to people.
There's one video of this.
Bear is guy's sitting there,
a launch here looking over at all these.
Yeah,
that's what it is.
The guys looking over at all these bears
eating fish and he's sitting in a lawn
chair and his fucking bear walks onto
them.
It is a tanker.
I mean it's gigantic and it just wanders
up and it's so full and it's just been
eating salmon that it's not a threat at
all.
It doesn't want to hurt anything.
Just lays down.
They're not like,
like some animals will fuck you up just
for fun,
like some wolves will fuck up like elk
and things like that.
Just for fun.
They call it,
they call it surplus killing or thrilled
killing.
Look at this video called fullscreen and
this,
this guy sitting here,
look at this thing.
This thing just walks up to him.
I mean he does his lawn chair,
dude.
I mean,
what to show you?
How close the guy is.
You'll see it because the bear moves
towards him.
Then he asked to start talking to it,
but this thing is huge.
I mean it's a thousand pounds.
It's enormous size of it's fucking head.
But watch when it gets close to them,
that's when you realize how big it
actually is and the guy has to actually
talk to this thing to let them know.
Watch this.
Here comes right here and this is a
river and that river right there is just
overwhelmed at the end of the video.
Get to see what's the name of this
video,
jeremy.
Nice
bear says next to guy,
but you can look at brooks falls and at
this see pictures and stuff.
It just sits down and it gets up.
God have you go a little further on it
gets up and the guy has to tell it.
Yeah,
there it goes guys.
And tell him to fuck off because it gets
too close to them.
Yeah.
So it looks at him when they start
looking at this mother fucker.
Wow.
He says,
hey,
hey.
And it wanders off.
But now watch when he turns towards the
river,
now look at this.
Look at all the shit.
I kept the camera on that.
Yeah,
look like,
try to pause it when you do positive,
like when it goes a little bit further.
Boom.
So this guy was.
Well,
he's a photographer.
He sees here there.
So this is the spot where everybody goes
take pictures of these bears because
there's so much salmon.
That's all they eat.
Oh my gosh.
I guess when bears get into one kind of
food,
like they say the bears are also,
they're safe to be around when there's a
lot of berries because they just say,
oh,
I'm just eating berries.
They're not into you will.
They're real omnivores.
Like they're not necessarily carnivores.
They'll,
they'll,
they'll just snack on yummy food.
And if you're the yummy food and that's
your ass
that the.
So they eat,
they eat plants as more than just a ton
of plans to sustain a thousand pound
body feed.
Everything holy,
their cleanup crew,
they're the cleanup crew for the woods.
Have anything dies.
They'll.
They'll fight off wolves.
Wolves,
a killer.
Like an elk or something like that.
And the barrel like,
yeah,
thanks dude.
I'll just take that shit.
They just wander up to the carcass and
just started eating.
Yeah.
The goddamn thing.
Or it's not because it's like a 10 times
the size wolf.
I mean that's really what a what a
bear's leg.
Nothing can take down a bear,
right in nature.
No humans.
The king.
Only humans.
When humans weren't,
they actually think there was a thing
called the short face bear that
dominated the bering strait so
powerfully.
It was so.
It was such a dangerous animal.
They think it might have prevented
people from immigrating to north America
like buy like thousands of years because
this thing was so dominant that it is a
huge aggressive grizzly bear type
creature that lived during the ice age
and it was so dangerous that it kept
people from speculation.
But look at the size of the god damn
thing.
That's the short face bear.
It's like even bigger than a goddamn
grizzly.
Crazy.
Like,
look at that picture of that fake one
right there.
Like that's what it would've looked
like.
Oh my god,
it's a death
machine.
This is a short face bear.
Tom is a bear that went extinct.
That was way bigger than a grizzly.
I mean it was so big.
It was like the hulk.
The hulk was a bear so crazy that that
used to be a real thing in north America
and they think tom was saying that they
think that that thing.
Look at it.
It was bigger than a buffalo.
Those thing woulD take out buffalo's.
They think that they were fearsome
predators and they may have prevented
people from immigrating to north America
earlier.
What is that thing would die a song die.
Don't die.
Don't.
Oh,
jesus christ.
Oh my god.
That's a real thing.
What the hell was that?
Diane?
Dawn.
Terrible teeth on that thing.
Good lord.
But it's just.
I mean,
it's kind of.
I,
I'm so torn on these Kinds of things
because I think it's cool that grizzly
bears are alive.
Yeah,
that's cool too.
You can go see him.
Yeah.
But not if you're that dude that got
fucked up today face.
Oh my god.
You hunted a bear.
Yeah.
Black bears.
Is that like why you don't really eat
brown bears or you can,
but most people don't because they eat a
lot of carcasses.
So apparently they taste bad.
Black bears don't.
Blackberries taste good date more.
Um,
more plants.
They,
they still eat carcasses.
They still kill things.
They did do a lot of cannibalism.
That's the big issue with black bears.
oh,
I had such animals.
They are.
No,
I mean,
you know,
I don't mean as like a corny joke,
but yeah,
it's males killing lions.
Lions don't eat them.
Oh,
just kill them there.
They kill them to keep them from growing
up and becoming the male competitors.
But the bears do that.
They think bears are doing it actually
because they're hungry.
And also because they think it might be
able to bring the women back into
estrous.
Yeah.
But that's speculation,
but yeah,
there's polar bears.
Polar bears are.
There are 100 percent cannibals,
especially the males.
Yeah.
There's a.
I've watched her ecosystem is basically
shrinking,
right?
I mean supposedlY,
but you know what they say?
I mean,
it's hard to tell who's right because,
uh,
the wildlife biologists and the people
who measure bare numbers versus the
people who are like animal
conservationist and mom rights
activists,
they disagree on how many polar bears
there are and whether or not they're
healthy populations.
Because I've read that there's more
polar bears today than ever that I.
That doesn't make sense.
Right.
That doesn't sound right.
No.
See if that's true.
Jamie,
jamie,
google show.
Yeah.
It's that time,
right?
Yeah.
You guys get you out of there.
We're going to lose our nanny.
Oh,
snap candidate.
It's 5:30
AM.
We didn't go on forever.
That flew by dude.
We covered a lot of shit.
We covered everything.
I learned some things.
I learned about the guy who was the
financial guy who doesn't give a fuck.
What else did we learn?
We learn about our proper pronouns and
how to use them.
No,
did we learned about that guy who has
all the secrets?
Who fucks kids?
Did 15 months speaker of the house.
Oh,
speaker dennis has.
What else?
We learned about a bear talk.
I feel like we have to have a format.
This show it'd be jerking off to the
black guys.
Fucking my wife.
That was important.
Uh,
well,
where are you guys at?
What's the,
uh,
what's the next comedy dates you guys
got going on?
Tom?
I know you're killing.
I know you sold out the trocadero three
shows with logan.
Yeah,
we added a Philly.
we added a fourth.
That's amazing,
dude.
That's amazing.
Congratulations.
Thanks so awesome.
I'm excited.
I got um,
I got,
I just added that I'm doing ontario
thursday and we sold it out so we added
another one there and then I'm doing
cobb's coming up and I'm doing
caroline's to you.
You're doing so many big theaters.
I got my start my theater tour in
january,
but it hasn't gone on sale yet.
It's amazing man.
Really excited about it.
IT's so cool.
Like when I met you,
you've only been doing comedy like a few
years,
right?
I met you in.
Oh seven.
So I was five years in.
Yeah.
Was it o seven?
One zero six.
I think it was.
Oh,
seven.
I'm pretty sure it was during the
maximum bud light.
Real men of comedy in phoenix.
We met at the hollywood theater theater
in the round.
Yeah.
Fuck.
That was awesome.
Yeah,
it was.
Yeah.
It's just so cool now to see you.
You're fucking killing it,
man.
That's awesome.
Thanks man.
Does netflix specials,
man?
Whew.
Yeah.
Really,
really give you a bump.
Lily also.
You're really funny.
Christina.
We need to get one for you.
Trust me.
It's in the making.
It's.
We'll see.
She's um,
she's doing this.
The Model I did basically like a year or
two ago where she's going out and doing
one nighters,
which I think is because she did helium
portland one night last week,
sold out and then seattle one night with
your podcast is so fucking funny.
You guys have one of the best podcasts
ever.
Thanks buddy.
It's so fun to do too.
It's so,
I mean I've only did it once but it was
just such a giggle fest to come on.
We have,
I'll be happy to.
I could ask about a lot interviews and
everything.
I always give credit to you because I
remember you being like,
why aren't you doing one?
It was like,
I don't know,
and then you saw her and you,
your wife is legitimately funny or you
think you guys could just sit there and
do one?
And I'm like,
oh no.
And I told her and She was like,
Now that's all we do.
It's just the two of us.
We play some clips.
We talked about what's going on and it's
grown so much in,
in the few,
you know,
we've been doing it now since 20.
The end of 2010 is when we started.
It's crazy.
Wow.
It's been six years.
Men like six years of.
Of that show.
Yeah.
I'm at almost seven.
I'll be seven in december.
I remember.
I remember watching or reading something
and I realized I didn't want to be your
first 10.
Yeah.
Sat on a couch.
My office are.
Should fear sold that couch?
Really?
I gave it to ari.
We sat on the couch and I gave it to
somebody was like bay thing and donation
money maybe.
Yeah.
Maybe like,
just keep.
Remember you telling me to like sit up
on the mic because I was like sitting
back.
Oh yeah.
Well there were,
there were like uncomfortably lean
forward on a couch on tommy talking to
them like,
oh yeah.
Well we,
I don't think we had headphones back
down and we did.
We didn't.
Maybe I thought you were bananas to
doing podcast.
What are you talking about?
How we go headphones?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I don't know what the fuck possessed me
to keep doing this.
Wow.
One of the youth stream podcasts this
week.
20.
Oh my gosh.
Hilarious man.
Made you.
I never asked you that.
What did you do?
One or see one where you're like,
I got to do that.
It was a bunch of shit.
One of them was doing the opiod anthony
show because opie and anthony show was
just like a hangout.
Right.
It wasn't like for what?
It didn't have a formula to it.
It didn't have a format necessarily,
you would come in and a bunch of
comments to come in and they'll just
start talking and it would be hilarious.
So it'd be a bike,
a bunch of people that knew everybody
and we all sit around and just joke
around.
It was really fun.
It was a fun hang.
Then anthony kumina started doing this
thing called live from the compound
where you put up a green screen in his
basement.
He had a whole lot professional desk and
professional cameras and he's just a
maniac and he would do karaoke holding a
machine gun and he would have a
background,
the background and be like manhattan,
who does change the bat?
And I was like,
but that would be an amazing thing to
have.
And so when he was doIng live from the
compound,
he was doing it on one of those
streaming services.
So then we started doing the thing.
Me and red band on ustream just started
one day.
Well we started doing it on.
We do it in green rooms first it was
even pre youtube or pre ustream,
like we did it in cops.
Remember we did in and joe yelled at us
and told us to shut it off.
Fucking fucking thing off your
blueberries?
Yeah.
He didn't even have a phone back then.
yeah,
yeah.
He told us to shut it off and that's how
it started.
We just started doing it that way and
then it was fun.
So we started doing it every week and
then somewhere along the line I just
realized it was this way that I can have
these crazy conversations with all these
interesting people and I could get them
once I realized there was a certain
number of people that were listening,
I could get people to come in and sit
down and talk to me.
Do you remember,
or like early,
early?
First five.
What kind of,
how many people were listening to
something like your show?
I never looked.
She never looked.
No.
PuT it up again.
I never paid taxes.
Every now and then he'd look over the
live thing.
It was like 1200 people be watching live
if it was a good show.
Yeah.
Sometimes it was only like 500 or $600.
But um,
yeah.
But once I had like,
I had like anthony bordain on and you
know,
it had a bunch of people like that.
I was like,
I can talk to some fucking cool people
through this thing.
and then it's just like,
man,
I want to know more about Egypt.
Let me get John Anthony West on,
hey,
I want to know more about asteroids.
Let me get randall carlson really become
just at your interest.
And then graham hancock,
graham hancock was a big one.
That was the early days when I was doing
it in my,
in my house.
And he,
you know,
he came over my house and we talked to
like fucking 3:00
in the morning with his long ass
podcast.
It's your biggest get personally for the
show.
The.
I don't know,
man.
It's a good question.
I don't know.
There's no biggest anymore.
Russell brand was pretty big.
That was pretty interesting.
Yeah.
He's a fun guy,
man.
Yeah.
But.
So I was already laying.
So it was you.
I love having you on.
Yeah.
It's like now it becomes like just fun
now becomes like,
like joey or bill burr or duncan or
come stomach was cut open in front of
the time.
That was so much blood.
What?
I got a mega.
Right.
It just becomes fun.
Right?
I mean,
don't you guys feel like that?
It's my favorite thing that we do.
It's the best.
Do you like it more than standup itself?
No.
Excuse me.
Standups.
Always number one,
but the podcast,
specially since we'd become parents,
it's the one thing that,
it's the old world,
it's who we were before.
It's still juvenile and it's the sealed
hour and a half of just nonsense
and then we can go back to being
responsible adults.
That's true.
That's a good way of putting it because
it is.
It's very juvenile and silly,
but that's why we have a good time just
being silly on it,
you know?
Yeah.
That's the.
That's the big takeaway from your
podcast is how silly it is.
You guys just always look.
It's the least serious thing ever,
you know?
No serious conversations.
I love black or tom to.
Yeah,
I need to do that again.
We got.
The thing is about the move is that the
studio is much bigger like actual space.
So we'll have,
I think some guests again,
because we haven't had guests in a long
time.
yeah,
well you could also,
you could add a bunch of elements to it
to once you realize you have all this
room to do stuff and you know,
you have like an actual professional
studio.
yeah.
No,
it's exciting.
It's going to be awesome.
Yeah,
that's reaLly exciting.
When you guys do it out here,
be happy to do it.
Oh yeah.
That's a fun fun.
So for now people can see your podcast.
It's your mom's house.
It's on itunes.
You guys on stitcher,
on stitcher,
youtube,
christina p on twitter at thousand
ranch.
She still hasn't changed her name to
secure a pure disrespectful.
Hey,
can I play a feminist as fuck ya.
Yeah.
So tomorrow night I'm in dallas,
hyenas,
and then October 5th,
houston at the secret group.
Shoe warehouse,
right.
Warehouse to change the warehouse line.
Is that.
What's that?
That's the,
the,
the secret group.
That's a group of promoters,
they actually have a venue I think
called that in houston and then.
But the secret group also proMotes
producers show.
So like you could bring you.
So secret group is going to have her at
warehouse live venue.
Oh,
okay.
So it's not like I was wondering to feel
like it was like a Just put on a show
somewhere.
It's a secret,
like someone really fun is coming to
town but you've got to find out what
super annoying knowing.
Oh my god.
Okay.
October 23rd indie and then the 24th
cincinnati tickets or at thousand ranch.
Thank you.
And how do people find it?
Is the website thousand ranch.
Oh fuck.
Is anybody going to know what that
means?
Tickets or thousand ranch saLad
dressing.
Don't tell joey.
Don't tell joe you like ranch.
smells like fucking feet blue cheese or
go fuck.
she's a wings and go fuck your mother.
She's thompson guerra website thompson.
Dr.
Com on instagram.
I'm on instagram thompson or on twitter,
right?
That's right.
Tom.
I'm going to put on for my trip
tomorrow.
Thompson girL on instagram is a british
kid.
Nice kid.
He was like 18.
Give girlfriend,
gave him the money.
I can't get that grapple with this
powerful higher primate.com
fanny pack to the best right.
Shout out to dice clay.
Turning right onto the roots fanny
packs.
All right folks.
Thanks.
Appreciate it.
See you.
Bye.
Okay.