Her low freak bitches.
Just keep,
keep it stirring.
It's hard cause it's fun.
It's exciting.
It's exciting to think that there's some
sort of a gigantic ball of super
geniuses that run the world and they
decided to blow up tower seven.
You know what's funny about the mountain
fuck out herself?
Not,
I don't even want to share about the
UFC.
You know it all.
Or you know what's crazy about the moon
is the hardest shit ever accomplished.
The greatest by the human race.
The greatest accomplishment was landing
on the moon.
Right,
right.
So you would think,
holy shit balls.
I don't think it does.
No,
it listen.
Okay.
But let's just at the time,
at the time,
Dan Internet is the biggest,
okay.
Okay.
But I'm just talking about like a
physical achievement.
Three dudes,
they got shot up in a rocket.
They were in a,
like a orbiter and then the orbiter
shutout the lunar like the lamb and then
it lands,
they played golf,
Went Dune bug riding,
did donuts in the sand.
They get take pictures,
they get back in,
take off
doc with that orbiter and then fly back.
That's the hardest she'd ever,
no one died and two,
can you imagine,
can you imagine that second mission,
six months later they did it again when,
when they had a break,
the news that they were going to use
different astronauts because every
mission they use different estimates.
What did you think they would like a
show like have the same star over and
over.
Now the three dudes have pulled it off.
Keep doing it dude.
Are you kidding?
They did it before.
Yeah,
but they don't want to keep doing it.
Fucks you up.
Let me do what if,
what if I got a thank God?
What if they were planning on using buzz
Aldrin and Neil Armstrong but they just
fucking got egos and shit.
They started going to clubs and fucking
like,
you know,
they want to renegotiate their contract
because they probably went to the moon
for like,
you know,
$70,000.
You know what I mean?
They've got that government cheque,
they go,
we'll get you two on the second album on
the second.
Uh,
it just like the record business,
you know what I mean?
My bachelors even make that much.
Of course it say,
listen,
we'll get you on that second on the
second and third land.
You know how much money you're gonna
make.
You're going to come back,
you're going to be famous.
You can be fucking doing all sorts of
press.
Think about the bitches.
Think about the coke.
Oh,
they probably got blowed out and got too
cocky and wanted to renegotiate.
Oh my God.
And then NASA said,
we just got to go with some new dudes.
They made $8 per diem.
When Uncle Sam folks,
you raw dog,
he was a sand uncle.
Sam Uses broken class on his dick.
When you draw those guys went to the
moon.
Do you remember that?
That this one always got to me,
man.
That um,
those brothers that shot there,
their parents,
the Menendez brothers and one of them
had a wig on memory.
This glorious fake head of hair.
The ma'am take it off.
When he went to jail,
it was really crazy store cause they
shotgunned their own parents.
Right?
Whoa man.
How the fuck does that happen?
Do you know the one on the left?
Two,
one of them has a total way.
I mean,
you look at it now,
you go,
oh,
I get it now.
The one on the right was just blessed.
Just straight up blessed with some curly
locks.
What the fuck man,
those,
those sons shotgun,
they're fucking parents,
man.
Do you know Kirk Fox used to teach them
tennis?
That's right.
I do somehow vaguely remember that he
has a whole story.
Well,
teaching them tear up tennis too.
That scares the shit out of me that
people could do that.
It doesn't scare the shit out to be
nearly as much as people can get so
angry at someone that they could shoot
him.
But it scares the shit out of me that
someone could do that to their dad and
their mom to write and they shoot the
mom to Jesus adopted right where they,
I think the Menendez brothers were
adopted.
Oh really?
Yeah,
and I think,
I think they're just trying to get
money.
Oh,
what is that sexual and psychological
abuse they had suffered at the hands of
their parents.
Oh,
well,
there you go.
I know.
It's like you always want immediately
blame it on the kids.
Right?
Because they killed their parents,
but the parents could have been fucking
monsters.
Yeah.
You never know what it's got.
They have to be monsters.
I mean,
if you think about it,
how do you make a kid that is capable of
shooting you in your sleep?
You've gotta be,
you gotta raise that kid horribly unless
you just by dumb luck,
have to complete genetic psychopath from
birth that you could have done nothing
to fix.
You've got two guys that are willing to
shoot you while you're sleeping and you
raise him from them time.
They were babies.
That's crazy.
Yeah,
man.
Anyway,
I was going to say their house.
Yeah.
I wonder what happened to their house.
Burnt that fucking thing to the ground.
Probably.
I wonder what happened and shit like
Nicole Simpson's house.
I think it's still there for somebody
live there wasn't Nicole Simpson's,
was that a house or was that an outside
of my apartment building?
Condo.
Yeah.
Dry.
Damn,
man.
Yeah Hoo.
That's a weird one because that's like,
it's a public building.
You got to just deal with it and people
just deal with it.
Is that apartment like still empty hers?
Nah,
that he'd killed them on the street.
Right.
He killed them outside.
But every time you go home you have to
step over a crime scene to walk into
your house
and you've seen the pictures.
Yeah.
You know the history.
Every time Oj documentary comes out or
every time they have an Oj series on tv
or when his a parole hearing comes up,
you're like walking through the doorway
into that house.
So I wonder if like,
I want to talk to the person who's like,
doesn't give a fuck and listen,
that motherfucker,
he don't say
deal baby.
Bat,
Sprint would listen.
She should have been nicer dorms.
Dan,
did you ever see the autopsy photos?
Uh,
did.
I don't know.
If you haven't,
don't,
it's not worth it.
You get it.
I saw it.
A murder scene.
Photos.
It's just so hard to believe that
someone could do that to someone.
Yeah,
it was pretty,
they cared about that they had babies
with,
right.
It's just people get crazy game of
thrones out here,
but just rarely.
That's what it is.
It's like every week it's the game of
thrones.
It's normal
and a Jonathan Hyde who's a social
psychologist over it and why you heat
it.
A really good piece for the Atlantic in
2015 about this phenomenon,
this kind of safe space trigger warning
phenomenon,
this idea that you must never be forced
into a position where someone has an
idea that opposes yours,
and what he said is it basically makes
people crazy.
You know?
It actually makes you crazy that that
the idea in psychology is that if you
have a chain of thoughts leading to a
bad outcome,
if you're depressed,
right?
If your depressive,
then you have a chain of thoughts
leading to a bad outcome.
The way that psychologists deal with
that is with cognitive behavioral
therapy.
They say,
okay,
we're in this chain of thoughts.
Are you going wrong?
Are you attributing to somebody a motive
they don't have?
Right?
Is your wife really being nasty or is it
you just attributing nasty to her and
that's why you're getting depressed or
spinning off,
right?
Try to control your own chain of
thoughts.
What the microaggression trigger warning
culture does is it actually grants vow.
The more you are offended,
the more value you are granted and
therefore you have actually an interest
in being offended.
We give you awards if you're offended,
right?
Yeah.
Your your treasured.
If you're offended because it
demonstrates that you're woke,
right?
You're,
the more you are offended,
the more we can show that you are woke
and because you are woke.
Therefore your granted this virtue,
you get to Lord it over everyone else.
I mean I say in my speeches,
if we could somehow identify like the
lgbt half black,
half Hispanic,
one quarter native American little
person,
you know,
then we would finally have the,
the person who we could go to dance for
all of our questions because their
identity would be unquestionable.
It'd be Yoda,
right?
If we could find Yoda,
we could just get rid of democracy and
discussion all together.
He can just rule from on high.
He,
she,
I don't want to put a gender on Yoda,
right?
I don't think Yoda is gender.
It is Yoda.
Does he do it right?
It's gotta be a guy with deep voice.
Maybe we're being rude by incidents,
but yeah,
you're absolutely right.
There's no one is a,
no one's left enough.
Yeah,
it's,
I,
I don't know where the limit is a and
it's there so far left that they've
actually made common cause with the
people they hate.
Right.
So when they talk about safe spaces and
is w w it misery it,
all these black students protesting and
they actually said we don't want white
people who think like us and who want to
help us in our safe spaces.
We feel insulted by that.
I just thought to myself,
well the KKK agrees.
Like if you want to do safe spaces for
separate races,
I can find some Jim crow racist or
totally up for that from like 1962
well,
there's the really bizarre statement
that I've heard over and over again that
black people cannot be racist against
white people because they don't have any
power over white people.
Yes.
Wow.
Which is just,
it's an,
it's an eight.
I mean,
it's an inane statement.
The this that you have to,
you have to have power in the
superstructure in order for you to even
to be raised.
I can understand the argument.
If they said,
look,
you being racist is not connected to
racist action.
If you don't have the capacity for
action that affects people,
then your personal racism is not as
important as the racism of people in
power.
Then at least as an argument or the idea
that you can't be racist at all if
you're,
if you're black because black people
don't have enough pat.
First of all,
the idea that black people have no power
in the United States is utterly crazy.
I mean,
it's utterly crazy.
Well,
especially when it was going on.
Alabama was president.
The attorney general was the president,
and I always said this about Baltimore.
We kept hearing you in Baltimore,
right,
where they had the riots.
They'd bought wood,
they had riots,
and they were saying,
well,
Baltimore PD,
you know,
they're,
they're cracking down on black people.
I'll get the chief of police was black.
The majority of the city council was
black and Democrat.
The entire,
the,
the deputy district attorney who was
prosecuting the case was black.
The majority of the police department
was minority.
The attorney general of the United
States was black,
and the president of the United States
was black.
But the majority of the city of
Baltimore is black.
But apparently it's the white guy's
fault.
Like I just,
at some point,
you're going to have to make your ideas
actually work in concert with reality.
I can't,
I can't like do this with you.
Do you ever step back
and
[inaudible].