Okay.
And four, three, two,
boom. And we're live pat of the
university of bad ass or eight.
I'm more like the, uh, I'm more like
the vice president, the president,
probably a CJ or TCC.
He's the president of the University of
bad ass three Maria cohost and have a
little podcast. We do, dude, I
fucking love your Instagram page.
If there's new stuff that I'm going to
call when the shit hits the fan might be
you woo, rock and roll, baby
on there for your brother.
I also like guys who are my age or older
that still get after it and the gym and
you're fucking page is filled with you
getting after it, bro. We could go on,
we could full of a full segment.
I'm that alone. And the secret,
the big secret behind it, which there's
not much of a secret as you know.
I mean, it isn't hard after hard work
sucks and not everybody's cut out for it.
Yeah. People just don't enjoy it.
Yep. They tried to find a lot of,
a lot of Nice excuses why
they don't get after it. And
one of the big excuses his age. Yeah. Um,
I run into guys all the time
during my full time training,
Gig Ram training guys on the
range who say, uh, you know,
38 or 40, or whatever, and I'm
getting old. I'm like, Bro,
let me tell you something.
This is,
this is something somebody told me
when I was 30 and I've got affirmation,
uh, uh, of this from guys like you who
have stayed fit their entire lives.
The fittest of a man's
age is around like 44, 45.
That's when you can be on the top of your
game and ultra runners. Yeah. You know,
the strongest, the fastest,
the fittest, the smartest,
you know,
when it comes to knowing your body and
how much you can do and how much you
could take after that,
then you got to start being a lot
smaller, you know, die how you work out,
how often, you know, like,
I'm, I'm super tentative now,
not to overwork. Yeah. Me Too. Um,
because I've been told there
is no such thing as overworked,
but there is a such thing
as under recovery. Um, I,
I err on the side of caution a lot. Yeah.
A lot more now. And I've got it down, man.
I, I, I started, uh, this
system combat strength training
when I retired from the military because
when I retired from the military,
I retired before reconstructive surgeries,
13 broken bones and any ground
pounder who's, you know,
special ops guy who did 20 plus years,
there's a lot of freaking mile,
which on that combat chassis, right?
You know, he's, he's jacked up.
What'd you get reconstructed?
Uh, the first one was,
uh, this bicep. I was a toad jumper.
It doesn't have to make sense. Uh,
what does it mean? Oh, it's
related to static line jumping,
uh, where you pass a static
line off to a jump master.
He secures it and the static line,
uh,
at the end of the static line deploys
your parachute. So it's like, you know,
it's like rookie jumping. It's, it's
real infantry base jumping. Well,
that static line got wrapped around my
reserve and around my arm and pulled me
with the plane and it pulled my
bicep into my form, broke ribs,
dislocated shoulder concussion.
And this is when I was fucking 18 years,
I'd just do it and I already
got jacked up. Uh, next one was,
um,
a diskectomy l five s one just come,
just a kind of an amalgamation of Hilo
crashes and vehicle crashes and stuff
like that.
People don't know what that means.
It means your disks,
they trim a little piece of it so it
doesn't go against your nerve. Yeah.
And it was,
it was a massive herniation,
so they were able to take the big chunk
out and then do that trim up as well,
which is,
that's an easy surgery.
Ever had really knee
reconstruction socked. I mean,
I was a full freaking year,
six months of, you know,
getting back on your feet. And then, uh,
another year before I
was like 100% and I was,
I think I was still in my twenties.
Did you get a ACL reconstruction?
Sasse senator Patella Tendon. Yeah, I did
that one. It's hard. That's a hard one.
I did the other one with the allograft
or cadaver. It's Wazier really?
So it's six months, six months, and
I was a hundred percent man. Yeah,
cause I've heard it's difference.
Yup. Damn, that's a big
chunk of time. Six months.
Yeah.
It's,
but the other thing is that sometimes
people's bodies reject those allografts
didn't have with me,
I got lucky,
but I do know of some people and also it
feels like it's healed before it really
healed. Oh, do you know how that works?
The Wa what happens is they take that
graft and they put it in there and then
instead of that being your new ligament,
your body has to replace
that with tissue. Uh, right.
So your body has to re proliferate that
tendon with its own cells and so it
takes a long time so it feels stable and
you're like, oh my knees back man, my,
my legs feel strong.
And then you go to pivot to throw a
punch or something like that. Pop, pop.
It just pops like a wet
piece of toilet paper. Yeah.
Yeah.
You know some people they say some people
are ACL to pain and others are not.
But man,
I need that one down too,
Jack.
I don't understand people not being ACL
depending on to stabilize and ligament
in your knee.
And then the last one was oh,
show up shoulder.
And they were able to do that. Not
that basically, you know, scope it,
they were able to scope it and like
four different places and they created,
let me see if I get this right.
They created a bigger injury
to promote more healing.
Jesus. Yeah. So they did like bone
scrapes and stuff like that and when,
and so they were able to do it.
Cutting the shoulder open. Oh,
what was wrong with your shoulder?
Um, bunch of tears. It was, uh, uh,
how did I hurt that one?
That was,
I got called in one day and uh,
I used to drive my dirt bike to work,
uh,
like eight miles of a real pristine
forest and a t bone.
The deer go up 10 55 and it's
like hitting a brick house.
I mean, I'm sure you stop. Yeah.
There is no give with that thing.
And thankfully have good,
I've been a riding schools,
like even the Gary sending motorcross
school. So I was up high, elbows up high.
So I flew like superman. I didn't
get all tied up, good bike,
but I mean I sailed for 2020 yards.
So Jesus Christ in the air,
60 feet and yeah,
yeah, yeah. Oh,
came down and hit directly flat
and then slid and hit a tree.
So I knew the shoulder was jacked up,
but that one I had all kinds
of neat injuries from that one.
Like I had this one thing
called a um, adhesion. So
I went, uh, I was able to make it to
work and they checked out my shoulder.
He said, yeah, you're jacked up. We'll
put you would get you Mri tomorrow.
Humma humma that night I go home and,
um,
I wake up to go take a piss and,
uh,
I realize I've got this massive like
bubble on my side, massive. And I thought,
man, I'm going to have internal bleeding.
Just think it was gigantic. It was,
we're right on top of my pelvis.
So I guess I uh,
set my alarm clock for like every 10
minutes just to see if it's still still
still with it and then went into the
next day and they sucked out a couple
thousand milliliters.
A bloody biproduct cause it was
the skin separating from the bone.
So I think that's what
they call it an adhesion.
So bunch of blood fills the
gap. Yeah, it was all orange.
Biproduct crap.
I've had some weird,
I'm sure injuries but,
but your piece back together I can tell,
you know you do a lot of crazy working
out with like I seen a lot of shit you do
with like cinder blocks make do
with what's around you. Well that,
so my work templates pretty,
it's off the charts.
Last year and the year before I traveled
to a different state every week and
most of them were Jetson. So lugging
all my shit to the airport every week,
all my guns and everything. This is for
tactical training, right? So it was this,
is this for private individuals
you military training?
Like how is all of the all new? Most,
most of my courses are open enrollment,
so I have all walks of life.
I mean,
the demographic is extremely wide.
And so as a skillset
disparity or guys who come,
you know how to 14 guys who
sign up for would be cops,
three military, the rest civilians.
And in that civilian group,
I mean they're from, you know, you got
computer programmers, you've got surgeons,
you've got lawyers, you've
got uh, uh, you know,
a strip club owners.
And I mean,
the demographic is pretty eclectic.
It's pretty wide.
And when I go to these places and stuff,
I used to like go to a la
fitness or something, you know,
like an la fitness after work.
But I got tired of that, you know,
just walking through trying to
navigate my way through endless maze.
A bench presses watching guys do
concentration curls in the, in the mirror.
So I started range work outs
where a planet during the
day and it became a thing
where like fit guys in the class are
watching me and they're going, hey bro,
what's the workout after after training?
So can we do with you on your Instagram?
Yeah. But then the guys in
the course, we'll say, hey,
can I do the workout with you after,
after training? Yeah, yeah, Yup.
So you just find whatever's laying
around tire, cinder block. Yup.
Anything Dre, you know, if I have
a wall, I could do a lot with that.
Let's say it's five,
six foot wall.
There's a lot you could do with that
lot you could do with just the tree. Um,
some cinder blocks, you know. Uh,
and then every once in a while guys
will bring like a 90 pound sandbag or a
couple of kettle bells because now it's a
thing, right? Expect it sort of like, hi,
we want to do a pat Mac workout
after range day. And uh, you know,
Kudos to those guys because
that shit that's hard. You know,
when you're on the range all day
working your ass off and especially in a
blazing hot sun and guys hang out to
do a workout with me like bad Kudos.
See you bro.
Well,
one of the cool things about the internet
is that people find other people that
want to push themselves and they find
inspiration through guys like you and
there's,
you know,
dozens of guys like you online that
are like fun to follow and you get,
you go, this guy's doing it. I got to
fucking get off my ass and go do it.
Because sometimes people
just need an example.
They need someone to look at and go
there and it literally can change the way
you live your life. No doubt.
See a guy who's doing what
you're doing. You're like,
God dammit, he's fucking intense
all the time. He's getting after it.
Beard. Like lucky over here,
there's a cinderblock. I love that.
That's an Eagle Lake, Texas.
Probably three years ago.
What's the smoke? Is that exhaust
fume or gunshot? No, the the owner.
I know what that he was, he was
smoking. Um, it was a smoker. Oh,
that he was making meat. Oh Nice.
Yup, Yup. Yeah. But those are, that's,
those are hard workouts, man. Those swings
in between the legs like that. That's,
that's how you build the, the real core
strength. If you're back and you know,
your, your whole, that, the whole
spinal column, keep it tight and
you know, it's, it's, it's funny you get,
even today I read the, I'm reading
some comments about whatever it is.
There's a lot of stupid people out there
when it comes to like not understanding
the right way to work out, right. And
I want to tell these guys, hey man,
two things. One is if you do, if
you do what you've always done,
you're going to get what you've
always gotten. Number two,
I didn't go home last night and smoke
a bunch of crack and dream of shut up.
I mean, there's not, I've, I've done a
lot of freaking research, a lot of, um,
there's a lot of time and effort
that's gone into this and um,
they'll say, hey man, you're going to
throw your back out and doing that stuff.
No mother fucker. That's, that's
building your back. You know,
work in that transverse plane is what
guys and neglect a lot. See here,
here we go. I'm going to get on this
freaking soap box. I swear to God, God,
go get on the bum. Do a box where
most guys, when most guys work out,
they live in what I call a Sagitta
listic environment. You know,
three planes of motion,
frontal saggital transverse.
So they're in this sagittal world doing
bench press and, and concentration curls.
Um,
out of the three planes of motion,
I would say that transverse most
important. Additionally, when we work out,
I would also argue with confidence that
it's the plane of emotion that is most
neglected.
That transverse plane.
I like to tell guys that
in the transverse plane,
lives lifesaving an ass kicking.
There are four reasons why we should,
why we should exercise.
This is Max opinion. Okay? One,
self preservation, longevity,
good for your health. Stronger,
longer. Motion is lotion.
Number two, the ability to save your own
life. Having that confidence. No one. Yup.
I could pull myself out of that burning
coal or over that wall, whatever.
Number three,
more importantly to me is being Batman.
The ability to save somebody else's life.
So there's three reasons.
The last one kicking somebody fucking ass.
So when I look at workout, I
look at those four things, right?
They're not like cosmetics or anything.
Cosmetics is a cool byproduct. Do you work
out right? You're going to look better.
You look better, you feel better, you're
more confident, you're more confident,
you performed better cause confidence,
performance work hand in hand. Sure.
So I mean there's no
freaking magic elixir to it.
You know it and it's,
and it's hard.
Yeah. People like to see, there
was like, if you do bench press,
you see a chest puff up and they see
those results. I always tell people,
if there's one exercise I would recommend,
like people who do Jujitsu,
Turkish getup. So the least romance
is the least romantic of all workouts.
Nobody wants to do those goddamn things.
Go to go to a gym.
You could go to a hundred
gyms if you're lucky.
You find one person doing Turkish getup.
Yup. Every gym we'll have someone,
someone somewhere is doing
bench press and someone's doing curls
and lat pull down machine and all that
normal shit. Yeah. Working
out. It's kind of there.
It's, it's like an anachronism, you know,
they're working in a world like
a muscle and fitness world still,
and that's fine working in isolation.
If that's your job.
There's three people who,
three types of people who should work.
How it concentration, like doing
uh, a curl or some, you know,
a concentration curls, a
professional bodybuilder, right?
That's your job man at your sport.
Number two,
you recovering from surgery and atrophy.
So it's physical therapy. Number three,
you had no fucking idea what
you're doing or you're a model.
You're trying to look sexy as fuck.
You know what I'm saying?
It's possible too. That's
right. Yeah. Right.
So they fall in that same category
trying to look prettier. Yup. Yup.
It's,
it's just not what you really need to
actually with exercise is something that's
going to mimic what you would actually
do in real life. Picking up things,
moving them around like farmer walks.
Yup. Pharma Walk, very unglamorous. Yup.
Carry a heavy ass kettle bell in one hand
and just walk around for like a half a
mile and who you're fucking forum would
be dying. Your legs will be killing you,
your core is going to be shaking.
It's amazing.
And I liked the way you put it to
carry on once you know, Lowe's,
that one sided she got to do,
people don't know that they
tried to do with two arms,
but with two arms it bounces out.
And then it's really just
a grip and a leg exercise,
a little bit of lats and traps.
But really what you want to do is one,
100 pounder on one hand,
carry that bitch.
Everything is just kind of balance it out
and then turn around and put it on the
left hand. Yeah, it's great.
We do. Um, and my gym,
a lot of that where we load
one side of the time. Uh,
one of the things I love to
hear is a guy will say, man,
I'd never see you doing the same thing.
Yeah. I'm like, well, I pretty much don't.
Um, because I don't want to
fall into a Rut of complacent
adaptation, you know? Um,
so even guys to say, do you, uh,
do you do like Oly Lifts?
See, yeah, of course.
Every once in a while I'll
probably do a dead lift,
a standard deadlift once every two months,
but I'm doing variations of that. Like a
shovel dead lift or a suitcase, you know,
dead lifts that suck and are like you
said, are not glamorous. Yeah. Um,
I'll throw those in a bunch.
But do you do much cardio?
Here's how I knock out cardio is uh,
I have uh,
a formula with this. I have a program,
combat strength train.
I got an ebook and website and
all of this and your programs,
something that people could sign up for.
Oh yeah, yeah, they can buy the ebook. Um,
what's the website for? Jamie could pull
it up. Combat Strength training.com.
And I'm,
the formula is work in work in anaerobic
chunks and circuit to near metabolic
threshold to meet in a robot goal
and then like 30, 35 minutes.
So that does include warmup, you know,
so you good. Whatever it is. For me,
it's like bag work or
something for warm up,
just to make sure everything's
Loosey Goosey. The older you are,
the more you have to warm up,
man. Damn. Don't Jack yourself up.
It's called fit and is not brokeness.
Oh
yeah.
People.
That's another thing that people don't
like to do because it's not glamorous and
because the people get lazy, they
don't want to do that workout with it.
The preworkout, they don't want to
do all the skipping rope and all.
They'll just switch and stances and
jumping jacks and all that stuff.
But you really need to break a sweat
of real sweat before you actually start
lifting weights. And then even if
you lift weights or do anything,
like say if you're going
to do kettlebells, I'll
start off with 35 pounds.
I'll do everything nice and light at
first. I don't start off heavy. Nope.
Yup. Well that's, um, that's also wisdom.
Yes. You know, that's,
that's fucked up a bunch of times
telling us and yanking that. Yeah.
Chalk that one up to wisdom because uh,
um, you, you learn that, Eh, you know,
it's okay to put my big fat ego
aside. Yeah. I still have an ego,
but I'm not going to get jacked up
because I want to smoke these guys.
And in order to do that,
I can't be,
I can't have tweaks in my
neck and my back and yeah,
does a,
there's a bunch of guys who do these,
they do these workout competitions
called train to hunt and uh,
it's mostly for bow hunters.
Would they have all these um, uh,
physical challenges?
Like you'd do a bunch of stuff with
sandbags and the idea is that Jack your
heart rate up and then when
you have to execute a shot,
you gotta be in enough physical condition
so that you can bring your heart rate
down pretty rapidly and it's all timed
and they're competing. I love that stuff.
Yeah.
Do that kind of stuff with tactical.
Yeah. I've got a whole, an entire youtube
channel dedicated to that stuff. Nice.
So, um, uh, yeah,
they're all very, very
tough like shots, rifle,
pistol. And prior to that I'm pushing a
truck pulling at climbing a fast robe,
running with a sandbag. You know, it's
like, I call it shot impossible almost.
You know where that heart rate is slamming
and your throat and now you've got to
go into respiratory
pause and take these 50,
50 yard pistol shots. You know, I'm
doing pistol at 50 yards and Ding, ding,
Ding. Um, but yeah, I love that stuff.
And that's where interval training
really comes into play. You know,
learning that to control the heart rate
or learning how to breathe the right way.
Man, that shit, that shit is bad
ass. How big fan of all that.
Yeah, I am too. I've never
done a tactical course. Oh,
I really want to take some lessons though.
Like I saw Keanu Reeves doing it for John
Wick and I was like that looks fun. I
mean I've shot my guns at the
range before and stuff like that.
I've hunted with rifles but with pistols
I would like to go to some sort of law.
You'd love my courses.
Um,
cause I keep them as this one
of your things right here. Yeah,
that's a dude that's on the
roof, man. That's a lot of rope.
That's a hundred feet of
fat ass hemp rope with uh,
two 70 pound CNBS at the end of it.
And I forget what I do here,
but uh, there's the, yeah,
I got my steel at the end. I
forget. I think I run up. Oh
yeah, there's three cones.
I see him now so that the forums and
everything are just smoked jacked. Yeah,
they're there. Yeah. Plus Ma music
that'll get us kicked off youtube if we,
oh, this was a, yeah, this was a turn and
burn here. Just a simple turn of burden.
But that rope crushed my spirit.
There's a couple of these youtube
videos that I've got one Wareham.
I fell in love with the idea.
I thought,
cause I do this at the gym where I grab
a kettle bell and a balance it on end,
you know, see your balance down, right
upside down. It's so 55 pound Kettlebell.
Most people can't do that.
He would just bounce a kettlebell while
walk on a balance beam with them and
stuff like that. Phenomenal.
Yeah, it's good stuff.
So I thought, all right,
next youtube video,
I'm going to do the 55 pound capital
balances thing on an shoot strong hand and
then balancing and shoot
support hand 50 yards, 50 yards.
So I got out of the race on a balance.
Yeah, it's on Youtube. Yeah. Uh,
so I got out there and I
got all my stuff ready,
got my bed of my truck,
got my gun laid out.
I throw that Kettlebell up lefthand first
and pull the pistol up and I'm looking
at the target and I am shaking like
a dog shit and sand spurs. I'm going,
this was a bad idea.
Oh my God.
And um, she had a clean shot to clean the
first time and then I have to, cause I,
I do this like a West Stroud
type of filming, you know,
West drought, the uh, survival
Manson Les Les Stroud. Yeah.
So where I go and talk
to the camera afterwards,
I was so happy when it
rang again when it rang.
So I had this massive smile on my face.
I dropped the kettle bell,
I had to erase it and come over
to the camera and go. All right,
well that was a pretty good
time. You know, here's the time
upside down.
Kettlebells are great for shoulder
stability cause it's all like that.
Wigley once again, something that
people don't work on in the gym.
Stabilization and bounced,
stabilization, proprioception,
kinesthetic awareness cause it,
cause it ain't sexy and they're not
building peaks on biceps and you know,
cutting their abs.
Uh,
so we do a lot of like rubber band
work, holding isometric, you know,
and watch everything.
Freaking shake. Just saying
when you put together these drills and
you put together these programs, do you,
do you just sit down and map it all out
in your head? Do you think like, okay,
how am I going to emulate the kind of
stress in a like a life or death gunfight?
Your,
your heart rate jacked.
You might have to physically do something
meant to run from someone or climb
over something.
Is that how you do?
Yeah. How do you create, yeah,
you're talking about like the youtube
stuff where I do the physical thing with
the shoe. Yeah. The first thing I do is I,
I put it on my calendar just so I know
that I'm going to make one and then I'll
start thinking about it. What haven't
I done? Cause I have to think also,
uh,
I have to think about the audience,
the audience that follows me on youtube.
A lot of our gun guys. So they want,
they want to know about the gun that
I'm using. I have to think about that.
And then I have to think,
all right,
what challenge can cause I
want guys to replicate it.
I want them to like put those
little notes on the Uta.
I did this and my time was a
minute and 30, or whatever it was.
So I want them to be able to
replicate them as well. And, um,
Juan make them,
uh,
rear w with some real world
application in mind, you know,
so front loading the sandbag or uh,
getting in,
pulling something in and out of a car
and doing that with a happy bunch of
reputations. You know, you, when you're
doing dead weight in and out of a car,
you know, 150 pounds pulling
it in, pushing it out,
pulling it back in and pushing it out.
That'll smoke every freaking ounce of
your being and it'll crush your spirits.
Crazy. Right? A full grown woman,
you'll be able to pick her up
and put her in a car. Easy.
No hard tried getting her out.
Right. Especially if there's no, you know,
you, you got gotta think dead weight.
You know what? This person
is incapacitated. They ain't
helping you. Those arms,
those,
you know,
those limbs are moving everywhere
and it is a pain in the Dick.
Yeah. You're way better off with
150 pound barbell. Oh yeah. Yeah.
What else? Yeah. It's like, all right,
you shoulder, pull it out. Yeah.
So, but I, I kept to keep
those things in mind.
The other thing I want to do is
I want to make him a kind of,
want to make them hard enough so
not everybody could do it. Uh,
because I wanted to do
something that mind,
like industry competitors are not
doing. And I've, I've turned this,
I've, I've, uh,
started a kind of a fad I bought 10 years
ago were more guys are doing this now
they're putting like shoots
up on in a webs, you know,
with some physical activity
prior to or during a witch. Yeah.
Good. But uh, yeah, I'm
pretty sure I uh, you know,
I, uh, I made it cool. Yeah.
Well the more people doing it, the better.
Right? The more competition, the better.
Yup. Yeah. It's, it's just such a
smart thing to think of if you're,
if you really want to train the way you
train and really want to think about,
you know, like tactical situations
and real world application. I mean,
it's such a great way to go about doing
it and as he looks exciting and fun.
I mean, I haven't done
it, but I'm sure it's fun.
It's good. I talk a lot during my w now
during my courses, I don't do this stuff,
you know, I'm not cause I have,
I'll have 60 year old women in it.
I'll have a guys with Parkinson's,
even man come to my course.
I have guys and wheel chairs.
Yeah. I think guys, how do you,
how do you stabilize a guy when
they have Parkinson's? That's good.
That's what I showed this guy a trick.
What was his name?
See if I could remember his name.
It doesn't matter,
but he was 77 years old
and uh, he said, well,
I could either come to your course and
train or lay on my couch and die or
something. You know, it was to that effect
because he likes to shoot. I said, bro,
anytime,
but I have to modify the course to him
now because he can't even lay prone to
zero. Right, right, right.
So I would sit him on a
cooler and then I used a,
you know, furring strips all or they
hold up a target. They're just two,
one by twos, you know, about
five foot long. I had him,
Kris Cross those and hold them.
And then V to v Notch and it put his
rifle and that Vena cause he could sit up
pretty good with,
he couldn't get into prone,
he can't stand shoot
but sitting pretty good.
And you know when, uh,
when guys like that are concentrating
more, you see that shake go away too.
That's something we do at my gym too.
We trained Parkinson's,
a tata box Parkinson patients.
Really it's a, it's a,
it's a national program
called rock steady boxing.
They come in three times a week.
Where's your gym?
North Carolina. What's it called? So
people could go there. Spartek spot, uh,
s p a r like smaller. And then
TC, is it open to, yeah, it's,
yeah, it's open. Um, it, uh, it's,
it's very flight centric.
It's an MMA gym.
So everything we do is very
like fight centric with the,
with the physical work and
the lifting and all of that.
Uh, and then we have, uh,
programs like there's, we've got,
we got some really good fighters,
man, dude, coach there. I mean,
they were like legit.
Um,
so we got really good
fighters who do, uh, you know,
one on one coaching,
um,
everything from Greco to Bjj to,
uh,
tie to kickboxing to
standard boxing. Uh, it's,
it's an, it's a neat place. It's, it's
small. It's warehouse. It's very spartan,
you know, it's not sexy at all. Perfect.
Yeah, it's my favorite kind of freaking,
it's bad ass. And so what do you
do with these Parkinson's people?
So the rock steady boxing, uh,
folks, they have a program,
they come in a couple times a week
and they put them through a series of
exercises. You know, a lot of
it's just walking a straight line,
uh, holding this in Wa,
you know, loading one side.
And then once they're all warmed
up, um, they all kit up, man,
you see these guys were wrapping
and everything. You know, they,
they're so excited to get there
and they put the wraps on and uh,
and then they have is they
work a series of bad drills,
you know, a one, two lateral
move to next bag is, uh,
hooks, you know, left and right hooks, and
there's an upper cut bag. And there's a,
you know, the double end bag
and granted they're not moving,
they're not moving much,
but they're moving and they get
there and they love coming there. Uh,
and uh, some of them work up a
sweat. You know, it's, it's pretty,
it's pretty amazing seeing them get
off their asses and get to the gym.
And I look,
I remember you put something out and
I pinged you like a year ago. Oh,
it was a on a podcast and you were,
uh,
you were getting pretty emotional about
somebody not wanting to, uh, work out.
And I pinged you and I said,
I think I've mentioned that we got fucking
Parkinson's people coming to my gym.
You know,
it's just when people make those excuses,
that just drives me crazy
because I've seen examples of,
I've been very fortunate
that I have good health. Yep.
But I've seen many examples and
I've also been very fortunate.
I never got out of shape.
I just kept working on my whole life.
But I've seen people that are fat as fuck.
350 pounds just barely can get,
get a w all round.
And then they decide I'm going to take
control of my fucking health and then it
gets just do it.
Yeah.
They just do it and even if you just got
to walk around the block you need for
walk up flights of stairs.
Even if you just do a pushup.
Even if you do us it up, just do
something man. Do some body weight squats,
do something. It can be done. Yup. It,
you know the journey of a thousand
miles starts with a single step and,
and I'll have guys
in my community who were saying, who
will say, yeah man, I follow your stuff.
I'm sure a lot of shape and I
don't have the time to snatch,
which is another excuse does things.
I don't have the time to
get up an hour early. Right.
You have all the time in the world.
You had an hour of workout.
I'll fuck you up in an hour. Right.
You come work out with me for one hour.
I will have you crying
by the end of an hour.
That's plenty of time from warm up to
cool down one hour. Yep. Done. Yup.
That's a hundred percent yeah. If
you're, if you're, oh man. Oh Man.
There's my friend and my own
need more than that. Keith Weber,
and he has this extreme
kettle bell cardio. A DVD.
Yeah.
It's
available as a digital download though.
The,
I can't even do 40 minutes of this
motherfucker's workout with one 45 pound
kettle bell. 40 minutes in, my legs
are shaking, my arms are shaking.
I'm walking like,
like I blew both my fucking ankles
out for the next couple of days.
It's a ruthless,
you can get a lot done in
40 minutes and there he is.
He's a savage right on. Yeah. Yeah.
That guy's not sure I did it all.
He does crazy shit too. He,
uh, brings a kettle ball.
It's all on the beach.
He just brings a pair of kettlebells on
the beach and just fucking gets after it.
And you just follow along with them.
It's a great workout too, because you're,
you're doing what he's
doing, so, you know,
it's possible he's doing it right
in front of your face, right.
Yeah. You know, when it comes to,
I'll tell guys I'm coming to my gym once,
just once because all I need to do is bait
the hook. Yeah. Okay. You feeling good?
Yeah. Yeah. And, and I, and
they said, well, I'm afraid
you're going to smoke. I said,
nope. Because I run a, uh, whether
it's shooting or physical stuff,
I run a called performance based
trainee. Good. You know, I got this.
It's recognizes that we
all perform differently
performance as measured by doing
what we can with what we have. So, um,
it gives them permission to work within
their capability level, not mine.
So you don't need to
replicate what I'm doing, Bro.
We're going to do the same movements,
but I'm going to,
I'm going to scale this to you,
to your needs, you know, and, and,
and the other thing is I don't
want you to be incapacitated.
I don't want you to work out so hard that,
that you're not able to move
for the next three days. Right.
I have another rule is that you could
work out as hard as you want and the gym.
But when you walk out
that door that says exit,
you gotta be ready to kick someone's ass.
I mean,
I don't like to work out to the
point of being incapacitated. Right.
So there's a balancing act there and
I've figured it out. Fuck that up.
Many times. Many. Yeah, no. Yeah.
And I think that's why I figured it out
because too many times I am for a whole
weekend going, oh my God. Yeah.
My freaking ass, my thighs,
my you do for recovery. Do you a fuck
around with cryotherapy or sauna?
Nothing. Do nothing really?
No. I, nope. Nothing. Uh,
how come I,
I dunno.
I cause I haven't really needed it.
You just get a song in your
gym. Yup. Just that alone.
Get a sauna and a fucking
ice bath. Yeah. I drink,
I drink beer for recovery.
That's,
that's a nightly ritual.
I will not be able to function if I don't
how many beers I'll usually write for,
but they're like good quality pints,
you know?
I'm not like Chug your login,
Nascar soda by the case.
Barley pops like good quality a IPA,
stouts, porters or that kind of thing.
You just live for it. Yeah. Love it.
I'm a hobbyist man, right?
Amma hobbies that are bourbon.
So I, I, that doesn't seem to go
hand in hand. A lot of people's eyes.
I know with hardware, like you freaking
kidding me. It's like, hey man,
I have a policy. My wife having an, I have
a policy every night is Saturday night,
but every morning is Monday
morning. Wow, man. I like it. Yeah.
So we'd go out almost every night we
go out just because if I'm at home,
I'm going to work.
I'm going to work until I fall asleep.
So, you know, that clock hits six,
seven at night. I'm like, all right,
let me go meet my wife.
She's getting off of work.
We're going to go have a couple of pints,
have a big old bourbon or
something like that. And, uh, Yep.
I smoke cigars. Um, dip. Uh,
how did they keep, the thing is,
well, that's what I'm going to die.
It's all about diet.
I mean,
my Diet's ridiculous and it's
predominantly when I meal prep,
um, it's Collard Greens, Spinach,
bell pepper and chicken and that's it.
And then spice it up with, you know,
salt, pepper and prep for the week.
You make like a bunch,
but it doesn't,
I don't have a pot big enough to prep
for the week. So I prep for like two,
three days at a whack and just chow down.
And that's the other thing,
diet man, you know, there's this,
what's due to, puts a secret in diet.
Eat Food in food doesn't
come in a bag or a box.
That's a product shop at the
periphery of the grocery store.
If you go into the guts, all you're going
in there is for coffee, olive oil, salt.
That's it. Yeah. That's a good
way of looking at you. Stay right,
stay on the outside.
That's where the meat and vegetables are.
Beware of the inside. Just be aware if
you're going in there, go with a purpose.
You know, don't get sucked into that damn.
Oh my God. Yup. Because that,
and then the older you get,
the less you can prop your
body can't process that.
Correct. Right. So Diet for me,
get up in the morning. It's habitual.
Full quarter water. Since I wake up full,
full quarter one, first thing, power
slam. Don't even don't even set it down.
And then, um, why is that? What's the
thought process behind getting that down?
I'm getting it in me.
No waste in time.
It's there for a reason.
I want to cause you wake up dehydrated.
I just want a power.
Slam that and get it all into me.
Um, and then you know, a clean,
I hate to clean breakfast,
like a couple of boiled eggs and some
bacon and then throughout the day and
people say, well, is
there a certain amount?
Because too many people
follow too many like diets,
which good for them if you're
following my diet, Kudos. Um,
but like meal times,
how many times a day I eat when I'm
hungry and I don't eat til I'm full.
It's, it's pretty freaking simple. Uh,
you don't eat until you're full, so
you're back off, right? Yeah. When you,
what do you hit?
Like 70%.
Yeah. How about that? Something
about that. And then, but port,
a portion of that is thinking,
well,
what if I got a sprint 400 yards,
you know,
or what if I got to kick somebody's ass
right now, right now. And if I'm 100%,
I mean it's going to be
shooting out of both ends.
So I die is freaking huge man.
Huge.
But it allows me to drink
those beers at night. You know,
it allows me to do stuff like that and
then make sure I'm hitting it every day
that, uh, you know, the
gym even on the road. Um,
I usually don't have time
for seven days. Uh, and I,
even if I did,
I probably wouldn't,
I'd probably take at least
one day off maybe too. Um,
but you know as well as I do that you
are more in tuned when you get older to
what your body's telling your brain,
your body when you get older says,
you know what? Back the fuck off
today. You don't need any of this shit.
And I listened to that man.
I do listen to that too.
That's so important to listen to that.
There's those days where I'm like, man,
I just feel a little off today. I'm like,
I'm being a pussy.
I don't think so.
I'm feeling off and then
all of a sudden I'll start,
my nose will start running and I'll
start coughing a little bit around me are
second and I got lucky.
I listened and then that call to be gone
a day or two versus if I just go run
the hills. Right? Yeah. I'm good to go
sweat it out. That shit is not real.
People say sweat it out.
That is,
unless you're getting in a steam room
or a sauna, he ain't sweating out shit.
You're,
you're twisting your body up and you're
probably going to make your immune
system even weaker. Yup. When you were
talking about those Parkinson's folks,
when they come into your
gym and they do that,
do they experience any benefit
in terms of, uh, their function?
Does it,
does it help them?
Absolutely. Absolutely. Um, uh,
and some more than others? Depends. I
think it depends on how, you know, what's,
what stage they're in, how long
they been there. But absolutely.
We've got one guy who used to be
a bow hunter and he can't anymore.
So we got to replicating that
motion with rubber bands and he,
you know, he could barely do
a small one. Initially he,
he gave it up because he thought,
you know what,
it's not working for me.
So he kind of gave up.
But once we started working the rubber
bands, he started seeing results.
This is a seven year old man with
Parkinson's. He's like, holy crap, man,
I'm going to be able to drop my bill
again because I'm doing these exercises,
you know? And uh, yeah, absolutely. With
a lot of guys, especially with their,
their balanced lateral movement.
That's one that I see a lot, you know,
with a lateral movement.
Uh,
they're making a big improvements with
lateral movement and yeah. What helps it?
Does weight training help them?
Like what I, I think, um, it's,
it's just getting, getting
that body moving, you know,
and then with the, uh, with the boxing,
it's that hand and eye coordination to,
you know, visual being
visually acute, you know,
to the spot that you're supposed
to hit on that bag every time.
So it's a combination of the,
uh, because the weights are very,
very minimal. You know, we don't want
these guys to get jacked up. And,
and the Gal who runs
it, Laura is pretty, uh,
she's pretty cognizant of that, you
know, not wanting them to get jacked up.
So their loads are very light when they
do any kind of a weight training. Um,
but I'd always wondered because it
is a neurological disorder. Yup.
But you know what?
They benefit from it because they're
getting out of the fucking house,
out of the hospital and get into a gym.
The wrapping up, they're motivated,
you know, they're fired up to be there
and you know, they're not, they're not,
it's obvious that they have Parkinson's.
You know, they're not, you know,
running around the ring like Roy
Jones, you know, they're, but they're,
they're fired up to be there
and it's given him purpose.
Yeah. People need purpose, you
know. Yeah. Speaking to me.
And then when you retired from
the military, was this, um,
did you envision yourself doing
something along these lines like teaching
tactical stuff or,
oh man,
I went through some rough patches
as most guys do. Right? Yeah, man,
man, it was, no, I,
I'm morphed into who I am only in like
the past six or seven years I retired,
no five I got hired before even retire
by a corporation to do training stuff.
And um,
I kind of fell,
I was almost falling into that
Rut of accepting mediocrity.
Plus what I didn't know is
that, uh, I had depression.
I had to know that because you no idea,
which is common,
especially in like the SPEC ops world
guys retire because you been there and in
units with guys with the same guys
for a long, long time and you've,
there's a level of intimacy there that
can't be replicated with another human
being.
And then when you retire,
you miss that Camaraderie,
that connection. Um,
so I had working for a
corporation, um, I was, uh,
had a really bad relationship. I was
living in the bonus room and my garage,
I'd lived there for five years
because I had a x who is, um,
on chemistry, you know,
prescription meds go big Pharma. Um,
and so the neuro receptors are freaking
gone. I mean delusional and, and, uh,
it was, it was a real bad. Uh,
and then I started booze and,
uh, with depression. Um, and I, it,
it didn't even occur to me that dude,
you got a fucking problem.
Man didn't even occur, I guess,
which is common with a lot of guys.
But I had an epiphany.
A lot of things happened at one time.
My local cops saved my life.
They said, Bro, you need to
get the fuck out of there.
Um, and a bunch of things
happened all at once.
And this was in 2013.
Um,
I didn't want to leave because I had
little kids, so I didn't want to, I was,
I was going to stay there.
And, and just the wither away.
Um, and I almost capitulated,
you know, to darkness. Uh,
but I got up before I
went to sleep one night,
my kid is sleeping with me and I'm
hammered and it's like eight at night,
you know, and uh, and um, I had an
epiphany. I said, you know what, I can't,
I can't do this and I will not. I remember
saying this to myself, I will not,
I will not be defeated.
And I put my running shoes by the side
of my bed and some shorts set my alarm
clock, got up early the next morning
and went for a run, I'll, ah,
Forrest Gump
and a pound the pavement for about 10 or
12 miles. And I'm not a runner, you know,
I like to run. I like to sprint.
And when I came back from the run,
worked out in my driver
for about an hour and, uh,
my local cops came all happen
at the same time. And, uh,
they came and said, hey bro, get the
fuck out. Kids would be all right.
You need to do this and that. And, um,
then I started, uh, kind of figuring out,
uh,
re uh,
reevaluating my path in
life. Oh, back up a step.
I got also got laid off from
this corporation and you know,
with a guy in the military,
you don't,
you don't ever think about job
security and whenever tired,
I'm working for a corporation that was
mostly made up of a retired military guys.
So you get laid off and you're like,
what the fuck am I going to do now?
What does that even mean? Getting laid
off? I don't, what am I going to do? Um,
so all that shit happened at
the same time. It was like a,
it was like this massive spiral of
bad events and a man I was able to,
um,
I was able to rekindle my own,
my own, my own fire because I recognize,
all right bro, you still got an ember,
you still got this. All you need
to do is just nurture that amber,
turn it into a flame,
turn that into a flame and then just start
adding would add would add wood until
it becomes just a perpetual
blaze.
And which led me to this thing that I
tell people now, you know, is that, uh,
you got to keep the blaze alive.
Um,
I've got that on t shirts
even because I like,
I like to kick people in the ass who are
willing to sustain their own fire once
they get that ass kicking it.
If they can't,
if they can't keep their fire going,
then it's not worth,
it's not worth it for me, you know, to,
to keep kicking them in the ass. Um,
but um, uh, yeah,
so ever since that point in time,
you know, getting laid off to
depression, the booze and, uh,
I was able to rediscover
me and rebrand and, um,
pretty much start from scratch.
I mean,
I had to start life all over again
when I was 48 years old. Wow.
Yep. The whole thing from scratch and I
discovered like social media and all this
stuff because I've met a gal and I'm
married to her now and she's probably the
best purse, one of the best human
beings I've ever met, you know,
all around human being. Um, so she was
able to help me with that and said, hey,
you need to do this. You need to get
this social media platform or that one.
And so it's,
it's,
it's detonated pretty well considering
I bet on a short amount of time.
Um, but apparently the
message is resonating. Yeah.
So it's a genuine message.
That's why I picked up on it. Oh,
right on. I love that you figured
this shit out. I love that.
That's my favorite thing
when, when, I mean, look,
everybody's prone to mistakes and prone
to depression and people are prone to
hitting rock bottom.
Yup.
Your life can go down a series of bad
roads and you find yourself in a bad
relationship or a bad job, a bad
situation in life. And it's very,
very difficult at that moment
to have faith and confidence
that you can readjust,
reconsider, and reengage.
And that's what you did.
That's awesome. I love that.
I love those kinds of stories.
I love when people get their
shit together and I think that
that helps me help. Other people
weren't sure. You know, cause I could,
I could relate and I don't,
you know,
I don't sit down with them and pat
them on the shoulder and say, hey bro,
you know, I was there two or anything
like that. I don't even share with them,
but I empathize and that's
sometimes that's all it takes.
He empathize and um, and you
just give him, just get, just,
just that, just a little bit of the right
advice, just a little bit, you know,
not too much. Oftentimes people just
need momentum. They need one good. Right.
That's what I said to that one guy.
Just come to the gym one day. Yeah.
If you have one good day, we eat clean.
You drink a lot of water and you like,
you did,
you got that day,
you woke up, you put your
shoes on, you went for a run,
you worked out your driveway,
you got a good day. Yep. Yep.
That's sometimes all you need to do and
decide this is what I do from now on.
I have good days. Yeah. Tomorrow's
going to be another good day.
And then I'm gonna Force myself into
another good day and the next thing you
know, I've got some momentum,
right? You've got some momentum.
You could change everything.
I've,
I've felt many times in my life I've felt
like I could slip the wrong way and I
just, I see it, I see the dark hole and I
go, fuck that and just go the other way.
Go the other way. The problem is,
and people fall into that dark hole.
They think that that defines them, but
it's, it doesn't, it doesn't define you.
It's just you right now,
you could be totally different tomorrow.
You are a human being.
You can think you can adjust
and there's so much inspiration.
It's one of the beautiful things
about your Instagram page and many,
many other Instagram pages
is that you can take,
if you curate your feed correctly and
you don't follow a bunch of knuckleheads,
you can go to your Instagram
or to whatever social
media platform you like and
you can go and check out a lot of cool
shit. Oh man, you feel good about it.
You get fired up and you want
to do good with your life.
Yup. I, I, uh, I am,
I love being inspired by other
guys that I follow on social media.
Uh, I'm a motivator, but I like
to be motivated too. Yeah, me too.
So I love,
uh,
I've met a lot of really cool people
on, uh, on those platforms, you know,
sitting across from you for example. And
it's not a, it's not cause too many guys,
especially like my age, are afraid of
it. You know their friend. Hey Bro,
you don't have to, you know, you
don't have to go crazy on it,
but you should at least a check
this out and check that out.
And you don't have to
follow thousands of things.
But people see like emojis and sponsor,
the fuck is going on.
What am I doing here? 15
years old, the fuck is this,
but to right too about, um, we are,
we are human beings and we were allowed
to air. And as a matter of fact,
in most cases it is a biological
requirement for us to,
for a subjection up.
But when we do,
all we needed to make sure is that it
doesn't become a recurring theme that we'd
learned from the past. Prepare for the
future, perform and live in the present.
Expand this. We've been, we've
been blessed with a very,
very short existence on this
planet that amazes me,
that can, uh, you know,
nurture and sustain freaking life and
a solar system that can do the same.
I like to feel insignificant and small,
like looking up at the stars through
a telescope. It's like, Damn, man,
I'm freaking nothing. I have
nothing. I could see the truck,
I could see the Andromeda
galaxy through my telescope.
And that's the closest
one that we can see.
And there's billions of stars
in that galaxy. I guess what?
There are billions of galaxies
just like that. Yeah, I mean,
I am,
I am so freaking significant.
So let me make the best of this,
of this time that I have on this,
on this planet with these other
several billion people. Um,
because I mean,
just the fact that I am a human being,
you know,
that are strands of DNA wrapped
in protein thrown in with some,
uh, you know, with some amino acids
it's mind blowing that bet. Uh, um,
you know that.
Yeah.
Yeah. No, I feel the
same way all the time.
I [inaudible] it's so easy to get wrapped
up in your own day to day existence
and weird little dumb things
and if there's only little
dump things in your life
to those dumb things become huge.
When you have big things in your life,
it's easy to look at those dump things
and brush them off. When you're,
you're really working hard at something
and you have a lot of positive,
positive things going on in your
life, then then it's easier. Like,
what's one of the good things
about really hard exercises?
It's very difficult to do so when
you go to a very difficult, real,
or real difficult physical struggle,
the other little bullshit seems like
nothing. It's just really see it,
it gets exposed for what it really
is when it really is. It just,
it seems like a big deal in the moment,
in the time,
but that's just a trap because your
body needs something to think about.
Your body's always worrying. Yeah, your
brain is always focusing on danger.
You were worried about threats and
predators, and if there's no predators,
then it's fucking microaggressions.
Then it's you.
It's this guy looked at me
funny at the office. It's like,
this bitch is always parking
in the spot. I want, you know,
like the people get weird. You get,
you start focusing on nonsense.
I'm in my new shit.
Yeah, but I think it's,
I think that's one of the primary benefits
of physical exercise is not just that
it blows out all that excess energy,
but I think your body stores up,
and I always,
the way I was described as at a person's
body is almost like a battery that's
leaking energy.
Like you've got to purge it.
You got to purge it of that excess
energy because it has certain physical
requirements. Then on top of that,
the physical difficulty of, you know,
running a hard row,
know two,
three miles in the mountains or wherever
you're at or doing like, uh, you know,
crazy crossfit workout or
whatever the fuck you like to do.
Taking a Jujitsu class,
that shit is so hard that all that other
nonsense and your life gets it puts
into perspective. Then
from there, then look up,
then look up at the whole stars and go,
man,
you're just lucky to be experiencing this,
right. To be able to think about this,
to be this person that's living in the
most amazing time ever for human beings
might be spinning around on this
ball flying through infinity.
It's nothing but gravy. Yep. Yup.
It provides you with, with great, uh, uh,
like centering balance,
you know, and expect.
Yeah. And um, man, what else? You
said something that uh, you know,
we talked about that, uh, people
focusing on the, my new show. Oh,
the other thing
you were saying how it's just a,
it's a sticking point with me
is all is um, how uh, you know,
we human beings primal,
our primal thought,
we worry about no dangers
and stuff like that. But man,
it's amazing how at how many people
nowadays have relinquished that pri there,
there their primal defense mechanisms,
you know, of like awareness said,
mobility,
all that they've just given,
they've given up their fat, dumb, lazy,
happy button pushers.
Flacid and complacent just walking
around a 45 degree syndrome.
Yeah.
I'm on that bus today.
Going to go to the rental car place
from lax and everybody's on the phone,
which, you know, there's times you could
be in the white, but I look around, I go,
well it looks like I'm on security right
now because nobody else is frigging,
you know, going to see this
or that happened. Yeah.
There's a ton of people that are just
staring at their phone all day long and
not paying attention to
their surroundings at all.
And it's not that you need to all
the time. Most of the time you don't.
But the time when you do,
boy,
that could change your life or the life
of your loved ones. Yup. Yup. And, and
walking around the streets is
not the time to do it. You know,
there's a time to be in the
white and you know, when you,
you know what I'm talking about,
what the white like Cooper's
color code white to black,
white is like Zombie mode.
And that's, you know,
me and my house and my range of
panties watching TV or whatever.
That's the time when
you're allowed to be loud,
to be in the white where black is, you
know, you're fighting for your life.
Horrible, horrific,
terrifying. But, um, you know,
in the streets you gotta be, at
least in the yellow, you know,
just have your wits
about you a little bit.
So let me take you back to when you
decided to get your shit together,
you decided to get your shit together
again. You begin the process.
And then how did you get to
where you're at now? Well, I,
I'm getting laid off was scary as hell.
But sometime you know,
when you're in crisis mode like that you,
you think most efficiently
there's a, there's a, there's a,
there's a series of things that happen.
One is, you know, you get scared of death,
right? Laid off Skype. I
think that was the first one.
Scared and then angry and this is
over a couple of days, you know,
and then focus.
When I got focused,
I built my company t Max.
Um,
I mean I just thought of everything, you
know, I just had one epiphany after I,
what am I going to call
it? You know, her own,
let me just make up an
acronym that sounds cool.
And the cover all the basis
training, marksmanship,
adventure, concept, security.
I covered t max and then,
um,
uh, and then um, man, shit just hit me.
I was so freaking fortune cause shit fell
into place for me. I had guys who were,
who I trained for this corporation called
the corporation and say, Hey, we want,
uh, you know, pat Mac to come train
us again. And they said, well,
he's no longer here, but we
could have somebody else do
it. And they were like, no,
we don't want somebody
else, you know, wha, Eh,
we don't care what it's called
or what your branding it.
We want this guy doing it. So they
were able to get in contact with me.
It was a big contract.
And then another one came up and then
another one all in the same year.
I was like, are you his all
tactical training? And it was all,
so that year was complete.
Um,
and then I had a bunch of
different, uh, you know,
lessons learned like government contracts,
Shit like secret station number
at 2013 with a week. Anyway,
sequence duration. So government
contracting and stuff like that.
It all went away. So there was a time and
13 where I didn't work for six months,
you know, it was, it's, it's
scary when you're working on your,
when you're doing everything
for and by yourself,
all your own admin and everything
like that. It could be,
it's very exciting but scary
shit. Yeah. Yeah. It's like,
damn man, you know, I keep Jane,
I don't care how much stuff I have in the
pipeline. Mikey jam and more shit. Yeah.
But once, uh, so I had those
government contracts, then
I just, I just built momentum and
it started learning. All right,
let's get rid of this. Let's do more
of this. Let's not do focus on that.
Let's focus on this. Uh, and um, it grew,
it grew into a,
into a very,
it's like self fulfilling machine.
You know, it's a, a, it's,
it's, it's, it's running,
running very well right now,
but it was not easy getting there.
I mean,
there was a lot of bumps
and obstacles in the road,
but I tell guys that all the time, man,
any, any, any road we're traveling,
you're probably,
you're going to have obstacles in it.
There's going to be temptation
like shortcuts, you know,
nope. Stay on that road,
Bro. Stand that road, go through those pot
holes, go over those freaking bumps. Um,
this road it's going to suck,
but after awhile it will smooth
out and sure enough, you know,
my road smoothed out and the bumps
are few and far between right now.
Um, so yeah, man, I'm, I'm,
I'm the happiest I've ever been
in my life probably right now,
54 years old. And, uh, I, I've,
it's like I've grown up that,
but that's smart. I mean that's,
if you're a person who's thinking and
trying to do better with your life,
you should be at your best right now.
Yup.
She'll be at your best or
how you perceive things,
how you decide to approach things,
how you look at things.
So when you're doing these, uh,
these tactical courses and you're,
you're traveling so much, um, that,
that's very hard on your body. That's why
one of the hardest things on your body,
right? All that travel. Yeah.
It'll say especially so, you know,
I,
I travel with two big cases cause I
have a gun case and a gear case and uh,
uh, you become a travel pro, but it
still sucks, right? You get up early,
drive an hour to the airport,
wait an hour to get your plane,
take that plane to this place and then
you know, another plane to this place.
Getting a rental car, go to
your hotel, has a travel with
the guns too, right? Yeah.
Well only because it's different in
every airport in Alaska than you used to
guns like, yeah, yeah. Alaska,
Wyoming, places like that. Yep.
But it's different in every airport,
so there's no consistency.
Even though, you know, I know what the
webpage says, I know what it says. Right.
And I buy,
but they don't know what it says.
I have no idea what I travel with
my bow. I find that lax. Right.
Depending upon who I talked to, like
some people I go, yeah, it's a bow.
What are you doing? Oh, I bow hunt. They
go, okay, cool. That's fine. Other people,
like, I don't think you can travel with
this one. I definitely can. A manager,
let's go to the website,
Jesus Christ and uh, you know,
give myself an extra hour just in case
shit like that happens. And I do that.
I definitely,
I give that I planned for that extra now
or just in case I gotta Piss and Moan.
Right. Um, but, uh, some of
them are real smooth, you know,
airports are real smooth.
Others are painted the deck.
But people must look at you weird though,
right? Yeah, a little bit. I mean,
they know me at my airport. Um,
but you're also North Carolina.
It's a different animal to bring
something like that to California.
People are like, oh, California is not to,
it's not as horrible as
[inaudible] heaven. Yeah.
But it's not as horrible as some other
states. New York. Oh yeah. That's,
forget about it. Yeah. You can't
even have a handgun in that.
It's so hard to get a handgun. You
see, you got like New Jersey, New York,
Connecticut. Um, yeah. States like
that. Oh, Jesus freaking. Yeah.
They have very strange gun laws there.
I guess it's just because
they've got so much violence.
They thought that that was the
solution. Yeah. Yeah. I don't know.
I don't know. Do you, so do you,
uh, what do you enjoy the most?
Do you enjoy doing the social media stuff?
Do you enjoy doing the tactical training?
Like what do you enjoy doing the most?
Um, I, I like doing,
I like doing the workout
stuff more than anything, uh,
because I think with that I reach and
help more people even if they could be.
Um, and it's amazing. It's amazing.
It's like, you know, I have so many,
I don't know how this has happened,
but I bet I have morphed into this guy
who people rely on to motivate them and
they tell me, bro, you're, you're
motivated. The hell out of me,
which fires me up is my buddy. Cj
says, what motivates a motivator?
Tell him you're motivating
them, you know? So, um,
so I love doing that stuff because it
touches a lot of people regardless of
their age or their physical ability.
And a lot of guys may be, um, you know,
bed ridden with an illness or something
like that and, uh, it'll fire them up.
So I like doing that stuff. I
think next would be the, uh,
the shooting thing. I mean, I love it.
I love running courses
and meet new people.
I meet a dozen new people every week
and from all walks of life and a guy,
all different reasons. Motivations
for doing it. Yup. And, and um, guys,
you know, they'll ask me during
the class, they say, Bro, what,
how do you stay motivated to duties
almost every week? And I say,
cause I get to meet guys like you bro.
I mean it's as simple as that.
If you find enthusiastic people teaching
them, that helps a lot. Yup. Yeah.
So, you know, I like to fire people
up, but I like to get it in return.
Do you find a lot of
guys that are also retired
from the military? They,
they want to talk to you about this
because they're trying to figure it out
there.
Yeah.
Path. Uh, a couple of them have hit me
up and I am man open arms. I'm like,
let me show you whatever you want to
know cause I figured this out. So Yep.
I'm your huckleberry. Uh,
it's not many of them,
but there bang, there'll be,
you know, half dozen a year who,
who will ping me, hey, I want to
get into the training in history.
Like it's plenty of room for it.
Every guy,
no, that's either been spec ops, seal,
whatever they've been when they retire.
It's one of the hardest
moments of their life. Yeah.
It's so hard for them to find
some purpose and there's,
it's hard for them to find routes to just
to really feel like they belong again
because that life is so intense.
Yup. Yeah. Cause you have, you know,
you have meaning. Yeah. You know,
and it's, and it's, and
it's selfless. You're doing
something bigger than yourself.
Yeah.
And
so yeah, because you want, once again,
if you're just in a,
if you just find a,
let's say a job where you're working
and maybe even working for the man,
there's no more, there's no meaning
there. Right. You're not doing,
you're not a part of something
bigger than yourself. Right.
So I always tell guys, hey, when whenever
you get out, when you have you separate,
especially if you've got, you know,
20 plus years and that's a long time,
you are going to be adversely affected
no matter how bad ass you are upstairs,
you're going to be some degree. Yeah. Um,
you know, it could be a little depressed.
It could be a lot.
Um,
but if you find something and it could
be working for a charity, you know,
whatever, if you find
something that, where you could
with impunity,
go to sleep and look forward to
the next day where you say, Matt,
Tomorrow's going to be freaking awesome.
I can't wait because I got
this project pending in,
I'm going to help so many
people be better people.
Um,
then if you could do that,
I mean find that instead
of just, you know, uh,
getting stuck in a Rut, you know,
instead of accepting mediocrity, but, uh,
cause that meaning
purpose, fullness and, and,
and uh,
selfless being doing something selfless
and being a part of something bigger
than yourself is freaking huge.
Do they prepare you at all when you're
getting ready to retire? And they said,
good luck. Yup. Sianora they just figured
you're a bad ass and figure it out. Yep.
Wow. Yep. You're making the
choice because you can stay.
I know I could have stayed
another 10 years or what
have you. So you're doing it,
you're making that choice.
Did you decide to leave? Um,
there was a, uh, you know,
kind of a defining moment.
I had to do some soul searching.
Um,
it was all I had 22 years in.
I lost a couple of buds,
uh,
at that moment.
And I had two little kitties at home,
so I had to do some soul searching and I
thought, well, we'll, there'll be, we'll,
there'll be, will there be any regret
whatsoever. And I, and I thought, man, I,
I pretty much, I've done it all, you know,
as far as like special ops goes, I, I am
not going to have any Gretz cause I did.
That was a big thing, you know, will I
regret this? And I said to myself, no,
I won't. So, you know, I, uh, I
decided to retire with 22 and,
and it was all special. I
was very fortunate. My whole
career was special ops,
the whole thing. Um, but
I did regret it after,
I'm sure it take long. It was, you know,
and it got worse every year that passed,
they got worse and worse. And
I was like, man, I should just,
well, it's gotta be so hard, even for,
not just for you, but for, I mean,
not just for the soldiers,
but for the wives. Yeah.
To know that the husband is constantly
in these crazy situations overseas
constantly in these very,
very dangerous environments.
We have the stress of that.
Yeah.
I think it takes a special
kind on both sides, you know,
and usually,
uh,
usually spouses have a pretty
good support mechanism to,
with the units and other spouses
and that kind of thing. So yeah,
usually they're pretty, they're
pretty tough and they get used to it.
It becomes a way of life. It
becomes a normal, right? Yup.
But yeah, still miss it, I'm sure.
Yeah. Well, everyone I talked to does,
have you ever read, um, Sebastian
Junger's book tribe? Oh yeah. Yeah.
I just, just recently I didn't, I, uh,
listened to it on a freaking
bad ass. Yeah. I loved it. Yeah.
He's great reading it too.
It's a,
it's an excellent book and it
does it explain in your eyes,
I thought he did a pretty good job with
that whole thing. Yup. Yup. Absolutely.
Yup. I thought he was,
yeah, pretty much spot on.
I was north and south in my head as I
was driving down I 95 listening to that
book.
So it's safe to say that you went through
this period post-military where you
just were really just trying
to find yourself again, but
then you caught it. Yeah.
And then he caught it and now you seem
like you're in your glory. Hell yeah.
Like I said, I really enjoy your page,
man. Oh, right. It's really tense.
And you're also kind of, you're a bad
ass, but you're fun with it. Yeah. Right.
Good time. You know? Yeah. I, I
love, I love doing, I love the um,
both the uh,
doing the,
the Youtube Channel and a pm Ige.
And I put thought, I, you know,
I, I put some thought into it.
And your wife helped you with this stuff,
does she, she helped me set stuff up.
She's like,
cause I didn't know any of this stuff was,
so we got married and we
met in like fall of 13.
And then the first social media platform
I had was Facebook cause somebody
posing as me. Oh, that's hilarious. So I,
in order to report them,
I needed to get an account
and then once I did, I friend
requested this guy who was posting it,
pose it has me in any way. What did
he say? Why was he doing it? Uh,
I figured it out.
I did some detective work,
but he was posing as me
because he wanted a bash,
somebody else in the gun industry
and pose as somebody credible.
So this guy that he was bashing
contacted me and said, hey,
why are you saying this? And I don't
talk shit about anybody. Right. So like,
Roe, I think you got the wrong
guy. And uh, I said, just
call me up. Here's my name.
And uh, we had a Chitchat and he goes,
Oh man, I got some bad news for you.
You do have a Facebook account, let me
send me awake and everything. Yeah. But,
um, so I started that one. I
already had a couple of youtube
videos up,
but then I just went full bore with it,
you know, when, when kind of
bat shit. And then the, uh,
the ige was fun man. When Rebecca, my
wife showed me that, that was probably,
I think, uh, I think five, I'm five
years into that and I figured it out.
You know, what my audience
wants. I pay attention to,
you know, that the, the uh, analytics.
Do you really? Yeah, I,
yeah, I'll only because, um,
yeah, because I want to, right? Yeah.
Because I want to give them what they
want versus what do you get out of the
analytics? What does it show the
d, The age group, the time of day,
you know, what those kinds of things,
but also the amount of views. And, uh,
what's the other word? The, uh,
not views, but, um, the reach. Yup.
So, you know, what's the, uh,
it's the videos do the best and uh,
if they're short, like I do a lot of
around the Acom at strength training.
So I, I, uh, supplement my ebook
quick little workout snippets. Hey,
this is another example of a
power thing, blah, blah, blah.
So I'm putting information in there
as well. You know, I jot down Info,
so make sure you work in the transverse
plane. Hama Hama you know, uh,
rate of force production, no speed,
no power, blah, blah, blah. Um,
and this could be supplemented with
a resistance band instead of a wait.
So I pay attention to that stuff
because that's what people want.
That's where I get the most
feedback guys. Like, Bro,
thank you so much for putting this
sound like how right, man. So I'm hell,
you know, I know for a fact
that I'm helping people or
if I put a, maybe a course,
a fire out or talk about specific way
to clean up and break down in 1911,
you know,
whatever it is.
When I put out information it resonates
better and it seems that it's more
palatable with the,
with the,
with the masses of the people who are
following me because I get a lot and man,
I, I answer all those freaking comments.
A lot of them, I mean, I spend,
I spend how many followers
you have on ige hundred 60.
[inaudible] how the fuck can you
possibly answer all those things?
A lot of them are just hitting the like,
and sometimes that means a
lot to people. Man. You know,
I'll have guys screenshot and Pat
Max liked my comment, you know.
Um, but uh, it's a couple hours.
I'll spend I think two hours
a day is what I do. Um,
the association like email, then
I could get to work, you know,
I don't have to fuck with that anymore,
but it's usually about that much. Well,
your page makes me want to take a
tactical course. He wanted to do that.
Where would they go?
They go to my website.
Tmx Inc com to you? Anyone
out here in la? Yeah.
I used to come out here all the time.
The only reason it's not the gun thing,
just I'm getting travel every man that
three hour time zone smokes and shit out
of me. You ever go to Australia? No,
I been invited to do courses there,
but there's a whole new nother thing we
training overseas. It's, you know, it's,
it's a State Department, Department of
State thing and I tars and all that.
It's a pain in the deck,
I'm sure.
So I'm just trying to blow these guys on.
Here it is.
Take a live CST course.
Oh yeah.
The CST co I don't do them live
much anymore only because, uh, they,
they didn't,
um,
they didn't sell and Phil
will because people would,
I think they thought that it
was going to be a beat down. Oh,
you were going to go and kick
her out. But it's, it's very,
it's a lot of information and a lot
of feel and stuff out, you know?
So what is it, what is a CST course?
What, what does that mean? Uh, well,
it's basically replicating what I
have in that ebook and people say,
Bro, put this book in
hard cover. It's 35 pages,
man. It's not cost productive,
you know what I mean?
Just download it and print
it out. Would you, oh my God.
What is the CST,
CST course would replicate what I have
in that book within a day's period.
Okay.
So it's a good supplement for those who
have the book because I do all of the
classroom with a white board stuff,
you know, you break the workweek down,
power day, strength train speed
and quickness, hypertrophy
skills and then, uh,
talk about, you know, east
centric, concentric, isometric,
transverse sagittal.
Where'd you learn all this stuff?
Got To have Naza,
you know,
National Academy of Sports
Medicine because I wanted to, um,
you know, it's freaking piece of paper
to me, six months to get. But um,
I wanted to, I wanted to have a
piece of paper to back up. Right.
And that was the closest thing that
I've found to what I was putting out.
And it w it was pretty spot on.
Only mine is way cooler, you
know, it's not like the lame,
uh, you know, health club
version. Got It. Right.
More tactical and
practical, right? Yup. Yup.
So the class would,
it basically just encompass what's
in the book in a one day period.
And now it's more like tangible because
see people are touching it, feeling it,
seeing it, you know, these
certain exercises versus
seeing a picture of it. Right.
But there's a lot of good
information in that, in that book.
And then I supplement both my youtube
channel and I g with all these other
little snippets and it's hot, man.
I put out a lot of information.
I mean a lot.
So
people will get bored cause I don't want
people to get bored with their workout
chick.
I want them to,
I'll do it as teaching them how to
cook and it's showing them ingredients.
And I'll go cook your own meal and here's,
you know, here's some of the recipes.
Throw these, throw these ingredients
into your, into your pot. Um,
so that's what I do with the social
media platform is a supplement that with,
you know,
whatever.
I'll come up with some dumb ass name
for some movement that I'm doing. Uh,
but they're good,
functional, safe, low impact,
uh, movements that encourage,
you know, it's self preservation,
longevity in fitness and that brokenness
too many.
Oh my God. Too many guys,
especially older guys, you know,
doing herky jerky stuff and,
and uh, getting hurt in the gym,
especially when they take a long
time off and then forget that
their bodies 56, not
26. Yeah, super common.
So when you,
if people go to your,
was a combat strength training.com
so what it's called for the CST,
but that's not for my
courses. That's right. Um,
like tactical stuff is t Mac sync. Okay.
Is, is there a link to that from there?
Yeah, I'll call it t max is my,
that's who I am. So t Max Inc.
And then from there there's
areas of the performance. Yeah.
Cancel bastard jacket too. Yeah,
man. So this is all like V,
it's got a lot of your videos up there.
It shows you what you're doing. Yep.
And it's got all the courses and
it's kind of bad ass store too. Man.
I got some booty on that store,
so, oh tools. Ooh, get
you some. So when your,
when you put in all these different
workouts together, um, uh, how much, uh,
how much did they change? Did it like
when you, if someone goes to your,
your website and once a
fall of your courses, right,
the physical stuff. Yeah. Oh, the, the,
the core, um, work out
doesn't change that much.
The movements do.
So I break the work week down into a
POW like Monday for instance, power day,
then strength day, speed and
quickness, hypertrophy skills.
And then there's a couple, cause people
don't have five days, you could lump,
for instance, speed, power, you
can love strength and hypertrophy.
Um, the, uh, so the,
the just stays the same power day,
work in anaerobic chunks in
circuit to near metabolic too.
I show up to meet in a robe and go pick
e five good power exercises and make
sure that two of Marin transverse
plane. Um, and if they got the book,
they'd be able to, that could
sustain them for just with that,
for let's say, I dunno, whatever
months, uh, without getting bored.
But they definitely want to go to like,
uh,
some of the stuff on that I put on the
interwebs to help sustain and keep the
ideas fresh. Right. Cause we don't
want to fall into that. Once again,
that Rut of complacent adaptation,
you know,
we're doing the same shit over and over
and over day by day and too many guys do
that and it's,
it's not healthy.
I noticed you incorporate a
lot of martial arts stuff too.
Like you were doing some arm drags the
other day. Yup. Yeah. Like what do you,
what do you,
do you just do this for like practical
applications in a street fight scenario
or,
yes. So yeah, I got, I'm a
big fan of uh, different,
different fight
and you're doing all this stuff.
You do it with shoes on cause it's
how you're going to be in real life.
Most of the time
I don't go into our fight room, which
shoes because it's got mats in there.
It's nice. So you know, where we,
where we, where we grapple and work,
even work bags,
I'm bare footed,
but usually there's a lot of times
I'm working and these woods with
a gun on two, which is appendix
carry on or my tee shirt. Um,
so you keep it unloaded or oh yeah.
In the chair. Correct. So, you know,
cause it impedes your
movement a little bit. Yup.
Just to make sure that it
doesn't impede my mood,
but just to know where it is that,
right.
So there's a place where you could keep
it, where you can move just as well.
And so this dude that you're working with,
he's a wrestler. Yeah, he's good man.
Randy's good. And what is, uh,
what is he working with you on?
You're just working on this was this,
we're,
we're not the sharpest right here because
this was after a power workout where
smoked. Right. We're smoked and all
we're doing here is just control,
just stand up for control, you know?
And um, I used to be a good wrestler,
but my game is off and um,
cause but that was
decades and decades ago.
So Randy's gay.
Then he's training for a
competition and just to competition.
I think it's a, it's a kind
of a mixed, uh, uh, wrestling,
Jujitsu, a competition. I
think he's doing the wrestling,
I'm pretty sure. So I said, hey bro,
let's, uh, let's start mixing it up.
I want to get back into, um,
you know, Roland, some more,
uh,
because I'm bigger here,
so it'd be good for him because I'm
bigger and stronger than he is. So,
and then it'll be good for me too.
I used to do a lot of fight training,
especially a boxing,
kickboxing,
little tentative on getting punched
in the face anymore for your hand.
I have degenerative spine.
What's going on with your neck?
Degenerative spine, degenerative
disc disease. Right.
There's, that's very
controversial. You know,
a lot of people say that it's a disease.
Then I talked to a physiologist
and they say, well, what it is,
is pressure on your desk because you're
lifting a lot of weights while you're
involved in something that presses down
on you and then you just degenerate.
It's not like a disease that's
causing this to go away. Yeah.
That that disease air quotes almost
always happens in people that are involved
with very strenuous physical exercise.
Yup.
And so there's different ways that you
can kind of mitigate some of that stuff.
Do you ever do spinal decompression? Uh,
no. I have no, I haven't done that one,
man. There's a harness that you could
buy on Amazon. It's like 39 bucks.
Hang from a door. Yes. Yup. Pull that
click, click, click, click, click.
And it stretches sometimes.
Just that alone give you a lot of relief.
Now I do have an inversion
table and that's freaking great.
I have one of those two.
Yeah, those are great.
And then there's another
machine called a reverse hyper.
That's fantastic for your lower back.
I'll show it to you outside.
We have one in the other,
uh, in the gym area,
but that also actively decompresses and,
and strengthens all those muscles
around your back as well. But the, the,
the stuff with the neck
too, um, there's another,
there's a bunch of different
things you could do. I mean,
I don't know if you do any neck exercises,
do you, do you fuck with anything? Oh,
yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah. It at least at least once
a week. And I've got to, yeah.
I always tope guys kicked through
to got to work your neck man
ports command center. Right,
right, right. Have to now you,
you said that it's disc degeneration,
so you don't want to get choked.
Is that what it is? You don't
want to get your neck manipulate?
Yeah. Um, because like
my distal Phalanges,
there's numbness there and
uh, you know, like sleeping,
I have to sleep like a corpse,
so there's no rolling or anything.
Just straight corpse.
So the numbness is indicates
is something pressing on your,
that decompression device will help you
a lot? Yeah, it's cheap too. Like I said,
it's like 30 bucks or 39 bucks, something
like that. But that, that's soccer, man.
I get in that thing and click,
click, click, click, click,
hang in a little bit. Just,
it feels good.
It just alleviates tension.
If you could do that every day
for a few minutes, you know,
that the inversion table,
all those things, you can
keep all that stuff healthy.
Yeah. I, I it, it, it feels good.
I just don't want to get punched
facing me. I had a bunch in
a place, a lot. I hear you
man. I'm not into it either.
It's just the brain is
not designed to get right.
It was one of the things that I do like
about Jujitsu more than anything is that
you can go hard. Right. And you're not,
you know, you're not hitting each other.
There's a big difference.
You can get a full hundred percent
exertion in exercise, workout in without,
you know, risk of hurting each other.
Especially if you go with a good guy.
The guys I work with, our poll and their
fight is way better than mine. So, uh,
they not a train. Yeah. Not going to,
they're not going to jail. So important.
You know, because I've been, I've
been doing flight stuff for a long,
long time and I've been
fortunate that there's always,
there was always somebody better
looking out and say, hey, let's work.
So worked back, you know, just
tweaking, just making those tweaks.
Yeah. That's what I was going to ask you.
Do you, do you do any ground training?
Do you do any Jiu Jitsu?
Not Enough. Not Enough. Not Enough.
Nope. Um, and, and like I said,
my coaches are really good, but I
don't do enough of it. I do, uh,
I don't have a good,
I don't have a good reason.
And I just said that to him. I just
said, hey guys, I have to do more.
I gotta do more ground stuff. And they're
like, right on. Yeah. Yeah. Get in there,
man. I mean, it's humbling. Yeah. We
can do to avoid a, do you know, um,
I mean we, I do it, but not,
but not enough. Right? Yeah.
I'm very comfortable on
my feet. Um, uh, my, my,
my level of confidence,
uh, on, um, you know,
being able to punch somebody's mouth
loose without them even knowing what
happened is, is pretty. I got, I'm
pretty confident there, you know,
with, with, with, you know,
the likelihood of who I'm
going to tussle with. Um,
that's the thing though.
Yep. And plus, stop.
I got Moxie,
you know,
I got a lot of attitude and that goes
a long way, you know, having that, uh,
that could, spa, that attitude.
Sometimes it's equally
important to have that.
I have a thing in my head that says
I could beat anybody at anything.
It doesn't have to be true, but that's
what I hear in my head. Well, the problem,
oh, that is when it's obviously that's
not true. Right? Then you're like, fuck,
now what? And then, uh, then
you get experience experiences.
So can you get shortly after
you need it? Yeah. Yeah.
So it's interesting that you
combine those things though,
that you have this gym or there's
all this martial arts stuff,
the tactical stuff.
What do you do to chill out?
Because it seems like everything
is fucking Coco, coco cow.
Everything is lifting weights,
shooting and pulling, ropes,
shooting and arm dragging and shooting.
Um, what do you do to calm yourself?
I am hobby heavy. Hobby heavy. Well,
you show me your drawing. Very talented.
I, so I draw, um, I burb I
bird watch third watch. Yup.
I bet a birdwatcher since I was
10 years old. Really? Yup. Golf.
I go down this list,
guitar, drums, um, uh,
Cook. Let me see. I got so many
freaking hobbies. It's ridiculous.
And, but the good thing about
most of ms I could go to him and,
um,
and um,
it doesn't take me a lot of
time or energy to invest in it.
A fishing on big time fisherman,
outdoorsman, woodsmen type of thing.
I love that stuff.
I get into rocky mountains at least once
a year and two like privation training,
you know, just on my own. So like
what do you do when you do that?
This camp out there and live off the
land. We tried it, try it, try to sustain,
you know, with what I have and
what's available to me. And it also,
yeah. Uh, and it also includes
a orienteering, so you know,
one over 24,000 scale
topographical map and,
um, so orienteering and, and
these are wilderness areas,
not like national parks or forest. And
then, uh, try to hunt a killer, eat it.
You know, along the way. Carry,
I carry enough food so I'm not going to
be miserable, so I'm not going to suffer.
How many days do you do when you're out
there? Well, it, it now that I'm retired,
not four to five anymore,
bringing ruck sack or something like
that. So I pack in, Yup. Whatever.
A, whenever I need. And you know,
pat king a ruck is a, it's a real,
it's a, it's artwork man. Even if
you've been in the military forever,
you know,
you just never ever get that
down to a perfect science,
especially a weight cause you got, wait,
you're going to rain, you got a, you know,
the, the, uh, uh,
the situation may dictate
to strip this and add that.
And then where are you going to put it
and to bring satellite phone or anything.
We do it or you do I bring it?
Yeah, bring one of those. Yep.
You don't want to roll an ankle out
there. Well, plus I usually go to Montana,
like the Bob Marshall, so that's both
the highest concentration of grizzlies.
Lower 48. So you're not on the top of
boogy man or some big Hungary's out there.
That's a fucking scary
spot. Yeah. Well it's,
it's always usually pretty good
unless you run into a female. Yeah.
With there corrupts. That's when it
gets super sketchy. I just wrote it.
I just wrote about that. Um, I write,
so I write for a
ballistic magazine and um,
combat handguns and I just wrote an
article about that wouldn't ballistic, uh,
about what should be in your
personal survival kit. You know,
let's say you go on a day fishing
trip in Alaska. What should,
what do you have in that thing in the
event that you need to go into contingency
planning mode,
that shit hits the fan.
You got to have something
on you instead of just your,
your Orvis fly rod and a couple of beat
heads yet with the big debate with a
hunter's is should you bring bear
spray or feed you bring a pistol? Yup.
Especially both smart that I need to
anytime bear country, I bring both.
I got them both on and I've talked to a
lot of grids hunters and I put that in
that article too. It's like guys, you
know, I've done some research here.
Uh, but yeah, so I'll
bring, I'll bring both.
Have you had any encounters when you're
out a pad? Almost every year. Really. Um,
the closest one 15 yards, man. Yeah.
That was the first time ever up there
too. And I'm smoked. I'm at the end.
This is what I was doing. I started doing
these when we were, when I was active,
so bringing up unit guys and
this one was 95 miles long.
We walk from um,
uh,
a little spot on the map.
Oh,
Columbia falls south of Columbia
Falls Montana to Lincoln.
The home Ted Kaczynski. The
Unabomber recently. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
So walk this stretch and it's
95 miles right north to south.
And you've got across like three
different mountain passes and smoker.
So the s I think it was,
it was the fifth day. Yeah,
because we had one more Ron, one more rest
overnight. And on the fifth day I had,
we would walk like lines of drift
and stuff like that, you know? Uh,
and whenever I couldn't see 25
yards up ahead, I would, you know,
clap my hands, make some
racket coming through mark,
you know, that kind of thing.
Because Griz want nothing to do with you.
Right.
You get in between their young,
their food source or you
startle them. That's when you
run into trouble. Right. Um,
so I did not want to stand and here I
am, I'm, and I've got six guys with me,
but they're lagging behind.
Uh, and I, you know,
come through and I look up ahead and
this gigantic male stands up booze.
And the only thing that I could see,
my only reaction was, whoa. I mean,
I was just blown away.
15 yards is less distance
than you flew when you crash,
right?
Yeah.
It flew in the fly in the
air and pass that five yard.
That's right. Yup. Yup. He
took off. Boom. He was gone.
She was lucky. Yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah, yeah. Because I mean,
that's a lot. That's a lot of animal.
Yeah. I tell you when you're standing,
like in the woods in the wild,
15 yards,
1550 yards, and when that thing
stood up, that's all I could say.
That's all. I mean, I had
a gun and bear spray on me.
I went for neither of them
all I could think it was whoa.
And then when he took off, my next
thought was, where's my camera? Oh, Jesus.
Well that's nature's cleanup crew right
there. Anything that limps falls down,
fucks up. Yup. That's what it's there for.
That's why there's a thousand pounds
of them, man. It needs to camp eating.
It's a, it's a majestic animal. You see
one in the wild, you realize like, wow,
like this is just,
nature has a system. Yup.
They know what they're doing when
they want to get rid of a moose.
They sent one of these motherfuckers
in there. I mean, really?
Yeah. So when you're doing
these, um, these things,
are you keeping a journal when you doing
these, these trips for you by yourself?
Um,
I usually don't go by myself.
I usually have straphangers and
they're different every year.
It's a lot of times just
like this, you know, a couple
guys talking, saying, aw man,
I like to do that with you.
We'll just send me an email and
I'll send you the dates. Oh Wow.
Because one is securities and numbers,
right. Especially at Greer's country.
Um, plus I like teaching stuff. So yeah,
I'll have guys who I could teach like
orienteering and you know, field craft,
you know, making a fire with sticks
and kind of that kind of thing and uh,
the right way to maybe to prep
and cook a trout, you know?
Uh, so do you bring a rod with
you? Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
I'm one of them small breakdown
routes. A bring a foe. I, I'll,
I'll bring two of them.
I'll bring a tell us telescoping
a 10 cholera and day a four piece,
like a five weight Orvis okay.
Because it's fly rod then. Yeah.
For me, that's sustenance cause I'm not
taking a lot of food. Plus I want to fish,
I want it to be time
off and I want to chill.
I don't want to just work my
ass off when I'm on these.
So I'm out there ripping lips,
but I'm eating two of them in
the morning and two at night. Uh,
and then it's a lot.
It's a lot of fun.
I've been doing these things now since 98.
I think that's a great way to
decompress too, right? Yeah.
The places I go to,
one of them is I will lose cell coat,
cell phone coverage in our, before
I hit the end of the dirt road. Oh,
Yup. So, and then you stopped
the call. You were at the
end of the road. Now you're,
you know,
you're already in.
You're just at the edge of the Wilderness
area deep into a national forest and
then into the wilderness for, you
know, however many days, miles,
uh, we run another folks in. You're out
there. Very rarely the best. You know,
I loved walking like under 95
mile one and seeing nobody,
nobody. Yeah. I mean, these
places that are remote,
the Frank Church and Idaho,
uh,
I walked wind river and uh,
Wyoming
to the Frank Church. I walked
from the town of Salmon to McCall.
That one's smoked me. How
far is that? W W on a scale.
Things as a crow flies. It's not that
far. I think it's 60 miles or something,
but it's straight up,
straight down.
It's the most horrific and
d just terrifying terrain.
I mean, especially if
you're, you know, uh,
if your objective is to move from point
a to point B and not just an out and
back, let me see how far it can go. No,
when you got somebody picking you up at
point B and you have to be there, right?
Oh man, it is a freaking smoker. Yeah.
I've never been in the Frank Church.
My friend Ryan Callahan was living up
there for a long time and it's cool.
He says it's amazing up there.
It's also so it's so remote,
but yet it's so close to Boise.
Yeah. That far, right? Yeah. Right.
Yeah. The grand scale of things, it's not,
it's not that far. Right. But there's,
when you have these wilderness
areas, like uh, I dunno,
let's say it's 500 million square
acres or whatever it is, you know,
that's also encompassed by
national parks and stuff.
And you know,
national parks will have dirt roads and
I mean they'll have little scatterings
of population here and there,
but those wilderness series,
there's nothing in those just animal.
There's no dirt roads and it's
such a complete ecosystem to me.
You have to have everything from wolves,
the grizzlies to mule deer to elk.
It's all living up in there.
And they are cool.
I mean, I love doing those two
because you have to think there isn't,
there is an element of danger
here that that can kill me.
And it's not just a big hungry,
you could get cut
out there because nobody's coming to
get you. Even if you got that beacon,
you know, forest service and stuff,
they're probably busy servicing, you know,
grandma broke her leg trying to take a
picture of a bison in his national park
coming into that national,
that wilderness area, you know,
there's no a Chelsea's there and
stuff like that. Right. So man,
I love that, that element of danger,
especially since I retired. You know, you,
I want to be cold, tired, hungry,
and maybe a little scared. Um,
and I want that several times a year cause
uh, yeah, it's, you know, it's primal,
right?
And I think most guys need that guy.
He's a yeah, no, I think so too.
Dude, you live in a fun life, man.
Yeah, I enjoy, I enjoy following
it. Right on. I appreciate it.
I appreciate you coming on, man. I
really do do tell people one more time.
Your websites. Yeah. My,
my website is t Max Inc Com t
m a c s [inaudible] dot com.
And the other one is combat sports
training.com combat strength training's to
combat strength training.
And then I got, uh, my,
my ige is a at t Mac sync. All right.
Beautiful. It's fun. And then my,
my youtube channels, it's just
pat Mac power, Mac, youtube,
a lot of information. Good Times my
friend. Thank you. Thanks for coming on.
Hell yeah, man. Thank
you. So freaking awesome.
Okay.
Ooh.