Four, three, two, one
David. So first of all, thanks for doing
this. Oh my pleasure. And it looks at it.
How much trouble are we
in? Legitimately? I mean,
it's pretty bad already and it's going
to get, I think a lot, lot worse.
So it's not bad right now. Right here.
It's raining. It seems nice out the hill.
I mean, how long ago where the fires,
right, right when I got back, you waited.
It was October. Yeah, it was rough.
But in all fairness had been evacuated
three times over the past 20 years. Yeah,
I know the fires, uh, California's fires
are kind of interesting in that, um,
they both seem like it's like the
future of the apocalypse. They're here,
but also it's so familiar from
like decades of wildfires. Um,
but you know,
their scientific estimates that say that
they're going to get by the end of the
century, 64 times worse. What? Yeah.
I think that number's a little high
because that would mean more than half of
California burning every year. But,
um, I mean it's going to get, yeah,
it'll get,
it'll get crazy.
And there's no way to avoid any of this
wildfire stuff. Well, I mean, you know,
if we don't raise the
temperature of the planet then,
but is that the only thing
that's causing wildfire?
I mean like obviously if
the temperature raises, uh,
there's more brown dry leaves
and grass and stuff like that,
but there's a, there's a lot of
preventative stuff you can do. I mean,
not building in certain areas.
I mean it used to be, you know,
the Indians who lived here
before the white people came,
did a lot of controlled burning.
They like lived among fires. And, um,
I think that's like a probably
more responsible way to be.
But we've now built up the whole state
so that there are all these homes that we
don't want to burn their, all these
properties we don't want to burn.
And when you,
um,
when you like restrict the ability
of natural welfare's to burn,
that means that like more Tinder gets
built over time and then, you know,
at some point some thing lights
the match and it all burns.
I mean, you could, you could
do more controlled fire,
you could take more aggressive
action in terms of, um, you know,
like spraying foam and that kind of thing.
Um,
you could have a lot more firefighters,
but I was just talking to a guy yesterday,
I'm out here actually doing some reporting
on wildfires and who was saying that
no,
Santa Ana powered wildfire has ever been
stopped by firefighters and he was like,
uh, environmental historian. Wow.
It's like you can hope that
the winds redirect them,
but like the action of firefighters is
basically just spitting in the wind.
So the action is not to stop and
it's a kind of contain it. Yeah.
As best they can and minimize
property damage. Yeah. But you know,
it's hard because you have a lot more,
it's a lot easier to do that when, um,
you know, if the land was
totally raw, you'd be like, oh,
we'll just like try to direct
the fire in this direction.
But if the land is like full of
homes, you're like, well we can't,
you know what I mean? You ever seen
it live? Not a person one. Yeah.
One time we were filming fear factor
and we were a way up on the five,
like I'm probably would say maybe
75 miles from here and for a full
hour driving about 50 miles an hour,
there was fire on the right hand
side of the road for a full hour.
I mean like Lord of the
rings end of the world,
like you waiting for Satan to come riding
on a burning Phoenix over the top of
the hill. It was crazy. I'd never
seen anything like it in my life.
That was the worst one I've ever seen.
But I think that was just
because of placement.
I think that this past one was actually
worse in terms of physical damage and
size. It's just, I didn't see
it the way I saw this one.
Well, I, the last year there
were, there were flames,
like hopping over the four
oh five. I mean, and that's,
that's really like crazy to me
because, you know, I'm a New Yorker.
I've lived my whole life in New
York and I just feel in my bones,
I now know it's sort of not true,
but like my inner emotional perspective
on the world is that I live in a
fortress. I don't live in nature, right?
Like I walked down on concrete streets,
I look up at steel buildings.
Nature can't come from me,
but when you see like fire straddling
the four or five, that's, you know,
this is a major metropolis here.
Um,
and we're not safe when we're
certainly not totally safe. Um,
and that's like, for me, that's a major,
like a major revelation I've
had is that wherever you live,
no matter how defended
against nature you are,
climate change is teaching us that,
you know,
you still live within climate and when
it gets fucked up, it will fuck you up.
It will affect you in some way.
Yeah, there was, uh, the both sides of
the four oh five, we're on fire last year,
last year or the year before that, one of
those. But it was insane. It was, it's,
it was hitting bel air. And people
are like, well, this is this.
We've never seen this before.
I talked to a firefighter once,
and this was years ago,
and he told me with the right wind,
it's a matter of time for a fire,
hits the top of La and burns all
the way to the ocean. And he goes,
and there's not gonna be anything
we could do about it. He goes,
if the right wind catches and a fire
starts at the top of Los Angeles,
it'll just go straight through la.
Look at this.
What does that from Jamie or five
fire. Yeah. Okay. Oh, that's it.
That's the crazy video.
So this is bel air and the left hand side.
And so these are people driving down
the four oh five looking at, you know,
the most insane site for a place that
has 30 million people or whatever.
La has to see the entire hillside on fire.
And Bella, to me, Bella is really
interesting cause it's, you know,
most climate impacts,
they hit the world's poorest
first and like the wildfires are,
they work in the reverse because it's
like people living in the hills. Um,
those are the rich people. But it just
shows you like no matter how rich you are,
no matter how comforted by that
wealth you are like, you know,
you might get hit. Well the best
example was a point Dume yeah.
And we were flying over it
and my friend, uh, Bill uh,
has a helicopter license and so we
went around the peak of point Dume it's
crazy. You know, these are like
$20 million estates,
these massive bluff side homes.
They thought they were living in the
peak of luxury overviewing the ocean and
like, wow, we're on top of the world. And
the fire just scorched it to the ground.
Like that's what it looks
like now. It's so crazy. Well,
it's really crazy because he like,
they couldn't even,
because people have always said,
oh well they'll protect the rich
folks that in protect these ones,
they can't protect anybody
when it gets this crazy. Yeah.
I think they lost more than 600
homes in Malibu alone. Yeah. I mean,
and that's, I mean, yeah.
And you think about Miami beach
going underwater and then it's, well,
Miami beach is a weird one, right?
Because the ground is porous. Yeah. Yeah.
So it's inevitable. I
mean, I'd get out of there,
that's basically a sandbar that like
some developers and the 20th decided that
it was, oh, we could make this into a
fake paradise. Oh, really? Yeah. I mean,
there was, yeah, it was, I mean,
la is kind of the same way.
Like nobody looking at La in
1850 it would have said like,
here's a great place to build a city.
Um, but we did it anyway, like America,
and it's like imperial swagger was like,
no,
we can create some paradise out of this
completely in his biteable land in both
places. And then, you know, it's
just a lesson that like, you know,
it's just a matter of time.
Well,
the most cocky people are the people
that have those houses on stilts,
on the water in Malibu,
like I want is this
gonna work out for you?
Like this thing moves back and forth
over time. And it has forever. I mean,
if you think about like the long,
long sweep of human history,
most humans settlements didn't happen on
the coast. Right? Um, like people live,
maybe they live on a river, maybe you
have like a little community on the river,
but the, you know, the last like 50
years or a hundred years we built up,
especially in America, is so much more
on the coast and that's like, you know,
really inviting disaster. I mean, all
of Houston, like all of that is like,
that was flood that like nature was like,
you know, it was swamp land. It was,
and now it's,
you know,
new suburban developments made out of
concrete and that just means more and more
flooding. Yeah. I've been to
Houston right after floods and it's,
Houston is a crazy one that we lost.
There was a hotel we used to stay at
whenever I used to do gigs in Houston.
It's gone now because the flood waters,
it just filled up the hotel so crazy.
I actually really love that city. It's
kind of like, uh, there's great food.
Oh yeah.
Houston's super underrated.
It gets lumped into this weird sort of San
Antonio vibe. I don't know why, but uh,
I'm, I'm, I'm a big fan of Houston.
I'm a big fan of Texas in general.
They're fun people. But yeah, if
it gets hotter there, fuck too.
Cause it's just like in the
summertime in Houston, you know,
when you're dealing with a hundred percent
humidity and it's 115 degrees outside,
you can't even explain to people what
that feels like. I mean cooked. There's,
there are places in the
world that are going to be,
they're going to literally
cook you by 2050.
So cities in India and the Middle East,
you won't be able to go outside during
the summer without being at risk of dying
by 20, 50 by 2050. Like what kind of
temperature we talking about it? Well,
it's a combination of heat and
humidity. So, but you know,
usually the heat will be like up in the
up around one 30 combined with some bad
humanity. Um, but you know, they're,
they've already been, we've already
broken that threshold. Like there've been
temperature records set every year, but,
um, last year broke 130 in Oman, I think.
But like the scariest parts or not,
some of these crazy desert places that
have gotten really hot. It's the cities,
it's like Calcutta has like 12 million
people in it and it may not be able to,
you may not be able to live there
in the summer in just 30 years.
And then you just think about where
all those people are going and how much
that's going to destabilize everything.
You know, I've talked to people, uh,
who are terrified about this and I've
talked to people who are nonchalant, um,
where, where do you sit?
Are you, are you terrified,
you thinking that you're going to be
physically in trouble yourself or do you
think that with proper planning and
does not being tied to one spot,
you can move to another area?
I mean,
I have,
I have different feelings about it at
different times of day because it's that
big a story. It's like going to affect
everything. I think. Um, you know,
I think civilization is
not going to collapse.
I think there'll be people around
even living like kind of rewarding,
prosperous lives forever.
And the question is like what shaped
those lives take and where there were,
where they are. So me
personally, you know,
I'm like a relatively well off
person who lives in America,
in New York.
I think I'll be able to do okay.
I think my children will be able to do
okay. And when I imagine their future,
I think it's a reflection of all of
our kind of like cognitive biases and
emotional reflex is that when I
imagine like my daughter's future,
I'm imagining a world that seems a lot
like the one that we live in today.
But when I look at the science, um, it
paints a really, really bleak picture.
So you know,
the question of like optimism and alarm,
I think it's really all a
matter of perspective, right?
So we're at 1.1 degrees Celsius right now.
I think there's basically no way
that we avoid two degrees of warming,
which is like the UN calls,
um, catastrophic warming.
The island nations of
the world call genocide.
And that's when we would be making these
cities in the Middle East unlivable.
It would mean like some ice sheets
would start a permanent collapse,
which could all of the melted eventually
bring 260 feet of sea level rise. Um,
and we're on track for
four degrees of warming.
So that would mean $600 trillion and
climate damages by the end of the century,
that's twice as much wealth
as exist in the world today.
It would mean there'd be parts of the
world scientists say where you could be
hit by six simultaneous
climate disasters at once.
There'd be at least a few
hundred climate refugees.
The UN says the low
investment is 200 million.
The high end estimate is a billion,
which is as many people as live in north
and South America compliance topic of
resilience, six simultaneous natural
disasters at once. What does that mean?
Like flooding, hurricane,
um, famine, uh, you know,
some public health issue, um,
you know, like malaria, uh,
it's like every, every category of modern
life can be affected by this. And um,
there aren't that many
that could be hit by six,
but like already right now in
Australia there was a crazy heat wave.
It's like over 120 in lots of Australia.
They're also dealing with like epic
floods in other parts of the country.
And that's kind of the problem
actually with wildfires in California.
It's not just that it's getting hotter
is that it's also getting wetter.
So the more rain means more growth
means when it gets hot again,
that growth gets baked and then becomes,
you know, firestarter. Um, and that's a,
you know, it's not just, um,
it's not just a temperature.
It's like higher temperatures mean
crazier extremes in all directions.
And um, you know, that's why I
think sort of looking big picture,
there's not a life on earth that's
going to be untouched by this force,
like over the decades ahead.
But that's not to say that we're
all be destroyed by it either.
I think like we will find ways
to live and adapt and mitigate.
It's just a question of how much
it's going to screw up our politics,
how much it's going to change, the
way we think of history. You know,
like I'm an end of,
I'm a nineties kid.
I grew up end of history thinking
the world was going to get better,
the world was going to get richer,
globalization was progress, et cetera.
What does it mean if like climate change
completely eliminates the possibility
of economic growth,
which probably won't be the case for
the u s but there are huge parts of the
world that is going to be the case
that we don't change course now.
So like at the end of the century,
if we don't change course,
the economist studying this,
say global GDP could be at least 20,
possibly 30% smaller than it
would be without climate change,
30% is twice as big an impact
as the great depression.
How did you get involved in this?
How'd you get involved in studying this
and what was your perception before you
got involved and how did it
shift? So I'm, I'm a journalist,
I'm an editor mostly actually at
New York magazine. Um, and you know,
I'm interested in the near future.
Like as a result,
read a lot of scientific papers,
read a lot of like obscure of sub
reddits and that kind of thing.
And I'm just in 2016 started
seeing a lot more of that.
A lot more of the news from science was
about climate and a lot more of that
climate news was really scary.
And when I looked around at the other
places that like we think of as our
competitors, you know,
newspapers, TV shows,
I just felt like the scarier end of
the spectrum was just not at all being
talked about.
So most scientists talk about this two
degree threshold is like the threshold of
catastrophe.
And I think most lay people think that
that means that that's kind of a ceiling
for warming.
Like that'll be the worst it could get.
But actually it's functionally
the best case scenario.
And yet we hadn't had any storytelling,
any discussion around what the world
would look like north of two degrees.
And I just felt as a journalist,
I was like, Holy Shit,
there's a huge story here.
Like the way that this world could be
completely transformed by these forces is
not something that anybody is writing
about in part because it's a long story.
But scientists and science
journalists were really, um,
they were really focused on making sure
that their messaging was hopeful and
optimistic and they were reluctant
to talk about the scariest findings.
And so I was terrified by the science.
I looked at it and I was like,
nobody's talking about this, this
scary, got to like spread the word.
And I wrote a big piece in 2017 that was
a very focused on worst case scenario.
So I mentioned before, I think two
degrees is about our best case scenario.
Four degrees is where we're on track for
now. This piece was looking at five, six,
eight degrees of warming. So things were
not likely to get this century at least.
And it was a huge phenomenon.
It was read by a bunch of million people.
The biggest story of the New
York magazine had ever published.
And I just thought,
man,
I guess there are a lot of people like
me out there who have intuitions about
climate suffering and terror but aren't
seeing it in the way people are writing
about the story. So I
decided, you know, there's,
there's more to say and even beyond
like telling the bleak story,
telling the really dark, I'm talking
about the really dark possibilities.
I just thought there are all these
categories of life that we haven't even
thought about how they'll impact us.
So we, we know about sea level rise,
but that's like,
as I mentioned before,
that makes you think if you live
off the coast you'll be okay.
But the whole planet is
going to be touched by this.
Some places are going to
be hit harder than others.
India is going to be hit by like 29%
of all global climate impacts of the
century. Um, but everyone's
going to be affected in some way.
And the way that changes our politics,
the way it changes our pop culture,
the way it changes our psychology,
our mood, our relationship to history,
how we think about the future,
how we think about the past,
what we expect from capitalism,
what we blame capitalism for,
what we expect from technology,
what we think technology can do.
Can Technology Save us?
Can technology entertain us
while the Burt world is burning.
These are all these kind of like
humanities questions that I felt really,
really had not been talked about.
And so the book does like it's a tour
through what the world would look like
between two and four degrees, but it's
also, which is a kind of hell scape,
but it has also, you know, about half
of it is about we're going to live here,
we're going to survive. In what form?
What will it mean, um, you know,
myth at the mythological level.
What will it mean at the personal level?
What will it mean the way we think about
our kids and their futures and all that
stuff. And, um, you know, my, my,
my big picture thinking
about it is, um, yeah,
it's really bleak and I think there are
some possible ways that we could avert
some of these worst case scenarios.
I mean,
there is technology that can suck
carbon out of the atmosphere already.
It hasn't been tested at scale. It's
really expensive. But if we really,
if we can over the next decade
or two really like build it, um,
like global plantations of
these carbon capture machines,
then not only can we like stop
the problem from moving forward,
we could actually reverse it a little
bit. Um, yeah, I've seen those before.
I've seen the designs for those
where they had these enormous,
like a apartment building
sized air filter things. Yeah.
I mean it's basically like only in theory
they're there and they do exist in the
real world, but only the, either
kind of like an in laboratories.
They don't exist at anything
like the scale they need to.
But there's a guy at Harvard named
David Keith who has tested his machines.
They're able to take carbon dioxide out
of the atmosphere at a cost of $100 a
ton, which would mean we could
totally neutralized the entire, um,
the entire carbon footprint
of the global economy.
We wouldn't have to change anything.
We could suck out all the extra carbon
or putting into the atmosphere for cost
of $3 trillion a year,
which is a lot of money.
But their estimates for how much we're
subsidizing the fossil fuel business that
are as high as $5 trillion a year.
So we just redirected those subsidies
to this technology. In theory,
we could literally solve the
problem immediately. There
are other complications.
It's like in order to store the carbon,
you need an industry that's two or three
times the size of our present oil and
gas industry,
which,
and where that goes next to who's homes
and all that stuff is complicated.
But we have the tools we need. It's
just a matter of deciding to, um,
put them into practice.
And I think we're pretty like that.
You know, recent history shows that,
um, we're not doing that fast enough.
So one of the big, you know, points
that I'm making the book in I,
it's six in my heads as
strongly as you know,
we think of climate change is this
thing that started in the industrial
evolution like centuries ago,
but half of all the carbon that we've put
into the atmosphere and the history of
humanity from the burning of
fossil fuels has come in 30 years.
The last 30 years.
That's since Al Gore published his
first book on warming it since the UN
established their climate change panel.
It's since the premiere of Seinfeld.
So like you and I have lived through the
lion's share of all of the damage done
to the climate in all of
human history. Whoa. Yeah.
And the next 30 years are going
to be just as consequential.
So we brought the world from the
basically a stable climate to the brink of
total climate catastrophe in 30 years.
One generation,
we have about one generation to save it.
To me that's like,
it makes me uncomfortable
to use this language,
but it's basically a theological story.
We have the entire fate of the planet
in the hands of these two generations.
What happens 50 years from now,
a hundred years from now will entirely
be up to the way we act now and what we
do. And the timescale is so crazy
because you have this really compressed,
we must act now to avert these
worst case scenarios, timescale.
But also the impacts will unfold if
we don't do anything over millennia.
So like we could have,
you know,
if we really bring into being
the total melt of all ice sheets,
that means that eight centuries from now,
12 centuries from now,
people will be dealing with the
shit that we're fucking up today.
We will be engineering problems for them
to be solving 80012001500 years from
now and that damage will be done if
it is done in the next 30 or 50 years.
So we are,
I mean we are really writing this epic
story about Earth humanity and our future
on this planet in the time of a
single lifetime, a single generation.
And that is on the,
on the one hand it's sort of like
overwhelming but it's also empowering,
you know like um,
all the climate impacts that I talk
about all the climate horrors that are
really terrifying. If we make them
happen, we will be making them happen.
Domain input in the system is how much
carbon we put into the atmosphere.
There are feedback loops that
people are worried about.
There are things about climate that we
can't control, but at least at this point,
the main driver of future warming
is what we do. And so we could,
if we get to a four degree hellscape
with hundreds of millions or a billion
climate refugees,
that will be because of what we're doing.
It's not some system outside of our
control, even though we're often kind of,
we find it kind of comforting to think
that it's outside of our control because
that means we don't have to change it.
Well
one of the problems with climate change
is that human beings like to react to
things that are immediate
and right in front of them.
And I think for us it's very
difficult to see the future,
especially if it's inconvenient as,
especially if it does
something to inconvenience or
get in the way of our day to
day routine. And that seems to be
what happened, what's happening here.
And that seems to me,
excuse me,
that seems to me to be why people
are so willing to dismiss it.
Uh, so flippantly because in front
of them right now it's not an issue.
And in front of them right now.
This very second is very day.
I'm going to go to Starbucks. It's right
there. It's open. Look, I'm outside.
It's 65 degrees out. Global
warming's not a problem. Yeah, yeah.
No, I think that's, I mean, totally true
and I feel it in my own life. Like I,
I mean I've been living, I've been
working in this material so long,
I know it so deeply and yet when I
look out the window I'm like, you know,
things are fine. Yeah. And I think that
has a really powerful anchoring effect.
Like we expect the world of the future
to look like the world as it does today,
but all the sciences,
that's totally naive and we're going to
have at least twice as much warming as
we've had to this point.
And I think we need to think about the
future of the world in those terms.
Like what? It will be a two degrees
or three degrees at four degrees,
but it's not just like the immediacy.
I think we have so many biases that may
like we want to be optimistic about the
future. We have a status quo bias.
We don't want to change things.
We think that will be
complicated and expensive.
We have a hard time holding big
ideas in our head like that.
The entire planet is like
subject to these forces. Um,
I mean the list goes on and on and in the
book I have a little riff where I say,
you know, there's this new not
so new now 30, 40 year, um,
discipline in economics,
behavioral economics,
which is about all of our cognitive
biases. How we can't really see the world.
Every single one makes it harder
to see climate. There's this, um,
he's actually an English professor
named Timothy Morton who wrote,
who wrote a book about, um, climate
and he calls it a hyper object,
which is like,
it's a,
it's a phenomenon that's so big that we
can't actually hold it in our heads at
once.
We can only see it.
It's like if you imagine seeing a four
dimensional object in three dimensional
space, it's that kind of thing where
you can only see it at an angle only.
Climate change is so all encompassing
that we can't comprehend it properly.
Um,
but I think that's all,
all of those things are reasons that we
need to be listening to the scientists
and what they're projecting.
Not to say that everything they're saying
is going to come true will come true.
Exactly as they predict it.
Obviously that's not how science works.
It gets revised. Some things are
alarmist, some things are extreme,
something's just wrong.
But you know,
I've been really working on this stuff
for a couple of years and the number of
papers I've read that show that make me
have a more optimistic idea about the
cut future of climate.
I could count on two hands and the number
of papers I've read that make me have
a bleaker view of the future.
It's in the thousands.
And when you look at the totality of that,
whether the six climate driven natural
disasters prediction is going to pan out
exactly as those authors say, who
knows? But when you see, you know,
so many, so many terrifying
studies that you could fill.
Like I did a 300 page book with them.
You realize that like there's a huge
margin for error and it would like,
we would still be really in bad
shape, you know? Is there a,
I mean,
I'm sure there have been some studies
that made mistakes in terms of like past
studies had projected that
by now we'd all be dead. Um,
are those a PR they'll seem to be a
problem with this whole concept we have of
wrapping our head around it and if we
find anything that we could point to that
say the way back in the 80s, they said
we all be dead by now and we're fine,
we're going to be fine. That kind of
thing. Is that, that is an issue. Correct.
Totally. Yeah. There was, um,
there was a really famous book in the
Middle Of the 20th century called the
population bomb. So this is a guy
named Paul Erlick or luck, um,
who he was like,
you know,
the world just cannot
support this many people.
Like if we get to 8 billion people,
there just won't be enough food.
There won't be, you know, the,
the planet can't sustain that.
And he's often pointed to is this
sort of like profit of dooms day.
That and his prophecy totally didn't
work out because we had this thing that's
called the green revolution. Basically.
We figured out a way as to make crops way,
way, way more productive.
And that's encouraging.
Human civilization does that a lot.
We figure our way out of
Fox holes all the time. Um,
but that revolution was literally like
one dude Norman Borlaug who figured out
how to grow crops differently and one guy,
one set of innovations and he completely
transformed the whole fate of the
planet. What did he do?
He just basically did, um,
like genetically modified crops before,
like the, you know, before the name,
it was like, um, he could golden
rice guy. Yeah. Oh, okay. Yeah.
And um,
and you know,
the whole developing world benefited
enormously and you're still seeing that
today. Like we see all these charts
that, you know, so much less poverty,
so much less infant mortality in
developing world. And that's great.
That's like incredible progress.
But a lot of that has was powered
by the of those countries,
so that bill is going to
come do going forward. Um,
and you know, I think like when
you look at climate change,
you know,
if there was just one threat,
like let's take agriculture since we're
talking about agriculture estimates,
say that, um, if we continue on the path
we're on, by the end of the century,
grain yields would be half as
productive as they are today just by the
temperature effect.
So we'd have just as much land,
just as much grain crops as we have now,
but the food we get from it,
we'd only get half as
much as we got today.
What's the cause of that is just
the temperature effects plants,
the temperature alone. Wow. I mean
there are other impacts to on food. Um,
like insects, there's hotter
temperatures means more insects,
which is bad for crops. Um, carbon has a
complicated relationship to crop growth.
Like in some plants grow better,
better with more carbon,
but actually they're like the weeds and
the ones that we like to eat don't grow
better with more carbon. Um, and
you know, by the end of the century,
so we could have half as much grain and
we could have 50% more people than we
have right now. Um, now there's
a way you could imagine, oh,
well maybe there'll be
another Norman Borlaug,
maybe he'll figure out a way through that.
But when you look across the spectrum,
it's like agriculture. It's, you know,
conflict for every half degree of warming,
we need to get between
10 and 20% more war.
So if we get to the end of the century,
we're going to have more than
twice as much wars. We have to,
and this is projected because of battles
over resources, mainly that famines,
droughts, um, weather,
you know, weather impacts.
Basically everything about
unstable societies get
stressed by temperature rise.
The Syrian civil war was,
you know,
it wasn't single leak caused
by climate change, but it was,
that's one of the causes.
There was a drought and that produced it.
And that conflict,
it's not just at the level of
nation states or even civil war,
it's also at the level of individuals.
So if you look at crime statistics,
when temperatures go up, there's
more murder, there's more rape.
People get admitted to mental hospitals
more when there's, when it's warmer out.
Um, babies develop less well in
the womb when it's hotter out.
If there's for every day over 90
degrees that have babies in the womb,
you can see those days in that baby's
lifetime earnings and we're living,
we're going to be living on a
planet that's considerably warmer,
that's going to have real dramatic
effects on everything. Um, air pollution,
there's a big study that I write about
in the book that's totally alarming and
eye opening,
just between 1.5 degrees and two degrees
of warming just through the effects of
air pollution would cause at one
half degree of warming would cause an
additional hundred and 53 million deaths,
which is 25 holocausts.
That's just air pollution,
just between 1.5 and two degrees.
And two degrees for me is
our best case scenario.
So our best case scenario is 25 holocausts
worth of death from air pollution.
And that sounds terrifying. People
when I say that to them, they're like,
Holy Shit, how could we
possibly that's unconscionable.
But already 9 million people are dying
every year from air pollution and we
don't pay attention to it.
So I think the likeliest outcome,
even as we enter into
this like climate scape,
is that we find ways to turn away and
not look at like the real pain of people,
especially in the developing world. But
to answer your earlier question, you know,
like you can imagine
agriculture getting figured out,
but when you see just how many impacts
there are, it's like it's everywhere.
Everything will be changed.
And it just makes the challenge that
much bigger and more complicated because
how he, you know, how are we going
to solve the conflict problem?
How are you going to solve the problem
of having 30% less economic growth?
You know,
like I said,
that's an impact that's twice as big
as the great depression and it would be
permanent, um, $600 trillion in,
in climate damage as twice as much
wealth as exists in the world today. Um,
and that's just, you know,
then you deal with the right
refugees, food. I mean it's,
it's, it's so all
encompassing. And I think, um,
that's another reason why we don't
want to look at it closely because it's
terrifying. Well, there,
there's also a matter of how it's being
projected to the public, right? Like in,
in certain circles, particularly
right wing circles. Uh,
there,
there are people that are trying to
paint this with rose colored glasses,
right?
They're trying to maximize short term
profits and sort of dismiss the risks of
climate change and dismissed the risks of,
or rather the impact of, uh, our, uh,
what we've done in terms of raising
the carbon in the atmosphere.
There's some people that point to that
like this, this is nonsense science.
This has been disproven.
There's a few people like
that, but it's an overwhelming,
the overwhelming consensus of scientists
who studied this are terrified. Yeah.
I would say there was some recent report
that said it now past the standard of
physics that like climate science
is now more reliable than physics.
Um,
but hilarious.
But you know, the, um, to the deniers,
you say things like, you know, the
planet was hotter than this before.
That's true. Yeah. Dinosaurs lived
here. Humans, we're not here.
I mean if we're four degrees warmer for
the last time the plan was four degrees
warmer, there were palm trees
in the Arctic. Um, what's, yeah,
really,
we've already exited the entire window
of temperature that enclose all of human
history.
So the planet is now warmer than it
ever has been when humans were around to
walk on it.
Which means to me it's an open question
whether humans would have ever evolved
in the first place. And this is all from
the industrial revolution from then on.
Yeah. And uh, yeah, and
like an to that question,
it's like there are people who say
there are some natural warming going on.
I don't think that's true. I think
most scientists would say it isn't.
But I also think if what we're
seeing is natural warming,
that should terrify us even more because
it would mean that it's outside of our
control.
And if we're really heading down the path
that we're heading down and we have no
control over it,
that's even more scary.
It should be a comfort that we're doing
it because it means we can stop doing it.
Well,
it should be a comfort that there's
people smarter than the people that don't
think that we're doing it.
That there are people that can possibly
consider some sort of way to mitigate
this. And what, what are the,
what are the ways that are being proposed
and how seriously are they being taken
other than this,
um,
the idea of building these machines
to extract carbon from the atmosphere.
I'm sure you're probably aware of,
um,
there's some of the programs
that they've talked about. Uh,
we're suspending reflective
particles in the atmosphere to,
to minimize the amount of solar radiation
we receive. Yeah. So it's interesting,
this guy who I mentioned earlier
who's like done the most,
the most innovative
carbon capture machine.
I talked to him a few weeks ago
and he was like, no, no, no,
but we shouldn't be using carbon capture.
We should be doing solar geoengineering,
which is what you're talking about. Um,
and that means probably suspending sulfur
is like the most useful thing and the
atmosphere, I'm great. We're going
to smell like software. This,
the sky would get red. Oh Jesus. They're
all of these aesthetic effects too,
which nobody talks about. So like trees
are going to just turn immediately brown.
I'm not going to turn color it.
There was a study a couple of weeks
ago that the oceans are going to change
color. Um, there, this is,
if we do that, if we suspend,
this is just pure warming
just from warming.
The ocean is going to change color to
what I think just from more green to more
blue, but it'd be nice.
Yeah. Um, but yeah, so the,
the software thing is,
so we could, you know,
we could suspend these
basically an umbrella of sulfur
around in the atmosphere,
which would mean that it would,
some of the sunlight coming to the
earth would be reflected back into the
atmosphere. And that would mean that
the sun would absorb less sunlight.
I mean the earth would
absorb less sunlight,
which would make it a little bit cooler.
Um,
the problem is that would have some
crippling impact on agriculture and we
basically don't know other
side effects that would have.
And how would you take that stuff out
when you could just stop doing it?
It has a shelf life of, I don't
know what it is, 10 years.
So you could just stop doing it.
And that's a big concern actually,
because if we did that just to mask the
amount of global warming that we were
doing,
then whatever program was responsible for,
it would be really vulnerable
to terrorism, to war.
Because if we,
if we were,
if the planet were functionally warmed,
say five degrees,
but we were suspending enough software
that it was actually only two degrees
warmer than if we just,
for instance,
like somebody bombed the
facility that was doing it,
the planet would be immediately
tripped into a much,
much hotter state and that would
be completely catastrophic.
Even more catastrophic than a more slow
approach to five degrees because we
would adjust to it. We, over a
century or several centuries,
we met in ways we'd be able to adjust to
it. But if it was immediate, immediate,
why sulfur?
I think it's just something about
the particular characteristic of it.
I don't know, wouldn't it smell harm?
It would literally be like hell.
Like that's what you yeah. You always
hear about with the horror movies, right?
The devil smells like sulfur.
Yeah. And I mean it's the, um,
it's what farts smell like. Yeah.
And the reason that we were,
the reason we're able to smell farts
is because sulfur is also, I mean,
some related compounds,
hydrogen sulfide are, um,
are really toxic. And so that brings me
to methane. That's another issue as well,
right? Yeah. The cows producing methane
gas, large scale agricultural. Yeah.
Wait, let me just say one more thing about
short boom. The solar geoengineering.
So the thing about it that this is real,
this sounds horrifying. This program,
people are excited about it
because it's really cheap.
It's way cheaper than carbon capture.
And um, but so there's a positive for it.
But it's also,
um,
we are basically already doing this.
So we have what's called small
particulate pollution. Um,
that's where aerosol pollution, um,
stuffed, suspended the, in the atmosphere.
That's why like Delhi is really hard
to breathe in cause we have a lot of
particulate in the atmosphere that is
already suppressing global temperatures by
as much as a half degree or
maybe one degree, which means,
and that's the reason that those 9 million
people are dying every year from air
pollution. So if we solve that problem,
if we solve the air pollution problem,
save those 9 million lives every year,
we would immediately make the planet
at least a half a degree warmer and
possibly one degree warmer,
which would put us at the threshold
of catastrophe or above it. Um,
so we're sort of already doing this
program, just not in a systematic way.
We're doing it in a haphazard way.
Um, the methane you mentioned,
there are basically two big issues
with methane. The first is, um, cows.
Um, so yeah, cows produce
a ton of methane, which is
depending on how you count,
about 35 or maybe 85 times stronger,
a greenhouse gas than carbon.
Whoa. Yeah, it's really intense. Um,
but there are also these like small
scale studies that show if we feed cattle
just a little bit of seaweed there,
methane emissions could fall by 95 or 99%.
So we could if, if that was scalable,
which is not clear it is, but if it was,
we could immediately eliminate the
entire carbon footprint of beef,
which people talk about a lot now.
That's incredible. Yeah, it just,
it's a reminder to me that
like, you know, you get told,
oh you should eat less for
hamburgers or whatever.
But obviously this is like a problem
that's too big to be solved with like
individual choices.
We need some kind of global policy
or national policy about it.
But the scarier methane issue is,
um,
there's all this carbon stored in frozen
permafrost and the northern latitudes,
um, that permafrost is
melting and when it melts,
that carbon will be released
into the atmosphere.
We don't know the proportion that it
will be released as carbon dioxide versus
methane,
but um,
there is in that permafrost twice as much
carbon as now exists in the atmosphere,
which means if it were all released
possibly in a relatively sudden way,
it could make, um, our carbon problem
immediately, three times worse. Um,
and it could be even the effect could
even be more dramatic than that if it was
released mostly as methane because
methane is stronger greenhouse gas.
Most scientists think that that's not
something that we need to freak out about
it in the short term,
but it's there,
it is melting and methane is
being released at some rate.
So craziest solution that I ever heard
for that one was to bring back the woolly
mammoth. Yeah, yeah. They're
trying to do that. Yeah.
And the idea that the woolly mammoth
is going gonna save us all by releasing
them throughout Siberia. Yeah.
It's crazy, right? I mean,
I think that we're going to have a whole
a century of shit like that and shit
like cows eating seaweed that everything,
you know,
we'll have our global politics will be
reoriented around climate change so that
you'll start to see sanctions put against
nations that are behaving badly. Um,
NBS, the guy who's, you know,
the like kind of thug who's running
Saudi Arabia now says he needs Saudi
Arabia's economy to be totally off oil
by 2050 and I think that's cause he knows
that,
you know,
the global community will not tolerate
someone producing more oil and as
recently as you know, as, as soon as a
few decades from now. But the impacts are,
you know, everywhere. So that like, um,
yeah, like in California now you can,
you know, during wildfire season
you can buy, um, masks to, you know,
to shield yourself from the smoke,
which is really, really damaging.
Its Effects on cognitive
performance are really dramatic.
It can lower cognitive
performance by like 10 to 15%.
It's effect on the development
of kids is really dramatic. Um,
there was an incredible study a few
years ago where if you looked at places
where they instituted easy, do you have
easy pass out here in California? No,
we don't. We don't have tolls.
Oh, right. It's an amazing thing.
What one or two places
depending on where you lived.
And you'd have to take that
every day. Dude, in New York,
they're everywhere. Okay.
So it used to be the case that the cars
had to like slow down and pay a toll and
because they were slowing down,
they produce more exhaust when they
instituted easy pass cars could just drive
through and that meant they produce
less exhaust and the effect on the,
on premature birth and low birth weight
in the areas where they instituted these
new easy pass toll plazas,
it reduced them by like 15% each.
That's how dramatic just the exhaust
effect is on development of babies. Um,
how much is an effect of electric
cars? Yeah, that could, I mean that,
that will be right.
You know,
it hasn't had enough of an effect because
there's not enough of them. Yeah. Um,
and, but yeah, I mean,
that problem on the,
unlike at the technological
level has been solved.
We know how to replace
cars with electric cars.
We can make them even pretty affordable,
not quite as affordable as they need to
be, but the new Teslas are like 35 grand.
I think if you get it down to
15 grants, that'll be, you know,
that'll be a huge solution.
But then there are a lot of other
problems that are more difficult.
Like air travel.
You can't,
we don't have electric planes around
the corner. You can't fly planes.
Is there anything like that on the
horizon? There's some people who are,
who are trying to develop it,
but it seems like probably it's at
least like a decade away. And you know,
one cross country flight in the u s is
the equivalent of one seat on one Costco
cross country flight is the
equivalent of eight months of driving.
Every time you fly from New York
to London and back, you melt nine,
three square meters of ice.
Every single seat on every flight from
New York to London melts three square
meters of ice. Um, of octagon. Yeah.
That's insane. That's real. Yeah. Yeah.
I think it's heavy at the time
you fly across the country.
It's like eight months
of driving. Yeah. Whoa.
So globally air travel is only
2% of the carbon footprint.
So it's relatively small,
but for people in especially
rich people in rich countries,
it's a much bigger part of the foot
then fly around all but yeah, no,
the average American,
I think the stat is the average American
every year amidst enough carbon to melt
10,000 tons of ice.
Jesus Christ.
That's just the average American.
And if you're a person like me who
flies like every other weekend,
it's way worse. Way Worse. Yeah. Oh,
so holy Shit,
you put it in that perspective.
It's how much fucking ice is there?
I mean, there's a lot of ice. Yeah.
But it's going to melt. Well, that's how
you get the out. The outside projections,
the high end projections for sea
level rise or 260 feet. No. Um,
the plus sign is, it's way better to
get hotter than it is to get colder.
Right? Like ice ages kill everything.
Well the, you know, the, each of the,
so there've been five mass extinctions
and planetary history in Earth's history
before one of them was killed,
was caused by an asteroid,
but the other four were um,
were produced by global warming
related to greenhouse gas. Um,
and one of them, the Ice Age, well,
the ice age doesn't count. It didn't,
didn't kill as many know really the,
the biggest mass extinction,
the end Permian extinction, which
is 250, 2 million years ago,
90 to 95% of all life on earth died.
When was that? 252 million years ago.
So each of these mass extinctions,
basically it's like a complete slate
wiping of the evolutionary record.
It's like we're starting over from
scratch. So we want to think that the,
the asteroid that hit the Yucatan did
the most damage in terms of the fossil
record. Is that not true?
Is the one that was the,
the global warming was that
more? Well, this other,
there are five and four of them were
from global warming and the worst,
the worst one was just from, from
greenhouse gas warming. But yeah, the,
the one that killed the
dinosaurs was also really bad.
It was something like
70% of all life on it,
but it's less than the one where there
was a temperature rise. Yeah. Wow.
There was a, um, a volcano, this
is a little bit sketchy science,
but there was a volcano explosion,
um,
something like 30,000 years
ago or something. I don't
remember the exact dates,
but that volcanoes can cool,
uh,
global temperature for the same reason
we're talking about with suspending
particles because it basically
clouds the atmosphere with, um,
and it dropped global temperatures.
I think it was two degrees and the human
population at the time then shrunk to
7,000.
There was this incredible bottle of that.
A bunch of times it's less
people didn't live on Nantucket
and it just,
it just makes you see,
like everything about the way that we
live on this planet is dependent on
climate conditions. Yeah. Like we'll
figure a way to like have a civilization,
but it will be transformed.
It will be very different if the
world is four degrees warmer. Um,
and you know,
everything about the way that we take
for everything we take for granted today
is like a permanent feature
of the modern world.
I think we're going to learn is much
more precarious, much more unstable.
Um, and yeah, like I
said earlier, you know,
climates were stable for
all of human history. That's
how we were able to evolve.
It's how we're able to invent agriculture.
The part of the world where we did
invent agriculture in the Middle East,
it's now getting almost
too hot to grow crops.
It's also going to be too hot to go to
Mecca for pilgrimage in just a couple of
decades,
whether it like we're entirely outside
of that window of temperatures,
which means we're functionally now living
on an entirely different planet than
humans ever lived on before.
And it's gonna keep changing.
So by the time we get to two or three
or four degrees will be a living in a
climate that's you know,
two or three or four times as much
different as the one that whereas now from
the one before the industrial
revolution and yeah,
it's like those impacts could be
totally overwhelming and catastrophic.
Now the Al Gore film is something
that scared a lot of people,
but it was also very widely dismissed
by a lot of the people as well.
How accurate was that movie?
I think it,
it proved to be too sanguine it like
it didn't deal with a lot of extreme
weather. I thought that stuff was far
away and I think this is one of the,
one of the big shortcomings of
most writing about climate, most
kind of communication about climate for
25 years is that we were told it was
slow.
We were told it was going to be coming
maybe at the scale of centuries,
something we'd have to worry
about for our grandchildren.
But when you realize that half of all the
damage we've done has been done in the
last 30 years,
and you see already the extreme weather.
We had a global he wave last summer,
totally unprecedented.
People died in Canada. They died in
Russia, they died in the Middle East.
The same season.
3 million people were evacuated in China
from a typhoon unprecedented rains in
Japan. We had multiple hurricanes
in the Caribbean all at once.
There was an island in Hawaii,
east island, a small island,
not one that most people have gone to,
but got literally wiped
off the map by hurricane.
They're thinking about inventing a new
category of hurricane category six.
All of these impacts, um, were,
are coming much faster than scientists
predicted even a decade or two ago.
And so I think the first inconvenient
truth is a little too complacent,
but Al Gore is also, you
know, I know him a little bit.
I've talked to him a few times. He's,
I'm temperamentally, he's a technocrat.
He's an optimist.
He thinks market forces can solve all
this stuff and I don't even totally
disagree with him. Um, I think that
market forces are really powerful.
We've had a huge green energy
revolution in the US that's, you know,
and had spillover effects
elsewhere in the world.
So solar powers now cheaper than anybody
expected it would be a decade or two
ago. Although it's also the case that we
haven't replaced any of our dirty energy
with it.
We've just added to our capacity.
So the ratio of renewable energy to
dirty energy is now the same as it was 40
years ago. Who made no progress.
Um, why is that? Because we just,
if we're like, rather than saying, oh,
let's retire this coal plant and replace
it with a, you know, a wind farm,
we think, oh, we'll have the coal plant
and the wind farm will have more energy.
You know, we just grow the pie of
energy and this is unnecessary.
It's not because there's
just a massive demand.
Is it just because they don't
want to end that industry? Yeah,
I mean there is a demand.
People like energy.
Trump was talking about clean
coal and everybody was like,
what the fuck are you talking about?
Clean coal? I mean, I think on some level,
American policy is a red herring.
The U S is 15% of global
emissions. Um, and we're falling.
The future climate of the world will
be determined by China, by India,
by sub Saharan Africa. Those are
carbon footprints that are growing.
China's now almost twice as big a
carbon footprint as the u s and they're
building all this infrastructure outside
of China that doesn't even count, um,
in Asia and Africa, you know, the
belt and road, you know, this project.
So basically taking the model that the
US had with like the Suez Canal and the
Panama Canal and they're building the
infrastructure of the developing world.
So recently they, they loaned, um,
Kenya a huge amount of money
to build a new rail line,
which was, it could being built with
Chinese workers. They built the rail line.
Um, then they can, you
couldn't pay back the debt.
So China is threatening to take over
the entire port of Mombasa as debt
repayment. And this is like going on all
around the world. Highways across Africa,
across Asia are being built by Chinese
workers as an in an effort to build a new
m imperial infrastructure for themselves.
And is the thought that they're doing
this in terms of setting up the debt in a
way that's unpayable so that they
could take over. I, that's one motive.
I think that the Kenya exam, but
they'd be happy if the deck got repaid.
I think it's,
they're,
they're stitching together an alternative
to the western infrastructure of trade
and transit.
They're basically stitching together an
entire second system of how the world
will work, how the economy will work and
it will be conducted through their own
infrastructure and through their own
ports and through their own airports.
And that's being done
by their own standards.
So China is now pouring more concrete,
um,
every three years than the entire,
than the u s poured in the entire
20th century. She's crying.
If concrete work country, it would be
the world's third biggest carbon emitter.
So the, the, the path of development
of these other countries, China, India,
and sub Saharan Africa are really what's
going to be writing the story of the
future.
America has a kind of,
I think like a moral obligation to lead
because historically we had the biggest
carbon footprint.
But at the moment we're a relatively
small part of the problem and within the u
s market forces are doing a lot of, are
making a lot of progress for us. Um,
so the real issue is how do we figure
out a new geopolitics that forces
countries like China to act better?
And one answer may be as weird as
it is to say that, um, you know,
Xi Jinping is basically a dictator.
If he wants to impose new standards,
if he wants to invest
aggressively in green energy,
he doesn't have any of the AHP political
obstacles that we have in the u s and
so there's this sort of weird sympathy
among American climate people for that,
um, authoritarianism. And he has,
especially since Trump has been elected,
being a lot more aggressive talking about
climate because he sees if America's
not going to be leading,
this is an opportunity for China to
be like the real face of climate.
And that means they've paid, you
know, they've invested a ton in,
in solar and wind.
They've done a lot with air pollution.
So Beijing used to be really awful in
2013 they more than a million Chinese
people died of air pollution
and now that's much better.
Um, what have they done?
Just imposing stricter standards
on, um, on pollution, emissions,
coal plants, things like that kind
of stuff. Yeah. And um, but you know,
we think about, we think about
carbon and the whole problem,
I think a little too
much in terms of energy.
Energy is just 30% of the
global carbon footprint.
And it's the easiest one to solve
because wind and solar is actually really
cheap. Now. Most parts of the
world is cheaper than dirty energy.
What's the majority of the footprint?
Well, it's all, nothing's a majority.
So there's energy, there's infrastructure,
there's transportation. Um,
and agriculture is like a
huge underappreciated part
of it. It's something like,
I don't know, 30% of the
global footprint. Um,
is it because of tractors or what does
it recover? Everything. Everything.
Everything that you need
to do to run a farm.
I mean really everything you
need to do to live in the world.
It has some kind of carbon footprint.
But you know,
if we were able to like
feed all our cattle seaweed,
that would have like a big,
that would have a big impact. Um,
but all kinds of crops have, um,
have carbon footprints and they,
but they would still have to do
something to get the seaweed and have the
seaweed travel, the seaweed to deliver it
to these farms. Well, you could also do,
you know, you can imagine lab grown meat
having a much smaller carbon footprint.
Um, I mean, it should, if it like
proceeds as we expect it will. Um,
and like I said before, like when
you look at each particular threat,
there's like, you can see reasons
for optimism. You can see like, oh,
we'll figure it out in this way.
We'll figure it out in that way.
But the UN says we need to have all of
our global emissions by 2030 to have a
chance of a Verdin two degrees of warming,
which they call catastrophic warming.
And the projects that we need to put into
place in those 11 years are just much
bigger than I think we're
capable of pulling off.
They say the UN says what is necessary
is a global mobilization at the level of
World War II against
climate starting this year,
2019 and there's just no chance to
work in to do that anytime soon.
I mean, maybe 10 years from now we'll get
there. That may even be optimistic. Um,
but the total decarbonisation that's
required is we need to totally zero out on
carbon by 2050 they say. Um,
and I just think, you know,
a lot of these sectors are much trickier.
We could maybe zero out on energy,
zero out on carbon when it comes to
energy in 15 years if we want it to.
But again, that's just 30%
of the total problem. Um,
which is why I think there's
the negative emission stuff,
the carbon capture so important because
it will allow us to move more slowly
than the UN says we need to.
And still if it works out,
you know, keep the planet relatively
stable, relatively livable. Um,
but that's, you know, those
technologies have been called magical,
magical thinking by the journal Nature,
which is like the biggest scientific
journal, um, writing about this stuff.
So it's sort of a leap of faith to think
that they could solve that problem.
Do you think that we're dealing with
like shifts in degrees of perception that
it, it is things like your book,
things like Al Gore's movie,
things like,
you know,
anytime there's a new story that's
written in the New York Times or in any,
any periodical,
we need more of this.
It needs to be hammered home
to people that it's neat.
It needs to be something that's a
global discussion that accelerates.
Totally. And I think that that's
happening. You know, I think, um,
there was this big report that the UN
did in October that spurred a lot of
conversation about it.
And I think in a grotesque way,
the best teacher is just extreme weather.
You know,
when you see every year these California
wildfires, every year they're burning.
And that is really dramatic.
People I talked to in Europe are
focused on the California fires,
even though they have
wildfires over there.
There's something we had the California
fires that they're really worried about
when you see these global heat waves,
when you see unprecedented
hurricane seasons,
we just had the typhoon in
the Pacific in February,
first time in recorded
history. Um, you know,
when every day on the news there's
some, um, there's some, you know,
dramatic extreme weather and when
they come one after the other,
I think that's a really powerful
teaching tool. So, you know, there's,
this term is now outdated,
but 500 year storm,
you hear a lot about 500 year
storm means, you know, a,
that would hit a particular area
once every five centuries, right?
That means five centuries ago there
were no white people in America.
So that means we're talking about a storm
that would hump come once as colonists
came to America as they,
you know,
committed genocide against
native Americans as they
built their own empire, say,
built an empire of slaves and
cotton as they fought a civil war.
They fought world war one's, they fought
World War II. Everything that we've done,
we'd expect one, one storm
of that kind. In that time,
hurricane Harvey was the third 500 year
storm to hit Houston in three years.
We are living in such
unprecedented climate that
it's impossible to look at the
news and not learn that despite
all of our inclinations,
all of our reflexes to look away,
I think it is seeping in.
I think people are beginning to be more
alarmed about it and I think alarm is
really useful. There are people in the
climbing community who think, you know,
it's, it's dangerous to scare
people. It turns them off.
But I'm somebody who's
awakened to this out of fear.
And when I look at the history
of environmental activism,
when I look at activism generally it's
like we don't try to get people to stop
smoking cigarettes by like
messaging through optimism.
We tried to get them to stop because we
tell them how bad it's going to be for
them. Drunk driving, nuclear
proliferation. Same thing.
Rachel Carson wrote silent
spring about pesticides.
It was called hyperbolic alarmist.
It led to the creation of the EPA and
you know when you think about that UN
directive that we should be mobilizing
at the scale of World War II to come back
climate.
We then fight World War II out of hope.
We fought world war two out of panic and
I think that that should be part of how
we think about this story.
Obviously I think, you know,
when I look around the world, when I talk
to anyone, when I talked to my family,
when I watch TV, when I watch
moot, whatever, read stuff,
it just seems obvious to me that there
are many more people who are still too
complacent about this issue. Even if
they're concerned about it a little bit.
Even if they're aware of it.
Um,
they don't think of it as like the
overarching all encompassing story of our
time that requires an
existential response.
And even saying those words make me
uncomfortable because I like, it's hard.
It's hard for me to believe that the sky,
the threat is that big,
but that is what the science
says. Um, and like I said before,
some of that science is
not going to get born out,
but when you look at the full scope
of it and just how, just how large,
just how bleak the impacts will be,
you realize like,
we really need to wake up to just how
dangerous a world we're heading into and
do everything we can to avoid it.
Um,
in addition to probably planning to adapt.
Now you live in New York where
you live in, in New York,
when Tribeca flooded a few years ago.
Yeah. What was that like? Well, I mean,
I think in a situation like that,
um,
most people emerge from a
particular disaster. Think, my God,
since this is so awful,
it must be an anomaly.
And you know, I think New York was
really horrified as a city by Sandy,
but there's going to be, sandy is,
I don't remember the exact stat,
like once every five years
by category storm Sandy,
I think it made landfall as a category
three so it's not even a five. Yeah.
So if a five hidden, is it possible for
five to hit New York as a too far north?
No, as possible. Totally possible.
I was talking to a really prominent
climate scientist a few months ago who is
like one of the, he was one of the
lead authors on the, the UN report, um,
lives in New York, does a lot of
consulting with the city. And I said,
so we're going to build a sea wall
to protect New York from flooding.
And he was like, oh, absolutely.
You know, Manhattan real estate,
it's way too expensive to let flood.
So we'll definitely build a seawall.
But an infrastructure project like that,
it takes at least 30 years to build.
And if we started right now,
we wouldn't be able to finish in time to
save Howard beach and parts of Brooklyn
and Queens. We started
right now, he said, he said,
the city knows this and you'll
see in the next few years,
they'll stop doing
repairs on infrastructure.
They'll stop attending to the subway
lines and those neighborhoods.
And even a few years after that,
they'll start staying explicitly
to the people who live there.
You might be able to continue living
in these homes for a couple of decades,
but you're not going to be able to live
them, leave them to your kids. Whoa.
This is in New York City.
It's like the richest country in
the richest city in the world.
And he a huge parts of,
um,
huge parts of southern Brooklyn and
Queens are going to be underwater.
So for the people that live there right
now, what parts are you talking about? Um,
well, the one that, the
one that he mentioned most
explicitly was Howard beach,
but, um, which is, it's
kind of an interest.
It's like a mob neighborhood and you
know, it's still, yeah. Really well.
Yeah. Yeah. That cause that was like
the Gotti neighborhood, right? Yeah.
That's where they buried
all the dead bodies. Wow.
I didn't know that was still a
mob neighborhood. Well, you know,
to the extent that there
is a mob. Yeah. Um,
and yeah, I mean that's true
everywhere on the coast, everywhere.
It's not just New York. New
York's not exceptional. You know,
their projections that like $30 billion
of New Jersey real estate could be
underwater by 20, 30, 20, 30.
Why does that not as alarming
was born in New Jersey. It's
not as alarming. And then,
you know, Miami beaches,
you know, Miami beach has done for, yeah.
Miami beach is almost inevitable. Correct?
Yeah. Yeah. I mean, you know,
they could, they could build
a seawall, but that, those,
that's not going to help because
of the, the ground. Right.
And it's just so expensive.
So you really have to, um,
you really have to pick your poison and
then when you look around the world,
you know,
it's like Bangladesh,
that country's going to be
almost entirely underwater.
That's hundreds of millions of people.
If we wanted to build a sea wall,
they can't afford that. Who's going to
afford, who's going to pay for that?
And this is all because of the raising
sea level because of the melting ice,
because of the temperature and all of
this is happening. And I think, you know,
we think of sea level is really a
thing that happens on the coastline,
which it is primarily,
but it also increases flooding on rivers
because the water is all connected of
course.
So flooding in the UK is expected to
grow 50 folds by the end of the century.
What? Well that life d
fold London is already like
underwater a couple of times a
year. I mean not the whole city, but
what does this Jamie, this is Bangladesh.
I just went to oh no, dash
under water. She's like a
video that pops up. Oh my God.
These people are fucked. Yeah. It
says 18 million residents live here.
That's a swamp. Yeah.
That looks crazy. Like it.
Like if you are a real estate projector
and you're flying over that, uh, yeah,
yeah, yeah. We can't build here. Yeah.
Jakarta will be totally underwater.
[inaudible] apartment buildings.
Like you could see the water level.
Look back up a little bit.
This is just a running little,
but if you see it look at like doesn't
that look like a water level and the the
apartment buildings in the right hand
side near where your cursor is like,
like that's going to go up to where
that orange level is fucking Christ.
Well, I mean over millennia where
they're going to rise hundreds of feet.
Oh God.
I mean it's going to take a long time
so you can adjust to that a little bit.
But um, but that's always been
the case, right? The, the,
I mean they're still fine.
They find these artifacts and things in
the middle of the ocean in areas where
people used to be able to live and
now they can't live anymore. Yeah.
I think that'll be, we have
to move, people have to
move. So what's a good spot?
Alberta? Good. Anyone
anywhere off the tin? Yeah.
That's the spot now.
I mean,
I think I would like ask me that
all the time and I say, you know,
honestly the place that I would move
to is somewhere in Scandinavia really?
Because, um, you know, I talked about
the impact of economic growth before,
but they're going to
be parts of the world,
the benefit economically from this
anywhere in the north. So Canada,
Russia and Scandinavia will benefit
because, but why don't go to Scandinavia,
go to Canada. It's right there. Well
let's get the navy yard at me. Yeah.
I mean I can, Scandinavia is nice,
but Canada is like our neighbors,
although they also,
they have wildfires there to Canada and
in the Arctic Circle and Finley tells us
bears and outlines. But
so you know, these guys,
the economist who studied
this stuff say that, um,
there is actually an optimal
temperature for human productivity.
It's 13 degrees Celsius,
which is the historical media and
temperature of the u s it's also the
historical media in temperature
of Germany. What is 13 Celsius?
Was that 60 degrees or
something like that? Yeah,
I think it's like in the high fifties.
Well,
we've got Jamie,
Google doesn't give it to you
whenever I'm in Canada.
I'm always like, I don't know what you're
saying. Yeah. They were like, Holy Shit,
it's 22 degrees, 55. Um,
and so for every degree
north of that you lose about
a percentage point of GDP.
So the US is now at about 13 and a
half a degree Celsius at a median
temperature.
That means that we're losing about a
half percentage point of GDP every year
from it.
But there are parts of the u s that were
cooler than 13 and are now brought up
to this optimal level. Silicon valley is
like exactly at 13 degrees right now. Um,
which is, you know, notable cause
they're like super productive. Yeah.
And that's going to be, so that'll
be true for Scandinavian generally.
And it may be part of the explanation
why there's been so much economic
productivity and Scandinavia of the last
generation is that they have already
started doing better with temperature.
Crops are going to be
more bountiful in Russia.
Like Russia will have better
agriculture because of global warming,
which is why they, they make
such a, you know, there,
there is such a complicated figure in
the geopolitical story about climate.
So they are a petro state.
They have almost all of their economic
activity activity has to do with burning
oil, but they're also poised
to benefit from warming.
So they're doubly motivated to produce
more global warming and they have such a
fuck the rest of the world perspective
that they're not going to stop.
Whereas Canada probably
they're like likely to,
even though they'd
benefit from more warming,
they'll probably get on board with any
program to avert warming. But that is a,
um, that's a dilemma that
faces every nation. You know,
like Justin Trudeau gets,
you know,
talks a lot of shit about Donald
Trump and his climate policy. But he,
Justin Trudeau's also approving new
pipelines on Glen. Marco does the same,
but she is retiring,
um,
nuclear so quickly in Germany that
they're having to use dirty energy. Um,
and even though they've had this
incredible green energy revolution there,
their emissions are going up. Um,
and every country in the world is,
it's a collective action problem.
Every country in the world is incentivized
to behave badly and let the rest of
the world clean up the mess.
So I was talking to this guy yesterday
about wildfires and he was like, you know,
California is doing so great, you know,
with all of the emission standards,
they're basically,
you know,
holding themselves to the Paris accords
even though the country as a whole isn't,
but that impact isn't local.
It's global. So it's dissipated.
The temperature impact on California
wildfires will be determined by it.
Like I said earlier, basically what
China does. So in terms of, you know,
what any individual area would any,
any individual nation is doing,
the motivations are really,
really complicated there.
And in California in particular,
this is a bit of a tangent, but, um,
you know, the state has done incredible
stuff with emission standards,
fuel efficiency,
green energy,
and yet all of those gains now are wiped
out every year by the fires because
fires are trees,
trees or burning trees are basically
coal in the sense that they are stored
carbon when they burn,
they release carbon into the atmosphere.
So every time there are wildfires like
they were last year in California,
it literally wipes out all of the
progress that the state made in all of its
green initiatives that year.
Um,
okay.
Yeah. And you know about,
in, in, in Brazil, the, um,
the president of Brazil wants to
like basically de forest, the Amazon,
the Amazon is responsible for something
like 30% of the world's oxygen, um,
and is a huge sum. All plants obviously
absorb carbon and produce oxygen.
Um, so plant life is really good
for fighting climate change.
When you say he wants a divorce, the
Amazon, like at what scale, what does he,
what does he talk about doing?
So the scientist who studies
his proposal say that, um,
his plans would be the equivalent
of adding over a 10 year period,
adding a second China to the
world's global footprint.
Jesus Christ. Yeah. And this is just
a pump up Brazil's economy. Yeah.
Well he has a kind of a trumpy like
I'm gonna fuck the environmentalist's
perspective too. So he's just like a
little bit like, you know, whatever.
Flipping the bird to
people who care about it
and then just makes you think that like,
it seems crazy now,
but it really won't be crazy.
I think a generation from now for another
country to threaten at least sanctions
and maybe military action to deal with
that. You know, after World War Two,
we built a whole liberal international
order around the principle of human
rights.
That would have been unthinkable in
the 20th and yet it led to a series of
military invent interventions
over the next century,
half century because people were
behaving badly toward thrown citizens.
If we could do that.
It doesn't seem all that crazy to me,
that say 30 years from now unempowered
imperial China looking at someone like
Boston Arland Brazil would just be like,
no, you can't do that. I'm just gonna.
We're just gonna go in and
like take you out. Yeah. Um,
and this is what I mean when I say it's
a kind of all encompassing all impacting
threat. Our politics will be shaped by
it or geopolitics will be shaped by it.
Our, you know, everything
will be shaped by it.
We could have climate wars like in the
not too distant future. Jesus Christ.
How is this being received? The book,
Yeah. Are People, people resisting him?
Is there any anybody that wants to
debate you on this? So I, you know,
I wrote this article a couple
of years ago that produced,
I mean it was a huge
sort of viral phenomenon,
but it produced also some scientific
criticism and um, you know,
we published a fully annotated version
where every single lot we showed where
every single line came from,
but there were still scientists who were
arguing about whether the messaging was
precisely calibrated, whether
it was too bleak to dark. Um,
the book has had none of that.
I mean, it's, first of all,
it's been the best at first week it was
on the times bestseller list number six.
It's bestseller in England. It's
been in the Amazon top 10. Um,
and all of the reviews have been really,
um,
I think this goes to what
you were saying before.
I think like the conversation is changing.
People are actually really interested in
talking seriously about just how a deal
this is in a way that they might not
have been just a year ago. Uh,
where is the resistance though?
Is there any resistance to it right now
to the book? Well, not just the book,
but just the concept in general. 73% of
Americans believe climate change is real.
70% of Americans are concerned about it.
Those numbers are up 15% since 2015.
Who are the 27 that don't, I mean,
I think it's, you know, it's a hard
right wingers. Yeah, yeah. But you know,
those numbers are,
we live in,
we live in a culture now where like
most people's worldview passes through a
prism of partisan politics.
So like, you know,
there's amazing studies that show
that in the not in the early nineties,
there was no partisan
divide between, uh, on the,
on the question of whether Oj Simpson
was guilty when you controlled for race.
Republicans and Democrats had the
same idea about Oj Simpson's guilt.
That is totally unthinkable today.
And there's now a huge partisan split
on whether 12 years a slave deserves an
Oscar. Partisanship has
like totally taken over our,
our minds such that the fact that we
have 73% of Americans believe global
warming is real and happening.
To me that's a really fucking high number
actually, because one of the two part,
I don't think that the Republican
party is really anymore a denier party.
I think they're just a party
of skeptics and self interest.
They want to like look out
for business interests,
which actually the calculus
there's changing I could
talk about in a second. Um,
but people don't want to believe that
horrifying things are real because who
would, it's terrifying.
Um, but 73% of the country,
that's a lot. I mean that's, you know,
that's more support than there
is for just about anything. Um,
so I'm like basically,
and the speed at which that those
numbers have grown is really dramatic.
I said 15 points since 2015 eight
points just since March has moved up.
That's incredible.
Um,
and I do think that the economic
logic is really powerful here.
So it used to be the case
that there was economic,
conventional wisdom that action on
climate was going to be really expensive
because you know,
we're required massive upfront investment
and it would mean also foregoing
economic growth.
But all of the new research the last
couple of years reverses that logic.
Totally.
So there's a big report 2018 that said
that we could add $26 trillion to the
global economy through rapid
decarbonization by just 2030. Um,
we could avoid all of these horrible
$600 trillion impacts that we're talking
about if we decarbonize rapidly.
And there are also obviously
business opportunities there,
their whole solar empires to build their
whole new electric grid to build. Um,
so the economic conventional wisdom
has now that fast action on climate is
better for the economy than
slow action on climate.
That hasn't yet totally taken over the
perspective of our policymakers globally.
But I think it will soon and when it does,
I think that we'll see like a real sea
change in, in their um, perspective.
Because I think for a long time, even
people who cared about climate thought,
well I want to do something,
but if I have to like costs and people,
some jobs and costs like a
percentage point of economic growth,
that's not worth it.
Let me just kick the can down the road.
This is a slow moving phenomenon.
We'll invent our way out of it.
We'll grow our way out of it.
But all the new research says like,
let's get started right now and
we'll see how that plays out.
I mean,
if we really have to have global
emissions by 2030, it means really,
really aggressive action,
which I don't think is possible.
But I do think that we'll see much more
aggressive action in the decade ahead
than we've had in the decades past.
So you think that once there's a
financial incentive for people to, uh,
either,
uh,
some sort of an industry that reduces
carbon or something along those lines,
industries that are working
to mitigate global warming,
that once there's a financial sort of a
benefit for these people to innovate and
to, to move forward with this, that that's
what we're going to see. Real change.
Yeah. Well also that, um, I mean direct
investment of particular companies,
but also, you know, government
leaders who look around and say,
if the economic picture is going
to be better 10 years from now,
if we make massive investments in
green energy than it would be, and,
and even like pass laws,
regulating safety, fuel efficiency, or
even banning internal combustion engines,
which I think will happen
within a couple of decades. Um,
if that's going to be at the economic
picture taking that path as much rosier
than the economic picture of inaction,
I think they'll go down the path of
action. Right. Um, and you know, again,
the question is how aggressively,
how quickly, um, and in what form,
but I do think that,
you know,
I do think the incentives
will be different five years
from now than they looked
five years ago. And that'll
be, that'll be huge.
So that,
that you think would be a great motivator
for people to shift their perceptions
and uh,
particularly right wing folks maybe
amongst the 27% that are in denial? Yeah.
Well, I mean, if you
look around the world,
denial is not really a problem anywhere,
but the u s there's a
little bit of an in the UK,
but it's a totally American phenomenon.
And when you understand that the u s
is only 15% of all global emissions,
cause that's just typical American
arrogance, like what did, what do,
what do you think is the root
of that? Uh, I think it's,
it's basically bad behavior
by the oil companies. I mean,
they've like put out really
aggressive disinformation in denial.
You ever see the movie a
merchants of doubt? Yeah,
yeah. Perfect example of that.
Right? Yeah, totally. Um, yeah, and, and
I know the people who wrote the book too,
who are really, really
great. Um, and you know,
it's especially horrifying because in
the sixties and seventies that the oil
companies were like doing some of the
most ambitious research on climate.
So there, you know, then they ended
up suppressing that going forward.
But they knew shit about how the planet
was going to change before any of the
rest of us. Really. Um,
no alternatives back then. And there was
no real emission standards like this.
That's when catalytic
converters started being inactive.
Yeah, well you know, somewhere on them,
if we had started decarbonization in 2000,
which just coincidentally was the year
that Al Gore won the popular vote for
president,
um,
we would have had to globally
cut emissions by about
3% per year to get below
two degrees.
We're now at a spot where we have to
cut them by about 10% per year and if we
wait another decade, we're going to
have to cut them by 30% per year,
which is like an unthinkable rate.
So we wouldn't have had to
take such aggressive action.
If we had started early,
we would have had to just be doing
moderate kind of on the margins changes.
But we're now in a situation where
the problem is way too big for that.
And there are people who want to talk
about the solutions that could have been
useful 20 years ago.
Now I'm talking about the carbon tax
is like one quite popular thing to talk
about. Um, the UN says that in
order to be effective, the carbon,
a global carbon tax would need to
be perhaps as high as $5,500 a ton.
And there's nowhere else in the world.
There's nowhere in the world where there's
a tax that's even one 100th as high
as that right now.
Um,
and the places in the world
where they do have carbon taxes,
everybody's admissions, there's
still grew up going up. So there,
there was a time when like the kind of
like you don't have to change anything.
We'll just like fiddle on the margins
here could have worked if we had taken,
if we had really been focused on it.
But we're sort of past that point now,
unfortunately. Um, but it's interesting
you the talking about the oil companies,
um, I think they, you know, I think
they're responsible for denial,
but I also think that denial is not all
that important in American politics. Um,
because when you look around the world,
you see many countries,
which v with very different politics,
even quite universally
focused on climate issues,
who are not behaving any better.
When it comes to carbon than we are.
And so you think,
well what is the sickness here?
Is that the Republican Party and their
climate denial or is it the fact that all
of us, Jen just want,
you know, more better,
cheaper stuff and we have a really hard
time conceiving of different paths that
don't push us forward towards
more consumption and you know,
more um,
more than modern amenities that we sort
of assume we'll keep accumulating over
time. I mean, people say financial
capitalism is the problem.
I have some sympathy for that view,
but I also look around the world.
I see social democracies who are behaving
really poorly when it comes to carbon.
I see socialist countries who are behaving
Um, it seems on some level like it's even
deeper than the systems that we have to
organize and manage our
cultural priorities.
And there are now, you know, getting back
to the villa, any of the oil companies,
they're now all these lawsuits that are
being brought against them for basically
on the model of the, of the cigarette
company is like that for climate damages.
And um, that may be,
they may be victorious.
They may put some of these
companies out of business. Um,
I think it's not that likely,
but it's possible.
There are also other lawsuits that are
happening that are really interesting.
There's one in the Netherlands
that some people held, um,
the Dutch government,
they basically,
the Dutch government was not honoring
the Paris accords and citizens sued to
hold them to that and we won the case.
So the Dutch government is now obligated
legally to do better on climate than
they were doing on their own.
And in the u s there's this amazing court
case called Juliana versus the United
States,
which is a lawsuit being brought by
kids using this kind of ingenious use of
equal protection clause.
They're arguing that their generation
has been exposed to climate damages,
that there, the previous generation, our
parents generation were protected from.
And so they're saying this climate policy
is a violation of the equal protection
clause.
You're not protecting us in the same way
that you protected our parents that's
at the district court and Argen, which is
just one level below the supreme court.
I think it will win in the District
Court almost certainly won't win at the
Supreme Court.
But if it did one of the Supreme Court,
it would immediately obligate the u s
to a totally maximalist climate policy
because it's literally impossible to
protect the next generation from climate
damages as fully as the
previous generation was.
But they'd be obligated to
do everything they could,
which would mean sort of
suddenly something like the um,
the World War II scale
mobilization that the UN calls for,
which would be really kind
of dramatic and incredible.
And I think that's one path
forward is through a litigation,
because so many places in the world,
it's not just politics are a nerd,
like American politics are a nerd.
It's just there's a lot of slow moving
bureaucracy and slow moving public
opinion.
And in the same way that a lot of civil
rights victories were fought and won in
the courts.
I think we might be able to make some
progress in the courts on climate too.
We'll see if you had a magic wand.
But if they made you the king
of the world and they said you,
you can decide what we do, what would
you, what would the first step be?
The first step is just ending
fossil fuel subsidies. I mean,
there's no reason why these companies
should be receiving public money.
And why are the just
incumbency advantages? They're
well connected companies,
a lot of them are really big and powerful
and any government in the world is not
going to want a major industry
to like completely collapse. Um,
but you know, if we're really
subsidizing them $5 trillion a year,
that's a ton of money that
can be poured into green,
like to r and D of New Technology.
It can be poured into the carbon
capture like we talked about before.
That's just an unbelievable resource.
And it would accelerate the decline
of coal in particular. And uh,
and other oil. And other fossil fuel,
uh, businesses, which will be great.
Is there any discussion about that in
individual countries? Yeah, but, um,
it's slow moving. Um, you
know, there's stuff about, um,
people are taking action in all
different ways at all different levels,
which I think is basically necessary.
So their cities in Europe where cars
are now being banned, um, cars, yeah.
In the city. Yeah. It
just like riding around.
You've been living in la too long. You
can do that in Amsterdam. You can do that.
It just seems ridiculous.
Yeah.
Well, I mean, I think, um,
maybe, maybe it'll just be,
you can only have an electric car,
um, you know, maybe 10 years from now,
like it'll be illegal in the u s
to build, uh, like, uh, you know,
a gas guzzling car.
I got an electric car recently and it's
amazing the blow back from my friends.
What are they saying? Well, first
of all, it's always homophobic or,
or a or a feminine.
They're always going after you about
your estrogen levels and your manhood.
It's like, it's weird. It's kind of like
a space. I mean Tesla's are kind of like,
there's kind of like space ships
though. They feel, I mean there's,
what have you been in one? Yeah, he
driven one. I haven't driven one.
I've been in one,
I've,
I drove in one years ago
and I wasn't that impressed.
I want to say like maybe
five or six years ago,
but now I have one of the new ones that's
crazy fast. It doesn't even make sense.
Regular cars are stupid. They're stupid
and you spend all that money on gas,
why would you want to do that?
But I mean they're stupid.
Like they don't work as good.
Like that thing is way better than
any car I've ever driven. Yeah.
And it's only going to get better there.
They don't even make sense how fast they
are and they drive themselves. Yeah.
Like you hit this little thing go do,
do and it just fucking steers.
It takes over. Yeah. Like
it drives, yeah. And it's,
it stays within the speed limit and you
could just kind of half ass space out.
Cause keep your hand on the
steering wheel and it a,
it breaks when there's cars in front
of you and slow. It's very strange.
It will even change lanes for you.
Amazing. It's fucked. It's weird.
It's weird. It's, it's very difficult
to let go and to give in like that.
But the strange thing that I felt was the,
the blowback from my friends like,
and they're joking around.
Obviously most of my friends are
comedians, but it's a, it's hilarious.
Even people have heckled me about it.
Yeah.
Well I feel that like just
at the aesthetic level,
I understand that mocking
of like the Prius,
but I feel like the Tesla is actually,
it looks like a macho.
The piece is a piece of shit.
It's like a cheese wedge with wheels.
But I mean it's like, you know, uh, yeah,
we live in a sick culture where
like being healthy and responsible.
It was like cigarettes and whiskey
in mock. Someone eating a salad.
It's very weird. It is very weird. But
um, I was a, that is an American problem.
Like other parts in the world, they're
not as attached to their trucks. And Shit.
Grouse were gross, but, but there's, um,
something particularly strange about
being on that side of it cause I was, um,
I wanna I don't wanna say I was
pessimistic about electric cars,
but when Elan did the podcast, I told
my by one of his cars, because he was,
he was telling me how great
they are. I'm like, yeah, yeah,
I'm probably one of your cars.
But I really did not expect to like it
as much as I do. And then once I got it,
I was like, oh, okay, now I get it. Yeah.
But then I was thinking about my own
resistance to it because I like cars.
I have no muscle cars. I have a
couple, I have an older Porsche.
I love them. They're fun. I like those
kind of cars, but they're stupid.
They really are dumb.
That's a dumb way to get
around the Tesla's a way
better way to get around. Yeah.
And you know,
he's got one that's coming out in 2020
that's going to have a 660 mile range,
which is in San mean you drive all the
way to San Francisco and back with one
charge. You know, I mean he's incredible.
I think, you know, I like there,
there are reasons why he
gets the shit that he gets.
But I also think like Tesla and solar
city are incredibly important and I'm
actually,
I don't understand why there aren't
more people in Silicon Valley who are
focused on climate in this way.
Like obviously they want like these are
people who see themselves as gods who
want to be a world historical figures
there. They're literally do that.
Who Do you think is doing that well?
Like,
like Jeff as you think he thinks of
himself as a god. Yeah. Really? Yeah,
really. You know, and now I read those
text messages he sent to that check.
I don't think God would
say that God would say,
you should be lucky to get this dick.
All this space exploration stuff though.
It's like,
you know,
all that people are obsessed with the end
of the life extinction extinction. Um,
but, but does he think that this is
a side effect of having $150 billion,
but you can do so much good with that.
Yes.
So basis is pouring $1
billion a year into his,
into his space exploration
project, which is like, I mean,
I'm excited by space too.
I think it'd be cool to go up there,
but there's some pressing problems here
which we could really benefit, you know,
that money could really
benefit and I agree.
But longterm I think the philosophy is
that we're going to have to get off this
planet if the human race is going to
succeed because of not just the threat of
global warming but of Astra steroid packs
and yeah, man, it's an asteroid thing.
I think.
I mean for me Novas there's a lot of
factors mark on the particular question of
climate.
Um,
there's just no way that the earth is
going to get as inhospitable as Mars is.
So the idea of building a colony there
as a hedge against global warming is just
crazy. We could, it is ridiculous
on a good, on the positive note,
if we could fix that shit
hole, like imagine what we
could do here. Yeah. Paradise.
Yeah. Well the idea is
terraforming, right?
That they can go there with some kind of
massive machine that's going to create
oxygen and the environment and yeah.
Well that's a good place to
practice because no one lives there.
So he could do all kinds of goofy shit
and go, well, good news and bad news.
The good news is we figured out a way,
terraform,
the bad news is we already fucked up Mars,
so we're going to try another spot.
We're going to go to, you know, we're
going to move on to, yeah, yeah. Well,
you know Venus used to be
actually quite earthlight. Yeah.
They went through a really rapid
global warming that made it,
now it's like a total hellhole. Right?
And that's like the sort of worst case.
Worst case for earth is
the venous scenario. Well,
ultimately the sun's going to burn out.
Right.
But that's many millions
of years for sure.
But if we really do look into the future,
something, something has to be done.
You know what I mean? This is a, the,
the grandest of grand scales. The,
the concept of a, some sort
of interstellar arcs. I
mean, I believe that I'm,
and I'm, I'm, I'm with it. I just think
the timescale, the threat that we're,
that we need to avert by
space exploration. That's
a timescale of Millennia.
Yes. We have a lot of new
technology develop over the
next thousand years that'll
allow us to do a better and more
efficiently. But climate change,
the timescale is like the next 30 years.
Right?
So we need to focus on it now to give
ourselves the opportunity to do the other
show. Why do you think it's sexier
to go to space? Is that what it is?
Like rockets and I mean, I think
for these dudes, yeah. Yeah.
It's a big metal deck sheeting off in
the atmosphere. That's what we're doing.
Trying to fuck space. I actually
made that argument about Mars. Yeah.
It's like they're shaped like dicks.
Yeah. Something to that. Yeah.
Well also this generation of
people really grew up in the,
in the age of like the, the
space race. I mean it's um,
and the aftermath of landing on the moon.
And I think there is like
Peter Teal talks about this,
there's this kind of unfulfilled
sense of future that we all,
like anybody who grew up in the post war
years in 67, they were like, you know,
whatever his famous line were promised
flying cars and all we got was 140
characters or whatever. I think that
applies to the space exploration stuff.
It's like,
well the government is no longer doing
the really ambitious shit but we can do
it privately.
On the other hand,
there is a government in the world
that is doing that shit. And China,
they just landed on the
far side of the moon.
They're doing really aggressive space
exploration and I haven't been there in 20
years,
but the people I know who live there
say there is so much faith in the future
there. Um, they just
believe in a very inherent,
deep down way that like
the future will be better.
And Saifai e in an exciting way.
And that's so far from the way that
Americans think about the future.
Is that part of the benefit of
having a dictator run things?
I think it's just like
they're on a huge upswing.
Like there's no debate about how
things get done. Yeah, totally.
I mean that's what I was saying before.
It's like it,
it gives you some hope for climate.
If like Xi Jinping is just like, okay,
immediately, no more
coal, they'll all stop.
But he's also throwing 2 million Muslims
and concentration camps. Right? Yeah. Um,
this bayzos thing,
I mean,
I'm not criticizing you because I
think it's a very common thought,
but why is it that we will look at
these super rich billion billionaire
characters that are on
the top of the heap?
Why do we think of them as like having
these tremendous egos and looking like
gods? Isn't it sort of just, just,
just how you're always going to look
at someone who lives in of $100 million
house and it's possible, I
think when you look at, I mean,
not to get too like armchair
psychologizing but basis,
but when you look at the
physical transformation that
he's put himself through,
when you think about like
the life extinction, what
has he done physically? Well,
he's just like,
I mean if,
if you look at photos of him
when he's like a young man,
he's just kind of like dweeby. Right?
And now he's like a, um, an action hero.
Is He really? Yeah. I mean maybe not
like you, but he's like, he's, yeah,
he's pretty as big as Jack.
Am I missing something?
Let me show you how it looks different.
Go pull up,
pull up some images of Jeff jacked.
I didn't know he got
a trainer. I mean, no,
I'm not blaming him,
but that's only one part of it.
I would say I'm bigger than that is, you
know, the, I had just had thin skins,
the worlds, okay. Let me say zoom in
or else I guess he's got
some arms there is, oh wow.
That's a big difference. Yeah.
But he's also got a vest on.
I guess his arms do look pretty big.
Yeah.
I mean in most ways I'm
not a business hater.
I think Amazon has been actually really
pretty great. I'm a fan. Yeah. I like,
well listen to the guy talk and I loved
his letter to the national enquirer.
There he is right there.
Yeah.
So he looks fit in front of the King
Kong rampage movie. Is that him? Yeah.
Yeah, he looks pretty good. Um, okay.
I guess physical transformation, but
that's, yeah, probably the life extension,
like uploading your brain to the computer.
There's so many busy into that shit. I,
he is actually, I think not as
into it as some other people,
but how does so psi Phi, you know, I, um,
I interviewed Kurzweil a while back when
I was doing the Scifi show when I went
to this, uh, 2045 conference that
they had in Manhattan and it was, um,
these guys are,
they're talking about something that
they think will be invented and they're
acting as if it's been invented
inevitable. Yeah, yeah, totally. I mean,
Eric Schmidt has said
about climate change,
that the solution is already here in
the sense that AI will just solve it.
And it's like that. Well, no, no, sorry.
That's a weird thing that we do though,
right? We, we always looked like, oh,
someone's going to handle
this. Yeah. Well, the, the, um,
the brain upload stuff is interesting
to me with regard to climate,
just because it's like a,
a portal through which we can
escape environmental degradation.
So if the world is on fire
and full of suffering,
maybe we can just upload our
minds to some machines and not,
not live in the real world anymore.
And when I think about
even my relationship to my
phone, like tech addiction,
generally we're sort of being taught
to think of the world on our screens as
more real than the world that's around us.
And that sounds in a lot of ways
like decline, nest and whatever.
But I also think it may be a kind of
coping mechanism for a world that we're
about to head into where there is
that much more suffering. And when I,
when I see for instance,
like the whole wellness movement,
I think their intuitions,
they are about like the toxicity of
the world and how we have to avoid it.
I think the way that it will reshape our
own sense of self and relationship to
the world and idea of our
place in nature and history.
All of these things are
really, um, up in the air, um,
and will be affected by climate
change I think in, you know,
in ways that we don't yet
appreciate or understand. So the,
to wave the wand. Yeah. What
would be step number one?
Step number one is ending fossil fuel
subsidies and fossil fuel subsidies.
Step number two,
step number two,
just massive R and d investment.
My massive investment in r
and D and New infrastructure,
which would be great for
the economy. Right? Totally.
So all these things taking a positive
or taking a negative and looking at
positive aspects of mitigating
the problem. Yeah. And Yeah,
new energy sources. I mean
they're, there really are,
there are already new business empires
that were, are from the climate change.
Are there new solar empires
that are new wind empires,
but that can happen globally.
That needs to happen globally. Um,
and you know, that's, you know, then we
have to, we have to deal with agriculture,
which may be about seaweed and maybe about
lab grown meat. I don't know. But um,
you know, it's, it's like the big picture.
It's all carbon. It's all just how
much carbon we put into the atmosphere.
So I think it will come to be the
case that in the decades ahead,
everything about the way that we interact
with the world will be described and
understood in terms of carbon.
So that for instance,
your walked down the aisle in the
supermarket, you see organic food,
you see non GMO food,
you'll also see like carbon free food.
And that'll be a big part
of the way that we eat,
consume everything that things will be
advertised that way, promoted that way.
But globally we just need to
really focus on reducing carbon.
Is it like, and wherever it
is, which is almost everywhere.
We need to figure out new ways to do
whatever it is we're doing. And that's um,
that's causing that problem. We need to
make it trendy in La. That's what we do.
Have some organic gluten
free carbon free food.
I feel like that's already
kind of happening. Should
be. Yeah, that would be it.
As long as that kicks in and people
realize there's some street cred to be in
carbon free. Yeah. I mean, I think
in different parts of the world,
people will relate differently
to it. So like, yeah,
in China there's scheduled to have this
huge boom in beef consumption and dairy
consumption because it's expected
that as that country gets richer,
the people will adopt a more western diet.
But it's also possible
that they want that.
Like the new Chinese middle class
will be still really interested in,
you know, Tofu, less interested in
beef, less interested in milk. They are,
you know, um, and it might be,
it might be easier to have them follow
that path and it will be to make the
American average American
eat less beef. But, um,
you know, it's, it's everywhere. It's
like everywhere you look, there's some,
there's some, some little problem to
solve. Um, but then when you pull back,
it really is just carbon.
It's like absolutely everything.
If you think about everything you do
in terms of the carbon impact it has,
then you know, the solution.
So suggest themselves.
And I do think that in the coming decades,
if,
even if you and I don't start to
think in those terms are as well,
that like everything will be,
oh,
we're entering into a new
trade agreement with Japan.
What's the carbon budget here? Like
what, how's their carbon behavior? Oh,
we're like, um, you know, this, um,
we're providing some public
subsidies for this factory over here.
What's their like emissions situation?
Like can we ask them to bring along
some carbon capture plant so that they
reduce their footprint? Um, you
know, every, at every level,
the level of the individual like talking
about buying a Tesla or buying a,
I'm buying a range rover or whatever.
Um,
I think we'll start to think in,
in the term in terms of carbon and that'll
be a sign of just how total climate
change will have,
how totally climate change will have
conquered the world so that there won't be
an aspect of modern life that will be
not just untouched, but in a certain way.
Kind of ungoverned by
it. Yeah. What about,
is there a way to educate people
in a way that's not preachy, that sort
of moves the needle in that direction?
I think conversations
like this are important.
I think your book's very
important and I think, you know,
interviews that I'm sure you're doing
right now on all these different shows are
important and everything kind
of like ups the needle or obs,
the perception of it a little bit.
But is there anything else it can be
done that can educate people in a way
that's, it's not preachy
or it's not, it doesn't,
it's not aggressive in a way
that annoys people because yeah,
it's a horrible thing to say,
but like the same way we're like,
we need sugar in the medicine. You
know, I like the song from Mary Poppins.
Yeah, I mean I think in
general like climate messaging,
climate communication has really suffered
for a long time because it was so
preachy and blue because
it was so holier than now.
And because the people
that get involved in it,
part of the reason why they get involved
in it's virtue signaling. Totally.
And I've been asked like,
you know,
as I've been proven up promoting
the book by a lot of people,
like what have you done to in your life
to change? You know, and it's like, well,
I'm flying a little bit less flying.
Really makes me feel guilty.
But otherwise I basically haven't
changed anything because I do think that
politics and policy are the most
important impact you can have.
And I'm like spreading the word whether
I eat like a couple of fewer hamburgers
a year,
it just doesn't really matter that much.
But the idea that you would ask a newcomer
to the movement to demonstrate their
commitment by making themselves the most
optimally committed that they possibly
could be, that's just going
to alienate so many people.
And this is obviously a issue where we
need more people engaged in a more direct
profound way. So I think for me it's like
anyone who wants to care about climate,
who wants to vote about climate, like come
on, like, um, and I think that, you know,
Hollywood can be really important here.
Um, I mean, since I've been out here,
I've been,
I have a couple of meetings about shows
and stuff and I do think that we've had
really corny storytelling about climate
change and that there are actually
opportunities for like really incredible
new kinds of storytelling. I mean,
in the book I about this
story that happened a couple
of years ago where, okay,
mmm,
you know,
anthrax that was,
had killed a reindeer in Russia
in the early 20th century.
The ranger was frozen in permafrost
for the entire 20th century.
Permafrost melted,
the reindeer thawed,
the anthrax was released and killed
at least one boy and a number of other
reindeer in Russia. Wow. And that is true.
So in the ice in the Arctic ice are,
you know,
we know of rock is like a
record of geological history.
Ice is also record of geological history.
So they're like the bubonic
plague is trapped in ice.
The Spanish flu in the from h 1918 that
killed hundreds of millions of people is
trapped in ice.
There are diseases trapped in the Arctic
ice from before humans were around,
which means that humans immune
system have no experience with them.
There's so many horror movies you can
make about this subject. Um, Holy Shit,
I didn't even think of that.
I didn't know that the Spanish flu
is trapped in ice. Yeah, I mean,
and there have been instances where
like in lab conditions anyway,
they've revived bacteria that
are millions of years old.
Um,
one Russian doctor literally injected a
bacteria that he had revived from like
35,000 years ago.
It had been frozen for 35,000 years.
He brought it back to life and injected
it into himself. Why would he do that?
Just to see what would,
that's a fucking marvel comic book.
That's how you become like the,
the red scholar some. Yeah.
Well that's what I mean about this.
This story is so big.
It's like the world that we live in
in the next couple of decades will be
completely transformed.
Like we will be reading about
diseases coming out of the Arctic ice.
We will be reading about tropical diseases
arriving in Copenhagen because now
mosquitoes are there because
the temperature allows
them to live there and the
way that they never lived before.
We will be reading about climate conflict
will be reading about, you know, um,
I mean all this shit, it's,
it's, it's everywhere. You know,
air pollution increases the rates
of autism and Adhd. It changes, um,
the development of babies in utero.
It's like, it's all encompassing. Wow.
The disease in the ice thing
is really freaking me out.
I never even considered that.
Yeah.
But that is something to think about
along with the methane and carbon is going
to be emitted into the atmosphere as it
melts. Well, let me tell you this story.
So I'm there.
We now,
so there was there this, the species
of antelope called a saiga antelope.
They, um, they're mostly in Siberia.
They're kind of dwarf antelopes and
they've been around for millions of years.
And, uh, all of a sudden in 2016 or 2015,
they literally all died. It's called
a mega death. The entire species died.
They're extinct. They're
now extinct. Jesus. Um,
and that happened because a bacteria that
had been living inside their guts was
changed by conditions.
It was an unusually hot,
unusually humid summer. And this bacteria
that had been living inside them,
presumably for millions of years
comfortably as a kind of peaceful,
cooperator became a killer
and killed the entire species.
Now we have inside us
countless bacteria and viruses.
Scientists believe
millions in every human.
So our guts are full of bacteria
that do our digestion for us.
They monitor our moods.
They're there. You know,
there are some scientists who think it's
really misleading to even think of the
human as a unitary animal rather than a
kind of composite creature with system.
Yeah.
And most of those bacteria and viruses
are not going to be dramatically
transformed by a degree
or two degrees of warming.
But there are so many of them.
The chances that one could,
it's hard to dismiss that and whether
that would mean we'd all immediately go
extinct,
probably not.
But what if that means suddenly
schizophrenia increases by 15% because
schizophrenia is related to,
um,
a bacterial infection called toxoplasma
guts things, bacteria Toxoplasma Gondii.
Um, well that's that cat
parasite. Yeah, exactly.
It was schizophrenia is related
to that. Yeah. Really? Yeah.
I'd like triples your chances of
getting schizophrenia. Wow. Yeah. Um,
and our bodies are so complex,
such intricate ecosystems.
Like you say that if one
little thing gets disturbed,
it could have really
catastrophic impacts on us.
And that's true of the planet as a whole.
I think that's,
that's one of the big lessons of my book
is that this is such a delicate system.
It's been stable for all of human
history and now it's not stable.
What that means for how we live,
we don't know yet,
but the changes will be significant,
will be profound.
But it's also true of the individual.
You know,
our bodies will be living differently in
a world that's two degrees warmer than
they are today. We can't really
predict what those impacts will be,
but it could be quite dramatic.
And they could be things that we can't
even imagine today because they're,
you know,
by some counts,
millions of bacteria inside us that
we haven't even identified yet.
Jesus Christ, you're freaking
me out, David. God dammit.
It's a crazy world out there.
It will, not just crazy,
but it seems like when,
when you're talking
about things like this,
when you talking about climate change
affecting our actual gut parasites or our
gut biome and that this literally could
change the way human beings behave.
I mean, these are all things that I've
never heard discussed and it, it just,
it's really terrifying,
really is, you know, I mean,
and part of the problem is people hear
like, oh, relax, everything's fine.
This is this constant thing that we do
where if it's not effecting us currently,
right now in the moment,
there's not a fire in front of us.
We don't worry about it.
It's a weird compartment,
compartmentalization thing
that human beings do.
Yeah. And um, it's, you know,
you'd think that evolution would
have trained us differently.
You think that evolution would have us
over time to have at least some long term
capacity. And I guess we do have some
longterm planning capacity, but it's, um,
we choose to think in really short
term ways just about all the time.
Now you've already freaked me out. How's
your book? And a freak me out more. Um,
I mean, it's every page, every
page is more of this. Jesus man.
How do you sleep at
night? You okay? I mean,
I sleep through compartmentalization and
denial to, I'm not, I'm not, you know,
I mentioned earlier like the,
and I think there's,
it's been a problem for
environmentalism for a long time.
This kind of holier than thou thing.
That's not who I am.
I'm not an environmentalist.
Until a couple of years ago when I
started really worrying about this stuff,
I had the same disinclination to take
it seriously that than most people do.
You know,
I thought climate change was real.
I thought it was something that we
need to worry about and deal with.
But I thought it was like a small problem
that could be dealt with without much
change to my life.
And I still basically feel that way.
I mean, I, you know, I like
going on vacations in nature,
but I'm not someone who's like spends
months hiking that trail or whatever.
I've never even had a pet. I don't
love animals, you know? But my,
the more I looked at the science,
the more I just realized this isn't
about affecting some part of nature over
there.
It's about effecting all of human life,
every aspect of human life
as it's lived on this planet.
And that really terrified me.
But even knowing that,
even staring at him straight in the face,
I mean I still get up in the morning and
you know, whatever, do the same shit,
go to the gym, watch
basketball, go to my day job.
And I don't think that we
should be ashamed of that. Um,
I think all of us have, are going to
have different reactions to this story,
different perspectives on the crisis.
And that's good. That's human.
Um,
but spreading the word generally making
people a little more alarmed is going to
make people take some more action
and that's what we need. Um,
but you know, the psychological,
like I said before,
the psychological biases are so strong
that like when I imagine my daughter's
life, I'm not imagining a
hellscape. I'm imagining the life,
the world that I grew up in.
And again,
that's not like that's how everybody,
that's how everybody relates relates to
the world and it's just a a reminder of
how important it is to
look really directly at the
science because the world as
it exists today is not a good guide to
the world that we will be living in in a
decade or two.
There's no way that the climate system
as it exists today will be stabilized
forever. It will get harder. All
of these things will get worse.
Every tick upward of
temperature we'll make,
we'll create more climate sufferings
somewhere in the world and if we get to
really dramatic levels of warming, that
suffering will be basically everywhere.
We can't continue orienting
our perspective on the
future on the world as it is
today.
We have to take seriously this range of
temperature temperature's two degrees to
four degrees that we're on track for
the century as a way of generating
sufficient activity and response
and adapting as we need to.
If we keep looking out the window
and thinking the world is, it is now,
will continue,
we're not going to do anything.
And that's what we've done over the last
30 years, which has been catastrophic.
I think that message is really important.
And I think that also the message of
that we need to change and evolve as a
civilization. But as a human being, you
need to still enjoy your life and that,
you know, it just, it's, it's
a, it's not a, Oh my God,
I need to drop everything I'm doing. That
leaves any sort of a carbon footprint.
It's, we need to address
it as a civilization. Yeah.
And I mean, you know, the,
if the average American had the carbon
footprint of the average European
Americans,
carbon emissions would fall by like 35%.
Now I don't think of lights the
difference. What do they do differently?
They drive less. They, it's weird
cause they make the best cars. Yeah.
But it's like less territory. Yeah.
Um, I mean there aren't many people in,
in Europe who like commute an
hour and a half to work everyday.
And that's like not so
uncommon in America. Um,
their diet is better carbon wise
and they have more, you know,
they have some more aggressive,
um, green energy stuff going on.
How's your diet better? Carbon was they
just, they waste less food basically.
So like a third of all American food,
I think it's a third is wasted.
That's just wasted carbon.
Yeah. Um, and you know,
I think the number of electricity is like
70% of American electricity is wasted
because how bad the grid is.
Like it just is so bad at
delivering from one source.
This is one reason why it's solar city
is so important because the battery can
be a much more efficient, um,
transporter of electricity. Well,
there's just no excuse for California.
I mean, other than this saw this winter,
it's sunny every day.
Yeah.
But so if 70% of American
electricity is wasted,
it's like we're just throwing
all that carbon and Alyssa.
Yeah. That's giant. Yeah.
Um, and if we were less
wasteful, we'd have, you know,
less of a problem on our hands,
but we still like order twice as much
food as we want. And then throw it out.
I mean, I did that. Yeah. Yeah. Um,
so you can understand why someone would
say to you like, what are you doing?
But it's that sentiment behind it
that's kind of gross, right? Yeah.
It's like they're looking for you to be
a hypocrite. They're trying to catch you.
Well, when I look at hypocrisy,
what I see is like, you know,
you want the world to be a better
place than you yourself are doing. Yes.
It's like that to me,
there's a way of,
it's like we think of hypocrisy
as like a negative quality.
I think it's kind of a positive.
It can be a positive quality.
You believe we should be
behaving in a way. Yeah. Yeah.
And he's like, I need to
adjust. Like you're saying,
not just what everybody needs to do,
what we need to do as well.
You're being conscious of this
need to change and like, you know,
if someone believes in,
say like better healthcare,
we don't ask them to donate all
of their money to hospitals.
That's what taxation is for.
Policy directs
our cultural energy towards targets
that we want to reach. So again,
as a civilization, we need to adjust.
Yeah. And as a, an individual,
we need to be aware so that we promote
and support this idea of a civilization
shifting. Yeah. Yeah. Listen,
man. Thank you. Thanks for
scaring the shit out of me.
Thanks for coming down
here. Uh, tell people, uh,
with the name of your book one more time,
please call the uninhabitable earth.
The subtitle is life after
warming. It's on my Instagram. Um,
and we'll put a link to it on Amazon, on
Twitter. And thank you, David. Oh, man.
Great to meet Shit, man. It's
great to meet you too. Good
luck with your book, man.
And really, I think it's gonna
make a big impact. Thank you.
Yeah.
Okay.