Is it a battle between the human
retarded monkey chimpanzee behavior of
take,
take.
The theory I believe was formulated
before they realize how many monkeys
chimpanzees eat.
What chimps attack.
People that go for your balls.
That's one of the number one things they
do.
They try to eat.
Your Genitalia isn't a weird now that we
know so much about chimpanzees,
like some kid,
that student in Africa just gotTa
fucking testicle ripped off to picture
that chimp clamping down on my scrotum
with his teeth.
That gets me through the last four or
five Reps.
I saw this picture of a chimp,
carrie and fruit,
and I looked at him like,
holy fuck.
There's that fucking gorilla that
they've chimpanzee.
They've recently discovered in the cargo
just muscle,
gigantic.
You know how fucking crazy it must've
been the first time they discovered a
Gabriella,
you know they're walking into what else
is here?
John Welders and the size of your hand,
Fred,
give me the machete.
Was hacked through some.
What the fuck is that like a regular
chimpanzees?
Fuck each other up.
They kill each other,
but.
But nobody really.
They mostly solve their issues through
sex.
Say you know how you saw your poop on
you.
You can't hold a chimp bitch and check.
Those bitches are freaks.
Brutal.
Talk about chimps every week.
Might not like.
This is probably the most.
No,
I mean it.
When's the last time you talked about
trump's with me?
All the time.
You do talk about podcast episode.
People are laughing right now.
Waiting.
Gentleman.
Black helicopters have been spotted.
I don't know if you know that he's a way
better athlete than you,
but it doesn't mean that we put up in
that,
so it doesn't mean that to me that he'll
automatically.
You burned a thousand calories.
Is there some sort of.
I talked to Pat McAfee one time,
he said it's about exclusivity.
It's about rape and murder.
My head's filled with it.
Stopping rapists and stop and murderers
and killing child molesters.
That's what I think about that Mickey
Mantle Gene.
That's Lou Gehrig's disease.
I'm trying to break burt's will.
That's what I'm really trying to do.
Talks all this Mickey Mantle Gene Shit.
I'm like,
motherfucker,
I'm crazy.
Fire alarm.
Up until two days ago,
everything seemed to be going good,
but I started being an exert,
coming out dark today I had to go to
something in my kids' school and I had
to go up three flights of stairs.
I got to the top.
I was out of breath and my legs were
shaking and I was like,
okay,
I might have fucked something up.
Felt so bad.
Okay.
I would like to ladies and gentlemen,
for this artist,
you feel present to you,
Joe Rogan,
this belt
sign.
You are the champion of sober October.
Qre huge shocker.
You're in better shape than the three of
us.
I think that had a factor,
but it's ultimately is about trt.
Is that tight enough or not even that?
Mickey Mann Will Jean.
Thank you.
He didn't say anything to.
I want to say this is Sandy Kofax.
Jean,
I want to say Mickey Mantle.
Gene.
Do you see a song mythologist thing?
What did you.
Did you play that back?
Do you see him?
Saw montage juice thing.
You guys did some mileage.
You'd get anxiety.
Like check the APP.
See where everybody's scores that shit.
Fuck,
you know,
you need,
you can do that.
You weren't competing against Bert
Kreischer,
Ari Shaffir and Tom's Gora.
So let's take it easy.
No,
I'm not saying still.
You know what I mean?
Like my competition.
Those guys post the last guy
competitiveness.
Oh,
this a mud rats out there that have no
jeans almost.
I feel like like mud wrap.
Humans,
just people that are just smoking their
own dicks out there who have no real
life.
Like,
you know what I'm saying?
Like I've met some people who yeah,
they're breathing,
but that's it really.
I used to live with these rich people
for awhile.
The Dad used to masturbate at night and
I would sneak out there in the kitchen.
This is back when the family had like a
family computer.
You know what?
It was in one part of the house.
Right.
And he's over there just in the glow of
that screen,
Bro.
And that's back when the monitors were
big,
you know?
And he's just over there just fucking
looking for the devil.
And he ended up getting divorced and it
was,
I think a lot of it was because of that.
Was she annoying first and he started
beating off or was he.
Had He beat the devil?
I think he had a pit of it in him.
The worst is if you're jerking off with
a hat on,
bro,
you're going to hell.
I think the best would be one of those
Chinese hats broke because if you squat
down low enough to the ground,
you can almost hide under it and you're
the most confusing.
It would be like one of them.
Daniel Boone.
Raccoon tail.
You pushed it.
Scared the fuck out of my way with its
tail do.
When I was growing up,
we couldn't even get point.
We had to get this dude nick on Friday
withdraws a pinterest and pussy,
you know,
cross for the weekend for dollar to this
dude nick for dollars for drawings,
Bro.
You'd pay eight dude.
And we come back on Monday and people
would have like these fucking busted ass
looking all sketches reign on him.
He was like,
oh,
this is what got rain on it.
No workers.
The white people that wish they were
blocked.
It's a totally different thing.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
We had the first one at our school
growing up and they put them in a
learning disabled class.
That's.
How crazy is that?
Yeah.
You guys are the first one ever.
I doubt it.
We had one of the first 60 or 70.
This was probably 1992,
but he was always dribbling it invisible
basketball and they put him in class
with the mentally handicapped kids.
He was against whites.
That was the thing.
Fuck all these white people and when he
was white they're like,
this is.
And I get it and I was making like a
nice smoothie and I'm fucking coked up.
I'm partying,
you know,
living high on the hog to vests on
maybe.
Right.
And I thought,
I thought I heard something outside.
Right.
Which is kind of weird to even think of
when you have a blender going.
Right?
So I'll leave out of my apartment to go
in the hallway,
lock myself out with the blender going
during in the morning,
coked up out of my brain.
I have to go to my landlord,
the blender shorts out and smoke
happens.
The fire alarm starts going off in the
building,
right as I'm at his door knocking right
now.
He's pissed and he's like,
what's going on?
And I didn't know what to say.
I told them that I was throwing a late
Christmas party.
Dude,
it was fucking into January.
I will with you at the time.
Huh?
Oh,
this is two and a half years ago.
So 30,
35.
So he comes back to my apartment,
right?
He's,
he unlocks the door.
There's nobody in there,
dude.
I talked to your buddy,
Eddie Bravo.
And that guy is a real.
He's out there.
He's like a,
he's like a death,
like a death Jack Russell almost,
you know a deaf Jack Russell because
once he gets going you can't.
Oh,
Jack Russell terrier.
You ever been around with the dog?
You open the car and then next thing you
know they're like,
yeah,
they're like sick.
Yeah,
but how's he depth?
Because you can't get them back.
Like once he goes,
you can't say you can't get them back in
the car.
Like you're sitting there honking the
horn.
You can't that guys out.
There are other cool dogs.
Isn't Jack Russell?
That's the coolest one.
That's just fucking insane.
That's insane.
That's bribery.
That's.
Are you saying that it's worth $200,000?
If she sucked every Dick in the room,
it wouldn't be worth $200,000.
Right?
There's no way.
Who's going to pay a thousand dollars
for Hillary Clinton,
Bro?
Job.
Other than for the story.
I think she can get a lot of money for
blowjobs using so fucking old.
Right guys with this fucking down.
Plus the Devin boot.
Cockies.
You know what I mean to you do.
Oh,
you do the copy for this.
I feel it just feels like a
disrespectful turn we're taking with
Hillary.
You don't think they put her in there
for a reason because she don't give a
fuck.
So I think they,
they want controversy.
Do you want people to get used to fucked
up decisions?
We're used to it.
That's.
Yeah,
I think they.
They want that because if they ever
needed to pull something out like
something was like,
dude,
this motherfucker
has to.
When people are like,
Oh,
it is vegas.
There's a conspiracy theory that Hillary
Clinton's father,
Hugh Ross,
Adam,
I,
I'm assuming he's,
he's not alive anymore,
but he was a huge Jewish mob boss who is
responsible for opium going into
Chicago.
I don't know if that's real,
but it makes sense to me.
I mean,
no one is ever before,
so no one has ever been.
Is that him right there?
Oh,
he doesn't look like you fits in,
does he?
How?
No one has ever been that guy.
I bet he went home with me when they
first.
Oh my God,
there was nothing like that before that.
That's a phd.
People say that.
That was all staged.
No screaming box saying that did
bieber's or fake and I'll send you a
link.
You know,
I sent you that one email that one guy
was telling me that he worked for a team
of scientists and they're working for
pesticide company and they're told to
the goal are we're going to do some
studies here and we want it to look like
this.
It seems like there's basically in a
nutshell like three kinds of science.
There's,
there's the sign like pseudo science.
It's like pretend science,
but for sure it's not real.
It's false science.
Pseudo science,
and then there's the scientific facts
like for sure it's not like it's a
scientific fact that I can get on the
Internet with my iphone.
I don't need to read a study about it
and say,
oh actually can I know it?
My friends know it.
And then there's the science that you,
you,
you have to take the scientist word for
it because there's no way that you can
verify that if you have to take.
You have to have faith in science.
That's like a religion.
But scientism,
hold on a second.
What are you talking about?
Like what particular kind of any kind of
science,
whether it's a medical science,
if you have a choice to believe in
science that you can't verify yourself,
you could believe it,
but you don't have to believe,
but you could say the experts in the
field verify it.
All the people who understood with all
the that we,
all the science that we know that had
been,
has been corrupted.
Just the big ones.
A sugar science,
uh,
tobacco science,
marijuana,
science,
vaccines,
signs.
We know for sure all,
just those four that there's been a lot
of corruption and so it's hard to trust.
So when someone comes out and especially
the government and NGOs,
yeah,
our scientists,
scientists say that it's safe and
effective.
You got to be like,
damn,
I don't know about that.
I'm not gonna.
Just take your word for it.
You know what I mean?
You guys are criminals.
You're John Gotti and you guys are
saying,
you guys are saying that this is safe
and effective.
I don't know about that.
You know,
maybe it is.
I hope it is,
but I don't know if you've watched the
videos of old nuclear test site,
which soldiers running towards the
blast.
Yeah,
I've seen those.
it looks like it looks like,
I don't know,
just like all that old footage looks
like it doesn't look authentic.
It looks like they faked all that shit,
but I dunno.
I'm,
I'm to retard nuclear bombs.
Is that what you're saying to me?
I,
you know,
there a conspiracy theory that uh,
um,
at,
at nuclear bombs actually don't exist,
that they never actually figured it out,
but they realized that the threat of
nuclear bombs is good enough because the
editor,
you can see the bottom.
But how do you know by seeing them that
they're.
But all I'm saying is how do you know it
wasn't just a regular powerful bomb,
like how do you know?
How do you know by watching a bomb go
off?
How do you know what's nuclear nuclear
nuclear bomb looks like when it blows
up?
I don't know.
How do you know if that's what kind of
bomb that that is the craziest amount of
power you could ever imagine?
I do.
You understand?
It could be a nuclear bomb.
I'm saying all I'm saying.
How can you know for sure?
Look at them.
What you said before the podcast was so
funny about the apocalypse that homeless
people are going to be psyched because
it'd be like homeless people are waiting
for the end of the world.
They're taking them because they're
going to be running shit.
They're going to be because they know
what they're doing.
They know bots and shit and they will
know exactly.
Not going to change their life.
It might get better.
What's going to get crowds in favelas?
If you live in a favela,
you don't have to worry about them in
the world because it's already the end
of the world for you.
You know what I mean?
Sorry about the nuclear war.
Sorry.
I thought you made some good sponsor
real and we're live with Joey Coco Diaz
and one of the baddest motherfuckers on
the planet.
Yo El Ramiro.
Thank you so much.
You got a good grasp of English.
Pretty good.
Joe is going to help fill in the blanks
and we'll be able to have some good
communication here.
No,
no.
And this club he was in was in the
second division,
you know,
he ain't got a clue that Luciano and
glue glue know.
No.
So he started training the fucking
fighters and the club one and they got
up to division one when she started
training.
Training.
Wrestling.
Yeah.
And,
and don't say Quando man.
Yeah man.
I hate when they call them for his MMA
fight.
You said fuck it.
I'll go down there near the 18 years.
Heavyweight.
Then the heavyweights.
Eighteen year old heavyweights handbook
can pounds.
Ain't going to tell a hundred pounds on
the bench press.
I will let the kid he ever been.
Daniel.
I bought these trainers that they have
are fucking top notch.
There's a ton of Santa Maria in La.
Really?
I don't deal with it at all because it's
all the same thing.
Like everything else in that light.
It's a bunch of white people didn't grow
up in it and it was a hot black guy and
they want to really just suck this day.
Talk about spirits.
I saw a video today,
video.
I'm like,
shame on them.
It's all confused.
It's like those white chicks that suck
that hip do dick.
When they go to hot yoga,
bikram,
big a pig.
We got a bunch of white with Hummus.
Flavor in your mouth that he gets to me
inside.
He you suck that fucking dead.
That smells like hummus chips,
but it's who we're supposed to be in a
way as a comedian.
What's supposed to be the social column?
Oh,
society in a way.
In some way.
So now you want to take that away from
me.
You want to take the way.
I can't say I grew up on the word
retarded.
I grew up on the word faggot.
I grew up on the word.
I grew up on a lot of words that people
don't accept today and I'm very sorry
that you don't accept them,
but it's too late for me to change my
game right now.
Yeah,
I'll try.
My hardest and I try my hardest.
I'm still gonna say tranny from time to
time.
I know it offends.
I'm here to tell you how I see it.
I see it.
This is how I said if I offended you
might offend you.
That was the mind.
Yeah.
Our paper that rewrote my income was
about allyship and they were like,
yeah.
We had two of them that did mountain
comp.
One of them we just more or less
replaced whites would replace Jews with
white men.
I mean,
so would that one.
What we did was we took the whole
document on online and we just searched
the word Jew and we just started picking
sentences and paragraphs.
So what was it that at the end it was
something like,
if we don't combat whiteness,
it's going to be the funeral wreath for
mankind.
This is why I've been telling people
clean up your room.
It's like,
well,
your room is actually network to.
It's not that easy to clean up your
room,
you know,
because maybe part of it is,
is that like everything around you is
full of potential.
Everything maybe more potential than you
could ever possibly utilize and so maybe
all you have is this little rat hole of
a room and some rundown place in the
world.
It's like fix it up.
There's more there than you think.
They devalued what they have right in
front of them.
Like another.
Another client I worked with was having
a hard time putting his kid to bed at
night and so we did the arithmetic.
It's like,
well,
I'm fighting with my kid for 45 minutes
a night trying to get him to go to bed
seven days a week,
45 minutes a day.
Let's call that five hours.
Twenty hours a week,
240 hours in a year.
It's six years.
Spending a month and a half of work
weeks fighting with your four year old
son.
I think you're going to like them.
You don't like anyone.
You spend a month and a half a year
fighting with.
It's a bad idea.
Fix it.
Your life isn't.
Margarita is on a beach and in Jamaica
your life is how your wife greets you at
the door.
When you come home every day,
you get those mundane things,
right.
Those things you do every day,
you concentrate on them and you make
them pristine.
It's like you got 80 percent of your
life put together.
Well,
you have some crazy tweets for sure.
I don't think they're crazy.
You just don't get 'em.
All right.
We have breaking news,
ABC News,
ABC,
I should say.
Just releasing a statement.
What is ABC say?
ABC is just a suit,
a stunning statement and Wolf that says
the show has been canceled.
ABC canceling the revival after Bar
tweeted this about former president
Obama's advisor,
Valerie Jarrett.
She tweeted that Valerie Jarrett,
who was black,
was the daughter of the Muslim
Brotherhood and planet of the Apes.
We were at home in Salt Lake City.
When I tweeted at 2:11 AM,
I just woke up and I had this thought in
my head,
oh my God,
this can make so much sense.
And then I tweeted it and I went right
back to sleep and when I woke up at
seven,
the shit had hit the fan,
you know?
Yeah.
But I was like,
I'm going to expound on this later.
That was one of those kinds of things,
right?
You just want to get it down.
And I,
you know,
always slept with my computer and tweet
when I wake up,
like one year old,
you have to go to the bathroom a lot.
So I always tweet and fall back to
sleep.
And then on the ambient tweets,
my daughter,
I used to always,
when I took my Ambien,
I called my daughter and she or she
called me.
She goes,
mom,
you get,
you're starting to do the Ambien tweets.
Get off,
get off the twitter,
you know.
But uh,
so I just called my daughter.
Then every night when I,
when I was doing the Ambien and uh,
I'd go,
you know what,
here comes the big fish.
She recorded it.
Here comes the big fish right through my
window.
All he's getting stuck in the mirror.
That's what she goes.
Mom turned it all off and go to sleep.
Susan Rice is a man with big swinging
eight balls.
But wasn't there another tweet that you
made a long time ago about who was that
other woman?
Susan Rice?
Yes.
Yeah.
What you said she has giant swing eight
balls that she's a man.
Let me explain that now because this is
the regional listic regionalism.
I'm from Utah and all the girls in Utah
when we got married and are we heard our
moms do it too.
It's always,
where's your ape?
They go,
what?
You're doing this Sunday it.
And he's like,
oh,
he's watching football.
All good.
Let's go out to lunch.
You know it all.
All of the men were all apes.
That's how it is in a breeder culture,
like Salt Lake City,
breeder culture,
Caribbean culture.
So it's like,
where's your ape?
And there's like,
man,
you're a peasant big fucking swing and
eight balls.
I give them that.
You know,
it's a regional logistic thing.
And my point is that this lonely two
things over the course of thousands of
don't mess my point.
I said,
Susan Rice,
let's say that she has.
She has incredible audacity.
That's what I meant as she does.
And you know,
I'm not going to bow down before them
and say you were right and they want me
to,
but they weren't right.
I'm right.
I wrote it bitch,
bitch.
So I know what I meant.
So you don't fucking get to tell me what
I meant.
Here's my impression of Mel Gibson.
He was a,
he just kept clicking the pen and I
will,
I didn't want to say anything.
I was like,
what do I say?
PNF One of the commanders of the immune
system that says,
hey,
let's,
let's cause a bunch of inflammation and
make you miserable.
And so the,
the,
these,
and another molecule similar,
similar to it decreased by 50 percent
and that decreased persisted.
But it's a um,
uh,
I don't have that stuff now.
And I don't know if I can attribute that
to the cells,
but I got a bunch of cells like twice
and that went away.
Now I talk about that for a minute.
Does that sort of a look a little harder
at it?
And it's a mystery to me why it isn't
the case.
But you know,
hey,
if there are places where one can go and
get some help,
it sounds like the old spook around the
corner.
Good for moles,
holes and pimples on.
But it's a vibe.
Incredible.
It is a button.
You press mute or you don't have one of
these?
No,
I don't.
Yes,
you do.
I definitely do.
You do now?
I definitely don't give no.
Fuck.
Snorted so much.
Coke and speed.
Oops.
Didn't mean to do that.
You're fucking monumental.
I love you man.
Love is getting weird.
I'm just fucking with your truth.
So you're into telling me about this
fucking shoulder shit.
Why are you so big?
Wrestling and stuff.
Good.
Googly Mowgli.
How fucking awesome is Steven Tyler?
He's a trip.
He's actually still here.
I don't think he wants to lead.
He's been.
He's hanging around in our lobby staring
at the Werewolf,
said he wants one.
We went into the war thing and I go,
I don't know anything about war.
I'm A.
I'm a guitar player,
but I went down for my draft physical
and when I went into the booth to give
my urine sample,
I made sure I ate Mexican food all week,
so instead of pissing in the Urine Cup,
I took a big dump in it was green and
went all over the place and the guy
went.
Wow.
Really?
Yeah.
Really.
And so I made up the story for High
Times magazine,
you know,
the great magazine of good information.
And uh,
the Ted Hating liberal press started
quoting the high times magazine and
quoting an ex girlfriend who claimed
that I had adopted her,
that I had adopted my girlfriend to have
you read that one?
I did read that one.
I forgot about it.
So this kind of stuff,
like you adopted her so you could take
her on tour with,
you know,
so I could fuck her.
That's what the story was.
But that's APP.
Absolutely.
It works.
That's not how I think.
It makes it easier to talk to them once
you adopt them.
I didn't adopt anybody.
I've never shit pants since I was,
I think eight months old.
Um,
I've never been with an underage girl
since I was under age.
I'm not a racist.
And what else do they say?
Oh,
and they saved that.
They claim that I made Courtney love
blow me when she was 12.
I think she claimed that.
Yeah,
I never met Courtney love.
You can tell.
I don't have a rash of you just got to
be kidding me
with me.
It made it even worse because I've got
to drag that fucking snake everywhere.
80 pound box of shit.
Be like currently.
Carry this around with a bad back over
there.
Hey folks out there.
Pray for him,
man.
He over there who and moving back.
He's making fun of young Jamie and Jamie
is a minor in French.
It's very difficult to talk about
injuries when you were on Jake,
the snake and when I'm going to bring it
up,
totally threw me under the bus.
He told me before when I first got here,
he's like,
I pulled my back the other day,
but I don't want to mention it in front
of Jake.
The snake,
because it's embarrassing.
Shouldn't be embarrassed.
He didn't.
He,
he torres,
Torres,
man Angina and that's,
that's the beauty of it because you
could get somebody like a nimble nuts
over here with a sprain sprain.
Men,
Joanna.
Joanna is warped out of shape.
He can't help himself.
God,
it's like the snake,
when it tries to find the Japanese,
he just likes playing with round things.
You'll there doesn't even the knobs you,
he's stroking the knobs
you want to be for the fight came like
you do on the use side of drug testing.
A was walking back through the hallway
with her official and she crossed paths
with you,
Ana and all by herself and you wanna go
ahead.
Negative.
You know,
when she gave him what's up and then she
was like,
I'm just like officially asked me
something like as you buy the ticket,
or.
I was like,
what do you believe him or do you
believe in them or something like that.
Do you believe him?
Did you buy the ticket?
And then she walked off.
By the way,
like in a moment,
something inside of me.
I was like,
I don't know what she's talking about,
but just gave her the thumbs up like,
yeah,
mother fucker.
I believe in him.
I don't know what you're talking about.
Yeah.
A few years ago
I drove my car on the street.
Then Montreal,
it's second in the evening.
I say,
I told a guy coming at me and he asked
for you beg for money.
I put down my window.
This guy swears.
It's true.
Story is that guy that used to bully me
in school.
I say,
I don't want to say his name,
and I said,
hey,
wait a second.
I parked my name at Park my car,
park the car,
go talk to him as he said,
what the Hell you doing here?
Man is like you.
Is that?
Yeah,
I know,
but things doesn't go well for me,
you know?
I'm like,
I all right is a good man.
You're a tall guy.
You're good looking as like,
what you doing here man?
It's like I give him what I have left on
me.
You know,
like,
I don't remember like I got a hundred
something
or when I met him that way we talk about
like,
it feels so good just to meet them in
the street and make kind of a piece and
give him money.
Like,
yeah,
you beat me up,
you didn't,
but you know what?
Even though you did that,
I give you the money and now he made me
feel like I'm kind of a revenge.
Better than a revenge.
You make me feel like,
yeah man,
you see without me,
you wouldn't have nothing maybe to sleep
or eat tonight,
so I give it to you.
I still give it to you if you do that to
me.
That make me feel much better than if I
would like beat them up.
Yeah.
I can feel tears running down my face.
My chest was wet with tears because I
knew I couldn't do on my own.
Almost impossible for me because I tried
and tried and tried and ended up back in
Nepal,
back drinking.
I almost accepted that that was going to
be my fate and I'll call it.
So I was on my knees in his bedroom
after praying for about 10 minutes,
I got up and I felt the weight of the
world was lifted off my shoulders.
Um,
for the first time in years I knew it
was going to make a comeback and I
called me wife has a parish parishes,
so bought she followed,
was drunk coming home from the pope.
I said,
Monday morning I start to regain mission
to try and get the heavyweight
championship of the oil buck.
She said,
yeah,
yeah.
Because before this,
every time I'd have a beer,
I'd come back and I'm going to be the
heavyweight champion of the world again
because it was,
it was the alcohol talking.
But even when I speak to her now,
she says,
no,
you told me that.
She said,
I hear a difference in your voice
swimming cap.
And next day I phoned up Ben Davison and
I said,
I don't want to go back downhill route,
but the same training,
same promoter,
same anything.
And everything's got to change as it's
going to be a new tyson fury.
That's so amazing,
man.
So art for the last hundred and 40
pounds,
more importantly,
lots of knee braces.
Back braces,
cage,
lost the knee,
but no more knee braces.
Knee braces.
How did he do that?
Well,
let me finish because knee braces and
canes.
Not just to walk but run.
But this is what the program is really
about.
When year he's five,
six,
took a picture of a six foot two son.
That's insane.
Standing on his back while he's doing a
pushup in one year.
One year.
That's great.
Imagine if you didn't see him for a
year.
Hey males,
go have lunch.
I'm seeing in a long time like we're.
Who
the fuck are you?
Where's Arthur?
I found the crack and I followed the
crack and the crack got bigger and all
of a sudden I see fucking glow.
Like green glow.
Crawl on Cron.
Cron.
Find it.
Try to get up.
My tags are too big.
I can't fuck it.
Get out of the little hole.
Can't get out of the hole.
I'm fucking big.
Big,
big,
big fucking hitting,
screaming,
freaking out.
Calm down.
Calm like calm down.
Kelly.
This is the way.
Calm the fuck down.
Reel it in,
reel it in.
We're here.
We made it.
Grab control.
Follow the cracks more up out.
Boom.
There's the K fucking I'm out.
Made it.
You're coming home.
You aren't talking about that was it.
And I texted my girl,
I love you baby.
And uh,
they was fucking scary moment but
daddy's coming home.
So you felt calm while it was flipping?
Oh yeah.
I always will.
I've seen cars flipped,
right?
I've seen it for years,
So I know that it's possible.
So I get in there and I got turned
around at a race in 1998.
I was racing at Daytona and I got turned
around and the car.
So I'm flipping for the first time in my
life and this car's like over 3000,
300 pounds.
So it's,
it's.
But it flies up in the air like it's
paper,
man.
It's the craziest thing in the world.
It's so you're weightless.
You know,
there's the cars flipping.
You're pushed into the seat.
So you feel great.
You feel weight of yourself in the seat.
That never changes.
You never kind of come up out of the
scene like that,
you know,
and so it's like somebody's role to prop
walla grass up against the side of the
car and then against the roof and then
against that side and then,
you know,
it kept doing that and I'm like,
it's just the weirdest feeling and you
feel completely safe and you feel like,
you know,
nothing's going to harm me.
And in doing so,
he was telling this story about being in
this,
uh,
this forensic laboratory isn't an,
as an autopsy was taking place.
And this autopsy table was adjacent to
this,
this huge indoor window that separated
the autopsy suite from this lunch room
and in the lunch room where the rest of
the,
uh,
the forensic staff,
they're all eating their lunches.
They all had tuna sandwiches and cans of
coke and barbecued potato chips.
And they were watching through the
window as this absolutely perfect.
Twelve year old boy was being autopsied
and just hours before at this kid,
like two hours before this kid had been
riding his bicycle,
he'd fallen over.
He'd hit his head on the curb.
And now two hours later,
he was dead and dead without almost a
scratch on him,
just this perfect naked dead 12 year old
boy on the autopsy table.
And as he,
that the technician is eating their
lunch,
watching it through a window that they
watch as the,
uh,
as the,
a pathologist in sizes around the top of
the kid's face,
at the top of the forehead,
the hairline,
and then peels the face down,
like peeling an orange peels the entire
face off of the skull of this little boy
and leaves the face around the neck like
a mask,
like a rubber mask.
And this exposes this liver colored dark
red musculature of the child's
underlying face.
And this one guy watching it with a
mouthful of tuna sandwich,
he points this out and he says,
see that?
That there,
that's the color of red that I want to
paint our rec room.
Holy Shit.
Okay.
So what I do when I got the phone,
I said,
let me do this with it.
Flip it around.
Yes.
And I reminded myself,
why do,
uh,
in,
in the military cadets,
why do they twirl their gun?
Of what possible value is this in
combat?
Why do they do these things with their
gun?
And then I realized you're not supposed
to drop your gun ever,
ever.
So if you twirl the gun and you don't
drop it,
it means stuff can happen to you in
combat and it is always attached to your
body.
So when I got my phone I said,
let me just do this.
Okay,
If I pick up the phone and dropped it,
Jesus Christ.
So when you do that,
then you never drop your phone.
So it's not that I'm a risk taker is
that I've changed my risk to make it so
low that it essentially won't happen.
And you've got apple care to get apple
care.
I know it's going to Bill Maher route.
Do you purple without getting me into
the alarm.
Do you have a Bill Maher character?
Yeah,
I did.
Do.
I saw you.
Did you went to those people who have
those people?
You're not.
Okay.
You're wrong.
There is no god.
Okay.
I never was a bond to heavy man.
I got shit to do,
man.
I can't.
Oh,
the just peeled down or the Dab thing
that I got friends in Colorado,
California now,
the first time I ever did what?
Shit.
I just pulled it like it was a big old
bong rip and then like everybody's faces
was like,
Whoa,
you know,
it was like,
I need you instantly know you just did
something you shouldn't have.
And uh,
I was like,
Oh fuck man.
So I sat down and for a couple minutes I
just started getting really cold and
clammy and was like,
Yep,
I'm going to Puke.
So I went and I was like,
I'm fucked this guy,
so puke rightness,
sink.
And I was like,
dude,
I got to go home.
I feel like dog shit now.
And I'm pretty sure I'm dying.
So we lived in this apartment and I was
like,
went out the door and turned the corner
to go down the hallway to my.
And it was full on vertigo,
like the hallway.
Every time I took a step,
the hallway got twice as long.
It was like,
this is fucked up.
My wife was out of the country on work
at the time.
I was like,
I remember I was sitting down in the
hallway just like trying to get my shit
together,
man,
because I thought I was having a fucking
heart attack.
It was just like sweating and I remember
this voice saying,
get up you stupid junkie,
fuck before somebody comes out here and
sees you sitting in the hallway like a
dumb ass.
And I managed to like pop out of it and
as soon as I got back to my place and
sit down on the couch,
everything was fine but was just so
initial
and the rush.
I was just like,
I don't,
nobody needs to be that stone.
I,
I wanted to tell her story about Mike
because he,
a tony our s,
another guy won't,
we'll call him chuck,
but he's with the government now.
Yeah.
So they always used to go around and,
and,
and want to fight balances and all this
shit.
I used to work at all the underground
hip hop clubs in New York and I take
Brian,
another dude from the school and Tony
and Brian is in the middle of the
fucking dance floor doing the Funky
fucking white boy nerd dance and all
these fuck,
and the floor just opens up kill.
Look at this motherfucking white boy.
Like I might go.
I gotta go,
but listen man,
I know what y'all motherfuckers do.
Don't start.
No Shit.
Wake up.
The next day I get a fucking phone call.
There was these three fucking karate
experts in the club last night and they
beat up all my fucking bouncers.
You know this guys all on the juice rips
off his shirt,
like fucking Tony throws a kick.
Fucking dislocates the guy's fucking
kneecap.
Brian's like fucking fight.
Then all of a sudden I'm fucking whack
and these dudes and us,
we're fighting these guys.
And then this fucking gigantic mother
fucker like lifts me up and carries me
out the fucking door and throws me
across this car.
Brian says,
and I look and it's this fucking crazy
white dude with a fucking scar.
When he points at Brian,
it goes,
don't even think about it.
And like Brian was like,
Yo,
you know,
it was,
he's,
he's a,
he's a character.
Like I said,
I was at his first comedy show
and Qbb who the fuck knows what's going
to happen with him,
you know,
and yeah,
I hope they're,
they're leaning on them so we can get a
rematch.
I mean I love watching invite first and
I can,
I can stretch myself to understand his
reaction.
I can stretch myself to.
And I can't stretch myself to understand
the order guys reactions.
Like I said,
for,
for Habib,
I didn't think it was,
you know,
it was,
it's just,
it's almost,
it's such a foolish thing to do because
listening to date already one,
I know that Dylan was talking shit and
he was angry but she didn't say anything
because I heard a few people saying that
now.
I was standing beside dylan.
I didn't see what he did but I could
hear.
So he didn't say anything and I watched
it back.
I see any kind of backing them on,
you know,
just stupid end the fight stuff,
but it,
I didn't think it justified that level
of response.
And then maybe there was something else
in the leadup,
you know,
Dylan is a bit of a troll online,
so there was probably a bit of a buildup
of voter stuff.
But um,
yeah,
like I said,
it wasn't that big a deal to me.
What have you did or not?
So is that a joint or instead a cigar,
you know,
it's um,
marijuana side of a tobacco.
Oh,
okay.
So it's like posh plot tobacco pot.
Never had that.
Yeah,
I think I tried one once.
Come on,
man.
Probably can't because stockholders,
right?
I mean it's legal,
It's totally legal.
Okay.
How does that work?
Do People get upset at you if you do
certain things?
Tobacco and marijuana in there,
that's all it is.
Millionaire Tesla had Ilan last up to
Tesla CEO.
Elon musk is the subject of a new
controversy.
Elon musk and seeing taken into joint
during a podcast interview with Joe
Rogan.
It's just the latest bizarre incident
for the high profile CEO of Tesla and
space x.
on the same day the podcast was
published,
Tesla's chief accounting officer
announced his resignation.
You did not cite the incident.
So Tesla stock also took a hit plunging
more than six percent is inhaling.
Yeah.
And I'm not sure.
Mosque under fire after taking a hit of
marijuana mixed with tobacco that has
already become a gift.
One of those moving images on twitter.
What about the pot?
Uh,
I do not smoke pot as anyone who watched
the part cost tell.
I have no idea how to smoke.
What might be a higher thinking life?
Well,
he might as well be right if he was an
alien and he looked exactly like that.
I'll be honest,
when he grabbed the joint and the way he
kind of looked at it,
I was kind of like,
it seemed kind of like a guy who was
kind of like,
I'm not familiar with this practice,
but.
Or maybe he's so smart that he thought
it would be funny if you print tended.
He didn't know what a joint was.
Could it be words or this summer?
Right.
But when he said that a tesla going
private funding secure at 4:20,
which is $20,000,000 for that joke,
that joke cost them $20,000,000 to sec
got mad at him.
They find him.
It was on your stock price is a little
bit.
Well that was one of the things in your
shareholders into a panic.
Jamie was concerned that they were going
to contact us and see if we arranged
that pot smoking part.
Like if that was something that had been
arranged in advance because it crashed
the stock.
That was what I was like,
Joe Rogan making noise.
Oh Jesus.
We didn't do that.
Did we?
You know what I mean?
No one says I'm going to bake cookies
and they're an idiot.
Fuck these people bake them cookies and
they got to like it.
No,
no,
it's.
I mean,
it's a.
food is a fascinating thing to me.
Yeah.
I mean,
I guess this is a good time to bring it
up as any.
Um,
you know,
obviously Anthony Bordain took his life
last week and um,
he was a friend of mine and it was real.
That was real hard.
Friday was real hard,
uh,
woke up and um,
I got a text from my friend Maynard from
tool,
um,
maynard said so much for the Keenan
versus bordain celebrity Jujitsu match
and,
and he was like,
fuck.
And I was like,
oh no,
what does that mean?
Yeah.
And so then I googled it and I saw it.
I was like,
Oh shit man,
I can't fuck Wyatt.
Yeah,
just why he hung himself.
Like what Chris Man,
like you would to Curtis Stan.
I mean you go,
you go to the jungles of Brazil.
I mean you go deep man.
That's a,
that's going to be a weird fucking way
to live.
You get up.
I'm just like,
I'm having this late in life childhood
of getting to go to all the places that
I dreamed about and read about,
you know,
I love,
I grew up reading books about pirates
and explorers and so of course,
given the opportunity,
that's pretty much what I'm doing on the
show.
Wow.
What a crazy change of life at 44 years
of age,
how much did you travel before then?
Almost nothing.
I mean,
I'd been to France a couple of summers
as a kid,
a bit to the Caribbean.
That was about it.
I mean,
I,
I was always sure of anything at age 44
standing in the kitchen.
It was that I'd never see,
you know,
Saigon or,
or Hong Kong,
much less,
you know,
I probably had no expectation I'd ever
see Rome,
so I'm just,
again,
I'm just kind of living that out and,
and as long as me and the crew,
as long as we're having as much fun as
we are,
at least finding ways to make like more
and more fucked up television.
As long as we can do that.