My friend.
Why you.
This episode of The Joe Rogan Experience
is brought to you by Audible dot com.
If you go to Audible dot com forward
slash Joe you will get one free audio book
and 30 free days of audible service
audible is one of my favorite Web site
sponsors podcast sponsors because it's
something I've been using for a long time.
They have over one hundred and fifty
thousand titles you can download them
instantly.
They have audio books they have podcasts
they have famous speeches they have the
Opie and Anthony show
they have comedy specials.
If you are in your car like a lot of
people listen to podcasts that way.
If you're in your car if you're commuting
it makes being on a plane or a train
whatever makes it more interesting than
just fucking sitting in traffic and
being retarded.
This will make it so that you're actually
enjoying that time you'll actually be
entertained. The amount of
titles. It's impossible to put
a value to it.
In my opinion I mean one hundred fifty
thousand titles is this is incredible.
I love audible I'm a huge huge fan of it.
I'll give you a recommendation if
your creative title type at all.
Get the War of Art by Stephen press
field a friend of the podcast has been on
before I was a huge fan of his.
Long before he ever did the podcast I
use to hand out the books the audio book
is actually even better very
inspirational Very interesting stuff.
So again Audible dot com Ford slash Joe
you will get one free audio book and 33
days of audible service I guarantee you
if you enjoy reading books you will love
audible and if you have a Kindle Fire
HD which is there the really cool tablet
audible has this really
incredible application called
whisper sync and what it
does is if you're listening to an Audible
book and you're reading a book at the
same time they sync up together.
So if you're reading the book at home and
then you have to get in the car in the
morning it will actually a professional
actor will start reading your book
exactly where you left off.
It's incredible.
So go there enjoy it Audible
dot com for its last show.
We're also brought to you by on it.
That's O and I T on it has.
If you haven't been there in a while or
if you never been there before on it is
a human optimisation Web site.
What we sell is the best shit that
we can find as far as strength and
conditioning equipment.
As far as nutrients as far as protein
powder and supplements of course we have
the primal kettle bells that the ape
kettle bells and the zombie kettle bells
which are new ones that we have
made. Why. Because why not.
You supposed to be inspired when you
working out no better way to be inspired
than to stare at a big fucking 70
pound gorilla head. It's frightening.
It's exciting and it's good for you
if you want strength in conditioning
equipment.
If you want to get fit and strong and
you want what they call functional
strength there's no better
way than than kettle bells.
I'm a huge fan and supporter of them I
work out with them every week and you
should to use skinny fuck get on it.
Oh and I t use a code word Rogan say.
Rogan was on Rogan wrote me yeah.
You know are OJ and save 10 percent
off any and all supplements.
And what is your new Web site do you guys
have while we're on this. What is that.
People can download media to episodes
meat eater dot VH X dot tv so all these
people have been saying Dude how do I
get these meat eater episodes man.
I can't find them online unless you've
gone the bit torrent route which is rude.
Don't do that.
Now you can go to meat eater dot VH X
dot tv it's a site that allows you to
finally sell volumes they can sell volumes
of the meat eater episodes online and
in HD as well.
And if you use the code word Rogan you
can get a five dollar discount on any of
the volumes.
And the one that we were on is season
four volume 4 is the bundle that has the
one with Brian Callanan that's
got both of them. Yes. Oh good.
So according to Helen Cho's
e-mail I assume she knows.
So that's it right there.
I'm so glad I didn't
get those now like that.
I know it's Friday and we get
a lot people asking about that.
We'll finally meat eater dot VH X dot tv.
That's it.
Do you have. I'm sure you have a
link on meat eater dot com too right.
I'm guessing meat eater is
immediately become more meat eater TV.
The meat eater dot com meat
eater sounds like it could be.
Well some guys sitting on it.
Oh well it's you and a gay porn
couple vying for fitting it up.
All right.
So go there meat eater dot VH X dot
com and go to the meat eater dot com.
Steven now is here. Let's not fuck around
any further. Cue the music. Young Jamie.
The Joe Rogan Experience. To. Get.
Some pigs are gonna die this
weekend Steve. No that's right.
I'm I'm 90 shots in my shoulders made
out of fucking hamburger right now from
all the impacts unless someone think
we're talking about police with time bomb
suits scruff.
Yeah I thought about posting a photo of
the targets that I shot and some pigs
are going to die but I didn't
think that that would be.
No that could be problematic.
Sue Sue. I'm glad you're here.
This the the Eurasian wild boar.
You know it's interesting man
all.
All pigs in North America so domestic
the kind you and your bacon feral ones
wild ones it's all one species.
Yeah you told me that much is
there's differences. They react.
They recognize them all as one species.
There's some old world like there in
Africa there's some other members of the
pig family and have a leaner and not have
leaner Pachauri so like many here have.
People talk about pigs in Arizona
they're often talking about a pack.
But yeah all the pigs so Charlotte models
the spider Wilbur from Wilbur to hog
Zilla is soooo scruffy.
That's so strange. I didn't know that
until you told me when we're in Wisconsin.
It doesn't seem right but there's always
varieties you know it's like what.
You know that but all that they
roll all the dogs under Romney.
You think that pigs look.
You think that Wilbur Ariel like you
know like a like a classic though they
don't really exist.
The is like pink hairless farm pig.
I mean he doesn't look as different from
what we'd call a Russian boar which is
a variety. He doesn't look as different
as a Chihuahua does from a mastiff.
Yeah but they would discuss those as
being what Qantas domestic Qantas domestic
what is of the common dog.
What's weird about the common dog is
that they all emanate from wolves.
All of them now.
That's so strange.
That's while you take a wolf and turn
into an English bulldog like How the fuck
did that.
But I don't know those boys
and you you might read this.
Those boys in Russia that were taken
silver foxes and just like selecting for
behavior and stuff they could move
those things so fast. Really. Move.
Move the trait to me.
Yeah. They're just. Yeah.
I came home the details and if I did tie
the details you'd look it up and then
call me in time world's wrong.
But somehow I don't I learned
not to get too detailed.
But they could move dogs really fast.
Selecting four color behavioral
characteristics was amazing.
Just a few generations you know.
Wow. They're very malleable.
I've always wondered how.
I mean I think it's a massive mystery
isn't it how dogs were initially created
of wolves.
I mean you hear so many so
much contradictory stuff.
I got a point in time I guess I've always
kind of followed this a little bit and
I've written about I learned a lot
about dogs. I mentioned this to other.
I wrote a piece about eating dogs in
Vietnam and so I had this kind of little
summation in this article
about the history of dogs
and it went through the fact
checking process at outside magazine
which is very rigorous like if you say my
mom is my mom they'll call your mom.
And make sure it's your mom in
I had all these things that I kind of
like assumed were just true you know and
this fact checkers like
that's in fact not true.
So I had to relearn my understanding of
dogs at the time they were saying oh you
know it seems that dogs originated in
China and you know like the oldest trace
of dogs is there.
Since then I feel like I've read that
you know they definitely the first
Americans deftly brought we're traveling
with dogs brought them down in the New
World.
But here there seems to have been some
intro aggression from the Grey Wolf.
So they picked up some
other characteristics move
things along the way even
though the guys that came through the
Bering Land Bridge were not pack and with
them a dog that looked Wolf like their
prey pack and with them a dog it was
decidedly domestic dog like wow.
So they had already gone already gone
through some you know who had already gone
through some transformations they were
just traveling Wolf dogs they were
traveling with a dog that had been under
selective pressure for you know fifteen
years.
I mean because I remember one time saying
all the domestic dogs seems to go back
30000 years the domestic dogs need to go
back thousand years but people arrived
here you know is debated but some time
between maybe 15 20 thousand years ago
and when they showed up they
had a dog that was not a wolf.
But but then there was intra
aggression from wolves.
But this seems to be like a really hot
topic and people are always digging into
this because genetics is
changing everything we
understand like things that we
used to think were related are not related
things we think we're not related are
in fact related.
You know we talk that I like
the whole media thing like that.
MUELLER seemed to be a very new species.
You know since the Pleistocene really.
Yeah. It is not. They
have been around long.
It was like a hybridization event between
black tailed deer and white tailed do
you created the media.
It's like our newest big game species and
it's probably will be one that doesn't
last long.
You know it'll be like in the long term
you might look at mule deer and see them
as this this blip really just like.
I mean they're so susceptible to
being out competed the very habitat
fragmentation is hard on them
and they have been here long.
I mean other hand whitetail deer
been here millions of years.
They're like they thrive.
They're super adaptable they
can eat anything live anywhere.
They're amazingly
capable of surviving on this continent
and mule deer like this new thing.
It's a bar like my favorite animal.
I like the sun.
You know the sun's going to last for a
billion more years it's going to burn out.
But I think I like this.
I like them you'll hear a lot to this
and it seems like I mean despite a lot of
people's best efforts to prevent it
from happening it seems like Mehldau are
vulnerable.
It seems like they're slowly
starting to die off too.
There was an article about the numbers
dropping in their habitat dropping and
being diminished.
They're being pushed down then.
Some things are hard to explain you know.
But white tails they've always lived in
the southeast and white tails seem to
periodically expand out again for climatic
reasons retract but they kind of keep
that like ancestral homeland.
I'm talking very long term ancestral
homeland the southeast but once I'm white
cells made it all across the country and
some climatic conditions or something
happen in the population retracted
but it left this remnant population in
California on the car on the Pacific
coast and then there was a massive genetic
barrier.
You know like if you took a bunch of
dogs and separate them and put you know
some dogs in South America and some dogs
North American came back and checked on
them in a long time they're going to
have gone in a little different direction
and that became the black tail.
And then at the time the black tail seems
to have extended its range eastward.
The white tailed deer extended its
range back westward and there was a
hybridization event where male black tails
were breeding with female white tails
and producing like this hybrid mule deer
there's a habitat retraction again in
black tails retracted back to the coast
and white tails retract back the other
way and you had this that spawned this
thing we call me older how do they follow
that.
Like how do they know there was all this
guy various guys who's like the most
interesting biologist he's a guy out
of Calgary and various guys has kind of
like done so much work on big game.
He's got like the mule.
He's like people like oh he's the military
guy. He's dealt guys the buffalo guy.
He came up a lot of interesting theories
like solving some stuff we talked about
the past where various guys came up with
the idea that what happens is species
when they colonize land had
been vacated by glaciers.
You know there's certain things that go
on and you got into founder effect you
know where imagine like one way we got
different as people is imagine that just
like for people
struck off across the oceans in a homemade
craft and landed there and you had a
male and a female in a spawn a new you
know they successfully breeding cranium
population.
Let's say they both just happened to
be six seven You know in three hundred
pounds you had like this thing like
the founder effect where a small little
population can carry traits and
characteristics that are maybe not totally
not a complete example of where they
came from and so you have like a radical
deviation when they spread out.
Wow. So he got into this
stuff with animals and in
water animals seemed to change
like when the bison
arrived in North America.
Why did it also have a 6 foot horn
span and then shrank very rapidly.
So he got into a lot of these ideas and
he also did a lot of genetic work you
know like mitochondrial DNA.
So they can track female descent
you should have in mind sometime.
Yeah.
You know he'd be the coolest guy to
have on the world actually various guys.
Yeah. Where do you live.
Could I come listen. Yeah.
Just listen at home with most people
right. We could just come in you come in.
I'm sure you'd have questions yeah. You
could just sit there and drink coffee. OK.
And I'll come and I'll be like.
Sounds perfect.
I no explain this to me Mr.
Guy is that he's a great guy.
So he was he got in a lot of stuff with
the deer and I bring all this up because
we're looking at your fine specimen you're
fine four by four mules sitting here
and would've never happened
if it wasn't for you.
Boom boom.
I was watching this thing there was
talking about deer on television they were
talking about the difference in the
size of the bodies of deer from the far
north like Alberta in Canada to
the far south. Like in Mexico.
And the further you go south.
The animals tend to be smaller
they tend to be smaller bodied.
Yeah it's the prints maybe got Mickey.
It's the print.
Alan Burt is the burger principle.
It's got a name tag there's a name for
that principle and it would be that if
you'd like to take the extreme like
white tail like the biggest guys dream of
going to Alberta to hunt white tails
because White tells a huge meal out 100
pounds right there a nugget big
know that's crazy that's an elk.
I mean 400 is huge but you know you get
deer it pushed up and you go down the
Florida Keys. That's a white tail.
Those things are 70 80 pounds.
So there's this principle the burger
Bergman It's got a name my brother he told
me the name what is and what some
species seem to be a little bit exempt.
They say that mule you don't do that
quite as much you know you get some really
big meal and other areas they're not
they're not as tied to but just like a
general principle what do they speculate
has to do with is heat retention.
So
you have more like you weigh more than me
I have
more surface area per unit of mass than
you have so if you're really big deer if
you're in the north the thing you're
trying to do is retain body heat in the
animals like people shed body heat by
just exposing parts like when deer lay
down they lay down with their legs talk
to them because look on the inside of
deer's leg. Very thin hair
very thin hair under the tail.
Right now we're laying down to protect.
If it's cold they're protecting
those areas that have thin hair.
So a big animal has less surface area.
So he's he's less capable of shedding
heat and more capable of retaining heat.
A small wiry animal has greater
service there. He's able to shed heat.
So one of the things you look at Mueller
like Mehldau further south will have
tend to have bigger ears because a very
a great way to shed heat is through your
ears will have thinner hair on their
ears bigger years if you think what a
radical version of it is
imagine like the woolly mammoth.
OK Roy Mann with the woolly mammoth
is more closely related to the African
elephant than he is to the mastodon.
So you had North America at the tail end
of the Pleistocene he had mammoths and
mastodons and mammoths were not
very close related to mastodons.
They're pretty close were they to African
elephants mammoths live in the north.
They have essentially no ear.
They have a very small here.
You look at African elephants had those
giant friggin ears because they can
funnel a lot of blood through
those ears and shed a lot of heat.
It's like you shed a lot of heat through
your fingers you know in your ears how
they get so cold so fast because you're
able to you know you push a lot of blood
into those areas and it's
cooling off in the air.
So that's one reason that that's
like a theory of if it is.
I think it might be the Bergman principle
Bergman's Bergman's rule that's where
Bergman's rule would has
one explanation for it.
I don't know if you'd ever really know
the absolute truth an explanation for its
heat retention heat dissipation.
That's fascinating so the stuff that's
on the northern extreme of its range
where it's boarding up against like the
thing that that puts the throttle on its
existence is cold.
He will tend to get bigger in mammals.
You know he'll tend to get bigger but
then there's all these other deviations
like why do you know how you get these
huge reptiles on islands you know. Yeah.
And then on islands you tend to have
dwarfing like that Rangel island off
Siberia had these little
mini mammoths you know. Yeah.
So there's all these other factors like
I don't you know I don't know why it's
like that with islands but not
with latitude. Do you get that.
And I've also I think I've read from maybe
as various guys was writing about how
Mehldau seemed to not be quite as they
seem to defy Bergman's rule a little bit
more than some other species do
prob because they're a hybrid.
I've no idea. That's fascinating.
The island dwarfism is a weird thing.
It's bizarre how it
doesn't apply to lizards.
Yeah they get you know like yeah I guess
those things get huge and these get
small you'll know nothing about weird
thing about Mueller and it just kind of
fits here in California like
you know I've obviously I five.
So for
black tailed you are very very similar
to Mueller Columbia blacks also in
California have Colombia Black Tail
Washington Oregon you have colony black to
eventually get up to the north of just
north on the coast you get to the B.C.
Alaska border these are calling them six
black tail sick of black tails man you
look at them like they almost looked
like a white tail but they're a black
tailed deer the Columbia Black Tail
resembles much more Amelia for record
keeping purposes the divided between
the range of the Colombia mule deer I'm
sorry the divide between the range the
Colombian black tail and the Mehldau is I
5 really.
So if that's some jumps the road he
is for for record keeping purposes he
because he he goes from being a Columbia
black tail to a mule deer so you look
like the all the record book Columbia
black tails you know are shot along the
the the left side of I five on a northward
direction because they're just like
so you know they're much bigger than
anywhere else but they gotta divide it
somewhere it's divide divided like that.
So when one thing's life he
could jump back and forth.
They're not even recognizes as distinct
if you look at the Latin name for him
you know the scientific name for him
there like taxonomy is don't recognize the
difference but we all do it like you
look at I mean like that's not a I mean
older man I can tell by looking but it's
just these morphological differences
these things you see but they're not
really betrayed in them you know in the
genetics that's fascinating man that's
it's so interesting trying to track the
history of these animals and somebody
actually did that and figured out yeah and
it changes all time yeah they use it like
this one is like my old man he used to
reject so much this stuff because it
would change but while you say this so no
made it look well they were saying the
best understanding and now this is the
you know it's not static subject to
change but it's frustrating for people.
I'm glad you're on this week because this
is a week that's pretty controversial
in the news.
This story about this black rhino that
they auctioned off a hunt for this is
some fascinating shit to me because
fill me in. Do you know the story.
I only know I know no
more than what you said.
I've been I've been at the thing oh all
week. Oh you are the shot show. Yes.
I haven't even.
There is a.
They they auctioned off a hunt
for a black rhino in the winter.
Paid three hundred fifty thousand
dollars to shoot this rhino.
There's only like X amount of thousand
of them left in the world and people are
going fucking bananas can I guess that
they're using that three hundred fifty
thousand dollars to put up enforcement.
Yes they can.
For conservation they generated over a
million dollars in the auction. Really.
Allegedly. Yeah. And what.
What they're saying is that this rhino
had to go anyway because this rhino was
an old non breeder and he was very
aggressive and he was trying to kill the
younger males. And because it's an extinct
or because it's an endangered species.
This was an animal that they were going
to have to do something about anyway.
And really.
Yeah.
They would have either had to I guess
put him in animal prison or they're going
to have to fucking shoot him.
So they decided to auction off.
They have this very specific animal that
they've targeted this old non breeding
male.
And the guy who auction who won the
auction is now in fear of his life.
I mean the really the press is has
he gone and done it. No not yet.
He lives in Dallas or just outside of
Dallas and he don't know if I was going to
pick what town he lived in.
I was going to ask you about that too
because Texas is a fucking strange place
man. You know it's way
different wildlife model. Yes.
Since being introduced to hunting by you
I've become pretty obsessed and I read
about it all the time and I'm trying to
sort out all the different philosophies
and try to figure out why
people think what they think.
But what I'm most fascinated by
in Texas is these wild game farms.
Is a really weird thing they do where
they'll they I saw some online that were
like fucking 70 acres and they have a
high fence and people pretending that
they're hunting in these things.
Yeah they'll sometimes set
the animal out on the day.
It's it's crazy. I mean it's but it's
something. But let's come back round it.
I want to talk for me about
the I the the rhino thing.
There are versions of that
here and we can talk about.
I can talk in a much more educated
where you're much more knowledgeable
fashioned about versions of that that
occur here in the U.S. but like I've never
been to Africa I haven't hunted in Africa
I have ill like ill informed opinions
about what goes on in Africa but I
recognize when it comes to stuff like this
it's there are so many contradictions
that are hard to deal with.
And it's really difficult. People get
their heads wrapped around why a guy
you know I don't know.
Not knowing the person.
I can't say that the person is saying
who's like oh I would just as happily give
you the money to help save rhinos but
if this one has to go anyways I suppose
I'll come and get it.
You know I don't really know what his
motivations are his motivations are not
that he he's a part of a big
game trophy hunting group.
Yeah.
He's never gonna be he's not gonna build
bring it back into the U.S. probably.
I don't know. I don't know. I mean
I know what he was trying to do.
I don't know he's planning to do.
I don't know but I know I've been reading
all these articles of the interview.
The guy he's afraid of his life.
I mean they're talking about skinning
his children alive. Is that right.
Oh it's fucking you know animal
rights people get pretty crazy.
Can I tell you about it can I tell you
about a parallel like a parallel thing
that goes on the U.S.
It's like I just can't speak to it they're
like I don't even know who is owned
the rhino. I mean is an honor.
Is it like Sonic conservation.
It's not a concession.
Well what they're doing is they have like
you know X amount of thousands of them
and they need money in order to maintain
the pride. Who is they force it.
That's a good question.
I don't know.
Yeah let me talk about a parallel thing
that happens in the U.S. if you're
interested. Yes. Get
in the US we have we
abide by the basic notion.
This is generally true in the US
that wildlife longs to people.
So if you have us take an imaginary elk
in this imaginary elk is on the also
National Park and one day the elk jumps
the fence and lands on national forest
and Montana jumps on a fence and his
own state forest in Montana and he jumps
another fence and he's on
a big ranch in Montana.
Throughout that animal's day he has
always been U.S. he's always belong to the
people.
When he's in Montana he's belong to like
the state of Montana is in charge for
his management.
So we have this idea in a rough sense
we have this idea that we maintain here
that the wildlife is held in the public
trust an individual can control access
to his lands for hunting but
the animal belongs to state.
You don't get to make
decisions necessarily about
the things that are on your
property.
And that's been something that like the
Americans and particularly the American
hundreds of AHS been proud of.
We had this like North American model of
wildlife conservation we always talked
about which is this idea of public trust
wildlife and that we manage it in long
term things because people have a
vested interest in having more and more
animals around for whatever
purpose viewing hunting et cetera.
One of the things they do though and so
you take an animal like like the bighorn
sheep in the bighorn sheep at a
time was pretty nearly wiped out.
I mean they were hurt.
They were never hurt and as bad as black
rhinos but they were hurt and really
bad. And as we got them restored we
started having limited numbers of tags.
May have a mountain range and every
year they determine that we can kill one
sheep out of that range and
people will do this every year.
People will apply for a lottery that's
conducted by the state and you put your
name in the hat.
You pay a fee they you know put all the
names they're drawing out be like Dave
draws a tag and this generates a
whole bunch more and they use it for
tranquilizing sheep that
you can helicopter in the
new areas and restore the
species and all the funding
comes to this kind of stuff.
One thing they realize a great way to
make money is if you can get that up
blessing you can kill five out of that
mountain range they might want it gone.
We're going to you know we'll do four
through the lottery which is for everyone
like the common man's pool but we're going
take one and auctioned off every year
the one the bighorn sheep take
they auctioned in Montana.
It goes for two hundred three hundred
four hundred thousand dollars.
Every year I mean I think
reasoning went for 380 or 4.
I mean it is always up there.
I don't I don't think.
I don't think it's broken a half million
but it goes up because if you go out in
Montana and you go hunt six if
you go on the Missouri Breaks
all the record book Big
Horns come out of there. OK.
Like the biggest big horns the biggest
Rocky Mountain big horns come out of the
break.
So guys will pay a ton for the gut what
they call the governors tag in Montana.
And it raises a ton of money and it does
a ton of good but some people feel I
see both sides this argument.
Some people feel like that bit of money
is not worth the damage you're doing by
upsetting
this idea of democratically
own and ministered wildlife
like most guys will put
in their entire life or a big ownership
tag you know pay the fee every year and
they have no chance.
I've been putting in for that tag
for 14 years I've accumulated.
They started a bonus points system 12
years ago and a bonus point system is that
every year you put it in the next year
you get a you get up every year you put
him without being successful you get a
point in a square year points so next
year my name will go in the hat
one hundred and forty four times.
If you did it for your first year
your name will go on that one time.
Even with my name in the hat one hundred
forty four times I don't think I'm even
up to having a 1 percent chance
of drawing a big horn sheep tag.
So meanwhile guy come in
and he makes much money.
One guy that buys lately made a
lot of money selling sandwiches.
He comes in and he's like me buying
one of those and I'll buy it next year.
And people like all that
money is so useful and it is.
People are like Dude this is not the
country we live in because we're still
we're still kind of hurting from the idea
of where we came from in Europe which
is like the Robin Hood model.
You gotta be rich to hunt a lot of
people don't know that the Robin Hood was
actually based on hunting.
Yeah.
It wasn't based on stealing money
from the rich and giving to the poor.
It's based on the poor
weren't allowed to hunt.
Yeah. He would go out and hunt
the Kings animals and he used it.
I mean at the even at the time when our
ancestors were like first coming over
you they could kill you for hunting they
kill you for hunting and then you had
to be rich to hunt.
So when guys like you think I like the
story of Daniel Boone man he came out and
he's like Jesus whole you know
his relatives came from England.
He comes over here is like man
this whole freaking country.
I go hunt wherever I want.
So people really fell in love with that
idea of freedom and you know and that
you kind of roam around and the
animals were there free for the taking.
And now we're a little bit upsetting
this model but all the people who were on
the other side of this say
the but the money so helpful.
And it wasn't for big chunks of money
like that we wouldn't have recovered the
bighorn sheep as effectively as we've
recovered the bighorn sheep and it's not
cheap you know three or four hundred
thousand dollars for a tag is incredible.
Type in Montana governor's tab you'll
see what it went for last time.
Do they sometimes fail.
I mean they must must.
I heard a story where the guys that the
guys that buy it once you spend that
kind of money you want to
rule out uncertain and you
know that you can picture
the area right.
Yeah.
You know all this stuff he floated through
and we saw when a guy I'll buy what I
want a guy held by the governor's tab.
He'll usually hire some guides or he'll
hire some guys to go spend a couple of
months they'll put together a dossier
on the animals that are in the area.
Yeah man. Oh my God. That's ridiculous.
A scout and when they
find one they stay on.
These guys just specialize
in this business.
Look at that four hundred and
eighty thousand dollar bid.
The record for 2013.
Oh my God.
Four hundred and eighty thousand
dollars somebody paid for the tag.
Look at those dudes going to war.
Yeah sack is kind of tucked up to the
left he can't really appreciate it. Yeah.
We we showed that video the other day
of you talking about wanting to eat it.
So it's valuable to people. It's
a ton of money. Not the sack.
No no not Zach. No but it really makes
people mad. Yes. There is a story.
And how do you know it's true.
I heard it from enough people
I tend to think it's true.
So these guys go out and they'll get
a guy they'll get guys out there.
They find a tanker you know
they want to ram it scored.
This got over 200 inches of horn or more.
And they file and they don't
let it out of their eyes. Right.
They stand up stand down and eventually
the guy comes out and they go.
There he is that's the one you want a few.
There's a rumor a few years ago this guy
had done this need spent all this money.
I think I heard. I'm just telling you
unsubstantiated stuff I'm nothing Tony.
I'm not telling you what year or is names
I don't because I want to say that and
be wrong about what a high roller buys
this thing pays a figure rumored to be
around 30 grand to have some guy fired.
Check this out it comes down to it and
guys like third one from the front third
one from the front.
They go down and the goalie
get mixed round and she was in
it goes or is wrong one. Bam.
Rumor has it that that he
that this gentleman later
bought another one went out
and bought another went out and got a
big fatty so he might have spent five
hundred six hundred grand.
I and man I see it like it tears me up
because like everything in life it's so
complicated. I see both sides
of it. Like I love our system.
I love the idea that
wildlife is public trust.
And I think that the like there's no
other way to explain the success of of the
richness of animals and the riches of
rulers habitats we have in this country
when you look at how many people live
here how wealthy we are what we call the
technology. Like so many other countries
that would be sitting where we're at.
Have destroyed their wildlife you know
but we have a very in place like a very
intact system.
And we've done a fantastic job and I
think that one of the ways you explain the
fantastic job we've done is that we really
held true to this idea that wildlife
belongs to us.
And when you do damage to it you're
doing damage to this idea of you know an
American treasure you're damaging
other people's interests.
So yeah man it's complicated. So that's
my long way of answering. The rhino thing.
I'm.
I bet you anything it is extremely
complex complicated and there is emotion
battling logic.
I'm amazed that it's cheaper to kill a
fucking rhino than it is a big horned
sheep that is mine.
It is amazing doesn't
buy me 100 grand plus.
That's crazy.
That's amazing. What's the
ivory worth. Not worth that.
I don't think they have ivory. They have
horns. Their horn is made at a hair.
A rhino has no black rhinos got.
No.
Oh rhino horn is not ivory but it's
very valuable. Yeah it's not ivory.
No no it's it's valuable because they're
idiots because people think that it
makes your dick hard.
And like I guess they haven't heard
about Vi Agger wherever the fuck they're
trying out rhino horn.
But I went to I went there did I mean
just like three days ago I saw the act the
current head of the U.S. I went to see
the current head of the U.S. Fish and
Wildlife Service speak about some issues
that we'll be facing this year in the
U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service is getting
really involved in the rhino trade and
we talk about all the money they're
spending you know spending money and
enforcement you're spending money on
trying to battle the sauce like that you
might somehow convince people
that they don't want it.
You know all the things you would do.
I mean really think about the millions
and millions of dollars of Tarmoh thrown
around a member being like to bet you
can't go find any guy who wants to go get
one. You'd give him more money than
he's ever gonna make hunting them.
Yeah but doesn't the world doesn't work
that way because some other day would be
like but nobody like you would make
every rhino poacher really wealthy.
Yeah and they just be like Okay cool
I'll quit. But it wouldn't work.
And other people come along
to be a rhino poacher too.
No I know but I've never heard a thing
of those guys could only know the amount.
Because you know they're
not like no matter what like
that business I don't like
moat the guys that are actually out there
with firearms you can imagine the guy
that's out on the ground hunting rhinos
being chased by people who have pretty
much a license to in some cases kill them.
Like I don't think that guy is a rich man.
He's he's making someone wealthy but
there's no way that that guy is rich.
And not only that it's
just such a bizarre thing.
The idea of shooting this giant majestic
endangered animal just for its horn and
they're not eating them they're
not doing anything else with them.
They're just shooting them
and taking their horns.
And there's no real medicinal value. It's
not like the rhino would be one thing.
The rhino horn had this incredible anti
aging property and it turned you into a
young person again.
Well you know they'd probably fucking
kill every Rhino they could find.
But it doesn't do anything it doesn't
really do anything but think about what
it's just but it's it's probably I
mean it's it's an issue of poverty.
Yeah and of that justifies mom saying
like I don't even know the guys that are
out poaching rhinos.
They might not even have any idea who it
is that they might have like some vague
awareness about the properties but all of
they believe in the properties as well.
Yeah I'm a little bit ignorant about
who's actually wanting these rhino horns
what I've heard it's an Asian thing.
But it seems to be one of the
most bizarre misunderstandings and
miscommunications ever in this day and
age with all the information that's
available especially because
it's always about penises.
It's always about guys. Well it's a foul.
Getting a red it isn't foul Yeah yeah.
It's gonna be just that
it's a nice phallus. Mm hmm.
But they did grind it up
for medicine man only.
It's so strange.
I mean it's an amazing animal when you
look at a rhino it to me I mean it's one
of the closest things when you look
like a triceratops or a stegosaurus or
something like that and you look at a
rhino it's like one of the closest things
to that ancient time you look at this
big fucking giant armored animal.
It's a strange strange animal you know
and the idea that people are killing it
to make their dick hard is
just so bizarre and and.
But no they're killing it to make money.
Yeah people are buying it together
to make the big art. Yeah.
And it's not even working.
You know it's just so strange.
We shouldn't have.
We should make a public service
announcement right now we'll have dropped
leaflets over China just it doesn't work.
His bags full of aggro drop them with
parachutes just just launch them you know.
Yeah.
Isn't it amazing like in that way that
this stuff now I'd be like no do this
really does work.
I mean like you to the point where
it could cause trouble for you try.
Well we have to go to a doctor
because your dick won't go down.
It works on everybody too.
Works on dying people chew up a biography
of a zombie dick and your parents
scratching at your zipper those veins
and you think that there would be no.
Do you think that the pharmaceutical
industry would would not the pharma that
what's what's the word the
effort like the aphrodisiac.
Yeah.
Guess what.
What is the term.
No I'm saying what is the term for like
something that you look you want Asian
whore or are you wanting
for these all right. Yeah.
Did the aphrodisiac market for men would
you know these Dick hardening market
for men would evaporate.
Well now that there are pharmaceuticals
there specifically tailored for that and
are clinically proven to work.
Well that's how you know that's how the
American troops get information about
the Taliban from the Afghani warlords
is vagaries and no one method of payment
really.
Yeah because these guys a lot of these
warlords you know though they're live in
like the same way they lived back
when Alexander the Great was running
Afghanistan.
Afghanistan has Kabul and then mountains
and mountains filled with villages and
extremely primitive locations and you
know that they're live in old school and
sometimes as a guy who's a warlord who's
got 20 wives and his dick doesn't work
anymore.
And you know they come along and they
go look we've got guns it's like I got
guns and we got women I've got 20
wives and I can even fuck them.
Oh listen check this out.
Give him a bottle of pills and guys like
listen these Taliban Fox I never liked
them.
They're hiding over there.
Those guys are over there.
How many more pills you got to give
these guys cases cases of Niagara.
They tell them everything.
They can't stop talking.
Yeah I've heard a big mac diplomacy.
That's the way via diplomacy.
That that that actually works.
I'm 40 years old month.
You ready to get it on the
vagaries that we try to tell me.
No I'm saying it's
back to this.
This rhino thing you're talking about.
Yeah.
I just can't I can't.
I just my head wants to blow up because
I just I see all sides of it. I do.
But that's beautiful.
I think that's important the part I don't
see the part I do not see though for
me is I don't like I would never like
I don't have that desire to hunt one of
those. But so much of that
kind thing is in his heart.
People that don't understand so much
that kind of stuff comes from context you
know well you develop over time a deep
context with an animal and for me that
familiarity in the hours you spend the
hours you log watching it understanding
it reading about it starting it for me
develops into something like produce is a
great desire to hunt the animal.
Once I get to know it an animal that I
don't know well I don't have any desire.
I don't have that much desire to hunt
for it but when I watch him and watch him
and watch him like like bighorn sheep
when I'm when I moved to Montana when I
was born Amish when I moved to Montana
I didn't go out there being like Man I
cannot wait.
I'm bighorn sheep.
But after spending years and years and
years out you know glassing for deer
glassing for elk glassing for bears
and like Big Horn Big Horn Big Horn.
And I really got through.
I love to watch big horns.
I liked everything about big horns and
in time all that man would someday love
to have an opportunity to go a big horn.
And it was born from that.
So when I say that I have no desire to
hunt Ryan I'll be like it's just like it
would be to me like like honing margins
like I just don't have any you know
familiarity with it.
It just doesn't like culturally.
I haven't read about it
my whole life I haven't.
Like when I go and look at calendars
like hunters love wildlife counters and
it's like all the stuff we like to hunt
you know you don't grow up looking at
like the Ryan O page on a
one on a hunting calendar.
It's just I just have no context with it.
And this gentleman that that bought
this thing I don't know. I don't know.
I don't know anything about him.
I'd love to talk to him.
He doesn't want to come on your podcast.
Yeah.
I don't think he wants to but he's he's.
His name is Corey Knowlton and he's
got a private security detail following
around all the time now.
He's giving this interview for this
interview with CNN and he's talking about
the people of threatened his kids because
he has people threatening to kill him
right now that I have to talk to the
FBI have my private security keep my
children from being skinned alive and
shot at a little hyperbole a lot of people
are just talking shit. I'm not
going to kill your fucking kids man.
They're not murderers but people get
angry when they hear about someone hunting
something as a trophy and absolute.
I think that there's a big distinction
between you wanting to hunt a big horn
sheep because you you follow it
and you study it and because.
But you eat the fucking sheep.
Yeah that's that's a difference man.
There's something creepy about wanting
to shoot something just so you could
stuff it and put it in your room
Yeah it's complicated it's complicated
it's complicated it is that that is like
it would feel very if I did
shoot the rhino I would eat them.
There's no way I wouldn't eat them.
Are they edible. They must be. Oh yeah.
Lead elephants.
I know that you shoot an elephant in
the village as friends of mine that have
hunted and friends of mine
that hunting in Alaska.
Sorry friend by the hunted in Africa.
Kind of marvel at the
rapidity with which like.
Like how or how quickly the animals get
hauled off and consume as it is like
not a lot of waste.
You know there are some animals that you
look at and you think they'd be really
good they're not very
popular and other animals.
You'd look at and you wouldn't think
would be that great and the really popular
table fare.
I don't know what the reputation of
rhino is but elephants are popular.
People like the elephant.
My problem with Alice my understanding
they're intelligent that bothers me.
Yeah yeah. Intelligent animals. It
bothers me. I have no desire to hunt one.
But again I have no context.
No I don't and I don't really understand
for me to go.
Like for me to go Huntsman also have to
know that it's sound that it isn't as
safe.
Position and one nice thing about
live in the U.S. I mean there's some
exceptions to this but generally in the
US like if you want to be if you want to
be ethical about your hunting practices
in the U.S. you can generally look to
the guidance of your state
Fish and Game agency.
I mean the state Fish and Game agency
get away with.
I mean theoretically can't get away
with and practically can't get away with
running a species into the ground.
You know it would be big trouble for them.
So generally if you if you're looking in
and you realize that there's a you know
there's a population of big horns and
there's some and there is a hunting season
form right now it's it's OK.
I mean it really is OK if there's if
they're finding a decline in that thing
they're going to curb it or cut it out
altogether and wait till it's growing
again.
And then you can also look at their long
term goal of you know where they want
animals. How many animals I
think the area can support.
So it's easy in the U.S. cause
this stuff is watch so much.
Obviously again coming from
guy to spending time in
Africa I know that in Africa
like money talks in a way that it
doesn't necessarily hear when it comes to
small issues like like wildlife.
You can buy your way into things that
maybe you don't have any real ethical
business doing you know in the
U.S. is just easier to kind of.
There's a lot more information at our
fingertips so for me when I when I go
hunting I can really kind of read up and
understand a lot about what I'm going
after where it's at.
What the management goals are what risk
the animal has is hunting it you know
productive and helpful right now as it is
potentially detrimental to the species.
And you can make your decisions.
It is amazing how good a job the
Department of Fish and Game or what is the
actual group what are they called.
Well there's the state so you have U.S.
Fish and Wildlife Service which is that
which is a federal thing and so they have
a hand in they have a hand in managing
migratory waterfowl but
most things are managed by.
So every state has a you know you kind
of like just in general terms you calm
fish and game but it's like in Michigan
it's the Michigan Department of Natural
Resources in Montana's Montana
Department of Fish Wildlife and Parks.
But just as a euphemism
versus fish and game.
So you know every state the D department
environmental conservation in New York.
So every state has a different name
but it's a State Department that sets
hunting and fishing
regulations in the new state.
The powers to be big boards and they'll
be be the people that said it will be
biologists various figures
different stakeholders.
So you'd have representatives from the
hunting community representatives who are
outside of the hunting community will
all come together and come to some level
of cohesion and in some level you know
they'll find a happy middle ground when
they set their quotas and they often mean
they meet every year to determine what
can be done and not done.
And they can control harvest number
ways by issuing tags shortening seasons
lengthening seasons you can if you want
to slow down the harvest you might move
the season away from the rut.
You know if you want to pick up a harvest
kill females you know if you want to
if you want to bring a population
down because of various factors like
agricultural interests auto insurers you
know generally want like generally want
deer numbers lower agricultural interests
generally want deer numbers lower
landscape people often
want deer numbers lower.
So to kind of factor like their concerns
and you got the concerns of people who
want hunters want more deer they want to
see more deer around and you figure all
this out there's all these management
tools to try to find a way you know to
tweak things.
Another thing is predator
control if you're if you
have a population it's really
hurting you go in there and do predator
control in that area and sometimes you
can bring you know you can bring
some animals back from the brink.
It's possible to lose isolated populations
like it's possible to have a mountain
range and you get a you spend few hundred
thousand dollars a million dollars
would ever move in some big horns in there
and you find that you're just getting
hammered by lions and you will lose all
the sheep and lose your whole investment
you might go in there and hit those
lions a little bit you know save them.
So there's so many tools at their disposal
but you know in general in general
there are exceptions in general I think
that I'm always amazed how well the
state Fish and Game agencies do Yeah
that's what I was going to say it's
probably one of the most efficient
government agencies ever.
They're good and you know everything
about them is is they don't get a lot of
hard funding there's not many agencies
like get so much of their funding from
license sales and so firearms taxes.
That's why there's so there's a lot of
conservation money out there right now
because the gun businesses have been
blown up as people feel that their gun
rights are under attack.
They've been buying so many firearms and
puts money in the you know the Pittman
Robertson filing is called
that gold conservation stuff.
There's excise taxes on firearms excise
taxes on ammunition excise taxes on
sporting goods.
All your license fees.
Every guy whoever hunts
ducks are migratory birds has
to buy a federal waterfall
stamp state waterfalls stamp all his
money plows in and creates money for
conservation work research and so these
agencies are in large measure some more
than others are self-sustaining.
You know that's what I find things I know
that you get annoyed by Peter as much
as I do.
It's like they're not spending the money
on doing this stuff that hunters are
like hunters are are bankrolling so
much of wildlife research and wildlife
conservation.
And it's not just stuff that
benefits the animals we're after.
You know my my problem with groups
like PETA or the Animal Liberation
Organization the people that want to
fucking save lobsters and rescue them from
restaurants and thrown
back into the ocean.
There's a lot of knee
jerk reactionary nonsense.
It's not based on the actual science
of understanding the population these
animals.
That's what drives me crazy.
When people start getting angry at people
hunting wolves like this is a perfect
example there's they've opened up Wolf
season now and a bunch of different
places. And the reason being
is that people's livestock
are getting decimated elk
populations are getting destroyed.
I mean they they have to move in to
control it but to a lot of animal rights
people all they see is bloodthirsty
maniacs that want to kill beautiful wolves
and they don't understand that.
First of all a these wolves
have been reintroduced.
A lot of these areas and then be like
we're supposed to be the stewards of the
land we're supposed to be the intelligent
people that understand the numbers and
that something has to be done about it
this isn't something that people decide
I'd like kill the wolves
yeah let's make it legal.
Now they're going hey we've got an issue.
What are you going to do.
Let's all meet let's compare data.
Let's see what we got.
Yeah I'm going to do here.
Yeah.
You get this idea like oh they've just
one day decided to go in and do it and
it's I'm sure you have.
On one level you have individuals who
absolutely like a guy opens up his
regulation but he's like walking by a
wolf type does your that individual does
not really need here.
That individual does not really need
to understand is nice if he does but he
doesn't need to understand the full
picture because that individual is a tool
being used by managing agencies like we
need to get rid of some wolves we could
bring back the days where we have like
you know government agents going out and
gun form or we could open it up and have
people actually pay money to go out and
have the opportunity to try to do
what we need to do anyways you know.
So the guy that goes out I can't always
speak to every guy that goes out in
hunts wolves.
I can't speak to his motivations I don't
know but they're servicing a greater
good and that they're being used as a
tool that winds up being an economic
driver.
Which kind of like points to
the efficiency of wildlife
management is like you
could hire the job out which in some cases
it does because there are you know we
do have government trappers
do some Wolf control.
But it's kind of nice that you can one
up turn like rather than you're paying
someone to go out and do it.
You can have people pay for
the opportunity to go and
do what we know needs to
be done. And in these cases we're going
to have to get rid of half the lower Wolf
numbers.
No one's not that no one is.
No one's arguing for like a
new extra patient of the wolf.
That would be in the worst
interests of the managing agencies.
The last thing Wyoming would want now.
Like you guys they get the
wolves delisted. People
are suing to stop the deal.
You know the de-listing Wyoming
gets the wolves delisted.
They're going to control no one in Wyoming
and the government would like to see
wolves wiped out and put back
on the endangered species list.
It'd be the worst thing that
could possibly happen for them.
There's no interest to
like extra paid them.
You know no one's arguing for extra
patients is bringing them into control
because we are puppeteers you know I mean
there's a lot of people living here in
your backyard you're like really
balancing a lot of interests you know.
And so again it's like
like so much in life you really have
to take before jumping to the stuff the
emotions of you really have to take
the time to look at this stuff.
It's a long complicated issue.
It's long there's a lot of factors
and we haven't gotten into ballistics
ballistics.
No one else trying six now I'll try to
explain you all the different caliber.
That's not to say it's like the whole
world of yes it's that's kind of why I
love all this stuff man. It's like
it's like chess or something. Well
there's new things to
learn that's for sure.
You know before long before I ever even
thought about hunting I would see a
beautiful deer and I'd be like Why would
anybody kill that is so cool to look at.
And then you see a few
people hit him with cars.
And one time I was driving home I was
doing a gig in upstate New York and I had
to drive home like 30 miles an hour
at the most because fuckin deer were
everywhere is madness. It was in the
middle of summer and I've never seen more.
I don't think I've ever seen more than
like two deer my whole life until this
day. And then I'm driving home from
this gig and it was fucking madness.
It was upstate New York in November.
I want to say it was the summer but
I it was so long gone. All right.
They were out and about fucking madness
just jumping in front of the car left
and right you see them on the side of
the highway and you see men get plastered
by a truck and it opens up
like that thing's made of me.
I had no idea they were exploding.
I mean I saw at least four of them that
had exploded and wrecked cars and it was
one of the craziest things
I'd ever seen in my life.
I don't know why there's so many of them
in this one particular area of upstate
New York but it was a
really an infestation.
Yeah.
People are so whacked out too like it's
in those areas in the northeast or you
know there's so many deer and they're
like well maybe we can hire snipers to go
out at night and shoot them or give them
a you know we'll put the deer on birth
control.
Yeah.
Meanwhile I got all these dudes being
like I've got a great I know the perfect
way.
Open up you know suburban urban
bow hunt people pay to come on.
Was like no we'd rather pay. I think I'm
in arenas the come out. What was that.
By the time they did this deer the town
lauds deer population was all sent down.
Had a thousand or more dollars
into each. Do they got rid of.
Well it's going on right now.
You know in the Hamptons.
Do you know what's going
on in the Hamptons.
No I also have overpopulation of
deer. So they're hiring sniper. Yeah.
They're gonna put suppressors on these
guns and go in the middle of the night.
They're gonna hand at night so that people
don't have to experience it or freak
out and they're gonna shoot these fucking
deer because there's so many of them.
And then the other argument was let's
let's get them on birth control.
They're gonna spend three and a fifty
thousand dollar implant give fucking deer
birth control like what are you talking
about this is there was a TV show about
this.
Well it's all to prevent the harrowing
experience that might happen to someone
so they wake up in the morning and
realize and see a deer run into their yard
and tip over because they had a heroin
and as much as upsetting as Abby is so
much better to go out and does
that night quietly snipe them off.
You know there is a line it all up.
There's a video of this happening in
some other country of. They showed these.
That was a joke that video lions released
to deal with the deer population that
was like The Onion.
Jamie's googling shit.
Yeah. The Onion you fuck.
It was one of those fake onions there's
a bunch of onions now fake onion you
know the onion if you don't know is a
parody website site there's a bunch of
fake ones that aren't nearly as good at
like being obvious but there's so fake
that they say the only known him. No no
no. Oh no. They're just like National.
Blah blah blah report.
But they're bullshit they're bullshit
like one of them had a report of the day
that Colorado legalized marijuana
37 people died of an overdose.
Oh fucking I can't tell you how
many people sent me that I'm like.
Marijuana is not toxic.
You dummies like you you'd literally
have to smoke fifteen hundred pounds of
marijuana in 30 minutes to die.
It's not killing anybody stop but these
people you know they read this online
and they think it's true that
there's been a gang of those.
Yeah.
Has anyone ever died like you ever heard.
No one ever dies from marijuana.
It's not possible.
You couldn't you physically wouldn't
be able to smoke enough yourself.
The the the L.D.
50 like we've we actually
we're talking about L.D.
50s of thing. That means lethal
lethal dose at 50 percent lethal dose.
Oh God I've heard that shit remember.
You know because my brother works in
his work involves a little bit not the
user but the understanding of herbicides
and pesticides that he talks about L.D.
50s on pesticides.
Yeah.
Marijuana is so high it's insane.
But there's a lot of things
that have really low L.D.
50s ecstasy for instance like if you
take I think it's 10 or 15 times the
effective dose of MDMA you're dead.
Yeah.
You eat 10 ounces of salt if you're a 200
pound man eat 10 ounces of salt you're
a goner.
Zero.
Yeah.
But think of how upset your body gets
when you're snorkeling or something and
you get a couple gulps.
Oh yeah. Or just you start Rach. Yeah it's
salt water. That's a miserable feeling.
Well it's also if you want to know if you
have like some sort of bowel issue and
you want to clean out the old pipes a
little bit of it take some Epsom salts and
some water to do a couple of tablespoons
garlic and shove it down the pipe and
it'll be like a broken 5 0.
Oh my goodness.
It's it's it's unbelievable.
It's very effective.
I used to wash when I was.
I got this job and I was 13
washing dishes at a summer camp.
I was washing dishes for campers that
were older and I was and there's a cook
there.
Was David S I'll say and when Dad does
he would drink iced tea and I put a bunch
of salt in his eyes to mess with him so
he'd sit in a big salt and spit it out
as retribution.
He comes up behind me and kind of puts
me in a lock and grabs my forehand and
tips my head back and fills my
mouth with poured salt Yeah.
Wow. Gave me some sauce made me
throw up. That's dangerous. Yeah.
He probably didn't know that you
could die. David S. that fuck.
Where are you Dave Davies.
Well I'll tell you the name of camp.
Camp Pendleton one.
Where's that at a West Michigan.
Is it still open.
Yeah. I've no idea. I don't
know why it wouldn't be.
Camps are fucking little. They're a little
like breeding grounds for criminals.
When I was a kid I went to
Boy Scout camp for two weeks.
It was just a bunch of inner city kids
from Boston alone in the woods with very
little very little guides
like Lord Of The Flies.
It was dangerous man.
It was I by three days in I was there
for two weeks by three days in I realized
like this is fucking dangerous you have
to keep your eyes open in the middle of
the night cause it was dark as shit and
kids were getting up in the middle of
the night and tying kids to their beds
and then leaving them in the woods like
Drag.
Oh leaping out.
You know they would wake up screaming
alone in the dark like in the woods.
No there's no predators or anything
in New Hampshire but it was fucking.
No it still brings out a the
ruthlessness of youngsters.
Yeah. So there was all these activities
I just hid and went fishing every day.
So you were in the boys game.
Yeah I got up in the morning and just
said fuck all your fuckin plans I'm going
fishing.
You took my fishing rod and vanished and
they didn't care as long as I was back
at the end of the day.
They even those gone.
No one knew I did the archery things and
then I went and fished and that's it.
I remember you know I work at the mass
ate at Outside magazine and they're
telling me that the most letter the the
most letter generating article they ever
ran was an article that
was deemed to be critical of the
Boy Scouts could have been another.
There had been a number of catastrophes
that happened to Boy Scouts that scout
camp like look a handful
things was a lightning strike.
There was a drowning incident this ma
thing is an area kind of ran this article
like is your kids safe at Boy Scout camp
and it really riled the organization
up. I think they were Tell me why be the
number one letter generating thing ever.
Well they don't want to face
the reality of the situation.
It's not 100 percent safe. If you're
going camping it's not 100 percent safe.
Most likely you're going to be fine.
Statistically you're
probably going to be fine.
But when you've got a bunch of inner city
kids they have fuckin bows and arrows
and pocket knives.
They're wandering through the woods and
there's only like three counselors there
was like 30 fucking kids and
three people watching us.
There was a lot of shit going on.
And you know they tried to wake the they
grabbed me in the middle of the night
but I woke up and I screamed and I jumped
out of bed and they let me go and then
there's just a bunch of
little in your city thugs.
And I was young I was probably like at
the time maybe twelve maybe 13 somewhere
along but there was other kids are like
16 and 17 and they were the ones that
were doing shit and they were you know
they were the Eagle Scouts the older
fucking weirdos that had done this many
times they'd they had been camp and
three or four years in a row and they
had like they were looking forward to it.
They were never the way
they were the warlords.
Man they covered you call
closed toothpaste toothpaste
doesn't come out of your
clothes try washing toothpaste out of
your fucking. Example a dribble dribble.
I got my take I have no
vertical toothpaste when I
fucking squirted all over
peoples clothes and mash them together
and throw it back in you and you pull
your clothes on the
cover with it was brutal.
Just a bunch of little criminals alone in
the woods with very little supervision.
My old man was involved was real heavily
involved in Boy Scouts for a while and
I think he'd become an Eagle Scout
and I joined Cub Scouts as a kid.
But the problem the way it was like my
dad was always doing such interesting
stuff and would take us to
do such interesting stuff.
They'd be like you know whatever Wednesday
it was a cub scout meeting you could
go do like nice things like if you
didn't have a dad it'd be great stuff you
know.
But on one hand like I could go over
and we could do like not tying this over
that or I could go out deer hunting my
dad it's like he always like would kind
of trump you know you could
do like the way cool stuff.
So I never got involved in it but it
was it was great for him because he was
born like an inner city kid
you know and didn't like that.
He was born in inner city kids wanted
to somehow be out in the woods.
For him it was a perfect avenue into it.
But then for me it was like a you know
you couldn't do his cool stuff doing that
as I could hang out with you know my
dad and his friends my kids I never got
really involved in it
when I was in high school.
I don't remember the kid's name but
someone wrote a really cool article one of
that one of the kids in my school about
a boy scouts about the problem with the
whole the code of the Boy Scouts because
one of them was keeping your thoughts
clean.
It was all right.
Yeah I forget the exact words.
Let's put up Boy Scout code so you get
to thinking about something that you like
mannish and be thinking well that's.
That was that.
That never works.
This guy was the guy who wrote this.
I remember reading this as I was you
know a high school student girls kind of
got a really good fuckin point.
The point was like What do
you give a fuck what I think.
Like why are you trying to control my
thoughts like I'm not hurting anybody I
might think something crazy and deviant
but I'm not doing it if as long as I'm
not doing it I know exactly
what's to keep my thoughts pure.
Maybe it's fun for me to entertain
ridiculous thoughts but isn't that I know
because that's kind of like what
self-control is. Mm hmm. Yeah.
Like self-control doesn't
speak to that thought.
The ideas you entertain self-control
speaks to like you get an email and you're
like I'm going to write a really mean
email back and then you it's fun to
imagine what you're saying. I mean email.
Put it up. That's my you like read.
You write a regular email and that is
like supposed to be like adult behavior.
Exactly. Yeah. Control.
Yeah well but you know some role
in controlling your actions.
You see someone who's an asshole on the
car and you want to pull them out of the
car and beat him to death but
you don't you don't do anything.
You just go and you drive down really.
Yeah I would.
I would pull his fingernails out.
So his eyes open and throw salt on
them and make us stare at the sun.
I never go there.
I just go to bone breaking right away.
Snap someone's arm.
They don't want to fight back.
Yeah.
Trustworthy loyal helpful friendly
courteous kind obedient cheerful thrifty
brave clean reverent.
A Scout is reverent towards God He's
faithful in his religious duties he
respects the belief of others.
Yeah. Here's the big one.
Clean a scout keeps his
body and mind fit in clean.
That was the one that this
guy had a problem with.
I remember reading and going yeah the
fucking boy scouts are silly kids right
but that's not what the
fucking scouts were.
Wasn't when I when you were in.
Well I was I went to my branch was in
Jamaica Plain which is not a very nice
part of Boston. It's become
more gentrified now. Yeah.
But in the early late
70s 19 I guess it was 80.
Nineteen seventy nine or eighty when I
was in it was fucking creeps what push
you to get involved in it.
What was your like. You
wanted to get out. No
I mean I liked fishing.
I liked outdoor stuff.
I was always into doing stuff from the
outdoors and I did a lot of fishing.
I was always fishing seems like a good
avenue Yeah perceived as good avenue to
get out and I just thought
it'd be fun something to do.
I'd love to be an Eagle Scout.
Thought to be a cool thing to
be an Eagle Scout you know.
But then once I got in I was cool with
the scouts until we went camping and that
was.
Get the fuck out of here
and then I was done.
I got here so sad to
miss my parents so bad.
Remember first time I've ever been
away for like two weeks by myself.
Bunch of fucking criminals in the woods.
I came home I was so happy I saw you.
I can't imagine now Max got
homesick when I was a kid.
Yeah I got the opposite of home sick now
you know I mean yeah I get homesick as
a kid.
Well do you find love.
I find I travel so much that when I'm
home for a couple of weeks I'm like Okay
ready.
Let's next.
I try not to be that you know
I try not to but yeah you do.
You get used to certain momentum you
know when you get home for a while.
My wife sometimes point out that you
have been home a week and I can tell you
you know.
Why don't I.
The one way I don't get that way is with
my kids like I never want to leave my
kids. Yeah and whenever I go
anywhere I like on vacation.
The thing that or on a trip to work.
The thing that always gets
me is I hate leaving my kids.
You know I don't like leaving out but
my wife I'm fucking leaving her at all.
I love her but I think it's good.
I think it's good to get the fuck away
from people but just not little kids.
But if it was just me and my wife
I'd be fucking vacation and calm.
I mean how would I be working.
I'd say vacation.
I did the long term it's going places.
It makes me appreciate or more it
makes me appreciate my friends more to.
Good good.
I think there's a balance and I think
when you're around someone all the time
you don't appreciate them as much as
when you go where you miss them and then
you come back.
I feel that I feel that's true for me.
Yeah I got to watch for
our sakes I can't imagine.
I'm trying to picture my wife going to
listen it's just busy all the time you
know.
But I never know what she might get a
free minute someone might tell her about
it. That's the real problem.
Yeah like a tattletale.
When I was little bitches
she goes to the gym with I.
I just want to say though I love my wife.
I love my wife.
So if my wife listen and hear
that my favorite person ever.
Yeah.
But just like I think that you know like
there's a balance you know and part of
the balance is appreciating
things when you're not there.
You know when you when you're
gone you appreciate them.
You know what.
You know my wife was annoyed with me
recently I discovered this Waylon Jennings
song called Freedom to stay.
It's like this dude the narrator Waylon
begins where he's got his backpack and
he ties it bandanna on.
You know and he goes as Dawn as woman
sleep and he's gonna go off and roam
around you know and be a vagrant and
he realizes that everything he wants is
here and then the refrain is kind of
like you gave me the freedom to go my own
way which gave me the freedom to stay.
It's like she got annoyed.
You know I keep saying it to her and
telling her how is our song you know.
That she. She liberated me from my
desire to be a wonder. Oh that's funny.
Well you know you have a very strange
life for someone to be married to you.
I mean you're constantly gone
away hunting. Yeah I'm gone a lot.
And you also are gone in places where
you don't get any cell phone service.
You know you know like you're in the
fucking mountains and you know you're off
in the landscape you're in New Zealand
you're not in these places where you know
you're gone and you come back
with this dead animal in a cooler.
No my life was last like
where where were you.
Who had gone who was with you.
Did you get anything.
And she usually likes
to ask after I get back.
It's like she's the as and has
when I'm gone when I get back.
She likes to know those things.
My three old ones know what
I could powered copout.
And if we're gonna eat it now she
doesn't want to know right. Yeah.
Yeah I guess I have I mean I
have a very nice existence.
You know I got to spend a lot of time
going to fantastic places and doing cool
stuff.
It's a very unusual life for a hunter
that you managed to figure out how to make
a living doing that.
I mean I know I used to think I would
make a living like I thought I'd make a
living doing that I was gonna make it.
I knew I wasn't made.
I knew I wanted to make a
living hunting when I was a kid.
I want to be a professional
hunter so I'll try.
I'm trapped for a long time and got
sold for got really involved like really
heavily involved in trapping and you
know took lessons and trapping rolling
about trapping I'll like to
be a professional trapper.
The fur prices are so low when I quit
trapping those just like wasn't gonna
happen and then I hit on this idea that
I would write about the write about that
kind of stuff instead. And so it's
like writing was kind of my plan B.
But yeah I thought that
I would just live out.
You know like when I was a kid I had
this dream or this fantasy that I would
just live out in the woods and never
talk to anybody and hunt you know.
And I kind of like made my living like
communicating with Soulsby the thing.
The one day I was the one thing that
wasn't in my plan was I was going to
communicate well that's really funny
because you're good at it you know and the
fact that the writing is there was sort
of you know it came about in order to
make it so that you can
make a living hunting.
Know you're a really good writer
man mediators a great book.
Yeah I enjoy what I enjoy it.
I remember when I was in 10th grade I
just English teacher Mr. Heaton and I had
written an essay I'd written
like a comparison contrast
paper about Melville and
Falconer.
So I came here what and for the English
class and he's gonna submit your essay
to a writing contest. And I forbade
him from doing. I can't imagine why.
I told my I was gonna do that I don't
want to be in the contest presented
anyways and I won second place.
When I got this letter that I had to go
this awards ceremony it mentioned a cash
prize super excited I suppose
you 250 bucks or something.
We go down there and the gal that won
the event was at this place called the
frozen ball center in Muskegon Michigan.
The gal at 1 goes up and gets a check and
then I go and they give me a thesaurus
and I was just like bombed I thought I
got 250 bucks and I was like visibly bomb
Mr heating had come to the awards ceremony
with me and he said he said something
I'll never forget.
He's like You know there's far more
than 250 dollars worth of words in that
book.
Yeah that was kind of my genesis as a
writer was the idea that the book is worth
250 but no he meant like
that if you can capture.
No no not his point I mean like you
thought you were going to get 250 bucks.
No they just change their
budget wasn't what it was.
I mean I never had a satisfactory answers
the wide and get to him 50 bucks but I
went there wanting my check and come out
of this book. I slammed the thesaurus.
You know do you really. Yeah that's
fine. Now keep in mind box like specials.
How did you wind up doing the wild within.
That was that was how
I found out about you.
You were on a show on the trial channel
it was called the wild within it was an
interesting show.
The first episode I ever watched you
were going to take the same route that
Lewis and Clark took and you shot a moose
and turned it into a boat made a bobo
out of a Buffalo Buffalo.
That's what it was. Yeah.
You shot it with a musket too right.
I mean you want like the show business
story about how I did but what made you
decide to be on TV like we did.
I would periodically like as a writer
I would periodically get called by
producers and developers about stuff I
had written or they would kind of summon
you you know like you might get a phone
call or you get an email and then a
phone call an email through a magazine
or whatever and realize that some guy at
History Channel wants you to come down
and and what they do is they're desk
bound individuals and they're obligated
to go into these meetings you know and
have like some ideas.
And so when they're putting together their
portfolio of ideas they would like to
go contact writers or people who are
out doing interesting stuff in the
hinterlands you know and come in kind
of report about what's exciting at the
time.
And I'd gone to a number of these meetings
over the years about stories I had
written and every time you get
the e-mail you're like Oh my God.
Be on TV and it would never work out.
But eventually I signed a development
agreement after I wrote my first book
scavengers God or cuisine which I just
got the rights back to the book sells
like there's so few those books out there
that they sell on Amazon for like 130
bucks.
Really.
And I just they just like Miramax The
Weinstein Company just gave me my rights
back. Wow. In a move that would
benefit them in no way whatsoever.
Just like out of the goodness of their
hearts like gave me the rights to my book
back.
Why they do that.
Like know lonely as much as people like
to talk about Harvey Weinstein being
like the worst guy on the planet.
I don't know that I know that his
companies gave me my books rights back.
I didn't even try to get money
out of me just gave him to me.
I've never heard of the worst guy on
the planet people telling you horror
stories. You know I've never heard any
horror stories. But I don't have any.
Here's a great book or a great documentary
detailing a horror story that he
dealt with. Those are right.
Yeah it's called overnight.
Oh if you see that's a great movie.
Yeah.
And that guy was to blame and that thing.
But yeah yeah that guy like the cover
of it is him hold the camera to his head
like that.
That's a phenomenal movie.
If he fucks it on now if you haven't
seen it it's about the producer writer
whatever of said fuck and shoot him out
scenes. Yeah. Boondock Saints. Yeah.
Terrible FUCKIN MOVIE BY THE WAY. DON'T
YOU DARE TELL ME THAT'S GOOD. NO I WON'T.
BUT NOT YOU.
I mean whoever you are out there
you fucking freaks like that.
People have told me that's good.
And I watch nose like I made it 20
minutes and I was like this is a piece of
shit. Terrible movie.
I didn't know anything.
I watched it after the documentary.
I was like I watch I my I go see this
movie but it only validates that you know
validates the movie.
Yeah well do you know what it came
out of it came out of Pulp Fiction.
There's that.
Yes this whole breed of this genre
that came out of Pulp Fiction.
But what they don't have sent Pulp
Fiction is a fucking genius movie from a
genius movie maker.
I mean Quentin Tarantino is a bad mother
fucker do when I want to see that movie
it felt like like like like something
came down from the heavens and touched my
forehead.
I had never seen him like I didn't
know anything about like cool.
I was blown away but it's so complex and
there's so many layers to the timeline
switched around and meets it's a genius
work of film and then this fucking dummy
came along and decided to make this shoot
him up and there's gonna be why fuck
you fuckin fuck and fuck
fuck fuck and bang bang bang.
And it's just it's an assault on your
intelligence it's shit and I just thought
it was a piece of shit and then I watched
this documentary on the guy who made
it was like Oh and being it's a great
job I don't know anything about the guy
that made that movie It's
a great job and a movie.
Yeah well I mean the people who made it
look the guy whoever made overnight like
a phenomenal job with the guys who made
it were the guys who were involved with
him in the beginning yeah
they were documenting this
this rise to fame they were
supposed to be documenting this guy who
worked at a bar Harvey Weinstein signed
him to this gigantic deal and buys
the bar and they're gonna own the bar
together and make giant movies together
they just were convinced this guy was
brilliant and meanwhile he's like saying
Alec anti-Semitic stuff and he's just
ego that the documentary is about ego
and if if you're a person who's like you
planning on any sort of a career in
show business I think it's a must watch
because I've seen those people I've never
met him but I've seen a hundred guys
like him that didn't make it.
I've met a hundred of those guys they
were convinced that they're the baddest
motherfuckers it's fucking towns.
Never seen anybody like us before
we're gonna fucking run this town.
I've met those guys I've met so many of
them and acting and the film business
breeds them it somehow or another the
idea of acting first of all is responsible
for a lot of disproportionate egos egos
that are not based on anything realistic
they're based on your ability to pretend
and then not even based on you being
really good at pretending sometimes
but you being famous for pretending and
these people just because the camera's
on them and the people pay attention them
have these enormous insane egos
I've seen it on sitcoms sets.
I've seen it in movies I've seen the
actors I've seen and the madness like the
reality of of life escapes them they they
they are insulated from it completely
and they live in this world where the
camera's on them and there they have this
idea that because the camera's on them
they must be special so because they're
special. But there is no ego check
there's no answer then you know to get.
OK like to put it in the honey
terms like say please say it's OK.
If you're gonna go after a very difficult
animal to track OK I'll say if you're
gonna go after Himalayan tar yeah OK
you're gonna fucking climb through the
mountains it's an incredibly difficult
task it takes a long time to get there
you might not see one for days when you
finally do see one sheet like this mule
deer that the skull that's unstable is
perfect example you and I hiked around
for days we walked seven hours we
worked our asses off and it's a haul.
So when that thing actually
when I actually shot it
and it dropped and then we
brought it back it was like wow
like we did it we did something.
Whereas if if that thing was in a pen
okay and I walked up and shot it in the
face I would have zero
feeling of accomplishment.
Well acting is a lot like
shooting an animal in the face.
It's a lot like shooting a penned up
animal in the face like you're not really
some Special person you're
just someone who's crazy.
So you're good at pretending because
you don't really have a self identity or
your self identity community be
manipulated in you know or you're your
personality can manipulate it in a role.
This is what you're saying has
validity because you do it you act.
I have I have acted I avoid it for
that very raw because I feel like those
people are sick I feel like there's
something about that occupation where you
pretend to be like you know many people
I've met that like they play tough guys
in movies so they think they're tough
they're fucking crazy I've met so many of
them it's it's a sick way to make a living
it's it's some people pull it off and
they become really sensitive people
like Henry Winkler The Fonz Yeah.
One of the nicest fucking guys I ever met.
I'll tell you I haven't heard that
I've heard from multiple people.
He's a sweetheart fly fisherman.
No I've heard that from old
people wrote a book about it.
I've never met an idiot on the river his.
Yeah yeah I've not heard of it and I've
heard from older people what it was like.
It looks like how surprised people are
what a great guy you talk to him you
would have known he played a tough guy.
Yeah he could turn on and turn off
electric appliances by punching the wall.
Please don't go to your high too which
is really what I mean I'm a short guy and
he's tiny me it's weird.
You know like this guy was like
this tough guy on this show.
How did that ever work.
Yeah.
He would walk into a bathroom and bang
the wall and run out of the bathroom and
he would talk. He tells
Cordero and they're good at
it. He's good at it too man.
But you know I've met.
I mean my point is I've met
a lot of really nice actors.
It's not a broad sweeping generalization
but I think that the occupation itself
is it's so unchecked like up
Tommy Francis is very checked.
Like if you're a funny comedian the
you the reason why you're funny. Yeah.
You have to write the meat.
You have to write the comedy.
You have to perform it. You
bomb you reassess. You go
back to the drawing board.
You have to figure out how to do it.
Once you actually get to doing it
there's a certain amount of humility like
after ten years of doing that
almost all comedians possess.
When you talk to them about comedy even
if they're really good at they'll never
tell you like I'm I'm a bad motherfucker
I'm the baddest motherfucker that ever
got on stage.
They know you live a flop
in such an immediate way.
MAN Yeah you die you fucking
you eat shit up there.
It happens so often you crushes your ego.
I get the badge you guys like.
You just watch you go ahead.
It's like a movie like you make it there's
all this excitement stuff and later
it doesn't do well. You're like up
there going like this is not going well.
Well I never done it.
I could just imagine how humiliating Am
I the way I described is like sucking a
thousand dicks in front of your mother.
It's actually probably worse than that
because it's somewhere out there that
someone that would like to suck a
thousand dicks in front of his mother.
Nobody wants to bomb on stage.
Now just a horrible crushing him.
But along the way one of the things you
learn is to be really good at comedy.
You you you have to lose all of
your sense of self-importance.
You have to lose all of that pretending
you're something special like you're not
something but you're just a person.
And the best way to do comedy
is almost to be non-existent.
Like you you're you when you write and
when you perform there's almost no you in
there unless it's a self-deprecating
aspect of it like you're you're pointing
out things that are silly about you or
pointing out ridiculous ideas he might
have had in your head at one point in
time but other than that like when you're
performing you're never thinking man.
I'm up here and I'm killing.
You don't think of that at all like in
fact you're almost like a passenger in
this weird ride that you've put together.
Yeah I go and you all you know is that
you kind of know how to do it and all you
know is that you kind of have to keep
at it in order to continue do it.
And it's really fun to do.
But the moment you start taking it serious
or tripping in it all of the success
of it to you being super special and
amazing and unique you fucking suck.
But where did your comedy suffers.
Oh it goes terribly wrong. Yeah.
Because people know that they
don't want to laugh at you.
Part of laughing at you is like you have
to belong in the moment of what you're
doing and if you're in the moment of what
you're doing the last thing you gonna
be thinking about is how awesome you are.
Like that doesn't come up whereas an
actor like you can pretend that there's
something really special about you.
Like when that ready action and then you
do this role and you you play this guy
it's all pretend it's all bullshit.
So there's the checking aspect to being
the ego check and the creative process
the tuning in that does is nonexistent.
We were treated probably around you.
You treat with a certain
amount of deference to that
you're not going to get us
doing standup.
Exactly. They're treated like
we were treated like shit.
The commune is a way you know people like
you if you're good and they appreciate
that. But no one like takes
it seriously as an art form.
Yeah it's one of the reasons
why plagiarism was so he's
so a huge problem with
comedy whereas it was treated with you
know if you think about plagiarism in
literature there's lawsuits and people's
careers are really like you'll you'll
be disrespected.
Music massive lawsuits.
I mean people have lost millions of
dollars just for a riff like one of my
favorite examples is there's a great
song by the verb Bittersweet Symphony
idealism but that riff is
stolen from the Rolling Stones.
So because of that those guys made
nothing. They didn't make anything. No.
Yeah they had to give it all away.
I still like that sounds great song but
the lyrics are great it's interesting
but there's no doubt about it.
That riff comes from the Rolling Stones.
Stones to remember oh you
know you know this little bit.
I think maybe you forgot. I'm going to
see you on January 30 first. Oh yeah yeah.
Oh cool. Is that sold out. Yes
we talk about yeah. Not sold out.
It's been sold out for months
the last time. What is it.
The last time. The rings.
That's those are the last time.
Yeah I will. After I saw you last time
when I went to see you in New Jersey.
We were driving home my wife was
saying to me she's like my face hurts.
From laughing at heart and I want to write
a thing I want read a thing like that.
I want to envision writing
something called like the
only happy comedian because
he's like I don't understand comedy at
all but you got to think you come at it
from a position of strength
in some way you'd like it.
Like so much stuff is funny because
it's like from a place of self-loathing.
Like so many comedians do like a
self-loathing thing and I to be real.
It's like it's kind of like they're
just where it spawns from is like
self-hatred.
And I'm so pathetic you know.
I mean it was like fire that you build a
whole act bill whole act and like come.
Like you're at a position of strength.
I'll have you ever think of it that way.
But like you're up there like you seem
like when you're up there you seem
somehow like in control and you know
like a word you like in control and
powerful but still funny.
It's a weird contradiction because we
get from stand up we get to thinking like
it's just like Yeah my wife don't like me.
No one likes me I'm awful.
I can't do anything.
Well people have always said that you
know you have to be nebbish she or fat or
weird to be a comedian guy.
I was so I was told that so much
that I was insecure about my body.
When I first started doing comedy
that's kind of what I'm saying.
They could be like No I'm fine. Yeah.
Like if I wasn't doing this I'd be fine.
We could be doing something else.
The thing about comedy is that
there's no rules. There's no rules.
I mean there's there's sort of
laws to it but there's no rules.
You know there's there's laws and some
of the laws are that it has to be funny
to you and that you you have to learn
it and that everybody's different.
Like there's Mitch Hedberg who is like
you familiar Mitch Oh yeah I mean I've
got a good match.
I've got a good match
that works really well.
We'll get in that one of
my all time favorites but
there's also Sam Kennison two
completely different styles of comedy
to my all time favorite comedians.
There's it's all based on what is the
world through your eyes and what what I
find funny.
It's funny coming out of me it's
coming out of my mouth my mind.
But if you gave my act to Demetri Martin
I probably be Bill put off you know the
more violent physical aggressive
aspects of my act. It wouldn't work.
You know it works because it's funny to
me. It's obviously funny to me. Yeah.
And I'm being honest.
Like when when I talk about the things
that I think are funny it's because I've
thought about it. I've this is these
are things that I honestly find amusing.
I'm not lying.
So you don't sit around and think like
what would be something funny I could say
never.
What I did is jumps in your head.
Yeah I mean like I will convert
this now into my comedy.
Well I've it's taken a long time.
I see the stages of comedy the first
stage is you're absolutely terrified and
all you're trying to do is get a laugh
in any way shape or form and I think of
jokes in that stage as tools.
All you're trying to do is get by.
You do like usually in the beginning
like when you're an open mike comedian
you've got five minutes on stage and
those five minutes are fucking harrowing
ride through hell. And when it's over
like who I got a couple laughs. All right.
You know I didn't I didn't die.
And then occasionally you will die
and then you think about quitting.
And many many times I thought
about quitting was like
Fuck that I can't do this
anymore is to Davis you can't handle
getting beat up like that you're an easy
the the punishment that your self-esteem
takes when you bomb on stage is all
almost overwhelming.
Like for it for some people I've
seen guys bomb and never recover.
I've seen them like their act diminishes
like they had some potential there's
something there and then I seen like one
night where the fuckin wheels come off
and then they never they never recover.
It's almost like a beating
that a fighter takes.
I've seen fighters take beatings and not
even just the physical punishment of it
but the confidence destruction of it
yeah just they they're never the same guy
again they never become that
carefree cocky guy again.
It just goes away you know.
And with that so does their
fighting career I've seen
that happen with comedians
as well.
So the beginning is just tools.
And then once you do that then
somewhere along the line you go okay.
I'm pretty confident that I have some
tools. Now what do I think it's funny.
What would I laugh at.
This is what's funny to me.
And then we come up with
stuff that's funny to you.
And then there's a stage
three that comedians may or
may not ever even get into.
And that is how do you make your
ideas funny ideas like philosophy.
Like how do you have a point of view and
figure out a way to impart that point
of view on people.
Like for me this a thing I'm doing and
just so just so I'm clear when you talk
about you talk about moving
away from just like jokes. Yes.
Like what does this do.
It's this like taking like a like a
philosophy's or trying to figure out a way
to get an idea in to turn that idea
into comedy trying to maybe maybe a
controversial idea maybe an idea that
you think is important maybe maybe just a
thought because there's a way to
introduce an idea into someone's brain.
Give me an example of an idea.
Well can you pull.
I mean can you throw one else
hard to do this what is it to say.
Like say like if you go on stage and say
Say if you're a Republican and you're
on stage and you start going off about
you know gay marriage or this or that you
know you just give a speech.
Yeah if I'm in the audience and I have
an opposing point of view I go I'll fuck
you I don't like your
opinion I think that's wrong.
And I think people should
be able to do this.
But if you go on stage and say something
that makes me laugh yeah even if I
don't agree with you even though I don't
agree with if you make me laugh I have
to at least consider your idea.
I have to at least you've you've
introduced like here's a prime example.
I had a guy who came up to me who is a
Christian and I say do this bit about
Noah's ark that if you told no one in
the Ark to an eight year old retarded boy
he's gonna have some questions.
So I had this whole bit about you know
someone sitting down with this young
retarded boy telling them the
story of Noah's Ark. Yeah yeah.
And it's this it was a really long bet.
It was like and this
guy came out to mangle.
I got to tell you man
look I'm a Christian.
And you started talking about Noah's
Ark and I started getting offended.
And he goes but two or three
minutes into that fucking bed.
I was laughing so goddamn hard I
started thinking What the fuck.
How is that a real story.
And he started laugh and he goes I just
wanna say congratulations you made me
laugh at something that's completely
opposed to my own beliefs.
This is this is a video where a guy came
up to me after a show in Georgia here
play this is because it is kind of funny.
You know this guy told me he found Noah's
Ark on a mountain archaeology sites
and look for a documented.
Battle.
You know check it out and say OK.
And we actually fund expeditions to back
up where somebody claims I'm going to
tell you.
That the shots I'll show you.
What kind of blow your mind but our
job is not to say what it is right.
Our job is just confirm what they face.
So I think you say maybe they believe you.
I'm confused though.
You really believe that Noah's Ark. Well
let me let me take. Well. Let me tell you.
When.
We first of all they did find a boat
shaped object in the mountains of Ararat
that's five hundred fifteen feet long.
That should be enough for all the animals.
Nothing or.
Something about a hundred million
species that seems we're gonna.
Well I don't know. OK. It's about
five as long as I need to hit us off.
Yeah can you even get the 500 foot thing.
Anyway if you suck shots.
How many.
Just the things were found.
It's a cool thing at the very least
you might be able to use a moment.
Isn't it possible that maybe
it's just a hoax. Yeah.
Well why would anybody assume
that that boat wouldn't pick.
Any there would be any connection in
history to a crazy story to do to get all
the animals to come on his boat against
God talked to told us that the rain was
going to drown everybody because
everybody wasn't paying attention.
We this thing we're all like that.
He makes out all but how could that
be Noah's Ark case. Well I don't know.
You don't actually you don't
actually have wood there anymore.
Whatever it is is great.
It's about even if it was a solid
boat it still seems the only thing.
Unless you're like a carnival
ship right next to Rhino ship.
Well I said glad you said we didn't
have samples. Yeah camel shakes.
We've taken core samples found
different species of animals remains.
We've got twelve.
No they didn't.
We've got twelve anchors again should
be about enough for a home away.
Isn't in the way of animals. It was
probably more than that of about twelve.
What do you do when you find this on
a six thousand foot peak in the hills.
But at the very least I could just show
you what they are without a doubt this
earth is over the last.
Thousands of thousand years gouges and
pretty capped huge cataclysmic events.
You mean they know for a fact that at
one point in time where Montana is right
now that's where all the Megalodon find
megafauna fossils that gigantic shark is
juicy. They find them in the
mountain amounts of Montana
which that's six million
years.
So they know that no matter what there's
some crazy shit happen to this planet.
Without a doubt.
So it's very conceivable that at one
point in time it was a huge flood in that
region.
And that's why there's a stack up there.
It's very possible it is pretty possible.
But but I can't confirm
we do have something that
matches dead and that's what
story is.
Well I love that I use that term.
No do have good Gilgamesh
is the original one.
Yeah it's one of the oldest ones that we
know. But it's it's a cool coincidence.
Yeah well I think.
I think what the story of Noah's Ark is
where it really is all about is that at
one point in time I think there was a
huge disaster and it's probably happened
more than once where like meteors hit
or you know what's in the polar ice caps
or something huge.
Fortunately he kills like 90 percent of
people at the level that are remaining.
They have a story.
Story of a great disaster and some people
got away and those stories the story
of the great disaster and some person got
away over time that person becomes the
great hero of the Savior.
They talk about around the
campfire and is and legend grows.
And when you have a story that's told
in oral tradition for over a thousand
years it's everywhere in nature Hebrew.
And to this day they only know
three or four words ancient Hebrew.
To this day 25 percent all the words are
told they have no idea what it means.
And in ancient Hebrew there
was no numbers. So letters
also double its numbers.
So you lose all the numeric value that's
important the text like the word God
and the word love.
They have the same numeric value.
And that's very important for sentencing.
And when I was translated into Latin
translated The Greek they lost all of that
shit and that's all these stories that
are distorted thousands years of people
bullshitting around a campfire to the
original tax being indecipherable to what
they have today. How can anybody think
that's real. You would have. To be.
Fucking.
Crazy to think that that really happened
to God talk to one guy and got all the
animals from all over the world and put
him on a boat that it makes zero sense
when you know people are liars
you know people are weak.
You know even most religious
people are completely full of shit.
And if after all that you think that
that storage room that's insane.
When you actually see the evidence about.
Well that guy obviously didn't listen or
you know that the ideas didn't get into
his head but you can't.
But he was so kind about it kind.
He never threatened you. He didn't want
to kill you or anything. Well I can't.
Well I don't think he was religious.
He was a documentarians All right.
I believed that he had
found Noah's Ark Yeah.
There was probably not the
best one thing but when he.
But one thing the bones.
They can't. They better not be there.
Fine. Because they only had two of each.
So they died.
Well that could've been the unicorns
bone. Yeah. If that's true right.
If they died then what the fuck.
Unless they bred before they died.
That could have been the longtime.
I'll tell you one thing though.
You're kind of getting at this like the
way the guy came up to you and he said
like you were offending
me but I was funny.
I think I struggle with like you talked
to really liberal people and you like
Rush. You know Rush Limbaugh
is funny sometimes it's funny.
It's that makes him so mad.
We I really conservative would be like
you know Jon Stewart is so you can be
pretty funny get mad
they get real mad at you.
They can't imagine I'm ever like when you
were doing part of your act or talking
about when people get really mad at
comedians for saying some of the comedy
years. And you kind of you mentioned like
how come no one's mad at Johnny Cash.
You're shooting a man just to watch
him die. It didn't really happen.
Yeah that's a big that's
the important thing.
Johnny Cash didn't really shoot a man
in Reno. That didn't really happen.
This is cop.
Well that's the thing about comedy is
it's an easy target and for people that
are looking to be offended which is like
a lot of bloggers and people looking to
find something to be outraged about
they'll they'll point to comedy because
comedy is a soft target. You know a
lot of comedians will say fuck that.
There's an art form.
No
one's always wanted to kill novelists.
Now let's use Solomon
Rushdie a long time ago.
People aren't always going to
kill novelists. There's a card.
The cartoonists who got stabbed in Holland
do to Muslims people go after most.
It's like I was killed right.
Yeah he was murdered.
Yeah he's just a cartoonist you know.
Yeah it's like the soft target of comedy
is the idea that there's this like this
real subtlety to language and there's a
subtlety to sarcasm and being facetious
and you know when someone's
being sarcastic but if you
just see it written down
on paper you can for just for purposes
of being morally outraged you can pretend
that you don't know that it's sarcastic.
Yeah and you could pretend that this is
just a horrible statement and people got
in trouble for that many many many times
especially when you take something like
on Twitter like in a text form.
Yeah and you try to pretend that that's
a statement and you try to pretend that
oh this is just someone who's
you know this is an asshole.
This is the person is just
a really evil mean person.
No no it's this is a person who's fucking
around like there's an art form to
saying fucked up things
that you don't really mean.
Yeah like you could say something fucked
up and I know that you're not serious
so I'll start laughing and
then we'll go that's so wrong.
But but it's we know it's funny because
it's not a statement. Yeah not exactly.
But there is like this P.C.
police thing going on now where a bunch
of people who in most of time when you
pay attention to those people because
I find it fascinating and I try to
consider myself to be a student of human
nature and one of the things that I
find about these people that complain
so much about all these different things
and then they find this moral outrage or
find one thing to harp on over and over
again to say they usually extremely
troubled personally they usually like they
it's usually like they have overwhelming
issues like they're morbidly obese or
they're you know socially inept or
there's something wrong with them that's
causing them to find this soft target
Yeah lash out constantly at this soft
target and then also if you look at like
what they do a lot of people what they
do is like Dell what they're trying to
do is stop someone from hurting someone's
feelings and they're they're trying to
say that what you're doing is mean and
you're hurting someone's feeling so what
I'm gonna do is hurt your feelings in
the most vicious and cruel way possible
you know with with these blogs and the
writing and I'm going to do to you what
you're somehow or another doing to him
being be a complete total hypocrite.
Yeah but I have a license I have this
license of moral outrage I have this moral
high ground that I'm going to stand on
so I'm going to attack and I'm going to
you know to write this vicious snarky
column about a comedian in the ideas that
they're trying to right the wrongs and
trying to be the savior of what's good in
the world.
But that's not the case.
What they're doing is just being an
asshole because they feel like they have a
license to be an asshole because they can
take what you said and put it on paper
and say look in quotes Tracy Morgan said
if his son was gay he'd stab them in
quotes.
So yeah fuck Tracy Morgan but
Tracy Morgan's a ridiculous
person like his whole
act is a bunch of shit
that he doesn't mean.
Yeah it's a bunch of crazy things that
have never happened and he says a bunch
of crazy things because that's that's
his style of comedy like Mitch Hedberg
style of comedy is to say
really preposterous things
that other people wouldn't
like.
My favorite Mitch Hedberg joke is somebody
asked me if I wanted a frozen banana.
I said no but I want a
regular banana later.
So yes so you know anybody else says
that it's a terrible joke but if he says
it's really funny that's his style.
Tracy Morgan's Tyler's must
almost got stabbed to new.
He doesn't really mean that.
That's not it's not a statement.
It's no he's not writing that down.
He didn't carved in stone and bring
it down from the top of a hill.
It's his art form.
But what's more upsetting than the people
who are so volatile and do get so mad
about stuff is the thing that politicians
do which is to feign that response.
Yes like you politicians you know you
look at their career they vacillated
wildly between all these positions but
they love to get up and act like to act
like the morally outraged guy.
Yes by thinking they were you know like
when you look in his eye like you don't
care at all about that but you're
like feigning the guy who is that way.
And that's more of saying that's
the one who really is mad about it.
Yeah well sometimes people are mad about
something that's just a perspective
issue. They just lack perspective or they
lacked a lot of it is a lack of social
intelligence you know.
And there's also a lack of having nuanced
friends having friends that have good
sense of humor.
People that joke around death things or
say mean things like some of my favorite
people like Jim Norton is
one of my favorite comedians
and is my favorite guy on
the radio because he says ridiculous
evil mean shit all the time.
But he doesn't mean it he'll
laugh after he says it.
Yeah but he's really smart about how he
does it and he takes a tremendous amount
of grief because of it because people
will try to point out some of the things
that he says and then you know and accuse
him of being you know homophobic or
this that one of the least homophobic
guys you'll ever meet in fact he will talk
openly about how many experiences he's
had with trannies he's had like all these
transsexual expects a pervert complete
total pervert but he's like he owns it in
and way.
And you know he takes grief because he's
a soft target because you know you can
point to look they're looking for someone
to say outrageous shit so they can be
angry.
So who more likely to say outrageous shit
and someone says outrageous shit for a
living. And sometimes they say
outrageous shit and it doesn't work.
You know it's not funny but Patrice
O'Neal had a great point about that.
The late great Patrice O'Neal one of my
was that he's a really funny comedian
who died.
Yeah.
He's one of my favorite guys to talk about
controversial point because you had a
unique way of looking at it but is his
point was always that like when someone
says something and trying to be funny
and it misses and it's fucked up that
comes from the same place as someone
trying to say something funny and it hits
and it's really funny and you laugh
like just because they miss you you know
with this attempt doesn't mean they're
like an evil mean person they just failed.
Yeah that's a good boy.
You know it's not they're not trying to
hurt someone's feelings they're trying
to get a laugh and that's
what what comedy is.
There's a there's a real art to that.
But but
yeah you're right.
I mean that's a cop that's that's a
complicated idea and is very complicated.
Well you know my friend Joey
Diaz did he will open up for me.
Yeah I love that fucking no man funny.
He's hilarious.
The funniest guy I've ever met in my life.
But he has this joke about transvestites.
He goes I love transvestites.
They cook they clean you can beat on
every once in a while the cops come.
Who's going to believe me as some
dude with a wig and a black eye.
Okay look Joey Diaz has never punched a
transvestite he's never he's never had a
transvestite over his house with a
wig and had him cooking cleaning.
It's not true.
It's a joke like you could say that's
a violence against transsexuals joke or
violence against transvestites Joe but
it's not it's not promoting violence
against anybody. It's a joke. It's
a fucked up thing that he's saying.
And you know it's it's got a good joke.
It's a great joke. My fave one
of my favorite jokes of all time.
But you gotta understand what it
actually is what it actually is.
It's just it's it's just like Johnny Cash
pretending he shot a man in Reno just
to watch him die.
It's is exactly the same thing.
But I wish Patrice O'Neal.
Yeah yeah yeah he yes.
Yeah I wish she was here because there's
so it's like you've been in a situation
where someone said something that
they wanted to be funny. Yes.
Let's say they're made that someone
makes a crack about gays. Mm hmm.
And it flops a way that it can flop is
if it if they're so transparent that you
see a win you see in them for a minute
and you're like wow that really comes
yeah from a place of
deep hatred yes yes yes.
And it's not funny because in that
I got a glimpse into that. Mm hmm.
You know yes if you make a gay joke I
know from I don't know why from your
demeanor whatever it is I know that you're
not at home you know wishing you'd go
out and kill gay people right.
How do I know that.
Well it allows you to explore
like a funny idea you know.
But sometimes some say something like
man this person really has a problem with
black people who are in a power position.
It's like you see it.
It's intent the intent becomes transparent
when when someone is a kind person
and someone just pointing out hypocrisy
like I have this bit making fun of
Marci. Marcy is the lead
singer of The Smiths do it.
But how soon is now is a rock solid song.
But I know you're more it's
not laughed at. Yeah I should.
I was like the know a guy because I could
come out and said You know what I like
how soon is now with
that shit about Maurice.
He was funny.
He makes he makes good music.
He doesn't make good music but his
idea that you know all you know war is
created by heterosexuals.
Yeah.
It's not only not supported
by history but it's her day.
But the point is like when I when I talk
about that onstage I make a big point
out of the fact that I want to make sure
that like I don't want anybody to think
that I have any problem gay people.
But I also don't want any gay people to
just take random jabs at the giant mass
of straight people and say
we're responsible for all
the wars it's fucking it's
all ridiculous.
And if you make as a 10 percent of the
wars where the response were came at you
know we're the gays responsible for 10
percent of the wars and it would upset
the theory.
Well all you'd have to do is look at
history like the Spartans all the gay
Athenians the Romans all
the gay sex they had.
I think a lot of time fighting bastards
that Alexander the Great is one of the
greatest conquerors ever
he's gay as fuck you know.
I think that one of the the things
about people that are in a group is they
always want to assume that this is
the good group to be in you know.
And the idea that all gay people are
cool is ridiculous because people are
people.
There's a huge range of how people can
behave you know whether it's gay people
or straight people like there's a there's
a bit I do about I used to work out at
this gay gym and these gay dude
used to hit on me all the time.
At this I used to work out at Gold's
Gym on Cole Street and because it was so
gay that because you were there
it was assumed you must be gay.
Well they were just you're a man.
It's like if you're a guy and you go to
a gym and there's a hot lesbian working
out there you know are you gonna
just you do you gonna take a shot.
Yeah they can try to find out how lesbian
and I got you know and the the idea
that gay guys are immune for from
sexual harassment they're not going to
sexually harass you because they're
from this marginalized group.
So they would they would be different
there'd be they would be kinder and
sweeter and more and more
bullshit they're dudes with dicks.
They'll spike your drink just like a
straight guy will spike your drink.
A gay guy will spike your drink.
Of course there's gonna be gay
guys in my group drink fuck yeah.
Gay guys would roof you just like a
straight guy I would root for you.
The idea that someone is really super
cool just because they're gay is
ridiculous.
It's just like the idea of someone being
super cool because they're black you
know like marginalized groups have a
little bit of leeway with a lot of like
knee jerk reactionary bleeding
heart liberals which is
why guys like Al Sharpton
is allowed to be on television.
Al Sharpton is a con man and an idiot.
But yet he represents black people on
television because no one wants the same
thing about him because he's black.
If you pick on Al Sharpton you're picking
on marginalized people and you are
therefore a racist because
he represents brown people.
Look at his skin he's a brown guy.
He's allowed to say.
But meanwhile if you follow his career I
mean the guy made his living off of the
Tawana Brawley thing where there was a
fake rape where he you know he came out
and had this gigantic protest and it
turns out that this woman Tawana Brawley
was never really raped in the
first place she made it all up.
Yeah and he was the champion of all this.
It was you know attacking white people
and attacking white America and the
racist establishment has allowed
this to happen. Actually not really.
You're kind of a con man.
You know and what you're doing is you're
taking advantage of a weakness in the
system.
I just had occasion. I'm
not going to go into. I had.
OK I just read the first and last chapter
of al sharpton the most recent book.
No like the second or third
chapter in the last chapter.
I read the second or third
chapter and it kind of changed.
I kind of I wrote his opinion about
it from I like that's really like.
Like he had it.
He made an interesting point
about something and expressed
it really well and he
got talked about his own evolution.
He went through on an idea like a flip.
He explained what would be
in politics a flip flop.
He did a big flip flop and kind of
walked through how a public figure does a
flip flop. No good then read the last
chapter and I just went back to being.
Who you are.
I've read those folks I'm reading that
book on about it with their money.
No no no no never mind the good times.
And every now about a guy comes out to
me and this guy looks like a yachtsman.
Like a good guy or on a yacht.
And he comes at me
because he goes Sharpton.
I had a meeting with Al Sharpton one time
he came in in a chauffeured car and he
was wearing a gold Rolex presidential
watch and the first thing he tells me is
how he survives on a ten
thousand dollars salary.
Then the guy left walked on the street.
Now at the end of the
story was a Sharpton story.
He's what would they call a race pimp.
You know I think that's the
best way to describe him.
He him and you know Jesse Jackson has
made a lucrative business out of going to
businesses and saying you
don't have enough diversity
in your businesses hire me
as a consultant.
He steps in as a consultant and gets
an exorbitant amount of money to try to
teach them how to hire black
people in their businesses.
If they don't do it he's
going to protest them.
And that's the the
insinuation behind all of it.
And it's the only reason why it exists
is because there has been racism no
reason why exists because black people
have been marginalized that evil things
have taken place. And then two hundred
years ago black people were slaves.
All those things are absolutely true.
So there's this there's you know this
reality to what they're saying that there
is racism there is inequality.
So there's someone is coming along as
capitalizing on that that problem but it's
not.
There's no Martin Luther King's life I
was like at my house here the day my wife
was playing a Martin Luther King speech
because Martin Luther King Day is Monday
and my daughter's like
who's Martin Luther King.
So my wife is playing this
speech for our five year old.
And you know what was it the
promised lands. Yes yeah.
I got to make what a
speech got gentler speech.
Well it's like I'm a teacher
played that for us once it's me.
Especially like when you
hear like what happened.
I mean yeah for his assassination. Yeah.
And so by healing him he predicts it.
Yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah.
Well he knew it was coming. I mean it
was an incredible time man. Unbelievable.
Well not just incredibly written
and incredibly performed.
And while we're watching it I was like
There's no one like this anymore where
where's this guy. Where's this guy
that represents the black community.
A guy who is making like these incredible
points and is saying something that's
so moving and then you look
in the audience and it's
so mixed is why people next
to black people and such an incredible
time in our in our culture where people
realize that there there was these
inequalities and there was this this
groundswell of movement to try to make
the world equal and behind it or the
figurehead of it is this incredibly
powerful incredibly intelligent guy who's
probably the greatest public speakers
of all time and an operator Yeah.
Just.
Hi I have a dream.
And you see him say it and he's just like
God damn it just gives you goose bumps
and then you see Jesse Jackson he
cannot stand a fucking word he says he's
mumbling through shit eating shrimp
cocktails flying in private jets.
He's like this is what's left.
This is what's left of these guys.
There's no guy like that.
You know I.
I'm not a fan of Obama.
I'm you know I was a fan of Obama
the candidate of the idea of Obama.
But Obama in office.
I'm not I'm not a fan.
I'm not a fan of most of what he's done.
Not a fan of the whole NSA thing is
spying on people the use of drones is so
many things.
It's almost too much to mention but
one of the things that makes me so
disappointed in him is his lack of
anything that he's ever said that's
inspirational.
The speech that he could have given the
speeches that Kennedy gave Kennedy gave
some fucking speeches that made you change
your idea of what's possible for the
future of this country. But I don't get
any of that from Obama. I get these.
No he will but it's funny because being
a performer is really I mean like being
a performer is what launched him
to where he is. Sure. Exactly.
Yeah it's because that
speech at the convention.
Oh yeah. Well yeah. That and
just the idea of who he was.
I mean we were coming from.
Yeah.
Yeah an amazing narrative you know about
the but one of the earliest criticisms
was its performances. Yeah. Well I mean.
But all speeches are
made their performances.
It's hard not like when you go look like
if you look like Hitler giving a speech.
It's hard not even fathom how I would
ever be that he's not as a loon.
I mean you look. How would it not
be. It's like transparently lunatic.
By the time it was like he would give
these amazing performances that would get
people stirred up and you know it's hard
to grasp the context of Hitler because
I don't speak German.
If I spoke German maybe I could
understand like all like all the maniacal
everything he does. What does that. Yeah.
It's so intense and so crazy but the
the the Obama speeches like there's like
there's nothing like oh can we back up
please don't think I was doing the ole
like Hitler Obama thing.
No I didn't think you were doing that.
I just thought maybe you're not powerful
or no yeah no maybe nervous something I
don't.
Yeah that's a touchy subject right.
You know you you're a Nazi.
STEPHEN LINNELL a Nazi the front
cover of whatever magazine.
Yeah I think we have a serious lack of
these powerful inspirational characters
these people that that go on TV and or
give speeches would they really like her
vision to them.
Yeah.
I mean Obama had some of
that as a candidate but as
a president it's almost like
he looks so tired when I see him on TV.
He looks so goddamn tired and I remember
when he was running like we had Bush
and Cheney we're at war and we're in a
war that most people didn't support and
was very confusing and it was coming
out that the pretense of this war was
incorrect and there wasn't really any
weapons of mass destruction and all these
all those lives and devastation and
people were looking into Halliburton and
that connection that Cheney felt evil it
felt like we were we were trapped with
these evil old white dudes.
And here comes along this guy who's you
know single mother who comes from single
mother and he's half black and he's so
intelligent so well so well read and so
so well-spoken and we thought this was
going to be the change this is gonna be
the big shift. Yeah. And it
didn't turn out to be that at all.
It turned out to be just
kind of more of the same.
But no no more inspiration all
that inspiration shit's gone.
I mean he's so vibrant as a candidate
and as a president I can't remember a
single time that he's ever like addressed
the nation where I was like that's a
bad motherfucker. Like there's
there's something there. Oh yeah.
He's saying something that
really gets people excited.
It's been you know it's been so divisive
but I always think like when I look at
things that look like
things that happened.
There's a there's things that happens to
candidates you know I think that it has
so much to do with money like we get
these figures you know going into the
primaries you get you know you get these
figures that have these you know they
bucked the trends and Mavericks might
say marriage I'm not like Trent I'm not
referring strictly to McCain you get these
people that come in and they're gonna
like upset the status quo then you have
to play the politics game and you all so
much stuff for money and then you pay
those debts and it's like corrupting.
And I think a similar thing happens
that people often in office I think that
like I can't imagine what it must be to
be president I say and I say this time
out George W.
Bush and Obama can't Maduro's be when
you present and someone comes in every
morning and runs through the list of
threats and you hear it and hear it and
hear it and it's like threats threats
threats threats I the paranoia that must
exist you know. I think it has to be
really taxing on people. No doubt.
And every decision you make.
And it's like it's like yeah it's going
to be it will be your legacy and you're
like and it's gonna be wrenching to just
have to make those decisions all time.
They look I mean guys come
on office looking so rough.
Yeah it's probably no one.
You never have a guy do
one term real popular.
He's like You know what.
Fuck this I'm not doing it.
Yeah there's something like It's
so intoxicating to be president.
Do you think that's it.
I think they probably don't let him
you know he probably has a look man.
We have a fucking deal that we
got we got you into this mess.
What are we funny though.
Well since George Washington they say
he could've won again and he left.
He only had one term. No but he was
gonna. People were like do three.
They want him.
They wanted to keep rolling.
And he stepped down and I think he might
have been the last guy that wouldn't
been like well take another one.
Bloomberg took out.
Jimmy Carter's one of the
few guys that was President.
I would really love to sit down with and
have a private conversation because he
seems to be like a true humanitarian and
he seems to be at all the people that
wherever ever president.
The guy who caused probably the least
amount of loss of lives in the least
amount of war and heartbreak
seems to be Jimmy Carter. Yeah.
He seemed like a truly like a kind man
who wound up in this weird situation
where he was the president United States
and he's like he wound up in a weird
situation out in the desert
oh the hostage situation yeah.
Oh well that's a crazy situation where
the fucking hostages were released as
soon as Reagan got into office.
Mike what kind of fucking
weird deal did you guys make.
Did you guys keep those people
hostage for for political gain.
That's one of the most
disgusting possibilities in
the history of power in the
presidency. That doesn't
make any sense. But you know.
You know to me it's like the idea that
that's a possibility that they might have
kept those people and use them as a
political ploy is pretty pretty gross.
That's bad but probably did happen.
I don't know man.
Like you said Who the fuck knows what
it's like once you get into office who who
has any idea. I just don't think
there should be a president.
I think the idea of having this one
alpha chimp running the whole show is so
fucking archaic it probably
works and was 50 of us.
What you want to go Parliament.
I don't know what I want to go.
I want to go Internet.
I think I think we need to go be like
this to be like those shows where people
vote from home. Like every issue
is always about this thing.
It's like everyday homes cars voting
on every issue son of the president.
The president should attack not as well.
I just think the idea of having one
person or a figurehead that pretends to be
the one person that runs
the show is just so archaic.
Well yeah but we have a system of
checks and balances man allegedly.
If you look
if you if you look at the wild vacillation
that some countries go through OK
then as well I mean you
rattle them off all day long.
People get frustrated with how slowly
things happen in the U.S.. That's the.
That's the story the gridlock
nothing gets done it's all idiots.
If you look at the gradual way one might
argue that all that gridlock and all
that mayhem and things being so stagnant
somehow works to our benefit from it
like from preventing wild swings
both is this lower that right.
You know we get like you know we're like
a really serious communist that we go
from that to a real serious anarchist
then we realize that doesn't work.
We go to a you know
some wild as dictator I feel that
kind of like just kind of these mild
undulations when taken when you view
it from a historic perspective I think
these mild undulations that we go
through in politics are to our benefit.
I'm like I'm a little bit pro gridlock.
That's interesting because just if it
was just like so fast I feel like we'd
makes we have more stumbles
than we have I think.
But I'm kind of like generally like an
optimist you know I'm a general optimist
too.
I just think there's too many people.
I think there's too many people too many
interests too much money too much too
many different directions to the money
things really should go like this.
This dude just got the mayor in New York
I want to go back to my show business
story to at some point.
No one tell me Mitch Hedberg story book.
And I want to talk about hunting pigs
mow how we had time. We're fine. OK.
So last month.
Oh yeah.
So the guy is the guy who's
got elected mayor in New York.
I mean he's on an hour a day and he's
like OK no more we don't have any more
horses pulling carriages around
in Central Park. Really. Yeah.
Right off the bat it's like are you tell
me you're now running the biggest city
the one that like terror is drool
about you know the one that's like
like balancing all these like ethnic
groups and tensions and the one thing
that's on your mind when you come in
is that horses are pulling carriages in
Central Park and is mean.
How could that pass.
It has to be some dude wrote that guy
check you know and he's like here's the
deal I'm gonna give you this check but I
don't want him damn horses in that park
because there's no
other way to explain it.
It's like it shows candidates like weird
ignorance and arrogance where if you
talk to him who's involved in livestock
theft and livestock issues we have like.
We don't have a horse thief. We don't have
a not enough horse problem we have it.
There's too many horses like there's no
since the closure horse slaughter plants.
There's like people are dumping horses
people farmers will wake up and be like
wow there's a bunch of horses out of my
place because there's just no way to get
rid of excess horses you have all these
horses that are unwanted horses that are
starving horses that are being treated
properly and you've got these like
gainfully employed horses that are fed
stabled care for veterinarian treatment
and the guy would be like the one
thing we need is unemployed horses.
It has to be about some weird money
thing or it could be he's just a bleeding
heart liberal.
Now it doesn't look at it.
You think so you think it's just a
money thing. I mean I don't know.
I can't see what the fuck
happened with a large drink thing.
How did that ever take place.
That was Bloomberg.
Yeah but it wound up not happening. Did
it really. Thank God. That's Riddick.
No band never banned big pop.
Jesus Christ that drove me nuts.
The idea that you couldn't
get a big gulp or a giant.
I never wanted those mediator.
Some computer is doing something he was
doing like a thing where he was like
you're supposed to complete the sentence
like It's so hot you know. Mm hmm.
Then one was it's so hot. Bloomberg had
to go over to Jersey to get a Big Gulp.
Yeah.
But the nanny state stuff.
I hate it like I hate the like the all
the like telling people do not do free
health.
I hate it.
Yeah like I could also picture like how
frustrating because you be like Yeah
it's like if you look out like a guy who
smoked on cigarettes on hand like it's
not you know why. Right. You can't go.
You've got to be big you've got to be a
big enough of a man to walk away and be
like OK you know a ride a
motorcycle without a helmet.
I'm like why then I'd sound like you
I'd be like a big enough person in some
weird way I'd be like OK you go ahead
and push on and I'm gonna try to not want
to like control your life.
Well there's gonna be people
look at you and go Dude.
You can't talk about cigarettes or
motorcycles you got charged by a fucking
moose. Yeah. All right. I saw it.
I saw you get hit by a moose.
I watched it five times now.
That was you describing it was harrowing
but watching it was way crazier when
that fucking thing got up and
started running towards you.
Even though I knew you were OK I met you
after the fact. I was like Oh he's dead.
He's fucking dead.
No.
We met there we met well before
but that's that was you know it.
You don't have tv like that
was what I did was so stupid.
Each one on one hand I did was
so dumb when I did not know.
I thought I didn't mean it but what it
was so stupid that you'd want to then
hide how stupid you were and
not have it be on TV. Right.
They're like but it's compelling TV.
Yeah like a guy getting run over
by a moose is interesting you know.
So it's your thing of like your
ego where and now it'll happen.
We're calling you know Ryan Kelly.
Yeah I love Ryan.
Great guy.
We were calling moose
and when you call moose.
That's an excellent picture.
Go pinch your nostrils.
That's the cow that's a cow saying I am
coming into Astros and party calling is
a fact.
Like Moose Calling is effective right
before the run rate for the breeding
season because bulls know what's going
to happen like the cows are gonna wanna
be bred to breed them but the
cows have really got rolling yet.
So which is all anticipation.
If they were actually all doing it and
the cows are really an Astros in the
bulls like with the cow that's an Astros
he's gonna be less likely to come to
one calling. You know it's all a timing
issue you got to catch him right. Yeah.
He wants it.
You're the first.
He's like there she is first cow to
come and just go get her. So we're out.
Brian's mimicking the noise of a bull.
I'm sorry mimicking the noise of a cow
and what inspired and begin doing that as
we heard a bowling ball make some
noise like this ball will go.
So that's all you heard.
It's like a soldier you don't
even hear it you feel it.
It's a suggestion of a noise.
It's like I was like What was it.
But it's very hard to determine where it
was not where it's harder. How far away.
And we heard that and then we debated
for a long time whether we'd heard it or
not.
We're like No I know I heard a bull I
heard a bull then it actually started to
thunder a little bit off in the distance
which made it even more confusing.
It was like Was it thunder or
was it that you know noise.
So Ryan starts trying to lure the bull
to us. This is on British Columbia.
He starts trying to lure the bull to us
by roaming around making cow calls and
he goes away from the bull and I stay put.
Hoping that the bull will come and he's
gonna want to see her before he gets too
close.
So by Ryan staying about 75 yards further
away the bull might hang up in the
vicinity of where I'm at.
You know while he's trying to get a
visual lock on the cow to make sure
everything looks safe and we keep calling
corn and then I'm starting I was going
crazy I never heard the bull in the
first place so we start going in the
direction eventually start moving in
the direction where we think the bull is
and sure enough I see some brush clashing
and he's in there rubbing his antlers
on some brush and Ryan starts calm and
now we're in his zone enough where he's
coming to investigate and he's coming
in and he kind of comes at me and I do
like a really stupid thing where I
take what you call a brisket shot and a
brisket shot a deer
wild pig is devastating.
You you're coming in like the sternum
and you know it is devastating to the
animal a small animal
but I'm just so much.
No it's like like layers of bricks and
stuff like basically at the front of made.
And he goes down and I
go running over there.
And sure enough he gets up and starts
running and I'm worried like the last
thing I do is chase a moose
but I'm worried that maybe
he's not bleeding enough.
So I start running after him and I get
up there and he's I catch up to when he's
laying down again and I go to shoot him
in the neck and click like I had messed
up my rifle and hadn't chambered around.
So it clicks and that bull got up and
just turn in like came and boom knocked me
over like coming at you like you know
head down horns down like a bull you know
head down horns.
And he punched me in the ass of one
of his antler times and I thought it
punctured me.
So I ran away and Callahan shoots the
moose down and I keep reaching around to
feel where he had popped me so hard
in the ass and knocked me over.
And my hankies come back bloody.
So I'm trying to feel where he put a hole
in me and I'm thinking like he'd like
punched a hole through my waders
and into my into my arms tissue.
And then I realized that like I got blood
all over it cause he had I'd hit him
in the brisket so when he ran me over he
like smeared a lot of that blood on the
back of my clothes. So that was the
blood I was feeling scared to help me.
And you saw that was a few days before
I got charged by grizzly bear. Yeah.
It was a harrowing trip.
Hey you're talking about people smoking
cigarettes and riding motorcycles with
no helmets.
That moose deal was probably the closest.
You know like you fantasize about bad
stuff happen to you from big animals you
know like you can get
mauled by bear or whatever.
And what really gets his little teeth
things like I like my hospital stuff has
been you know like serious issues Ben
Giardina so drinking bad water and Lyme
disease by getting you know bit by
little teeny bugs that are infected with
bacteria and that's like
my real source of trouble.
But when I'm laying in bed and then I'm
not thinking about microbes I'm thinking
about big giant animals coming to get
me in on that one came and knocked me in
the minute but it's like it's mixed
emotions this was happening like that was
the stupidest thing I ever did I
can't believe that I'm so dumb.
And then and concurrent with that as a
thought of like I am so happy that that
happened.
That was an amazing thing you know.
And now it is stupid as it was down there
and I'm like I love that that happened
because you're OK.
Yeah yeah.
It's actually mortifying.
Looking at it now I wouldn't even be
disappointed had he punched a hole in my
butt as long as you live. Yeah but what
if he hit your sack. Would have a horn.
I mean think about that.
I already got two kids.
You're cool with a hole in the sack
from what I can tell. Have two days.
My wife is like go down and get a
vasectomy half days. She's like No way.
It's more one on one.
I just mean you know what David
is the dead issue now moves.
Across my who was killed by
my Zach. I'm a eunuch. Wow.
They'll be harsh.
It was fun man.
I mean I love that like you know you'll
appreciate this because I was reading
this book about human history called
Lone Survivor not Lone Survivor.
That's the seal story.
Yeah it's somebody lone survivors.
It's by a geneticist a British geneticist.
And it was something
like that sole survivors.
He talks about the suite of injuries
that are common to Neanderthal skeletons.
I told you about this.
So like everyone they dig up Neanderthal
Skelton in the miles of caves and stuff
like one you find that they've been cut
like their bone they've been butchered
so that they die and their bodies would
presumably their bodies are chromatic.
And we've had a tendency to go eat
them and they also find all these like
fractured bones like busted bones
fractured skulls fractured vertebra Lone
Survivor yeah yeah.
And in some ways in this book and these
guys kind of got warning like why do
they have this type of
injury and eventually some
doctor looks at the like the
injuries that are common in Neanderthals
and he says you know I see that as
rodeo riders and it's like the things
that happen to people who are like mixing
it up with big critters.
And the theory that this guy puts forward
not not Sykes not the guy that wrote
it was to pull it up again. What
is the name again. Christian. Yeah.
So Chris I don't think
Chris Stringer fault said.
He talks about a guy who floats this
idea that they had a confrontational
hunting style that Neanderthals did today
were in there you know tearing it up
and Cro Magnum has had a
little bit more of a stay back.
You know stay back and get them a
better time when the other tools are way
closer to the rest of the
animals than than we are.
I mean they had they were five feet tall
200 plus pounds big thick fuckin bones
no one else's is that they didn't have
a lot of sexual dysmorphia the males and
females are much more similar.
Really.
Probably he met females were in there
hunting more probably had to be positive
that they weren't just structurally
the females or similar.
And so having that little run in with
that moose was kind of I felt like a
little bit in a positive way I felt a
little bit like maybe like there was like
a Neanderthal experience
with the Neanderthal thing
is weird man because they
find out like all these things that
biggest thing they didn't do was like
evidence that they that once they came
into contact with Cro Magnum it was like
they started picking up some of the
things that they were Indu like there's
evidence to suggest that like at that
they had been around for you know hundreds
thousand years and also in dudes show
up but we show up and also they kind of
got interested in decoration a little
bit I got interested in art a little bit.
Music theory you know that they had see
they were somehow interacting with us
some were kind of like stealing our make
sense stealing our groove a little bit.
Well I mean you think about all the things
that we use guns computers this table
we didn't build in a shit.
Oh yeah yeah we figured it out
from other really smart human.
Yeah you dad. And so they were
kind of like came into somehow.
It was going on and there
was some internal aggression.
He talks a lot about that in that
book that there was there were
he argues a little bit argue that isn't
the case that the argument there is that
there was certainly some intro aggression.
Yeah I've heard that and I've also heard
that it's it's confusion and that would
it really is is common ancestor.
Yeah. Know I've heard all. So I'm not
I'm not like I'm not definitely I'm.
You know when it comes to that kind of
stuff I'm not the guy let you do the same
like I'm saying what
some people say right.
You know I mean some people say that
it's an interesting idea and lots of
changes so fast. I always hate to be
like well this is what it was you know.
But you talking about you know what.
What is the most recent version of
Neanderthals one hundred thousand years I
mean when they when they went out thirty
thirty thirty thirty five thirty thirty.
Could anybody know what the hell exactly
happened thirty five thousand years ago
it's too it's too far. He explains
how he explains what they know so far.
Well yeah.
He explains how the people that have an
opinion on it came to form their opinion.
That makes sense you know.
Yeah but for sure I look I know men and
I know that if men live at the end of
thoughts somebody would affect.
Oh yeah I know dudes.
Yeah they would do it even if it was sort
of like an act of aggression like you
look at conquering forces you know.
Yeah.
On one hand they're coming into
Congress because they despise them.
But like dudes conquering dudes will
often find themselves you know like
history's full those examples where a
conquering army that's coming out to get
like the worst people on the planet
all they want to do is annihilate them.
But they also kind of have sex at.
Did you ever see there's one.
I think there's an Australian
anthropologist very
fringe guy but he had this
really funny take on Neanderthals that
they were the super predators and that we
we hunted them and do extinction.
Yeah.
Because he knows is that they
didn't look like people at all.
They look like gorillas that Cro
Magnum hunted them. Yes. Yes.
Did you ever see that.
No.
But but I've I don't know if I've seen
that guy's ideas but seeing the idea that
that's the case and what people point to
is that they always find butcher marks.
Not always but it's very common to find
butcher marks on those bones and also
find what to crack the heads open
and presumably get the brain out.
Yeah. I wish I could remember
killing Neanderthals.
I forget what the id be like if you shot
a Yeti now or not a Yeti if you shot
Sasquatch. People be
pissed. Oh yeah. You know.
Yeah but I bet you that crow mangling
the Neanderthal weren't is different.
There might not have been
as many differences between
those two as there would
be between us and a Sasquatch if you
haven't run into one hole up them in us.
Pull up some images the books called
them and us and his proposal was the eye
sockets were much larger the features
more simian the bone structure is much
closer to lower primates than ours and
we're just assuming we anthropomorphize
these animals and assume they had
white skin legs and hair like us.
But he gives them like black skin like
a gorilla and you know decides that they
were these really intelligent
predators that hunted us down.
We widely discredited.
Yeah but it's this is
look at this the images.
Well that's what you think they look like.
Yeah that looks like something
you'd have in your studio.
Yeah exactly.
Yeah like a yeti or something.
This is his crazy idea.
I mean most likely horseshit but really
kind of fastening Von horseshit though.
Yeah.
We don't have a soft tissue
from these fucking guys.
We don't really know what the hell was
going on. We don't have their skin.
We can't compare the color and texture.
We don't really know.
I think the picture will
become more clearer eventually.
I mean because they get such
sophisticated ways looking at stuff.
Well there was that one
misinterpreted idea that I think a
Harvard geneticist was saying that one day
could be possible and there may be an
ethical consideration that we would have
to ask a woman if she'd be willing
to give birth in Neanderthal baby.
And then it became you know distributed
Harvard geneticist wants women to give
birth to Neanderthal looking
for volunteers and like
taking place in the aerosol
baby in your body like you know not it's
not exact what they're saying but like
this is what you would get so
many women that would do it.
Fuck yeah for sure.
Just to become famous.
Look at that they would they think that
things might look like well sugar packet
that there's some footage of one.
Yeah.
Well the idea is that you know we we
think that they looked like people but he
kind of goes out the way of
giving a real sinister appearance.
We'll look at the bone structure the
differences in the bone structure not
thicker and yeah he makes them look like
monsters in a movie with little tiny
dicks. Interesting. How
can they have little dicks.
I would think that thing would
have a giant dick whatever.
While we're thinking about Neanderthal
dicks coming tell me about tell me about
your need for Mitch Hedberg story.
You know one thing about try out real
quick is not the great story but I had
this girlfriend who had this fellowship
she got in San Jose California and saw I
was back for Team Montana and saying
sales a whole time and there's always this
marquee about this comedy house.
Oh you told me the story.
I didn't think you told on the podcast.
Good.
There's this marquee about the comedy
house and he kept saying like Mitch
Hedberg you know March or Mitch Hedberg
whatever it is always in the back of my
head like may I go get my
ticket got to get my ticket.
And then one day I says
like we'll miss you Mitch.
I'm like Son of a bitch I thought
it was coming up you know.
And I thought I like that it mentally.
He came and performed and went home.
You know and I ran to the window be like
Why do you guys have it on your marquee
that is coming in March when he's
when he's already and she said no.
He died this morning. It's kind of a
weird I agree it's not a great story.
It does.
It feels it feels that way to me.
There's the thing right there
that was all over the country.
Well it was those. Yeah they did
those everywhere they did though.
I think they did one at the Laugh Factory
the marquee at the Laugh Factory as
well.
Now Amanda was funny for my all time
favorites and clean to clean comedienne if
I know.
Yeah he.
Have you gone on listen to the comedian
good storyteller Jerry clown that I'm
always asking you. Yeah. Yeah I did. I've
listened to you know like it. It's funny.
It's all about putting it in the context.
He's a funny guy.
Yeah. Knowing the context. Otherwise.
Oh I thought that just
because had mid-February like
you could actually listen
to Mitch Hedberg with
your kid and your grandma.
Yeah yeah. He swears in the last one
the most most recent one he does.
Says a few quite a few fucks.
Yeah I mean does that
good. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
He's using them you know
Stoner is stoner humor.
Yeah he's.
He was a brilliant guy who really unique
comedian but too to bring it all around.
I want you to bring it I want
you bring around the pigs.
Well that's what we're doing this weekend
and I'm fired up like I told you I
shot 30 rounds today 60 yesterday and
then 300 fucking arrows the day before as
my right arm is so useless right now.
My I can't remember the last time
my right shoulder was a sore.
It's good that you're shooting them.
I miss a lot of shooting. Yeah.
Ms Nottle is not alone.
She never like guys are really into
shooting with a lot of shooting for a 3.
Good to.
No.
I mean to like to get that level of
proficiency coming just from repetition.
Yeah.
Learn how to do stuff through repetition.
I'm not you know I'm a big
believer in preparation.
I don't believe and I like one of the
things that I learned when I was young
when I was competing mouse fighting
when I wasn't in that good shape I was
really fucking nervous. I was in really
good shape and I was really well trained.
My nerves were considerably less Yeah
and I think that that's with everything.
Yeah you gotta be fully prepared.
So yeah.
Guys I know like the guys and all the
best hunting that I somewhat you go out
and you have to. It has to be you
know you're going to you know. Mm hmm.
Cause if things get hard and things
get bad and things are going your way.
If you've already been going into like
you didn't know what was going to happen.
It allows you to more quickly jump
into that it didn't happen right.
Like if you go under like it has
to happen it will happen. Has that.
Then when things are like sucky you
you still pursuing that narrative.
You know what will happen
when we were in Montana.
You kept saying We're gonna get one.
You kept saying that.
Yeah we're gonna get it here. You keep
saying that we're gonna get there.
Like you said that many times I feel
like what what we're doing this weekend
isn't gonna be you know
like hunting wild pigs.
I mean there's gonna there's
gonna be obviously a lot of pigs.
I mean there's this place T.A.
John to HoN t e t o n Jahan ranch.
Yeah I think has it.
I gather they have like quite a bit of
a pig population enough to the point
where you know people go out there and
go out there and like you know do a
guided pig on.
They do this throughout the year.
So if there were none there
wouldn't be that way. Right.
And oftentimes when I've hunted pigs I've
found that you know it is like there's
so much more for and you know like a deer
go on a deer never use that word in my
life. What is that word mean for
kind. They have a lot of babies.
So I could take a look at another animal
native animal around here and be like
you know black tailed does
have to do with the premise.
Fuck it start with fucking the
kind of comedy kind of VCU and.
So like for comedy is
good at making babies.
Yeah it seems like and the rude as fuck
dear someone's line you know and have
one or two a year right.
That pig's gonna a female pigs and keep
kicking off litters of you know six 10
several times a year.
What a powerful animal too.
If they're I mean they're
really they're really smart.
I mean they've
gotten they've through our
you know through them trying
to put together an idea
it's not actually that
complicated thanks to us.
And in spite of us at the same time
they've managed to get everywhere.
You know like oftentimes we just do it
like we thought was a good idea for a
long time.
You go put pigs everywhere.
Now we're like maybe it wasn't such a
good idea to put pigs everywhere and and
you know there's not a lot we're doing
to stop them. That's not the case here.
Like in California they treated
more like a game animal.
You know the number like when people
travel more people travel to California to
hunt wild pigs and anything else really.
And they just don't seem to really cause
the level of damage and hysteria that
they do in some other areas like it
like in you know certain areas in the
southeast and the Gulf Coast area.
I mean there's pigs the point where
it just is really hard on agricultural
interests and it's kind of inexplicable
how they seem to be there for so long
and explode into some level.
But in California just bend and just
bend there's some pigs around and people
generally appreciate them.
I used to hunt pigs at night used to.
I still do.
But I have a friend who's got some.
Her family has some cattle ranches up
around Sacramento and he's kind of got
this little bit like yeah.
You know sometimes I get too many and I
need to get rid of some but then we'll
get a dry year and they'll all go away
anyway and I'd like it if you went out
and shot some if you see one shoot one
for me and they kind of are causing me a
little bit of problems. And you can
tell it has its conflicted relationship.
But I put it to him one day I said Glenn
if you could shake a magic wand and all
the wild pigs would be
gone would you shake it.
No you know so he even
admitted like they're a hassle.
He doesn't want a lot of them around.
But he would never want
to see them all gone.
You know and it feels kind of like
the relay. It's a great general.
It's a huge generalization.
I feel like that's kind of been the
relationship is a lot of hunters.
I get all kinds of e-mails from guys
live in California and they're like they
went out pig hunting six times everyone
saw a pig you know hunting on public
ground and these guys I wish there was
more of them in and in other parts of the
country.
You got government agencies paying real
money to try to wipe them out because
they caused such a problem with native
species and agricultural interests and
you know. But here it's just a it's
a different vibe in California.
Have you seen the pig
man Ted Nugent footage.
I've seen clips of it I haven't seen it.
I mean I know everything
I know so much about.
I mean I have shown that network you know.
Yeah. They shoot for folks or just listen
and not know what we're talking about.
They have pig man has a couple
of episodes called a pork lips.
You know where they shoot pigs
out a helicopters. Lots of them.
He shot one with a bow and arrow
out of a helicopter. Did he kill it.
Yeah I saw that. Yeah. I mean I
I knew that it happened I know.
I didn't know it came to be
that he got it and got it.
We had to aim way high because the the
downdraft of the blade shove an arrow to
have the arrow down so I had to judge it.
Know I heard recently I heard that they're
in the situation learned to be like
paying people by the hour to kill pigs.
Yeah I would imagine. I mean they have
millions of pigs in Texas apparently.
Well they have a lot of
farmland in Texas too.
But they're it's it's
a weird thing about it.
The endangers like not
the endangered species.
A weird thing about stuff like pigs
and how you know just so I don't.
I'm sure your viewers if
someone up to speed on this.
But wild pigs are not from North we don't
have wild pigs are not native to North
America.
People brought wild pigs to North America.
Early on in the pioneer days or during
the current years contact years they
brought pigs to North America from their
native and your Asia brought them here
as a food source and they would keep some
in pens and other people would have a
practice where you go into an area and
you just kind of turn pigs out they
wouldn't scatter too far they'd fatten
themselves on acorns and masked and grubs
and various things.
And when you want and when you could
take your rifle out and find a couple and
shoot them it was a way to to produce
meat where it wasn't you weren't needing
to provide it with all of its feed.
It's a very sturdy animal that
could fatten itself on land.
And inevitably these pigs would get away.
So we've had wild pigs here about as long
as we have to have had Europeans here
another version happened later where
people brought them in as a game species
and when they would bring them into the
game species they would bring them in
from you know like Siberia and other
areas where you still had the original
stock.
So the original Sioux scrap it was like
what we call the Eurasian wild boar they
had been bringing in domestic versions
that had been bred off the Arabian wild
boar and then people brought
directly in the wild boar.
Now if you look for a parallel with cattle
like the ancestral cattle Zain and we
now call the oryx but
the oryx went extinct.
So we lost the wild version but retained
the domestic version with pigs we had
the domestic version that we
humans created over long long.
Tens of thousands years
coexisting with the wild version.
So people brought wild ones in Boston
in New Hampshire in the late eighteen
hundreds or early nineteen hundreds.
They brought them to California.
Around that time and kind of put them
out on the land as a thing to hunt and in
time we now have populations
that are of domestic stock.
We have populations that are Eurasian
stocks so they look like a real souped up
European wild boar. And we have
populations that are various hybrids.
They demonstrate different degrees of it
and they've been around a long time and
in some areas there's way too many.
The trouble with some like
that one troublesome thing
that hams mean against it
is complicated as shootin
rhinos to save rhinos is it.
We've always had we've
had over the last you know
150 years we've been developing like
this this set of ethics like what's an
acceptable what are acceptable
practices to use when hunting.
And we made a general determination that
certain things aren't acceptable like
you know we don't Jack like deer like
you can't use spotlights to go out and
shoot deer at night.
We've built up these rules because we
have ideas about what's sporting what
what's the elements of fair chase
also what leads to too much harvest.
So if you make it too easy to go get
animals then you're going to have shorter
seasons you're going to have
fewer available tags you know.
And so they kind of balanced technology
to sort of make it that you're going to
have whatever success rate
like a lot of outcomes.
Only 10 percent of the hunters that
participate in the election are successful
90 percent are unsuccessful because
we have rules in place that make it
difficult to do to hunt
there's so many pigs now.
In some places that we're like discarding
a lot of that we have to do in dealing
with that species we're discarding a
lot of the notions that we've held dear
like you would never go out
in a helicopter and shoot
deer it would never be
legal it would be frowned on by
everybody in the hunting community.
But with pigs it's like an exception
because it's a non-native animal that we
want to get rid of.
And so it really is like it becomes kind
of a cloudy issue like when we're doing
these like big game hunting practices
that we worked hard to get rid of in order
to save North American wildlife from
the pits where we had driven it in the
early 90s hundreds and now like all these
like ethical practices are not really
applicable to this animal.
So you see some things in season things
happen like your initial reaction is
like Oh man it's just like ugly you
know it's ugly but the like but it's a
really complicated situation.
There's a ton of pigs causing a ton of
economic damage and it's really putting a
hurt on people and it's putting a hurt
on native species to you know like we
lose like Hawaii lost ground nesting
birds many species of wild ground nesting
birds because of pigs and rats.
Introduce species. Eat the eggs. Yeah.
Pigs are really hard.
There is like you know rare bird
preserves in Florida where the number one
problem to have those preserves is pigs
eat all their eggs because these are
ground nesting birds and
pigs just vacuum them up.
So you bring like kind of these like
practices that strike someone who grew up
in the in the American hunting tradition
and it's like oh man you know I've even
engage in some things like I've done
to pigs I've done things that wild pigs
that I wouldn't do to any
other animal like what.
I mean like running you know running
the dogs and Coleman knives and digging
them out of holes and chasing them in a
little fenced enclosures and kill them
in there and you know it's like it's
their legitimate honest problem.
Well you're your last show that
I watched last night actually.
You had a pig.
It was a whole head to hoof pig cooking
wild pig cooking special was really fun
special.
Very interesting yeah.
Very educational I heard a story of that
pig. Yeah the pig had his balls removed.
Yeah.
So this is crazy I'd gone down to
Florida hunting turkeys and we have the
American there's like but multiple
subspecies of the American Turkey.
So we have it's all one species but
there's subspecies or varieties you have
like the Eastern Wild Turkey and most
of the east the Osceola Turkey which was
in the south half of
the Florida Peninsula.
Then you have the Rio Grande Turkey
Miriam's Turkey the ghouls Turkey and
northern Mexico southern Arizona.
And if you're like a turkey geek you
might want to try to eventually get all
have the experience of hunting all Turkey
subspecies I kind of accidentally got
four of them and I realized that I want
to go to South Florida and have a chance
to hunt as the oldest.
So I went on the hunt seals down the
swamps donor and we're down there running
these guys who hunt pigs with hounds
what they're set up is this guy has big
cattle ranch and it borders a rare
bird preserve and the preserve.
You can't even walk around and it's close.
Most of the preserve is closed
any human visitation at all. Cane.
Take a walk through there but they have
guys like full time pig hunting here.
He goes around and kills pigs as a way
to try to protect these rare bird species
to give them nesting opportunities.
The rancher who likes to hunt wild hogs
goes and he usually kind of hunts along
his border with the preserve because
the pigs will come out of the swamps and
the preserve and come up and hunt on his
route around on his land in the cover
of night and then retreat back into the
preserve where they're relatively safe
and hide out.
So what he realized is he went through
and put this fence in and put trap doors
one way doors in his fence so that pigs
could leave the preserve and enter his
fence.
But then they couldn't get back out.
It was like it was like a fish trap door.
So now and then if he gets the itch and
to go pig hunting he'll go out at four
in the morning and make sure all the
doors are shut like closes the door is up
so the pigs can't get back
through the other way.
And then he knows they're
probably somewhere on his ranch.
And when he starts chasing when his
hounds they won't be able to make it back
into their safety in the preserve.
And when he goes out if he gets a boar
like an old boar Scott is not intact.
He knows it's not going to be a great
eating board because they just they run
themselves right. You know they're
not like they don't have a lot of fat.
They're full of hormones.
They're not at they're certainly
edible but not as good eating.
So what he'll do is he'll do
something that benefits everyone.
He will castrate that hard
and turn it out because now that hog
cannot contribute to the population he's
not a viable breeding
member of the population.
And if he catches them again he'll
have what's called a barred hog barrel.
What was that word bear.
Bart Hogg which is a castrated hog.
So like a steers a castrated you know
steers a castrated male cow castrate a
bull in a bar dog is castrated.
So we went on one eye and caught a big
board was not intact castrated him and
turned him out so he could as this guy
put it it would take his mind off ass and
put on the grass
and then we stayed out caught another pig.
And this one had at some point in time
they didn't know if they had it or
another guy had done this
one had been castrated.
You need to known as totally healed up.
But he had me castrated those guys
like that'll be a good one to eat.
So we kill that hog and kept it for food
and we ate that thing
from from honest to God.
We ate it skin as pork rinds took its
intestines out and flushed the intestines
and stripped and made our own sausage
casings liver heart it is nose in head
cheese eight feet by eight
every part of that hard.
Yeah. The guy actually is the one thing
I got left is one of the good parts.
I got one back leg frozen.
I want him in my freezer.
I didn't know what head cheese was.
I didn't narrow hall.
That's the word I'm
good arrow Beryl Beryl.
Well let's look it up here.
Please read it hard.
I've even written the word
I wrote a thing about this.
What is a castrated pig
called Bard barrel bear hug.
Be a r r o w Barrow hog Barrow hog.
Hmm hmm. Colonel Barrow Yeah. B or w.
Yeah. These guys love to
hunt. They love to eat pigs.
D It's a good little system they
got the head cheese was so weird.
I never I'd heard that name
before word description.
I didn't know what it was.
It's like a gelatin.
You know I made head cheese with the
first the first wild pig I ever was in
California.
I went out to hunt wild pigs and I had
never laid eyes on a wild pig and I don't
want to shoot the first wild pig I saw.
So I went out one day without my
rifle just to see some wild pigs.
And the next day I went out and got one.
I want to make head cheese
with it where it's not.
It doesn't make it cheese was like
gelatinous so a lot of the cuts.
Like when you put your name
a lot of the cuts that are
too weird you know that don't really
make great steak. They're not that way.
They have a lot of connective tissue
you know and fatty deposit levels have
something like terms in the college and
when you cook it like it turns in like a
gelatin when you cook it. So a head's
full that stuff in the bones have it.
And so you simmer that
head for a long long time.
Eventually can pick off all meat and a
lot of the gristle and connective tissue
and stuff turns into like a gelatin
like substance you can make real gelatin
that way.
And now we just have a packet reporter
powder mix of the water makes gelatin but
old style gelatin and natural gelatin
would be just derived from as an animal
byproduct.
So you take all the meat you pluck off
the same way like hog job well if you
ever had that you take the tongue
out and chop the tongue up.
There's all this other at Roo.
At when it's warm it's liquid but it sets
up as gelatin and it's just all bound
together with natural gelatin that you've
derived by slow cooking the pig's head.
So it's like little bits of pig meat
bound up in an aspic are bound up in
gelatin and of course you season it and
flavour it with all kinds of good stuff
to eat.
And then when you when you when it when
it sets up when it's chilled you can
pour it out like it looks
almost like a fruitcake.
You know it pours out in a mould and
then you slice it and it's not cheese.
It looked great.
It looked great because my body does it.
Yeah my body that makes it this guy
Matt Weingarten a chef I hang out with.
He puts all his amazing stuff in there
and he puts you know you can put like
colorful things and citrus he
flavours and it's beautiful.
One of the things I really love about
your show is that they occasionally do
show like recipes and how to cook but
also that you butcher the animals that you
cut quarter the animals got them.
You do all that on the show.
You don't see why you see whales up on
the show that you don't see on other
stuff.
Now we have a trip.
It's like it's amazing how much liberty
like how much liberty we have like how
much the network lets us get away with
is it because it's on the Sportsman
Channel because you can.
Yeah there's another there's a there's
another channel that shows on shows they
won't let the people have bloody hands.
What show is that.
My understanding is not a show there's
there's a network I've heard that that.
Yeah there is another hunting network.
I've heard it it's protocol on other
hunting networks you're not supposed to
have bloody hands like you
won't see him got animals.
That's ridiculous because they think
that to make people turned off by hunting
is like how you think people get turned
off by hunting by seeing people eat what
they hunt is beyond me.
But sportsman channel is really
cool because they let us do stuff.
I mean in it it works the advantage is
people like you know what. I get it man.
You know it's like you're showing like
a thing that most people are hiding from
but it's the reality that meat goes
through a metamorphosis you know to get
there and then it's sometimes gory
so yeah we get to show all that.
And I love it but I don't think
of it as just like gratuitous.
No it's like it's instructional really.
Yes yeah.
That's that's how I feel.
I don't I don't feel it's gratuitous at
all but I think I like watching you like
when you eat that mousse. I like watching
guys cut it up and then eat it. Now
that me it was like on believable man
we had that marrow cracked the marrow
bones open to working with the marrow on
deck and believable like that meat was
so tender and good and you know getting
the thing realized when you're on TV you
know you suppose you know you watch like
morning shows and they have a cooking
segment. The host is like oh
it's so good. Oh it's so good.
You know sometimes I cook
something so it's not good.
And I just try to be like That's
not good at karaoke. Yeah.
You know it's not that great because I
want it to be that when it when something
is good I feel like I want you
to believe me. And that was good.
It was just a phenomenal moves me looked
unbelievably delicious Elks widely
regarded as like if you went to survey
people who've tasted a wide variety meats
elk is the one that you would be like
it's the best one where we're going.
Deon has elk on it Tulio.
Yeah.
You know you got like Roosevelt elk Rocky
Mount all these different subspecies
elk is a very rare one in California
not rare but yeah rare and a very small
range that was almost wiped down.
It's back now because you have like big
chunks of property like that where they
can find you know find some refuge and
people are working to maintain them
provide habitat forms so it's kind of
cool spot you go there and see a elk that
most people have seen.
I hope I hope we run into one this is
like a two the two the elk you know do you
feel like the moose was right up
there with elk it was I'm not joking.
It was one of the best pieces of
meat I eat and eat meat in the field.
You know we age mix it tenderizer you
know and we're eating meat like fresh meat
often tastes like art where
you eat some fresh meat rich.
There's like a onion kind of thing to it.
It just doesn't quite taste like age meat.
I like that.
But when we're Wisconsin man we're
you're cooking those steaks and it is
phenomenal. Yeah so so but
sometimes it's pretty tough.
Like my brother Eric my brother
my brother lives in Alaska.
He kills moose every year. Like the
guy that kills moose is moose all year.
He's a moose snob but he won't
hunt a lot of stuff you like.
He likes to hunt moves and all sheep
because moose is good but he puts a moose
in his freezer because just because
he doesn't have a hanging you know he
doesn't have a lock or
he can dry age his meat.
He'll kill a moose and tip because
of weather and bugs and other issues.
He comes home and right away processes
his moose and puts in his freezer and he
don't usually touch that thing for six
months because it will slowly age like
meat will tend to rise in
your freezer over time.
So when he calculates his a year out
he knows he's going to kill a moose in
September.
He doesn't plan on having the one he
killed before be gone in September.
He plans on having the one
he killed before begone.
No it's staggered so the one that he
kills he lets it slowly age in his freezer
and it will tend to rise in your freezer
over time and then he starts in on the
new one. So when he kills moose he so
eat in the moose from the year before.
That seems so weird because
you way you eat that moose.
It didn't seem like you needed anything
at all because it was an exceptional
animal.
So that's unusual.
It's yeah.
Those animals like most animals especially
males and bowls like most animals not
most animals benefit like like
undulate benefit from aging.
No one age you know age wild pigs you
know you don't age black bears a lot of
critters you do age deer l moose it all
benefits those animals all benefit from
aging.
There's natural you know there's natural
enzymes whatever that the process is
well understood.
I don't understand really well.
It's well understood that you hang
it there is like a natural decay.
You know I'll put Doc say if I killed Doug
I've got the Doug if I have like a wife
or if I have a girlfriend or whoever
doesn't want it or when I had my chance
say Forget it I've got the duck put in
the fridge now I might need to put it
in a paper bag because someone might not
want to see the duck every time they
open the fridge but all rolled up in a
paper bag or of still breathing I'll put
in my fridge and I'll leave it in there
a long time I might leave it in there
ten days and that meat gets to where you
could scrape it away with your thumb
you know the inside that gutting this is
where you've got to the burden might
start to even smell a little off but the
meat is getting just perfect you know
increase the flavor enhances it gets more
tender just like aging you know it's
a Why was that move so good then.
I don't know just what
it was eating just good.
I've had part I mean we had we had a great
piece off or eat it like kind of like
the most tender part of the rear leg
but just a great animal that there's so
much variability like when that's one
thing about being a wild game chef I am
wild game Cook I think Chef
sounds a little more formal
but I'm a wild game cook
and one thing about being a wild game
cook that's more challenging than me and a
regular Cook is you're dealing with so
much variability like you get some great
chef and he can do some amazing thing
because he's got a purveyor you know and
when he buys a pig it's like the pig a
disc for 72 days and then we hit this for
14 days then we killed it on this day
and chilled it at this temperature for
these many days and you know and every
time he buys a pig the pig comes in his
kitchen or his restaurant and he knows
he is nowhere is going to be like you
know animals you don't know what kind
of that there's age issues and what kind
of trip they've been on there's all
kinds of variability so you learn how to
kind of control that and sort of bring
the ingredients into line because some
animals are good and some animals aren't.
I shot a milder one time that was just
implied it was just disgusting to eat and
then you get another meal there it's like
that is so good that was the dish some
salmon and then some.
You know it's like you don't know what
they've been up to or there's just a lot
of mystery with it but that
moose was a phenomenal moose.
I've also had my buddy he was
my buddy we had a falling out.
I told a homeless guy he killed a moose.
He brought the meat over.
I thought he'd kill the Loch Ness monster.
I was like I'd never seen anything
like it. It's just funky and nasty.
He had a cow tag.
See one thing about shootin males on
antlers game is you can get an idea of age
the antlers betray the age there's a
growth pattern they go through like if you
see a fork you deer a spike on Deer
It's like that's a one and a half you'll
deer is gonna be great eating when you
shoot an antler lists the clues are much
more subtle what the guy looked at the
two though so he had a cow mustache.
He went on got a cow moose he later
had someone look at the teeth and they
estimated that thing to be 20 years old.
Oh my God.
It was like you couldn't really chew it
tasted like Oh they taste like Oh that
tastes like a sea monster I mean
because it's really hard to tell.
There is a guys that really know their
business like you know Doug Dern and
Wisconsin Doug Derek and look
at Dougherty hold it is yeah.
He's looked at so many damn deer.
He's looking to see me do
that live on his place.
He just knows like what their groove is
you know isn't a weird sort of symbiotic
relationship. Those deer have farmers like
balls almost not really a wild animal.
Canada geese crows whitetail
deer love people people.
Yeah.
When we were at Doug's place I mean first
of all what a fucking great guy he is.
Doug he's one of the bad
guys one of the best.
And I like to say it like a big ask
I don't say this about many people.
I don't throw this around lightly like
he's a big hearted guy. Yeah I mean.
It's not something I would really think
of when I'm describing other individuals.
Yeah. No I'm so glad he introduced me
to him. He's awesome and it was so cool.
Me and me and Brian Cowan staying at
his place and you know that he let us do
that and film the show there and god
damn there's a lot of deer up there.
Jesus Christ.
I mean we didn't see a lot of big bucks
but god damn we saw a lot of deer.
And you told about this I
think he did when he was a kid.
If you cut saw a deer track you
ran home and told your parents.
Wow you're in no frigging to your own.
Well they've they've fucking grown in
population we saw 16 the first day right.
We saw about 16 deer at least.
But I mean know.
Yeah I mean it's just that's like a real
deer spot but they do have the early
word they have a symbiotic relationship.
Wait til deer have really
are one of the winners.
When it comes to development issues and
in art like our good friend the milder
which is more to me like it's a more
romantic kind of mule deer and somebody
would be like oh yeah we have
mildew in my yard all the time.
I know but generally they
have they don't do as well.
They don't do as well with fragmentation.
They don't do as well.
Kind of the stress. You know they
have some things they like to eat.
They're kind of wed to those things we
like to eat and White tells like Oh yeah.
That down I'll eat corn you know.
They're just like they're
always gonna find some.
And that places is like a
deer culture down there.
Well there's a lot of places like
that in this country. Oh yeah.
Oh Lord farm lands right like Illinois
Iowa Kansas a lot of farmland.
Lot of crazy white tailed you get way way
way more white tailed you than you had
the time of European
contact way more right now.
That's nuts but still of every dude in
America went out and shot a deer we'd be
running like a 200 million deer
deficit really no way. Wow.
So people say to me like so you think
everyone should go out and shoot their own
meat. I'm like well we really
couldn't we'd run on the critters.
It's like it's going to always
be like a fringe activity.
I think it's always gonna be a fringe
activity anyway as long as society keeps
going the way it is.
No no I'm not worried about that. I don't
I don't stay up at night what I might.
One of my goals not a goal but a thing
I'd like to see happen is rather that I
mean we could definitely
have more hunters.
I think we need more does to have
political clout to defend our lifestyle.
But I also would like to see the people
who have no interest in hunting come to
Reckitt Lake through understanding kind
of the mechanics of wildlife start to
recognize it as that hunting is legitimate
useful practice not the opposite.
You know I think people that pay attention
do see that I know for the most part
the real issue is that most people
have this sort of periphery view of it.
They don't really look at it.
They don't get in there and try to
understand what can what is hunting what's
going on with it.
I know.
Like I said my own personal transformation
from looking at deer like why would
you kill a beautiful animal. Oh
you have to kill them. OK I get it.
You know it's understanding
what's going on.
Oh well that actually keeps the population
say well if you don't do that they
run out of food.
Well then as you know the massive strain
on the resources and there there's well
there's no predators in the wild
fluctuations and I didn't get it.
I had to look into it.
But when you do look into it the only
people that don't get it of the people
that don't want to feel whether it's
for moral political you know what.
Whatever reasons whatever bias you
have coming into it if you look at it
objectively I don't I
don't see how you could.
I don't see I could not get it.
No I think anyone who looks at wildlife
politics in a way that's like immersive
and you have to come to understand it.
You go ask someone who runs a wildlife
agency like a state wildlife agency or
federal wildlife agency and ask them what
their job would be like without having
hunting as a tool.
And you know it would make them shudder
because you just you know it's so much
it's gonna be very difficult to maintain
the kind of the portfolio of different
species we have at the levels we have.
You're gonna have to be.
You'd have to be open to having really
wild fluctuations having cycles of
disease and things that aren't as pretty.
And also why.
Like why deny ourselves access to a
renewable resource that generates so much
revenue.
It generates economic activity.
It pay it's self-sustaining
helps pay for itself.
And it's fun.
People don't want to say that for whatever
reason they don't say killing animals
is fun. Seems like it's a mean thing
to say now. I love Hunt man it's fun.
I always say that it's not
you're not being mean. It's not.
It's an exciting activity
that speaks to your DNA.
I always tell people I wouldn't because
I heart like I'll talk about the food
element of it.
I wouldn't hunt if it wasn't for the food.
I wouldn't hunt if it wasn't for the fun.
Yeah you know I mean it's it's both it's
exciting and you could watch the meat
eater online now.
Finally you pay for them for the longest
time and you only get them on DVD.
But now if you go to meat eater dot VH
X dot tv or go to the meat eater dot com
you can get them.
They're selling them as a bundle and
volume 4 is the bundle that the two part
episode with me and Brian Cowan in
Montana I should say Brian Callen and I.
And if you use the code word rogue.
No no you shouldn't say that.
No.
Was just picture that you're saying
it without Callen what would you say.
Brian Cowen and I know no picture saying
you wouldn't say it features I Brian
calendar.
Me I would say Brian Cowen and me.
Yes.
Picture what you'd say without
the other guy there. Right right.
You would say me you'd say me but
you would say him first. Right yeah.
But I'm talking with my eye OK OK.
I meant I was just saying the I was just
trying to put him all you're worried
about the sequence not the
pronoun not the pronoun you.
Yeah yeah you're correct though means the
right way say I fucked that up all the
time.
I don't pay attention to I know
the rule but I don't care about it.
I ain't concerned with it.
You ain't volume for.
Use the code word rogue and
get them although it's a
great fucking show it's not
just a great hunting
show it's a great show.
You know I was saying that to my wife
the other day while I was watching I was
like this show it's almost
like I want more people see it.
Well I wish more people
would see it because it would
open their eyes as to your
approach your.
It's it's more intelligent philosophy
behind like you see all these hunting
shows like Well I'll tell you what is a
big book came out it will tell you what
we shot and with that gun I tell you what
you don't have any of that stupid shit
in it.
It's interesting it's fascinating.
It's your you're a well read introspective
guy and I love the narration on it
too.
It's a great fucking show.
Thank you man. I like it. I would
watch there's only about wasn't in it.
I would watch it.
I do watch it.
It's a great thing for you and
it's one of my favorite shows ever.
And in my inbox right now is the first
cut of the initial pass on the Wisconsin.
Really. Oh come on man. We
had a good time Wisconsin.
That was a lot of fucking fun.
We've talked a lot us on.
Yes we'll talk about
that before it comes out.
Meat Eater dot v h x dot tv and again
use the code word Rogan and you'll save
five bucks and volume four is
the one with Brian Cowen and me.
All right you nailed it.
Audible dot com thank you to
audible dot com go there downloads.
Cool shit go to audible dot com forward
slash Jo get yourself a free audio book
and 30 free days of audible service and
thanks also to on dot com that's O N and
I t use the code word Rogan and save 10
percent off any supplements we will be
back we have a very full week next week
a lot of shit going on boy I got Neil
Brennan and John Hackman and Peter
Schiff the economist is gonna be here on
Wednesday that should be interesting what
is the economist who is expert on the
economy John Hackman trainer of many
many great fighters including one of the
greatest ever in chocolate Dell and Neil
Brennan our pal stand up comedian and
co creator of The Chappelle Show.
All right folks we love you and Steve
Reno and I are gonna go bring home the
bacon literally. See you soon. Big kiss.