We're live.
All Right Jeff,
thank you very much man.
Appreciate you coming on here.
It was very cool talking to you in
Brazil and even though it was a very
short conversation,
I learned a lot and I got very fired up
about this podcast.
Awesome,
man.
Great to be here.
Thanks for having me.
Well,
thank you.
And thank you for all the stuff you've
done it for folks who don't know,
you're the guy who essentially took down
Lance Armstrong or at least made the
case or solidify.
I mean,
how would you describe it?
Yeah,
I mean I was involved in the
investigation.
Um,
you know,
it was a case run by the Department of
Justice out of Los Angeles.
I was one of the case agents on it,
so I was associated with it.
That's one of the things that's creepy
about it is that the government was
going after bike riders.
It's like,
wouldn't you think that they've got some
really important shit to do?
Like I think that bothered a lot of
people about the baseball thing with
barry bonds and with mark mcgwire and
all that Sammy Sosa stuff.
It's like,
why is that the fucking congress
involved?
And it seems.
Yeah.
You know,
uh,
you know,
on one hand these were laws that,
the agencies I was with was,
we're tasked to investigate,
uh,
on the other hand in terms of
importance,
um,
you know,
I was on a personal level.
I looked at the message that was being
sent to youth not only this country but
of the world and that it,
it became a fact that in the mid to late
nineties,
steroid use was so pervasive in sports
that kids are smart these days.
You on the Internet,
they know what's going on,
that it really did see it trickling down
to kids,
you know,
in high school.
And at some point if you wanted to take
that sport far enough,
you ultimately had to make that
decision,
hey,
do I want to keep going?
And if I do,
I'm gonna have to make a decision
whether or not,
you know,
I'm going to use these things.
So,
um,
I think,
you know,
the,
I think about the number of
conversations that probably happened
around dinner table between parents and
kids because of these cases,
got to be in the hundreds of thousands
if not millions.
And that alone right there,
you know,
I think would justify the resources that
were spent defendants in those cases
always.
I was always overblown in terms of the
research,
the resources that the government did
spend doing it,
you know,
you heard often the barry bonds case was
50 slash $55,000,000
case.
It really wasn't,
um,
you know,
in that case involved not steroid use
but lying in front of a grand jury.
So it transcended spare steroid use.
It was about lying and telling the truth
and misusing the justice system.
I've had agents all across the country
on non-steroid related cases come up to
me and say,
hey,
thanks,
thanks for that case,
because we can use as a,
as an example when we go out and
interview witnesses or witnesses come
before a grand jury that,
look,
you need to tell the truth and if you
don't look what can happen.
You know,
the government went after barry bonds or
shouldn't,
they will go after you and when that
truth starts being told like that,
the are legal justice system starts
working.
When it doesn't,
it breaks down.
So it wasn't $55,000,000.
How much was actually spent around,
you know,
it's funny.
A 49,
40 9:50,
no,
not even close.
Some media outlet,
uh,
did a freedom of information request
with the US Attorney's office in San
Francisco who prosecuted the case.
So this was after the case was done.
So they put the dollar figures together
with the trial costs and not,
not,
not necessarily,
you know,
the entire investigation.
But the trial itself,
I think it was less than $100,000.
And the comment was,
Jesus is the most cost efficient high
profile trial that's probably ever
happened.
Um,
but that's not a full account of all the
money that was spent trying to bring
them down.
It's not that.
And again,
this wasn't trying to bring anybody
down.
This was a situation where he went
before grand jury,
uh,
didn't tell the truth.
Uh,
his grand jury transcript,
ironically enough,
was leaked by the BALCO BALCO attorneys,
defense attorneys,
and so the public all of a sudden got to
read exactly what he said in there.
Um,
it was obvious that he at least was
obstructing,
if not outright,
not telling the truth.
Um,
and so I think the Justice Department
was faced with,
what do we do now,
what kind of message are we sending if
we don't prosecute this guy,
it sends a message that,
you know,
far transcends steroid use in sports.
There's thousands of witnesses every day
that appeared before grand juries.
So it was almost a necessity to have to
do it.
It wasn't about steroids,
but it was about steroids because the
only reason why he was there was
questioning him about steroids.
So it essentially was,
and it's not a lot of people feel like
when it comes to like organized crime,
like didn't they bust Al Capone on tax
evasion?
Like that's how a lot of people get
caught.
They get caught lying while they're in
the middle of committing a crime.
But it's really about the original
crime,
wasn't it?
Well,
they did.
I mean,
that's why he was brought in there,
but you know,
when he was brought in,
it was made very clear that,
look,
you got to tell us,
accusing you for using steroids.
He was given immunity,
actually show them that long as you tell
the truth,
you're not targeting this thing,
you're just a witness.
So tell the truth.
But he was never convicted for using
steroids and wasn't he off the hook even
as far as the investigation goes,
like he never did any time and it was
even penalized.
Like how was he penalize other than
having to go through trials and spend a
lot of money?
Yeah.
I mean ultimately,
you know,
after he was convicted in the jury
trial,
the judge sentenced under house arrest.
Um,
but I tell you that he's got a sweet
house.
It's not really that bad.
Can you can watch TV when you're in the
house arrest?
I think you can,
you know,
it seems a little ridiculous.
I like being at home,
but I'll tell you,
even in a situation like that,
I tell people all the time and being
under investigation to begin with going
through a public trial with know
potentially embarrassing things about
you.
That's rough.
I wouldn't,
I wouldn't wish that on my worst enemy.
And I was standing with the ultimate
sentence was.
But the most embarrassing thing was that
he did what everybody knew he did,
which was take steroids to get bigger.
I mean that was the most embarrassing
thing about it all right.
And it wasn't anything else.
It was like maybe there's some more
things.
So it was an ex girlfriends that were
called it went on the stand in his ass.
He got the thing that people have a
problem with is that there's like legit
problems in the world and they're
chasing people for hitting a ball with a
stick better.
You know,
like baseball is boring as shit.
And the best part about baseball is when
they hit home runs and people were
saying,
well these guys are doing something that
makes them hit more home runs and it
turns out that there's something
involved science and chemicals and we
don't like it.
So we're going to come down on these
people and we're going to spend a lot of
taxpayers money.
I'm going to bring these people before
Congress and Joe Biden's going to get
all goofy about it.
That's how a lot of people felt about
it.
Well,
I think anytime you,
you could spend resources on something
that's going to directly affect the
youth of society and sending them a
message about what is right and what is
wrong.
You know,
having grown up in a,
in a sporting household myself,
three daughters,
which,
you know,
played sports growing up and I look at
kind of what I went through and what my
daughters have gone through in the
life's lessons that you learn in sports
that transcends sports and learn how to
work under pressure,
how to work as a team,
how to individually succeed.
There's so many great lessons to be
learned,
health aspects of being healthy and
working out.
All the sudden you introduce into that
equation,
number one,
breaking the law,
breaking the rules,
and so there's,
you know,
the ethics to look at surrounding it.
And number two,
you know,
ultimately there can be risks and health
consequences with using these things,
especially if you're young doing that.
So,
you know,
again,
going back to the message,
I think that it's sent to our kids and
two parents with where I think society
was going back then with the pervasive
use of,
of drugs in sports.
I think it was a positive one that's
going to benefit people positively.
And I think it did.
It did have an impact.
The landscape has changed in the last 10
or 15 years.
Yeah,
I think you're definitely right about
that.
And that is,
that's the most compelling aspect of it
as far as the argument for chasing it
down is if kids are growing up and the
kid says,
Hey,
I want to,
I want to be a professional baseball
player.
How many people are going to tell that
kid,
look,
you gotta take steroids if you want to
get into a good college,
if you want to get it,
you know a bunch of recruiters looking
at you,
you got to start making some noise right
now.
And the way to do it is this stuff right
here.
Score that stuff in there.
The amount of conversations I had with
young athletes,
baseball players,
definitely cyclists where they talked
about that moment that all their life
growing up,
you know,
they aspired to be a professional and
then they got to a certain point in
baseball it was,
you know,
minor league,
maybe triple a and cycling it was,
hey about to get signed onto a protein
going over to Europe and realizing,
oh shit,
to go any further.
I'm seeing what's going on around me
here.
I'm going to have to make that decision.
I have had.
I can't even count the number of
athletes I've had sitting across the
table from me recounting those days when
those decisions were made that were
bawling,
like little babies.
Talking about that.
And I think a lot of it was guilt in
terms of the decision that they
ultimately did made,
but just the pressure of,
of coming to that moment either given up
your lifelong dream or hey kid,
if you want to go further,
this is what you gotta do.
And in some instances,
you know,
Kinda rebuffing that and not doing it.
Then after year realizing,
shit,
I really do need to do this or I can't
go any further.
How many,
many of those stories told to me,
yeah,
it is really crazy that sports like
professional cycling especially.
We talked about this
when I saw you in Brazil,
that I had a buddy that was a
professional cycler for awhile and he
told me this was long before the Lance
Armstrong stuff went down before he got
caught.
He said they're all doing it.
He said,
you can't compete at that high level.
not only that,
but the doctor that he talked to said
you could make an argument that it's
actually more dangerous to compete in
that sport without the drugs.
And then I said,
well,
what kind of a fucking sport is this
man?
Like,
this is crazy.
Then after you and I had this
conversation,
I started looking into the Tour de
France Times.
We spoke about this briefly in Brazil,
that the guy who was winning the Tour de
France,
I don't even know what his name is.
He was breaking records that were set by
guys that were on drugs and we were
trying to figure out how the fuck that's
possible.
Yeah,
it's a pit suspicious
a bit.
I mean these are hyper human levels of
performance and you know,
he's beating guys that we know where the
elite of the elite were also on
steroids.
We're also on EPO.
Yeah,
the cycling,
I think we talked about this in terms of
level of sophistication versus all the
sports that I saw.
Her drug use was prevalent,
was by far at the top where they were
investing in machines to bring along
with them as they were competing and
traveling to to test their blood every
night to make sure that their levels
were within reason.
Wouldn't pop on a,
on a drug test or a biological passport
tests,
um,
biological passport,
if I'm not mistaken.
What that means is like say if we test
you and we get your levels that we can
test you on a regular basis and you have
to stay within a consistent range.
Is that the idea?
Yeah,
that's pretty much it.
And it's something we're using in our
UFC program.
So you know,
the more tests you have,
the better you're able to read it,
but over a longitudinal study of your
blood and urine markers,
a science and studies have shown you're
going to have normal variances,
you know,
each human being will have a normal
variants.
How does that factor in with
overtraining and a lot of these athletes
are overtrained and that's a consistent
aspect of mma camps as a guys are just
really breaking themselves down,
doing two and a days wrestling
strength and conditioning,
kickboxing.
It's just sometimes you see these guys
testosterone levels,
they come in,
they're just racked and their mid camp.
Yeah,
that's definitely,
you know,
I'm not a scientist,
but in talking to the scientists and
read these,
they take that into consideration.
I think the overtraining you attend to
see some of those variances on the lower
side and that may be normal,
but when they're reading these,
you know these biological passports and
you see some way on the lower side and
then all of a sudden you see way one on
the higher side then begins to raise
questions about what's going on.
Now a lot of times the biological
passport will just lead to more
intelligent testing or targeted testing
may not necessarily be,
hey,
this person's definitely using,
but based on these variances,
something may be suspiciously going on
here.
Let's test this,
this guy or girl,
you know more hone in on suspicions like
that.
And really the most accurate tests or
blood tests is that the case blood are
the most accurate.
Correct.
Do you.
This is the other thing you were telling
me about were in Brazil I thought was
fascinating,
was that there there,
there's a new type of testosterone that
they are making testosterone from Yams,
right?
Correct.
That now they're doing it through
animals.
Yeah,
they are,
um,
so,
you know,
one of the most accurate test now to use
is called the carbon isotope ratio test
and what that's able to do is
differentiate between natural
testosterone which all men and women
have in their body and foreign
testosterone because there's a different
carbon atom in that testosterone because
it's made from a plant instead of an
animal.
Um,
there's now,
at least in research supply companies,
I don't think it's approved for use,
but there's animal based testosterone
floating around which has the potential
to possibly defeat a carbon isotope
ratio test because it has the same
carbon atom as natural testosterone
does.
Is there any hesitation and talking
about these things because you worry
that you might educate cheaters?
No,
I don't think so.
I think,
you know,
I've always found that,
your credibility rises when you're
forthright about what's going on and
because on the other side of things,
um,
you know,
the sciences,
looking at these things and always
coming up with new tests.
I think something,
that's fact.
I just read it today.
Um,
and we do this in our program as well,
is uh,
there was in cycling,
they will freeze samples both urine and
blood and keep them for years at a time
and cycling just recently went back and
retested some of the frozen urine and
blood from a few years ago for a new
drug with shade,
just develop a test for and they were
able to catch a guy from a couple of
years ago that had used it.
We're going to do that in UFC as well.
So even if,
you know,
there's a new drug out there that,
scientists,
chemists are saying there's no test for
potentially a couple of years down the
line when there is a test for it,
we'd have the ability to go back and
that now maybe that
athletes no longer with the UFC are no
longer competing at all anymore,
but you know,
they're still reputation and legacy at
stake.
Wow,
that's crazy.
So the UFC is going to have like a giant
meat locker filled with old blood and p
laboratories will have that.
Wow,
that's a,
that's fascinating stuff.
But doesn't that.
Well,
there's a chain of evidence issue with
that isn't there?
Which just sitting around in some sort
of a lab somewhere.
Yeah.
There'll be secure freezers where there
is a chain of custody that goes along
with each sample.
So outside that freezer will be guard
this paperwork.
No water laboratories are very secure
laboratories.
This.
Yeah,
I've tried to get in than before.
It's tough.
You're signing off your life to get in
one of those things.
But um,
no.
So there's,
the chain of custody will be good going
on indefinitely on those things.
So,
so far as you know,
this hasn't been approved where people
haven't used this animal based
testosterone yet.
I believe it's being used now.
You believe it is?
Yeah.
Um,
there's also like wasn't an Alex
Rodriguez.
Is that who it was that was using a slow
or quick release?
Testosterone was,
gets out of your system very quickly as
short lifespan or short half life?
Yeah.
What was the deal with that stuff?
It's just fast acting flax clearing
testosterone.
And I think,
you know,
the landscape on how drugs are used as
changed over the last several years is
tests,
you know,
got more accurate.
And so the idea is you could take this,
I think he was taking like gummies or
lozenges,
you know,
take it at night and by morning time,
the testosterone could be clear your
system.
So you take it while you're sleeping to
help you recover.
That's the idea behind it.
Yeah.
I think you see more along the lines of
it's called microdosing.
So small amounts where,
um,
you know,
again,
talking more of recovery versus building
up massive muscles,
which you saw maybe in the mid to late
nineties,
you saw these cartoonish figures out
least on a baseball field.
I think now it's evolved a little bit
more where there's less amounts using
more for recovery benefits.
Now a guy like Jose Conseco,
how much damage did he do when that guy
or positive,
you know,
depending on how you're looking at it,
when that guy came out with that book
and explained what he did,
what everybody he knew did.
How,
how illuminating was that to guys like
you?
Well,
I mean you talked before about
congressional hearings.
I think his,
you know,
his book came out of the time when,
the balco case was kind of in the media
and it probably caused those
congressional hearings where Congress
called baseball to the table and bud
see,
and you look now 10 years later and
baseball is completely done a one 80.
They,
they lead sports in terms of,
you know,
anti-doping program,
professional sports here.
Well before our program came along.
Um,
but,
uh,
yeah,
I mean they're testing program is,
is pretty good.
And compared to 10 years ago,
do they,
do the athletes look different?
I don't follow baseball,
but are they smaller guys now?
I think so.
I mean,
I don't think you see,
you know,
the Mark Mcguire's
or the Jose Conseco Osers as prevalent
as you did back then.
Definitely look at the statistics.
I mean those,
those don't lie.
You're not seeing 50,
60,
70 home runs anymore.
You know?
See,
I'm torn.
I'm torn on that because I think
baseball socks and this.
The only cool thing about it is when a
guy wax a ball and sends it flying,
I totally agree with you on the message
that sends young people.
I think there's a difference between
that though and fighting and the
difference between that and fighting
clearly in my eyes is that when you are
taking something and you're fighting,
you can do more damage to an opponent
and you kind of force your opponent to
also do something if he wants to be on a
level playing field.
If we had a sport where it was just
anything goes like the pride days now
obviously we do.
A lot of it is speculation and anecdotal
evidence and and just people witness
accounts from people that were there
like in any.
Anyway,
who's been on my podcast before and
talked about the pride contracts which
openly stated we will not test you for
steroids.
That was in the contract and my own
experiences with friends who went over
there were there were telling them like
you should take steroids.
Like,
uh,
I have a buddy that would normally fight
at 170 pounds,
could even get down to 1:55.
They were telling them to do steroids
and get up to one 85.
And he was like,
what?
Like he,
you know,
he couldn't believe it when he came back
from Japan going do they told me to do
steroids.
And that was the wild west of the
performance enhancing era where it
seemed like a giant percentage of the
people were on something.
The difference being that when you're on
something,
if you're on EPO and testosterone and
human growth hormone,
all this thing and you're inside of a
ring or cage,
you can do more damage to your opponent.
You can possibly land strikes that you
would not be able to land and some of
those strikes may or may not have a
permanent effect on your opponent,
so in a lot of people's eyes it's a much
more dire and serious consequence.
Then baseball,
were you just hitting a ball with a
stick?
So in a lot of people's eyes and in my
eyes,
I think it's amazing that the UFC has
taken this chance and done what they're
doing because they really didn't have to
do this.
What they did is bringing a guy like you
a board,
you know I,
I've talked to a lot of trainers nail.
They raised their eyebrows and shook
their heads like,
oh,
shit's going to be different now because
they realized that this is.
This is a,
a real big commitment to try to clean up
MMA and a commitment that quite
honestly,
they really didn't have to do.
They could have stuck with the Nevada
state athletic commission protocol.
The urine tests after fights,
the occasional blood tests,
if they wanted to do random tests on
people they were suspicious of,
but in a lot of people's eyes those
tests were more of an intelligence test
and they wore have,
you know,
a real honest to goodness anti-doping
effort.
Yeah,
I'd agree with everything you just said.
I'm,
I'm often asked,
hey,
do you think steroid use in mma or the
UFC is way off the chart compared to
other sports?
And my answer is I don't know yet.
I mean I've seen very pervasive use in
other sports.
I don't think it's unique to mma or UFC.
What is unique is what you just talked
about,
the importance of it and that this isn't
hitting a ball over the fence with a
stick.
This is two human beings getting into an
octagon and trying to get the other to
submit by inflicting pain and hurting
them.
And when you give someone,
you know,
an unfair and an artificially enhanced
advantage over that other person,
a man in terms of it just not being
right.
It's at a whole new level.
Um,
and yeah,
I mean Dana and Lorenzo from the minute,
you know,
I had conversations with them before
coming over here,
jumped fully on to this and I think
everybody realizes that,
you know,
from a business standpoint,
especially short term this,
this could hurt the UFC,
but you know,
in terms of longterm and short term
health and safety of their fighters,
which I'm telling you these guys are on
board with.
They care about their athletes.
Um,
I mean this speaks volumes of what
they're doing.
It's a big turnaround
also from just a few years ago where
testosterone replacement therapy was
sanctioned by the Nevada state athletic
commission.
That was a big issue that you were
getting.
I mean,
there's no need to mention names,
but I know a guy who was in his twenties
who is on trt.
It's like,
what the fuck?
If you're on testosterone replacement
and you're in your twenties and you're
competing in mma,
you shouldn't be competing in mma if
you've got a real problem.
If you're at such a low level of
testosterone.
I'm one of the things that when I was
trying to sort it out and make sense of
it all,
one of the things that I found most
disturbing was my conversation with my
friend Dr Mark Gordon,
who's a famous for his work with
traumatic brain injury,
a lot of soldiers that have come back
from getting blown up by an ids and the
the impact that it has on the pituitary
gland and how a lot of these guys have
very low testosterone because of the
impacts that they've taken and he's
pretty adamant about it.
He's like,
if you have to take testosterone because
you've been getting hit in the head too
much,
that the answer is not take
testosterone.
The answer is don't get hit in the head
anymore like you.
You shouldn't be like putting a patch on
that and then getting right back into
the octagon.
If you are forced to take testosterone
because of the head injuries,
you shouldn't be competing anymore.
Yeah,
I agree.
I really,
I can't believe how naive people were
just a few years back to to allow that
happen.
It's just,
it's amazing.
How did it happen?
I think just,
you know,
not being an educated,
uh,
just,
just not around it enough.
They didn't look into,
you know,
things as hard as they should have as my
guest.
I don't know.
Yeah,
I don't know either.
Um,
it was never approved by the Olympics.
The Olympic Committee never approved.
It did.
They did not.
I think in the history of therapeutic
use exemption on the London or
something,
there's maybe one and I think it was
literally,
you know,
someone
involved,
I'm not sure,
but say sailing that lost their
testicles to testicular cancer and
almost got to that level versus someone
who,
you know,
urine test would show low testosterone
on one or two occasions,
which my understanding was alleged was
being required for trt back in the day,
which not only that is easy to
manipulate.
That's all they have to do is just be
tired.
Like literally all they have to do is
workout really hard to a crazy workout,
stay up all night,
piss on in a bottle in the morning.
And they're like,
this poor guy got the testosterone,
have a 90 year old man.
But meanwhile they're manipulating it.
And also it's a sign of steroid abuse
because if you have taken steroids,
you've wrecked your endocrine system and
then you go in there and you take these
tests and it shows that you're into
consistent direct and like,
wow,
you need some steroids to fix that.
It's crazy that that was.
That was the protocol and this was a
just a few years ago,
we were dealing with several athletes
that were competing at the highest
levels of MMA and they were Jews to the
tits.
Yeah.
And it's a good thing we're talking
about being in the past because that,
you know,
it's not happening going forward.
Our program does have a therapeutic use
exemption,
a possibility for athletes.
So athletes can apply for certain
medicines that maybe our band that an
independent group that you saw to puts
together a physicians and scientists
will look at to determine if there
really isn't a medical need.
Like what would that be?
Testosterone replacement theory will not
be a therapy will not be one of those
like adderall adderall.
So someone recently,
one of our fighters has some type of
disease where they need medicine
administered.
The Niv,
every month and ivy as we'll probably
get to talking about here is a
prohibited method under our system.
So they would apply for a cue saying,
look,
I'm using this ivy because I'd need this
drug for this disease I have,
so,
you know,
give me approval to use it and this
board will look at it and determine
whether or not that's needed.
This is one athlete.
Yeah.
And this athlete needs at once a month.
Yep.
So when you do that,
would you test them when they're not
doing that drug?
Whatever they need and then make sure
that they haven't been using an IV bag
then?
Yeah,
I mean that's,
that's a difficult one to how you saw it
is going to do it.
Uh,
I think they would go along with their
normal testing protocol and that
individual and whether or not it was,
you know,
hit that individual when they were using
an ivy or not.
If evidence of an ivy usage did come up,
then they would go back and this could
apply to any drug that is granted for
therapeutic use exemption.
They then go back and look at that file
for that athlete and say,
Hey,
looks like that athletes use Nivea all
he was approved to use one under a
therapeutic use exemption.
Are you at liberty to say what the drug
is that they have to take a.
I don't remember what it was.
Okay.
Um,
now what is the,
what's the reason why they can't use an
ivs to mask possible performance
enhancing drugs?
That's the primary reason.
And I saw this,
you know,
we talked a little bit ago about cycling
community.
I saw it,
you know,
front and center in cycling and that
they were using ivs of sailing solution
to manipulate their biological passport,
so to manipulate their blood level
readings,
which were being used to determine if
they were blood doping.
Um,
it could also be used to flush the
system.
It,
it dilutes blood in urine so that,
you know,
natural steroid steroid profiles are
very hard to read after you've taken,
you know,
an ivy bag.
So that's the primary reason.
Um,
I think water also prohibits them for
some health reasons.
Um,
those are many.
I mean,
that's,
we can talk,
I'm sure we're going to talk about it
here,
but those were on many different levels
of health reasons.
I think primarily,
uh,
you know,
when an IV is administered,
um,
and I've talked to too many athletes
that have had this happen,
especially close to a competition,
uh,
there's a possibility of,
of blown out of vain or having clotting
after,
you know,
the [inaudible] taken out.
If the idea is to rehydrate,
it's much safer to do it orally.
There could be some issues with,
with ivy administration and a Dema,
so swelling,
so we're cells will not be able to get
rid of fluid because they've got too
much too quick.
Um,
I have heard of that.
I have heard of that being an issue with
ivy replacement and I think that was an
issue with at least one UFC fighter.
I'm trying to remember the story,
but I,
I,
God,
I wish I could put a name to this story,
but I know someone did have an issue
with legal use of it back when it was
approved where they got a Dema.
Yeah,
I,
uh,
I don't know of any current fight.
I've talked to a few retired fighters
who told me about problems that they had
with that.
I'm now,
I'm sorry to interrupt,
but the concern that a lot of people
have is that a lot of these guys are
cutting a tremendous amount of weight
and some of them more than 20 pounds
that cut that the day of the weigh ins,
they weigh in looking like a skeleton
and then 24 hours later they're supposed
to engage in the most ferocious form of
unarmed combat.
We know of what would these guys
normally would do is rehydrate with an
ivy.
They would go and they would have
several bags of liquid put into their
body and then they would just blow up
like a balloon,
come back in 24 hours later and you'd
see them the next day.
They didn't even look at it,
the same person.
They look so much bigger.
I mean some guys,
it was just freakish to see.
You would see them rehydrated and you'd
be like,
Whoa,
like what?
How did this guy do this?
They can't do that anymore.
Now they have to drink the water and
what are the issues with drinking the
water and how hard is it going to be for
these extreme weight cutting guys to
rehydrate?
Yeah,
I mean,
there there's many issues.
First off,
you know,
studies show that orally rehydrating is
better for you if you're,
if you're mildly dehydrated.
But what studies are they done by
Gatorade?
Who Does these studies?
Uh,
yeah,
American
meal,
now they're real American trainers
association,
a Sports Medicine Journal.
There's many of them out there.
Um,
there's,
there's two things that they,
that they show consistently.
Um,
well,
number one,
it's obviously safer to put something
through your mouth and you put it in the
needle in your vein.
Uh,
number two,
I thought was interesting is your
perceived rate of exertion.
So how hard do you feel you're working
after rehydrating orally is less than if
you rehydrate Viv.
So,
you know,
the message we're trying to get out is,
look,
if you,
if you rehydrate orally properly,
UFC fighters,
that next day you're going to feel a
whole lot better when you're exerting
yourself.
And multiple studies have showed that,
um,
now that's mild dehydration,
extreme dehydration,
the studies do show that ivs are
necessary.
You probably should go to a hospital and
get one if you're extremely dehydrated,
that oral rehydration is not going to do
it for you.
And in this,
you know,
in Wada's prohibited method policy,
there is an exception to ivs where if
you are administered to a hospital
setting and given an ivy,
it's okay.
You don't need a therapeutic use
exemption under our policy.
You don't need to notify Usada the
problem or the catch 22 there is,
I think you need to notify the
commission where you're fighting that
you were administered to a hospital the
day before your fight and they wouldn't
let me not going to let you fight.
Wow.
So what it all comes down to,
Joe,
is our guys and girls need to get
smarter about those weight cuts and
should not be excessively dehydrating
themselves the day before.
Let me tell you one more thing.
These studies are in their infancy of
time.
I'm talking to a lot of different
scientists and physicians about this,
but right now rehydration studies are
showing that in 24 hours if you're
dehydrated,
seriously,
you're likely not gonna fully rehydrate,
whether it be orally or ivy in 24 hours,
it's probably going to take more like 48
hours and the last thing to fully
rehydrate is going to be the blood brain
barrier,
so that fluid around the head,
the brain that's protecting it from hard
shots.
There's some science out there that
shows that may take 72 hours to fully
recover.
Wow.
So I mean really throw,
you know,
the ivy thing out the window.
Even with Ivy Rehydration,
you're still putting yourself in serious
danger 24 hours later if you're severely
dehydrated.
Well,
let's talk about this because your,
your job as the VP of a.
What is it,
performance and what does the health and
health and performance.
What about zero way to stop weight
cutting.
I mean,
look,
ideally what we should do is match
people up that are the same size and
have them compete against other elite
athletes that are the same size.
Forget about all the way cutting
nonsense.
Let's just.
What do you wait?
You wait one 80.
That's what you want.
When you're at your optimum,
you should be fighting guys that are
also won 80.
Let's find out who the best 180 pound
person is.
There's a real problem in the UFC with
weight classes there.
There's a giant jump in between them.
There's one 85 and then there's two.
Oh,
five of you stand at 185 pound man next
to a 205 pound man.
You're dealing with 2016 ounce t-bones
that's pushing that 205 pounds.
Just think about the amount of mass and
power that you can generate with the
amount of weight they have.
That extra 20 pounds.
That's significant.
The amount of more power that they could
possibly generate,
the amount of,
you know,
just the ability to pick you up when
they maybe couldn't if they were just 20
pounds less.
The ability to push out of a lock,
to,
to break out of a submission,
to break out of a clench.
That's significant and when you have
these big giant gaps,
it's encouraging people to make these
extreme weight cuts because they want to
be the big guy in the division.
I agree with you.
I agree with you with all of that.
Hopefully Viv ban and you know,
kind of those statistics I was quoting
earlier in those studies will have an
effect on things and,
and,
and cause,
you know,
our athletes,
um,
trainers support to take a look at that.
Uh,
I can give you examples of ncaa
wrestling in the late nineties had an
issue with a bad issue with weight
cutting and last three wrestlers in one
year,
two Saunas,
plastic suits,
things.
When you say last they die,
they died.
Yeah.
A NCA went to the extreme and band.
She's most weight cutting practices.
They banned plastic suits,
Saunas,
things like that.
Um,
they adapted and became much more safer.
The Ivy ban went into effect after water
past,
I think 2012.
And that effected severely Olympic
boxing in Olympic wrestling.
We're doing weight cuts,
you know,
similar to what an amazing experience
now.
But they,
those sports have much smaller weight
classes.
True.
I think they do.
I think that every 10 pounds,
right?
Yeah.
Um,
well I mean,
but there was,
I think initially kind of similar to
what we're talking about here.
A Lot,
a lot of pushback from the athletes
about,
you know,
this isn't fair,
this isn't right,
this is going to be unsafe,
adapted pretty quickly and it's become a
thing of the past here.
So I think,
you know,
in terms of what we're going and where
we're going,
I'm constantly just trying to be a
sponge and absorb,
you know,
studies,
science,
medicine,
pass it along to our fighters,
pass it along internally with UFC.
Um,
and,
you know,
let's see where it goes.
There's,
as I said earlier,
my position and I think the position of
leadership is always
with a health and safety of our
fighters,
you know,
at the forefront.
Um,
so it'd be an issue that,
you know,
personally I'll definitely always be
looking at have you had the conversation
with them whether or not there will be
additional weight classes.
I haven't talked about that
specifically,
but you know,
have talked about what this issue of the
Ib band's gonna mean and some of the
statistics and stories that we're
hearing about weight cutting,
I'm definitely sharing that with,
with everybody that I think that's
hugely important,
but there has to be some sort of an
option for these people.
And for someone who's like say Chris
Weidman,
Weidman's a big guy,
I mean,
he's very to the fact that he makes one
85 is shocking enough.
I saw him when he cut weight on a short
notice to make one 85 for Damien Maia
and he looked like death.
I mean he was on death's door when he
weighed in and then the next day went
out and won just by sheer toughness and
will and skill and just the fact that
he's that Kinda guy.
But that's,
that's because he cut a lot of weight.
I mean,
that's how he made that weight.
And then then he fought the next day and
he was definitely depleted.
You could see in his performance.
I mean,
he won a decision against my,
uh,
buddy look sluggish.
And you just push through just through
sheer toughness.
A guy like him was the champ at one 85.
If all of a sudden weight cutting starts
getting banned.
I mean he's walking around.
I,
I'd have to guess at least 20 pounds
heavier than that.
At least.
What does a guy like that too?
He's the champion.
If he can't make the one 85 weight class
anymore.
So you just move up to two.
Oh,
five.
Yeah,
that's,
that's an interesting tough question.
I think,
you know,
these,
these are the toughest guys and girls on
the planet and just able to put
themselves through unhuman,
uh,
pain and suffering both in the ring and
I think through the weight cutting.
Um,
so,
you know,
I don't know the answer to that right
now other than,
you know,
educate and share as much information.
I'm not a big believer and throwing a
million rules at people.
I think you take things one step at a
time.
Let's see.
With the [inaudible] band does,
let's see,
kind of what the education that we're
providing our athletes does.
And you know,
all was reevaluated month to month,
year to year.
I just think that there should be some
sort of an option for these guys.
I mean the,
the idea that they have a 20 pound
weight jumped between one 85 and two.
Oh five.
And then there's a big one is two.
Oh,
five,
two to 65.
I mean that is fucking crazy.
There's a lot of guys that are small
heavyweights or just dehydrated light
heavyweights and they have to figure out
what to do about something like that.
I really think the UFC needs many more
weight classes and they've resisted
that.
They think it waters the sport down like
it does with boxing.
But I think it creates more champions
and more champions creates the
possibility of more champion versus
champion fights.
I just think that these,
these gaps,
if you're going to institute this no ivy
thing and you're going to change the
whole system of weight cutting,
it got to give these people some
options.
Yeah,
we'll see where it goes.
It's not,
you know,
other than the ivs being used to defeat
drug tests,
which is in my past experience a new
issue for me that,
you know,
I'm learning on a day to day basis.
So,
uh,
what about athletes and camp?
Are they allowed to use an Ivn camp?
Like what if they have a particularly
brutal day in the Hot Sun?
They go run up hills and they come back
and their doctor says,
listen man,
you're really fucking dehydrated.
We would like to get an IV bag in you.
Can they call you guys up and say,
Hey,
we have an athlete that,
uh,
he just did a two a day and didn't know,
did hill sprints and we would really
like to get this kid in ivy again,
in a,
in a hospital administration setting.
They can do it.
Don't even need to notify us.
That may be an instance where they would
want to do it because then they wouldn't
have to tell,
you know,
the commission.
Um,
if there was no fight coming up soon,
but wouldn't that be something that
could potentially manipulate?
It could,
but you know,
they could manipulate.
Yeah,
but uh,
their blood levels,
absolutely,
but you know,
hey,
it's a balancing act.
If somebody is really truly that
dehydrated and needs one,
you know,
even if it can be used to manipulate a
blood test,
if it's for their health and safety
because there are so severely
dehydrated,
then you know,
the policy is made to so as not to stop
that.
Now,
uh,
Andy Foster,
who's the head of the California State
Athletic Commission,
has done a fantastic job here in
California.
I'm a big fan of this guy and he's just
aggressively going after drug doping and
tested a lot of people on the UFC card
here.
I believe he tested everyone.
Um,
and you just,
who got popped,
I think they gave him a three year
period.
That's,
that's extreme.
I mean that,
that is sending a big,
big message.
Do you think that that's the kind of
stuff that has to be done?
Like it has to be so extreme that if you
have to have a few sacrificial lambs,
were the rest of the athletes have to
go,
look,
this is my fucking career.
You know,
if you want to really compete,
this is the way you're going to have to
do it.
You,
you can't take any chances because we're
not talking about nine months anymore,
which is not that bad for fighter
because the reality is they're not going
to fight more than once every six months
anyway.
So they get,
you know,
at an elite level.
It's very rare that a guy like say a
Vito Belfort fights more than once every
six months at the most.
You might fight three times a year.
Right?
So the guy takes a few extra months off.
Not that big a deal.
Three years.
It's kind of the end of your career.
Yeah,
I agree with you 100 percent.
There needs to be the deterrent effect
upfront and that's one of the reasons I
think our policy is so strong.
It's our policy first time is too,
but if there's aggravating circumstances
and that would be quantified as say
somebody was found to take a steroid and
did an ivy bag just before the test and
we found out about that.
That could be an aggravating
circumstance and possibility of four
years,
which,
you know,
as we get out and educate our fighters.
I,
you know,
I talk about those terms and I asked who
thinks to definitely for is a career
ender.
Most of them heads bobbing up and down
mean unless you're on the
absolute top of the UFC,
you know,
food chain for years,
for years as you're done long past.
I mean if you get popped at 34,
then you come back,
you 38,
that's crazy.
It's not going to happen.
It's just not.
I mean,
if it does happen,
you'll be severely diminished and the
likelihood of you being mean,
you're going to be off the sauce now
too.
Like you were probably doing something
so your,
your system has to recover,
you know,
you're.
Then there's also the mental aspect for
a lot of these guys.
There's a lot of these fighters that
were fighting enhanced for most of their
career and they have this mental
advantage of fighting,
enhance where they know they're juiced
up and it gives them all this
confidence.
Then all of a sudden you take that away
and they just don't seem to be the same
guys.
Yeah.
You know,
it's really interesting on the mental
side of things,
and you know,
I didn't.
I learned this kind throughout my
previous career.
Talking to athletes is the mental effort
that it takes to use drugs when you're
under a good solid anti-doping system.
Many athletes say,
hey,
despite the performance benefits I was
getting from these drugs,
I definitely felt stronger.
Could go longer.
What it took to figure out what drugs to
take,
how long they were going to clear my
system,
worry after I took a drug was shit or
the tests is going to come tomorrow
morning.
That mental burden for a lot of these
athletes far outweighed the physical
enhancement they were getting.
That's a good point.
As an endless amount of stress,
could you imagine?
I mean our,
our policy,
you're going to be tested.
The ability to be tested 365 days a
year.
You know,
an athlete who would choose to use
something that night,
that athlete use something.
Can you imagine like listening for that
doorbell or that warnock all night long?
All morning long.
There was some athletes I talked to that
had surveillance systems up where they
would literally at night after taking a
dose be looking at their television
screens and shit's coming down.
It's crazy now.
A huge mental tasks and they can't hide
either.
Right.
It's not like you could just go to palm
beach and take a hotel room and camp
out.
You have to like let the UFC know where
you are all the time.
Yeah,
so we have a whereabouts program and so
that requires our athletes on a
quarterly basis to fill out whereabouts,
where they're going,
where they can be located,
where they're staying overnight,
regularly scheduled activities that they
have during the day so that if you saw
to who's administrating our program,
wants to go out and find that athlete
they can do that now.
Doesn't include.
It doesn't include our involved.
Twenty four slash seven.
Whereabouts are athletes don't need to
let you saw to know where they're going
to be at all times if they're going out
to a movie or the supermarket or
something like that.
It doesn't mean that it just means if
you saw to,
chooses on a day or night to go locate
one of our athletes,
they have an idea of where to go find
them and can find them within a
reasonable amount of time.
I was having a conversation with a to
keep this as vague as possible.
Um,
I was having a conversation with an
athlete who was telling that he knew of
an athlete that was not clean.
And then so this athlete decided to go
overseas and train,
just decided to like go hang out in some
other country and train there for
awhile.
What do you do if someone says,
you know,
hey,
I'm going to go train and Thailand.
You guys going to go fly out to Thailand
and,
and test them.
It's one of the reasons we hired you,
saw that you saw to,
has partnerships with international,
uh,
anti-doping agencies all across the
world.
I mean,
that's,
that's their job.
They're constantly going to conferences,
they're going out and training
collection officers from other
international bodies.
So they do,
they have the ability to reach out
anywhere in the world because our
population of athletes is spread across
the world and get a test taken or a
sample taken from them at any time.
Well,
let's,
let's just say like,
I mean,
I'm not,
uh,
not accusing anybody of anything but
let's just say if you were an
unscrupulous athlete and you had ties to
maybe people who also do unscrupulous
things and they had a reasonable amount
of power in a certain country,
um,
and you could just go there and they
kinda had deals with people and they,
uh,
they said,
look,
you know,
we're,
we're going to give you a blood sample
and we're going to give you a urine
sample,
but we just like you to wait here for a
moment and we'll just go in the other
room and we come back with this stuff
and they come back and they give it to
these guys.
It,
are you getting like video tape of this
happening?
Are you making sure you're seeing the
exact athlete put the exact blood in the
exact thing,
like how were you going to make sure
that there's no fuckery,
no shenanigans going on,
especially in other countries?
Yeah.
So there's a certain standard,
no matter which country the collection's
going onto a of how these,
how these collections happen and the
doping collection officer,
the,
the DCO has to physically witness the
athlete providing the sample.
Uh,
whether it be urine or blood test,
they have to.
How do you prove that they did that?
Like if you're dealing with someone like
I said in another country,
how do you prove that this,
uh,
this commissioner guy actually was
there?
Well,
I mean these,
you know,
the Dcos are trained,
uh,
based on worldwide collection standards
and um,
you know,
they're vetted before they're hired.
I mean that,
that could happen anywhere Joe could
happen in this country or another
country.
Um,
but I like,
you know,
Erika better than I like other
countries,
so like to talk shit about them.
I think part of it will be,
okay,
so the laboratory gets these samples,
you know,
we're,
I think we're doing 2,700
to 3000 tests a year.
You start looking at samples,
you know,
from a particular country,
whether it be the United States in a
certain region or another country,
and you start seeing suspicion in that
sample.
Um,
you start seeing Aaron variances in the
biological passport and collections done
in another country versus when,
you know,
maybe they come here to the United
States,
things like that.
So it's a constant detective game going
on and there's,
you know,
things put in place for every
conceivable situation to try to,
to try to detect that it's his seems
like,
um,
you're going to catch them.
It just seems like there's only so much,
so much wiggle room these guys have
these days,
but are there any things that are on
your radar that could possibly be used
to cheat that we're not aware of yet
that most people aren't aware of?
Like the testosterone that's being done
with animals?
I never heard about that before.
Is there anything else like that that's
going on right now?
That's why I can't give you any specific
example,
but I will give the example of cyclists
that just got caught for the drugs still
in a clinical trial and what the
anti-doping with that shows,
what the anti-doping community has been
doing is reaching out to the
pharmaceutical industry and saying and
querying,
hey,
any drugs that you have,
you know,
in clinical trial or to being developed,
do you see any potential for athletic
performance enhancing benefits?
And if the pharmaceutical industry.
I said,
yeah,
you know,
this particular drug was,
it was called oxygen and a pill,
so you take it and create more red blood
cells similar to hipo but in an oral
form.
And so the pharmaceutical industry
obviously told anti-doping,
now this is coming out.
Anti-Doping community was able to
develop a test kind of secretly and use
the test and caught somebody's oxygen in
a pill.
So it was called.
Yup.
Wow.
So it's essentially the same thing as
epo or works in a different way.
My understanding essentially the same
thing.
It causes your body to produce more red
blood cells which carry more oxygen and
can replenish your muscles quicker.
Now here's the rub on that.
Okay.
Obviously that's an illegal substance
and it should be banned,
but what about guys who trained at
altitude?
What about guys who,
who sleeping altitude tense?
Like I remember on one of the countdown
shows,
Bj Penn was sleeping in this crazy
zip-up tent and one of the things he
said,
Bj Penn's accent,
he goes,
you know what?
I'm sleeping in a plastic tent.
Someone's getting their ass kicked
because yes,
the zip up this fucking tent to sleep in
it to simulate that he's at 10,000
feet or these sleeping there.
Um,
there's all sorts of other things like a
scent of you,
you're aware of those altitudes machines
that they use at very,
the altitude.
It's like A.
I know I'm a Ian Mccall is a big fan of
those.
He said they have tremendous effects.
A cryogenic chambers.
I'm a huge fan of those.
They have massive effects on
inflammation,
massive effects on the neo Pranav
friend,
a cold shock proteins,
all these different things that help you
heal and reduce inflammation and help
you train more the.
If you could do what that could do in a
pill form,
it might be illegal,
right?
Yeah,
and you know,
I don't,
I,
I hear the argument of,
Hey,
isn't that cheating getting in an oxygen
tent,
but I don't buy off that.
That's the same thing as taking a drug
that manipulate the hormones and
steroids in your body.
I think what ego,
I mean,
isn't it exactly the same.
I mean if you,
if you take gpo doesn't do exactly the
same thing as sleeping at altitude,
but I think it does,
but it does it in a quicker forum.
You don't have to put forth the effort
of sleeping in an oxygen tent every
night for a period of weeks or months.
It's instantaneous.
I'm not on the side of EPO.
Don't get me wrong.
I don't think you should be allowed to
take it.
And I think as far as I know,
the only fighter that has been popped
for in the UFC was Ali bag off,
which shows you how impressive Demetrius
Johnson's cardio is.
He outworked that guy who was on epo at
the time.
But if,
if he's taken that and that's illegal,
but he gets the exact same benefit as
someone who's sleeping in an oxygen
tent,
why is it more difficult?
I just don't.
Why is that legal?
I don't think you get the same exact
benefit.
I think it's way more extreme.
Um,
and using the drug you can get your
love.
I mean,
I've seen some hermatocrit levels of
some athletes get up in the mid fifties,
60 years.
What's a normal number of adequate
levels?
The amount of red blood cells per blood
volume.
Normal numbers are 42 percent,
maybe on the high end,
47 or 48 percent.
Um,
I've seen them again in the mid fifties
to sixties and we start talking about
him.
Adequate levels of those amounts.
There's so many red blood cells per
blood volume that your blood becomes
thick.
Tar like,
and I think we saw this with cyclists in
the mid nineties that just discovered
epo and we're using it.
They were dropping dead in their mid
twenties because of having strokes
because their blood became so thick that
any small little blockage,
the blood couldn't get through and stops
circulating.
You've got instances where they were
setting their alarms in the middle of
the night and to get up and drink water
and do pushups and exercise to make sure
that their blood was,
was still flowing for fear of it slowing
down and stopped flowing in the middle
of the night.
So you can extremely increase hematocrit
levels via using drugs like this versus
you know,
training at oxygen and oxygen tents.
I think maybe you can get up a little
bit higher into that,
that normal range and the 47 or 48
percent,
but I haven't seen extremes of getting
into mid fifties and sixties from that.
Yeah.
My friend who was on the cycling team
said that he would hear,
they were,
they would be on a tour,
a sleeping in a bus,
and you would hear guys get up in the
middle of the night and hear their bike
come off the rack and they'd go riding
because they had to.
Yeah,
because their heart would start beating
funky and they'd be like,
Oh shit.
And they.
They literally are producing so much
blood that they had to burn some of it
off.
That's terrifying.
Yeah.
I don't know if it's burning it off.
It's just keeping it circulating
internally,
but also the fact that these are the
same guys who are taking this stuff.
I'm not the.
The cyclists were obviously,
but fighters,
they would get hit.
You're going to get hit,
you're going to get a lot of bruising
and bruising is essentially just
internal bleeding.
I mean that's
what you're getting.
When you used to look at a guy's leg and
he gets leg kicked a bunch and you see
these big welts and black and blue all
over his legs.
That's blood.
He's bleeding.
It's clotting up inside of his leg.
But he's bleeding and swelling when a
guy's on epo,
is there a more significant danger when
when something like that's going on,
if you are bleeding like that or if your
a bruising?
Yeah,
I think so.
Again,
I'm not a scientist,
but common sense will show you if you
had more,
lot more red blood cells floating around
that are,
that are able to clot,
then yeah,
you're likely running that risk.
It's just amazing what people are
willing to risk just to win.
It sure is.
It's certainly,
that's been a lesson that I'm just,
I'm not surprised anymore.
You know,
there's,
you see a lot informal questionnaires,
interviews of athletes.
If you could give up a couple of years
in your life,
you know,
and there was a pill that would allow
you to win an Olympic gold medal that
you had to give up,
you know,
four or five years and your life would
you.
And typically you see the answers to
that overwhelmingly.
Yes.
Um,
and I think a lot of it is athletes are
a little bit younger and their mid,
early twenties feeling invincible at
that time.
Who's thinking about five years on the
end of your life then,
and I think,
you know,
a lot of the decision making of,
of taking some of these performance
enhancing drugs occurs then,
um,
were you feel young and invincible and
who cares what you have to pay 20 or 30
years down the line,
uh,
for making a decision now.
Yeah.
And there's also a bunch of athletes
that are putting money in the bank of
medical technology and innovation and
they're like,
look,
one day they going to fix this.
Let me just take the shit now.
And then five,
10 years from now,
they'll just build me a new liver.
Yeah,
yeah.
I'm a,
you know,
one thing,
people were kind of surprised that this
is my opinion.
Uh,
but I understand a lot of times why
these decisions are made.
There's such temptation financially.
There's still,
there's such incentive out there
financially and a lot of these sports,
um,
there's such pressure.
I don't know what the word is,
distrust of their competitors or
teammates that they all feel that,
that are using something.
There's a lot of distrust of sports
governing bodies that they really don't
feel that they care because they're
programs aren't solid at.
So I've had,
I've had so many of these athletes
really surprised that I say,
Hey,
I understand why I made that decision.
I get it.
As opposed to,
you know,
well you do and you should never have
done that.
So you do the good cop.
I do.
I mean,
I genuinely feel that.
I like to think that I wouldn't make
that decision,
but health.
I was in my early twenties,
mid twenties.
I don't know.
I couldn't sit here and tell you that
and if you're in the culture of,
you know,
you're in these camps and everyone in
the camp is using you most likely would
have a problem.
If you weren't where people wouldn't
trust you or
now they would be more likely to turn on
you or you'd have a problem with
training with these people.
And there's A.
There's this culture of comradery that
comes with fight camps,
especially where these
guys have to trust each other because
they're beating the shit out of each
other on a daily basis and they have to
trust that they're hitting each other at
60,
70 percent,
not 100 percent,
and that they are trying to work and
help each other.
Have you had resistance from any camps
in particular?
No.
Outwardly,
no.
It's all been positive.
A lot of questioning on the ivy issue,
so maybe quantify a little bit of
resistance there in terms of the
anti-doping.
Overwhelmingly,
hey,
good for you guys.
This is great and I don't know if that's
some of that's lip service or not,
but I'm guessing that even those
athletes that have chosen in the past to
use that,
a lot of them are like,
thank God I don't.
This decisions now made for me.
I don't have to be making this decision
anymore.
I'm now.
There's something in place where I can
trust that my sport really does care
about me.
I can trust that,
hey,
if my opponent is using,
he's risking at least his career,
you know,
go down the tubes so I can begin to
trust that who I'm fighting is clean or
just being really stupid.
We had this conversation in Brazil about
Vituro Belfort's levels.
Uh,
when he was tested during this camp for
Chris Weidman.
Vito Belfort was a guy who was on
testosterone replacement because he
allegedly had low testosterone and you
know,
he was making it out like he was a
martyr and he needed medicine because,
you know,
he was sick and he had an issue and even
compared it to someone being a diabetic
and needing insulin,
you have to give them their insulin,
which I thought was disingenuous and in
a lot of ways is kind of a crazy thing
to say when everybody knows.
It's not a mystery that he used to be
240 pounds and he's 19 years old.
It's not a mystery that he was on
testosterone replacement and looked like
a fucking gorilla.
And then during camp he tests three
times higher than Weidman.
Weidman's tests at 300 Vittorio test at
1200 and everybody was like,
well,
what the fuck is going on?
You know,
it wasn't a.
What am I saying?
The numbers,
right?
It was a four times higher or it was
900,
1200,
right.
I think I was right.
Okay.
So he's four times higher.
Right.
And he tells,
you know,
Weidman tells him,
I'm going to punish you.
I know you were using in camp,
But you were saying that it's not
necessarily the case and that when
someone tests at 1200 through a urine
test,
explain that.
How has.
Yeah.
And I actually relied on experts to kind
of guide me through this,
but urine results like that,
uh,
are depend on,
I think it's called your excretion
level.
Different people excrete out in urine,
different levels of testosterone depends
a lot on your metabolism.
One person could be a high excreta and
one person could be a low Iq screener.
It's not necessarily a representation of
your true testosterone levels.
We've talked about earlier.
Blood tests would be
way more accurate.
So why test him for urine at all?
Well,
I mean,
I think the urine test is done because
it's a little bit cheaper.
They could initially look at the
testosterone to epitestosterone ratio.
That is a pretty true marker and you're
in the amount of testosterone that you
have to epitestosterone.
The levels can barely vary depending on
how you're excluding out,
but that ratio,
you know,
we'll stay will be very accurate of
what's in your body.
Normal human has a one to one ratio.
There are some variances on the positive
and on the plus and negative side.
And if you look at what vittores ratio
was there,
it was within normal range.
Now you,
but you allow up to four to one in
Nevada.
Is that still the case with the way the
UFC has?
This new program is still four to one
because he was six to one at one point
in time that was criticized and it was
dropped down to four to one.
So that's gone out the window a little
bit.
Um,
the ratio is looked at to determine
whether or not you go to a more accurate
backup tests called we talked about
earlier,
the carbon isotope ratio tests.
So in all cases you know,
if,
if a test proves high over whatever the
number is,
three to one,
four to one,
six to one than the termination is
usually made.
Hey,
let's go to the definitive test carbon
isotope to determine whether or not
that's foreign based testosterone and if
it is foreign based testosterone,
how much of a time,
like once you get the test results,
like say if you test a guy and his urine
tests are kind of Funky,
he's reading really high and then you
decide to go to a blood test.
If he's doing something like Alex
Rodriguez was doing where it's like
quick release or how would you describe
it?
Quick,
quick half live,
what would you describe it?
Yeah,
fast acting fast.
Ach Clearing,
fast clearing.
How would you,
how would you mitigate that?
So ask the question again.
So you do the.
So you do the one test and shows that
he's got a very high level 1200.
Um,
and then you want to,
you want to do a blood test,
not necessarily you could go right to
that same urine sample and do a
different test or cir test on that.
So it can be.
So you don't do that.
Ordinarily the carbon isotope is not
done immediately in our,
in our program.
It will be,
that will be as opposed to,
you know,
hey,
let's do the testosterone
epitestosterone ratio tests first.
In some cases we'll go right to the
Usada,
we'll go right to the CIO,
our test and bypass the t ratio.
And that is because of the micro dosing
issue.
So say like an Alex Rodriguez took a
fast acting testosterone,
didn't really manipulate his tat level
too much if you were just doing that
test would show a two or three to one
maybe and in the past and say,
okay,
well he's good.
He's under four to one or six to one.
Um,
where if a car test was done on that,
they would have known right away that he
was using.
So under our program,
oftentimes the cir tests will be done
right away regardless of what the t
ratio is.
Okay.
So if you are doing with Alex,
Rodrigo was.
Rodriguez was doing,
even if he tests okay.
Within his boundaries and normal levels,
you can do a cir test and catch him even
though it's out of a system.
Well,
no,
no.
If it's out of his system,
it's out of his system.
But if it's a four hour thing,
that's true.
Is that actually the level.
I mean,
it really is gone for hours.
that's what they say.
I'd be a little bit hesitant if I was an
athlete to depend on,
you know,
I had a drug test in five hours.
It's,
something's going to clear in four
hours.
They can detect pretty minute amounts,
but my understanding is it does clear
pretty quickly and you're going to ask
guys in the middle of the night,
uh,
the side,
it has the ability to do that.
I don't think they're gonna,
you know,
make that routine.
But if,
again,
this is all detective work,
if they're looking at biological
passports over time and see variances
between mornings and evenings,
they could get a tip or other
information that's,
you know,
non science related.
Just a tip from somebody that,
hey,
this is what's going on in this camp.
They'd had the ability to do that.
Yes.
I'm a tip.
Has that happened before?
Do you guys have tips from people like
the fighters are using?
There's a uh,
so actually you saw it.
It has a hotline or a tip line that's
given dollar athletes,
you know,
here's something about something going
on from somebody or a camp they can
anonymously call and lead that.
And you look back at,
you look back at all of the major
performance enhancing drug cases that
have come out over the past 15 years.
You look at Belko,
you look at Biogenesis,
uh,
you look at Kirk Radomski,
who in New York,
mets,
bat boy that was distributing to
athletes.
There's a bat boy.
He was,
he was a clubhouse attendant.
The back boy was getting them dressed or
was.
Wow.
How they catch him.
Was He in jail now?
Uh,
he is,
uh,
he's a convicted felon.
I think he's done with probation.
Um,
but all of those cases,
all the major cases that have happened
over the last decade,
decade and a half all were a result of
investigations not necessarily
anti-doping side of things.
And you sorta who we're using is aware
of that.
They actually have someone on their
staff,
former law enforcement who's
investigator that will liaison and reach
out to various law enforcement agencies
both here in the United States and
internationally so that say another case
comes out and local law enforcement
agency goes in and does a search warrant
and they find,
you know,
list of UFC athletes of what drugs they
were getting or being distributed.
You saw it would have the ability
hopefully to go to law enforcement said,
hey,
when you're done kind of with the
criminal side of things here,
can you give us,
find a way to give us some of your
evidence,
use it here and uh,
and use it that way.
So again,
Joe,
we're just trying to.
Our program has every resource available
that we know of science wise,
investigative lies to create that
deterrent effect.
So athlete,
you may have found the newest,
latest,
greatest,
greatest strug that they will never be a
test for,
but you're running
the risk of whoever's getting that for
you at some point,
you know,
running along to some investigation and
that information out and catching you on
the back door.
It's,
it's definitely happened a lot in the
past.
And is that what happened with Bronco?
It was.
So Balco was a criminal investigation,
uh,
first,
um,
and what we did there was interfaced
with anti-doping.
So we discovered drugs in balco that
were designer drugs that they were,
weren't tests for,
and through the back door went to anti
doping and said,
hey,
here's what we've got.
We're trying to figure out who palcos
clients are,
what they're using.
If,
when we bring them in,
they're telling us the truth about what
they've used.
So the anti-doping side of thing was
able to develop tests for these drugs,
go out and test some of these athletes,
both current samples provided and
samples that were frozen and leftover
from previous provisions and kept some
of those athletes for the drugs they
were using.
They then pass that information back
along to us so that when we go out and
question athlete and they say,
I,
I didn't use anything we will to say
you're full of shit now.
When you say it was a criminal
investigation first,
what was the crime?
So actually that was back in my days,
I was a irs special agents.
So it involved a financial crime and
money laundering.
So the taking of profits from Doug drug
distribution and putting them back in
the financial system.
Oh right.
Because they have to have some way to
account for the money.
Correct.
Right.
Because you're making all these might
look good.
How much does a guy like barry bonds pay
for for steroids to a guy like Victor
Conte,
like how much does that work?
He was interesting because he didn't pay
anything.
He paid in the form of giving.
Advertise and it was really an ingenious
plan instead of,
you know,
in exchange for what I'm giving you,
you give me back money,
do advertising for my supplement
company,
go in magazines and ads and say,
Hey,
you work with me and my supplements and
they're the reason for your success,
like cma and stuff like that.
Who knows what the value of that was of
that.
Advertise for a guy bonds millions.
It's really an engine.
It was an ingenious plan.
Money Laundering plan.
I've had content here and Dana White
fucking hates that guy,
but I found them to be a pleasant
individual.
I didn't have a problem with him and he
was very forthright.
He was very honest about what he did and
how he got away with it and what he
thinks is going on right now.
A lot of people are suspicious of him of
course,
because I mean he's now like working as
an anti performance enhancing drugs
advocate when he became famous for being
a guy who provided performance enhancing
drugs to athletes.
It's a weird sort of turnaround late in
life and people or they're suspicious
and rightly so,
but what he has,
what he has done is at least illuminates
what he was able to pull off.
Yeah.
I'm asking about him often and I always
say,
Hey,
I,
I welcome anybody over to,
to the good side.
You believe him.
I'm a firm believer in second chances.
I think you have to have to take
everything he says with a little bit of
grain of salt.
Um,
I read something the other day that he
still keeps a hand in kind of the dark
world and that's where we learned about
all this stuff.
And if you're truly,
if you're truly an anti-doping advocate
and you know about things going on in
the dark world and you're not exposing
who those people are,
then you're really not truly an
anti-doping advocate,
but a [inaudible] guy's a character.
I mean,
I enjoyed.
He's one of those guys and in my former
career you run into a lot of characters
like that and I enjoy everything about
those people.
It's just living life and running into
characters like that.
Whether in a good or bad way.
Fun.
You enjoy it because it's part of like
the flavor of the Gig.
Absolutely.
And also because you're a pretty
straight edge guy,
you know,
like people are living on the edge like
that.
It's always fun to see how the other
side lives.
I don't trust anybody with a fucking
mustache like that.
I'll tell you that when you get one of
them little skinny mustaches,
there's just very few people that I
trust.
Maybe a couple of black eyes,
maybe some people of Puerto Rican
descent and have a little skinny
mustache,
but I dunno content that you've seen his
mustache.
Yeah.
It's a psalm about that mustache and
makes me go,
hmm.
You know,
I just hope at some point when,
because he does.
He's got a bit of a platform,
you know,
still a lot of tell you had them in here
without mustache.
Get out of here dog.
Come on son.
I'm waiting for it.
You know,
he's been critical of me.
I'm waiting for.
I'm waiting for a thank you from him for
him.
Vocal to the good side.
What's his criticism in A.
I don't even know,
don't listen to it,
don't listen to it really good for you.
Um,
Aldo,
Josie,
although has said that he won't do the
Ivy or that he won't listen to the band
on Ivs,
he's going to take it and he said
they'll still let me fight.
You know,
what do you think about that?
Actually,
when we were in Brazil a couple of weeks
ago,
had a conversation with them about that
and you said it was just one of those
days where he was in a certain mood,
uh,
maybe a little bit joking,
maybe a little bit pissed off about
something else and said those things and
said he shouldn't have.
Doesn't believe those,
you apologize for doing that.
And uh,
so I felt pretty good at conor mcgregor
felt that way.
Crawl inside that Dude's head and camped
out,
planted flags shit all over the place.
I mean,
that guy was dealing with some serious
psychological warfare at a level that I
don't think he had ever experienced
before.
It was.
Connor is really good at that,
isn't he?
He's the best.
It's like he took Mohamad Ali and chill
Sunnen and he rolled it up in this crazy
Celtic warrior character.
It just and just.
And He's good.
That's the thing.
He's not just trash-talker,
he's fucking dangerous.
It's a once in a lifetime personality
and he pulls it off consistently.
He's always on his game.
Well,
the fact that it was willing to Bet Dana
and Lorenzo,
$3,000,000,
it would knock Mendez out in the second
round and he knocked Mendez out in the
second round.
I mean,
he's a fucking freak.
He really is.
He's a freak.
I wonder if it,
if it comes naturally or you sits.
It sits around at night plotting these
things out.
So damn good at it.
Well,
he was always a very good fighter.
I was a big fan of his when he was
competing in Europe and you know,
he's fighting in the UK and quite an
actually I tweeted him way back in the
day before he ever came to the UFC
saying that I enjoy his fights and I
hope he gets over here.
And then boy,
did he get over here.
Jesus Christ.
I mean that UFC wayans when he fought
Mendez was the craziest thing I've ever
seen in my life of all the fights that
have ever called all the weigh ins that
I've ever been at.
I have never seen anything like that in
America.
And it was like we were in Dublin,
so it's amazing.
I'm,
I'm four months into this,
so I'm a Newbie,
so I expect that now.
Don't know.
That was,
that was a total outlier.
I've never seen any expected.
If he fights again though,
in a bigger way in December when he
fights,
although Jesus Christ,
that's going to be crazy if,
although makes it to it without getting
injured and he makes it to it without
getting injured.
Which is a big problem with this sport.
You know,
if you look at boxing matches,
boxing matches that get arranged and how
many of them actually come to fruition?
It's most of them,
most fights gets scheduled.
They'd come and they,
they actually,
they come to pass with the UFC.
It's,
it's maybe 70 percent,
you know,
maybe 70 May.
I mean,
I might be wrong,
but if I had to guess like big fights,
75 at the most,
25 percent of them fall out.
It seems like just.
It's interesting,
it's another,
it's lagging behind a little bit,
the anti-doping side,
because that's taken up so much of my
time,
but it's another responsibility under my
title is to try to provide our athletes
reach out,
provide them with other resources.
In terms of training,
rehabilitation.
We've reached out to a couple of
companies here domestically,
exos,
which there's a lot of training for NFL
exos or out of what does that x o,
s and what do they do?
Their training facility?
Yeah,
so they,
they are most widely known from taking
shoot.
If you look at most of the first round
draft picks in the NFL,
they've gone and trained at exos from,
you know,
their end of their last season in
college through the combine and they've
just instituted good nutrition,
good training methods.
We've contracted with them a couple
months ago,
sent a couple athletes down there.
Um,
I think Rashad Evans went down a forest,
went down kind of from an internal
perspective,
look at things.
I think Luke rockhold went down their
cm,
punk is retired.
He is,
and he went down there to look at
experience week of training.
So the idea is to get our athletes to
train smarter,
to listen to their bodies,
to uh,
you know,
give them techniques and proper
nutrition,
things like that.
So that as our guys are training
smarter,
listening to their bodies better,
there will be less instances of getting
injured.
You know,
coming up to big fights in the UFC is
developing some sort of a performance
center,
correct?
Correct.
We are that,
I think they're breaking ground pretty
soon on that,
but the idea would be through consulting
with these other companies that had been
in the business of training high level
athletes to putting all these resources
and tools and machines and space
available to this state of the art world
class facility that our athletes would
have the ability to come to and train to
come to an rehabilitate.
Not only UFC athletes,
but I think the idea is to make this
place so state of the arts that we would
welcome in athletes from other sports
that,
hey,
this is the world class place to go to
your training and learn how to do your
training and a similar that as we're
doing with our anti-doping program,
hoping to lead the pack.
The idea is to lead the pack in terms of
how we teach our athletes that train.
Is there a consensus though on the
correct way to train as far as strength
and conditioning goes as far as like how
much time to spend doing skill work
versus how much time to spend during
endurance work.
There seems like there's a lot of debate
and then there's a lot of athletes very
as far as their needs,
their style of fighting.
Like how would you manage something like
that?
Yeah.
That's a tough one for me that I'm a be
the first to admit.
Just learning and coming up to speed.
I mean,
you probably know better and your
involvement in mma and what it feels
like to train in which you would need to
do in your training to be able to ready
to get into a real fight a month or a
couple of weeks later.
I'll turn that back around on you.
What do you think in terms of how close
to a fight these guys need to be going
full speed so that when they get in that
octagon,
it's not a shock to the system like holy
shit
going on?
Well,
it depends on who you ask because
there's a lot of people that I respect
that very wide wildly on how they
approach things like you'll.
You'll talk to one guy who's a strength
and conditioning coach and he has this
very specific idea of how you should
train and then another guy who was also
very well respected but completely
different methodology.
I'm a big fan of what Marv Marinovich
was able to do with Bj Penn and the
amount of work that he did with Bj's
endurance.
I think that Bj during that time was
just one of the greatest of all time
during the time we fought to Diego
Sanchez and Sean Sherk and when Bj was
in his prime and I know during the Diego
Sanchez fight in particular was an
absolutely brutal camp for him and he
went and worked with him for only a
couple of fights because it was so,
so goddamn brutal,
but a lot of people think and nick curse
on who was a protege of Marinovich.
I've had him on the podcast.
We discussed it pretty,
pretty deep and he thinks and I liked
the way he thinks.
He believes that strength and
conditioning during camp is everything
and that's really what you should
primarily focus on.
That these guys already know how to
fight and that really they should be
putting almost all of their effort into
conditioning.
Getting their body to the point where
their body can perform at an extremely
high level for five rounds,
five minutes each and that all the other
skill work and everything like that
should actually take a back seat to
conditioning.
Because what you're dealing with when
you're dealing with a championship level
fight like that is an athlete that's so
finely tuned in skill wise already that
really what you need to do is give them
the horsepower and give him the gas tank
and that also would,
that also would do is it would prevent
the really hard training that is
breaking guys down like the really hard
wrestling training that's breaking guys
down.
Instead of doing that,
you would just drill and instead of
doing these hard sparring drills,
you would just drill.
Matter of fact,
Tim Kennedy was just on the fighter and
the kid podcast with Brian Kaylin and
Brendan Schaub and Brendan texted me
last night and said that Kennedy said he
doesn't spar,
said he just doesn't spark city moves
around with guys and he just does
strength and conditioning work and
everything like that.
He said,
but the sparring,
like if you take enough punishment
fighting,
so he's.
He's of the mindset that you shouldn't
be beating yourself up in the gym.
So I think there's a lot of variation
there.
Yeah,
I agree.
I think that's something that exos
promotes,
is that it depends on,
you know,
an athlete,
individual to individual,
some are,
are different than others.
One thing that they did tell us was they
were just amazed and getting back to
kind of the weight cutting thing that an
athlete who's going to compete 24 hours
later,
it's putting their body through such
extreme conditions just 24 hours before
and the fact that that's going to have
on your performance when you do an
extreme cut and then put that weight
back on.
Um,
and that,
you know,
during the off season when you don't
have a fight scheduled and you're maybe
even 20 pounds heavier than that,
you know,
the muscle memory of getting used to
working out at that 20 pounds heavier
than you're actually going to be
fighting a doesn't seem to make a lot of
common sense because you're fighting is
a completely different feel and person
and muscle mass.
Um,
that,
you know,
training wise doesn't seem to make a lot
of sense.
So I don't know,
again,
I'm new to all this and trying to be as
a sponge and absorb everything and uh,
yeah,
I've seen the horror stories.
I've seen guys cut too much weight,
just fight like shit.
And I've seen guys that really blew
their opportunity of being champion.
The best example that I've ever used as
Travis Luder,
Travis Luder.
It was one of the best American black
belts in Brazilian Jujitsu,
especially at the time.
He was just extremely high level black
belt,
very,
very technical,
very strong and fought Anderson Silva.
It didn't make weight,
didn't make weight.
And,
and when I tell you that he was on
fucking death's door,
I've never,
in all my years of watching fights,
uh,
watching weigh ins,
seeing guys look dehydrated,
I'd never seen anybody look as bad as
him.
His lips were cracked,
like you could see like he'll like
cracks in his lips.
His lips had shrunken down and like his,
his,
like he was chapped,
his face was completely sunk and scary
and he was shuffling.
He Walk to the scale,
he was shuffling and he didn't make the
weight and he tried for like an hour and
a half afterwards to try to make the
weight still.
The next day took Anderson Silva down,
mounted him was on top of them and I'll
tell you what,
if travis was 100 percent right there,
he would've submitted Anderson.
Like Travis was submitting.
Everybody who's was just kinda blood
will like Charles Mccarthy who was a
friend of mine,
have train with them in the house.
He said it was like rolling with Ricardo
Laborio.
He said his level was like super high
level and blues chance and really never,
never sort of reached the full potential
after that.
But that was,
that was like the worst I've ever seen
is like a guy who just blew his
potential.
I'll tell you an interesting stat.
I think it was the American Journal of
Sports Medicine,
so they had a,
a dehydration rehydration study and they
had certain percentages of dehydration
and what that meant to a body,
and I think it was seven percent or
more,
your cognitive skills decline immensely.
And I think it was 15 percent dehydrated
in the study.
It's a death imminent death organs shut
down 15 percent.
Start doing the numbers,
Joe,
of what some of these cuts that you've
heard about and seen.
I heard one the other day,
someone on the radio talking about an
athlete that they had that was one 74
days before a way in and went down I
think to 1:45
and do the math on knots.
Assuming all that weight cut was water.
I don't know if that's actually the
case,
but probably in where you're talking
about your time,
that's almost 15 percent.
Conor mcgregor when he fought Chad
Mendez,
he looked like a dead man.
I mean you could see people were
commenting and online.
They like Jesus Christ,
look at him.
Can a guide like that?
A guy like that who's fighting a guy
like Mendez,
Kennett guy like that in 24 hours orally
rehydrate properly.
Yeah.
I don't know what the question of that.
I mean,
I think,
I think our athletes are outliers.
They are the toughest individual,
you know,
their genetic freaks to begin with.
So you know,
maybe this common science doesn't quite
apply to them by the exact number,
but I tell you,
it's something we had,
we had a meeting the other day with our
operation staff and our fighters come in
on Monday or Tuesday and the first thing
I do is weigh a men just to kind of get
an idea of hey,
where they're looking at,
they do a body or water company that I'm
aware of,
but I tell you I'm going to start being
aware of kind of what these numbers are
coming in versus you know,
what,
what the ultimate way it is.
And again,
just trying to be,
you know,
not trying to be the police but trying
to be an advocate and maybe sit down
with some of these fighters as a hey
look,
look what the studies show here,
you know,
look what you're subjecting yourself to.
Maybe you can get away with it,
you know,
on the outside.
But on the inside these things don't go
away and you're probably doing,
you know,
lasting damage.
Have you talked to any x fighters?
I've talked to a few about that.
Have ongoing kidney problems are
probably going to have the rest of their
life.
Fibroid problems where their thyroid is
all messed up from these extreme weight
cuts.
It's definitely there if you have to
have
a statement.
Yeah,
it's devastating.
And well,
Daniel Cormier didn't make the Olympic
team because was in.
Didn't compete in the Olympics because
of his kidneys shutting down.
Um,
it's a,
it's a giant,
giant problem.
Um,
it's just,
it's awful and it doesn't.
Here's the thing for a guy like,
although when a guy like mcgregor,
what really people want to see is what
they want to see.
Aldo fight mcgregor,
right?
They don't give a fuck if they weigh in
at 1:45,
then rehydrate backup to whatever the
hell they weighed before that.
That's nonsense.
What they should do is figure out where
are these guys are healthy,
like,
where are you healthy?
Then we're going to see the best fight
out of these guys.
The problem is the title.
The title is everything,
right?
You want to be.
Chris Weidman is the UFC middleweight
champion of the world.
If Chris Weidman releases his title and
says,
look,
I can't make the UFC one 85 pound limit
anymore because of this new,
um,
and non ivy using policy,
so I'm just going to drop the title
Chris Weidman and could still have huge,
super fights because he's Chris Weidman
and everybody knows he's a bad
motherfucker.
So if he decided to fight at two,
oh,
five or whatever,
people are going to line up.
It doesn't matter if it's for the title,
he's got a name.
Rhonda Rousey has a name,
connor has a name,
but there's a lot of guys that just
don't have a name.
So for those guys,
it's that,
that,
that title is critical.
The difference between Robbie lawler
fighting Carlos condit just in a fight
and Robbie lawler fighting crime was
kind of as a champion.
It's too big goddamn difference.
It's a big difference.
And that's unfortunate because I think
that this,
the,
the situation that they're in right now
where they have to hit this specific
weight class,
I think we should match guys up based on
their size and not based on weighing in
24 hours beforehand.
At a very specific way,
I think it's dangerous and I also think
it's irrelevant.
I don't think it matters.
I mean,
I think there's advantages that guys
would have if they were a more than a
certain amount over their opponent or
less than a certain amount of,
you know,
there's a way that you could mitigate
that though.
There's a way that you could figure out
like what,
what,
what is the range of these guys could
weigh in,
but make sure that they are within the
range of dehydration within the range of
body composition and then they're not
fucking with the numbers any.
Let's find out what you actually weigh.
What,
what does Johnny Hendricks actually way,
when he fights,
when Johnny Hendricks is at his best,
that's where Johnny Hendricks,
you'd be fighting.
What about Tyron Woodley all those guys
and figure out where everybody belongs
and then compete at that level.
But everybody's competing for titles.
You know,
and I think that is part of the problem
is the 1:55
pound title,
the one 70 pound title.
But really what we want to see as the
best fighters fighting against the best
fighters.
That's where the money's at.
Yeah,
I hear you.
I don't think there's,
you know,
a simple answer to this.
I think it's,
you know,
it's a process and steps and then all I
can say is,
and I already am beating this,
but I'm going to be the squeaky wheel
here that,
you know,
hopefully at some point squeaks enough
that,
you know,
get some grease into this.
And in terms of the fighters,
hey,
I have just one interest at mind.
My one goal in one interest and that's
looking out for their health short and
longterm with everything we're doing
with this anti doping program with the
ivy ban.
I mean it,
it is.
Ultimately,
I,
I challenge anyone to say that I don't
have that,
you know,
at the forefront of what we're trying to
do here.
I certainly think you do,
but I just think that the ivy band,
without some sort of weight class
management is almost like
counterintuitive.
I think there has to be something that
allows these guys who they've got like
Weidman is worked so hard to get to the
185 pound title to all of a sudden he
can't make it anymore because you can't
use [inaudible].
It just seems ridiculous because you
have a policy that he's too dehydrated
and you check them and you find out what
he's doing to get to one 85.
Even though he's been doing his whole
career.
You guys step in and say,
Hey,
this is too dangerous and we're not
gonna allow you to do it anymore.
That's,
you know,
it's kind of crazy.
If he's gotta move up 20 pounds.
He's already talked about fighting Jon
Jones statement he made recently and
there's one thing I love about this guy
said he wants to fight the best guys in
the world and he says if Weidman or if
John Jones rather comes back,
he goes,
I have to fight this guy because he's
the best and I'm not leaving the sport
until I fight Jon Jones and because he's
the best at two,
oh five.
And so he wants to do that,
but I just think that,
I think the,
making the weight cut and making that
way classes probably reducing his career
and probably reducing a lot of these
athletes' careers.
They can do it,
they get through it,
but at what price and that price is,
I'm sure cumulative.
It has to be.
Yeah,
I hear everything you're saying Joe.
Um,
you know,
I don't think I say as this program has
been up and running now for a month,
month and a half,
I'm generally don't listen to me,
man.
They gotta listen to you.
They think I'm crazy.
You gotta you gotTa talk to them.
Weight classes,
more weight classes and all the people
who support shut up dummies.
Shut up.
All of you.
You don't know what you're talking
about.
Just fucking sport is so filled with
crazy people.
They're willing to do anything to win.
I mean,
that's one of the,
one of the things about the weight cut
is that the amount of effort,
that titanic effort that it takes to get
down to some of these weight classes and
rehydrate and compete against world
class athlete,
world class athletes and the toughest
sport in the world.
Twenty four hours later.
It's just nuts.
They're superhuman on so many levels,
so many levels.
The fighting skills,
their ability to withstand pain.
It's just incredible.
The mental toughness to the mental
toughness that it takes to go through
those weight cuts and then compete 24
hours later.
It's just insane.
So we were talking earlier about the
designer drugs that you're catching
people on or these drugs that they're
testing that they like.
We were talking about the cyclist.
Is there anything else that's like that
that you may see coming up?
Possibly.
I mean I don't have anything for you
here today,
but there's
constantly drugs in clinical trial phase
that could have an application to,
you know,
performance enhancement and how do you
guys stay on top of that stuff?
Like what is,
what's the method of making sure that
you're aware of every new thing that
these guys are doing to try to get some
sort of an advantage and when these
things should be legal and illegal?
Yeah.
What's.
I mean that's,
that's the role of the anti-doping
authorities and you saw to who we use
and they constantly interact and
interface with the pharmaceutical
industry so that way they know these
things run the pipeline.
They can get a look at,
hey,
what's potentially performance enhancing
or not?
I think the pharmaceutical companies
been pretty cooperative about it.
I mean financially they could probably
care less but you know,
it doesn't look good.
I think when they have a product like an
EPO,
which is a great drug for someone who
has cancer,
Rosa anemic and helps your body create
red blood cells that you need to live
great drug,
but then you know,
most of the press about it as athletes
that are using it to cheat.
So I think it's good for our reputation
standpoint for the pharmaceutical
industry to,
you know,
get on top of these things and seeing
what the application could be in and
helping anti-doping with that.
Is there a window where these guys are
going to be able to use certain things
that you guys haven't caught onto yet
that are actually legal for them at a
certain point,
like some natural supplements perhaps
that turn out to be like a little bit
too effective.
Like how do you make that distinction
potentially and that that really lies
with water.
The world antidoping agency and they are
constantly monitoring things.
There's certain things,
I forget what it was,
we were talking last week,
but they have things on their watch list
so that something like you just talked
about could be some type of legal
supplement and they're taking a look at
it and studying it.
What are the performance enhancing
benefits?
Does it have side effects were that,
you know,
if you had athlete and say hey,
I don't want to risk myself to those
side effects,
so I don't want to use that.
Even if it is legal,
as somebody's gaining an unfair
advantage because they're willing to
risk,
so side effects.
So it's a constant monitoring process
being done by the top level anti-doping
authority,
which is water.
Now what about unintentional
contamination?
Anderson Silva just got through this big
crazy trial in Vegas,
which I'm sure you watched those in the
front row.
I was right behind him.
What the hell was that about?
The songs that kept playing I was
hearing was disturbing on so many
levels.
So many explain to people what I'm
talking about because for some they hear
it from me.
They're gonna think I'm kidding.
Like explain what was going on.
So they had a,
they had a little conference call
device,
which they have actually a couple of
scientists on the line for that were
testifying about some of his tests and
somebody out there was able to get the
number and in the middle of the hearing
was playing these songs.
Uh,
so let's say he was taught,
he was testifying about the Cialis that
he thought was cialis that he was using.
And like a shaggy came on,
salt and pepper song came on.
Yeah,
it was.
Songs about sex kept coming on during
the.
It'll be such a zoo.
The whole thing was just so ridiculous.
Yeah.
It wasn't good.
It was great for people that were paying
attention.
I mean,
the courtroom burst out in laughter.
Yeah.
But it's,
I mean,
sad somebodies career,
reputation at stake in a bright.
I mean,
to me that's.
I'm all about having a little humor
injected into things,
but I hated to see that.
Um,
I.
well,
I can't say I hated it.
I,
it was just too funny to me.
I think the whole thing was odd in the
first place.
Um,
the,
the argument is for folks who hadn't
heard that,
that he was taking or the excuses that
he was taking liquid cialis that was
apparently made in the laboratory that
also made steroids and that this liquid
cialis was tainted unintentionally.
Like you get a vat of stuff and you mix
it all together and then you throw the
new stuff and the next VAT and you
haven't cleaned it.
His story was it was liquid.
Cialis from a friend that he recently
got to know that came from Thailand in a
blue on mark vial,
which is crazy,
but if you're gonna make something up,
but you really make that up.
I would lead,
lend more credibility to that story
because of the personal nature of taking
it and maybe the embarrassing,
the embarrassment around taking that.
He have come in and said,
hey,
I used the protein powder and found
something in it.
Right.
I would lend some credibility to that.
Well,
uh,
you know,
I had alluded to that on this show.
I didn't,
didn't express the exact nature of the
issue,
but I'd known about this for a long
time.
I had heard about the liquid cialis
excuse for a long time,
but if I'm correct,
he said that he had taken that same
steroid,
went while he was healing from his
broken leg.
I'm pretty sure that he had said that he
had taken it before to heal his broken
leg.
And then when he was surprised was that
he had tested negative during camp,
but then positive after the fight and
that's when they decided to check out
the liquid cialis.
I wasn't,
I wasn't aware of of that.
That didn't come up in the,
in the here and yeah,
that's my boss route and was critical of
it boss route and was saying that he's
changed his story more than once.
And boss was saying that,
that this is what he had said,
that he had taken it to heal up his leg
and then you know,
then it was this new excuse with the
liquid cialis.
And if there's a lesson I learned over
the years of seeing so many of these
high profile athletes kind of get
brought to the table and you know,
their reputations kind of tarnished
forever is come to the table and just be
transparent and miss exactly.
Transparency.
That the public is very forgiving,
very forgiving.
Especially in a sport like this where
most people believe that a large
percentage of the athletes at one point
in time have done something that at
least now would not be legal,
including testosterone replacement,
which was legal just a little bit more
than a year ago in Nevada.
Which again,
going back to what I said,
the,
the understanding of why things happen,
my personal understanding of why
athletes shows to go that route.
I think most of the public will be like
that.
Hey,
there wasn't much testing going on.
You know,
maybe a couple weeks out the night of
the fight,
um,
you know,
you were probably stupid if you weren't
doing something based on your risk and
your life every time you got in there.
So definitely under those circumstances.
Now under the new one here,
and I don't think people should be as
forgiving because everybody should know
now how serious this is,
that it's,
you know,
year round that there are serious
consequences and the risk is far going
to outweigh the reward.
Hopefully.
Now,
as far as inadvertent contamination,
as far as accidental dosing,
you,
if you buy something from some protein
powder or vitamin that comes from some
shop,
you know and you don't know,
you know,
it's supposed to boost testosterone
naturally or something like that,
and then it turns out that steroids in
it.
How often does that happen?
Is that a real issue with athletes or is
it a bullshit excuse they use to cover
up the fact that it took steroids are
real issue,
so my career I just left to come to the
UFC.
I was with the Food and Drug
Administration Office of Criminal
Investigation.
We investigated the dietary sports
supplement and industry and there's
hundreds of products out there on the
shelves with steroids over the counter
with steroids and other substances which
would cause our athletes to test
positive for and as we're getting out
and going out and educating our
athletes,
that is a huge portion of the education.
It is that you have to be more than
careful,
extreme careful about what you take.
Ultimately you're liable for everything
that goes into your body.
Hey,
we'll be here and will be a resource for
you to help kind of Wade through those
issues and those,
those landmines that are out there,
but ultimately you're responsible for
what goes in your body.
Now we have built in our policy
mitigating factors that can reduce
sanctions so that if somebody,
you know,
did test positive for steroids,
they were able to show because they kept
a sample of it.
Um,
they told us what the lot number with
the bottle was.
Someone went and got that off the shelf
to ensure that hey,
they didn't just spike the sample that
they had,
that there was that steroid in it,
that there were other circumstances
about,
you know,
occurrences like that,
something like that could,
could be grounds for a reduction and
sanctioned to as low as,
you know,
maybe a public warning for the first
time maybe.
Um,
but nevertheless there's still going to
be some type of sanction and that'll be
your first one.
So that the next one that came about
could,
you know,
double potential penalties.
So it's tough issue,
man.
One that I worry about a lot because all
of our fighters take supplements.
We're not going to get up there and say
don't take supplements.
Anybody I don't think that's realistic.
And they say,
hey,
John,
contradicting.
If you think about the fact that all
these athletes takes off elements,
right,
why are they taking supplements?
Why gain in performance enhancing
advantage?
How much of an advantage that we're
talking and talking supplements you're
talking,
you know,
derivatives of food.
I'm talking drugs here,
but some of these derivatives of food
had been known to enhance testosterone
development or production.
Theoretically,
no,
I haven't seen tests.
Some of these natural testosterone
boosters.
Uh,
you know,
personally,
I think a lot of it's Hocus pocus and
just marketing and sales pitches.
Well,
the standard ones,
things like creatine,
we know that has an athletic advantage.
There's a performance enhancing benefit
of creatine,
but creatines legal,
right?
It is.
Yep.
So the amount is just small enough so
that it's not,
it's under the wire,
it doesn't,
it doesn't reach this steroid,
like level where you guys have to step
in and say.
I guess that would be the reasoning why
water has not prohibited Korea,
10 that,
you know,
in terms of the level of what it's
really going to do for you.
It's,
it's minor is zero and avenue that
fighters have where they can send you
guys stuff that they're thinking about
taking.
And then you could test it like say if a
guy is at,
you know,
some vitamin store or something like
that and see some human growth hormone
booster,
that's all amino acids and totally
natural.
And I'm like,
ah,
I don't know man,
can we,
can they send it to you?
Uh,
now we don't have anything in place
where they can send it to us.
That would be,
you know,
I'm sure we get inundated with things
and be spending money.
We could be spending on a testing on
that.
But what they do do is shoot.
I get 20 to 30 a week,
maybe emails from athletes about,
hey,
here's what I'm taking.
Can I take this one?
Um,
that one.
And typically what I do is for that to
United States antidoping agency you saw
to where they,
uh,
actually have,
a phd,
a woman who's,
she is probably the nation's expert on
dietary supplements and she buys you
Sato will buy on their own hundred or so
a year and test them theirselves.
They actually have a website that lists
a lot of these that have tested positive
for substances that would be a positive
test under our program.
So yeah,
we're constantly answering questions,
providing resource.
But ultimately I tell everybody and
they're disappointed that I say I could
never give you 100 percent green light
to take something.
I can't on the other side,
say 100 percent,
don't touch that one.
I can give you red flags.
But you know,
even,
you know,
the most reputable company that sells,
you know their vitamin in Costco,
you don't know about that one bottle
from that one batch.
I gave you the horror story of all time.
And it's in the,
it's in the news,
you can google it and read it.
But there was a a vitamin company that
had a vitamin B,
I don't know if it was 12,
I think it was manufactured in long
island a couple of years back,
and the guy that was manufacturing it on
the run before vitamin took,
did a run of a raw product that he got
from some guy in the south.
Ran that through the machine with
instructions of how much to put in each
capsule.
Sent that off to the guy in the south.
The vitamin companies product is next on
the machine.
You didn't clean the machine off well
enough,
and that previous product had a
designer,
anabolic steroids,
super drawl mythos drone,
which is one of the most powerful
anabolic steroids.
It's orally taken.
That got into the [inaudible].
The [inaudible] I'm sure I'm thinking it
was maybe a.
I mean it was a reputable retail store
or it was sold a week or two later.
Elderly people started presenting
themselves at hospitals in this area.
What was being sold with yellow eyes,
yellow palms.
Because they were ingesting a vitamin
that had his very toxic steroid in it
and they were getting sick from liver
damage.
Luckily that's the extreme,
but there have been cases of and we
talked and then we start talking to
sports supplement and industry,
which is,
you know,
testosterone boosters,
maybe more edgy stuff.
You see that happen way more often.
I invite you after it go on.
You saw it aside.
It's publicly available.
A supplement for one one.
They have listed all of the dietary
supplements that they've bought this
year and tested.
I was just looking at it last night.
I don't know if it's over 100,
but it's probably more than 50 in there,
which the public can still go out and
buy a there on the shelves of stores and
they contain,
in many instances,
anabolic steroids in all instances,
compounds which would cause our athletes
to test positive.
Wow,
that's crazy.
There's that many of these things.
Here it is right here.
There it is.
Supplement four,
one one.
Realize,
recognize and reduce.
So if you scroll down,
Scroll Down Syndrome list,
keep going,
go,
go back up a little bit.
High risk list there on the left high
risk supplement products.
Are you going to have to enter?
You can put my name in there baby.
Put Joe's name and there you have to put
it on.
Were searching.
I think the idea behind,
Ya know,
motherfucker,
the idea behind that is actually a
protection of the athlete so that if you
went in there,
um,
and you put your name in and then later
said,
hey,
I went and searched,
you know,
you saw it as site.
Um,
there will be a record of,
of you haven't searched that.
All right,
let's see what we got here.
Okay,
got it.
What do we got?
All these different.
You're scrolling down,
but scroll the page down for.
So we get a full screen.
So there you go.
Zero liquid and that stuff has got dag.
A product contains a list of prohibited
substance label lists a prohibited
substance product contains prohibitive
in testing revealed presence of one
Andrew [inaudible] dial.
And that stuff's illegal.
Now though,
isn't it interesting that those
prohormones he used to be able to sell
those?
There is.
It was a new law passed.
It was late last year,
early this year,
the designer,
anabolic steroid control act or Baska
and it basically made it easier to
quantify some of these designer drugs as
steroids and took a whole bunch of known
ones that weren't on the steroid.
Yes.
List yet and converted them to control
Sepsis,
but here we're still only at the aes on
product name on the list.
This is a crazy list.
Look,
look,
all this stuff.
A lot of xander's teen dial up.
Wow.
This is amazing.
Now.
It used to be just a few years ago that
you could basically.
I mean I guess more than a decade ago
now,
but you could basically buy steroids
from like GNC.
I mean the stuff that they had was oral
steroids.
Yeah.
Are there still some of these out there?
They've just become more designers.
Just look at the fucking list of
prohibited substance in this Angel Dust
Shit.
Oh my God.
Wow.
Okay.
Well we'll.
We'll leave it to anybody who wants to
look into this.
I mean,
our athletes,
we're constantly directing them toward
that.
Obviously if it's on this list,
don't take it,
but there's hundreds of others that
aren't on that list.
They only have so much time and
resources to buy these.
They they could probably hire another
two or three phds and by these full time
and triple or quadruple that list.
That is mad.
No,
the industry that's crazy.
So an athlete go into a vitamin store
and just buying a bunch of these things
off the counter.
There's a very good possibility that
he's going to get an actual steroids and
I'd be very concerned and that's where
we pass it along to them.
They shouldn't be concerned.
Now the story that you told about the
[inaudible] is really disturbing because
I would think that if they cleaned it at
all,
how would it be possible?
These trace amounts would get into these
people's vitamins to the point where
they're getting sick from liver damage
when it's toxic.
Steroids,
they obviously didn't do a good job and
you know,
clean it at all.
It's exactly.
You know,
as a,
so the dietary laws in here in the
United States and you know,
for foods and dietary supplements,
there's no premarket review of a
product,
so you and I and I,
in fact,
I think the bells you had on last week
as part of bigger,
faster,
stronger,
did a little piece on what the dietary
supplement industry is.
And I think he hired a couple people off
the street to make supplements and
showed you could put them right to the
shop.
That's accurate.
So it's up to the FDA after the fact,
after something's already been on the
shelf after probably somebody's already
got sick or hurt,
unless you have somebody in the FDA
being very proactive,
which I'll tell you,
coming from the FDA,
they're not proactive.
They're reactive agency,
um,
that typically either a complaint has to
be made or somebody gets hurt before
they go out and you know,
enforce what the law is.
That product shouldn't be at the show on
the shelf.
They need to do a much,
much better job.
And especially in my position now where
I have this group of athletes,
which I feel very fatherly over a,
I would call on the FDA to,
do,
you know,
a way better job than what I saw was
happening on the inside.
It's a huge organization,
mostly regulatory.
I was
on the criminal side,
but they have a huge population of
regulatory employees that they could be
doing a much better job in managing and
uh,
and taking these products off the shelf.
It just seems almost like there's no way
to keep up with.
And if there's that,
I mean you looked at so many different
supplements right there that just were
the letter a and how many of them all
told that they have on their list.
Jamie,
you can answer that.
How many,
uh,
if you say it,
is there a number that shows how many
they have now?
These were all even just tested this
year.
She's been doing that for a period of.
Oh my God,
that's so crazy.
Wow.
Cause you know,
you'd heard about that before from
athletes.
We've all heard,
you know,
that he,
he took a supplement and it turned out
to have a banned substance in it and
inadvertently tested positive for
steroids and a lot of times you think
they're full of shit and that's just
their excuse.
But Wow,
I'm looking at it a different way right
now because of that.
It's no doubt concerning.
Now what about,
is it possible that one of these things
like an Hvac machine or,
or altitude training,
or is it possible that one of those
things will eventually be so effective
that you guys are going to have to think
about banning that as well?
I don't know.
I mean we're,
we're following the law prohibited lists
and Wada prohibited methods.
So it ultimately would be if,
if water decided this,
it would fall under our program and
actually under our program,
um,
you know,
I think we'd have the ability to
evaluate it and determine whether or not
we wanted to adopt it.
We likely would,
I mean,
what is the gold standard and you know,
they're not just arbitrarily throwing
things out there that that wouldn't give
someone an unfair advantage to put on
their prohibited lists.
So we'd fall along likely.
Now.
One of the things that I really wanted
to make sure I talked to you about
because it was one that really raised my
eyebrows when we're talking in Brazil is
gene doping and it seems like we are at
this very strange point when it comes to
technology and innovation that there
it's.
I don't think they're more than a decade
away from doing something very bizarre
to human bodies where it might be
undetectable or might be so prevalent
that it might change the rules.
If you,
you're aware of crispr.
Do you know about the innovation that
they created in 2012 called Crispr?
That allows them to much more
efficiently manipulate genes and they're
doing it mostly,
you know,
they're testing it in non viable embryos
in China and they're doing it in all
different animals and different things.
But the idea being that within a certain
amount of time,
it's just undoubtedly going to be
something that they experiment with with
people.
In fact,
I have a friend who knows someone that
was.
They were traveling to the Middle East
where in this one lab they were
performing these tests
where they were going to make it so that
you could determine.
I mean this is all.
A lot of it is.
I'm in the preliminary stages and a lot
of it is,
it hasn't been totally proven that it's
effective,
but they're gonna be able to manipulate
it.
I call her think I'm going to build,
manipulate sex,
change the hair color,
they're gonna,
be able to do all sorts of different
things to,
to the baby in the embryonic stage to
change what they are as adults.
And the idea of creating a super athlete
through genetic manipulation is not that
far away.
It's crazy.
You know,
I know anti-doping when they get
together many times during the year and
have their conferences and bring
together leading scientists.
It's almost always,
you know,
one or two hour block on where gene
doping is going,
where it is now.
When was it now I don't,
I don't know the technicalities of where
it is now,
how close athletes are doing it,
but God,
man,
you talk about taking a risk,
one thing to take a drug,
but when you're manipulating your gene,
who knows,
you know,
and shoot one or two years,
what that's gonna do to you.
It feels like an x men movie though.
Does that?
It's like Jurassic Park,
you know,
or getting out of control real quick.
I'm mostly that happening.
I'm talking about Wolverine Guy Heels
like that and saying,
yeah,
I mean Jurassic Park Wolverine.
Although I mean I just feel like there
people are gonna be the first to take
the leap.
There's going to be someone or some
government or
somebody who's going to be.
It's going to be the bodybuilding
community and every drug that I've seen
used in athletics,
performance,
anti benefits,
that is the community that always tries
at first.
Those guys are willing to risk anything.
What does it get bigger or die trying?
Kind of the motto that is very common,
uh,
saw it firsthand.
They're willing to try and be the Guinea
pig for anything and they'll still get a
little bit bigger,
die young.
I do a lot of those guys.
They're usually the ones that refine how
the drugs are taken to determine,
hey,
this,
even though it's,
you know,
marketed or promoted for this,
actually we'll do this for you as well.
And saw that firsthand where non
bodybuilding athletes would rely on
advice from them of how to do it and
what the effects were.
Well,
they turn over again,
saw that insulin,
right?
Yeah.
Which is super dangerous,
isn't it?
No doubt that make you a diabetic real
quick
myostatin inhibitors.
That's something that I have been
fascinated ever since I saw a photo of
those whippets that have that genetic.
It just an aberration in the whippets
from breeding and they've been able to
manipulate cows and pigs and,
and cause it to happen now.
And pigs I think are the latest ones.
They've been able to do it to where they
have double muscle.
I've seen some of those photos and sane
and they've been able to do it to mice
and the fucked up thing about mice as
they live longer,
they have doubled their lifespan I
think,
and they look awesome.
Beach,
they look like Kevin Randleman mice.
I mean,
what is,
what's going to happen when that stuff
makes its way into mma?
What do you do?
Yeah,
I mean my guessing an anti doping is is
you're going to at some point get to
some type of gene testing and the
ability to look at human genes and see
if they'd been manipulated,
manipulated or inhibited.
But what if someone has a natural
manipulation?
Like there's a boy that was born.
I think it's been more than one person,
but I know of one that was born in
Germany that has that same issue that
these cows have and these whippets have.
And this young boy,
there he is.
Jesus fucking Christ.
Is that real?
That's not real.
Oh,
come on.
Is that real way to scroll up?
Scroll up.
Don't hold on.
How genetic engineering to make us look
like.
Bodybuilders naturally it.
Just scroll down so it can hear what
she.
In past posts.
We'll look into this because this might
be bullshit because that's Chris Bell
right there posing with that cow that's
from bigger,
stronger,
faster.
Find.
Find out if.
Because I know there was a young boy
looked different than that because I
looked like a kid with an adult arm.
The other one looked like a kid that had
like a six pack.
It was.
It was really bizarre.
He had really thick leg muscles and and
they were saying that this child was
born without that gene.
I mean myostatin inhibitor gene and that
this is something that's.
It might be him.
Yeah.
Myostatin muscle.
Her looks real like,
look at that.
That doesn't look real.
That kid is fucking shredded.
Look,
get a six pack.
That's nonsense.
He looks like he's got a turtle shell
grown out of his stomach.
Jesus Christ.
That kid is going to be a stud.
So what do you do with a kid like that?
If a kid like that,
once it compete in the UFC,
do you say,
no,
you're a mutant.
You have to compete in the x games.
Yeah.
I don't know.
I always liked seeing that,
that genetic freak of nature that comes
along.
Everyone Herschel Walker or even like a
babe ruth who was,
had a boiler on him that was obviously
strong as hell.
So maybe one of these.
He's one of those,
those cool people that come along once
every generation and everybody can get
behind because I know in there knowing
that that's real.
I Dunno.
Well it's real,
but it's also a genetic freak accident.
I mean,
he is definitely a real kid.
I mean he didn't,
he wasn't born as far as we know it
wasn't created in a lab,
but he has some sort of a freak
advantage.
Like it wasn't.
I mean Lebron James is a genetic freak
accident.
Izzy.
I mean,
one could argue that.
Yeah,
no,
you absolutely can and you would be
right,
but he's not competing and fighting.
I see that that is a little bit more
extreme there.
Uh,
I don't know how you deal with that.
I mean obviously he's going to be able
to show through medical records that
it's been that way.
And all through his life and didn't just
suddenly appear when he was 16 and did
manipulate his jeans.
So I mean I guess you can show that was
his natural.
I don't know.
I don't know what the answer to that is.
It seems like a for your job,
it seems like there's like a window of
time for you to enact change before all
this crazy genetic shit starts rolling
in from China and Russia and who knows
where.
Not accusing China and Russia,
but they have been known to do some
funky things in the past.
Yeah.
You know,
I worked at my last job,
I worked at the Air Mail facility at San
Francisco International Airport and part
of that job was to monitor everything
coming in from China and the stuff that
came through there.
And my primary focus was on drugs and
raw product and compounds that we're
putting into dietary supplements here.
But the majority of bad stuff going into
these supplements come in here.
That's where it's coming from.
From China.
It is,
Yep.
They don't have a lot of rules over
there.
They don't.
And that's why it's also scary than
manufacturing standards over there
aren't good so that they'll send
something over to a US manufacturer here
saying,
Hey,
here's what's in this product or this
raw compound,
and the US manufacturers take that at
its word and really not know what's
going into his product.
And that's why often you see supplements
that don't have on the label.
What's what's really in that and it's
not cost effective for them to test
every batch and every lot that comes in.
So you see a lot of that as well.
Well,
I learned from the Sopranos that most of
the shipping containers are coming to
the United States don't get tested and
true volume that comes in,
it would be in pot,
you'd have to hire a million or 2
million people to inspect everything.
So they target things.
I mean the intelligently target,
you know,
depending on what area is it comes from
and what,
you know,
what is declared at.
But no,
there's the percentage of things that
actually do get looked at and tested is,
is pretty low.
It's just kind of disturbing.
It's just,
it's amazing to consider that there's so
many shipping containers that are coming
in from somewhere like China,
China on a daily basis and who knows
what could be possibly in them.
Scary now as far as like what is
prohibited in band right now,
how many different things are prohibited
in band?
We could actually pull up.
Water's got they're prohibited list
available and that's one of the cool
things about our policy is how
transparent it is.
Everything that we're doing,
our rules,
UFC rules are fighters can go look at
their support personnel,
can look at the public and go look at.
They can look at the water prohibited
lists,
the water prohibited method.
It's out there for everyone to see.
Another thing that you know,
a lot of people are surprised at this,
but actually when we as our testing,
we're testing now,
but it goes forward and starts really in
earnest.
You cited will start posting who's
tested and how many times they're tested
by athlete name,
by the end of this year of public and
pull up the USADA UFC websites who ufc
fighter a was tested eight times UFC
fighter.
Be They were tested three times total
transparency and that's done.
Again,
to go back to what we talked about
earlier,
trust and credibility of the system.
It's,
it's paramount.
It's huge for us.
For you to be able to say,
we're not hiding anything here.
It's all out in the open what we're
doing.
So that athlete,
you know,
if you don't really think you know
what's going on or I think this has got
here,
it's all out there in the open for you.
Take a look exactly what we're doing is.
One of the things that people found
disturbing about the Anderson Silva
allegations was that it was revealed
that he would never been tested outside
of competition except this one time
where we tested negative for most of our
athletes fall under that same
circumstance.
Um,
Nevada California started doing it too.
It was probably the best,
I think maybe New Jersey where they
would do what we call enhanced testing
where they would maybe take the top two
or three fights on a card and go out for
maybe six weeks.
That was the extent of any out of
competition tests,
you know,
as we educate,
we're going out to different gyms,
we're educating the fight cards,
uh,
on the Wednesday before Saturday fight.
We usually ask the question,
hey,
who's been tested other than,
you know,
a day of competition test.
Very few hands go up,
you know,
maybe a couple per session.
So yeah,
I mean,
in terms of,
again,
understanding why an athlete will do
something,
Hey,
when you're not testing anybody,
unless it's on the day of the fight,
which is really just an Iq test as long
as you're smart enough to know how fast
a drug a clear your system,
you could easily use drugs in the past
and get off,
um,
you know,
a week or two ahead of time,
have them clear system and maintain the
benefits of those drugs,
most of them through the fight.
So is it,
is it any surprise,
uh,
y,
you know,
especially when you're risking your
health and in some arguments your life
when you're getting in that octagon,
is it any surprise why a lot of athletes
have made that under really?
No testing in the past,
it's not to me,
but a guy like Anderson Silva who's
widely considered to be,
if not the greatest of all time,
one of the top two or three grants of
all time.
The fact that he was only tested once
out of competition and failed.
That's a,
that's really disturbing to a lot of
people.
They go,
well,
you know,
you're looking at these spectacular
performances that he was able to have.
Who knows what he was under or on when
he pulled those off.
Yeah,
I mean,
and not just,
you know,
taints the legacy.
Looking at him individually.
But yeah,
you extrapolate that out with,
you know,
everybody in the sport that likely,
if he wasn't tested out of competition,
how about the other 549 behind him if
he's at the top of the game.
So you extrapolate that out.
It's scary.
Um,
so a,
we'll see.
We'll see real quick here.
I'm in.
I think a lot of it though early on is,
and then thank you for this platform
today,
but just getting the message out,
being that deterrent effect upfront.
You know,
having those athletes and support look
now saying,
okay,
the game's changed now.
It's no longer,
you're not going to be tested.
You don't trust that your opponents.
Now the game's changed that they're
using every method and tool available.
They're using blood,
urine testing for specific drugs.
They're looking at a biological
passport.
So if a specific drug doesn't show up,
they could catch somebody that way.
Hell,
they're freezing our blood and urine
that if the test isn't available today
and maybe in a year or two and they'll
go back and test that and then maybe if
I'm not fighting,
my legacy is,
is done.
Hopefully everybody's hearing all these
things that we're doing a hearing me
talk about experiences I've had with
athletes in the past about how damn
stressful it's going to be for a UFC
athlete right now to use drugs and get
away with it.
They are going to be thinking about that
24 slash seven.
I guarantee you a shit who's coming
tomorrow.
Okay,
how long do I got for this clears my
system?
Can I trust the person that's telling me
that all this shit's going to be
happening from now out in the hope would
be being that determine up front,
so the decisions made on the front end.
Okay.
It wasn't something that we can do now
as opposed to all of a sudden dozens of
positive tests on the back end.
The hope is I can get out and do a good
enough job of expressing how serious is
going to be that that our population of
fighter here that
now.
What about the difference between in
competition and the competition testing
and as far as like what the penalties
are for added competition testing and
what about recreational drugs in
competition?
Not a competition.
Testing like John Jones tested positive
for cocaine and it was out of
competition so he was still allowed to
compete in.
A lot of people were kind of critical of
that and like how is that possible that
you tested guy?
He tests positive for a banned substance
and yet he still allowed to compete.
You don't even hear about it,
but the results were known before he
fought and they never went public.
Yeah,
I mean a lot of different issues there.
So let me one at a time.
So first our UFC policy,
so out of competition,
the test for out of competition drugs,
those drugs are,
those substances will be your hard
substances,
your anabolic steroids,
your human growth hormones,
your blood doping type drugs,
those are tested for both out and in.
And those are tested 365 days a year in
competition.
And the definition of in competition
under our policy is six hours before the
weigh,
in to six hours after the fight.
During that period of time,
the drugs tested will be your drugs,
recreational drugs,
marijuana stimulants,
including cocaine,
other drugs.
So there's only really a,
you know,
a 48 hour so window that those will be
tested for those recreational drugs are
not tested for at a competition.
And the John Jones situation that was in
Nevada State Athletic Commission test,
uh,
they have the same rules at the time.
Drugs of abuse were to be tested for
only in competition.
My understand drugs of abuse,
you mean recreational drugs?
Racial drugs.
Sorry.
Yeah.
Some.
My understanding is somebody made a
mistake and check the box to do
recreational drugs and an attic
competition collection.
Oh,
so he wasn't supposed to be tested for
cocaine?
Correct.
Dave,
you know,
their policy was not to test for
cocaine,
marijuana,
they're stimulants out of competition.
It was a mistake of checking a box.
So when it turns out positive,
he's not punished for it because they
weren't supposed to test for it in the
first place.
That's my understanding.
Yep.
Okay.
Um,
you know,
it's unfortunate.
I don't like when any mistakes are made
like that.
I think,
you know,
even though it was Nevada state athletic
commission,
it taints the entire anti-doping,
you know,
arena.
I think anti-doping needs to be almost
perfect because again,
going back to that trust and credibility
factor,
regardless of who's doing it,
when they make mistakes and anti-doping
like a false positive.
I mean,
to me,
a false positive could never happened
because no one would ever trust anything
that's going on for a,
you know,
mistakes like that,
collection errors where the collectors
aren't going observing.
If you have holes in the system and it
gets out,
does it matter who's doing it?
I think it taints all of anti-doping and
so that's one of the reasons we went to
Usada is these guys have been in the
business longer than anybody else.
They're known as kind of the gold
standard entity and all the world they
are in that business.
They've been doing it for 15 years.
They know what all the pitfalls are and
they expect themselves to be perfect and
I think that's huge to lend that
credibility and trust to our athletes.
Nevada recently changed its levels of
acceptable use of marijuana.
They changed the levels of acceptable
and metabolites in the system.
What is it at now and what you were
discussing with me in Brazil,
you were saying that you essentially
would have to fight high in order to
test positive.
Yeah,
likely.
So Nevada adopted in terms of marijuana
with the water standard was,
and that's 150 nanograms per milliliter
a,
it probably doesn't mean much to most
people.
But to give you some perspective,
it used to be 15 nanograms per
milliliter.
So they've increased it 10 times,
10 times.
Exactly.
Um,
so you'd have to be under the influence
while you're fighting.
It's tough because that's,
as we're out educating,
the next question we get is,
hey,
how long would I,
if I was a chronic smoker,
how long would it have to be off it?
It's tough to say each individual varies
in terms of how they metabolize the fat
content on your body may store it
longer.
So we can't give our athletes guidance
like,
hey,
if you do it a week out or two days out,
you're fine.
I'm the only thing we can give them is
just kind of what statistics have borne
out.
Um,
you sought as tested all their Olympic
athletes.
Thousands now under this standard of 150
milligrams per milliliter over the last
couple of years.
They've had very few positive tests.
Maybe,
you know,
a couple.
Then along comes Nick Diaz
was under 150 nanogram per milliliter.
Stays at that point he was under,
but he's still tested positive.
He was over.
That was over when,
I mean Andrea,
he fell under.
Oh,
that standard.
So what was,
what was his test results?
I don't know specifically what it was.
Other than that,
it would have been over 150.
So he essentially fought high.
Probably respect.
Imagine that you're not just fighting
Anderson Silva.
You fighting them while you're stoned.
Damn.
Nick Diaz is a beast.
I mean,
I don't advise it,
but I respect it kinda crazy though,
right?
That he could a fight in the UFC in the
main event like that.
Yeah.
I don't know.
I was uh,
I was a basketball player in college
basketball player and uh,
you know,
when I played,
I had guys on my team that will get
stone before practice.
I'm dominate practice.
Yeah.
People love it.
A Jujitsu to Jujitsu.
It's a huge part of the Jujitsu world.
So many guys like you go to a lot of
Jujitsu schools and you'll see the
parking lot before,
but he goes into train.
Guys are smoking pot.
It's very,
very common because they feel like it
puts them in a zone.
My own personal experience I feel like
it does puts me in a,
in a zone.
It makes me understand the techniques
better because you look more of a
sensitivity to training.
Well,
how about in the MMA world because
you're worried about so many different
things.
A strike a take that you got so many
things to worry about.
I mean,
do you find that you're focusing in on
this one thing and you're not paying
attention to?
No,
no,
no.
Unless you're not ready.
This is.
Yeah.
What
I find,
I find that it's not that good for
learning things.
I find that when you're learning
something,
especially like if you're drilling
I find drilling is better done sober.
Like I'm better off at learning things
sober,
but once something is committed to my
nervous system,
once I understand how to do the move,
like there's certain positions,
there are certain positions that did
just fall into the way a Eddie Bravo is,
describes it best.
I love this analogy.
It's like,
you know when you tie your shoes,
you don't even think about it.
You just wish you just tie your shoes
because you've tied your shoes every day
for your whole life and it just becomes
natural.
There are certain positions where you
find yourself sinking into submission.
You don't even know what's happening
until you've done it because you've done
it so many times in drills that it just
becomes automatic.
Those are enhanced by marijuana,
but the learning part,
I feel like sometimes you don't get all
the finer details,
but maybe that's me.
Yeah.
I think there's also the possibility
that everybody has their own different
way of experiencing marijuana.
The biodiversity aspect of human beings.
It's.
Some people just don't like it at all.
I have friends that just can't do it.
They'll smoke a little pot and like,
fuck.
They just hate,
it freaks them out,
they don't like doing anything on it.
And then other people,
they like doing everything on it.
So I don't know.
I don't know what other folks feel,
but for me I feel like I learn things
better when I'm not high,
but I feel like once I'm,
once I understand
something,
it just become,
it's like a second nature thing,
then I feel like I'm more tuned in if
that makes any sense.
That's interesting because there's the
argument out there from a lot like why
is that even band?
That's not.
How is marijuana performance enhancing?
So it's interesting to hear you say
that.
I think it can be a performance
enhancing drug.
I really do.
Oh,
how bout,
how bout deadening pits obviously used
for pain relief.
So what do you think about it?
Could mask pain?
Certainly could.
It's certainly possible.
It's definitely not even,
it's not baseline.
You're not,
you're not sober.
So the,
the idea that anything that you could
use that could possibly give you an
advantage,
I just know it gives you an advantage.
Uses Jujitsu.
I know it does.
I know so many guys use it,
so many guys roll with it like big name
guys that that are high level Jujitsu
competitors.
They train high every time and they love
it and I just think you can't ignore
that.
I think that it's quite possible that
there's an advantage to using it and
then the pain relief aspect of it.
Look,
you can't fight on pain pills or and if
you,
if there was a pain blocker that allowed
you to not feel impacts of strikes and
he just went out there and fought and
dealt with the consequences tomorrow
when it wore off,
that would be illegal for sure.
Well,
marijuana is absolutely used to help
people with pain management.
Absolutely.
So I don't think it should be legal to
compete with.
I just think I.
I think there's too many possibilities.
I also don't think a lot of testing has
been done on the performance enhancing
aspects of marijuana,
but what has been revealed recently is
the benefits that ultra marathon runners
experience with and marijuana that they
can push through better put their mind
in a different place and not.
Yeah.
I took this on the hours and hours of
monotony and I don't think you can
ignore that.
I think,
uh,
I think that's certainly something that
should be considered and if you're going
to ban a lot of different things,
obviously I liked marijuana.
I'm an enthusiastic,
but I think that there's,
there's absolutely potential that it
could be a performance enhancing drug
and a lot of ways I was people mocked me
on that for a long time,
but now that this,
these new studies are coming out,
especially with a ultra marathon
runners,
I feel vindicated.
I feel vindicated for you.
Thank you.
Um,
is there anything else we should cover?
We pretty much nailed almost everything,
the comprehensive aspect of the drug
testing policy.
The randomness,
uh,
I believe the top athletes are going to
be tested five times a year randomly.
So it's going.
I,
that's,
I think if you look the average with our
population versus how many tests that
were contracted to do or that you saw
this contractor to do with us,
um,
it'll average to that.
But you know,
again,
everybody will be able to go on and see
starting soon here,
who's tested by name,
how many times,
and you're not going to see across the
board,
five for everybody.
Likely you're going to see 10 or a dozen
per year for some people.
Really.
Maybe two or three.
And is there a.
sorry,
it's not random testing.
It's intelligent testing.
You saw it as not going to say hey,
we're going to roll the dice and whoever
comes up,
they're going to look at everything from
tips they may get.
How they'll even look at physical
appearances of athletes.
You know,
does this athlete pass kind of the
physical appearance,
smell tests?
And if they don't,
hey maybe we need to test that person a
little bit more.
Physical appearance,
smell,
test.
Really.
So like,
like what would you like?
You look at a guy and you go,
man,
that guy just looks juiced.
He looks different.
One,
you've seen it.
Yeah,
but I don't know man.
I mean,
I've seen it on guys that have tested
negative and I've seen guys that have
been accused of things,
but they've tested negative every time.
I agree.
I agree with Dos Anjos,
heartfelt dos Anjos was a UFC
lightweight champion when he beat Pettis
and he beat Pettis in such a convincing
way.
Boy,
there were so many people accusing that
guy and being on performance enhancing
drugs.
But if you look at his body over the
years really hasn't varied that much,
a little bit from the first time he was
in the UFC,
but that was before he was on
comprehensive strength and conditioning
program.
You look at him like over the last few
years,
he's pretty consistent,
but yet once he wins the title,
everybody starts pointing fingers at
them.
And if you look at him like pull up a
picture of a Hoffeld dos Anjos UFC
lightweight champion of the world,
uh,
when he is fighting and when he's in
shape and he's fit.
Yeah.
He looks like,
like I would like to look like if you
were on steroids,
I would say that people would take
steroids if they could look like this
guy.
Does he pass the smell test?
Like see,
see if you could find a picture of him
where he's just looked jacked.
So there's a picture of him over in the
far left up there.
That's him after he beat Pettis.
But look there,
there's like,
no,
that looks just like an athlete,
but that looks okay.
That's a perfect one.
That's him.
When he was fighting pedes I believe.
Is that from the same fight?
Okay.
Look at that.
He's fucking shredded.
His six pack has a six pack.
I mean,
but not much different physically other
than like a little bit less body fat.
I mean he's a fucking Stud,
you know?
I mean that's why he's the champ.
Obviously there's a lot of hard work
that goes into that,
but when people look at him,
you know,
you say,
well,
that looks like a guy who,
if,
if someone didn't look like that and
then they took something and look like
that,
you would say,
well then the guys on steroids.
But if he always looks like that,
it's hard.
It's hard to.
I different.
There's outliers,
uh,
you know,
over those,
that 15 year law enforcement career I
had involved with all of these cases.
I mean,
I knew of many athletes who look like
they did,
who didn't release no evidence appeared
of it.
Many who didn't look like they did,
did.
Uh,
this is strictly,
you know,
another tool to be used.
It doesn't mean all the time that,
you know,
an athlete that doesn't pass the smell
test will test positive.
But a lot of the times it does,
is,
it,
means,
is a test doesn't
mean that person's all your positive
because you look like you did.
It's like,
hey,
you may be an extra test or two.
And if I was at athlete,
that was that freak,
I'd say,
Hey,
yeah man touched me more because people
were accusing me of it.
So that'll be cool.
At the end of the year,
everybody will look at my stats on the
webpage and see I was tested 10 times
and no positive test for me here.
So I'm hoping a lot of this is,
it's going to be,
you know,
in terms of the whereabouts program,
the amount of tests are athletes
getting,
it's going to be an inconvenience.
But I'm hoping that there's a lot of
acceptance and embracement of it that
like hell yeah,
not only is this the baddest sport in
the world were the toughest dude,
but we have the toughest anti-doping
program and bring it on.
I'm hoping that there's a lot of that in
the sentiment that I get is as we go out
and talk is a lot of that.
Um,
maybe it's lip service,
I don't know.
But,
um,
I would like to think that,
you know,
little certainly become that.
If it's not that right now,
it will certainly become that.
Is there any potential for manipulation
by opponents calling into hotlines,
accusing someone of something and having
them task,
giving false information,
false tips.
Sure.
There always is.
I can see her doing that.
I dealt with that all the time.
And in law enforcement,
right?
First Time,
first thing a tip comes in,
you have to evaluate who is this person?
Are they an x wide for an ex husband?
Okay.
Hey,
are they being sued by this?
You know,
evaluate that and you it do that too.
Um,
so does someone have to say who they are
when they give a tip or can they leave
anonymous today?
Can leave it anonymously.
Funnels conor Mcgregor.
I'd be calling that although hotline old
day.
I bet he just to fuck with them.
You know,
it's got to be guys that are going to do
that.
Right?
The brogue might give it away.
I don't know.
Yeah,
right.
Uh,
is full.
Can shape but a guy like like say dose
on Joe's,
you know,
like who has that appearance just looks
absolutely shredded and is beating
everybody is automatically going to be
people that point fingers at a guy like
that.
Right?
Potentially.
Sure.
Is there any other type of testing that
they're working on on,
on the pipeline that may perhaps be even
more effective than what they're doing
now?
Oh sure.
Yeah,
sure.
I mean,
again,
I'm not the scientist.
I don't get too far in the weeds when
the scientists and these conferences
break off the middle,
a little group or if ever I have a lot
of it goes over my head.
I don't understand what they're talking
about,
but I mean there's really,
really smart people that their
profession and life is dedicated to this
arena of anti-doping.
Figuring out what's out there,
figuring out if there's not a test for
something,
how to do it and develop it or some
super intelligent people on that mission
out there.
So I'd be concerned if I was using
anything that at some point someone's
not going to come up with a test for it
or tech.
What it was,
I would,
you know,
again,
part of the stress that's going to be
out there from someone who's still under
this program chooses to do something
that's going to be stressful.
Yeah.
I mean,
this is really the gold standard program
now,
isn't it?
I mean,
in professional sports.
Okay.
So there's no other professional sport
that has number one,
a truly independent authority
administering it.
And what that does is it shows you
there's not going to be any business
interest,
um,
in,
you know,
carrying out the program you saw doesn't
give a shit if it's our number one
earner,
if they test positive,
does that benefit them?
They don't care.
All they care about is clean sport.
There's gonna be no allegations of
favoritism.
You sought.
It doesn't care who the athlete is,
where,
where they live,
they're all about clean sport.
Again,
365 day a year or two.
Well,
first off,
no other professional sports have that
independent nature.
Olympic sports had that.
They have independent agencies,
but professional sports don't.
That's huge.
To begin with,
365 days a year.
Testing.
I mean,
you look at the other professional
sports here,
at least in the United States,
they can't say that I'm urine and blood
tests,
um,
at any point blood by the way,
we,
a lot of concerns from athletes like,
man,
how much blood he taken from me,
that's going to be a deterrent or that
could affect my performance.
If you take blood from me,
it's less than a tablespoon of blood
really.
So very little amount science shows will
have no effect whatsoever on your
performance even later that day.
Um,
you know,
the biological passports huge.
So even if you don't find a specific
drug,
you know,
we can go over time and look at abnormal
variances.
Um,
and so you throw all those things
together and you know,
in my experience,
both dealing with sports here in the US
and worldwide,
there's no other organization that
touches with this thing is now there's
some sports that you could argue really,
they just can't exist without
performance enhancing drugs.
Bodybuilding,
of course,
comes to the frontline.
That's the first one that everybody
thinks about.
If bodybuilding instituted something
like this to sport would change
radically overnight.
I mean you would see people shrink to
the point where they didn't.
They bear no resemblance to Dorian Yates
or green or any of these guys that were
in their prime that were just these
freaks that look,
they didn't even look like real people.
Yeah.
Not agree with that.
But what about pro football?
Like those guys are fucking gigantic.
How much of that is strength and
conditioning programs?
I mean,
do you know how much of that is that
they didn't have those strength and
conditioning programs in the sixties and
how much of it is steroids and growth
hormone and.
Yeah,
it's,
it's hard to say.
I mean they,
they do have,
they have,
and I know and I've worked with,
they're people who are instituting their
program.
Their program is not administered at a,
is not independently administered.
It's them.
It's in house,
in house.
So say if they have a star athlete,
the test positive,
they can kind of.
You don't know that.
I don't think that's happening because
you looked at,
you looked at some of the athletes that
have.
And,
uh,
you know,
I don't think that's happening,
but you know,
that question would always pose itself
because that is the Fox guarding the hen
house.
They're not nearly as comprehensive.
It's not.
And you know,
one thing that I've found in anti-doping
programs,
you could have the most solid program
all the way around.
If you have one little weakness in it.
The tiniest weakness could be a loophole
that you can drive a tractor trailer
through.
I'll give you a perfect example.
Say a program has everything that we
have a 365 day year testing.
Say it's even,
you know,
you sought administering it and say in
the collection process,
during the season,
the collector would call up somebody on
the team or in the organization the
night before and say,
hey,
I need a parking pass tomorrow.
Um,
to get in,
I'm going to be showing up that one
little phone call.
Despite all the strength,
comprehensive strength could be,
could be the weakness that would cause
everybody to run through that employee
is friends with somebody you know,
the players on the team knows who's hot
or not makes a call the night before.
Hey Man,
they're coming tomorrow.
Don't show up tomorrow to the
professional sports leagues.
I don't think they do have a three
strikes.
Whereabouts,
policy where if they're not there for a
certain day,
then that can be used against them.
Or if they're not there for that day as
a test said,
oh,
I'll just get that person later.
Um,
so little things like that can be
manipulated to,
to again,
drive a truck for.
What did you think about the vandelay
Silva situation for people not aware of
it?
Vandelay Silva,
they showed up for random drug test out
of competition.
Um,
he wasn't scheduled for a fight and just
bolted.
And when he bolted,
they gave him a lifetime suspension.
They said you're done.
Your career is over you.
You avoided a drug test.
Um,
what,
what did you think about that?
So first under our program,
well we had this whereabouts where you
get basically three strikes in a rolling
12 months and then there's a sanction
that's if you know they just can't
locate you or you didn't do a good
enough job or using complete your
whereabouts.
If a tester comes to test,
one of our athletes say out of Jim says,
Hey,
I'm here from Usada to test you and that
athlete says,
screw you and runs out the back door as
a sanction right there,
a penalty and potentially under our
system with aggravating circumstances
could be four years.
That may be an aggravating circumstance
where this guy or girl said,
screw you,
I'm not doing this thing and runs out
the back door.
So that's four years on the first time
his case that he had had one before and
he had a positive before.
That was the first one.
It was this first one.
Uh,
well he,
he obviously didn't test positive even
then because he didn't test it all.
But then he admitted that he was,
in his words,
he was taking some sort of a.
It wasn't a steroid,
I think it was a diuretic,
it was saying because he had fluid build
up something.
It didn't make any sense to me.
Um,
but like Aldo,
he avoided taking a drug test in Brazil.
Correct.
Uh,
I mean,
I don't know if that's the,
that he avoided it.
I mean,
there was obviously,
I think Nevada play,
you know,
publicly disclosed what was played out.
They sent a collector here from the
United States down there and showed up
at the gym.
They disputed whether or not.
Yeah.
Who knows what happened.
One thing,
you know,
I don't know exactly how everything went
down there.
One thing I can say is under our
program,
and that's one of the reasons we went to
Usada.
Usada needs to go to another country to
do a collection like that.
They reach out to the national authority
of that country so that when somebody
shows up on behalf of you saw or with
Usada out of gym,
you're not going to get an instance or
you know,
reasoning that,
hey,
we didn't know who this person was.
There'll be credentialed.
Every bone will know who they are.
There'll be a representative from that,
that nation there.
I think they tested,
although sample anyway,
if I'm correct.
And he tested negative,
is that true?
They did.
Ultimately,
I think it was the next day that he
provided a sample,
um,
and that did test negative,
but there was some issues about the day
before or sample wasn't provided,
um,
because because it went 24 hours and he
could have whatever he had could have
cleaned out of a system that is,
you know,
that would be a concern.
Sure.
What,
uh,
so they can test for human growth
hormone now too,
which was something that they couldn't
ask for for a long time.
They couldn't true.
And there's also another test that came
out for it,
um,
where they can run back a couple of
weeks.
It used to be with a blood test,
she would have had to detect it within
maybe 24 hours of its use.
Um,
there is now an isoform test,
which isn't necessarily for the drug
itself,
but kind of like with the biological
passport.
If you take growth hormone,
it will affect certain markers in you
that will last over time,
even if the drug is cleared your system,
so it gives anti-doping that ability to
reach back a couple of weeks and
determine if it was used.
So again,
an evolving tool that you know,
maybe some organization says,
Oh,
news tests two weeks,
we can call back all those frozen sample
that's go back and retest them and see
that maybe it wasn't within 24 hours an
athlete use but two weeks.
So that factor I think is always hanging
out there for somebody who chooses to
do,
to use the substances band.
Well Jeff,
thank you very much for coming on here
and then taking the time to explain all
this stuff and thank you very much for
this incredibly comprehensive effort to
clean up the sport.
I think it's awesome and I think what
you're doing is just.
It's very,
it's very,
it's very intriguing.
It's inspiring and I think ultimately
it's great for the sport.
Appreciate it.
Yeah.
He wants to say no,
I think I'm good,
man.
Thanks for having me on.
Thanks for the platform.
And Yeah,
look forward to seeing you at a,
an event soon.
Absolutely.
My pleasure,
Jeff Novitsky.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we'll be back tomorrow with Jeff Ross
and,
uh,
that's it.
Enjoy your day.
Thank you everybody.
Bye.
Two hours.
Thirty five minutes.