That story seems to show up.
So I'm flying them out after we called.
Okay.
I'm going to do a podcast and him which
subtitles in Spanish and I'm bringing
them up here on Friday.
Why?
Yeah,
my company to do it for me in Spanish
with subtitles.
And then I'm going to bring him up here
on Friday and we're going to have a
three way about Cuba.
Well it was like to rest on the whole
thing if you don't mind.
Well you mind so I'll do mine about
subtitles.
Justin at Barnard.
Yeah.
So no,
we will not clash with you dude.
The three of us together would be the
greatest podcast cause I could interpret
it and you would be,
would be,
uh,
it would be a real mma.
You could really talk to them about
under hooks and to Russia.
That's a fantastic,
the Cuban where they shipped them cause
they ship you off when you were a young
kid.
They did.
A lot of people don't know.
Yeah,
they look at you on that ain't go,
uh,
I looked at them.
You don't have a choice.
They look at you and they go do,
I said,
look,
try that on.
That's it.
Now.
Then they'd take her to a certain age
and that or the 80 to send you to
Nicaragua or Russia.
You train and that's why a lot of Cubans
that you docus because they'd go to rush
and learn judo.
Wow.
So he's going to tell you how they
shipped him off and they don't just tell
your mom like would take him tomorrow.
That's it.
It's always been interesting to me
because the Cubans and the Russians in
particular were always thought of as
being very technical.
Really.
The Russians,
Russians are super technical.
That was what a lot of people attributed
George Saint Pierre Success in
wrestling.
You know,
George didn't wrestle in college or in
high school,
uh,
but he trained with a bunch of Russian
nationals and Montreal and apparently
phenomenal wrestlers and they have this
incredible wrestling program.
Like when you see,
when you see Norma met off the way he
mauls people inside the octagon,
like what in the fuck?
Like that is like a,
a perfect example of that.
Like style of super hard,
super technical wrestling.
They're so good at it.
There's so many.
Did you see,
you know what you see Loma Chanko used
to be a wrestler is a video of La Loma
Chanko.
It looks like he's doing sambo.
It looks like he's got a like a gian and
it's him and some other cat and he's
like 11 years old or something like
that.
So his father put him in everything.
His father made him.
Do you know Loma Chanko is?
Yes.
One of the best boxers ever.
Like literally one of the most
technically beautiful to watch boxers
it's ever lived.
But this guy,
he used to wrestle too.
Like is this is a,
I don't think this is,
it is.
It does him.
Okay.
Is this him wrestling with somebody?
Yeah,
this is one now.
Or he can still do this shit.
This is like pretty recent.
Like he showed some of his wrestling
moves,
but the other one was him when he was a
little boy.
Like he's really tactical man.
He knows how to wrestle.
This is legit.
Like when you see the way he's moving
his body,
he's not faking that.
He's done that a bunch of times and
yeah,
this is,
this is one when he's a little kid,
man,
it's crazy.
It says Greco Roman wrestling,
but they're wearing a geek,
so I'm not exactly sure what it is,
but he gets his kid and a gets behind
them and send them for a ride.
So he was,
he's always been an amazing athlete,
like an area.
I think there's,
there's something to that.
There's something to,
his father had an idea to crazy ideas.
His father took him out of boxing and
put them in a dance for like several
years.
Uh,
Ukrainian traditional dance style.
Apparently they were talking about it on
one of those hbo shows for like four
years,
I think it was the hbo show,
but for four years,
I think he just danced.
You imagined that his father's like,
you want to learn how to box,
you got to dance and now nobody's got
footwork.
If you've seen him,
Joey,
you've seen like his highlight reel.
It's insane.
Jamie,
pull up.
A woman will highlight reel because my
daughter goes to ballet and 80% of the
clashes Russia,
so I was thinking about it.
Yes,
that was watching the movements,
the last parade movement.
I'm like,
Jesus Christ.
If people did ballet and I was thinking
the GSP,
like you know me,
I'm like pre probably fucking does
ballet give them any wood bats would be,
it's great footwork.
This guy is the wizard or footwork.
It's crazy because he was like right in
front of you,
but he's one step ahead of you at every
turn.
Like he knows what you're going to do.
Right.
While you're doing it,
he's moving in a way that you can't
move.
He's in front of you and then he's not.
It's crazy.
Like he's the one of the most technical
boxers I've ever seen and it just an
amazing stylistic achievement like what
he can do with his body.
His style is totally unique.
I mean every,
but a lot of guys have done it.
A lot of guys that moved in and out.
A lot of guys have done it,
but he's doing it and it's such a high
level,
such a high level that it makes people
confused.
Guys quit in their corner that like what
in the fuck?
And I really think a lot of it probably
had to do with his father's cross
training and it particularly with the
dance,
I mean think about how effortlessly he
goes,
like steps around guys.
I mean he's got some incredible control
of his feet,
but it makes sense that like you would
learn how to move your feet in a
specific way that weren't the way you
weren't learned how to move your hands
in a specific way.
Right?
Like think about a guy like floyd
mayweather,
right?
His hand combinations with his upper
body.
There are so precise.
It's like that,
that,
that right?
But with his legs,
is he as precise as he asked?
Precise moving with his legs,
his,
his with his hands or his,
the 60% or 70% or 80% lama chanko is
probably po perfectly proportioned for
his style with his ability to move,
but also also his ability to box and hit
you.
Well,
he's got both things going on at the
same time with next level angles.
So that's what I was saying.
Fuck.
When you're younger in Cuba,
they picked you.
It's not like you
wake up and go,
I want to be a wrestling.
No,
they look at you and go,
you look like he could go,
go wrestle.
And like what I was hearing back from
them in the early seventies it was like
they just took you away from your family
that and that was part of your training.
You know your,
then they put you in there.
Go.
We had no,
you know where you train and like there
aren't me.
Have you talked to y'all about this turn
you well yeah,
like no.
We've discussed what this thing is.
I already have graphics on the podcast,
so I figured that I put them up and
we'll do a podcast in Spanish with
fucking subtitles.
Like an English film,
like a,
like a Giulini movie,
whatever one of those movies.
People think that unique.
Okay.
You have it because his,
his English is too rough for me and I
know what he's trying to say and the
frustration in his face.
I love you.
[inaudible] being so now he did a tape
the other day of him in Cuba waiting for
Biz,
being in Cuba.
Went to Cuba.
No Romero's back.
See if he's fine,
but what is the,
see if you can find he's,
he's nuts.
He's nuts.
He's fighting rockhold now,
which is a tremendous ride on the test.
Right?
That's a crazy fight.
That's a crazy fairing.
Good fight.
It's very good fight.
Rockhold when he's on,
it's super dangerous.
You know when the rockhold made one slip
up against Bisping,
but you know,
fair play to Biz,
Bang.
He,
he came into that fight regardless of
where anybody ranked him,
you know,
like how,
how they felt.
His chances were he came in swinging.
He has like,
I think he had like 11 days notice,
something like that.
What was,
how many,
how many days notice that Michael
bisbing get when he fought Luke
rockhold?
I want to say it was something crazy
low.
It wasn't much time.
You know,
route clock.
Luke rockhold is very,
very good.
He's a beach.
Very,
very good.
His top game.
Let me tell you something.
I think when he fought Michael Bisman,
I'm not going to lie to you.
I think his focus was a little off,
maybe two in a way.
I think he was dating rockstars and
hanging out in Hollywood.
I think he's not dating or whatever
anymore.
Now he's just fucking,
he thought when he beat a branch,
he looked great.
But his Jujitsu is great.
He has great cakes.
He's great with his hands,
his movement,
him against your,
well,
it's going to be interesting.
Let's skip vicious kicks,
man.
No,
he's four and he's won,
right?
So Luke Rock robot is number one and one
of the five I believe so.
I think this Joel [inaudible] is a four.
Yeah,
it's a great fight.
And then you got jocker raised back in
the mix.
You know what's crazy like I always say
to you like,
oh,
I don't mean to pronounce his name
wrong,
and then some guy out,
right?
Like when he fought steel picking Dano
whom God on when he fought my man.
Immigrant mentality.
Like a motherfucker.
Yeah,
he hits hard and all that stuff like
that.
But now that dude still going to be more
dangerous.
Now he's going to fucking take that
loss.
Batman man fucking machines.
You got to think how crazy it is that he
went from a guy who
was homeless too,
five years later fighting for the
heavyweight title.
This is like a total amount of training,
five years of elementary training,
fighting for the heavyweight title,
and he's the favorite.
He's the favorite over geyser.
He defended it twice.
I mean,
it's crazy.
That's how talented he is.
That's how terrifying is.
That's how special he is.
But Oh,
a loss like that to a guide like that,
like to a real champ like Steve Bay,
if that,
what's you realize where the top of the
game is?
There's another,
there's a few more things to learn.
There's a lot more days to get in and
training,
but that guy has just begun.
He's just began five years ago.
He didn't know shit.
He's way better now than he was two
fights ago.
Yeah,
I see the difference.
I see the difference in the way he
moves.
When he fought overeem,
it was since significantly different
than when I saw him in his first and
second fights is first,
second fights.
He was very good.
It's very,
but just insanely strong.
He would hit guys with these
combinations and clean technique to
matt.
He's like,
he's not just a physically strong guy.
He's also very smart because he's
learning to do everything mechanically.
Very good.
It's not like a guy who's only been
striking for like three or four years,
so they look a little tight and weird,
but they can,
if they land,
they've got a lot of power.
Nah Man,
everything is clean.
Like you said,
some big of those trenches,
Jack.
Oh Dude.
That type of work gets you a tough
stuff.
He's just a special athlete.
And if he keeps going,
man,
I mean sh boy,
that guy learning more to think about
how little you learn in five years.
Most of these guys have way more time in
way more time in wrestling,
way more time in kickboxing.
The average guy,
by time it gets to the UFC,
I would like to know what the number is
like how many years of training and
competing they have,
but it's gotta be more than two.
Like he was.
He was like right in the UFC and
smashing people.
It's his amazing story,
man.
It's an amazing story and for a lot of
people,
the way it ended is a good lesson for
martial artists.
It's a good lesson.
See what,
even if you weren't in Gando Fan,
you're bummed out that he lost.
I appreciate that.
I'm going in gone who fan?
Fan Too,
but I'm more of a fan of mixed martial
arts.
I,
I'm a,
I'm a fan of an honest,
like extreme,
like I wanna I want to know what it is.
Like what,
what is this like?
What's this?
What's this contest right here?
What's,
what's actually going on here.
What's going on here is phenomenal
athletic talent,
massive potential,
like Super Alpha athlete versus one of
the toughest guys ever who's been in the
game longer.
Who knows more.
He's wrestled.
He's been fighting way more.
He's been in the trenches way more
times.
He said dig deep.
He knows what it's like to be really
hurt and tired in a fight.
She,
I appreciate the strategy of like,
how do you go in to fight a guy like
perfect.
It was like rocky
against Mr T.
Yeah,
that's what exactly it was like.
So it was like heart and fucking a
little smart.
Stay away from that punch.
It had to be,
and I,
I haven't watched the full fight,
you know,
I was working then I'm on fucking stage.
My brother getting hit by Francis and
gone and we put mma gloves night.
Worst thing that can do a person,
he's terrifying and steep.
Bang,
got cracked multiple times and not
fight.
It sound like he didn't get hit.
He got cracked,
but he had made up his mind.
He was going nowhere.
He knew what to do.
He'd been there before.
That's like,
that's an incredible lesson,
which is for the overall s the sport for
the,
for mixed martial arts in general.
And the lesson is like,
he figured out like he had like the
craziest end of video game character
ever.
Right?
And God,
I was like the big,
like the big boss in a video game that
like fuck,
I got to fly.
I got to play against this guy that's in
Gansu and steep a figured out how to
beat him being 20 plus pounds lighter
than them.
No Way.
You know,
way less intimidating in terms of his
physical presence.
All those tpa,
it's pretty fucking intimidating.
But in Ghana was so intimidating.
He's so next level two 65 natural giant,
crazy frame.
You look at people when you're next to
steep it.
That's when you realize how big is too
big.
Fell on TV,
you know,
look that big when you're next to him
and be like,
this guy's a big fuck.
He's a big function.
You're walking around his asset is his
mind though.
Yes.
Come on.
Been fucking talked about the wikipedia
page dog.
I told you the immigrant mentality with
media page,
listen,
American ingenuity is fucking brilliant.
And with the immigrant mentality mix,
like let's say you're still an American,
but it that could have called you steve.
No,
you could still call them steep and Mayo
chick to remember where the fuck you
came from.
You understand me?
His father came.
That's really a win like that.
You know it was on,
I almost called you joe.
I hate calling you.
I almost called you to go.
When was the last time you watched bronx
tale?
Oh,
you know what?
It's going on all week.
I watched it a year ago with,
he fucking finds him with the guns and
he starts smacking the kids in the
neighborhood.
I still remember people's parents
smacking kids in the,
but wow.
Like people's parents come in and go,
what the fuck are you guys doing it?
Get the fuck home man.
I'm like,
won't kick.
Got a kick to the stomach.
And the father punched the other kid and
nobody was said Dick,
nobody set deck Dick.
No,
like I'm watching this Brian with a
biker scene.
What was the lab like?
I,
I haven't watched Bronx town 20 years.
It's on AMC at six 30 and they locked
the door and that you can't leave.
He's eaten his shit and lost to the
here's the bikes and shit and he walks
over.
Oh,
okay,
nice.
Like a gentleman.
Yeah,
no problem Ben.
You know what I'm saying?
They do a thing and he walks up to the,
I got to leave now you can't leave.
And the collage euro,
like that guy named son collage or
row who would do something like that.
That means you,
you want your son to have the immigrant
mentality,
but when they throw that beat of the
bike,
it's,
it's a true story.
That's a true,
true story.
I would listen in the 60s you couldn't
have long and walk around the Bronx.
It just wasn't accent really.
Yeah.
That,
that hippy shit that,
that,
that did happen in the Bronx.
And so what if like a hippie was walking
through the Bronx,
they called you dirty hair day,
insulted you.
They called you a bunch of shit and then
they drew a beating on you.
And it's hysterical because that scene
is so accurate because after the adults
drew have beaten on you,
then the May book kids chased you like
the young kids with sticks and that's
what we do.
Wow.
You know,
like the little guys would chase you and
once you were beat up and they took all
your money,
it's a classic scene.
I was thinking about that and I'm like,
actually I got to call Joe and ask him
one last time.
Look at this.
Look how bad to the bone that rather he
stole with Joe.
Whether he stole the scene or look at
this,
you go away.
I'm your man is Thomas.
You got to leave.
But I just tell him him so I think
green.
That's it.
We'll be on way looking for trouble.
I appreciate it.
How can all this come together?
So got them around,
right?
Yeah.
Oh,
this is a great scene,
but the scene,
it's a perfect song,
right?
Perfect song.
When he walks in,
it's stretching the beginning to the
goon.
Go Watch it.
Is this going to get us kicked off of
you?
No,
no,
no.
As long as we talk over it.
Okay.
This is it right here.
You again.
Oh,
nice.
I'll tell you what the fuck we leave.
Watch the bites.
Man.
Shuts the door.
I will never forget the look on their
face to face just dropped all their
courage and strength was trained right
from their bodies.
Got a reputation for breaking a boys.
What?
They knew that they made a fatal mistake
this time they walked into the roll bar.
This is real Joe Rogan.
This was 1968 fucking Jeroma have urge
shit.
So this is a true story.
Jesus Christ.
This scene was fucking brutal.
This is it.
This was one.
This was allowed.
Two.
This is craziness,
Bro.
This was,
this was the bronx in 68 69 and the
neighborhood,
you know like the enabled would tie
hurry up to cops or people on the third
floor with Tay.
We could see the cops from the third
floor.
We could see the bolts coming down the
street.
You're like the whole neighborhood was
in on it.
You know what's interesting to me,
like this is all from immigrants,
right?
Yes.
It's all this was what they had to do
because of not,
but there's also a movie is about him
dating a black girl.
Right.
And what that meant that the say I
forgot how good this movie was.
This movie's brilliant.
Yeah.
Shout out to Frankie Renzulli.
Um,
this movie's a genius movie.
Look at this.
Watch my car.
You know.
Chazz Palminteri is great and it's
fucking good.
This is it.
This was it.
I forgot how good this is.
Now.
See the young guys now that's us.
Right?
Well,
let's see what's going on now.
You take this guy and we would fuck him
up though.
There's like animals.
Stop to think about it.
This is it.
This is how you were Italian immigrants.
Spanish immigrants.
Oh my God.
This is crazy.
Crazy.
When you think about there,
one generation removed from people came
off a boat.
Let me tell you what the other side of
this here,
here's the other side.
Like,
all right.
The big thing was as we were,
we came to move here.
I remember that when he would come to
the store,
Frank Stahl,
Mike Star was your friend and he would
come to the store and there was a big
room with that.
Chaz stole these stories from him and
put this together and there was like
this little war going on,
but not from Frankie.
Rental ranking ritual is the other
gentleman.
There was somebody else that was just,
that turned out to be some believe very
big.
And uh,
but there's a story one time that a bike
dude,
old gravano money and Gravana was
hitting him and when he fell off the
sidewalk and broke his leg,
so gravano one night went out and
fucking did something like this.
I'm like with 20 guys,
they beat up a bike.
I don't know how true it was,
but I still remember being five.
Like if I could think,
if you could put,
hit me with truth serum,
I,
I could go back to being 1968,
1969 in the bronx.
My daughter's five and my mother would
send me from the dry cleaner that she
owned to the corner where there was an
place that had slices and Italian ice
and shit like that.
Right.
Like I was allowed to walk to the corner
at mercy on Treemont Avenue.
Like I think about,
I was looking at my daughter when I was
watching Bronx.
I'm going,
I I,
how different as time change.
Like I was allowed to go to a liquor
store with a note and get my mother
Marlboro reds and bring them back in
that neighborhood.
We didn't live there.
My mother just had the dry,
clean it up.
There was a bookie numbers joint.
That's why we had the dry cleaning.
We were partners on the dry cleaner.
You didn't know that?
No.
That's why I got scars on my face.
I got bit by a German shepherd as a kid.
Those three by one of the eyes.
That's what we did when we came from
Cuba.
I lived in two oh five west 88th street
and after my father died,
my mother had a dry cleaner and that's
what we were up.
We were up in Jerome Avenue and Treemont
and grand concourse and we had a dry
cleaner and every,
every weekend I would go up there and I
would sit there with the fucking,
I learned how to dry clean and they had
black Mike Black.
Mike was the guy that I ended
everything,
but he made the best spaghetti in the
bronx.
So even the Italians came to he black.
Mike Spaghetti.
Really?
Yeah.
This was a,
I knew all that shit when I was a kid
because when you have a numbers
operation,
uh,
you have to keep moving it around.
The cops can't,
so you have to every three or four,
we should have to move it around
explaining numbers to people don't know
what the numbers is.
A,
the Parimutuel,
it's a,
the last three numbers of the
Parimutuel,
the track,
which is the amount of track made for
the day,
soak them track,
made six hundred and eighty six thousand
four hundred eighty two thousand dollars
a number for the day is for 82 and it
comes out as the Brooklyn number.
So there's three numbers a day.
There's Brooklyn,
the Bronx and New Jersey,
but what happened was that was a big
business until the 80s till the lotto
came out and the lotto cut that in half,
but before that,
that was all put it a little different.
Little different immigrant neighborhoods
all over New York City because as
immigrants will one hope.
Yeah,
we know we want that money to get that
refrigerator and the stove and shit like
that.
It's such a weird thing that they would
gamble.
Just $2 a day.
Remember $2 a day when George thousand
dollars yeah,
I can do a lot in 1975 with $1,000
with two kids.
My grandmother was obsessed with the
numbers.
Yeah,
she was obsessed and she would always
have like a number in her head that she
thought it was going to be and it was
like one off or something like that.
It was like these stories she would tell
you.
What would you say to,
what can I say?
I was like five.
I just remember it very distinctly.
My grandmother went to jail for running
numbers in New Jersey.
She wouldn't,
she wouldn't rat him out.
So they put her in jail.
So she made sweaters,
gave sweaters to the guards.
Mrs D,
She's the nicest lady.
Did you feel that your grandmother had
done time?
What did you think?
We didn't find out until I was probably
like,
I wonder when I found out,
I think maybe I found out my teenage
years and I was like,
why?
What the fuck people are good.
It's the year where is a,
I don't want to say my grandma's name
out a respect,
but people would say,
you know,
where is she?
Oh,
she went to visit her,
her cousin,
her.
She wants to see her aunt and she was,
you know,
choosing the pokey for like six months.
I forget how much time it was,
but every time we'd go over there it was
like some new excuse.
See It in New Jersey then put you in New
Jersey.
They put you in jail for Gatling is
bigger accident.
They don't give you a ticket.
You know,
they would give you like a ticket and
shit in those days.
I don't know what it's like now.
This fucking the employee in jail for
weed down in New York City.
I don't fucking know.
My grandmother was one of the few people
I've ever known where I legitimately
thought they had intuition.
She has weird intuition.
She would do things.
It's real weird.
Like when my mother was a kid,
it was a rainstorm.
It was like real bad rain storm and for
whatever reason my grandmother decided
to wake my mother up,
take her out of her bed and bring her
downstairs,
some crazy hunched.
She had the ceilings,
claps like right above the bed where my
mom was sleeping.
So like pieces of,
you know,
it wasn't a lot,
it was just chunks of plaster.
But like,
you know,
three or four pretty significant pieces
of plaster fell off of the ceiling.
It was rain came through with the whole
deal,
like the ceiling game out.
Somehow or another,
she had this idea in her head and it
could be because she knew that the
ceiling was fucked up and she knew it
was raining hard.
It was probably going to give in any way
or she might've had an intuition and my
fault.
Everyone was always convinced it was
intuition.
Everyone's always convinced like she's
looks a little bit psychic.
It was always weird.
It was always weird around there.
She brought her monkey.
She had a month in New Jersey.
Yes,
in north New Jersey.
She had a monkey named Chichi and cheat
you everybody,
but my grandma,
my grandfather made it keep the monkey
in the attic.
Yo.
My grandma was crazy.
She had a monkey would open up packages
a gum and chew gum.
How or where the fuck she got it from
him?
I'm telling you,
my grandma was crazy.
Italian people had butches and they'd
get you anything.
She can't look game pigeon.
She kept a monkey in the house,
man.
Do you understand what crazy then you
remember monkey?
Yes.
Chichi.
The monkey's name is cheesy bites you
now.
He never bit me,
but he bit my sister.
You Bet my sister.
Yeah.
Cheat.
You would fuck you up.
I think he bit my sister.
I think he tried to bite my sister.
I think it was one of those things they
might have bit my cousin some when our
family got pit ever touched him.
I couldn't even see.
I know Italian side.
Yeah.
That night she was crazy and once you
give,
no disrespect,
but once you get those lunar texts,
that option that they do have intuition,
you're fucking done.
They start giving you the fish eyes,
zoot don't do shit.
You got to listen to all her cooking was
from another planet.
It's from another planet.
It was like pure immigrant cooking.
Like the pasta that was design.
Yeah.
You just sit there and go,
holy shit just perfect.
Just knew exactly what supposed to be in
there.
She baked her own,
like she would make her own macaroni,
should make our own Ravioli.
She would stuff her own Ravioli.
She'd be out there rolling and flatten
out flour and shit,
throwing the flower on top of,
flatten it out.
She was a wizard though.
Usually get a monkey,
call it cheating.
It's gotta respect a little monkey and
keep her head though.
Either respectful for grandma.
My grandma was a special lady.
She was powerful.
Once you give those,
listen,
when I was a kid,
man,
I went to my buddy's judo school.
I didn't join.
I just went down there to see what it
was like and it was hidden in union
city.
It was on seventh street,
but I knew that my step dad played cards
on ninth street on Wednesdays.
Wow.
Okay.
I knew my stepdad played cards down
there.
They played baccarat.
Okay.
And they'd gamble in this little club
and I had to be maybe 10 but because I
grew up,
how I grew up with the numbers,
I always had my eyes out as a kid.
When I went to judo,
that man at the end,
I got in the bus to go back and I
noticed unmarked police cars and I went
home that night and look bro,
you know,
made dog get Christie love used to be a
show on ABC about a black chick that new
martial arts and tried to capitalize on
it with a system.
And she was good looking with an Afro
when she was a cop that she'd come in
and do karate moves on Wednesday nights
at nine or 10 o'clock and you caught me
at home watching get Kristy Le and I'll
never forget that my stepdad was leaving
that night.
And for some reason,
I know you're going to play it back home
after that.
And they looked at me,
he was getting dressed a suit on.
You have like the billy bad suit on and
shit,
you're going to play cards or five men,
why are you getting dressed to the
nines?
And I said to him,
I said,
hey man,
today I went down there to go to Martins
judo school and I saw a bunch of them
marked cards down there.
If I was you,
I wouldn't go out to that.
And He fucking just looked at me.
He said,
I love you.
And he walked down the stairs,
he got in the car,
started it,
opened the garage bro.
And 10 minutes later I heard the car
turned off in the garage close and they
came up and he goes,
I think you're right.
And he made Sundays for me and him and
next morning and that card place,
I got rid of that.
So now they would listen to me on the
housing.
I had these fucking moron,
my spouse.
But you want me to tell you what else I
did?
Joe Rogan,
like this is me and like me and my
stepdad had this weird relationship.
I got to an age where I wanted my mother
from myself.
You know what the feeling is dry on when
we've all gone through it.
When you lose a dad and your mom
remarries that comes up a day that he's
not going to tell you what's going on
anymore.
And you know what?
I just want you to know that I,
I'm the mother fucker that runs this
joint.
You might be sleeping with my mum,
but I run this motherfucker.
So once I gave him that advice,
like it really for a while,
then him and I would go in a float.
I kept stealing his coins from the
center.
He had this sand Laszlo thing and that
was everything to him.
So he had this big bottle of like scotch
that was empty and he would put silver
dollars in there and I would steal them.
And from time to time he would come home
and go,
that bottle's looking like somebody's
stealing my car.
I destroyed his mind for you because he
was a very particular man.
So he had different bundles of,
but I gotta tell you something,
I respect them today because I saw him
get out of the joint and I show what he
did with bookmaking and how he became
part of,
it's on a butcher shop.
I started businesses,
he started different businesses.
So,
uh,
after I saved this that night with the
backer,
rocky would listen to me.
And then one day I went and I signed up
for biddy basketball and union city.
And they used to give,
you know,
like now if you sign your kid up,
you got to pay any dollars.
In those days you just show up on an
address and they gave you a tee shirt.
They put you on the team and they gave
me a number.
They said,
like,
you didn't say department of recreation.
And it was a purple shirt.
My number was 57 I walked into the house
and he goes,
what do you got there?
And I go,
Oh,
I joined the basketball thing and he
goes,
what number is he goes,
57 Cubans again,
a very superstitious 57 he goes,
put a number on that.
And he picked up the phone.
I go five.
He called some guy and he goes,
give me five 57 for $10 guess what
happened?
Joe Rug.
What happened?
The number came up.
No,
I really had them under my spell.
Right.
The Fuck Anissa had this motherfucker at
the age of 12 so he wouldn't listen to
me.
How old was the guy?
My step father Juan at the time was 47
did not drink gig,
did not drink,
did not do drugs.
Carry the straight razor.
Joe Rogan straight razor to cut people
in.
Yeah,
and he used to cut.
He used to web carpenter pants with the
straight raise.
At this point,
the guy had money.
He would have a gold chain.
He'd wear a Chinese tee shirt,
which a lot of people do not know what
it is.
That's what real pimps were.
That silk and made shirts from China
that you went and they have three little
buttons.
When when you were real motherfucking
Spec,
you cut those buttons and you get your
initials and you put them in gold with
diamonds in it.
That's how spics ran in those days.
Well,
and uh,
once I had them there,
Joe Rogan,
I had him,
he trusted me,
he trusted my eyes.
So one night we're in union city and I
fucking went somewhere.
The walk back,
there's a place called pastoral music
and there was next to the new moon
Chinese restaurant.
And I show a bunch of unmarked cars and
I never forget that.
I went back to the bar and then he'd go
out and I told him,
I said,
dog,
I saw three on my,
like I had him and I seen,
I seen three on my cars up to corner.
He was very always scared of the phone,
even though he was a bookmaker,
he never used the phone.
Joe Rogan never used the phone.
And he would never have a conversation
close to a phone.
This is because he always felt he didn't
not like phones.
He did everything like a pigeon.
His,
he would write the numbers and the
little piece of paper real small and
fold them up and put him in his hat.
And if he ever saw cops,
he would just eat the piece of paper.
He didn't give a fuck.
He always had the piece of paper
somewhere close.
Sometimes you would put it in this ring.
This motherfucker was a savage dog.
Oh my God.
So that night the cops were going to
jump on us on the bar,
but it was for a drug thing.
It wasn't for him.
But when I went back,
I told him,
listen to cops are up the corner and me
and him,
he grabbed me by the hand and him and I
walked from 29th in Bergen Line,
the 58th and Bergen line down the Hudson
telling different borrowers that there
was going to be a raid.
Like that's how are untrustworthy.
He was a phones.
And by the time we got back to the bar,
we got raided and there was a dude in,
his name was Monina.
Right.
Monina is those,
uh,
those crazy Cubans that Albert Albacore
Monina means good man.
Like y'all my bra.
Yeah,
the albacore there.
They don't need pussy and dental.
He puts it here and they fucking,
you can't fuck around with animals
because of Saint Lazarus.
Know that show.
They have a very specific religion.
They have their ma,
it's a manhood.
They were longshoremen and Cuba and they
maintain order.
So we have a fuck up.
They'd come over and fuck you up there.
But he had a wig.
I'll never forget this.
The Guy Monina had a wig and the cops
were there and they threw him.
And I'm like,
12 dog.
I'm up against the wall.
This search and made through that search
and my step dad,
they got my mom and they went to Monina
and they searched him and the cop looked
at his work and he goes to check the wig
and they pulled the wig off and he had a
little aluminum foil weed,
cocaine.
Oh my God.
That's hilarious.
That whole bookmaking numbers world is
fucking nuts that I grew up in.
I love it.
Still.
I love,
I wonder what it's like that there's no
business in it.
It's unfortunate because you think about
how many bets are placed.
Oh,
Jesus Christ.
I mean,
there's so much money,
so much money out there.
People love to gamble fucking games when
games are on.
People love to gamble.
What do you think is spent this weekend,
Jamie?
Come on.
[inaudible] question Joey.
Like why is that a problem?
Like what?
What?
What is what's helping us by letting
them regulate that shit.
Like why?
Why does that happen?
Why do you have to have a license to
gamble?
Why?
No,
if you think someone's not paying their
taxes and you can prove it,
is it because it's money?
It's cash that's been thrown around
mostly like what?
Why is it an issue?
The government's got not getting their
piece.
It seems ridiculous that grown adults
could tell other grown adults that can't
gamble,
but you can hear but you can't there.
Oh,
gambling is one of those things like
legalization of marijuana,
legalization of fucking cocaine lately.
Lization of anything,
Bro.
You know what?
There's going to be fucking winners and
there's going to be fucking losers.
My friends,
two years ago,
Connecticut did,
uh,
did an expo say on 60 minutes about
women who have just lost death.
Fucking mine's gambling.
I don't know.
He can sudden because they installed,
no,
no disrespect the Mohican Sun at Casino
Industries,
they installed these type of slot
machines that could just fuck what your
mind what?
So these women were going down there and
losing fucking mortgages.
Houses.
You know,
I was like a John Waters movie,
the dog and that dog.
It was just something that,
listen,
listen.
Let me go.
Let's go.
Let's get something out of the way here.
The biggest percentage of degenerate
gamblers are usually women.
Let's look this fucking percentage up
here.
Women go fucking deep.
That's a fucking hole.
They don't give a fuck about nothing.
They,
they fucking play cards.
Women fucking bang it out.
Wow.
And they bang it out while you're at
work.
Joe Rogan while I'm at work.
They start with a horse.
Then they go to this.
You know those little promos they do,
and in Jersey,
what did they say when you know when
Atlantic City was Atlantic City,
you went to union city,
right?
You pay 15 bucks to get on a bus.
They gave you a coupon book and when you
get to Atlantic city,
they give it $15 in quarters back.
So that basically driving you to fucking
gamble and drive back.
I believe in gambling.
I believe in making your living.
I believe that it's an itch.
It's an illness,
whatever,
but when you're losing your house,
there's got,
that's where I want to know where.
That's where it bothers me.
It's just like cocaine.
It's just like a drug abuse.
It's just like the opiate problem.
It's just not any even fucking thing
else.
It could fucking,
you and I both know people who have lost
their fucking lives.
Gambling.
Okay.
You've seen people in pool halls.
You see how they get Joe Rogan.
There's no difference in the drug addict
and the gambling addict.
Not at all,
no difference
there.
It's just a scary too,
because they're conscious.
It's like if you've seen the drug act,
you see him,
he's shooting up or whatever it is,
and you see him fainting,
you go out of their poor bastard.
But when you see a guy who,
who's fully in the grips of gambling,
trying to figure out how to make,
get his money back,
and he's all jazzed up with adrenaline,
doesn't understand why,
see there's gamblers like Michael
Jordan.
Then there's gamblers like Joey Diaz,
this gamblers who have the means to
gamble.
And that is a fucking killer.
Also like on Michael Jordan,
Michael Jordan.
And I'm not saying nothing bad about
Michael Jordan accusations that you hear
that he even bets on his own while I'm
one basketball games.
I think it very,
uh,
he was very,
competitive,
but now how Joey Diaz was doing it,
not how people,
Charles Barkley lost nearly $30 million
gambling it to us.
He's this Charles,
uh,
Joey,
how much money is,
tom asked how many people did you grow
up?
But that will,
like Joey Diaz did not have the means
that when 19 years old.
Okay.
And One night they put a 10 time better
than a fucking knick game and they won
$50 when you're 19 $50 is a lot of
fucking money.
That's a lot of fun.
So now you think you got the world by
the balls.
So you do it again on Friday,
Saturday,
and now you enter this world Joe Rogan
that gets dark.
It's,
it's a instead of the drug addiction,
alcohol addiction,
every morning you wake up like his
today,
my lucky day.
It's like the people who go to the seven
11 every day and you're trying to just
get a pack of rolling papers.
You're just in a rush.
You just left your Jitsu.
You just want to ruin papers and water.
If there's a guy in front of you and
he's telling you,
give me three 68 four 60 fours and this
poor fucking whatever gives them 20
lottery tickets and it's $118 this is
what this guy's doing everyday,
seven fucking days a week.
My friend and he bite,
he might be winning $200 a fucking week,
but every week he's getting deeper and
deeper into a fucking hole because in
your mind you think today's your lucky
day and it's never,
you're lucky.
I was in that hole when I was 19 dog and
I saw a friend lose any Dallas and when
you're 18 years old and he had to get
three jobs and I never really fucked
with that again.
I learned that addiction,
that shit left my world early.
You know,
it was a degenerate loser Gambler,
John Gotti.
He wanted,
because they brag,
that's that conversation in mind.
They may know who I'm still fuck got
away from me,
you know I have no fucking idea.
If I had fucking Michigan and the hook,
I would have made 30,000
they lose 80 90 200,000
in a weekend that the system is designed
to bury the degenerate gambler like from
from August 15th look at this John Gadi
secret obsession and that wage 600 bets
and scrabble and a $3,000
monopoly.
Buyin you have no idea.
Guys did the generous for like eight for
like seven months.
I played this fucking ugly game Joe,
but I would start I the action.
I knew that you had a bet on Monday
nights and try to win and you know what?
I lost every week and all these people
show you information.
Listen,
Arch Lisa played the fucking game,
lost Pete Rose and lost even Michael
Jordan and loss.
There's room is that,
that's why he was asked to play baseball
for a few years because there was a
cover up again.
I did not write this.
This is just things I hear on the road.
Everybody has a fucking boat.
Gambling grabs you fucking weird bro
year and it grabbed me for a long time.
I kept thinking that was the day and I
kept betting 40 times what's touching
me.
If they had a problem playing scrabble,
they would call up the parker brothers
hotline.
Dick Mobsters would to dispute the
rules.
Then explain and what those fucking Lami
is a word.
It's a word Joe.
Stop means is not a one stop.
Mean kids don't word Wiki.
Wiki,
Wiki Dude,
he told me they stopped me.
That's why they would get into arguments
about garbage.
Man was a real word.
Garbage man cafe.
You know?
Oh my God,
gambling is a fucking nightmare and once
you get caught in the web and you enjoy
rogue and shuts me down,
then I start putting batch with Jamie
and then pretty soon I start plucking,
dipping into accounts and pretty soon
now you're done.
Now you get forced into a bad hand.
I told you that I was a backer on the
road for a while.
My friend Johnny B,
when I started making money doing
standup,
I put together a little bankroll and me
and him would go places and gamble and
he would win or lose.
You know?
Sometimes he'd win.
Sometimes you lose,
but it was just uh,
being an action.
It was fun.
You know,
that kind of gambling.
Like I was never good enough to like
play those guys.
But I could play like people that were
like my level and you'd bet like 20
bucks or maybe if you want to get crazy
about like 50 bucks.
I never bet like a lot of money gambling
on pool,
but it makes you think more,
it makes you play like way more serious.
It's good for your game.
And if you can have a friendly sparring
partner,
they play friendly games like maybe a
race to seven for 20 bucks.
So it's costs you probably in any city
pool halls,
I don't know what the rate is per hour,
but they gotta be like at least 20 bucks
for once and for all,
I want you to break it down from it.
I walked into a pool hall with Jamie.
Yeah,
I got 10 g's cash in my pocket.
Jamie's my main man.
How do I exactly make money and why is
it that the people the room passing
money around and how does that money get
dispersed?
It was real simple.
Everybody puts like you put in,
I'm in for 120 matches one,
it depends on who's putting it together
cause they might decide to just in all
their money
like everybody put in on one side pool
in money and you know,
and and back this guy or they might be
betting on the side.
They might not even be playing the game.
There's always a side bets.
Side bets are probably more like if you
had a bet,
if you had like a big pool game right?
There used to be a place called uh,
w what is it?
Western billiards.
I think in New Jersey,
west end,
I think it was called,
we'll see if you find west end
billiards.
It was a world famous pool hall.
We would take the drive from,
I'm from New York to go down in New
Jersey to this famous pool hall that
would have these like serious high level
professionals play there and real high
level hustlers from all over the country
would go there for big money games.
You go there and watch people play for
$5,000
$10,000
I mean the best in the world would be
there all the time.
I got to play against some of the best
in the world.
They killed me,
but I got to play again against him.
Like real good guys.
Let's say into the tournament,
you and I,
you and I are in the tournament and you
are a Efrin Rayez the greatest of all
time or earl stricklin or Johnny Archer
and I'm just Joe Rogan.
I barely could play.
It doesn't matter.
I put my money up,
I entered the tournament.
I can play against you unless it's a
huge,
huge like where you have to get invited
so that those joey dee has come onto the
side and go,
listen,
I'm putting three to one hud's on this.
Sure.
Some people definitely,
definitely.
That's a side.
Yes,
I,
that's all.
I don't know how the pool,
we got 100 bucks on archer.
You know,
you'd never seen this diaz kid play.
I've got a hundred ideas and dudes,
I'll take that,
I'll take that and then you just work it
out and everybody works it out.
But when sometimes guys will get
together and back somebody to like say
if you got it like a friend,
it's a really good player and this guy
is coming in from out of town and he
wants to take a crack at him and go,
well he wants to play $100 sets.
Okay.
And then you have to think how many
barrels do we have?
You Pool your money together.
Okay,
we got four barrels.
That means if he wants to play sets we
can lose four times.
So you have to be able to lose a couple
of gain.
A couple,
like if you're going to really play a
guy out,
these guys would play 10 12 hours.
Then we keep going back and forth and
back and forth.
It's,
it's,
it's crazy.
Like I've seen guys and you would see
him the next day.
They'd still be playing.
You'd go there in the morning,
they'd be playing all through the night.
I don't know what the fuck they were on.
Most likely some sort of emphatic means.
That was a big thing and the pool world
for a while,
guys would just break each other with
gambling.
It would just,
it would be about who quits.
It wouldn't be about who won.
It's very rarely about like,
you know like you would,
you'd be,
you would be frowned upon highly if you
left on top.
Say if you're ahead by 500 bucks and you
want to quit me and,
and I'm still ready,
ready to keep playing,
I still got more money,
man.
Let me win my money back.
If you just walked away,
Nope,
I've got what I wanted.
I'm going to leave now.
Like that would be,
you'd be what's called bad action,
but guys,
I've got two kids are having to get up
at seven and go to the pool hall.
Motherfucker with two kids.
You're not playing that kind of pool.
There ain't nobody would two kids
playing that
level pool in pool halls like gambling,
it hustled pool maybe now there are,
this is actually a few guys,
I take that back.
There's a few guys with kids that are
top of the food chain because the pool
hall mile from my house,
whenever I get,
whenever I go into Hollywood now I can't
do her.
Okay and no more,
so I got to go a long way and I get off.
I'm victory just to see it fucking
always felt with the generous.
I'm petrified to pull in there.
Sometimes places we're home to me,
he's always told them talking about
right next to the Strip club.
Is that on victory?
Right when you exit then there's a strip
club right next to a ball.
Well,
I know the only good one in this area.
I shouldn't say the only good one.
The only good one that I know of.
His house.
A billiards in Sherman oaks.
I like this area.
Have you been?
You been on the one on one?
Have you seen what that place is that
where you took me there a couple of
times to eat.
We did comedy there.
Remember Hollywood billy and you took me
there.
Yeah,
it's fucking a building.
What is it now?
The goal then next time.
What does it look like?
I don't Joe,
next time I drove by and I was like,
oh my God that we did comedy that to eat
dead with the a couple times we played
pool there are a bunch of tiny chip
time.
Bunch of times that place was fucking
done.
That whole area is completely,
that's where I met.
Crazy.
Max are bully.
Really?
Yeah,
like that dude can play some fucking
pool.
Ooh,
so when you play Max separately,
how much drive to pull it up guy?
He's still put them on the one I would
get tortured.
You would have to bet like that.
I would go to,
you're never going to bet on me.
Like a guy like Max eberly.
He's top of the food chain as far as his
technique and delivery.
He could win a world championship
tournament.
Like legitimately he's that good.
I have no chance.
Like if if we played 12 games,
I might win a couple.
I might get lucky and win a few.
Maybe I went for,
he's getting way more.
He's going to get to 12 for sure
quicker.
It'd be a terrible bat.
The bat would be,
how many games did I get too?
That'd be the bat.
If you say you'll never get past three
because a guy like max tablet can run 10
racks in a row and I'm not exaggerating.
I've seen him do it.
Blam breaks,
runs 10 racks in a row,
but to the point where you're sitting
there,
he did it in Vegas.
We were all hanging out.
I think it was man was an Ari.
I forget who came with me.
How could you forget?
You guys are going to the Italian place.
Yes.
That place was amazing and that's
exactly what Max Max's plan.
He,
he would break and run out on guys and
they would just get frustrated.
They'd be like,
what the fuck man?
They just get,
didn't get to shoot.
We watched him.
He was gambling some guy and when the
set was over,
the guy was just pissed off because Max
wouldn't miss.
It was crazy.
Just watch him.
He's playing a guy that really just
wanted to take a chance and play like a
top of the food chain guy and he gambled
with them.
But just watching the difference between
a kid who can play a little pool,
it's pretty good versus a world
championship caliber pool play.
They're so precise.
I,
because technique is so clean and his
angles are perfect and he's just efforts
effortlessly move in the cue ball on the
table to where he wants it.
He sees clusters and problems.
Wayne advance and breaks them up.
It's so high level.
That's my boy.
That's Max Albert Lea.
He taught me how to play pool.
Uh,
not that I didn't already play it before
I met him,
but he taught me how to play it way
better,
way better.
He made my game,
I'm way more uh,
technical.
He was explaining things that I was just
guessing before and he was explaining
what was wrong with my approach and like
what was the,
what's,
what's a better way to do it?
He's a wizard when it comes to
technique.
Got He can make a living going from pool
hall to Pool Hall.
No Way.
Cause he's that good.
He's an artist too.
Fortunately for Max,
he uh,
he makes pretty cool artwork like um,
a lot.
See some of it's probably on his
instagram.
[inaudible] pool cubes or something?
No,
no,
no.
Max does pool cues.
Ooh,
somebody along the way.
He said he makes like fucking eight
jeep.
Oh,
Judy's ivory.
Eric.
Chris.
That's my boy.
Eric from shake the tree.
Somebody.
That's what I play with.
I played with his cue.
His cue is a,
he's a wizard man.
He's a guy who's like really into like
the grains of woods.
He's really into like patterns and he
thinks of like,
to him what is like mesmerizing.
He finds like the most beautiful pieces
of wood and comp combines and together
and they have to have a certain harmonic
frequency.
Like he drops him on a safari cement for
just like Dank,
Dank.
Like he wants to hear a certain sound
from the wood,
otherwise he won't use it.
He's like finding logs on the side of
the highway and shit and recognizing
some weird hardwood that no one's ever
used before.
He cuts it up and execute out of it.
He's a wizard,
like his cues or for Dan,
he doesn't give a fuck.
He makes as many as he wants.
You know,
sometimes they don't make them for
awhile,
makes them first.
Friends won't let me pay for one after I
have to pay for everything,
just to not feel terrible.
He's like the nicest guy ever.
Play some fucking pool too.
So I don't even know when this podcast
started.
Amazon,
it's happening.
It's funny.
Before we started,
we were talking about uh,
yeah,
4.8
billion.
I'm like,
well 3% will happen in Nevada.
Only 3% so most of it online online was
that Chris Christie thing you pulled up
earlier.
James,
listen,G
and banks,
banks,
there's still people who are like a,
you know they have,
they got a ton of loot.
Chris Christie goes to the Supreme Court
on sports betting.
Is he trying to get sports betting?
Yeah,
he lives,
they passed something in a Jersey I
think in 2011 to allow betting and
sports,
but it's still only a lot of vegas
because of the whatever law there is
back on your team,
Chris.
Yeah.
All right,
so he has a few problems,
but we all do 17 states also with them
on this.
I think I want to do it so he would
want,
he opposed it.
They wanted again,
they want betting again because they
have an NHL team in Vegas and that's
always been like the,
the logic is that there'll be some
issue,
whatever.
You can't not be betting where their
sports being played because someone will
throw the game.
Everybody should be able to bet every
city she'll do whatever you want to.
We're going to talk to you going to do
these games though.
These,
I'm fascinated by these games you see or
hypnotizing ladies and going crazy,
losing all their,
their money.
That was 60 minutes did a whole,
he bought a whole piece on these games
are like laser ish and people actually
put the percentage was higher.
Most women because of its,
uh,
so let me explain something to you.
It's your view.
You know,
it's just uh,
it's like video games,
more like gambling.
It's very fucking so addictive.
Like a video game,
but also the gambling very game.
So that's what the beef was to remove
these type of games because I'm telling
you since I was a kid,
I always first off,
yeah,
I lived with my mother.
She had a lot of proms,
shovel out your rate issues,
but she was a degenerate gambler on
baseball
between the Boston Red Sox and the New
York mets.
They killed it.
They killed her.
And I saw the decline.
I saw what did that,
I saw a person watched two baseball
games at the same time.
I remember in those days you didn't have
a split screen and direct TV.
So if you were Puerto Rican,
you took one pv and you put it on top of
the other TV and you got fucking MBC and
you had cable with it,
came with the cord member with Hbo,
still had the cord to the fucking thing
and it was a thing with a box that you
pressed and you switched three levels in
those days may be there was no edit and
there was no aba package or NBA package.
You got like one other game.
So we would pray that it would be the
Boston red sox and she would watch both
fucking games and gamble at the same
time.
Not,
not even that.
The numbers,
if she had a dream about a goat bad.
If she had a dream about going back to
Cuba,
Bam.
Your family,
if she had a dream about,
um,
seeing her daughter,
Bam,
it was a number they would call her.
They would call her at a quarter to
three because she had all that,
all those contacts.
So that was that gambling.
Then there was the,
then there was the track addiction.
Okay.
Which started at aqueduct in the
afternoon.
If the sun was shining,
that was my excuse to go to aqua duck
from my mother.
Let me go to act with duck pasta.
You had three after school and she'd be
there at three but the whole time she'd
be scratching because the meadowlands
started at eight
okay.
She knew she could catch the metal lands
at eight so guess what happens is,
is that if you lose the eight o'clock
meadowlands what?
You haul your ass to yonkers with the
death of death.
This is
where you go to before you go to a pool
or this or your blood.
You go to yonkers raceway.
Do you understand me?
Have you ever been to yonkers raceway?
Yeah.
You leave there with a corner,
the one where do you think you're going?
You either going to sell your soul or
give you a blood.
She'd go shoot pool because you're
saving the day.
You cannot go home a loser.
Right,
right.
There's all day gambling.
Oh my God.
So that was her thing.
So I also grew up in an Italian family
that the mother was a chow away.
It was like a fucking act.
It was like an act.
She had three kids.
They were tremendous kids.
I knew the husband,
he worked for a big corporation,
they drove a nice car,
they went to church.
But on Saturdays when I go over there,
I would always go with your mom and
they'd go,
my mom plays cards with uh,
with the Rogan's and uh,
and this name.
But why as I got older one day somebody
said to me,
don't be careful when you go over there.
Why they might shoot that lady in the
head.
She knows like 600 down.
I mean,
and when I was a kid,
I was like 13 and somebody came to me,
they said,
be careful when you go with it because
the mom's a little bit on the those card
games.
And then as I got ahold of,
they're scared for your life from a card
game.
Magic being scared for your life.
Well,
it was a different game.
That's how they suck you in.
So a lot of the people now,
I also grew up with men,
degenerate gamblers,
but I know all of the symptoms.
I know the itch.
This,
this thing on 60 minutes just spoke
about this addiction with uh,
a computer thing with women.
That was it.
That was really interesting,
but I know how it fucking creeps up on
you.
It's not a couple of years ago it's
called the slot machines.
The big gamble.
Oh,
so it's just slot machines in general.
These type of slot machines.
Computer ones,
yes.
They have an effect on women in
particular.
Maybe.
Man,
the fuck up ladies.
How about that?
No dog.
Here's my take on this whole gambling
thing.
Like you remember horse bedding in New
York?
Like you'd go to the horse,
you could go to the track better.
Yeah,
it was right there.
Right there.
They made that for a reason.
I mean it just trying to make it legal.
This is legal.
Come on.
It says legal.
It's not legal.
It's to take a piece.
Jerome,
they want that piece.
Have you been to a medical marijuana
store recently?
No,
I haven't.
Okay.
What are they like,
if it's $60 your tab is now $76 cause
the tax,
it's $16 in taxes.
If you buy something for $60 the thing
about weed though is it goes so far I
think about how much like $100 worth of
weed goes.
You could be on the moon for three days
for three days.
You could be on the moon with the proper
edibles.
Get a $100 worth of the proper edibles.
How much do you think you can handle?
How many jumbos do you think you can
handle?
Do you ever have a Jon Boat?
Okay.
What do they have
like just depends on I think a hundred
to $200 yeah dude,
I fucked up.
Need a half a jumbo.
Once my,
I felt my cells,
I felt all the cells in my bones.
I felt like were the tendons connected
on my spine?
Like it's like you could get fucking
blasted on and then the last 12 hours
and then take the other half.
That's another 12 hours for other taxes
higher than Las Vegas.
Jamie.
Then they aren't here for week 35% here.
How much?
35 and what's in Vegas?
It's high,
but it depends on if they chase the
motherfucking game dog like yes,
no more stars or death.
That's so silly.
No more.
Hello,
she's the Tkos.
I bought the final fucking,
I got a the towel.
I'm like Pablo Escobar.
I got a fucking cache of the ones I ate
this morning.
Those hello?
The Tk hose.
Yeah.
You can't find them.
But I got to college.
I got the league.
They become like Cuban cigars.
Oh my God.
Like Cuban cigars now.
So some people are just going to keep
going.
There's no more.
Like I told people,
there's no more stores,
but they stars like people going fucking
bananas now.
Cause now you guys,
you got to see the like I only go to w
two weeks doors,
but I go to one that's by the book and I
go to war that they just said,
you know what?
We're like steeping Mayo check.
We don't give a fuck.
This is immigrant mentality.
We opened at six,
we close at 10 we give away free bagels.
If you come at six o'clock and you got
to see it,
that rock rocking the road,
they're going to sell those 200
milligram stars.
Tow people go down to fucking end.
Wow.
Or the dea comes in and shuts him down.
They don't give a fuck.
That's too,
like if you're on Ventura Boulevard,
you gotta be really cool cause you're
done.
I don't think there's anything wrong
with having a limit on the number of
milligrams.
If that's going to keep it legal,
it's in.
That's also,
they just grow a lot of people that are
jumping at black pocket.
That's it.
You know how much it cost.
You know how much it's gonna cost of
stars that that dude just stay open.
How much?
A half a mil.
Oh my God.
Because it's 70 grand just for the
license.
Cheap money.
They take that,
they take that paper up in front,
that like led Zepplin.
They're like Peter Grip and 1975 the
economy's going to improve and they're
still gonna kill.
Oh No,
no.
He's going to improve of when I tell you
what,
how much are they going to take right
off the target of the tape.
Bang it.
They looked at Colorado's thing and
said,
listen,
we'll cover that with steroids.
Were coming in with H,
forget what they're doing.
Listen to,
we're doing just to set shop now.
We don't care if you've been in business
with nothing just to set up shop.
We got to get a piece of the actual okay
fine.
If they just,
they work deals out with banks and made
it easy and acceptable for these guys
could put them,
but it's right.
And a lot of places it wasn't,
they were dealing in cash.
They hired,
especially in Colorado in the early
days,
they had a higher,
a lot of like Spec ops guy.
I love saying in Spec ops like,
I know what the fuck I'm talking about.
Just sounds cool.
Um,
they would hire like former seals and
shit and then they would have to carry
the,
uh,
the money to the bank cause everybody
knew there was like giant sums of cash.
So it made it very dangerous.
They weren't allowing them to use banks
or credit cards,
rather,
they weren't allowing them to,
you know,
sell.
We would credit cards,
but they selling weed and credit cards
in a la medical in the 90.
[inaudible] the hot store when you
turned me on to my license,
the hot store at the time,
which they're not there.
Know that dude at the height of it was
walking out of there everyday with 25
gram by himself and cool life.
Wow,
that's dangerous.
He was a,
but you know what,
he was just dumb as fuck when the dea
came in to have that cash in the safe
right there that they just swooped on
it.
I knew a guy who got shot.
He was a really nice guy and he used to
work at the Inglewood wellness center
and a,
this was the early days of,
um,
the medical legalization.
It was like,
I want to say it's like somewhere around
[inaudible] 99,
somewhere,
somewhere in that range.
2099.
And,
um,
he apparently was coming out with a big
bag of cash and someone shot him right
in the stomach,
took his money.
They didn't take care of them.
So I took all the cash.
There was nothing to hire people.
You had a higher piece.
You've got to hire people,
you know.
I see,
I see amateur mistakes.
Yeah,
I saw this Jamie.
I see amateur mistakes constantly.
For example,
the store I'm talking about,
he lost.
He lost everything.
Joe Rogan when you over,
they will,
he lost everything.
He would any weed he got.
This guy was an exotic guy himself.
Like he was head when you're ahead,
you love when somebody brings you.
So he bought as much as he could.
I love that expression I had.
He was a head,
nobody uses that anymore.
So what he would do is when you walked
into this place,
he would have 60 weeds on the wall and
he kept all his weed on the property.
When the feds came,
it was like stealing.
He had everything there,
everything was there.
One in the open.
You have to have an apartment and you
have to have an amount on the mouth.
Six ounces.
It's all you should have one week.
If Jamie comes in and he wants eight
ounces,
give me 10 minutes.
I got a pigeon that will bring it over
here and 5 million right across the
street.
Then I got a little apartment,
which a stash that you have a couple of
saves.
You have to,
if the cops ain't going to let you
deposit,
you've gotta be fucking creative.
If you read all these guys' stories,
the hardest,
the Joe Rogan,
you ready for this expression?
The hardest thing is what to do.
We'll call him dick about that problem.
Joe Rowe in Syria.
Now.
It's a real problem.
No,
no.
Think about this room filled with her.
Hello?
What was the movie?
I just went,
oh,
it's tomorrow.
Oh,
no,
no.
I just on a plane.
You can,
when you're on a plane
and Tom Cruise's on,
you've got to give them the benefit of
the doubt.
Oh,
I've got another bullet in me.
I watched the barry seal thing.
How was it?
It's not an academy award winner,
but it's very interesting when we're
just burying money.
Joe Rogan,
4 million a shot like me and you are the
yard like burying money,
like a suitcase with hundred dollar
bills falling out of it and you don't
give a Frenchmans fucked.
I always wanted to know this snopes,
this.
Did Barry Seal die with George Bushes?
Phone number in his pocket.
That's what they always said and he
died.
They shot him on the way to the trial.
What?
George Bush,
his phone number in his pocket.
Oh,
he was top notch.
That guy.
He had it all.
He's seen it bro.
He took pictures of them loading a
fucking plane in Nicaragua with Escobar
and the top eight and Nicaragua.
They had him by the fucking balls.
No matter what.
How you that took balls.
Fuck.
They fucked him in the ass.
They told him that they wouldn't release
the pictures.
Then they release the pictures,
which was Douche and that's why they got
got shot.
That's fucked up.
They should have taken him and hitting
him.
He Fuck is interesting though.
They assassinated that guy.
That's a 100% assassination in
connection to some sort of illegal
government.
It was the fucking come up whether
legal,
what are you talking about?
That was escobar,
that set the bird a message.
They had a deal.
We're bearing can seals could land
though,
right?
Like it wasn't,
part of the thing was with the people on
the ground,
the ground that was in mean.
Here's the problem.
This is where Eddie Bravo comes in.
They were landing in those everglades,
no quote me on this.
Right.
And he broke it down for me and somebody
else broke,
broken down,
made it be honest with you.
And they were allowing that on your boys
clock.
Clinton clock.
That's,
that's,
that's like theory,
the whole thing.
That's what you always be.
His drops out,
right about truth.
Because the truth is fascinating.
The truth,
his two boys were murdered and uh,
the,
uh,
car near the official report they gave
to the parents was a,
that they had fallen asleep on the train
tracks.
So a,
the parents pay for some sort of an
autopsy and it's revealed that the kid
had been stabbed.
And the one of them had been stabbed and
then they find out that around that same
area was where those guys would drop
their drugs before they landed.
They would parachute down their drugs,
they would,
they would like and they would land.
And these guys,
they had dropped points where they would
put their shit and then someone else
would come by and pick it up on the
ground.
You've got coordinators and these kids
apparently saw something they weren't
supposed to see.
So they fucking murdered these kids with
knives.
And then the coroner was all in on it.
So they had to conduct some sort of
independent.
So that is what got this whole barry
seal's thing going.
It was this lady trying to figure out
this parents trying to figure out what
happened to their kids.
You know,
Joe wrote a fucking crazy story.
You have to imagine,
okay that these
guys were getting,
you know,
let's just draw a number.
I,
I mean I'm just an idiot,
but let's just draw a number.
And they were probably getting $4,000
per kilo.
What would they put on those planes?
And there was sending five of those
planes over a day and dropping them in
the Louisiana,
and this is,
listen man,
I told you a thousand times in the
podcast and 83 they found the bear dead
next to a Duffel bag filled with cocaine
and aspen,
Colorado in the mountains because they
would drop into fucking coke in the
mountain.
This is a very bad way.
The coke and he fucking old deed is
hard.
Oh,
what does it say?
okay.
Barry Seal,
seal it.
Organize a sting operation where he
managed to get photographs of Pablo
Escobar helping Nicaraguan soldiers to
load 1200 kilos of cocaine onto a seat,
but 23 male,
it's a plane.
Soon afterwards,
Reagan went on television with the
photograph to denounce Sandinistas as
drug smuggling,
corrupting
duck duck bats,
how much he was getting for that 4
million,
800,000
for one fucking low.
Now here's the tricky thing.
Here's what,
here's what really pisses me the fuck
off that I see narcos and I see
everything,
but now this is your uncle joey talking
to you.
Joe Rogan,
please show me the good side of Pablo
Escobar.
No,
no,
I'm not gonna.
No,
no.
There's no good side to Pablo Escobar
and the Saint Lee Harvey Weinstein.
This is a story that we have never
brought up,
but you have to assume.
Okay,
you,
you see all these shows and the whole
fucking thing and they were in bed for
sure with Nicaragua.
Yeah.
Who else is in bed with Nicaragua?
Let me ask you this.
Do you think that it is the actual CIA
or is it people or if it,
when it was,
let's not even say cia.
Dea.
FBI named a bunch of fucking letters,
put them together.
Is it the actual organization?
Whichever one it is that's bringing it
in,
are they complicit or are they're just
cowboys?
See the theory's always been that
there's been these few cowboys corrupt
guys.
Maybe they get too close to drug deals
to crow close to the drug deal,
and then sometimes they get seduced
like,
cause there's a many,
many stories of under oh under cover
cops getting seduced by the actual
lifestyle of being a criminal young
kids.
They probably did a little crime
themselves here or there.
They see some cops doing some dirty
shit.
They see him.
Some guy,
you know,
there was a thing that came out about,
was it Baltimore?
What?
What does the city where cops had came
out and trial,
they'd kept toy guns on them to plant at
the scene of a,
of a crime.
Like if they just
shoots,
there's a fucking toy gun in the big
picture,
the big world picture as an intelligent
individual as you are the plant.
It was planned in the sample.
The CIA wanted a piece of their action
and the dea was tricked into going down.
That I really control a,
you can't be this,
and I'm not saying you as an American,
you can't be this dump.
So all the research that we've done,
all the research that we've done with
general north,
he was in on the package with barry
seal,
the whole fucking thing.
And here's what it gets even deeper.
Let's talk about the deep disturb that,
that nobody ever even looked at.
And you have to think of,
because I heard this story a thousand
times,
there was a guy by the name is Carlos
laid that,
that,
that he got crazy.
You know,
they show him getting his dick sucked on
the radio and uh,
Columbia and everything and all these TV
shows.
No,
he was on an island snorting coke with
long hair,
talking like Jim Morrison and having
fucking threesomes and the fucking,
uh,
their own cartel gave lay dare up to the
law.
They are to keep them off their back.
It was five partners.
It's me,
you,
Jamie and red band,
but fucking red bands out there doing
videos of him snorting coke with a
fucking pigeon on this head.
We can't have this.
They gave the dea fucking Carlos that
comp like calm things down for a while
when the,
in 83 and 84,
when Reagan sent his troops down there,
don't quote me on the dates here,
but I will tell you as a professional
cocaine sniffer,
what was going on,
and 85,
the price of cocaine went skyrocketing
and it wasn't,
I'm sick and tie.
It wasn't because of cocaine
skyrocketing,
it was because the cocaine was coming
in.
But the toughest part was getting the
ether alcohol and to Colombia to process
it.
The Colombians had got a tip that the
uh,
the,
the troops were coming down to raid
their jungles.
Now what they had not told you in all
these shows and research,
but this is uncle joe is going to drop
on you is what do you think they took?
What other,
they took some labs to Nicaragua and
they shipped cocaine out of Nicaragua.
But guess who else partnered up with
them to your buddy fidel.
Fidel was shipping it in.
Yeah,
he's going to be on the podcast and
three weeks I can you imagine having for
Dell I give you and Fidel,
you told my God this whole block would
have the snipers and fucking everybody.
Fidel just walked in with a suit and you
had to teach them like a UFC move and
shit cause for Dell and come in and
asked,
you said you'll know getting the mixable
westgate tech cause they were anyway,
but they weren't serious man.
They went to very nervous in the
presence of a guy like that lay dead
said in front of Congress that he was
getting 800,000
he was given Fidel 800,000
a shipload to come in under his flag at
the time.
She imagined being in the presence of a
Fidel Castro,
just being in his presence like if he
was,
you know,
in his prime here in the room with him
in his prime,
no one he how he ran cube.
We took it over.
You have no idea.
Maybe he would be destroyed.
This terrifying to be arrested Cuban
American.
You have to hate the guy.
I have to hate him,
but as a man that thinks you have to see
what his path was crazy again,
that's where my man,
Tj was,
comes in with a van and knock toward the
Ha,
the revolution for how he started at
three different places at once.
The revolution,
it just wasn't eight monkeys that put on
gorilla suit and went to the mountains
of Cuba.
He came to Jersey first,
got arrested,
went to Tampa,
I got arrested.
He was already passing out flyers.
They always confuse Lee Harvey.
I was,
well,
no,
it wasn't Lee Harvey given out
pamphlets.
It was Fidel Castro get with a helper.
That's a joke.
Please don't quote it.
The CIA.
It's a joke.
I'm not ratting.
Yeah,
Fidel Castro was in union city,
New Jersey.
I can't tell you the dates,
but like I have my friend Colin to the
podcast and tell you the story about
Fidel talking to his mother on a daily
when she would have waited to get on the
bus.
She was an Irish girl in union city and
she goes,
I know Fidel in 19 fucking 52 and you
need city.
Just think of what he did to the
Italians.
He kicked everybody out.
It's like,
fuck your casinos.
Mine now.
It wasn't very brilliant movie started
in the mountains.
He fucking,
he,
you know,
he just took over the little villages
and then he changed their minds because
blood,
first of all,
it wasn't an easy thing for to them to
do.
Battista was really fucking the country.
He had really divided the country.
You have no idea what racism was.
Tow.
You were in Cuban,
1955 black people weren't allowed in
casinos.
You have no idea.
These poor people today,
everybody's crying about,
you have no idea what black rights were
in Cuba for those black fucking people.
They got no rights.
So those people were poor.
That was such a high level of dot.
You see all these people dancing,
but on the other side there was fucking
famine,
like people were fucking dying,
so they wanted a change.
Fidel came in there as a hero.
First of all,
he came in as Cuba was going to change,
but then he switched it on him and he
aligned but Russia and he became a
communist.
That's what made it worse.
Racism and hunger has always existed in
Cuba.
It did that.
That was the problem that they always
showed that party side of Cuba,
but that other side of the island is
probably,
there is people starving.
Wow.
And Battista come on,
but how do they keep up the tobacco
production?
That I don't know.
I don't know.
I was still thinking of that Joey,
but now all of that,
they had the best cigars in the world,
but that people complaining now that
they're not the same cigars.
This is,
some people are complaining,
but a lot of people
getting frauds apparently.
Apparently when you buy Cuban cigars
from untrust and trustee people,
you could definitely get some fakes
because now they're talking about how
the soil isn't rich.
White people will go there as an expert.
Oh,
Bobby Kelly.
Bobby Kelly's a real expert.
Like he was on a Arusha fears podcast.
They were talking about cigars.
Bobby Kelly really knows his shit like
he was,
he was going in depth about how many
fake cigars there are and how he can
even kind of taste a fake cube.
And he smoked so many cigars and he
thought maybe one of ours was fake.
He's like,
maybe it might be fake ninth deals.
No,
I think this Israel,
I think this is like,
it's like he's like that discerning
about that shit.
Huh?
There's a lot of weird freak.
So when it comes to cigars,
like people who are super into them,
they get sued.
They get you high as fuck too.
This is something that people aren't
talking about.
You smoke a cigar,
you're like,
whew,
that's,
there's so much nicotine in that.
You had the Cuban coffee to it.
Oh my God.
It's how the process is supposed to go
down with the Cuban coffee.
That's a win we do.
And you go deep,
deep,
deep in the only needs a little taste of
it that a bull and a half of Alpha brain
and you'll be there.
You'll get the Jack Chappelle smokes it
with uh,
sometimes with cigarettes in it.
We did it the other night in the back of
the comedy store with cigarette and
tobacco and done a couple of times to,
Yay.
Ooh,
you get elevated.
It was,
it was interesting.
I got one time from San Francisco to
Reno,
one time from San Francisco to reno dog.
The cops were looking for me and San
Francisco and you go down to the,
any of those tourists districts and they
have like a bus that'll take you to
reno.
So I just jumped on the bus to reno at
this check and this is 1985 when we're
sitting in the bus and there's this
Egyptian k,
I'll never forget this and the back of
it,
you could smoke on the bus in those
days.
Cigarettes.
So he had rolled a blunt with hash and
tobacco when it got,
and I had never done that before guys.
I'm not going to lie.
I had never even,
I took two hits of that fucking thing.
Dog.
I had a puke in that bathroom.
I got high as fuck.
But that combination together,
that tobacco,
this we'd hash.
He had the real,
yeah,
that's too much.
Rockwell Joey.
That's a bit much for Uncle Joey.
The first time I ever smoked a spliff
was with Charlie Murphy.
Charlie Murphy rolled them is his cousin
Richard.
We're on two.
Charlie could role,
he would,
um,
he would take a swisher sweets old
school,
you know,
any kind of cigar paper and he would
turn it into a joint with the cigar
paper,
which is like,
you inhale weed,
you never really inhaled those cigars.
You,
you could just kind of get them in your
mouth and you taste it.
Then you blow it out.
But when you take a drag a weed,
you open your lungs up and fill your
lungs with the smoke.
Cigar.
Smokes too harsh for that.
You don't,
you don't smoke
like that for the most part.
Most people don't.
But when you do it with pot,
you do.
So you get this career easy blast of
nicotine and the carets e blast a weed
and you're like,
wow,
it's very different than just weed.
I think I smoked.
Yeah.
Last night on the podcast,
I took two hits off in front of mine,
gave me one of those.
I like those.
And it was pretty fucking scared.
I'm scared of us.
I'm scared of my life.
The ones with the cigarettes in them,
I'm scared.
No,
no,
no.
I don't want no smoke.
No,
no.
I'm not talking to cigarettes.
But the ones with cigarettes and um,
it's an interesting little high.
It's like,
Ooh,
this is a new door to the room.
It's a,
it's interesting.
That's what like smoking.
One of the hardest things I ever gave up
with smoking cigarettes after you smoke
a joint,
right?
That is just pure brilliance.
When you hit a fucking joy and you'd
take a little sip of coffee and after
you smoke that through to you light up a
Marlboro some life.
It's life fucking changing bro.
I know a lot of people love him after a
real good meal.
Well,
the whole,
it's the whole package.
So I was like,
God,
let me ask you a meal.
I meal a joint and then the cigarette
and then another cigarette and a cup of
coffee on top of that.
Some dessert said another second.
Right.
You have no fucking idea.
Cigarette scare the shit out of him.
I'm pleased.
[inaudible] body,
I can't smoke them.
My Tony's hooked.
My blood pressure would be 2000 over 80
Tony says he can quit it anytime.
A little fella.
And you know what?
What was the best one on one?
What I realized was two years ago I shot
something and I smoked that night.
I asked one of the camera guys,
let me fucking get me a cigarette.
And that next morning was when I
realized how really fucking bad day are
you felt terrible.
Oh,
how many of you have one to two
cigarettes to Marlboro Lights?
And I was fine that night.
I did a comedy club and I was like,
what the fuck is going on?
And we all,
and I don't want to smoke the fuck.
No,
no,
I'd never do it again after that night
in Chicago.
I'll never do it again.
I took one of Tony's ones before it
show.
Interesting cigarettes or interesting.
It doesn't,
it does a weird little thing to your
breasts.
It does.
And that's one of the reasons why I did
this because I read something about a
nootropics are talking about um,
different vitamin,
like what's good for brain function.
And one of the things they said that
nicotine,
nicotine is actually a nootropic and
that they found that some people under
the use of tobacco with the use of
tobacco,
they achieve like a,
an elevated state of like certain
functions of the brain.
Like it actually has some sort of a
small measurable effect.
So it really does stimulate the way your
brain works.
I don't see,
for me it's different.
I have to,
it's a combination.
Yeah.
That's for me.
Like I,
I don't,
I wouldn't just enjoy right now you can
say goodbye itself,
but the cigarette with the weed,
but if that coffee was brewing hot right
now and it was maybe 60 degrees outside
with a little bit of wind and sunlight
will,
you know when you stand out in the sun
you'll warm,
but when you're in the breeze your
little cool.
You go outside and a good join us,
some fucking tremendous reef with the
sun hitting your face and you're taking
a nice hit of a cigarette all combined
or even,
or even like,
I like what I do,
I took a cup of coffee,
I'll pop a fucking number and then a
little nicotine gum to give you a little
gods,
some blood prior to him.
One blood pressure medication on top of
that all together,
it all works out.
You know what I'm saying?
If you take them apart and nothing
really happens,
I get it.
But together,
that's where you put them a fungo in.
For me,
it's a small shot of Jack Daniels and
one to two hits of a joint before
comics.
Just a little tap to taste.
Just a little yikes.
One Hand has really preferred.
It's a smart move.
Two inches.
If you're feeling I did it.
I did the Tequila the night w three
points.
Not Bad.
Oh,
well the weight watchers.
Yeah,
but how long are you doing the weight
watchers?
How long it,
I started December 9th I went from three
Oh nine to two 96 old.
Excellent.
But you know what,
Bro?
Here's the stupid thing.
Joe Rogan.
Here's the dumbest thing in the world.
I got sick and tired of people saying,
I cleaned that diet was,
you don't know Dick until you go to
weightwatchers.
Listen,
you want me to tell you what the new
way,
once this is your rent,
it's different.
It's Mike though.
Check.
Ah,
okay.
So the chicken nutrition's chicken
breasts,
chicken breasts.
I come to your house tonight and you go,
Joey,
what do you want to give me two chicken
breasts?
Just the marination.
I got to watch how your marinated who
got 0.0
pieces of salmon,
zero gods,
beans,
all types.
Zero.
Corn,
zero.
Uh,
what costs money or what costs points?
Beef.
Beef,
beef does 19 for Preston puts his over.
No,
no,
no.
But if you look at it,
if you look at it,
bro,
check this out.
You know you do a Jujitsu during 30
minutes and 16 fucking buoyant.
They fit it in.
You get your exercise,
you add points.
See,
I tried thinking about it.
I'm going to wait a second guy.
Smart.
Wait a second guys.
I kind of bounce them swinging bats.
I'm hitting the bag.
I'm walking around the park.
I'm still gaining weight.
Something's not right.
So it's the like the butter.
I don't use bothering them.
I could eat my piece of wheat toast with
my eggs.
Oh,
you ready for this?
Are off the other way.
Ready for this rock.
Throwing away the toast and just eating
the butter.
I don't like,
I gotta have my thoughts wrong.
Yeah,
but eat the butter butter's good for
you.
Especially if it's grants thing.
I get that.
Yo.
Hey Yo,
no egg whites.
I cut around them.
You had a bit about that.
None of those.
There's a a thing in the news yesterday
where they were saying that people only
eating egg whites is a tremendous
health,
uh,
deserve site.
Listen,
five years ago
it don't take a fucking moron.
The time,
20 years ago,
nobody was getting concussions.
Nobody was getting soft.
Nobody was getting their feelings hurt.
This specialty men,
all of a sudden I saw people started
eating egg whites and I saw big rise and
people having a hard time getting their
wives pregnant.
All of a sudden I saw commercials about
erectile dysfunction.
Men never talked about having men talked
about bug.
I did some bloaty at night and I didn't
get my dick hard.
Now all of a sudden there's a commercial
on national TV primetime,
some fucking guy saying that and
awesome.
They started dropping that low
testosterone shit and I'm telling you
dog,
one thing about Uncle Joey,
I've always loved egg yolks.
I don't like,
I don't even like mixing them.
I think it's bad for real.
I don't even like scrambled eggs.
I'll eat them if you make them,
if you make them nice to me with a
little sour cream and a little milk and
do it and run it.
I like it,
but I don't like just prison.
I got to see the Yolk.
I got a rule.
When you take me for breakfast,
I always got to see the yolk,
so I cut around it.
The other day,
the awaits.
You set them.
You've been coming here for a long time.
You do not touch the white and she goes,
I mean you do not touch it.
I have become like a surgeon with that
knife.
I get the yolk perfectly.
I take that wheat toast now I don't even
eat the whole two slices of wheat.
Those I only eat a half a wheat toast.
I take one egg yolk and put it on one
side and I eat the whole thing.
Like Robert Deniro eight the fucking ag
and and Angel Heart.
When he wanted to scam Mickey Rourke,
he just,
hey,
that's how I do it.
I put a piece of bacon in my mouth and
then I'd take the other piece of wheat
toast,
put the egg yolk on that.
I take the other piece of banking and
they ate my fruit and that's fucking it.
That's beautiful.
I got ap Egg Yolk,
the egg yolk,
and as you can eat three egg yolks,
but you could also scramble for eggs,
getting a Tortilla,
put black beans in it and the salsa.
All that costs you is the fucking
Tortilla dog.
Why four points where you can have a
full fucking point breakfast.
I need a bowl of fruit and get brand
fucking new dog.
It's amazing.
That's a great scene.
A great download is creepy fingernails.
Remember you bro.
You much a mother for these two guys
were such motherfuckers.
It's so funny.
Oh,
from Brooke.
How crazy.
I don't believe in that Mumbo jumbo.
I mean the top these guys where the
basketball,
he just told you believe that the ag is
the symbol of the soul and some
religions looking.
You see how skin,
I don't know,
but this face when he's eating that ag,
show me.
Show me that again.
That's a brief looking at Mickey.
Rourke's raised handsome fella.
Yeah,
but poor fucking Mecca.
Look at his face.
Not exaggerated.
That's the devil.
That's about as good as a human being is
ever going to an impression of what
the devil would look like if he's a
human being.
Seriously,
yeah.
He wouldn't be free.
Who else played the devil by J.
Dot.
O when he would do those crazy devo red,
remember it was all that.
Every movie had to have a rant.
I'm fucking tired.
Right?
He went through a whole period of time.
Whereas brands are so powerful.
They're like,
how al l,
here's what we're going to put the ramp
right here like right.
His rants were fucking phenomenal.
I mean how Pachino is scar face,
right?
I mean,
who has,
who has more epic screaming rants in
film history then Al,
but Chino?
I'd say zero,
but I'll tell you something else about
Al Pachino.
Look at them.
Nobody's had a bitch is hard.
Everyone one on tv on Pachino.
He smacked her sister in scar face.
At least smack that chicken.
The Godfather when she told him she had
an abortion.
Yeah.
Like relax.
He really had a blast.
Him Dude.
It looks scary.
Like he looks like he hit her.
I give,
it looks like if you an actress and you
never got hit like that before,
you'd be like,
oh my God.
Steve McQueen and Allie McGraw real.
That was real.
It was real.
It wasn't even supposed to be in the
seat right smack the just out of
principle.
Have you ever seen that?
Seen Jamie?
Oh,
we showed it before show before.
It was just so repetitive.
No,
no,
no.
That's sweet folks.
That's what you get.
You get the fun stuff,
but you also get,
who else memory about a thousand deals
now said Dale is,
I also heard that fucking,
did they role play the Dracula?
Oh yeah,
that,
oh no,
no.
Gary,
Gary Oldman.
Sorry.
No,
but didn't,
didn't near a play the Dracula in
something?
No.
It Prank Frankenstein Deniro played
Frankenstein ones.
What does he to be good?
I was terrible movie.
It was one of those ones where you're
like,
wait,
what?
It was weird actually.
He was pretty good as a,
as a monster though.
He's there.
All the actors that played the devil for
movies.
What was Kaiser?
So say he wasn't the devil,
right?
Yeah.
Waze.
Sure.
Wow.
A lot of people.
Jennifer Love Hewitt played the devil.
Jesus Christ.
John Ritter plead the devil.
John Ritter did a a couple episodes and
news radio.
Look at that.
At least one.
Hold on.
We'll look at Vincent Price,
Bro.
Vincent Price.
Who was fucking just amazing.
He really was.
But some of those movies,
he did like two movies that really
scared the shit out of me.
Yeah.
What?
What did he do?
Which movies did he do that was to,
I'm trying to remember.
There was a lot of like really fun
movies back then that if you watch
today,
you're like,
what the fuck?
He was definitely a Batman.
Right?
What was he on?
Batman?
Um,
house on haunted hill.
There's,
there's his thing,
house of wax that was a big one.
House of wax was a big one.
The last man on earth.
He was always,
it was like thought of,
is that like real good creepy actor
guy?
Okay.
Who's good in scary movies?
What's his imd be?
I wonder if he was a bad,
bad.
Yeah.
Yeah,
it was.
If he was in Vincent Price,
he was in and [inaudible] funny how a
guy gets like synonymous with a genre.
Movies like Vincent Price.
You think of it all scary movies.
You know,
there's a few guys like that.
You think of their name.
Oh,
scary movie.
You Know John Romero,
You know dawn of the dead.
Okay.
That's filled.
Low TV on.
That's his name,
right?
John Romero.
John Romero did what?
George Romero.
John Romero is a guy who was a game
developer and the early days of a doom,
he was with id software like doom and
quake and those kinds of games.
No,
George Romero was to guide that on
paper.
Officially started this whole Zombie
fucking shit much,
right when we were kids,
the dead and the other one dog,
he has what's seen in one of those that
had to be 1975 I was maybe 12 years old,
maybe 13 one of those came out and we
took a hit of acid and we all went to
the movie theater on a Saturday.
Take the number one bus,
Jersey City,
and they would play two of these movies.
Dollar Dan and something else,
right of the living dead or something.
Fucking that night of the living dead
was the first one.
There's one scene where the black guy's
goal for the helicopter,
they just chops his head off.
Jesus fucking Christ.
I run out of the movies was scare the
living shit.
I Dunno how many times I took the number
one bus to go to Jersey City,
the Journal Square.
There was a movie theater dog.
That's why I saw Richard Pryor live at
the sunset strip the first time on a
Friday night I got stabbed.
That's so nice.
You got stabbed.
He's got caught.
I still got the scar.
That's where I saw the pink panther
movies.
That was my first John.
And to getting high and go into the
movies.
Like I knew I couldn't go to the movies
and Wartburg and he didn't city cause
I'd bumped into one of my mother's
friends or something.
So me and my little goombas figured out
if we went to Jersey City,
we could get on the bus,
cause little drama,
get the six pack,
split it four ways and smoke a joint and
go into those movies and Giggle and act
like I'm an asshole.
We also went down to the sea,
the Groove Tube and Kentucky Fried and
Movie Kentucky fried movie was a genre
that stone for Saturday night live.
And there was a movie put together by a
bunch of sketches,
but one of the famous sketches is the in
a court room and uh,
and there's a gorilla fucking people up.
Yeah.
They would just say different stupid
things and the fucking guy go,
yeah,
that was loony.
They Teddy's fucking do this movie
today.
You too,
by the way.
This was on hbo where we were killing
me.
All right,
Jamie.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
This is on Hbo.
So you had a talk to your mother and to
get an HPO because groove tube or
Kentucky fried movie was going to be on
and they were hilarious.
Could never have this movie.
Yes,
she's good.
And gang triggers.
Yes you could.
You could do this move.
They don't have the balls to do this
movie tonight.
Girls are getting pie and look at this.
Look at this.
Look at this shit.
This is crazy.
You can never do this in movie today.
And a regular movie,
they would never allow that.
Catholic high school girls in trouble
and the guys banging the girl on the
shower and you see her tits pressing up
against the glass,
like legitimately see everything.
American pie was not,
I mean it's not a sketch thing,
but it wasn't too far different.
No,
but even American pie.
I think you'd struggle to do that now.
I think the climate shifts,
no,
we're just still a part of America loves
this type of humor.
Joe Rogan no know that trying to,
they took f1 grid girls out of Formula
One racing the grid girls like hot wing.
They took them out and now they're
petitioning to take octagon girls out
and ring card girls.
They're saying like,
we need to stop this like,
and they're like,
what are you talking about?
It's how we make a living stupid.
Like what?
Woo Hoo.
It's the objectification of women.
I think if you can have chippendales and
you can have,
I think you should ever end card boys
see who gets hired.
Joey,
what happened?
Just cause people are crazy people,
you know.
Do your mind,
you,
you made a point the other day with
those two young men that,
uh,
I don't want to quote you.
You said something about that as a,
somebody got mad at people with a
vagina,
hats
black,
which I was transgender charters were
mad because it represents the woman's
march and not everyone who was a woman
has a vagina that was there.
There were upset.
It's transport.
Holy Fuck
of it.
As much as an American,
as you will hold.
I'm fucking done.
I'm done.
I don't know what else to do.
I mean,
three months ago,
uh,
the fucking,
some guy came out with a brilliant
movie,
Stephen King that scan everybody that
did not,
it wasn't number one film about a clown.
Yeah.
And all of a sudden there was a parade.
You know,
they got together.
Clowns marched in protection of clowns
because ever since that movie came out,
a bunch of clowns lost that job.
Oh my God.
In the spring,
they were booked for the fall.
So they belong.
You know,
we'll get into something now that's just
totally out of control.
I read the Amy Schumer thing with the on
Xeon Zari,
I read,
uh,
you know,
you try to not avoid everything,
but it's right in front of you.
You know,
every day there's something else,
you know,
he just waiting for the fucking shoe to
drop every day.
I am going to continue to be who I am,
John Rowe and on stage.
I don't really give a fuck sensitive.
I can't.
I'm a stand up.
I can't,
I don't have time.
I think about it.
I would.
I also watched the podcast of you with
Brendan and Brian and you talked about
something that didn't happen to no,
no.
It did happen to me where I was at a a
child children's school at a fair and a,
and I tried to turn it into a bit.
I just couldn't sell it to be funny.
Kid was playing in front of me and I
could tell there was something not right
with the child.
And some of the child called him a
faggot and the kid's mother came out.
She goes,
he's not a fact that he's a transgender.
And then the mother came up to me,
I'm high as fuck.
How old were you?
Two.
This is three months ago.
Okay,
this is three months ago at a park.
You know before you go to those events,
you get tuned up and you put [inaudible]
in your eyes and you go down and you try
to be as nice as you can as a parent,
but you tried to avoid talking to a lot
of people.
Your wife does all the talking.
You just sit there and wave the people I
and why?
Who Do you think's in the wouldn't
Machida.
Yeah,
Machida and you're just,
you're just watching the girls.
You know what I'm saying?
You try to do that,
but there's always something that,
those events that you get back in the
car with your wife and go,
Mrs Rogan,
what the fuck was that about?
And then they'll break it down for you,
Tami,
I'm lying to you at every fucking thing.
It's like you,
you were talking about the people
believe in the earth that there was no
Adam and eve.
That's what I'm striving to.
When you were telling that bit.
I didn't know what the fuck he would
talk about.
I go,
who does he hang out with?
This is what's,
yeah,
with this poor bastard.
But now that I have a child that's five,
I'm getting up to see different people's
views that are my age.
And this lady came up to me and gave me
a whole here beat how the kid is 15 they
have my medication and he's known he was
a woman since he was nine and that,
uh,
but then she fucked up Joe Rogan.
She said she always wanted a girl
anyway,
knowing Jesus.
But you guys are talking about something
about there was of somebody or they've
got in trouble for a three year old,
give them block and see,
I don't want nothing about that world.
I know nothing.
Oh,
and Benjamin,
you've got in trouble.
Get fired from his agency.
They dropped him because he was tweeting
a bunch of shit about someone using
hormone blockers on a three year old.
He's like,
this is crazy.
What I listened to that day and where I
live.
I thought my head was gonna blow up and
her when she came over and explained why
he was going to be a trend again.
Well,
here's the thing.
Here's my thing.
If kids behaving a certain way,
let him keep behaving that way you don't
have to fucking throw hormones in the
mix.
You don't even know what's going to
happen when you do that.
You're going to change who he is.
So you're telling me that he has this
urge to take hormones that are not
native in his body and the same amounts.
He's this urge to do this,
so we should just let them do it.
No,
he has an urge to be identified as a
woman.
Like you don't even have to do anything
to do that.
If you just decide you identify as a
woman,
most people are going to be cool with
it.
Like we're saying that a child has to
take some chemicals in the middle of
their developmental cycle.
This is the only way we can do this.
This is the smart way.
This is a smart way when they're six or
16 or whatever it is.
That's crazy.
That doesn't make sense.
From a developmental standpoint,
like I'm not a scientist,
but I understand enough about the stages
that the human being goes through before
it reaches adulthood and you're not
really completely formed until you're
like 20 years old or 25 years old or
something like that.
It's like the frontal Cortex does inform
to your 25 so your decision making is
always a little weird.
So you don't have $12 what the fuck they
want to be at Fifth Katelyn?
16 six or a three though.
She said that he knew it done.
Come on and I went home.
I told my wife,
my wife said,
well you got to watch a show or be week.
Are they eight is a show about kids that
want to,
you know,
make the child listen.
It doesn't matter.
It's just that I'm trying to,
I'm trying to tell you that I'm finding
out about shit now though.
But you know,
it's weird.
It's like why?
Why does if someone feels a certain way,
they feel they are a certain way and why
did they have to take chemicals to
achieve a new state?
Like what?
What is like the identify with being a
woman so they have to take chemicals to
reach this state.
I think man,
if I was a person who was a transgender
person listened to me talk,
I'd be like,
shut the fuck up.
You don't know shit about that.
But a lot of you cheered if you're
listening to this,
but that all I'm saying is that this is
a very unusual situation.
It's very unusual.
I don't think it's a bad thing,
but I think that doing it to someone who
really can't fully make up their mind
yet just seems insanely risky and what,
what could happen to the kid could be
terrible and people have made successful
transitions when they'd transitioned in
their thirties you don't have to do it
when you're six if you want to be a
transgender person and union thirties
sure.
Where your 20s or whenever we decide
that a human being is rationally capable
of making full life decisions that are
as dramatic that that's what I thought.
I was like,
what the fuck makes a good decision at
six days?
You know,
but it does matter what he want a 25
that doesn't mean that someone had 16
who thinks they're a woman.
Couldn't absolutely become one later and
be super,
super happy with it.
That's not,
I'm not saying that's not possible
either.
Like everything's possible.
There's a thing for everybody and if
that is what you feel like is your,
your thing,
you want to be that.
That's just your,
it's who you identify with and you,
you have every right,
you have every right to do that.
So what you're saying,
probably you know how many fucking drugs
I did between 16 and 20 a lie.
It's not funny.
You did a lot of drugs from the time I
met you.
You were the fact that you had a heavier
schedule before that.
No,
but I'm talking about like I,
I tried to stay away like I was a karate
guy.
Like you and the kids from karate on
Saturdays.
They were geeks.
We either went to a martial art
festival,
we competed or we went to a karate movie
or we went to a Honda martial arts
supply.
Hi Man.
Those places.
So we saved our money.
Like would you want to go to the movies
and see the five deadly hands?
No,
no.
We've got to save our money.
We're going to Honda next week to buy a
kaboodle time.
Fuck.
Like we would always buy like the ones
that you'd hold,
uh,
with the,
just so you know,
I don't fuck around g money.
What are you drawing?
This is what,
if you look at you,
you know how to write Chinese letters.
Yeah.
If you look at those old Chinese things,
they all had this side.
That's how you wrote karate.
That's how you wow.
Roland karate like that.
So you would,
I knew all about this.
You would buy the,
the handle that I would hold the ones
where you wouldn't take one dog,
they had the water at the top and they
had for riches of canvas.
And you would stand in front of it and
you mock url,
Maki war and they would have like,
you would get nuts guys.
Really?
Oh my gosh.
And then we would save our money.
We would geeks.
That's what we did at 12 but to had a
little Goombas and my neighborhood and
when they were 12 they did something
completely different.
They went behind the school and they
would row one joy and put it in a piece
of glass tube and,
and light it up.
And we would drink a boone's farm.
Oh,
the fruit shit.
And I'd get pukey so I didn't know who
to hang out with.
So I would have to be like a double a
check.
That was a tough job for me as a 12 year
old.
I liked hanging out with my karate
geeks.
You know what I'm saying?
I like going to competitions.
I like doing forms.
I like doing the semi contact
competitions where you couldn't kick
above the head.
Yeah,
those are good for kids,
but you don't like it that way.
But you still kick the kid and get
disqualified.
But fuck fucking.
I think the joy of that,
just seeing,
you know,
people did that.
This is when life was simple for me.
This was so I had to make a decision
because the Kung Fu kids didn't get no
pussy.
They just weren't into policy.
They would talk about girls and they may
be had a crush on the girl and the four
30 class,
but they never asked to accompany of the
events.
My other buddies went to pussy,
so eventually I cut the karate fucking
geeks out and I started hanging out with
a little,
the druggies and you make your
transition into and from those
developmental ages,
like I tried to hide my drug use.
I tried to hide,
especially with marijuana use for two or
three years.
It was just marijuana.
While then,
once I became a freshman,
got it and start basketball.
My freshman year I decided to let's
venture out into this acid thing.
Let's venture into this masculine thing.
It was a different name.
It was masculine,
but it really wasn't mescal and Joe
Rogan.
It
was a little tag.
Cody,
it would know,
wasn't even pay on it.
It was a little thing.
I did the same shoes.
Me Isn't Paoli Mba,
but masculine is what they saw you in
the south.
They supposedly put in Tequila as
something that's a sow,
right?
Yeah.
This is something that two little
fucking white kids made in a pill.
It was rat poison,
but something else and something else
and it was very tiny.
It was maybe a little size of this.
That's it.
And it came in aluminum foil.
Even smaller than that.
Wow.
Even smaller than that,
way smaller,
that sort of thing that that's it.
You paid $80 for it and you got a
hundred of those and you're struggling
for $3 a piece and that would fuck you
up for six hours with a two hour hayes
in between an hour buffer.
I want to come down and I did that for
three or four months.
Then they introduced me to thc crystal,
which is snorting.
They sold it as,
what we do is we got a bunch of stems
and seeds from the reefer.
We put it in a pot and we boil that pot
and whatever separate from the stems and
the seeds that goes to the sides.
We scraped that off.
And that's where you snot in your nose.
Oh my God.
So I was,
I was,
I had like a personal karate rule cause
I would always just smoke it and do the
masculine,
but I was never going to put nothing in
my nose.
Oh,
you had a rule?
Like a drug addict puts something in
their nose.
Like that's it.
Like that's a complete different range.
I'll never shoot heroin and I never was,
especially at my karate man as a carotid
man.
Right.
Carotid morals.
I was just straight away with the reef.
And then I finally ended up snorting
that fucking gorilla biscuits because
that's what it was.
It was angel dust.
They just told you.
And I went under the Angel Dust Tab.
Like every Sunday me and my friend
Carlos Perez would buy a six pack of
Michelob.
He only like Michelob.
He has good friends tonight in this kind
of special to appear with the beer will
pour must say something more.
Call it as long brow.
Low Brow.
What are we talking about?
Michelob.
No we would,
we would drink low brow,
low brow.
That one we would get a six pack on the
eyebrow and fucking snot.
A $10 package of the crystal and mother
would go to the track on Sundays.
So I knew she wouldn't come back til
seven so me and him would snow in it as
soon as my mother stepped foot in that
car and 11 being hit with having and
we'd snorting it and then fucking just
sit around like and be fucking zombies
all day.
But that was a development and then I
went after my mom got it.
Just want to and acid tab fucking a year
or God knows
what was in those goddamn things.
God fucking know what's going on here.
Well on rock commercial,
Oh this is,
oh my God,
look at that guy.
This is like a sketch.
It's a truly great American beer.
Why?
Why does it have an American name
motherfucker?
What are you embarrassed you embarrassed
to be from here?
American beer.
Low and proud.
Fucking drink low brows.
Shit.
Actually it isn't American beer,
right?
That's like steep amy.
Oh check.
Keep your fucking real name.
That's as American as it gets.
And she's still around.
Lowenbrau I don't know.
But if they said low and breath,
that was their name and they started the
beer company and it didn't change her
name.
That's as American as it gets.
So I'm wrong.
I should shut the fuck up.
It's even looking it up.
It's the German brewery.
Liars.
Liars line about American American made.
Apparently they make a lot of American
American plants make a lot of cars now
that you think are Japanese cars like
Toyota Tundras.
They make them in Texas can make a bunch
of them in Ohio too.
Honda's Nissan's.
That's weird,
right?
Like if you think you'd buy in a Honda,
you sink.
You're definitely buying a Japanese car.
If you think you're buying some American
cars,
it might be a Mexican car.
How crazy is that?
Like what companies making their cars
down in Mexico?
I think they,
I think they closed a couple of plants.
I think Toyota was down there.
Somebody else for a while.
But here's the thing,
if they put him down in Mexico,
but they gave him American money,
like the levels of American money that's
in Mexico,
they would stop doing it a lot actually.
Wow.
Look at all these different ones.
Chrysler has three plants,
four to three plans.
GM is four plans.
Moms does one,
they do it down there cause it's
cheaper,
which I guess they have to do what they
gotta do and I'm sure it helps the
community because then I know it does.
I know people that have had
manufacturing down in these countries
and they do it for the cheap,
but it does help the people.
Like there's some places that don't have
much,
but what's arguable is like why is
living like a western person so
important when these people have been
living in their own way for thousands of
years.
It's just they just didn't have like all
the crazy infrastructure and all the
shit that we had.
They didn't have the crazy cities.
And you know other than a few cities in
Mexico like Mexico City.
So they would go and put these plants
and like why is it doing,
I mean I don't,
I'm all for people being able to work.
But is that better?
Is it better than the way they were
living before when they were living like
indigenous people are living like
villagers are living like trades people
or whatever they did to get by.
I Dunno.
Maybe it is better.
Maybe it's,
let's go back to the whole situation
here.
I still remember,
cause I'm a little older than us storm,
remember where it was kind of starting
to get that bull if you bought a foreign
car like I,
I'm bad old ways.
I'm not sure that that,
I still remember the La
mid seventies I still remember when
Toyota advertised or Nissan advertised
the car for 1995 and I would go,
wait a second,
I got $40 in the bank.
I could buy one of those.
It was $1,900
stupid like a corolla or something.
And I still remember there was a time in
this country when if you bought of what
if you were on the first person on this
block.
If you showed up with a foreign car,
you got a little bit of grief,
and then it felt like they sold
themselves.
It felt like we dropped the ball at some
point.
As Americans,
as you know,
I don't know what happened to Detroit
and all that stuff.
I know that where's the highest
populations of Puerto Rico in this
country?
I don't know.
You think it's the bronx,
but it's not.
It's a suburb outside of Cleveland.
Why?
Because in the 50s they took a bunch of
Puerto Ricans and put them into this
suburb to work at the car plants.
All the car plants shut down at that.
We ended up going other places and
whatever and blah,
blah,
blah and blah,
and then the foreign car and started
checking our fucking ass.
Why again?
I don't know.
What's it?
The workmanship?
Was it the quality?
All I know is if,
if I got a fucking Toyota,
I could drive it for 80,000
miles without stopping to get gas.
You know what I'm saying?
You as a consumer and as an American,
you want to buy American products and
you want to buy American made products,
you know?
So there's a couple of places now like
beside Mexico,
there's,
where are we?
We have places now,
like in Indiana we had like,
Toyota has a couple of places and they
should bring it back.
I mean,
Eh,
fuck it.
Let some,
you know,
so we trade,
we get someone to tell you all of this
stuff,
which is a,
what kind of car are they?
Japanese or Chinese or Japanese?
Japanese and let some of our strict get
made over there as part of,
is it Nafta?
Um,
that's North American,
North American free trade agreement.
So that's just,
I think,
I think I'm just talking about my
answer,
but I think that's just us.
Mexico and Canada.
So when we build a car in Mexico,
it's a lot cheaper.
Develop that car because of the rate.
Yeah,
they pay,
people pay feel blessed.
It's cheaper to get land.
These people don't have anything else
going on down there or not as much going
on down there.
Obviously as they do in America and some
like heavily populated cities and so
they can offer people much less money
and they do it.
There's a lot of plants that do that,
but here's the thing,
it's the real question is do you think
that this is just going to elevate these
people and they're eventually going to
catch up with the Western world and live
the way that we're living right now in
the United States?
Like there's ultimately a possibility of
that or are we saying,
well,
we're always going to have these people
that would treat less good and we're
just always going to keep them in that
position.
They're never going to get any better.
I mean,
what?
Which one is it?
It's either one of those two things or I
made it possibly be that people just
want shit cheaper,
so bad.
They don't care.
They don't care if a guy's making a
dollar a week or whatever the fuck they
make.
How much do they make?
If you had to guess,
if you guess,
how much does someone in a um,
uh,
an automobile plant in Mexico make as
opposed to an American worker?
I'm sure someone must have done some
sort of a study.
It's weird,
man,
because if they were doing the exact
same thing on this patch of dirt,
we would go,
what?
You can't pay that little?
Then you say,
oh,
but down there,
everything's cheaper.
And the given these people an
opportunity like why is it better?
Here's the question.
Why is it better than the way they've
always been living in Mexico?
$2 per hour workers make $40,000
suv is $2 an hour.
Jesus Christ to imagine a person working
all day and you hand them $16 you sir
are a piece of shit.
Could you imagine guy busts his ass on
an assembly line all day?
You give him $16 fuck you.
That's crazy.
Started a dollar 10 an hour.
Oh my God.
A dollar an hour.
You make more than prison.
That is ridiculous.
And that's Mexican money.
That's American money.
A dollar a day,
$2 and hour.
Maybe it's like the translated joe would
go,
fuck,
that's insane.
But it's,
it's just the idea is that if you're
always going to be able to,
you got to always be able to make more
money.
Like these people have this idea in,
a lot of these corporations have
unlimited growth.
They just want to constantly be growing
and growing and growing.
It's some people think it's a very
dangerous idea because if you're your
bottom line for your companies to always
outdo every quarter at a certain time,
people start getting desperate and they
start cutting environmental corners or
cut and research corners.
They're doing whatever the fuck they
have to do to keep their bottom line
down and keep their profits coming in.
And that's what you could say about like
these prescription drug companies,
people want to think that these
companies are evil.
They're companies.
Their job is to make money,
okay?
And they're caught up in a storm where
they're allowed to make legal money and
this legal money is fucking substantial.
It's a giant amount of money these
pharmaceutical companies are making on
an opiate,
so people are dying left and right.
Joey left and right.
This is one of the craziest,
unspoken Emmett epidemics.
The human race to a little bit forever.
You the truth of everything.
I still talked to my truck.
It was good to me when I needed them.
And from month to month I still taught
for the Armenian.
I still talk to Don sleazy and in fact
the hustle.
He's,
he just did a big movie.
You got a couple of lines of big movie.
That's awesome.
They do what they do.
I do what I do.
I have a family.
I got a call from the guy made him,
I saw him at rouse.
You have bet you did.
Do you see do about the Armenian?
This is one of my favorite bits.
All of the army that routes.
He gave me a hug and all with his kids
and kids.
Are you right now?
You'll know how many times I met him
with his kids and he would put an eight
ball in my head.
You know,
I've been in that position now.
I had groceries and I hugged him and he
goes,
you mind if I call you later?
You know,
and I go,
she'll call me whatever you want.
And he goes,
uh,
do you,
where do you live?
And I told him,
and he goes,
I live here.
Can I meet you?
I went to ask you a question.
I didn't know.
I thought he was going to ask me if I
still did blow.
I didn't know.
I,
you know,
I'm,
I'm good,
I'm good.
And when I met the men meet him,
what he wanted to know was,
he goes,
you're a comedian.
And uh,
I just wanted to ask if you knew anybody
who,
Eh,
get pills.
And I go,
I got a Xanax at the house and you're
free to take them.
He goes,
no,
no.
I talking pain.
I see.
Or whatever.
Again,
like shook his hand.
I gave him a hug.
Joe Rogan,
I don't know nobody,
I don't know.
A week later I told him I'd to ask,
cause I do know a guy kind of saw the
white dude in Hollywood and I called him
like I was a week later they are meeting
and called me and he goes and I go,
you know what?
I'm sorry,
hold on.
And I went,
I looked when I called this white dude
and he called me back and he said,
ah,
give me a couple of days,
you know?
And he called me back and what he told
me was mind boggling what he's done,
the prices.
I went just getting what you pay for
pharmaceutical.
He hit me back and he told me three
numbers on the phone with three
different names of what this guy had.
And I'm not a drug dealer.
I called the Armenian and I just said,
listen,
this is what they told me and this is
what he wants.
And the guy goes,
okay,
don't tell him in a week I get a
thousand.
Um,
I could not believe the amount of money
for these pills.
Rarely,
you know,
I never was a big pill head,
but oh my God,
the black market for pills is fucking
ginormous.
And I knew this kid and Hollywood will
come through,
I know him
15 years,
he's a big Jujitsu guy door and they
can't close it.
It is mind boggling what you pay for
pills.
Well,
you know what happened,
right?
You know what?
We've got it all started.
Well,
this is what happened.
First of all,
they're obviously very addictive.
Um,
second of all,
something happened in Florida where they
allowed people to get the all clinic
prescription pain clinics everywhere.
It was basically what offtrack betting
is for gambling.
That was heroin,
heroin,
60 minutes show me,
everybody's got an ache.
You know,
sometimes my fucking neck bothers me
after a couple of podcasts,
I need to get a little oxy,
my back,
just I can't sleep.
Here you go.
Have some oxy.
They would have a pharmacy attached to a
doctor's office town of 3,200
was flooded with neuro 21 million pain
pills as addiction crisis worsen.
Lawmakers say,
whoa.
A town of 3,200
people was flooded with 21 million pain
pills town in West Virginia.
Jesus Christ.
People in,
in those towns like from the wild and
wonderful west of West Virginia.
What does that,
the whites of West Virginia remember
that well,
wonderful.
Well what kind of wild and wonderful
whites of West Virginia oxies,
Xanax,
nick,
whatever the fuck you got.
The little ones.
I got the little ones for anxiety.
You know,
you take an anxiety.
I get them lately before I get,
like if I haven't gone in the road for a
while.
Oh really?
That Thursday morning.
Oh my God.
Joe Rogan.
As I'm getting ready,
I keep thinking like I'm fucking not
packing.
Right.
I forgot something.
I forgot the holes of sleep apnea and
I've been buying half of it.
And you know what?
I even fall asleep.
I got out of the plane and I fall
asleep.
But on the road people give me weird,
creepy things and it's so blackberry is
so that I just go to Web Deb d and You
looked for a pill indicator and if
there's something good,
I'll save it.
Cause at least I got to live.
If I ever have an emergency,
if I'm lonely with or something,
you're capo,
these little pills,
you know?
Wow.
But when the dog,
when they told me that,
like I knew when I was a kid,
I would go to central,
uh,
to Washington square park and I could
get eight,
10 milligram Vallian with the V in the
middle.
That's the real deal.
When you're going to fuck,
and they got a v in the middle of cut
out all the shit.
That's the shit of Mac daddies.
I could get eight of those for $10 and
that would,
here's the question.
Do you think if it was legal,
more or less people to use it or the
same?
Why are you,
what is this trick points?
Thursday?
I'm curious what you gambling and drugs.
Pills you give people the green
greenlight dog.
We're fucking,
we're crap creatures of habit.
We're all going to fucking go.
Some of us are going to control it.
Listen to some people that get knee
surgery and neck surgery like yourself
and you thrown away the Vicodin and
there's other people that take that
prescription and two years later they're
shooting heroin.
Yeah,
I don't understand that.
Okay.
I have different holes in our jeans,
Bro.
Well,
there's some people that like pain.
I'm not one of them,
but there's some people that genuinely
like it.
They get pleasure out of it.
What kind of pain do you like?
I mean,
what kind of pain?
I don't think this is what I'm saying.
This is the question.
I think they think there are syndromes
where,
and it's probably fairly common,
it turns,
it's not just one person.
It's like several people that could
point out that uh,
experienced actual like pleasure,
like a serotonin burst from certain
amounts of pain.
They don't feel,
I don't think they feel it is the way we
feel it.
And so they're always trying to do
things to themselves and they say that
some of the people that get like a lot
of piercings have that,
uh,
some people that get a lot of tattoos
have that.
They start to feel the want to feel it
more.
They want to burn it into themselves.
It's an I.
Dot.
I'm not,
obviously not a psychologist,
but it's apparently a pretty common
theory.
Another day I want to talk to you about,
I was the pub cash can believe.
I have to say I'm not a psychiatry.
I love to podcast where you were talking
about cause I want to do,
to really tell you the truth.
The podcast are,
you were talking about,
that may be some,
the Jones John Jones actions were caused
by head injuries.
Could easily been.
I tell you not caused by,
not caused by cause he usually could be
a fact.
I got to tell you something.
Joe Rogan,
uh,
again.
Well,
let's go back to abuse from gambling or
pills.
The mind with cocaine is a very tricky
mine.
Oh yeah.
And it takes a year off.
I'm just telling you this from
experience because I learned a lot about
new tropics from you.
I don't really know much about it,
but Roman [inaudible] sent me two of his
jugs.
It's the ship that neuro one,
the orange juice.
But that's not shit that got me into
nootropics when I got off cocaine that
came in the mail and I really drank and
I didn't tell nobody my secret because I
knew,
especially for a guy like me,
you know,
John Jones is 26 years old.
He's a phenomenal fighter.
I didn't think that it really had
anything to do with any other thing.
I think it was that when you were on
cocaine and that year afterward,
cocaine,
thanks to pleasure patterns out of your
mind.
I'll be your brain.
It's not the same or tone and the
Melatonin.
I don't know.
Don't correct me on this,
but I feel that it took me a year to 18
months for me to just become a human
again and I haven't gotten hit in the
head.
Not since I was about 13 I got beat up
by the guy.
I tried the Mug and I got hit in the
head with a flashlight.
It really took me 18 months to embrace
your man.
Yeah.
Again.
I want you to remember that.
I want you to think of that morning,
what happened in Santa Fe with when he
ran the light and he ran away from that.
What?
What was he,
Jamie,
do you think he just woke up and was
going to church?
No,
he was out the night before.
Yeah.
He could have very well been out from
the night.
There's no pleasure.
You know,
you take,
it takes your mind a long time.
You know what's the thing?
When I get off the juice,
I got to do something for my boss to
grow again.
You'd have to take something called
clomiphene.
Okay,
and what?
Well,
there's a couple of different ones.
Apparently a,
it's an estrogen blocker.
It blocks your estrogen.
That's actually one of the things that
John tested positive.
So how long would it take for me to get
my balls back again?
It'd take you a little while.
Hey Ben,
he stayed here the amount of time that
you were doing it.
Oh,
see if that's why you're only supposed
to go on like a short cycle unless
you're a crazy bodybuilder guy.
Those guys just stay on it all the time.
Thing with the cocaine,
Bro.
I thought about your statement and I
went home and started writing and
thinking
I got off November,
2007 it took me a year and a half just
to become a human being to realize I was
fat.
I was 400 pounds.
I need it to go to weight watchers.
Took me 18 months to realize I hadn't
married.
My wife took me a long time for my brain
to think normal.
Like anybody else does.
Right.
So I want you to take that into
consideration.
Or deb.
I definitely do.
I know you're saying,
I agree to me a long time.
You know when you do blow,
when you go on stage to say,
if I do blow three nights in a week and
I go on stage,
I have no control.
Joe Rogan,
I'm looking at you in the face.
You see me on stage.
I have no control.
I have no connection from my brain to
what's coming out of my mouth.
I can't.
Now you're going,
do you,
are you speaking to rats now?
Uh,
it was empty words.
There was no passion behind that.
That's why it wasn't funny.
You know,
you said to me,
you said it blocks love.
It blocks the love.
That's it.
The love in between my,
the cocaine in my words is gone.
But that's what stimulus do.
Stimulants or ramp up the aggression and
the impulsiveness and they ramp up your
fearlessness.
They ramp up your courage and get
disproportionate.
They ramp up your ego like some
stimulants on some people.
Some people obviously look to people
that can handle booze and these people
that can't amble even a little booze.
And I think that's the same with
stimulants.
I think that's the same with pretty much
everything,
every almost every life experience.
In fact,
I think there's some people that can
handle things and some people that can't
and some people that can't at first,
then they eventually learn to.
Um,
someone sent me something about Rodney
Dangerfield was fucking great man.
All from New York Times,
the relentless thing.
Yeah,
it was great.
John.
John Dudley sent it to me.
Fucking a,
it was amazing.
Yeah,
I read that.
It's amazing.
Oh No.
Tait Fletcher.
San Antonio's great.
It was tate.
Shout out to take flincher where tate a
jam letter of recommendation.
Rodney dangerfield.
It is an amazing piece.
Who wrote this?
What does the name of the gentleman,
Alex,
how stat Alex,
you made a masterpiece.
That's a fucking hell of an article
about one of the greatest of all time
when it comes to standup comedy.
And he just talks about the evolution of
Rodney dangerfield and how like it
wasn't until he was like in his fifties
and he really fucking got it together
like and became the great standup that
we know him as and his process for
boiling down as material.
Joey,
it's a fucking amazing article.
I read it two times,
so I look,
I get tism.
What do you want to do?
We to do this special?
Yes.
We're going to do a special,
I'm going to direct your comedy special.
We're just going to figure out when to
do it and where to do it.
In June at the Ice House.
The Ice House is the place I think.
Yeah.
Let's do six shows.
Let's do six.
Let's do,
let's do I want to do to Thursday to
Friday to Saturday.
Boom.
I want to get those
crazy week.
Savages is a different kind of animal
that goes out on Thursday night.
One hour there.
They're a little more ramped up for one
hour,
15 minutes.
You Go,
you're going to go crazies.
We're going to do,
I would just want it.
We're going to capture the real Joey
Diaz experience and we're going to put
together a special,
that's it.
We're done June in a ice house.
We'll give everybody a the details,
but this is the first special that I've
ever even attempted to do something with
other than my own.
So listen,
you would be the guy that they would do
with fucking crazy.
Yeah.
I think I picked the name of it is a
immigrant because the towel,
the immigrant mentality is proof with
respect to pay me.
That's perfect.
That's a perfect name and the perfect
fucking name of the album.
Okay,
beautiful.
I'm already in process to write and I'm
ready to go.
I think the ice house is the place we'd
been there a million times.
It's home.
It's family.
Oh my God.
It's all,
yeah,
it's a great place to film and when that
place gets Rockin Holy Shit.
It's going to Colorado.
I'm going to Colorado.
I'm flying in a day early.
I'm interviewing Antonio La Dzio.
I'm going to go show people were
kidnapped.
Bella doesn't show pupil the halfway
house.
I'm going to walk around Bova I book
tape all that and I'm going to have that
up this fucking spring.
I got some shit.
I'm planning.
I want to do like a little mixed tape
type of stand up drop.
We got to let these mother fuckers.
Yeah,
I'm ready to shoot the special.
They don't had a great time in
Charlotte,
man.
I knew you weren't Durham and you and I
would discuss in the comedy scene in
North Carolina.
Amazing how it was judged.
I just want to thank new people and the
week before that I was in Austin and
that place is like this last time I got
emotional and Austin like I don't know
how many times I drove from Houston to
Austin to do the open Mike on Wednesday,
Joe Rogan and that little stage,
I can tell you looking at your face five
times and now I was headlining and
selling the place.
I just didn't walk in that dog.
I did the open mic for Margie and she
would tell me,
you're too dirty for me.
You know what I'm saying?
Yeah.
I'll be at the Austin is fucking,
it's really weird to see the growth of
cities,
but not only that,
to see the growth of comedy in these
cities,
Portland,
Oregon,
like that's what happened.
That's how fidelity took over Cuba.
Just little growth in different areas
and internet that has made people more
aware of comedy.
15 years ago we would go to Houston and
be excited.
We would go to New York and maybe like
three other places.
Everything else was just a regular town
down.
And Freetown is excited about your rogue
and Bert Kreischer fucking,
uh,
the garage.
It's a Chinese girl.
Uh,
Amy Wong,
Allie Allie won.
There's a lot of grace.
I'm fucking excited about people coming
town.
You know,
it's uh,
we've seen this growth.
Like it's been an amazing,
like,
see,
I got into comedy,
I'm the tail.
And like when I got into comedy,
people were telling you to Tobar kid
because five years before that ever seen
is we're getting 1500 plus add and
features again,
2500% and have the line is we're getting
five grandpas and all of a sudden what I
got it,
I still remember the first notes he gave
us was before you guys get into comedy,
I went in to tell you what happened to
the bubble busted and he broke down what
comics are getting paid.
I didn't give a fuck.
He was just trying to discourage us.
Yeah,
he's wrong.
He's wrong.
You know what the Bible is not writing
jokes.
Yeah.
That was the Bible does the Bible in
Boston.
I'm,
I'm almost positive.
I don't know what people blame it on the
access of comedy on television at the
time.
I believe that cause the great ones are
still there.
I think what happened was there was a
lot of guys that were really,
really,
really fucking funny cause they had
taken their act and Polish that
motherfucker like a diamond and they,
they brought it to you and it was just
perfect.
It was a perfect act,
but it didn't change.
It was a perfect piece of work.
But they didn't write more.
Some guys did,
but not enough guys dead.
And so people would keep coming back to
the shows.
They'd be able to say the jokes word for
word year after year.
Like they'd go to see some guys,
they would do the same act year after
year and they never left Boston.
And it's a very unfortunate thing
because like when it comes to like
proficiency level,
there's guys like Steve Sweeney that
used to kill in a way that you're like,
oh my God,
what's the guy that used to drink the
white Russians and a container?
Don motherfucking Gavin.
Gavin is one of the stuff for guys out
in Boston.
When I started that you heard about your
boy too at the Tony Clark packing some
heat.
Let him when he was killing it.
And what's the guy that had the shows?
He was funny.
In 91,
Bro,
Anthony Clark married to Anthony Clark
was fucking throwing,
he's a merge that murder.
He used to fill the uh,
faneuil hall club with all screaming
checks.
I never saw anything like it cause he
was cute,
you know,
and he would,
he would be silly on stage.
Carl's loved him.
I mean to the point where that place,
would it be overrun with girls?
It would be like 80,
20 girls in this faneuil hall common
connection.
We'd be like,
what the fuck?
Like what are their comic brings in
girls like this,
that love him.
And then he's another one,
they'd see the same bits over and over
and over again.
They didn't care.
They would find with it.
It's weird.
It was a weird time.
What fucked everybody up was people
would go to see someone special,
like Kennison did a special and then he
tried to do the material from the
special on a show and the people already
knew the material and they were like
yelling out bits and fucking up beds.
And so I think comics then started
realizing once you do like a real
special and put it on hbo or something
like that and it makes you famous,
you got to throw that shit away and
write a completely new set.
That's why it's so tough now Tara,
because you're trying to develop your
hour on the road and you put your wire
the road and you go off and follow a
week to promote that hour and you got
the same half you got half hour or that
hour unless you're fucking Harry
Houdini.
Well now prepare for that already.
When I went through after the last time
was a big fucking lesson.
Everybody has that lesson that's going
through that right now.
I'm just putting this out.
That's it.
Yeah.
Yeah,
and those weeks when you're putting that
out,
just stay home.
Yeah,
just stay at home.
Don't embarrass you.
Don't try to do some stay home and get
15 minute bits of the show and once you
get six of those 15 minute bits,
then you go out and put 45 together.
You start from scratch and then what?
You still got 30 35 minutes.
Once you shut your bed,
once you shut that 50 minutes,
you still have 35 minutes to work on it
again.
There's no shame.
Fucking your boy is an Adam.
We stays home for a fucking year to work
on an hour and then goes out.
Russell,
Russell Peters.
Yeah,
he stays home for a long time.
He still does some gigs in the road.
Be MCS and just talks to the crowd Fox
with them,
Bro.
Shout out to our little pep part and a
Friday night.
Sound out the stamp of only the second
comic to do it.
Who sold out the staples?
Gabriel,
did he really?
Jesus Christ,
Friday,
Friday till they get game.
That's a Laker game.
Gabriel Iglesias,
hold out a Laker game Friday night at
the staples center.
Him and Kevin Hart are the only ones to
do it.
An animal and a sock to yourselves.
Murder in it.
Here's why he's funny.
Anybody can go see him.
You can take your kids to see him,
your mom to see him.
He's a nice guy.
Everybody loves him.
You're getting what you want to see.
You getting a funny comedian having a
good time.
That sounds fucking thousands.
I want to say that's at least like
18,000
people.
I think that might be 25 it might be
20,000
I think that places dog.
Here's the beautiful thing.
I still remember him paying me $35 or
the ones and I think I'll do the bicycle
club and he would host.
Wow.
How many people?
21,000
Jesus Christ.
Oh my God.
That's so many people might have 21,000
people.
Powerful.
Gabriel Iglesias.
Holy Shit.
That's nuts guy.
This fucking,
there's,
there's so many.
I'd of comedy.
He's right at the top right now.
Him and Kevin Hart and t in terms of
like being able to do that,
especially being able to do that in la.
He's a hero in La.
He's done more shows consecutively at
the Ice House and sold out like fucking
10 years ago.
He was doing that.
He would do like Monday shows,
Tuesday shows two shows,
Wednesday two shows three if it's just
fucking crank them out,
man.
He was taking people out to breakfast
after it shows.
Yeah,
I'm Christmas Eve after that,
he still got,
he still does two shows on Christmas
Eve.
That's amazing.
He could do shows at three in the
afternoon.
He would do shows to the ice house like
whenever he wanted and every path hit
three in the afternoon fucking pack.
Let's God woo people wanted to see it.
Have a couple of drinks,
watch funny comedy.
Why
not tie cut?
Just just the amount of people that are
going out the comedy.
I'm just honored to be a positive thing.
You Know Joey,
you and I have known each other for a
long time now and so we've seen like a
couple of waves.
Oh my God,
no,
nothing like nothing like this.
The fuck where you at?
The wiltern sold out and who he is and
Chappelle and John.
John Mayer at the fucking forum.
They were sold out too.
He was sold out,
but he did a warm up the night before
somewhere else like yeah,
let's just try it out just to see if it
works.
And that sold out too,
like people are out and about Jack.
Yeah.
People are out and about.
Well,
we're,
we're very,
very lucky to have dave out there right
now,
like,
like doing a lot of comedy.
Like he's the top of the food chain and
he's doing a lot of comedy.
Did two specialists last year in two
specials this year and they're fucking
good man.
One,
he did it from DC.
That is a really good special,
gosh,
that's a whole,
I enjoyed the shit.
I enjoyed the belly room too,
but yeah,
I love how I have,
I haven't seen that one.
How bout for every age?
Told you the belly room wouldn't work.
You'd go,
fuck.
They're selling belly room when you get
into a groove and the belly room.
Okay,
let me break something down here at the
comedy store and again,
you're going to go,
we heard this guy's,
no,
you haven't heard this whim because I
just found this one out fucking three
weeks ago when you got sick that night
and you couldn't,
I covered for you and the belly room.
You had the flu and they called me.
That went through the belly flew and he
flew though I heard through the belly
room and I have this shirt analogy gone
at the belly room and it just wasn't
doing it.
The belly room does it where it is.
Why at the belly room does it require
the efficiency that the original room
required?
How so?
So you'd be,
you want to slow it down a little bit
and the belly rooms out.
You're saying,
okay,
so I'm sparring with you and we're not
doing 50% we're doing 30 now,
right in the belly room.
If we do 50 it's a little too
aggressive.
That two right there,
the energy's right there,
and I learned this after 20 fucking
years of doing spots that right.
Remember the belly room was where I
learned the story though.
Before that I was rushing to the
punchline and not getting into a joke
out the belly room was where I learned
to sit back a little bit and explain
what the fuck you,
what it is you're trying to tell us why
you just kept telling me,
what did you just say?
There's no segue here.
There's nothing to joey.
You're just eating some girl's asshole
is great and we don't want to hear that.
We want to hear how you got that.
I learned that in 99 and the belly room
fucking around and I went back up there
a couple of weeks ago for me,
the main room,
I got to come out like a fuck in the
main room.
I got to come out like Mike Tyson when
he beat up.
Uh,
what?
What did he beat up in Atlantic city and
knocked him out in the 57 seconds.
Who?
He was part of one of the brothers with
the mouthpiece.
Leon spinks.
Michael spinks.
I eat dick in the main room.
I last,
I come out jasmine crossing one to a
different room.
I got to come out one,
two in the main room and the original
room,
the gauges.
Who you're following.
I gotta follow crystal lip with a,
I got who came out this year,
who came out of that and travis with a
flying sidekick riddled fabricio
version.
You got to come out with the flying side
kick at the original room.
Okay.
There's some people break it down for
you.
The original room,
you got to follow Joe Rogan,
Chris,
Leah or bill burl like I had a couple of
weeks ago.
I got to come out from the curtain.
Okay.
Until a flying side kick upward.
It's just hasn't been done since Bruce
Lee and the Chinese connection.
There's no,
it's me.
And you would usually do a flying
sidekick from an evil ground.
No,
I got to go upward.
That's their comedy and the fucking
original rule.
That's where you see me go bananas where
you've seen me at my best,
like crazy red in the face about to have
a heart attack.
Pitching your heart out on stage.
You have to come out with a flying site.
That's a crazy move you,
but you go on a vertical or a tremendous
up.
You're on your back kick and y'all got
to get out my shoulders and kick up and
tried to get you in the drawer.
That's the original room.
The belly room,
like the rest on my right hook.
I could rest on my one toe.
The belly room.
You can,
I could breathe and just throw one twos
and keep you off me deep breathe deep.
Kept my composure and even though you
hit me with some of those zoom guy,
oh slugs,
I got him whom?
God,
no.
If I keep my hands up and stay away from
you're right,
I'll be okay.
That's the belly room.
That's why the belly room I always
thought would be a great place to shoot
us.
You know what's great about the belly
rooms?
The same thing that's great about the
White House.
The Ice House Annex.
The second room.
Yes.
That's like there's no room for an act.
There's no room for an ax.
It's too intimate.
Like you have to figure out where's the
no fat aspect of the bet and you got to
be tuned into the bet they feel.
With my 55th birthday up there,
I put the Ice House.
What days at,
it's a Saturday.
The 19th so 19th I can't get the comedy
store,
so I got the original room.
I got the a small room at the ice house
on the 17th and 19th and then the 18th
I've got the original room.
I got the belly room at the comedy store
and it's the night before George
Washington's birthday.
So I got people doing that one too.
So I turned 55 that weekend.
Oh Shit.
And working out with Uncle Joey,
I only tried to 10 or 15 bucks.
I do that once a month and I go on that
stage too.
And you just fuck around you just
reading.
I write down in a notebook that I don't
really know about and we develop it
together up there and sometimes it's
phenomenal.
Nine at that time,
it really is phenomenal.
It's a good idea.
What would they tell you?
Why?
Because I met 30% I purposely the
mandible,
this is purposely,
I wouldn't do that.
The comedy store on a Saturday night?
No,
no.
I purposely did that ability to take the
edge off.
Okay.
I might even have a shot of alcohol.
Whoa,
whoa.
Just one.
It's three point.
Yeah.
Cause,
oh,
I don't eat much alcohol.
So I'll do it edible and have a little
shot of alcohol at the Ice House and
tape it and always get one or two great
things.
Joe Rogan,
I'm not going to tell you I got an hour
of greatness,
but because you're so relaxed and they
know what they're getting,
it's a big difference job.
The comedy store.
Listen,
how do you sharpen metal with metal
comedy store stones?
You do?
Uh,
we do.
we do a special on June.
May I got to go to the comedy store
three nights,
four nights a week.
That me,
that's it.
That's the gym.
And throw it low that,
that the WHO's next?
None of no it.
Delete it.
Get up there.
Take,
I do take downs for an hour.
Take them down.
I don't care how bow,
that's what you do before you shoot a
thinking.
You need all of it.
Right.
You need to sense,
you need the writing.
You need to set all of it.
You need to riding.
You need to working out.
Your head's gotta be at the right place.
Absolutely.
You know what else?
I think you need,
do you need friendship?
I think that helps.
I think that would,
I think that when you set up to me on
the phone the other day and you also
know that you got,
when I get there,
you got to leave some stuff to aggravate
me.
But I've thought about this many times
like who would I be without you guys?
Like who would I be without you?
Who would I be without Eddie?
Who would that be without red band?
Who would that be without Ari?
Who would that be with that Dunkin?
I think about the same.
The Thompson girls think about the same
thing.
Who would I be?
These are these people like Bert.
They mean a lot to me.
Like they're,
they're very important people.
And then there's your family,
which is through the moon.
That's that.
That kind of love is very weird.
That that kind of love is over.
Whelming how,
how much it changes who you are.
You have,
you were talking about the tower g come
doe the Bruce Lee Book and you were
saying that,
you know,
a lot of excerpts were stolen and the,
I don't even know,
we're not even,
and that's not the proper word that I
used.
Play drives.
I have a tie with Joey Diaz and half of
that tile is what I learned from Joe
Rogan.
The other half of that ty was what I
learned from my Ra and working with
Dunkin.
None of us are very original.
I just kicked it up a bit.
Uh,
one thing I love about you is you didn't
sell teachers that happened to show you
don't need to do nothing.
When I go into a town,
I focused on five shows.
I don't want to do your podcast.
I don't want to go see the statue of
Liberty.
I really don't.
You're right.
He did a kick ass.
I'm there to go to get them a good meal.
Uh,
after the first show.
Look,
it's a small club.
It's sold that let me not go out and
take pictures.
Let me focus on the important thing,
which I'm 55 I got to give you 150
fucking percent and those are the towel.
You know,
I'm up early.
I do my radio,
I'm up early to get out of there.
Every once in a while on Saturday you
got to have,
you've got to have a drink with the
audience,
a little charlotte on stage or whatever.
You know what I've,
I've come to think of myself as one
piece of,
I'm a piece of three or four.
You guys,
if you want the truth,
are we,
I like Ari's relaxation on stage already
takes chances.
Like we all want,
all three of us love to take chances.
That's why we do what we do.
You're not gonna get the same hour,
year out the fucking,
he had not even close.
We also have a similar style of mixing
everything up.
Yeah,
I have.
Everybody has their own towel,
man.
You know Bruce Lee just,
he just wanted to teach you how to
combine it and that's what we're doing
right now.
For sure.
You'd think I'm johnny original.
I'd take a little bit.
I learned from Bert.
I learned from Tom,
I learned from Bill Burr,
I learned from Dave Chapelle and now
this is your art again,
there's every,
the arm bar is the same whether I go to
you or John Jockey and showing me the
same thing,
but it's how I do it.
Yup.
It's the same point.
It's a really good point.
I think there's no way you could ever
say any one person is not influenced
because every single style of standup
comedy is in some way or another or
originated was like the Lenny Bruce's
and you know the,
the Dick Gregory's and the,
you know the guys who were doing it.
Wait,
the danger fields guys doing it way back
in the day and even Bob Hope,
all those guys,
they started this thing.
You got to think the world has had no
standup comedy up until like what a
hundred and fucking 50 years ago or
something.
That's nothing.
This shit just started and the owner was
one of the first guys to do it.
Mark motherfucking twain.
Mark motherfucking twain would do
readings of his book and it was funny
and people would laugh.
He was in front of people rocking.
He was killing.
He's telling stories and reading and
people thought he was hilarious.
He would give speeches.
They found somebody before Mark Twain,
I'm sure,
but he was really popular writer years
ago.
Yet they is living proof that that
standards existed before him.
Uh,
uh,
a form of this art form existed before.
Yeah.
It's sub civilization.
I did read that a couple of years,
I'm sure.
Subdued.
Yes.
There was some store and because,
and now I see myself on stage.
It's like when I take my sets now pro,
I hear,
I hear a little Joe Rogan.
I hear a little arriving.
I hear a little lenny bruce.
I love when
he bruises.
Yeah,
man,
man.
Dig.
That's,
I love that Levy.
Bruce said Shit that you didn't know.
People said,
fuck.
Yeah.
And it wasn't dirty.
Not just a certain word.
Like when I go on stage that,
you know,
uh,
you want,
you don't want to know my leukemia and
the place,
my Luchia is those mergers.
Like,
what's he,
what's he saying?
Right,
right,
right.
My Luke,
it's just bad luck,
but that's something Lenny Clarke with
say the fuck were you?
He put them a luke on me.
You know what I'm saying?
We were all,
we're not plagiarizing or doing anything
like that.
No,
we're influenced.
We're influenced and muscle wrong with
that.
One thing that's important is,
uh,
we're all real fans of comedy.
I know.
You're still a fan.
You still enjoy watching common hell of
it.
I go to the fourth wall a lot.
Chair,
rugged.
The fourth wall was with Mickey told
rocky to do dog.
I gotta you don't mean I got to take him
out of the rock.
Nikki told rocky do.
Why?
Because,
because he wanted he,
somebody took all,
no,
I'm sorry.
Apollo took rocky.
Oh,
dirty gym.
Some look at that.
Look at these motherfucker taking it
back.
No,
no,
no.
He took him to his own black gym and he
goes,
I wanted you to look at these guys so
you can look at their eyes.
And he goes,
remember when your eyes used to be like
that?
Ooh,
that's right.
He goes,
remember when your eyes used to be like
that rock?
So lately I've been going before I go
out and then they go to the fourth wall
and North Hollywood and I pay $5 to do
five minutes.
And the rule is you have to sit there,
you know,
most open Mike should do your state's
time and you leave.
You have to sit down and watch others.
Why did I tell you something?
The last six weeks I've learned more
from watching these open Mike,
hers than anything because I also
realized that where I was when I was one
of these guys,
I wanted what I had.
Right now I want it to be a headline.
I wanted to not be a rich guy,
but I wanted to just be funny.
I want it to be accepted as a comedian
and ever since I've been going to the
fourth wall,
I go there three or four nights a week.
Joe Rogan,
I pay $5 to do five minutes.
I'm no better than anybody else,
but the main thing is he asked me what I
want to go up and I always tell him
towards the end because I want to watch
these kids and joy.
Every time I leave that Bri leave
laughing and I fucking learned something
and I'm back.
No alcohol and that Joe Rogan.
Hmm.
Just fucking eight people watching you
do five minutes.
I want you to think about when you were
doing five minutes and what was going
through your head.
I'm just telling you my heart's beating
because I stood.
I remember bombing and leaving there
thinking,
Nah,
I'm going to have to get a little way
the job or now you're going to have to
get a cook job.
These guys all have day jobs.
They all talked about this jobs,
but every time I go to the fourth ward,
Bro,
I fucking learned something.
I go there some nights I go to flappers,
I go there some nights I go to the
store,
I go there some nights I go to the how I
do it that way,
but I always go there and every time I
go there I always go there with like
five minutes planned pro.
It doesn't even hit the stage because
from watching those guys I learned
something and I remember something and I
just come up with this crazy story so I
look at it as like a like doing
kettlebells.
Yeah,
that's a good way to look at it.
I really do.
I look at these young guys and I
remember that pain and that confusion
that I had that fucking feeling you had
when you were an open mike or in your
friends are telling me you were funny,
but you still had to drive the limo,
keep the paper job route or still drop
off papers or whatever the fuck job you
said you had.
You told me the story about meeting at
he Atlantic's and all that.
You're still in that crossroads of
comedy where you don't know what to do,
but you know in your fucking hard that
you just can't wait to be a headliner if
somebody would just give you a chance.
Back then,
I wasn't even thinking I can never be a
headliner.
I was really just hoping I could make a
living.
I never thought I'd wind up being,
when you mean living,
you mean food?
A one bedroom cable TV.
There was a guy that had a fucking loft.
He was the king.
I had a loft it,
they'd taken a school house and turned
it into condominiums.
This guy,
I never,
I'll never forget.
I looked up to him like I couldn't
believe where he was living in Dj
Hazard.
That's his name.
Hilarious comedian.
Oh my God.
He Damn.
Sure.
Well Dj has always been a real nice guy
and an excellent guy.
Very funny,
very funny guy.
Always has been,
but I remember he had like a loft
apartment.
I remember everybody talked about it.
It's like what?
This got brick walls inside.
He was like,
he was the king.
He was living like an adult.
But he was,
he was a standup comedian.
Like everybody else.
We had thought about like,
you know,
you're living like you're barely getting
by stuffing a bunch of guys and do a
house.
You know,
there was a lot of like comedy flop
houses or comedians would wind up moving
in together or you're living in some
shitty apartment and he could barely
afford.
Are you living with your girlfriend or
something?
It's weird when you go back and think
about it,
you know?
Okay.
Like you coulda quit at any time.
Think about it.
Think about it your early days when it's
terrible and it just bombed all the time
and you're like,
it really?
Yeah.
I watched some do with set one night at
the old triple and in front of 8 million
people and he and his mind,
he was at the garden though.
Wow.
It's like I get it now,
but where's your meat to Pitt?
I left it at home.
You know who,
uh,
one of the most proud moments as a young
comedian when,
uh,
I was at the comedy store and um,
I did a set in front,
you know,
like literally like maybe five or six
people,
but I did,
it is hard as I would do it in a regular
room and I heard in the back,
Paul Mooney going right,
ah,
laugh,
laughing and support.
You know how Paul Mooney would laugh and
support and you would go,
oh shit,
I just got the green light from Paul
fucking Mooney.
Like Paul Mooney was laughing at my
shit.
Then he came up to me after a show and
he goes,
you're a real comic.
He's like,
you did that show in front of all those
people.
And he goes,
you knew that there was five fucking
people in that room.
You did that show.
Like it was packed and does,
that's a real comic.
He goes,
you made me laugh.
That's what you learn to become.
It kind of like a,
Paul Mooney says that to you when you're
just coming up,
you're like,
Holy Shit.
Like,
I might be able to figure this out.
I might be able to do this.
It's big,
right?
Someone coming up to you,
you know,
it's crazy when you do a spot at the
store,
you low,
you're in the big leagues Bro.
Like no matter where I do a spot,
when I travel,
that's one day when I'm at the store on
Thursday night,
Tuesday night,
you know,
you're in some fucking good company.
You're doing something right or you did
something right.
Yes.
I love when comics are in the room.
I love laughing at comics.
I love going to the stolen early and
catch and two or three great calming.
So laughing and that makes my fucking
night.
Whether it's you or even Bobby Lee is so
fucking out of his mind on stage.
You know,
lately we've been getting around whites
and the fucking uh,
Bill Gilbert.
Yeah.
I mean Ron White,
Bill Burr last week there was a lineup
last how's there?
All the time.
There was a lineup last week that was
just ridiculous and two weeks ago,
but then I saw you down there.
That was just ridiculous.
Places on fire.
I the weighed down.
I have anxiety,
you know,
I puked on the car one time on the way
down there from the anxiety of going
down and following while I'm having this
surgery at March 5th for your ear?
Yeah.
And what do they have to do exactly?
Put a tube in there.
Whoa.
To drain the fluid.
What's,
what fluids in your ear?
Whenever I have,
it's getting to the point where with
some brown for the last six months I've
been living with plugs.
When I go to the shower now I got weigh
a blog when they go to git.
So why?
What's going on with your ears?
Because the fluid goes in.
I don't know dog.
I stuck a bean in my head when I was
six.
I was playing that game,
please.
I spill the beans and then you stuck
when you're here and fucked it up and
they couldn't get it out and I just left
it,
then brought it over.
It went in there.
My mother put hot oil in there.
They took all out.
Where the fuck Oh,
they took her to a chair.
So they wrecked my esl.
Today I get a doctor didn't take it out.
Yeah,
I went up to La,
uh,
the,
the Jewish hospital 68th and Broadway.
That how that's hurting my ear.
Just thinking about it.
So now,
50 years later,
because my driving
or whatever,
now I get carsick oh look,
equilibrium.
So I have to even wear ear plugs when I
walked,
go on walks and the tide,
I got to wear ear plugs because if not,
the sweat goes in my ear.
You know what I used to get a terrible
fucking car sickness from trying to read
a book in a car.
Oh yeah.
You cannot do anything like that.
The car after a while,
you're just like all,
especially with reading glasses at this
really poor design and try to read your
twitter Jack,
come around that turn where the four or
five hits the one o one and see what
happens to your fucking stomach.
It's a weird thing,
huh?
Motion sickness.
Some people get it all the time.
I get it all the time.
Not,
I'm playing,
it's not,
I get it.
If I get high and get on a boat,
go down the Jersey shore,
getting on a boat,
I'm done.
I got to take the pills I was at treat
those pills.
Drama mean that stuff is brutal.
That stuff is rather BCC.
You gotta be tired.
I'd rather be sick.
I'll throw up.
I don't give a fuck.
That sucks.
But at least I don't feel like I'm
drugged out.
Like I fell asleep in a diner.
Me and my friend Jimmy Utilia,
we went out blue fish fishing.
I'm on those tea party boats and the way
home we stopped at a darn and gets on
me.
I literally fell asleep head down on the
table.
I literally was like drugged out where
you are.
The drama being.
Yeah.
It was on drama,
Maine and I was only like 150 pounds
back then.
154 pounds.
That was like what,
what I was weighing when I was competing
and uh,
I'd never did anything.
I didn't do anything.
I didn't drink.
I didn't smoke pot and then I didn't do
shit.
So in that drama,
meaning in my system,
my sister was like,
check please.
It just shut down.
I couldn't hear.
I had no tolerance at all.
I fell completely asleep at a diner,
but I tried to take with my friend Jimmy
took,
he's way bigger than me.
I think I just overdosed.
It will be,
it's just something where the Harvey
Weinstein gets out of Rehab and he wants
to come on the podcast.
We do let them month.
Um,
I let them out of,
you're coming on to why?
Because we're going to have some fun
with them.
Oh yeah,
it's hot box him.
We want that.
We want the fucking real for that.
She's got some crazy,
you can't,
you can't have them anywhere.
You know that guy,
especially in the middle.
We were joking around folks,
especially in the middle of a trial,
because he's in the middle of like a ton
of trial.
Oh,
well he comes back,
he's going to get charged.
I for sure something's going to happen.
There's so many different trials in
terms of like civil lawsuits and stuff
and it's a lot of women saying he did
horrible things.
It's undoubtedly,
there's no way he's going to skate.
Something's to happen.
Something civic trial,
criminal trial.
Some days I have several trials.
Absolutely.
We're changing as a species.
That's what's happening and in the way
it's like we're making it up as we go
along and there's a lot of rocky things
that are happening,
a lot of chaos and,
but this is awareness of like what you
should and shouldn't do to human beings
in terms of like forcing yourself on
people and you know fucking them when
they say no,
it's like rape and
the idea that we're still doing that in
2018 and people are doing it at a really
high level.
It's like boy,
bye of creepy.
Thanks.
I'm over to this fucking town.
Of course,
right off the bat,
soon as I got here,
I heard the creepiest pocket things.
Boy You got into like the movies,
like I heard he was creepy things and I
saw creepy bayview and listen,
Ben,
you've ever want to call a fucking spade
a spade because you're getting in
trouble.
But you look at Kevin,
what's his name?
Spark was event.
Which guy?
Kevin Spacey and Kevin Spacey.
You can't tell he sucks.
Dick puncher knew he would suck a dick
part time and we looked at Kevin Spacey.
If you look at that fucking dude,
Lee Harvey Weinstein,
you can't tell that.
That dude would make you suck his dick
before.
Think about that and all of these people
took pictures with him.
Would that be to the fuck?
Are they agents that actually sent you
on that mission to Lee harveys fucking
hotel room?
I want to know where the fuck they are.
They didn't know that Lee Harvey was
going to come out with a massage and
asked you to suck his fucking deck or
watch them naked pro.
We knew for a long fucking time.
Everybody knew when there's a fucking
gap,
when you have a dream and you have
power,
a lot of things could happen.
I mean,
I'm no fucking liberace,
but I got my Dick's up at the comedy
store just because of being a comedian
and some real thought that you were like
had supernatural powers.
It's fucking crazy.
And if you don't know about fucking
Hollywood,
listen man,
they'd been fucking people till they're
dead for you.
Look at this fucking Marilyn Monroe.
They kicked that bitch and you don't,
who else was a dirty motherfucker?
That fucking liberace.
That guy was making you sign contracts
making you fucking have plastic surgery
making you have places like clam him.
Are you fucking kidding me?
There's been some creepy fucking shit in
this town you got away with for fucking
zillions.
He is.
And now I tell you what,
man,
I'm more for the movement.
I'm all for it.
I have a daughter.
You have daughters.
I have sisters.
I got friends.
I tell you would fucking bothers me the
most.
I tell.
The only thing that bothers me out of
this,
you know what bro?
Who was in pappy on with Steve Mcqueen?
I don't remember Dustin Hoffman was him.
If he fingered bank,
get a 73 shut the fuck up.
Shut the fuck up.
People changed.
I'm not the same guy who kidnap can't
bell in 1987 I'm not sorry Joe.
I'm not.
So how are you going to come back at me
about something I didn't like deep
bought an 87 I was a different guy.
I was doing blow.
I had asked you to finger bang yet you
can't do that.
That I don't want to do.
Don't let somebody fucking career cause
he stuck a finger in your ass and 92 and
now it came back to you to the scale of
Amnesia.
You can't do that to me.
You want to call me out personally,
call me the fuck out.
Call me at home and go,
hey man,
in [inaudible] 94 one that you asked me
if you could eat my ass hole,
who said you were wrong?
Listen,
I was doing an eight ball a day.
What do you want from me?
All right.
I resolved that issue that I understand,
but don't call me out on something like
that.
1972 people fucking change pro.
That's what pissed me off.
Giant.
There's a tiny gaps we're talking about
like the chair pivot and it was 1985 and
don't fucking call me out.
If you call me out,
call me out with a friend.
Whether you're talking about,
look at what level though,
if it gets to rape a dog.
Hold on.
Listen,
the way I come from,
that's not even allowed.
That word never entered my mind.
I'm talking about if I was coked out of
the bar one night.
Now what I'm telling,
I told you I'd tell these were banging
and I want to put a coke rock in your
asshole.
You can't come at me for some in 1988
cause I used to do what every other
night.
That was my opening line.
Listen,
your ass hoes on fire.
What's it gonna take for me to stick my
tongue in that fucking thing and make
that thing you know you're not going to
listen.
You're not going to get a piece of ass
by selling somebody real estate.
You've got to sell them Dick.
Well,
the ones that it works on,
that's the ones you want.
Like if you can go up to a gal and say
that to her,
Oh,
you gotta write me already.
Where if I knew who you were a girl and
I knew you did coke and you had that
certain look in your eyes,
what's the cluck to the look?
That is when you do cocaine,
you do dirty fucking things.
So when you look at a girl that's doing
cocaine and she's like,
she suggest to you that she's going back
to your hotel with you.
It's time.
Nobody goes back to the hotel with you
when they have a boyfriend.
If you're doing coke at time,
because percentages keep getting go
higher and higher.
What Cook apparently makes people
promiscuous,
right?
Right.
It makes people go fucking bananas to go
suck a Dick.
So you take somebody who's wife up to
your hotel room and then 6:00
AM she's doing coke with you.
You'll notice that one of the times she
comes out of the bathroom,
the button,
it'll be opened.
You know what I'm saying?
Then the next time she comes out,
she'll come out to tell you a story and
her pants will come out and show button
them in front of the little things start
to happen if you signs and pretty soon
you're like,
listen,
nothing.
Nothing.
Take off your pants.
I'm gonna see you play with your pussy.
Do,
do,
do.
That's what the,
what gets me right now is the,
the 20 year call out,
the 30 call.
I ain't going to ruin Dustin Hoffman's
Korea.
Yeah.
He was giving out foot rubs.
He was asking him ask him acting creepy
black.
You know what bro?
Part of that shit,
we allow that creepiness and society.
We turned our fucking heads.
You follow them saying,
I'm sure you're not the type of return
you had.
No,
I'm not the type of turning my head,
but I noticed that you didn't notice it.
The cocaine thing is a,
is a real interesting one because you
see people making crazy decisions.
Just real nutty fucking decisions.
Oh,
you sell a tonin men of pounding
everything.
So what y'all [inaudible] system.
So your whole system's delusional.
I remember going out like after a long
night and not sleeping.
Okay.
Now that comes to a point where you have
this paranoia where you don't leave the
house,
but now that comes through with paranoid
that you're going to leave the house and
bump into somebody and guess what?
Sometimes you actually do,
you go to a seven 11 together soda and
you bump into somebody who was in the
same predicament as you.
That happened to me once I was,
I went by Gavin's I think I was staying
with Ralphie and I went by Gavin's and
I'm the first floor.
They was just checked that we used to be
a stripper and she had a daughter that
was about 13 kind of ugly.
She always like Pavarotti.
We used to call it bob or cause she had
thick fucking eyebrows and shit,
but the mother was kind of a freak and I
got up like that.
Like I was up all night and it was like
nine in the morning and I was about to
call my drug dealer.
They get a package of 11 that keep the
body alive and I bumped into that animal
to stay away and she asked me like,
you know,
I got some coke,
I was on my way and that chick,
that chick was in gay,
Ooh,
I'll never forget this.
She was engaged and like,
well I'm on my way right now.
And she goes,
do you want to split the gram?
I go,
yeah,
let's put the grab.
It was like 30 bucks.
We went over there,
we split the fucking grand and we went
back.
Her daughter was sleeping so we had to
do the coke in the hallway on the first
floor.
All right.
Under the stairway,
you know what I'm saying?
And after we did two blanks,
we were just thinking they are looking
at each other and she was like,
don't even ask.
I just told the guy that was bothering
me all night that I wouldn't give him a
site.
Like,
oh listen,
it's 10 in the morning,
you know,
do something,
man.
We got to do something.
And I started swapping spit.
What the next thing you know,
she's stuck in the helmet and when I
went to come,
she goes,
don't do that.
And I came on a jeans,
uh,
like it was all over her jeans.
It's 1130 in the morning and you come on
some of these genes,
you're coked up.
I felt like a piece of shit.
That's what the worst of it.
I see her three nights later and I'll
come by audrey and she's with her
boyfriend and her boyfriend comes over
to him and he goes,
hey man,
we might have a problem here.
And I'm like,
what?
What's going on?
He goes,
my,
my girl was a little bit angry.
I don't know what happened,
but I think you should apologize.
I felt like when I came on the pants,
I was just suck my dick.
That's what happened.
Did she tell you that?
That's how crazy to coke world is?
Oh my God.
Like she told her boyfriend,
she was angry at me.
It's none of your business.
Why?
But so he came over to me,
cause I don't know what's going on.
You're a nice guy.
I don't know what's going on.
I felt like going,
you know why she blew me a letter in the
morning.
I was like,
came on the jeans.
I shot a load of the jeans.
She couldn't fucking,
you know what?
What are you spraying your genes to get
shit off?
I'm going to shout it out.
She put the shout out that spur,
if she fucking wanted to that old coach
Carter,
no vitamins in my system.
I weighed 380 pounds.
Those genes were stayed for lifetime.
Oh.
Uh,
uh,
I did the dumbest shit on all those
drugs.
The dumbest shit.
And especially the year it took me to
get off it.
What's going on?
Someone at our door.
Oh,
okay.
Who the fuck is this page?
You may have five 46 in the morning.
Crack of dawn and what's going on his
own fedex,
probably someone dropping something off.
Um,
anyway,
my brother told nothing.
We got to get out of here eventually.
All right,
I'm going to leave eventually.
I'm good.
I'm having a good time.
It was good to see you.
I'm just getting to see you too,
man.
Jamie,
my man.
I thought about you when I saw fucking
the cramps and ty come back against
them.
I thought about you.
Who'd you bet I lost on that one?
I had told me to check.
Check part lands some stuff.
Ah,
fuck.
Like I don't go straight up.
You love those sucker bets are going to
go straight up.
It's winning the lottery.
Why when 20 bucks when you can win 200
no,
because I'd rather them raise my
percentage of bet one and double up on
it and you just worry about one.
Why am I sweating to moves through the
fucking minor sweat to most?
I don't want to get in that long game.
Oh my God.
Fall too deep like you're talking about.
But who the fuck this is?
What's the next fight on the car?
We got some great cards to go over the
rock over Merrill fight.
That's Great Romero.
And then when you got March 7th Khabib
against Tony Ferguson.
Shit in Brooke coming at you from all
directions.
That's going to be Brooklyn,
New York.
Are you doing this show that weekend?
Isn't it April?
It's April,
right?
April.
What's the exact date?
April 7th I believe.
Fuck cats.
That's a crazy fight.
That has a hard time.
I'm at a rock 'em sock.
'Em robots fight.
That's who the fuck knows fight.
You know that's one of those fights
where you're like,
whoa,
that's going to be a crazy one.
Tony Ferguson's a bad mother fucker and
Khabib Nijmegen Madoff is already one of
the scariest guys have ever seen compete
ever.
Malls people already.
This is his first shot at the title.
Just stop and think of what,
what happens if that fucking savage gets
the title?
That guy some mash.
It's people.
What he did to Edson Barboza was super
natural.
It's like he's not even the same thing.
You said something during that fight
that said it all.
There was one point of the fight that
you said,
look at the look in essence face.
Yeah,
and I've had that look and that's when
you're getting chased by 18 people.
He had
a look that heated.
No,
no hitting.
No hope.
He went into like a survival situation.
Like,
like when you see a deer that's getting
attacked by a crocodile or something,
they have this like survival thing where
you're like,
you're just trying to survive.
Obviously deer is not the same.
I that's terrible analogy.
Hold on,
let me correct this.
What I think is that Barboza had
realized that like there's no way he's
going to beat this guy on the ground.
It's not even close.
Like I think if he went to that fight,
probably thought he'd be able stuff more
take downs and probably be able to get
back off his feet because he was doing
that with a lot of guys in camp.
But once that guy gets a hold of you,
there's an acceptance that certain
fighters go through where they,
they're locked down like holy shit.
Like they're just drained from this
animal mall and them trying to retain
their energy,
trying to recharge their battery,
trying to get back in it.
And you've got to realize that guy
that's in proposals,
one of the best fucking kickers ever,
ever.
He's one of the best kickers ever.
That fucking guys,
the fastest switch kick I've ever seen
in my life outside of like professional
Moitai like San Chai or blue cow or
something like that.
He's got a world class left leg kick.
I mean woo,
he's fast as fuck.
He couldn't keep that guy off him and it
was so scary.
That guy's face to me where he drilled
for hours.
He drilled,
take down the fence,
he drove everything that was,
but he never drove this,
couldn't do it.
Like there was one point where he looked
and it was like,
wait a second,
I've done everything I can.
I,
I even trained with the giants taking me
down for a week.
Different animal.
It felt this depending on how he keeps
you down on either,
his control on that side is fucking
something that is,
there's certain guys that have a
grappling skill that it's very hard to
see when you look at it.
Even if you're a skillful glow grappler
yourself,
you're looking at someone like you like
why is he able to do that to everybody?
Like what?
What is he doing differently?
Like,
why is this one guy being able to do
certain things and other people can't
do?
And there's a few of those guys out
there while you're watching me just go
Jesus,
like what the fuck?
And but Comedians,
the number one guy in that category,
because he's never been defeated.
He said one moment of adversity in the
octagon.
I get clipped by a punch from Michael
Johnson.
I can't think of a single round.
He's lost.
Not off the top of my head at least.
I mean he may have lost rounds on some
judges' scorecards,
but he's essentially mauled every
motherfucker they put in front of him.
He's an animal.
So this guy versus Tony,
it's phenomenal fight.
Cause Tony is a savage and Tony fights
very well off of his back.
He is a seriously dangerous guard.
You can't sleep on him.
He's durable as fuck.
He can knock you out.
He never gets tired.
And he's,
his game is,
they come and he's a fucking champ right
now.
He's the interim champ.
You know when he beat Kevin Leave with a
triangle,
you'd beat a top guy like Kevin leave
with a fucking triangle.
That's a big move.
Tony's dangerous,
nasty,
dark chokes is darce choke is one of the
best,
was great,
but he wasn't ready for Talia.
Kevin Leach was sick to his staff.
That's,
that's that action.
But note unquestionably hurt.
He wasn't totally as it's too high
level.
That was to,
you could see in the second round
perhaps.
I would like to see that fight to get
what you,
you have to say that because that's how
it went down.
Sorry.
But I think that if you wanted to have
them fight again and Kevin Lee can go
into that fight healthy,
I think you'd see a very different
fight.
I don't think you would see tony.
I'm not saying that you would see tony
lose or Kevin when,
but I would think you would see a Kevin
Lee that could sustain its performance
longer.
I think being drained from staff is
just,
there's no judge,
there's no effect.
I've had it before.
It's the worst.
Your body.
It's not the worst,
but it's not good.
Your body goes into a very weakened
state.
It's your,
you are not the same thing.
You're just not.
You can,
if you're a real professional and you
can go out there and do your job.
And a lot of guys have,
a lot of guys have fought in one.
Luke rockhold beat Chris Weidman on
antibiotics.
How about that?
He was fighting off staff when he beat
Chris fucking Weidman.
That's how good Luke rockhold is.
Guys have done it,
but that's not him at 100% he wanted,
he wanted 70 or 80 or whatever the fuck
it was.
You know,
there's no doubt about it.
Staph infections and antibiotics both
fuck you up.
And Kevin Lee,
I believe,
opted to not take the antibiotics.
So after the fight,
so he didn't want to weaken the system,
but he's still weakened by the staff.
Fuck fuck.
Oh shoot.
Demetrius Johnson versus Tj dillashaw.
Superfight targeted for UFC two 26 and
co main event.
Oh Shit.
Two 26 that I dunno.
July Vegas.
Hello?
Steve Bay DC fight.
Oh good.
Oh,
that's a big court case.
I'm Bro.
They got some good cards coming up.
That's what Greg is.
Kevin Co sleep don't sleep motherfucker.
This game might run by by his ship,
whose mother fucking fights are getting
better and better now.
Again,
I'd love to see Steve Bay become a
superstar.
Me Too.
I think.
I think he deserves it.
And I think you look at where that guy
is right now.
Like what is more American than this
guy?
Like you said with his immigrant named
what is more American than a guy who
works right now as a fireman while he's
the UFC heavyweight champion of the
world.
And he's a great dude.
Good,
good.
And broke the record.
Broke the record for the most defensive.
He's beat the scariest contender we've
seen in a decade.
You know.
Uh,
I watched the podcasts a lot.
Yeah.
Had those guys aren't here.
We're talking about the Tao of Jeet
Guido.
And I think that a lot of people really
miss out on the main thing.
And this is what you miss out with me
every time.
It's not with you.
No,
no,
no.
I don't.
Other people.
You mean like whenever I want to see is
Bruce Lee fucking things and I see these
kids are the 30 talking about Bruce Lee.
I get sick to my stomach because Bruce
Lee that bring martial arts for this
country.
Then he caved immigrants.
Hope Bro.
I was a kid.
I just come from Cuba to Green Horn in
on Sunday nights.
I would throw you out the window to
watch that show when I was five and then
they canceled them and then he came back
with the first one that supposed to be
fist of fury,
but some argue that was a flat that
didn't do that good that introduced him.
It was the one in [inaudible] 71 the
Chinese connection when I was eight.
That was a great model that really put
this country over.
If you were,
it didn't mean you were a tough guy.
How many,
how many I youtube,
how many black guys are there that think
that Chinese is and they got wisdom.
What was the guy used to send you videos
of,
forget the guy's name,
but he's a bunch of those things.
Make people tougher.
He gave immigrants blacks.
He gave them hope.
How many black dudes started dressing
like Bruce Lee and you know,
doing crazy shit and wearing gunning
fool our kung fu outfits.
You know everybody's wrong about Bruce
Lee because I saw it and I saw his death
and I saw how people would go to
Chinatown because there was no internet
can confined kind.
They go to Seattle.
They go to is greg.
I went to his grave,
took a picture and gave it to Eddie
Griffin.
That's why Eddie Griffin will always be
indebted to me cause I gave him a
picture of Bruce Lee's brave and just
shit.
That's how I Bruce Lee,
when he died there was no internet.
They didn't report per sleeve that on
the news.
How did people find out about it?
You found out a week later when the
trainees newspaper Hit New York and then
in China town,
it came out through China town.
When I heard about it,
I was forced to go to China town and get
the paperwork with the pictures.
But everybody had to,
it was an open casket and China and the
open casket was glass around him and to
him,
nobody believed Bruce Lee was that then
enter the dragon came out.
But I bing Bada boom,
everybody made $1 million and nobody
said nothing but his debt browth fucked
people up.
Like,
you know Bruce Lee gave hope because the
Vietnam War was going on and there was
something else going on in this country
that people don't remember that
destroyed this country.
You know,
which shot this country down.
What?
When the Beatles broke up this fucking
Christ.
Did people lose that mind?
So you always get into arguments with
people led.
Zap One's a good bat.
Yeah,
but wait til the beetles get back
together,
bitch,
because they were always threatening you
with the Beatles talk.
I like jethro Tull.
Yeah,
but they're not nothing compared to the
Beatles.
So until John Lennon got shot,
then those people had a voice.
Fuck you at the Beatles,
bitch.
You know what you were?
Springsteen is the man.
You know what you would love.
Go to the Mirage show to the Beatles,
a Cirque de Solei show.
It's called love fucking crap.
When did you go credible?
A couple of weeks ago.
You were there doing it with my family.
Okay.
And W I wanted to see the Cirque de
Solei show.
It's supposed to be amazing and I seen
the original circus de Soleil.
Well,
this guy,
nobody would have met the Beatles,
broke up this country,
went to a tough time.
You have no fucking id now.
You don't have any idea if you're,
you're young,
you have no fucking idea.
Put it in perspective.
The Beatles,
let let it be out.
In the end of that,
we'll let it be dog.
That was it.
People will crack White People Crack
Jack fucking incredible song.
When you think about what John died
with,
John,
let him die.
What happened in New York that Sunday?
You think about that?
That was amazing to look at.
Now he was on another level.
The whole band was on another level.
They were very psychedelic,
mostly came in at the perfect time,
right?
The Beatles were breaking up.
Muhammad Ali,
but also in 1973 this is a very
interesting fact.
At $50,
at $15 ticket sales at $15,
$12,
$10 ticket sales.
This country gross,
$3 billion and concerts really go watch
the 70s on CNN.
The one of my music,
I can't say I'm the seventh.
So much good music came out of that
time,
that era.
Every school was on tour.
They had a list of who was on tour
Zeppelin,
the stones.
Uh,
the whole,
when I was in high school,
we always went to concerts.
You always,
when I was in concerts,
concerts,
high school,
we went to see j geils band.
Went to see the who I saw johnny winter.
I saw jethro tall.
I saw George thorogood the destroyers.
He did a 50,
50 tour in 1981.
That dude,
he did 50 states in 50 days.
That was the big thing to do.
Uh,
George Federal Goodman destroyed.
People forgot about j geils band,
Jake giggles band.
That was about freeze frame.
Angel as a centerfold.
He was married to Faye dunaway.
That's sanger mean.
Whatever it is,
he don't come then Peter Wolf.
Bad motherfucker.
All right,
Joel,
I gotta wrap this bitch up.
I got shit.
I love you mother fucker.
I like to do this in June,
June.
Do a planet right now,
folks.
We'll keep you guys updated,
but I'm going to direct and,
uh,
put together Joey Diaz,
his comedy special.
We're going to let mother fuckers know
immigrant mentality to come to until
about,
well,
everybody,
thank you.
Thank you.