Down Highway Forty one,
I'm Laura was born Ram than trying to
make a living and doing the best I can.
So when it's time to leave and I hope
you understand that was bone rambling
man.
I don't think we live.
Are We?
We are live.
Oh Ladies and gentlemen.
Oh Dude,
I'm a big fan man.
Melissa,
you heard that?
Oh,
I love that song.
I used to listen to um,
midnight rider.
I used to,
whenever I used to do radio,
whenever do Kevin Vein was to the last
radio that I decided to do in La.
Like I,
I used to do a lot of radio morning
radio and getting up in the morning is
rough because then you try to take a nap
and you always feel a little groggy
during the first show.
Yeah.
Weekends.
So the last one I would do is Kevin had
been in La and smoke a joint,
get up in the morning,
smoke a joint and,
and always put on midnight rider always
for some reason because it was dark
house to.
I wish we could play it.
We can't play it though,
right?
God,
what happens to I,
I play Presto.
Just be dead air.
Kind of.
Oh,
that's kind of sing along to talk about
it.
Okay.
Let's do that.
So the youtube will pull us off,
but regular radio won't.
But Jamie has the ability to go live
unregular podcast type shit as anarchy,
Bro.
Yeah,
I like some light anarchy.
Do Doon.
Doon.
If you haven't heard this.
God.
Is this a live version?
Oh yeah.
Is it?
Wow.
And um.
Oh,
it's totally different now.
It's good.
I'm not calling called catch.
No,
not catch them in.
Plus he fucks share diddy.
Yeah,
he used to fuck share back with.
Oh,
the clothes.
I'm wearing animals and I'm not gone.
I don't know.
That's beautiful man.
Giovan.
Ladies and gentlemen.
I knew you would appreciate that kind of
music feel.
Vaughn,
you got taste.
You got soul kid.
You got something going on.
I wish I was blind sometime you ever
take.
But that the music so good because if
you're blonde I bet it's just even
better in their.
You know,
I would say yes,
but have you ever seen Leonard Skinner
play?
They played free bird and you got to see
what's the guitarist named again?
Leonard scared.
He's such a bad motherfucker.
I should know his name.
I don't know hardly anybody's name and
Leonard Skinner,
but I love letters.
But um,
there's a video of them in like some
crazy huge show,
just gigantic audience.
And this dude is,
he's playing the guitar like performance
art man.
And that,
you know,
that one long solo and freebird,
which to me I maintain is like the
greatest solo in the history of music.
I mean,
as is up there.
Every results may vary.
Nobody has their own opinion,
but you can start sex and finished sex.
I don't know.
It depends on how your rocket.
I don't rock it.
Well man,
I'm going to get mad that I'm bad at
sex.
Yeah,
he,
there he is like in this,
in this fucking gigantic audience full
of people.
And this is Leonard Skin.
The crazy thing is Leonard skinner came
out of Florida before people figured out
Florida sucks.
See,
because when I was a kid,
Florida was cool and if you listen to
this,
you know what the fuck I'm talking about
Florida,
Florida state.
If you listen to this,
you know what I'm saying?
Folks.
I used to live there.
I lived in Gainesville.
Lastly,
lived there for awhile,
but Florida back then nobody had figured
out the Florida socks.
It was like Florida is the place to go
to get away from this fucking winter and
they all go down there and then I'll
move and then we realized like the dregs
of the Weirdos.
Yeah.
I remember seeing if,
if somebody had a tee shirt,
because I grew up in Louisiana.
If somebody teachers said Florida on it,
dude,
that was when they were somebody you
know.
Wow.
They made it a thing.
Florida.
Yeah.
Florida to Louisiana looked up to
Florida.
Oh,
definitely did because Florida had that
coast land had pitches a sunshine on
their shirt.
That's right.
Sunshine.
Yeah.
That sun or people sitting on like an
umbrella.
You know,
they weren't infested with alligators
yet either.
I don't think so.
I mean,
we didn't.
We didn't worry about it as much then,
you know,
if you lost somebody to an animal or
something.
Back then I felt like it wasn't as big
of a deal as it is now.
Really in the eighties and nineties if
you lost somebody to an animal or an
animal bite,
it was more,
you know,
part of God's plan I think.
Whereas now it's like just something
crazy that happened at Disney world,
you know?
It was like the biggest thing ever.
Yeah.
That little kid.
That's pretty fucked up.
God Damn Monster Living at Disneyland.
This is how tolerant people get.
They get so silly.
They're like,
well,
he is here before us.
This is,
he's probably a 17 year old alligator
lives.
This is peaceful environment.
And he made while he ate a baby.
Yeah.
Well you got to be a nasty alligator if
you sit in there and you could.
There's probably been other choices came
by,
you know,
that was probably a couple of,
young lovers that were out there by the
water earlier and you waited.
You know,
you might not get a young lover though.
A young lover might fight back.
Yeah,
yeah.
There's two of them.
That's true.
I don't know.
Don't worry though.
They're pretty invulnerable and if you
cut off an alligator's arm,
it just grows back.
That's gangster gangster.
As it gets chopped off.
I'll see in a month with a new one.
Dude.
That's the Tupac of the Animal Kingdom.
Really when you think about it,
two fingers full of bullet holes headed
to the ambulance and he's throwing up
his fingers now.
Gangster alligators that their arms are
so short and then just so capable.
Man.
I'm sure you've seen the video of that
new one that they found in Florida that
is on a golf course and it's like 15
feet long.
It's one of the biggest gators were
filmed and these people are on the golf
course.
They're looking up at this gator.
See if we can find a jamie.
We can't show it on youtube.
You have to find it on youtube because
we.
I got that gut be pulled off facebook.
There's something happens when you have
these animal videos in particular,
when they go on facebook,
like people own those videos,
so when they go to look for a,
they have like an algorithm that can
find it and if it's on your page they'll
pull your whole page down.
Yeah,
they own this but so this so many films,
there's a couple different angles of it.
A bunch of people filling because it was
so crazy.
So these people are all playing golf and
they're in the foreground so you could
see him like,
there it is.
Look at that.
Look at the guy's a real animal and you
realize how big it is.
When you see a guy.
Now Watch how this guy walks in the
foreground and the guy.
When the guy looks Turkish,
a little doesn't.
It looks fake.
It looks fucking gigantic now.
Now you see how big it is.
Now you understand how big it is because
you see this guy like,
are you?
Are you kidding me?
And they estimated it's somewhere around
15 feet.
And did they catch it?
I don't think so man.
They found it again.
They found it again in a pond.
See if he can find it.
Um,
they,
they really rediscovered this alligator
in a pond.
I think that was the title of the video.
Maybe they're making a comeback.
Dude.
I hope something good comes into tax at
some animal.
Dude.
I'm ready for it.
Everybody to fight.
Don't fight alligators,
man.
You don't want to fight them.
Well,
I'll get out there and do something,
man.
There's this dude that I have A.
I've had on my podcast before,
but he said his name is Jim shockey.
He's a very famous hunter from Canada
and they hired him to go to a certain
river in Africa.
I think it was the Congo,
but I'm not sure.
It might have been the Nile.
Anyway,
he had to go.
He went down there to kill some
crocodiles that were eating people.
It is one of the craziest videos,
man.
You go there and the,
these,
these villagers,
everyone's got to stump where everyone's
missing an arm or a hand or they got a
chunk bitten out of their chest.
It's crazy when you look at these poor
people and they're all just living in
fear and while he was down there,
a woman got taken.
Oh yeah,
they were up river looking for these
killer crocodiles to try to shoot him
and one of the women was washing clothes
and she just got yanked right out of the
water.
Maybe the worst,
but it was really scary,
man.
He's seeing the laundry.
Oh yeah.
Right.
Underwear.
Seeing the reaction of the people that
were wailing,
just wailing,
crying,
you know,
because it wasn't just like they lost
someone.
It's like God,
they lost another person.
It's like,
that woman's gone now forever.
She was consumed,
consumed by a monster like that.
That is their actual existence.
Damn.
Sitting by a river that they need.
It's water for life and the water is
infested by monsters who are actually
actively targeting them for food.
Yeah,
it's crazy.
That'd be like if somebody like,
there was a killer in Walmart and they
just didn't know who or where.
It was constantly like what?
Lions would jump out while you were
eating at Walmart.
Yeah,
but when you're buying food.
we got it pretty easy,
man.
You know,
those people must be so interesting like
people that live under that kind of
pressure,
like their view of life and we can
understand their language.
I bet they have like a,
you know,
like you'll listen to like read like
ancient works of literature,
ancient poetry,
stuff like that.
And you think about it like these are
people that are going through a war,
like the ancient Greeks and the ancient
Romans.
Like you would read their words,
you go,
well this is fascinating.
We know it's being translated.
This is the words of someone who's gone
through like sword war.
Yeah.
Back when they would fight with arrows
and shit and swords and catapults and
the intensity of life.
Back then when death was just around
every corner,
it was everywhere.
It must be so,
so intense to talk to someone like that.
You should fly in a pygmy or something.
You thought about that?
No,
but I have had my friend Justin wren who
has been with the pygmies in the Congo
is for like many,
many years.
He goes and builds wells for them days
over there for months at a time.
He's had malaria three times.
He's going to come out again soon.
He just texted me.
I got to text him.
We're going to find a date,
and I used to be in the wishlist and be
in the well business a little bit.
Not wishing wells,
most of the.
Not Water Wells,
but I worked for this.
This is made by a pygmy in the Congo out
of a nail.
It's a little knife that justin brought
me.
Wow.
Yeah.
They take these nails and there's one
over there to see that now,
right there on the desk.
That's what it looks like.
The hammer these nails out and they
turned them into knives.
See?
That starts out of nail that they find
way and they pound it down and sharpen
it and turn it into a knife.
Additive history came back.
If history struck back,
did we would.
I wouldn't make it.
I wouldn't do it.
Make It.
I wouldn't make it long.
Ah,
you'd be fine.
I don't.
I'm not prepared for a bull.
You would be though.
People are adaptable.
You're a smart dude.
Thea Yvonne.
I would lead,
I would think a little bit.
I would adapt.
I'd lay low in the beginning.
You know,
like somebody doesn't pick my battles.
Dude.
You'd have to kill somebody immediately.
You have to find the first person in
your group,
the weakest person and kill them in
front of everybody else.
Yeah.
Like you can't just stand there and be
like,
yeah,
Duh,
kill some dude.
But think about them and you can't stand
there and just be in a comment.
You know,
everybody's chatting group huddle and
everybody's like,
you got to take somebody out right then
because that's going to show your
dominance of $100 million.
At least going to show like this dude is
gonna do something.
I see.
I see what you're saying.
But I think if you think ahead,
you would think,
well no.
Then they're going to think that he's
got arbitrarily gonna always kill the
weakest person.
Eventually it's going to get to know one
because there's going to be.
The next week is person.
That guy is dead now and the next week
like,
who's to decide whether or not you're
weak
or you're not.
We if you were going to do that,
that person would have to be either a
terrible person who is victimizing other
people or they would have to have
attacked first.
We'd have to be or they would have to
been such a piece of shit that people
are rooting for you.
Like somebody who was real chatty and
you just asked them did.
There's no way I'm trying to survive
like a,
you know,
the second coming of the universe and
some dudes chatty in my group,
bro.
That's not.
Especially with like,
he fucks up some hunting parties.
You're out there the sneaking up on a
pig and he's like,
oh my God,
it's so hot out.
You fucking pig runs away and
everybody's hungry.
Yeah,
he did.
Was He the first man?
I think about that kind of stuff.
Like if a plane crash,
I already know I'm planning to head did.
I'd eat a Vietnamese guy.
Why?
Because that's easier to start or move.
If you attack somebody bigger,
you eat somebody bigger in front of
other people,
it's going to alarm people,
but you got to eat a small person,
so stature is important.
I think if you've dumbed down a viet
people aren't gonna be that upset at
you.
It means people are going to be super
upset.
What are you talking about,
dad?
Their sacrifice.
They're more understanding of things.
Dude,
is this a character you're playing?
No,
but if you eat a black dude,
you eat a black lady and her family's
there.
There are going to be pissed.
So you think a Vietnamese person,
we'll let you slide.
I think that they'd be much more
forgiving of a couple of day period.
I think a like their relatives.
You don't think so?
Honestly.
One thing?
No,
I don't think so.
I definitely think they'd be super
pissed at you.
Especially modernized ones,
but what is interesting is like Vietnam
was one of the few places where
Americans can go back to Vietnam and
they don't seem to hold any grudge at
all.
Exhibit a exhibit a man.
Honestly it will.
Asian people in general are just much
more forgiving and understanding.
It seems like after like,
I think,
I mean,
I don't have much,
I think,
I think that's a giant generalization.
It probably is,
you know,
I mean,
I did a fast for like four days and then
I was at the best buy and um,
and I remember this Vietnamese guy was
trying to help me out and I couldn't
even hear him.
I was so hungry.
I couldn't ended up fast for four days.
Oh Dude.
Yeah.
When you're trying to prove,
I don't know,
man,
I was probably just dealing with some
stuff and I was just trying to find a
different way to handle it,
you know?
Um,
and then I remember this Vietnamese guy
and I remember thinking,
if everybody turned the other way for a
second,
I could eat this young fella.
His name was ben actually over here in
Westwood,
but,
and I'd never thought,
God,
it's so ridiculous.
Well,
I mean,
but here's the thing,
I'd never thought that before.
So you only,
you got to the verge of cannibalism
after just four days.
Yeah.
Damn.
How much weight did you lose?
I probably lost about four pounds and
pounds.
I needed to know,
but I got clear man.
I could see and I could hear.
Swear to God.
Y'All could hear somebody fold a piece
of bread from 80 feet away,
bro.
I was so hungry dude.
I could hear a fucking skittle hit the
summit.
Cross the street.
I really
could.
Man.
Do you think that it heightens your
senses because your,
your hunger was so sharp.
One hundred percent and I could see how
people felt.
I could see how people felt if somebody
wasn't feeling well,
I could see it man.
Whoa.
Really?
I swear I just,
I think I became much more in tune and
it could've been the hunger that then
like manifested itself into you,
you know,
wanting to find other ways in a way to
connect with people.
So then maybe you know,
limbically you would think,
oh,
maybe they'll give me food or something.
You know,
if that makes any sense.
It does a little bit.
Well also I wonder if this is pure
speculation,
but I wonder if it's possible that
animals,
you know,
they say animals have like intense acute
sense of smell and we know that their
vision is fucking spectacular,
right?
Like a cat.
Cats have spectacular.
You're like,
I think that they said a wild sheep has
a vision that's 10 times better than a
human beings.
Like yeah,
they have like 10 x binoculars.
Like that's how wild sheep is looking at
you all the time to hey turkeys think
too.
I think Turkey's main might be even
stronger or turkeys.
Turkeys might even be 20 power.
I got like double,
like a powerful set of binoculars.
You wouldn't expect it looking at him,
you know.
But what else was going to say is I
wonder if they see things that we don't
detect.
Like I wonder if they could see like an
actual aura or like it maybe be like you
don't just smell different when you're
scared because they say you smell
different.
They can smell fear and adrenaline.
Like I wonder if they can see things
too.
Yeah.
Like if they could see your feelings
kind of.
Yeah.
Like Dang,
that guy over there is depressed,
you know,
like the guy said,
yeah,
I could either.
That's interesting.
Well,
it's interesting then because animals
are like,
you know,
supposed to be like,
for some people they're very comforting.
Maybe that's one of the reasons why if
they have a better sense of sight that
can then like transcend
just a visual capability.
Shit.
Would it at Jamie just pulled this up.
Some animals are capable of magneto
reception boom,
an added sense that helps them detect
magnetic fields.
European scientists have now learned
that the molecule responsible for this
trait is also found in the eyes of dogs
and some primates,
which suggests the two might be capable
of seeing magnetic fields.
Holy fucking shit.
I knew it did.
Holy Shit.
I knew dogs and primates may be able to
see magnetic fields.
Now.
This is February 23rd 2016.
So this is a year ago.
So this is all fairly new stuff.
Which is funny though.
A year ago,
you're like,
God.
So long ago,
dude.
Yeah,
it was new shit.
Now that's a year.
That's amazing.
So they might be able to like you,
you know you've heard it or as did you,
do you ever,
do you believe in ours?
What's your feeling on someone who said
they could see your aura?
Well,
I'm in.
I remember one time this lady thought I
was,
I was at a Vfw,
right?
And I was waiting to get a ride home and
this lady said she asked me if I was
like an angel or something and I was
like,
no.
And she said,
you seem like an angel.
She wants some deck.
She might have wanted some decks.
Sweet Angel.
And she was kind of busted as well,
so that's Kinda bad apple.
But it worked.
You might.
Well thank you ma'am.
I was waiting for someone to come and
say that to me and if they did,
I knew I'd be with them because that's
how it's meant to be as true.
It could have been over here.
Angel Swing,
a sweet Dick ran out swing Lulu beer and
feet.
She was going through a tough time.
It's all I vaguely remember about her,
but she wasn't very.
She wasn't doing physical fitness?
No.
Do you think that people,
like when you hear someone like an can
see ours,
what is your automatic assumption?
Bullshit or.
Hm?
Well,
I think some people can get indefinitely
or closer to getting a feeling if
they're.
If they're pretty clear themselves and
they are coming from like a neutral,
pretty neutral state where they're not
overwhelmed in their head and that sort
of thing,
then yeah,
they might be able to pick up energy is
pretty much better I think.
Hmm.
You know,
like have you ever had somebody come up
to you and be like,
you have just like one of those kind of
a little bit hippy Ish lady.
Usually this.
Usually it happens to me.
It's a hippyish woman and she'll be
like,
you just have the best energy,
you know?
But I always think they're.
They have ulterior motives.
Yeah.
She was trying to get some Dick Theo
Vaughn's another one.
I don't know.
You ladies if I was a Hippie Lady,
you're the kind of guy.
Go for really fucked Ya.
An eight.
Yeah.
But you look like you'd be fun for a
Hippie Lady.
Perfect.
Hippie lady still has good feet even
though she wears sandals all the time.
Yeah,
that's true.
No TV fricking but a whole room full of
dream catchers.
I'm out,
dude.
He can't treat 'em out.
Dude.
This is where my dream sleep.
Well,
when I get up in the morning,
I say my praise,
my praise to the universe.
And then I checked the dream catcher for
ideas.
What if we caught today?
What's my first thought of the day?
Just emptying out my dream catcher.
She's shaking him into a net and that's
when I knew that I was going to teach
aqua yoga.
It's my new style of yoga that I've
created.
I hope we were out here in a kitty
swimming pool or yoga there.
That's La man.
I got involved in orgasmic meditation.
You ever done that?
I wish I had.
If you had somebody in about it,
no orgasmic meditation.
Like you meditate as you're coming or
you meditate until you come up,
will you?
I don't get the man doesn't release any
semen.
The women,
uh,
they find pleasure in it.
Um,
but yeah,
I mean there's a lot of stuff like that
out here in Los Angeles,
you know,
you can get caught up.
I remember this story about this dude
who was in jail and he had managed to
seduce one of the female guards.
It was a female guard and just cruise
around her enough and eventually she'll
let them out or something like that.
Something happened.
But this dude could lie in his bed and
through the power of his mind,
he'd make his dick fully hard without
touching it.
And then he come on himself without
moving.
That's the dark art.
Sounds like what I'm saying.
Don't trust somebody that comes without
touching themselves.
It seems a little extreme.
I can understand that.
It could be possible to do that because
I've had wet dreams,
so if I've had wet dreams,
wet dream is all like you.
Your mind thinks you're actually having
sex and then you ejaculate and then you
wake up and you fucking idiot.
I am.
I came all over myself.
That's,
that's the reality of a wet dream.
Right?
So that's all possible through the mind,
so that's possible through the mind.
Why isn't it possible for someone who's
a really dedicated practitioner of
meditation to just concentrate entirely
on recreating the sensation of
pleasurable intercourse to the point
where they ski all over themselves,
excessive while you're staring in the
eyes of the guard,
the prison guard now.
That's awesome.
If you can look them in the eyes and do
it and she's looking at you like,
let's just move to Mexico,
baby.
Aww.
That's a wizard work,
man.
That sounds cool.
And Louis throws documentary where he's
at the prison.
They talk about like trying to come
while they're staring at the prison
guard in the eyes and it's like,
that's not sexual abuse or something
like that.
And I'm talking about.
Did you see that?
Yeah,
that's right,
right.
Yeah.
I try to do it to try to get them to
pass by.
They tried to ejaculate on them too,
I think.
Yeah,
I think so.
Well that was in silence of the lambs
number.
Yeah.
Actually saw up,
ran into that guy the other day.
Anthony Hopkins.
Dude,
remember the guy next to Anthony Hopkins
Migs,
he uh,
came,
came in his hand and threw it in Jodie
foster's face.
Yeah.
What happened to him?
That was his one moment.
That was this big moment,
a big moment that I did.
Dude,
come home and in a movie that's a
fricking old,
that's old fashioned.
Did our big thing.
Used to be the jerk off of the bus
window when I was growing up.
But it's a weird thing to want to come
on somebody like,
like,
like as they're coming here,
they come here,
they got ya.
And see right there he throws it at her.
I think it seems old fashioned to me,
kinda seemed like an old fashioned game,
you know,
it's a barbaric game,
but it makes sense that prisoners would
do that.
But how crazy is that?
Like he got his cum on her face and
she's probably haunted by that forever.
Obviously it's not a real person.
It didn't really happen and it probably
was just like frosting.
If you were in prison or some sort of a
deal like that,
do you think you did advance into
homosexuality or not?
Honestly,
honestly I think a lot of people do.
I think you'd have to really consider if
you're going to be locked in there for
the rest of your life,
whether or not you were cool with
fucking dudes or no pleasure.
Now what if you had like one appeal but
it was like 25,
like an appeal trial and it was 25 years
later.
Like that's kind of the risk,
you know like how many years will some
dudes would get.
They rationalize it like in like gang
banger communities.
They call it gay for the stay.
Yeah.
And they would go and they would just
get gay soon as they get in jail and
then they get out of jail.
They try not to be gay.
That was in that movie American me and
obviously I have no idea how,
how accurate that was,
but that's been discussed before.
But I think Edward James Almost when he
did that movie,
I think he kinda got in trouble with
some gang bangers who were particularly
upset about the way he portrayed her
while in prison life in there.
And they're like,
you know,
they were upset at them about the
alarming the.
They'll be quite terrifying.
I mean,
alarming group Tub.
Set the wrong group to upset because
they have like drug induced gays.
I remember.
Hello.
Bye.
Is that real?
Yeah.
The rug induced.
They can,
they can get you with the drug.
No,
no,
no.
Like if you like,
I remember they had like a,
I mean there's popular culture in the
eighties and nineties where they had
like behind the rest areas,
a lot of men would meet up and um,
you know,
do drugs and find pleasure with each
other back there,
you know,
rest areas,
rest stops on highways.
Yeah.
Rest stops off the interstate.
Um,
you know,
usually like a seaman building,
couple of water fountain where it is.
It was a party stopped back in the day.
You when you want to rest like you
tired.
Yeah.
Fuck,
that's a long drive.
I'm just gonna pull in here and take a
nap.
We leave this window open.
Some do reaches in and grabs your Dick.
Like,
Hey,
I'm just trying to sleep at all and
everybody comes here to fuck.
No,
this is the desktop.
We used to walk.
We used to go see it because I lived
across from this river and the other
side of the river was the back of the
rest area.
I know a lot of me back there partying
and you smell it.
No,
you couldn't smell it.
It was fun.
It's like a dog chasing a dog could
smell it because he dogs would be like,
I think a Turkey could see it fucking
going on somewhere within this five mile
radius for sure.
If you can smell skunk a block away,
a dog.
It's Muslim,
but fucking away from your house to that
rest stop.
One hundred percent guaranteed.
Like if that rest stop was like a,
a fucking escapee from prison and they
gave him the shirt,
smell it,
buddy.
Go get him.
You.
It smelled that bud fucking,
you know they were there.
Maybe.
I wonder if we could get heightened
senses in the future.
Maybe that's one of the things that's
coming next.
You know?
I would imagine we're gearing towards
it.
It feels like maybe naturally our senses
might be getting dollar.
Yeah,
because I think we don't use them.
We don't use them for danger.
We don't use them to stock pray.
We don't use them to run from something.
We just don't.
We don't use them,
so I think they're getting weaker and
weaker when the are thumbs up.
Thumbs need to move fast.
Now I bet we have the fastest thumbs.
Have any fucking living being that's
ever existed.
I mean to look back at people like thumb
dexterity now compared to today.
Oh I bet people can do.
I bet if I did this to some,
some people in the 18 hundreds,
they would go like,
you will learn to move your thumbs with
such speed.
Come and see the mind.
If you showed somebody an iphone back
then and just texted a message on it and
you're like,
here,
just text.
Text your name on there.
They but they would be so slow and
stupid,
but you're flying through your phone
phones.
We'll get your fingers will get quicker.
Hearing will probably stay the same.
No need for it to get any better
hearing.
Your body's going to shrink shrivel
away.
Bones,
muscles.
We're going to become like little
aliens.
The aliens,
the big heads.
A little bodies will be in carts.
Will be in some type of a cartoon.
Yeah.
It's like an old fashion.
Look at Tesla will.
We'll have individual teslas that are
like eggs and surround you and you can't
even steer and they just drive you to
work,
drive you where you want to go.
You just talked to and it takes you
somewhere.
But we will.
Will we still have sex?
We'll have to have some sort of a of a,
of a union,
but it'll probably be done in a lab.
I don't think they'll do sex anymore.
You know?
That's kind of happen one day.
Yeah,
I think you're right.
I think one day they'll make the people
decided,
look,
we have sex for pleasure and you know,
we'll,
we'll still do that.
And we'll meet in the meeting,
will be done in a laboratory because it
ensures 100 percent excellent DNA,
healthy children.
You can factor out racism,
you know,
you could,
you could probably do things to your
kid.
Like I want my kid to be a seven foot
tall,
you know,
pro lineman.
I want them to grow up to be 440 pounds
lighter.
All right,
there you go.
Done.
And they fix it.
Yeah.
If that happens,
man,
people are not going to just take a
chance with regular sex and having
regular kid.
So they're going to produce these super
babies.
So slowly but surely it'll start out
like cell phones were.
Remember when Gordon Gecko was walking
down the beach,
that big ass brick and nobody would be
caught dead with today.
It would be just like that.
We'll start off with those stupid
bricks.
It only rich people have and that
eventually that break will be a fucking
joke.
And everybody,
it's going to be easy to pay.
It'll be just like everything else.
Do you get your kid vaccinated?
Yes.
Did you pick what your kid's gonna be?
Yeah.
Yeah,
I made a fucking Amazon woman,
they can kill people with their legs and
some people would still be like,
well,
we went the old fashioned way,
you know,
we were deciding not to choose.
We're going to leave it up to the
universe.
What if your kid is born with some sort
of an ailment?
You'd be so heartbroken.
I'd go big Asian Dude.
I'd go four or five.
Six huge Asian sons,
nine feet tall.
Nine feet to loggers.
Wow.
The loggers browse more than a logger.
How long do you think they would last
though?
Like how long do you live if you're nine
feet tall?
Not,
not a whole long.
Eight or nine years old.
I bet you know what I'm saying.
Who is the biggest guy?
The biggest guy knew growing up,
this kid named Ricardo,
he died at like 14 or 12.
He died at 12.
He had a heart attack.
How big was it?
Playing basketball and he's probably
about 65.
Wow.
He was huge.
He was that age.
He had a hard time,
had a heart attack in the basketball
game.
Hold on Shit.
And do remember len bias.
Remember that guy who was playing for
the Celtics,
he dropped dead in the middle of a game.
Well,
yeah,
and he hits some cocaine.
Didn't he?
Donate doom.
Doom.
Wow.
That is the tallest guy ever.
Robert Wadlow.
He was eight feet 11 inches.
So he's essentially nine feet tall.
I mean he probably had a fucked up
posture to like his body looks like it
was all wrecked with arthritis and shit.
His joints must have been just
completely fucked up.
I bake.
Took a whole family out with his leg
though.
It was.
Well,
you would be able to escape his triangle
because his legs are so long.
They wouldn't be able to squeeze down
enough.
He could decorate his legs for
Christmas.
I bet it would be trying to triangle a
squirrel.
Like good luck.
Tronic Triangle Square Squirrel.
The little motherfuckers gonna escape.
He's getting too much room and his legs.
You'll pop your head right out of there
and take side control.
But wouldn't you be scared to like.
I feel like some of these athletes,
they got to be scared.
They're going to die a lot.
Like you think that's a fear that kind
of lives in their head because because
of they're so big and immense.
Yeah.
Larry Bird was actually talking about
that recently because Larry Byrd is.
I think he's six foot nine.
Wow.
And his wife was real bummed out about.
I'm saying it because I'm saying that no
one over seven feet tall ever lives to
be like 75 years old.
They just don't live that long.
You don't see those guys walking around
with that age.
And it's true.
It's real sad.
Know had to do something about that.
And we need light for the tall,
not a charity.
You know what it is,
man.
It's just this weird fucking give and
take to this universe.
And if you have this massive advantage
in size,
your ride is quicker.
You know?
It's almost like having a muscle car
with a small gas tank.
This is what you get.
You want that 600 horsepower shelby gt,
500.
Well you get this with.
You got a 10 gallon gas tank.
So good luck.
Yeah.
You know I had a ford escort back in the
day,
man.
You ever drive an escort?
Bill?
Russell's still alive.
80 three.
Holy Shit.
That's amazing.
Somebody send that to Larry Bird,
but he's black.
Black people have better genetics.
Um,
no,
no.
They have just as many problems.
I'm joking around,
but black definitely doesn't crack.
It's definitely a better skin for aging
for sure.
It's sugars a little bit.
It doesn't crack.
You know,
Larry Bird,
someone get him that quickly I think.
I think it's more likely today that a
giant people like that will live longer
because they're just so good with
medicine and health and so much
understanding about how to take care of
yourself.
Yeah.
But I bet back in the day was like a
real problem.
You know,
the heart attack is a real issue I
guess.
Just so much travel.
The blood has to go through and imagine
like if you're seven feet tall,
all the extra real estate your heart has
to pump through.
You know,
even thought about that.
Yeah,
I mean in that sense,
you got to think like you're,
you're on borrowed time once you're
hitting your sixties.
It's like,
oof.
Anything can happen from here on out.
Man,
you got a heart,
like a regular heart.
Yeah,
but you've got a giant body.
You had a crazy body.
Their heart's got to be bigger than a
normal person's there.
Big.
Everything's bigger.
Their feet are bigger.
Hands are bigger.
I would assume their head's bigger.
Their heart's got to be bigger to right.
I would guess,
man,
I got the heart of the lesbian.
That's what they told me that I was
young and I got a small rib cage to.
Don't they say your heart is the same
size of your fist or is that bullshit?
Is that real?
They tell you when you're a kid.
I don't know if it's real though.
Brock Lesnar and a giant fucking heart.
He's a big fist.
Giant dude.
Huge,
ridiculous lunchboxes.
Big Old lunchboxes.
Is it scary when you meet him?
He's just so big.
It doesn't even.
You don't even feel like you're the same
thing.
Like,
wow,
how are you and I both people the fuck
is that possible?
It's like you ever see like a poodle
meet like a great Dane and the great
thing is like the fuck is this.
Who was like,
what the fuck is that?
The same thing.
It's hard to believe,
you know,
a while.
Then the really freaky Ufo people,
they believe that that's proof positive
that human beings were genetically
engineered the same way dogs were,
because you know,
nobody knows where dogs came from.
We know the dogs came from wolves
because they do genetic tests on these
dogs and they realized that all dogs
started off as a wolf.
All of them,
and this is like really recently,
they realize that dogs did.
Yeah.
All dogs.
Wawa,
even a Chihuahua.
That part I don't.
I wouldn't either except for these
scientists.
Dudes have already done the DNA work.
You got to respect what they came up
with,
I guess,
but what they thought was at one point
in time they thought it was a bunch of
wild canids.
Like all of them were like,
they thought like some dogs were from
this wild dog,
from Africa and some dogs maybe came
from wolves,
like a Husky that looks like a wolf,
right?
Nope.
Once they did the DNA,
they realize,
oh my God,
they're all wolves.
It's the wolf.
Everything's a wolf.
Then what happened then?
How did some of them get done?
We don't know.
We really don't know Sean.
Good question.
They know that they can do some things.
There was a great article,
not article,
excuse me,
episode of Radio Lab,
which is an amazing guy,
great podcast.
It's really good man,
and they had a really good one on Fox.
Says it was part of the episode,
but it was about engineering animals and
about engineering evolution and how long
you could change genes,
how long it would take,
and they took these foxes.
They took them from Wild Fox is like a
completely wild.
Yeah.
Were you know,
they were just in a regular Fox and by
selectively breeding them,
just selectively breeding them.
They had them down to this floppy eared,
weird,
docile,
like pet fox thing.
Just a few generations,
like just a few years.
They just did these experiments for a
few years and then eventually got these
animals down to.
They were like almost unrecognizable
from a Fox.
Their jaws were smaller that yours were
floppy.
They became like a different thing.
Is that going to.
It took while to make them domestic hit
enough were to create a market.
I think they were doing that may be,
but they were definitely also writing it
down as experiments that we're trying to
figure out how long it would take.
I don't totally remember the premise for
the experiment,
like why they decided to do it,
but I remember the results and the
results were they would take any,
any of these foxes that showed any
aggression towards people,
any of them that weren't like instantly
submissive.
They would shoot him,
kill him,
and then the ones that were submitted
them,
they.
They lived,
so the ones that lived with the ones
that were the most timid and the most
submissive,
and they started getting these floppy
ears like their ears instead of sticking
straight up.
They started flopping and their jaws got
smaller,
like the whole thing changed.
I think they've changed color to like
what's happening,
like what's happening in America,
kind of a little bit,
little bit,
little bit.
Well,
that's what these UFO freaks believe.
They believe that.
That's proof positive that aliens came
down and grabbed some monkeys,
like has a monkey become a human.
We look.
You could see a person,
you see chimpanzee and you go,
okay,
I kind of see where that could have gone
into that.
Yeah,
I don't buy it,
but where's all the stuff in the middle?
Yeah,
we're the middle monkeys as well.
How come we're udall understand
genetics.
You're right.
I don't,
but I'm just saying it.
It is odd.
I'm not saying we didn't come from
humans from chimpanzees.
Of course we did.
Or from lower primate.
That's a cousin to the chimpanzee really
early in the Middle Lane.
I think there could've been a middleman
whether it was for sure,
but those.
Those all died off and that kind of
makes sense,
but it is totally fascinating that we're
so far ahead of everything else.
My point is when you look at a human,
there's nothing remotely like us.
It's not like a giraffe is similar to a
deer.
A deer is the intellectual equivalent of
a horse,
you know?
No,
there's none of that,
man.
There's this one thing,
this one thing that has the weirdest
hair,
like,
uh,
your face doesn't have hair except for
like this part.
It's an anomaly.
Your body only has like a little like,
what?
Where's that hair?
What's the hair for?
Is it leftover?
Is this,
you look like a mixture of some shit.
He was like one of those hairless cats
who did this to you?
How did they make this out of you?
And people think aliens took us.
It took monkeys and came back with us.
That's what they think it will make.
If you look at Shaquille o'neal and then
you look at like Brittany Spears,
clearly they look very different.
They're the same species.
They could easily interbreed just like a
wolf could easily have sex with a
bulldog because they're really all
wolves,
which is so hard to believe.
Like if you didn't know species,
if you came here,
you were some fucking ball of plasma
from another dimension and you came here
to study.
There's not a fucking chance in hell.
You would think that Brittany Spears was
the same thing as Shaquille o'neal or
me.
That I was the same thing as Shaquille
o'neal or you know,
look,
look at anyone,
like I'm a fucking molly ringwald and
then put her next to Mike Tyson.
How is that the same?
How is it the same thing,
but it's all the same thing.
You have the Anthony Lyn,
the,
the Chinese basketball player that got
famous for awhile.
Jeremy Lin?
Yes.
Jeremy Lin.
That's right.
Sorry.
Put.
There you go.
Look at Shaquille o'neal.
He's enormous.
He's so big.
It doesn't even make sense.
Look at his pants too,
man.
But you see if you saw him and we'll pay
next to like a very small Asian guy.
Like maybe the one that you tried to eat
at the store.
Ben was his name actually.
Then if you saw him next to Ben,
you would say,
okay,
if you came from another planet and you
saw a chimpanzee next to an orangutan,
you would like,
well those are different species,
right?
This is clearly two different things,
but they're not.
They're not.
Well,
those are chimpanzees.
Orangutans aren't,
but people aren't.
Yeah.
The same thing.
We're so weird.
It's so weird that we can like,
we look so different from each other,
but we all breed with each other just
like dogs do.
I'm amazed that monkeys don't like,
here's what I don't think that we
evolved from monkeys because.
Because monkeys never come visit us.
Know what I'm saying though?
Oh yeah.
Do you make it a lot of sense?
Like we go visit them though.
Think about this.
We go visit them at the zoo.
We're out in the nature Malaysia,
but they never went.
Have you ever like,
I'm it.
But when you open your window up and
seen a couple of monkeys just seeing,
you know,
hey,
what's up?
What could have been if they had gotten
their act together?
Man,
yeah.
They will be like,
look at these motherfuckers in their
car,
but they never do it.
They,
they show pretty much zero interest when
we pass by and that seems striking to me
if,
if we're the top grade of that species,
dude,
I'm a peek over and see what's going on.
You know when I see shack,
I go watch shack.
I paid to go watch him because he's the
best of,
you know,
have a physical space,
maybe have,
have part of our breed of humanity.
Well,
there's people that go to brock Lesnar
just to watch and pick a man over his
head and slam them down on the ground
because they'd see him hoists some 300
pound dude over his head and you're
like,
what in the fuck?
Like,
how is that guy?
The same thing as me,
but if I'm getting my associate's degree
does not 700 monkeys in the woods.
Like freaking out.
Like I can't believe they did it.
Yeah,
man,
this is like an inspirational movie.
Maybe the whole human experience is an
inspirational movie.
The monkeys.
Yeah.
You know,
they're like looking at us and like
maybe one day,
Nah,
let's just eat these coconuts.
I don't know man.
I just don't know if they know,
like,
I don't know.
That's where I really fall apart is when
they don't care as much as we do.
Well,
if you go to Costa Rica,
they care around you all the time.
You go to a stay at a hotel in Costa
Rica,
they always hang around hotels because
people would go,
oh my God,
the monkey,
and they feed them and is how much to
feed them.
We gave a monkey some oreos like oreo
cookies and we were like,
debating,
should we give this monkey oreos?
I'm like,
it's going to be like crack for that
monkey.
Like that amount of sugar.
What do you think eats on amount of
sugar,
and then I thought about.
I'm like,
I bet that fucking monkey eats oreos all
the time.
I go,
it's just keeping one oreo.
You don't.
We did.
He take the Oreo and he twisted it
opened.
They start eating the frosting.
That motherfucker had gotten so many
oreos.
He knows how to eat the frosting like
the party.
Did you do that when you're a kid?
Twisted Tyler,
and then you scrape it with your teeth?
We see frosting and then you would
reluctantly eat the cookie like that.
Hasn't had a little frosting on it
first,
but the half that have more frosting on
it for us.
Exactly.
I miss that,
man.
I would love to have the trails of a
child,
but whatever.
I mean,
not like a,
you know,
I know what you mean because you just
have system with child.
Think about that.
I remember eating a.
me and my buddies split a 90 pack of
Vanilla cremes one night.
Wow.
Wait the whole thing.
Just 45 cookies up there.
So insane.
That's so many cookies.
No issue.
We will up in the morning.
Headache,
nausea,
diarrhea.
No monkeys at the window.
Nothing.
The thing is,
you're not aware of what it's doing to
you either.
So your kid doesn't understand.
Why do I feel like shit?
They don't like directly put it
together.
What?
You just ate a tub of ice cream.
Fuck.
You can't just eat a tub of ice cream.
That's like 50,000 milligrams of sugar
or some shit.
Kids are nuts,
man.
I think we got to lower some of these
regulations on a lot of these children.
You know?
Um,
just to be firm up a little bit,
a lot of these kids are a lot weaker.
I feel like they,
when I was a child,
what kind of regulations are you talking
about?
Regulation to beef them up.
I mean,
I just think,
you know,
younger driving age is younger drinking.
They just things that are going to get,
you know,
more experienced.
I feel like,
you know,
well that the problem with the younger
driving age is they're gonna put us in
danger like I think even the age it is
right now.
Fifteen and 16.
That's a little sketchy for some kids.
It was definitely sketchy for me.
It was a shitty day.
I got a lot of accidents,
but I was like 15,
16,
definitely shouldn't have been driving.
It was too crazy.
Where were you driving in cars?
I always had muscle.
You were that guy you selling drugs or.
No,
I have a 19,
68,
four,
two.
A wrapped around a tree right in front
of the high school.
Hydroplaned man had bald tires and it
was.
The water was wet and we were going
around this corner.
My car just just said,
Ooh,
we're going to slide.
Did everybody see?
You know,
they found my car afterwards,
so smashed my car in half,
like cracked the frame and shit.
You remember the first time you ever
drove off in your car?
The feeling you had,
like the first time you ever pulled off
in your vehicle by yourself?
Yeah.
Crazy.
Well,
I just think I was an irresponsible
driver because I was,
I was,
I was going pedal to the metal with
everything.
Yeah,
like whether it was a car or there was
fighting,
like what is.
That was what I was competing in martial
arts too.
It was like I was crazy.
Like you can't,
there's no way a kid who's 16 years old
who just started driving,
she'd be able to get a 400 horsepower
muscle cars.
Much insane.
Too much power.
I had to,
I had no maturity.
You know,
I just,
I grew up for a broken family,
so it's like all this anger issues and
weird chill.
You can't give someone like that.
A muscle car.
Did you have to have some discipline?
Did you know that you like were pedal to
the metal like that?
Did you like,
did you realize it in relation to other
kids or were you just being yourself?
Is.
It was just being myself,
I didn't realize how crazy I was.
I've definitely felt uncomfortable
around other kids sometimes.
You know,
we moved a lot around a lot though.
It was attributed to that.
We'd never looked in one place at one
time.
You know?
I just think in general,
teenage boys are really risky for a lot
of things.
Like my buddy was talking to me about
this the other day.
My Buddy Eric Chris,
he was like,
they're the most dangerous thing in our
societies,
teenage boys and I never thought about
it,
but he's kind of like a teenage daughter
at the time.
She seen edge and we were talking about
it and he was like the most dangerous
thing in our society,
and I thought about it.
I was like,
yeah,
you don't want it is because they're,
they have manpower,
laboy brains and their brain,
your frontal lobe doesn't even fully
developed until you're like 25.
Wow.
Your total ability to process thoughts
correctly.
It's not like fully functional until you
look 25.
That's the middle of it.
Maybe that's the middle monkey joe to be
on.
You know what I'm saying?
Like maybe that kind of maybe like
that's why that whole species died off
if they were here because they were all
like teenage boys.
They had the boy brain,
but the man body will let chimps.
Chimps are like horrible people.
That's what they're like.
That is super strong.
They're strong.
It's like a 500 pound person and they're
horrible,
mean,
vindictive,
jealous people.
Are they?
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
I didn't even know that chimps punish
each other too.
They punish people to God.
They don't just try to hurt you.
They try to punish you.
They try to take your fingers away,
take your genitals away.
It literally pull your genitals off and
attack you.
What did they learn that or I wonder if
they're smart.
They're super smart.
They're not as smart as a person,
but they're way smarter than a chicken.
Yeah,
they're,
they're.
They're thinking and looking at you and
when you're doing something that they
don't like.
The guy that got really torn apart,
it was a terrible story,
ripped his face off and tore his eyes
out and shit.
Um,
it was his pet.
He was going to see how to pet chimp and
after a while with champs,
one of something will happen at temple
snap on somebody like you remember that?
Chimp fucked up.
That lady's friend in Connecticut.
She had a pet chimp at tore this lady
apart.
When the police.
I know a lady,
a panther killed her cousin one time,
but this chip.
But the chip thing is crazy because this
guy had a pet chimp,
but then it's chipped bit someone's
finger off.
So they really couldn't keep the
chimpanzee morning.
They brought it to a chimp sanctuary.
So as they had this chimp at the chimp
sanctuary,
these other people had brought chimps
there.
And it was like this whole like
enclosure where all the chimps were.
And he gave his champ a birthday cake
because it was champs birth and Kim to
settle,
celebrate with them.
And the other chimps were so mad they
didn't bring him a cake that they,
that he didn't bring them a cake that
they escaped from the enclosure.
The one of the gates was open,
got ahold of the guy in,
tore him apart.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
Towards feed off.
Just tore his dick off.
Like they'd tear you apart.
They,
they,
they try to tear apart the parts of you
that they think you value the most.
Really.
A,
yeah.
And they do it out of jealousy.
Like they were punishing him for making
them feel bad that they didn't get the
cake.
They're monsters just heartbreak there.
They're in.
They,
they look,
they're not always this way,
just like people aren't always monsters.
But chimpanzees inhabit some of the most
terrifying traits and human beings.
There was a great article recently about
these chimps and they had this one alpha
male that was teamed up with another
Alpha male and they dominated this
village and they were horrible and
ruthless.
And then one of them got real sick and
he went away for awhile and came back.
But he was like physically all fucked up
and so the original Alpha team was down
to one guy and this one alpha male,
they teamed up on them.
They all,
all the other chimps got together and
they figured out a way to Jack this dude
that they attacked him and killed him
and then cannibalized him.
They killed him and then cannibalized
him.
Yeah.
I didn't know they were up till that.
See,
now I might even go to the zoo now.
Dude.
Honestly,
it really does give you a different
perception,
you know,
because you don't see that.
They don't put that on the sign out
front.
You know,
they just put that there,
you know,
some of them are from Africa or Malaysia
and that they're happy to be there in
the zoo,
you know?
Definitely not happy to be there in the
zoo.
Definitely not.
Would you fight a chimp fuck that.
They'll kill you.
You have no chance.
No chance.
Do you think it's like a baby?
Do you think a baby and kick your ass?
Not most babies,
no.
Yeah,
that's what I think about a chimp.
I think there's not a chance in hell.
Chimps going to kill you.
What about this chimp one?
Arm Chimp either.
He'll still kill you with one arm,
right?
He might kill me.
Would you go against him?
I'm know he'll.
He'll fuck me up too strong.
I don't think you understand how strong
you're talking about.
You're talking about something that's
like a 500 pound person.
It's so much stronger than you.
If it gets a hold of you and it will,
it's going to pull your arms right out
of your socket.
One arm of norms.
If it's face,
it's going to grab a hold of you with
his feet.
It's got feet that a thumbs on it.
It'll hold onto you with its feet and
they'll bite your neck off.
Fuck man.
You making me nervous?
Honestly.
Did.
Well,
that's where we came from.
I mean that's one of the reasons why
we're still capable of,
uh,
you know,
hand to hand combat to this day,
because we used to have to probably do
it.
It's,
it's got to be somehow or another in our
ancient primate DNA.
But it's the question is how did we get
so far ahead of the rest of them?
Yeah.
Something happened,
something happened and we hit a jump.
We hit a leap year.
Man,
I'm serious.
That was something occurred where or
something where we came from the other
way.
It could be just some random mutation.
It could be something that we ate.
It could be something that hit us,
it could be radiation.
You know,
Terence Mckenna thought it was
mushrooms.
He thought people found mushrooms and
started eating mushrooms that have made
us evolve at a faster rate.
Some people have attributed to our diet,
but that doesn't totally make sense.
Some people attributed to our use of
fire because when we used fire we cooked
meat and we got more nutrients out of it
and that allowed us also to a bit get
clever and how we kept the fire and use
of throwing tools like spears and shit
like that or di coordination.
Women could have made us do it though.
They could have literally been like,
get your shit together,
you know?
And we brought it up,
push pussy.
So good.
We had to evolve to keep them around.
It's gone now.
I think.
No offense if anybody has a puts out
there,
but I think a lot of pussies going down
hill these days.
I don't feel like it's what it used to
be.
You think so or not?
What's changed?
I don't know what's changed.
I don't know if just the value that they
put on it or just the fact that it's.
I think a lot of it feels a little bit
more like a Dick.
A little bit.
Like it doesn't have the same pussy
feeling is that same texture.
I think it just doesn't have the same
softness to it.
You know?
So literally Vaginas have changed you.
I think vaginas are getting harder than
they were when we were 30 years.
Do you think it's possible?
It's just a guess like maybe something's
going on with you.
You just think it's like a collective
across the board transformation.
I think that yeah,
I think the species are kind of like
even in an up and that's going to make
you don't think so man.
It's a funny thought.
So now they're getting stronger and
harder.
Men are getting weaker because men are,
because there's some other purpose
anymore.
He knows a lot of men out there just
crying behind a fucking dairy queen
right now,
not knowing what to do with themselves.
There are on a show and he's probably.
What's Tony's anymore?
Scissor now,
what is it?
As Jamie says,
we're now.
But yeah,
places like that,
you know,
and a lot of managers disheartened and I
think that they just not the same.
What is the instinct because there's an
instinct from males are.
And so to put women down and to hold
their significant other down,
but there's also a,
an instinct that women have to,
uh,
diminish a man's manliness and to like,
it's not always the emasculate them
demasculate,
right?
Yeah.
Or masculinity masculine.
And it's not a,
it's not all of them for sure know when
I'm done,
I'm not talking about it,
but I'm talking about,
we all know that they exist on both
sides,
on the male side and the women's side,
like people that did not try to pump you
up,
they trying to shoot you down.
Right?
But what is that instinct,
that instinct in the women that some
that some women have to try to like
diminish.
You try to chip,
chip,
chip away at you.
Maybe they have more man and maybe they
have a little more man in them and so
they're more pitch and they look at you.
You fucking,
you're such a bitch.
You don't even have any heart.
You don't have any cards,
like almost challenging you.
Yeah.
Almost want you to smack them.
You think,
I'm sure a couple of years have started
that way util the murders started for
sure.
That's the cops say,
right?
That's the scariest thing they faced.
Domestic violence.
Yeah.
Because you might like find a guy
hitting a girl.
You might pull the guy off and the girl
might shoot you or various diverse.
Yeah.
I don't know what it is in a woman that
does that.
I mean maybe there's probably some of it
is.
I don't think it's genetic.
I think at some they were probably done
wrong by a man previously and that some
of that still probably resonate.
Send them,
you know,
because some women do.
They just want to just make you feel
nasty,
you know,
they want to make you feel nasty.
I hate that.
Don't you think it's also how the,
how you raised,
like if you watch your mom and dad
insult each other and yell shit at each
other becomes ingrained in your system.
Yeah.
Well I think it's fascinating how we
turn into our parents,
even though everybody says they don't
want to.
Well,
it's always interesting to me is how a
lot of people do.
You know,
a lot of people definitely do.
It's easier.
Certainly easier than becoming your own
person.
Becoming your own person requires a lot
of thought.
He,
a lot of people want to think anymore,
man,
but I wonder if people ever wanted to
thank you know,
this is probably the smartest
conversation I've been involved in.
It may be months.
It really is there.
That's the most I've talked to anybody
in a long time.
Well,
I think people want to think but it's
scary and it's a lot of work.
It hurts her head sometimes.
You know,
didn't you?
Your parents were like real old when
they had you write your dad was he and
my dad was.
My Dad was 70 when I was born.
Wow.
Yeah,
he was born in 1910.
Um,
Holy Shit Dude.
You're from a different era.
You got different genes.
Yeah.
Sometime I do think I'll feel a little
more tired.
I feel a little bit.
No,
that's not what I mean.
Yeah.
I mean he got like a,
like early human genes.
Yeah.
You know,
like you're a direct descendant from
someone who was born in 19.
Oh nine.
Yeah.
You know my jeans.
I'm,
I'm 49.
So,
um.
How old are you?
I'm 36.
Yeah.
See I'm more than 10 years old in you.
But my jeans are from 50 years after
yours.
You're 19.
Oh nine.
Is that what you said in 19,
10,
19,
10.
Almost 60 years.
Yeah,
I was born in [inaudible] 67.
So 57 years of difference in our genes.
Like you come from a part of your stock,
you're like old school outlaw Josey.
Wales jeans.
Yeah.
Maybe.
I don't know what I mean.
My Dad did Erp type shit.
Nineteen.
Oh nine dude,
that's like
Ebola for credit cards at the colleges.
I don't think that's really wider,
but he definitely,
you know,
he got out there still,
in 19.
Oh nine.
I mean they didn't even.
I mean,
how many cars were there?
10.
19.
Oh,
nine.
And he didn't have one.
I remember asking him if he had,
when he didn't have one of them.
Was He riding a horse everywhere?
I guess they walked it or something that
imagine you have to work to do gigs.
If you walk thiel Vonda walking,
standup comedian.
Oh my God.
Pending on the spring.
I'll be in Sacramento.
I live in.
You'd have to learn how to do ultra
marathons.
We to run a hundred miles in between
shows at the amazing.
Yeah,
man,
it was wild.
It was pretty wild.
Grown up with an o with an old debt.
I think that's what got me into comedy
honestly.
Just because people would make fun of my
dad a lot and then I had to.
You'd have to have something to say,
you know,
and then you had to create a story too
because people would ask if that was
your dad and you didn't want to admit
it.
A lot of times you.
Wow.
When my dad would just be asleep,
he coming to this,
I'm going to basketball games and be
asleep.
They fall asleep in the car all the
time.
You Fall Asleep in the car pool.
If he came to get us.
Wow.
We thought he was dead all the time,
you know,
just like weird shit like that.
So I think it gave a weird,
uh,
so I guess yeah,
I didn't really think about it,
but maybe that's where I started making
up,
you know,
getting involved in more storytelling,
you know.
How old was he when he'd done or how
will you were 16?
Yeah,
16.
And he was a good dude.
He just got cancer and he was a hard,
you know,
we work pretty hard.
He was,
he was working deep into his seventies.
Oh yeah.
He used to do the credit card he used to
and that's where I first got on stage,
kind of I'll get to the credit card
colleges at the credit card when you go
to the,
you know,
the people that sign up for credit
cards,
you know,
come and get this card,
at the college,
get this card,
you know,
get this free Frisbee.
They always got like a handout with you
and then I get up on the table and bark
and get people over to,
uh,
to do the credit cards.
And so you'd start Kinda riff and a
little bit on people that were walking
by,
you know.
Wow.
But it was,
it was interesting.
He was,
he was 25 years older than my mom's
parents were.
So that would be weird sometimes when he
was 25 years older than your mom's
parents.
How old was your mom?
She's 65 now,
so I don't know.
I don't know man.
I'm,
I'm a,
I'm a middle monkey I guess.
Did you say you're 35 to six?
30 six.
So she was somewhere around 30.
Yeah.
So she was somewhere around 30 and he
was somewhere around 70.
Yeah.
Congratulations sir.
Yeah,
but he didn't have any money though.
He didn't have any money.
Just slinging it though.
Yeah.
But I'll tell you this,
just being a product of it,
you want to,
you want to come out of something that's
got a little bit of cash and it's nuts.
If it's in his seventies,
you know,
but why don't you think that if you did
have that money,
maybe your life of being a little
softer,
maybe you wouldn't have as much
ambition.
Maybe you wouldn't be the seal feel von
sitting in front of me today.
Yeah.
It's,
I think it's all blessing adversity of
the experience as a child that doesn't
fuck you up.
Like physically and you know.
Yeah,
you're right.
Ruin your body,
I think is all good for you,
man.
You're right.
It's just.
I think sometimes I still resonate with
a lot of the feelings that it has a
child.
It's hard to sometimes,
you know,
I'm still getting through some of those
now.
So yes,
I agree with you.
Um,
and I every day I hope to try and see
that a little bit more and I know it's
happening and it does make me realize
more now that the saddest thing in the
world really is a,
is when a kid doesn't really have a
chance or an opportunity or you know,
like you said something physically
happened to him,
you know,
that's bad.
Yeah.
That's one of the saddest things in the
world for sure.
But uh,
yeah man,
that was,
that was the wild part.
I guess that's what it got me into this,
in doing this.
So yeah,
I mean I am,
I am grateful now because I'm able to
look back on it and you know,
and talk about it.
And how crazy would it be if you knew
your grandfather?
Think about how,
what his genes go back to.
Yeah.
I don't know.
I mean look,
if he's,
if he had your dad when he was 20,
that's another,
that's in the 18 hundreds.
Yeah.
So he's born in the 18 hundreds.
Holy Shit.
Yeah.
The 18 hundreds chances.
Christ.
That's crazy.
Oh Man.
Born in the 18 hundreds.
Was your grandfather for sure he was in
the 18 hundreds for sure.
Unless your dad was born and he was
fucking 10 years old,
right?
Yeah.
My father from Nicaragua actually.
Wow.
Nicaraguan.
Where's your mom from?
From Illinois,
Wyoming,
Illinois.
Small town.
And he came up here talking like Juan
Carlos hit bilateral.
Indeed the tongues slinging.
Did Dick?
Yeah,
man,
I got the dig for you.
Yeah.
That wasn't good or bad,
man.
I don't know what he was doing,
I speak Spanish.
Yeah,
he spoke Spanish.
He was nice man.
I don't remember a ton about them
honestly.
I've wished as I was just getting old
enough it was a,
he was falling out,
you know,
but I do remember being scared a lot of
my feelings when I was younger.
Just fear man.
I remember like my dad would walk me to
church sometimes and um,
and I would be scared because the
sidewalks in Louisiana there,
you know,
there's a lot of routes that are coming
up and this bad,
you know,
it's under sea level a lot of it.
So all the sidewalks are all wonky.
It's not even a walk,
it's really just a challenge of pieces
of concrete.
Really look at it.
I never thought about it before,
but through this whole wall,
those kinds of sidewalks,
it's Kinda cool to see those roots
struggling against concrete know it's
ballsy.
It's ballsy for mother nature to be out
there.
This pressing up against those plates
like that and moving them.
Yeah.
And moving them.
But what was weird when I remember being
a kid was walking and just being scared
that he was going to like fall.
And so it was like,
I just remember always being gay or just
being,
you know,
and then I was such a kid and I'm like,
but I just remember this from my first
feelings were like I got to make you
know,
just make sure he where he's walking is
okay.
You know,
I was probably six years old,
so it was just a lot of fear
I think.
And then shame I,
I became ashamed in hindsight.
I feel bad about that.
Yeah.
But that's understandable.
And when you're a kid,
yeah.
It's all confusing to you.
You know,
why doesn't my dad looked like the other
kid's dad?
Why do I have to do this?
Why does this have to happen to me?
You know,
man,
I stayed with my grandpa when I was
first moving to New York.
I couldn't afford my own place when I
moved from Boston and New York and I got
signed by my manager and I was like,
man,
I'm going to move to New York.
This is going to happen.
How to,
how do I make the money?
And My,
my grandfather said,
you can come stay with me for awhile
until you save up enough money for an
apartment.
My grandfather lived in New Jersey and
uh,
it was a very important moment in my
life to stay with them for a few months
because my grandfather was,
he was getting old.
He was and my grandmother was almost
dead because my grandmother had had a
stroke and they had given her 12 years
to live.
But,
or excuse me,
they'd given her 78 hours to live what
you want to live in 12 years.
Damn.
Yeah.
They thought it was over.
They thought the stroke is going to do
her in a couple of days.
She's probably going to be gone.
They found her in the back porch.
It was a really sad story.
She lived though and there was even
sadder that way because she was in pain
and she would get bedsores.
My grandfather had a 10 to 24 hours a
day and I was staying with him during
this time.
Yeah,
so for a few months I was staying with
my grandmother who was on death's door
for.
She lived like a year or so after I
moved out and she wasn't really aware of
me anymore.
She was not quite there anymore and my
grandfather who was struggling to take
care of her and just seemed sad.
Yeah.
And I remember thinking,
man,
this life is temporary.
Like this experience that I'm
experiencing right now is a 24 year old
man.
Like this is not going to last like this
is the prime of my youth.
And I like hard in my ideas that like
you got to get going,
wow,
this is going to happen to you too.
It's going to happen to all of us and
you,
you think that you're this static thing
like you stay in this same exact state.
It's not true.
It's an illusion.
All those people that you see that are
old people that are walking down the
street with their back's hunched over
that you're going to reach that age some
day.
It's going to happen,
and if you don't pay attention and it
all goes wrong,
you could wind up looking like that guy.
You could wind up thinking and behaving
like that guy.
It is a slow ebbing of the life force of
the body.
If it's gonna,
it's gonna Drain you so God dammit.
Get your fun out.
Get your life out.
Just live.
You got to live.
It's fucking coming and you got to
remember because if you don't remember,
you're going to sleep in.
If you don't remember,
you're not going to get anything done.
you're not gonna.
You're not gonna.
Have the same focus and determination
that you would have with the
understanding that this is a temporary
experience.
Yeah.
Let's see.
It's interesting.
You'll be able to alert,
you are able to learn that,
you know,
like not saying that that moment kind of
helped culminate.
Yeah.
But it helped definitely helped some
people.
It's just hard to learn.
Why is it so hard?
Sometimes for us hard.
I mean,
even when I got out of there,
I probably forgot it when I got my own
apartment and started living normal.
Probably like let it slip for a little
bit,
you know?
I mean I definitely went through some
moments in my own life where I lost my
motivation and my point of view or got
lazy or lost my perspective,
but I've figured out the consequences of
that and I always bounced it back as
best as I could,
but I just remember those few months
that I lived with my grandfather being
real important.
Real important too,
because he lived in a neighborhood that
was real bad man.
It was,
it was north ninth street in Newark,
New Jersey.
Sounds horrible,
dude.
Honestly,
I've never even been there.
It was great at one time when he was,
uh,
you know,
when it was all families that had all
moved to this neighborhood,
thugs.
Well,
what had happened was they did this
thing called blockbusting.
They come around and say,
Hey,
black people are moving into your
neighborhood,
you got to sell now.
And everybody sold,
my grandfather didn't like black people
to fuck off my lawn,
like one of those things because real
estate agents,
they would do that and just turn these
neighborhoods over and just make
profits.
And so,
uh,
and then it changed.
Went from a black neighborhood to a
Puerto Rican neighborhood and now it's
like a bunch of different kinds of
immigrants and you know,
they're all,
it's all kind of the same cycle.
They're all trying to come to America.
They're trying to establish themselves
and that's the place where they get
going.
So there was a lot of crime.
It was,
it was kinda dangerous.
The next door neighbor was selling crack
and they battering rammed his door.
I was like,
oh,
I think something happened while I was
there,
but the big raid was before I got there
because I got there.
This guy had like barriers in front of
his house gates and he had an Audi in
the driveway.
It was selling crack.
Yes,
right next door.
It is funny.
There's always that one house and like
the crappy neighborhood that has all the
like it's like,
uh,
like obviously it stands out.
Something's going on the statues of
lions out front and stuff.
Yeah,
man.
Yeah.
But I think having a dad like that
must've given you a different sense of
the cycle of life,
you know,
instead of having a young vital dad,
you're like,
my dad so healthy and he's my hero.
You grew up going,
holy shit.
My Dad was not much time left,
man.
Yeah,
he,
I think it just made me scared.
It just,
it just made me,
it.
First of all,
it made my sense of humor really dark
because I remember like my mom would ask
us if my dad was still alive or not,
you know,
and make us check on him like,
around dinner before I remember,
I remember having,
like,
I remember my brother would sometimes
hold like a mirror under his nose as he
would fog up,
you know,
to see if we would,
if my mom would,
um,
and then we just tell mom,
yeah,
he's fine,
you know,
so,
and my mom wasn't very caring.
She was,
she's a good woman,
she's a hard working woman.
She delivered newspapers,
you know,
her whole life,
but she just,
I don't know,
maybe she was angry that she felt fallen
for this older man.
I don't know.
Anyway,
It was weird,
man.
It was,
I don't know,
I,
I didn't develop much of a relationship
for them with them.
Sometimes I just develop moments that I
remember that I kind of pieced together
that create the relationship that I felt
like we had.
I guess,
you know,
I like treasurer about 10 or 15 moments.
Um,
and then in hindsight he let me drive
when I was young,
you know,
he kind of took advantage of me a little
bit like you would drive them to
colleges when I entered to due to credit
card stuff when I was 12 and 13,
you know,
tall enough to drive.
So I'm driving 70 on the interstate man
and shit dude.
Yeah.
And he didn't.
And in hindsight it,
it made me think that everything was
okay.
Like uh,
you know,
life doesn't,
whatever,
you know,
somebody,
you know like who care,
you know,
whatever.
Everything's fine,
you know,
like it doesn't matter what,
like everything.
Kids can do adult stuff,
adults can do kid stuff,
you know,
there's no real lines in the sand there.
Wow.
So there wasn't like a moment where you
felt like finally you were grown up,
like you just doing the same shit you
always did.
Yeah.
So you started driving at 12?
Yeah,
I remember driving my dad to come to
these colleges and he was 82 at the
time.
He was 82.
I remember one time dropping them at the
post office did.
And he said there's nowhere to park,
just go around the block,
you know.
So I went around the block and he had
like a delta 88.
He bought it off.
Oh my God,
of brothers and his April had speakers
in the back and one of them had broken
out and had a bunch of Chinese food and
Chinese food or some type of to go items
in there.
And um,
and fucking the speakers are always
speak up.
And I just remember I hit him.
I probably hit three or four cars is
going around the block to get back to my
dad because it didn't have power.
Power steering you that should have had
power steering.
I don't think I'm willing to me at 88
oldsmobile.
Yeah.
To me it was big man.
It felt like a,
you felt cool,
you know,
but,
and the car was such a piece of shit
man.
And so he couldn't even tell if it had
been hit a bunch of Shit,
you know,
he was always hitting shit.
And here was it again,
I don't know man.
Delta 88.
I would feel like those are so big.
They would have to have power steering,
but I don't know,
man.
What a risk cracker that must've been.
If it wasn't champagne colored,
I remember that.
Those are boats,
man.
Yeah.
It felt big.
It felt good and bad thing.
Look at it.
Oh yeah.
He wasn't like that.
Yeah,
Dude.
It was like,
no,
it was probably a year or two.
It seems newer than that.
A year or two newer than that one.
Yeah.
Those were,
those were like American boats.
Look at that motherfucker.
What year is that?
That thing's awesome.
That's an two.
Is that an ltd?
Seventy one.
Nineteen 71 thing that is just
Americana.
Oh yeah.
Open up that hood.
It's just a controlled explosion.
And cayston steal.
Did.
I remember one time my dad took me to
get donuts when I was young and uh,
they had crows in Louisiana,
these big crows and they busted out the
windows in his car and I would,
uh,
crows did this huge crow.
Yeah,
like a huge,
broke the window.
Broke the windows in his car.
They broke,
break it.
I guess maybe with his beak.
Come on.
Yeah,
they can do that.
I mean,
they did this day,
you know,
and uh,
you should have somebody else didn't
break the window and the crows were
inside.
Well,
I
remember,
I just remember trying to tell them it
was a black bird.
I was like four years old and he thought
it was a black man because he couldn't
turn his neck.
So he was like yelling all these racial
slurs.
Yeah.
And we're just going to get some towels.
Oh No.
So there's just always things like that
that were just weird.
Yeah.
He couldn't turn his neck.
Like that's one of the things I remember
most about him.
You know,
I remember you had change in his pockets
a lot.
He liked to whistle.
He slept on the couch,
you know,
some parents kiss one time my dad kissed
my mother on the head one time at one of
our birthdays.
That's it.
Uh,
yeah,
just one time.
Wow.
And I don't know,
I feel like when we started to grow up,
my mother became a little bit
embarrassed maybe almost to us that our
dad was at age.
What makes sense?
I mean if she was like 40 and he was 80.
Yeah.
You know,
she's 46 when he died of old age
essentially.
Right.
You might have a disease or cancer or
something like that,
but when you,
once you hit around 86,
it's kind of like that's the age where
everybody starts to go over,
man.
Yeah,
I guess that was some of it.
Yeah.
Not to be a debbie downer.
Nothing.
No.
You're not a Debbie Downer and just
being honest and talking about your
life.
It's pretty fascinating man.
I mean,
you know,
I've,
I've kind of talked about this quite a
bit,
that there's a,
we all have these ideas of like what
your life is supposed to be like.
I think a lot of them are based on
movies were based on like a movie
version of life.
You Go,
well that's how it happened in the
movie.
That's how it's supposed to go down in
my life.
And why isn't it happening in my life
the way it happens in the movie,
but then when you talk to people like
you or you know,
my child was different.
Jamie's childhood was different.
Like I know a lot of people that are
like really weird childhoods.
Joey Diaz,
his childhood is the craziest story
ever.
Julie Diaz,
his last spring,
it seems insane to me.
Shall we found his mom dad while he was
on acid?
Oh yeah.
I mean his childhood,
his car.
You got adopted by his friends family
and they took him in and you know,
it's his car,
his childhood.
It's crazy.
And he's one of the most incredible
people I've ever met.
I love that guy.
Always hard to his heart to go in the
Smithsonian and when they're done when.
No,
no.
There's a lot of people like that,
man.
There's a lot of people that have come
from like,
all my best friends have come from some
fucked up.
Crazy childhood.
Yeah.
We're all experiencing that.
But the,
the thing that's unique to me is that
all these people with these fucked up
crazy childhoods.
Those are the diamonds in this world.
Yeah.
You know,
like those are like you ever talked to
Whitney Cummings?
Not.
I listen to a little bit of her on your
podcast the other day.
The smartest people I've ever met.
Wow.
She's so fucking smart and she's almost
too smart.
Like she's like psychoanalyzing yourself
24 slash seven and talking about her
childhood and experiencing life through
try and experiencing through her words
what she had to go through and why she
became who she is now.
It's like you don't make a person like
that.
Like they don't come out normal.
Like if you don't come out that way,
if they had a normal childhood.
I just don't know.
The only way you make a Joey Diaz
because you got to experience with Joey
Diaz is experienced.
Yeah.
Like regular life people.
They're just not.
You're not going to ever get one of
those people out of that regular life.
You're not going to make a thiel Vaughn
at have some regular life.
Yeah.
You know what I mean?
It's,
it's interesting thing because most of
my life or my youth especially,
I pined for that regular or this idea of
what it was,
you know,
or something we saw on television or
little house on the prairie with the
thing I really attached myself to,
you know,
I've always been a huge Michael and,
and fan as an adult.
Either a big fan of the man from Atlanta
and seeing that.
Remember that?
Yeah.
Michael Landon.
He used to be,
I think it was sam.
What was it?
Patrick Duffy might be Patrick Duffy.
There was a,
uh,
a show called the man from Atlantis was
Patrick Duffy who was in what show was
he in?
He was in one of those step by step.
No,
no,
there was one before that.
There was a big time show that he was in
before.
It was like a superstar before he did
the man for the last.
It's silly.
It's terrible.
Breathe under water and shit.
But it was,
it was like on TV when I was a little
kid.
You know,
this God,
I loved it.
I was,
I was a little kid.
I was stupid.
What year was that on 77.
[inaudible] 78.
10.
I was 10 years old and he was swimming
in the water and breathing under water.
Like a fish.
Like he would keep his legs together
when he would swim.
He had this weird way of swimming
underwater.
Yeah,
and I used to swim in a pool.
I still try to swim Atlantis.
It's actually like an effective way to
swim.
It's not like he would swim like,
like a,
like a dolphin.
Like he would get in the water.
What is that?
Is that him?
Is that him from way back then?
Yeah,
it is.
That's from the show look.
Wow.
Yeah.
That was always in very good shape and
they would have him swim against the
Dolphin and he was faster than it off.
Look how stupid that is.
Homeland was a.
This show is so stupid.
He's faster than a dolphin.
I think I saw that real contest like
this in Arkansas.
One,
he's going to shoot it out of the water
and grabbed the fish with the dolphin.
Can't get to it.
This was crazy.
Look,
flies up in the air 30 feet out of the
water and then he gave the fish to the
dolphin because he's even better than
the dolphin.
I feel like that show would make it
today.
Oh yeah.
They should do it today with the exact
same scenes and the exact stage put on
comedy central will be fucking
hilarious.
Same cast.
But he would.
That wasn't a race,
but there was other times when you see
him swim underwater and gyrate his body
like a dolphin would.
Yeah.
Weirdest.
Fuck man.
Yeah man.
I never wanted to be a fisherman my
whole life.
I did.
That didn't,
man.
I've never thought about that.
Yup.
I've never woke up a day of my life.
Said,
man,
I wish I was fish.
Or how about,
how about this?
How about a fucking platypus.
I mean,
what is the,
what is this Jamie?
Is that a double headed sea horse that's
as tall as a person.
Wow.
This seems real.
Look at it.
He's trying to.
He's trying to bite them.
The sea horses biting him and at the
same time he's trying to get himself
free.
He's rubbing this.
Uh,
yeah.
I always do.
Is moving his head,
his rubbing,
his rubs against the stick on the muscle
free and he falls to the ground.
Is he naked?
Was he naked?
What is.
Hold on.
Why is he rolling?
Oh.
Oh my God.
He moves like a dolphin on earth and
then he gets the water is free.
Why is he naked?
He's naked,
right?
Yes.
Oh,
this looks like a.
Oh my God.
This is worse than the Captain Kirk.
A fight with the alien scene.
Remember that terrible one with the
aliens.
Got The crazy eyes and he kills it with
a rock.
It's just like a scavenger.
Looks like a tender dating key West
actually is what?
This looks so bad man.
From Atlantis.
A scavenger hunt is what it says on the,
um,
on the youtube video.
If you want to go watch it,
that's worth checking out actually after
Dick off.
That is worse.
That's absolutely worse than the Star
Wars.
Fight with Captain Kirk in that alien
guy.
Yeah.
I never seen that number.
I never got into star wars.
Hold that shit up.
Star Trek.
Star Wars.
Did I?
Yeah,
I get them confused.
I think if I was star track,
I'd be pissed that star wars came around
pitch.
We already used star Star.
How'd they come up with something else?
So what about the fact that it.
They got both huge series off of both of
them.
Was the Canadian.
How about it's not star Trek Bitch at
space trek?
Is it really?
Yeah.
It's not star wars either.
So here's Captain Kirk first.
Is this a green alien dude that moves
and super slow Mo.
Like,
look at him.
He's Like,
whoa.
Here comes the left.
The car hits him with some terrible
punch to the body here comes to right.
A terrible karate chop.
This is so stupid.
Look at him.
He's got crazy eyes.
He's reaching for him.
It didn't happening.
Cool.
Throws a kick.
Oh good move.
Shitty ass kicked.
But the green monster obviously knows a
little bit of moitai because you just
got him on a single leg dump.
Didn't even trip,
didn't bother the trip.
Just severe strength.
Just thrown through the air.
But meanwHile this is how inconsistent
they are right now.
They're battling no problem.
Like the,
the green monster is not overpower them.
He's trying to bite them wearing a
dress,
or is that a uh,
probably something's going on.
Meanwhile,
meanwhile he's having a hard time
battling it out with shafting.
Oh,
snack.
They're double fucking palms into the
ears.
the double pump to the ears is always a
good move.
When you're fighting monsters calling
this man,
check this shit out.
This is where it gets really stupid.
He picks up this fake rock,
obviously fake rock.
Look at him.
He pretends he's trained in way.
Gets it by you.
I'm gonna hit you with this fake rock
and it's gonna fucking kill you.
And look at this beautiful man.
He was back then.
Look how he throws it.
Bomb look as stupid as it bounces off
him.
So how come he can hit him with the
fucking double pump to the head?
And it's like the most devastating blow
ever.
But that rock,
nothing you.
They're so inconsistent with his ability
to generate force.
The religion jones' a little bit.
How dare you say you think she's had
enough?
He'll get it.
He's going to pick up a fake rock now.
Oh you motherfucker.
I'll show you.
And he's like,
you throw a rock at me,
motherfucker.
I'm going to throw a fake rock at you.
And kirk's like,
I'm out of here bitch.
And see runs out of the way.
Oh,
just just shy away from that rock.
You can't hit me with that.
And so now what happens?
Nothing just get stupider and stupider.
Like why don't I just keep running.
This thing is so slow.
Why he duking it out with it.
It will never catch you.
Like you would literally never catch
you.
And you could run for a couple hours and
then take a nap.
And this stupid fucking green man will
be coming over the top of that hill.
He'd hear his footsteps.
He probably makes a lot of noise when he
walks and he would wake up and then just
runs more.
I never fought nothing like that.
You know whAt I'm saying though?
I follow you dog.
One time this guy fight in me when I was
young,
he fighted you.
Well,
you know what I'm saying?
I did past tense.
He,
um,
he,
they made us hug in the hallway.
That was the big thing at our and it was
over at our school.
We had to stand there all,
all afternoon for literally probably
maybe two,
three hours with your arms on each
other's shoulders after you fought.
Yep.
To make it up with each other.
and he became one of my best friends
after that.
Oh,
just make out his brother went to prison
though for a bit.
Same thing.
Yeah,
that's true.
So his brother,
I guess made out on our behalf.
So you guys fought over,
what?
Do you remember what it was about?
I remember,
man,
I was probably talking smack,
you know,
just being a young,
loud mouth.
And sometimes you call it your desserts
whenever you ran your mouth.
Sure.
Every now and then,
um,
I remember that though.
And I remember another man who I met,
a man who was a boxer.
I know you're big into boxing and ufc
fighting.
And um,
I met a man who was a boxer who looked
like don flamenco.
Do you remember that guy down the video
game guy?
He looked just like my friend.
Yeah.
He popped that jab yet my friend
william,
just like him.
WhaT's that noise?
What was that?
How was the noise go?
It was more like a pool,
wasn't noise.
When he hit you look at him.
He looked like adam sandler with the
prosthetic nose.
Yeah,
that's what my buddy looked like a
little bit.
There's a homosexuaL gentleman in
italian.
Yeah.
Remember he had the rose in his mouth
come out and you'd be even more
humiliating when he kicked her ass.
And my buddy and I used to get high
together that gentlemen and we used to
actually do steroids together back in
the day on the side of the interstate
and we would,
uh,
and we were both busboys.
Well,
He was a bus man because he was an
adult,
but we would do bussing tables at the,
at this steakhouse that had opened up.
And I remember we got really stoned one
night,
went over to his place and a princess
diana died.
Princess diana was,
you know.
And um,
you really didn't know who she was when
she died.
No idea.
How old were you?
Think 16,
probably.
Wow.
You didn't know princess diana was.
That's interesting.
I mean,
I remember at one point they had a
beanie baby about it.
That's the most that I remembered.
Yeah.
She had her own beanie baby,
I guess.
Oh,
princess
diana thing was strange man.
Yeah.
Well,
especially if you didn't know who she
was and like I remember my buddy's mom
crying and like people were just
devastated I guess a lot of like
southern kind of women.
Were you?
She was an idol to a lot of those women.
She was like elvis presley kind of.
Well,
it was crazy that she got killed in a
high speed chase with the papa razzi was
chasing her.
yeah.
Think about that.
It's crazy.
Like if tHat happened here,
we'd probably be stoked about.
Depending on who it was,
who they get.
He get some of these retired nascar
driver,
they would give them a camera.
Do you remember when tony stewart a
camera,
he'll kill somebody.
Did halle berry got into a car accident
and ran away?
Just ran off the car and said,
fuck this,
and figured out what my attorneys she
took over.
I remember because radio stations used
to,
oh tom lucas used to play a huge have
callers.
They would call In and so let me go,
tom,
take me out with a bong hit and he'd
play like bong sounds like someone doing
a bong hit and he would take me out like
halle berry and you would hear like
cartoon footsteps,
you know,
like when,
in cartoons when someone's taken off a
that sounds like a xylophone with little
slaps on the ground.
Like that's crazy.
But what would you do you think if you
got an a in an instance like that where
she messed up,
you think as well?
She did it.
She was under the open.
Yeah,
she Could have been.
Who knows?
Did you ever get caught up in any of
that?
Jealousy and drugs and stuff?
This was chris brown's lamborghini was
found a couple of weeks ago,
but it was flooding.
IT was his friend that drove it and just
disappeared.
That's,
I know it was his because it was like
what a registered to him.
He wasn't driving.
He wasn't in town.
He did apparently let's like seven or 10
of his friends drive has a fleet of oh
really expensive cars revoke privileges
after this happened,
but total that's I got fucked.
Which,
which kind Of lamborghini is a really
expensive one.
Yeah,
you have.
Do you have a.
You have a pretty nice cars,
man.
I've seen some of your cards at the
comedy club.
Yeah,
mine are older though.
I don't have any.
I don't adore.
Oh shit.
That's like a 300 plus thousand dollar
car.
Lamborghini,
aventador.
I want to Say that's $400,000.
Find out how much that fucking thing
cost.
So the same there should say right.
There he is.
Why do these rappers?
I mean they just always.
Ah,
why did they end up in so much strife?
Do you feel like a lot of them remember
what we were talking about earlier about
us?
Same thing with them.
You don't make them,
you don't make like a,
a,
a big time wrapper or a funny comedian
or you know,
or a great fight or any of these weird
profession.
So you don't really make those things if
you don't have some sort of pressure
growing up.
How much does that Bitch?
300.
Ninety 9,000.
$500.
god damn it says from.
That's like that's a stripped down
version.
Unless you call,
you talk them down a little bit though.
That three 99,
399,000.
You can't talk them down.
You can't know.
He's got nice wheels on it too.
Those are those look like an aftermarket
wheels.
Those are dope too.
Crazy car.
That's it.
That isn't insane.
Car for a human being to be able to
drive.
You can just go and buy one of those
things.
Is it scary driving a car that it costs
a lot of money?
Is it like nerve wracking?
A little bit for sure.
Yeah.
But it depends.
It all depends on how much money you
have.
Right.
You know,
like for chris brown driving that car,
he's probably could afford 30 or 40 of
them.
Right.
You know.
So for him it's probably not that scary.
Right.
And plus there's something about that
world,
the rapper world,
but he's not really a rapper,
right?
Would you call him a rapper?
He's like a singer.
He could've been like michael,
janet painter.
He could have been,
just call him an entertainer.
There's something in that world where
it's very valuable to be flossy.
It's very valuable to have like floyd
Mayweather type watches and gold chains.
And like if you're a singer or a rapper,
you know,
like you represent a guy who's made it,
like chris brown represents the guy who
pulls up in a ferrari.
Like,
oh,
of course he's in a ferrari.
He's chris brown,
he's canadian.
He's a famous entertainer dude.
So for guys like that,
you can't be pulling up at some fucking
toyota land cruiser,
you know,
camera cameras at worst.
I do it on a nice accord.
The court is a very nice.
Now is this fleet of cars?
Forty $5 million.
He's got $45,
million dollars worth of cars.
That's what they said.
Oh my god.
How that could not be realistic.
Oh,
you think it's not.
But he plays arenas.
Man.
If this dude's that's his house,
that was another guy.
Is that his house down there?
That one that you did get your brothers
right there.
You got gotta,
rick ross.
Your brother filters a little stronger,
but rick ross is a serious fucking
cadillac.
That's a dope cadillac.
Whose is this?
This says it says,
but I was trying to find them.
Look at the house though.
jesus christ was nice.
Man.
I could get a nice restaurant.
You feel so peaceful,
but it's just the maintaining of that
lifestyle is what breaks a lot of those
guys.
Yeah,
because you might make $45,
million dollars.
You really might make that like,
wow,
that guy made $45,000,000,
but you're going to make $45,000,000
every three years because if not,
you're going to burn through it in three
years.
like the way you're living.
As soon as you stop making money.
Oh,
you want?
You want to take time off and you want
to write some new material.
Oh,
you do?
that's weird.
Because you've got bill's mother fucker.
You're chewing through money left and
right and you just see some new crazy
diamond studded watch the jewelry shop
and you're like gotta have it gotta have
it.
It's a million Dollars.
Got to have it.
Boom.
You throw a million dollars.
It's a good investment.
You got a billion dollar watch on what?
In the fuck?
Yeah.
I mean I lost $2,000 in a pyramid scheme
when I was younger because I grew up in
an area where there's a lot of pyramid
schemes coming through.
How they get ya.
Um,
they just asked me for $2,000,
pretty much dead and I gave it to him.
And what did they say?
Did they say,
well,
they showed you this specialized sheet
of paper.
That's what they really called it.
Even specialized chart,
which in hindsight is the most,
I mean it's the lamest name for like a
pyramid scheme,
a specialized chart,
you know?
And then they had these different blocks
in the bottom row is green and then
yellow and then red,
blue and then red.
And each time you put 2000 and you got
somebody else to put your money in and
then you sold your and you kept moving
up and it literally was a pyramid and
you'd heard like the term pyramid scheme
and was still fell for it,
man.
So in hindsight,
I still miss that money a lot of times.
I had an old boxing coach tried to hit
me up.
One of those really?
Yup.
When I first moved to la,
I was working out at this place in north
hollywood and I was uh,
taking boxing lessons from this dude.
And uh,
one day he came up with,
this is the clunkiest shittiest pyramid
scheme pitch ever because he wasn't like
a good talker in the first place,
you know?
And he thought,
oh,
here's this guy.
I was on a sitcom.
Nobody was watching.
Nobody knew who I was back then.
It wasn't like he targeted me.
I was Just a dude with the gym that he
thought it was an actor might have some
money.
Right.
You know,
and he's like,
I'm telling you,
I bought these rims on my truck.
I got them from that,
like,
oh yeah,
how's it work?
He goes,
well,
you put in money and then after awhile
you know you could take some of the
money out and you can get a lot of money
that way.
I was like,
what is this a pyramid scheme?
He just looked at me,
his eyes glazed over.
I go,
no,
it was levels.
He's like,
you put on this go.
It's a pyramid scheme and we just stand
there in the parking lot looking at each
other and I go,
I gotta go,
and so I leave and then I never wear
worked out at that gym again.
I was like,
well,
I'm done.
I can't come here anymore and Just
fucking guy's trying to get my money.
Plus he's a big dude.
So it was kind of dangerous,
dangerous to say no dude.
I used to work out with David Duke when
I was growing up.
Holy shit.
We shared the back fence when I was
growing up.
Holy shit.
We used to go to.
I mean,
that's kind of,
I don't know if you consider the klu
klux klan a pyramid scheme or not,
but um,
and he dated.
I,
I've worked at the seafood restaurant.
I was a Bus boy over there and he dated
the prettiest girl that worked at the
seafood restaurant.
Was this when he was in the kkk?
No,
this was after his nonpracticing
honestly seemed like a nice guy to.
How many years ago was.
This was 1995.
So that was when he was in the public
guy.
He was like a big deal back then,
right?
Wasn't that one,
was it later than that?
That he was like running for public
office?
Let me think.
It was when I was younger.
He was running against edwin edwards,
I believe,
for public office.
That was probably around 1990 or 88.
I feel like he did some stuff after that
though on a national level.
It wasn't on a state level.
What is he running for?
Governor or something like that.
He ran for governor a couple times.
yeah,
him and I remember the signs because
that wouldn't.
Edwards was a crook allegedly.
And uh,
David Duke was a racist and that's what
that one of the campaign poster said,
don't vote for the racist vote for the
crook.
That was the campaign.
She's everywhere.
She's crying.
And a crook one,
that man,
one that's quite.
We used to go to,
and I'll tell you this man,
he was,
you know,
I'm not a believer,
this is practices,
but he was a.
He was elected to Louisiana house of
representatives in 1989.
And that year the sitting representative
resigned his seat to become a judge.
And duke ran in the special election to
fill a seat.
Daily beast describes the race in
writing the off year,
special election in which David Duke
through himself,
little media notice at first out through
him.
So through himself,
a little media newness notice,
notice at first,
who turned himself to as a what a taught
himself as a pro life.
Fiscal conservative was known as an x
clan member.
He issued overtly racist language and
instead pointed to crime in the city
criticizing affirmative action and
minority set asides.
Jada's did chest and tris with them.
So I wouLdn't in all that,
you know,
we just did basic workout.
Did he quit like a bitch when the reps
got hired?
He was a,
he was,
he was an animal.
He was,
he was strong.
he's a strong man,
a probably a lot of people after him to
kill him.
Probably got to be on your p's and q's
possibly.
And he gave me direction.
He just gave me direction in elliot
didn't.
Yeah,
like how to do it right.
He didn't compensate a ton,
but he would.
Yeah.
this is how you do it.
This is how you do it,
you know?
Uh.
Did you ever ask him about the clan?
I didn't ask him about that date.
I wanted to try and meet as lady did.
I was trying to mill around and see if I
can smell a payer.
Her pencil loans,
you fail me to it when you were a little
kid.
I mean at that time I was 15.
I what was the correct bra?
I've never been more direct and I wasn't
back ever.
I tHink that's what began your whole
idea that pussies changed,
or maybe she was so good to like regular
girls.
Oh,
I can't possibly do that.
So I think sober sex,
I have sober sex is for children.
I've always thought that.
And I think that um,
the more you get adult,
it just,
it just wears down and a lot of this,
a lot of this puts it comes with a lot
of extra just chat or inside items these
days.
It's just a lot.
Is that David Duke and his girlfriend at
the time,
that's not the one,
but she looks,
she looks like she's like north Florida.
She's kind of north Florida in about a
woman when a woman has an american flag
bikini on that just takes it to the next
level.
Hell yeah,
dude.
Just down.
Yeah.
She's down for you.
That's not her either,
but the interesting.
I tell him,
yeah,
the 90 to vote an interactive timeline.
Look at that.
But he is,
he's a big man.
Look at the got wide shoulders and said,
man,
you gotta lift weights if everybody
wants to kick your ass because you're a
racist.
Yeah,
we got to be ready at all times.
You know,
you pull into the wrong fucking
convenience store at 2:00 in the
morning.
You might get the fuck beat out of you.
That's true dude.
That dude is that dude.
I saw you on tv,
man.
You that x kkk dude.
Like what?
Why?
What are you saying?
picking up stuff in the laundromat and
he started to get a 40 ounce cause
that's crazy,
man.
I probably got to be real careful where
you go if you're a guy like that.
Yeah man.
I guess dude,
racism was pretty popular.
I feel like we're always from,
you know.
Was it popular when you were growing up?
Um,
boston was definitely more racist than
san francisco,
but Florida was more racist in boston
for sure.
Yeah,
I saw I had way more racist shit in
Florida.
I think that I did way more than san
francisco.
I remember I had,
I convinced my mother that I did not
know what the word nigger meant.
I didn't know what it meant.
And she was mad at me.
She's like,
you know what it means?
I go,
no,
I don't tell me what it means.
She had to tell me what it means.
I couldn't believe it.
I was like,
what?
Because someone had said it at school.
It was like,
what?
I was trying to pretend that I knew what
the kid was talking about and then I got
home and asked my mom.
Yeah.
She also got Mad at me when I asked her
out how people had made babies.
She didn't think I knew.
She thought I knew it.
He knew all this.
She goes,
she goes,
I'm going to tell you,
and you just gotta laugh.
I go,
no,
I'm not.
And then she tells me.
She's like,
I was seven.
I'll never forget this.
I was in the car with my sister and she
goes,
man puts his penis in a woman's vagina.
I'm like,
fuck.
It fell to the floor back then.
We didn't even wear seat belts,
you know?
I just fell right down onto the floor.
I was slapping the fucking floor of a
1971 barracuda.
I thought it was the funniest shit ever.
A man.
Wait a minute,
wait a minute.
Wait.
You make people buy a man and she's
like,
I knew it,
I knew you were going to laugh.
Like,
what the fuck's wrong with lab?
do you think there will be a more
creative way?
Kind of a little bit,
you know,
like maybe you have to like hide some,
like,
like hide it in their ears or something.
like you got to sneak semen into
somebody or when they're not looking or
just something a little bit more.
I don't know what was a fucked up way to
be introduced to it because I didn't
know.
And I asked her and she said,
you're gonna laugh,
you're gonna laugh.
And then I'm like,
is it funny?
Like now you gotta tell me because I'm
like,
now I got to hear it.
I'm like,
no,
I'm not gonna.
And then when she tells me that I left
and it kinda pisses me off now thinking
about it.
I was Only seven.
Fuck,
was I supposed to know?
Yeah,
you weren't supposed to know it.
That how the fuck was she?
But she was like,
don't you already know?
She just assumed I knew everything to
like.
My mom wasn'T big on lessons.
She was like,
you know,
I'm like,
I don't know.
Tell me dude.
I remember.
I can't really tell a seven year old.
I know.
I know some 11 year olds.
I wouldn't even tell them that.
How you make a baby.
I want her to know,
but I think a seven year old in 1974 was
just way different than a seven year old
in 2016 or 17.
Seven year olds back then were little
animals.
They're little fucking savage monkey
people were like monkey people.
We didn't have any internet.
There's three channels on television.
You had to get up to change with your
hand.
One of your friends was missing.
People just disappeared.
They would go to the woods and it never
find them again.
You left the house.
There's.
There was a fucking answer.
Machines it tells in high school,
nobody even knew where anybody was.
No one had a portable phone until well
into my adult years.
Yeah,
like he came back in the stuff from
summer for school and just hope
everybody was still alive.
He couldn't find,
you have to go to your friend's house.
You'd knock on their door.
Hey ms dot wilson's mike home and they
let you in like,
hey,
what's up dude?
Like you had to find that shoe.
I know you let's go hang out.
You know,
I have to drive to each other and he'd
have to make some very specific
instructions.
So come over my house around 6:00,
the warm out in front and I'll know and
I'll come out.
Okay.
And then you pull up mom,
you got to go.
I remember that shit.
That was awesome.
Did I,
I just,
I,
I just miss the old days when the only
way to communicate you like it'd be in
front of people.
Just good information like information
you got through rumor and basically
mystics or hope you know.
The other thing,
the communication we had was all looking
at each other or at the very least
hearing each other's voice on the phone
and very little shit was the only girl
broke up with you over the phone.
Oh,
that's cold blooded.
She didn't look at,
you knoW,
do.
She called me up,
said it's over,
motherfucker,
but she had to make contact with you.
At least you couldn't text you.
It's over bitch.
Yeah,
I'm fucking your friend right now.
Back then you had to actually make
contact.
This is just not working out.
I need my space.
No,
you had to hear it.
You couldn't just look at it on text and
then you had to hang up in your house
and some of your house and be like,
who was it?
And then you had to expound to them when
it just occurred.
Dude.
and people will think it's hilarious.
She broke your heart pussy dude.
I remember this.
Uh,
we will after this dance one time.
First time a buddy of mine ever hooked
up with a girl,
um,
he touched her genital you after this
dance,
you know,
we'd had a dance at the school and he'd
been touching her genitalia out in the
woods actually.
And he was our first one of our buddies
to do that,
you know,
so she ends up leaving and we're all
hanging out around the,
uh,
my buddy's house from this fire.
and we're like.
And we kept like doing different stuff,
like with our skin and our mouths and
that doesn't feel like,
oh god,
like kind of reenacted a pussy,
you know,
like trying to just basically be a
vagina for a minute.
And uh,
and then my buddy's father comes out,
right?
And he sees you guys making out,
know what it is.
Like what's going on.
We're trying to recreate pussy.
Whoa.
Okay.
I'll leave you guys alone for way too
long.
You got some fucked up ideas.
We're going To have to cleanse them.
it's just breaks out the fucking liquor.
The only thing I could do,
I had to,
I had to get.
I'm so drunk.
I forgot what happened.
But uh,
could you imagine dad goes to those?
Sit the fuck down.
Comes out with a jug of whiskey,
drink,
tastes shut the fuck up and want to be
fucked up for the rest of your life.
Or do you want to forget everything that
happened so far?
That's awesome man.
And he knows stuff,
but the dead ended up smelling my
buddy's hand,
right where the posts he came through.
And then,
and he knew,
oh well we told,
we told them what had happened.
We tell,
we tell them,
but that just shows you how bad our
sense of smell is.
You have to be that close to somebody
saying,
I know like a shark could smell your
pussy when you were in like ankle.
Deep in tHe water.
It's a mile away,
dum,
dum.
It's a medium rare and key biscayne is
not.
Some speculation about certain animal
attacks occur when women are
menstruating,
like the animals,
more likely to see.
Is that bullshit or is that like some
human human rumor?
You know,
some silly.
I believe that did.
I would have never been to Maine.
If somebody's bleeding in your pool,
you could attack them.
I wonder if you think about it like
that.
Like if somebody come to my house,
they're bleeding in my house and don't
even care about it.
But you get mad getting fucking attack.
You get attacked.
Yeah.
If it's in my carpet or something,
you're standing for girls is.
If you have one of those 19,
70 shag carpet,
all white.
Please take your shoes off at the door
and this girl comes in with some old
school gym shorts on and a really wonky
ass pad leaking like have like a god
damn deer got hit with a rage broadhead
and she's leaking all over.
She's leaking all over your shag carpet.
What do you do?
You attack her.
Do you help her out as a friend and just
wash your car?
Man,
you get the woman a towel.
You've got to hire an archer.
I think at that point did not.
If somebody is doing that in my house,
do they need to learn?
I wouldn't do that to you.
You don't do that to me.
You don't bleed like that.
That's going to be a huge drag.
If women just bled.
Yeah,
but if you are purposely just dripped
dropping her in my living room and you
know that I love this carpet and you
know that I probably can't afford new
carpet.
There was a,
there was this thing where these women
were letting their periods run down the
legs,
like in some sort of a protest.
I forget what the protest was about,
but I remember watching that going,
we have absolutely failed as a human
being if we're so in denial of the
biological process that it's somehow or
another a protest to let your menstrual
blood rolled down your legs somewhere.
There's been some serious errors in
communication.
If that's a statement,
if you were making a statement by
letting period,
like it's either a massive failure in
the sight of men to not communicate
that.
It's no big deaL.
It's just a natural cycle of life.
It's a part of life doesn't freak us
out.
It shouldn't freak you out.
Let's figure out how you can get
tampons.
Let's make sure you get take care of
just like the same way we make sure
people have toilet paper in the
bathroom,
right?
You don't just go shitting your pants
and the of protest,
right?
It's a.
It's a Hygiene issue,
like it shouldn't be a pro,
a good gender based protest.
Like how bad is our lines of
communication?
You have to get where women in any way
think that letting your pussy bleed down
your leg is reclaiming some sort of
power.
I don't think so.
I think it's.
I think it's tacky.
I do,
man.
I don't and I don't.
I honestly don't know a woman that will
do it or really want to know.
Well,
I don't want to even happens by
accident.
It's not.
It doesn't freak me out.
I don't get freaked out.
Freaked out by it.
Some people do though,
right?
Yeah.
I don't get freaked out by,
you know,
a period or somebody,
that kind of stuff.
I just don't know.
Yeah.
Gone wrong with the communication where
that becomes a protest.
Yeah.
Like I don't want to.
I don't want to.
I don't.
Maybe it's wrong of me to say.
I don't want to see that.
Maybe that's what the protest is about.
I get it.
I get it on both sides,
but it seems so unnecessary.
What was the reason they were doing
that?
Yeah,
it was really recently.
Well,
why aren't men protesting more about
anything,
do you think?
Have you noticed that there's not as
many tests.
We're trying to get sex,
tampon tax.
That's it.
Okay.
How long ago was this?
Pretty reasonably 15.
Oh hmm.
Yeah.
Well I'm thinking like more recent
events.
It's like a drip in events where women
protest by letting their menstrual blood
running down their legs,
school that place and prepare for some
inquiries from the fbi to see some
footage you probably don't want to say
and they're going to come to your house.
Yeah.
I never,
uh,
I remember protesting in college about
the soccer coach.
Had the girls' soccer team on Korea team
when I remember protesting about that.
You protested?
Yep.
Me and to my buddies and I even remember
this,
uh,
at the last minute,
the coaches are out there and meet the
local news is out there like
interviewing us.
We all have signs,
you know,
and,
and a handicap fell on mine.
He was in,
he was in,
he had that carl sagan disease or
whatever that is.
Who's that guy?
Who knows?
Even the stars.
Stephen hawking.
He showed up in that van,
you know,
with a loudspeaker on.
And he's like,
wait,
got rain forest.
And then the little ramp came down and
he came rolling out with a picket sign.
Wow.
And then he died.
He actually died.
He died,
um,
in the float a few years later.
That fella.
But yeah,
protest one time in the katrina flood.
It couldn't get his medication.
Whoa.
Fuck.
You don't think about those kinds of
things,
you know,
right.
Medication gets denied of people when
they die.
They become a casualty of the disaster.
Fuck man.
So why wAs he given the girls creatine?
What's dangerous about giving girls
creatures that come out?
And we just did it like people didn't
know about it.
It's like the member of the first time
creating hit the market.
Everybody was like,
you know,
it works,
you definitely work.
But it made you gain a little bit of
water.
Waterways get a little little chubby in
the face.
But what,
what does the,
uh,
negative ass is?
Was there a negative?
The coaches just take it and they didn't
know.
Oh.
So the coaches didn't even know.
They just wanted some sort of an edge
and hadn't been established whether it
was safe yet.
Yeah.
Oh,
I see.
And I was just kind of like,
we got antsy and got out there and
started protesting.
Yeah.
There's not a lot of protests going on
except.
But when there is a protest,
it's almost always liberal people that
are protesting these days,
it seems to be like protesting.
Like some speaker at some university
tHey'll,
you know,
have some speaker and they'll be
protesting them or you know,
it'll be like the women's march as being
as protest.
Yeah.
All these protests against trump left
wing marches.
People say that the tea party had some
massive protest,
but I can't find anything that shows
there's been any numbers that were
anything close to that women's march,
especially in la.
Something that said there was speculated
numbers that weren't proven upwards of
one to 2 million people.
One or two places.
Did they had any people back then
because I heard that crowd or go.
Yeah.
But the thing is Like when you,
when you're talking about that,
like you got to think of what's
confirmed confirmed numbers.
Like we have satellite images now that
are,
that are different than what they had
back then.
So like if you look at the,
uh,
like the footage that they were talking
about with the inauguration,
it's pretty clear when you look at the
full 24 hours sped up footage of how
many people were in the crowd versus how
many people in the crowd.
For a mama there was more people.
For oBama,
it's pretty clear.
It looks like a massive amount of people
when you look at it on the ground.
but overall,
and you look at the big picture from
above,
it's not as many people.
So knowing that they tried to conflate
those numbers,
they try to inflate those numbers and
make it seem like,
I mean with a lot of people were saying
it and they even said it on television.
that was the biggest crowd for
inauguration ever.
We didn't know.
Now we know now that's not true.
So maybe that was the same thing with
the tea party.
We really don't know.
It's tough to tell unless it happened
tomorrow.
Like if they had it tomorrow and you
could use the same modern methods of,
you know,
figuring out how many people in an area.
But they said that they think there was
970,000 people at the women's march,
just in los angeles.
Oh yeah.
I heard that'S the biggest thing that
ever happened.
And it was all over the country.
I mean they were in pretty much every
big city.
Right.
Didn't they have a bunch of them?
Yeah.
You think it was a lot of dudes who were
like hoping that like there was an
attack or something.
So they lose their wife or something,
you know?
I don't know about a lot of dudes,
but it probably at least one guy.
Oh,
there's more than one.
I bet.
Yeah.
it's 50 least 50 guys,
you know.
There was some dude who like hugs,
vice extra heart thinking that like
some,
you know,
militant islamic or non islamic group
was going to get them to be it,
I guess.
Anyway,
I never been involved in any terrorism.
I haven't been either.
Yeah.
The,
anything.
There was some stuff going around the
end of last year with mike pence and a
house bill about an abortion bill in
Indiana,
which is bringing up some more stuff
about the taxes on tampons all over the
country.
That's what it was.
And so these girls were letting their
menstrual cycles run down their legs
that the other satellite.
I just.
I'm okay with saying I don't like that.
It makes me feel uncomfortable and I can
feel that way.
I feel like I can't even say that
anymore.
Like I'm on the girls side.
Why the fuck are you raising taxes on
tampons?
Yeah,
but you want to make more money off
something that people have to buy.
that's fucked up.
Yeah,
that is fucked up.
It's fucked up because you have to buy
tampons and men don't have to buy it.
So if men decide make them pay for the
fucking tampons,
but here's a tax.
They're just,
they're just lazy and dumb.
Trying to figure out where to shove
taxes and don't make any sense like
tampons.
What or how,
but what else?
Net tAx vitamins you piece of shit.
What are you going to tax healthy food.
Fucking assholes.
Why would it like seeing just something,
a little craft here?
I feel like maybe take tampons,
put them on the end of a arrow,
firearm into the capital.
You know what I'm saying?
like something that really know what I'm
saying.
I know what you're saying,
but that's dangerous.
Yeah.
I guess I just wondered if you died
because you got hit with an arrow that
had a tampon in the end of it.
Right through your eyeball,
right into your brain.
You dead and it's sticking out of your
head like a planted tree.
But at least the blood flow stopped,
right?
At least you know what women go through.
I had this group online for a while
where you could put a tampon in your
butt to get know what women go through
hollow.
She had to put a tampon in your blood
for like three or four days to kind of,
uh,
um,
no they don't.
Unless they're doing it wrong.
Jesus christ,
they go through these to put in there.
But no,
they had this group online about six or
seven years ago where you put a tampon
in your buttocks to a experience.
So man can experience what it's like to
have at least something in his body all
the time like that.
Yeah,
it's fucked up.
Um,
but you know what man,
there's a big problem also with like the
shame of it.
It's weird that people have like so
ignorant.
Silly.
I agree.
This is the shame of period.
Like,
oh my god,
I have my period.
EveryBody run,
you know,
like,
well,
what do you think that started from now?
Do you think it's something that we
learned or something that for sure,
ignorance,
ignorance.
I'm like a puritan values.
This isn't making sense.
Like why would you be scared of periods
because we all beat up period,
didn't we?
And now what happens when you live?
That's right.
And we made it through and what not.
What do you think about the iud?
And they have things like that now in
women where they're stopped and their
periods.
Is That scary you think are not scare
birth control pills.
Do that cycle.
Um,
off and on to get their periods back.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
The birth control pills have positive
benefits though.
Like some women take birth control pills
for certain ailments.
You know,
that was one of the big things that was
an issue back when rush limbaugh got in
trouble for saying some girl's a slut
because she wanted birth control pills
to be paid for by insurance.
Remember that?
And people got real mad at him.
I mean it just sounds like something he
would say.
Yeah,
it was a big issue because I think some
women for their own health,
they actually need birth control pills
and not just for a sex women that don't
even have sex.
Like it regulates certain diseases and
issues that they might have.
So there's apparently more than one
reason to take that stuff.
I don't know.
Yeah,
I mean I think,
I mean I think they should,
you know,
they should be able to choose what they
need,
you know,
like which just crazy to tax it,
like the extra taxes and bonds,
finding some money some other way or
even just ask dude's ass.
People say,
hey,
you know,
women are having a tough time or we need
extra money.
Dudes are going to go,
fuck you think I throw a couple extra
dollars out there for a lady that needs
a couple,
you know,
good for you.
Yeah.
You goT a good heart.
I guess,
man,
I would do that day.
I believe you.
You know?
I mean it's definitely.
It's just,
it's a,
it's a necessity.
Yeah.
Like whether tampons or maxi pads,
it's some sort of a necessity.
We're just lucky we don't have that
issue.
But if that was an issue for men,
like if men bled out of our ball sack
for ball sack leaked once a month.
If that was the case,
how pissed would be if they started
making tampons and you got a tax
tampons,
you'll make more money off me in my
balls.
Bleeding.
Fuck you.
We will be so mad.
Oh,
we'd be fucking furious.
We wouldn't handle it.
Well dude,
if we had,
if we had that,
we would not handle it well.
Did I be scared?
I'll probably stay indoors.
I'd rather you get nervous a lot and we
would definitely want birth control to
be paid for by the government in a
heartbeat.
I'm on with that.
That's true,
man.
It's a great way to put it actually,
when you really put on yourself and see
what you would do,
you know?
Yeah.
That's why when you look at a guy like
mike pence who you know who's the vice
president of the United States
respectfully,
but if someone told you he was a dick
head,
you wouldn't be shocked Just by looking
at them.
It looks like every high school
assistant,
like football coach,
you know,
is that crazy?
Like who ended up in less than or like
dating a girl.
You know who those were from.
My high school was a spanish teacher.
Really cool guy.
We had a science teacher,
really cool guy that ever talked about
come buka a juice was this science
teacher of ours.
He's like,
it's going to be the future.
Yeah.
He goes,
it's going to be the future.
And were like,
you're nuts.
And then even though it was almost
married to a girl,
they busted him.
How old was she?
Oh,
I don't know man.
I'm.
SHe was probably 16 or something and I
used today.
I used to work for his brother,
actually the dude because he has wishing
well company buy us nice to work for
them.
I think wishing wells when were popular.
I think when I was in high school this
dude got away with it.
I think it was like one of them legal
deals,
like it was just legal,
legal,
but he was a cool guy.
yeah.
It was a fun guy and the 17 year old
girl and him hooked up and everybody
found out.
Well,
I mean,
could you see that happening though?
Say you're a teacher and you're 22 at a
high school.
It was only 25.
He was 25 and she was 17,
but he thought he was a 150,000 years
old when you're 17 and the teacher's 25.
Really?
That dude is anxious for a quarter
fucking century.
Yeah.
I mean he wasn't even.
he was eight years old and this girl and
he was banging her.
It was crazy.
Do you think that those laws are
accurate?
Those age?
A little age,
age limit loans for here's why.
Laws about consent get blurry.
Here's why.
Because when I was 18,
okay.
I turned 18.
I had a girlfriend and she was 17 and
when I turned 18 she turned 17 first.
No,
I turned 18 and she was 16 for like a
month and then she turned 17 and her,
I think it was her mother,
white girl,
white girl.
Her mother was worried that what we were
doing was illegal because she knew that
we were having sex.
I was lying to my mom.
I didn't tell him.
We're talking about mom.
She would come over my house and locked
the door and my bedroom.
What are you doing there?
Even tHen,
mom?
Nothing.
Well,
I remember when you told me how it
happens at seven going down,
but she caught knew,
you know,
and she just didn't,
you know.
Anyway,
um,
there was a real worry and I got scared
that I could get arrested.
Yeah.
I'm like,
all the sudden we're not.
We're like at first,
like wHen we first got together,
she was 16.
I was 17 and then all the sudden I'm 18
and for like a couple months who was
super illegal because it was two years.
Did it feel better because it was
illegal?
no,
scary.
Scary,
dangerous.
I was like,
wait a minute,
wait a minute.
So I could go to for having sex with my
girlfriend when I'm 18.
Like is that real?
Like a year?
Because one day your legal.
Like if she's 17 years in 364 days,
she's illegal.
The next day she's legal.
So you're telling me is some magic
thing.
Takes place over 24 hour period where
all of a sudden she's illegal.
That seems odd.
Especially if you're just 18 or 19 or
whatever it is.
It gets super weird if you're 70 right?
You know you,
you're super old and you're sitting
there outside of the school going one
more day waiting one motherfucking
rubbing your hands together.
We'll go to wendy's after I got candy
for you.
But you know,
it's just,
it just like a hard law like that as to
when consent occurs,
when it was,
when the age of consent,
whether it's 18 or 17,
and in some places it would be 16 and
some places you can marry people at 13.
It gOt real weird.
Do you believe that like a 16 year old
and a 30 year old could fall in love?
Do you believe that?
I don't not believe it.
Yeah.
Because weird people are fucking weird,
man.
People are weird and sometimes people
get together and it defies all odds,
but it works great.
Yeah.
Like there are people that have bizarre
relationships where they're,
they're separated by vast distances in
age.
Their personalities are different
actually,
whenever you go eight years.
Yeah.
I mean think about that.
I mean 38 years.
That means when your dad that just stop
and thInk about that for a second.
Your dad was 48.
Your mom was 10.
Yeah,
that's illegal.
That's crazy amount.
he's my age.
Your dad was my age.
And your mom was 10?
Yeah.
WhoA.
Yeah,
that's right.
Yeah.
I'll vote no on that.
Well,
in that,
in your situation to meet the ovando
yeah,
nobody got hurt,
but I think.
But I guess,
yeah,
I mean that's weird if you.
Do you feel like at that,
how would it look?
When was with 16 year old boy?
Here's where I would feel way less
weird.
It was a hot 30 year old woman and a 16
year old boy.
Sorry,
sorry.
Got to be honest.
I feel less weird.
I don't think it's ideal.
I don't think it's ideal for the kid,
but what if he's 18?
If he's 18 and she's 30?
Yes.
Yeah,
they had that famous case about that.
A couple of thinking about 20 years ago.
Remember that?
I'm 20 years or 15 years ago.
It was a couple.
It was a woman who was dating her
student.
Oh yeah.
And they ended up getting married.
I think they live in Hawaii.
One of the islands.
And she went to jail for a while,
right?
Yeah.
Baby.
Jessica on here.
Remember that person?
If it's a girl that fell in the.
Well,
yeah.
Did you ever come on your podcast?
Why don't you ask that?
Why would you think you fell on the well
one,
what's it like?
Mostly about math and sugar and then
sometimes cornflakes.
I just remembered her.
I saw this video the other day.
It's eight shows.
The video says it's an 80 year old man
meeting his 12 year old bride for the
first time,
second arranged marriage,
and that's the whole family's there at
the house while it's happening.
This
is real.
He's like meeting her and she looks like
she wants to die.
She looks super sad.
He's 80 years old,
so it says for the first time he has got
to be.
Yeah.
That's what it says is going on and what
is she reading something?
I don't even want to see that.
Yeah,
dude,
that's,
that's pronounced.
Marriages are terrifying.
Yeah.
That's got to stop.
I mean I have to stop.
I don't know.
I don't live there.
It's like going on from the beginning of
time because people have been oppressed,
but now it's the first time you can
broadcast to the whole world.
So they look at it through their
standards versus the standards of the
people that live in that area.
So you.
Do you think thAt's fair,
that safe idea or no?
No,
it's 100 percent.
Not care or safe and scary.
It's ancient.
Antiquated.
He comes from liKe these,
these cultures that have not caught up
to our own current perception of the,
of,
of civilization,
of life.
You know,
that you should let people do what the
fuck they want to do.
There's no way that kid wants to do
that.
Do you think at some point we start to
like,
like at what point is technology like
not good for us anymore?
This has been on my mind a lot recently.
Like it's just make me think about that.
like at what point is it that if we want
to survive as humans still like at what
point do we stop it or not stop it,
but what do we do?
Hmm.
I know because I feel like it's taken
over so quickly that we're not going to
be human.
We're behaving very.
I mean we'll still be human.
What are behaviors are going to be?
Nothing.
We're just going to be running little
systems were operators.
Yeah.
No,
I think what you're feeling and thinking
is what a lot of people feeling.
Think it's a pretty common subject.
A lot of people are talking about.
A lot of people have perceptions and
ideas and fears and projections of what
they think are going to happen and no
one really knows.
No one reAlly knows,
but for sure the way we live right now
is super alien to the way the people
that lived when your dad was born and
that's just,
you know,
a generation ago.
I mean really,
if you really look at what it really is
like your dad like one skip one go to
the birth,
your dad.
that's crazy.
I mean that.
That isn't an insane amount of
innovation and change.
Yeah,
and once we start becoming integrated
with the computers and then once they
become a part of your body,
that's when things are going to get so
fucking strange.
I mean they're gOing to happen.
There's a guy,
did we play it on here?
The guy who has the artificial legs that
are powered by neurochemicals,
I'm out doing that.
Did you play that after the podcast
showed you after the podcast,
put it on,
put it on for theo because this is the
craziest fucking thing ever,
man.
They figured out a way to make these
artificial legs that work like real
legs,
like for the longest time they've been
awkward and maybe strange and they got
better and they made some artificial
limbs for veterans that were were pretty
passable and they can even walk without
a limp if they pulled it off correctly,
but now now they've come up with
something that you're controlling with
your mind and it's like a machine and
they have their essentially bionic,
the bionic legs,
and these are functional like they have
real people that have these artificial
legs attach to their body and their
neural impulses.
The normal impulses that trigger tissue
movement on a regular person make it
happen under this new.
This guy,
hugh herr is the father of bionic
revolution.
He has designed his own prosthesis.
I lost both of his legs in a climbing
accident,
so this guy engineered these artificial
legs up a knife.
He was 17 and he decided to become an
engineer,
found a solution to the problem it will
do away with outdated prosthetics,
which he had been given a.
So this guy developed these legs that
make him walk like he's walking with
short sawn.
Look at.
Look at how they're injecting it into.
They can feel and move from sales.
From the brain.
Yeah.
It's amazing,
man.
This guy is moving it.
Anyone can use them.
He can dance with them on.
He can run.
Look at that.
He's fucking running.
You can run with them.
You can go upstairs.
The coming together of man and robot.
I mean,
and this is again human limitations.
So that's his daughter.
She's riding his back bro.
Did you see that boston dynamics robot?
They showed the other yesterday or going
to play that because one day a human is
going to get these legs like this boston
dynamics robot wants to jump.
That's a man.
No,
it's a robot.
It's like a terminator.
Robot can jump like six feet in the air
or some shit like,
yeah,
see it's just a matter of time here.
People take their feet off and put these
fucking things on and rolled down the
highway and we're going to choose those
demon legs,
those backwards horse type legs because
apparently they're more efficient.
They're more efficient springs and you
sit down on them.
It doesn't matter where you.
Does that scare you when you watch it,
when you looked at it?
Depends on how high.
I'm prettY high right now.
Fairly scares me.
It scares me because it's um,
it's changed and it's radical change and
it's probably coming at a,
at a,
at a pace that we can't really manage
now.
That's what I think is the scariest
thing about the change that we're
experiencing right now.
It's happening so fast.
We're not going to be able to manage it.
It's not gonna be able to predict
whether or not it's a good thing or bad
thing.
and even if it is,
we do predict that it's a bad thing.
We're not gonnA be able to stop it.
Well,
there's a crazy race going on and we
don't exactly know what the goal is,
but there's a crazy race to innovate,
to keep coming up with better and better
stuff,
whether it's better,
laptops are better computers,
but it's all leading somewhere.
We're not exactly sure where,
but we're chasing the best product
available possible.
And that contributes to this sort of
matrix of technology,
this incredible sort of,
um,
this environment where if you looked at
like the technology,
you looked at it as like a,
like a life form.
It's evolving quicker than anything
we've ever seen ever.
Oh yeah.
You know what I mean?
EverythiNg else from the champs that
were talking about earlier to bugs,
to the snake that was eating the snake,
they all evolved.
They've all slowly changed.
There's been natural selection.
There's been random mutations is,
but all sorts of factors that allowed
them to get to the state they're at
today,
but we've never seen anything like
technology mean from my,
from my day I had a computer in 1999 or
something like that and had like a four
gigabyte hard drive.
And I thought it was the shit kenny.
And believe this dude,
four gigabyte,
now your phone has a 128 gigabytes.
Now every new phone that comes out,
it's going to be even bigger and bigger.
They're going to 300,
260 gigabytes and terabytes.
Laptops have a terabyte on a regular
basis.
Now that that is a thousand megabytes,
it's fucking insane.
We have this incredible environment now
where everything is getting better all
the time,
whether it's cars or tvs or phones and
it's happening right in front of us were
just sitting there watching it and we're
helping it.
We're helping it.
We're feeding it.
We're in.
The newest shit comes out.
You can't wait.
There's a line outside the apple store.
Please,
please show me what's going to replace
me too.
I get to see it yet no little step
closer.
Look,
this one takes your fingerprint.
The next one takes your dna.
Yeah.
The next one you blow into,
it powers it.
It literally feeds off your breath.
And the next one's in electric chimp
that takes you a dick.
So this one goes right up your ass like
a fucking tampon and then we're done.
Yeah.
They have one that wraps around your
risk.
Now.
Nokia just came out with one.
It's crazy.
What is you waLk,
they have a cell phone and you walk
right up to your fucking wrist and go
like that flap.
And it slapped one of them.
Little rubber bands.
Things that kids have bracelets.
Yeah.
Slap bracelets and it just slaps around
your wrist and as a flexible screen you
could look at your screen on your wrist
while it's like showing you your email
and who's calling.
I remember when radar came out and that
was the big thing around us.
Radar.
I remember that.
People loved radar.
Radar detectors.
Let the fuckers aren't gettIng me,
dude.
My body.
One of my buddies used to just drive
around the grocery store and just hear
it beep,
but he went by the electric doors in the
front of his mind.
Still does that to this day,
that radar detector.
That's awesome.
Did I miss the old days,
man?
Sometimes.
You know,
I'm not like a,
you know,
one of those naysayers that believes
that the future isn't going to happen,
but I surely miss the old days.
I miss,
I miss old diseases.
I miss.
I miss old when people had ailments and
handicaps and it was just part of life,
you know,
every battle wasn't fixed and corrected.
That's still the case for now.
But eventually I'm going to bionic legs.
Everybody geTs a nice teeth.
Everybody got soap.
Everybody gets,
you don't want that.
I want to.
I want some people that are a little
different than.
I remember they had a dude who broken
his neck and he just heard his clavicle
and his shirt just never.
He was just the dude.
His shirt never fit the same way,
you know?
And that was just,
we was,
you know,
he wasn't,
they never kind of warrior warrior life
with you a little bit more,
if that makes any sense.
It does.
It does make sense.
Or if you got rabies or something and
you lost a limb or if you've got,
you know,
you just have bionic legs,
you had like crazy prosthetics at
somebody with one dude in tucson had
cigarettes.
He kept in his leg one time he had an
astro built in the,
in the side of the other one.
He Would cross his leg over and really?
Yeah.
And it just don't know what it was.
That guy.
I'd be like,
fuck that.
I want to get some bionic legs,
wouldn't you?
That's true.
I don't,
I'm not that guy.
So I don't know that that guy you would
want the bionic legs,
like just,
you don't want to become that guy.
if you.
Do you want to become that guy with the
cigarette in his leg.
Lamb?
No,
I don't want to become that guy with the
ash tray in your thigh.
You don't want to become that guy.
You want to be the guy with the bionic
legs if you're either one of those guys.
Yeah.
One hundred percent.
Yeah,
I guess so.
I guess maybe I just missed the visual.
I was making us miss that time and it
was just.
Things seemed a little slower.
Well,
people always long for the past years
with.
Yeah,
that,
that feeling of nostalgia,
especially to people that never really
totally felt secure during that time.
Sort of romanticize that time.
you know,
I state this one girl she used to
vacillate between her childhood was this
amazing dream and her childhood was
hell.
He never.
You never get a straight answer out of
her Like either she would tell you that
her childhood was this terrible,
terrible life that was just constantly
filled with stress and pressure and
yelling and fighting and everyone was
poor and no one can pay the bills and
then sometimes she would describe it and
it would be like this wonderful magical
time and everything was beautiful and
amazing and if she could only go back
then when life was simple,
it'd be like,
what the fuck are you talking about?
You have this delusional perception of
the past that you occasionally adopt,
but for the most part you're talking
about your childhood and the scars that
it's left with you and they fuck with
your head all day long,
but then occasionally you'll pull out
some bullshit version of your life and
like,
like you're looking at some like,
like a memory scene in a movie where
everything is blurry and perfect music
is playing.
Is thAt a survival skill or just
something where she's nut to thinks
she's definitely nuts,
right?
Yeah.
She was definitely nuts,
but it's also a survival skill.
I think people that grew up in horrific
childhoods especially,
they have a way of a longing.
The longing for that past they long.
They have so much nostalgia that they
distort their memories,
but memories are fucked up anyway,
man.
Yeah.
It's crazy how they alter as you get
older and you can all.
You can almost.
If you plant the seed now of what could
be a memory later,
it will almost become a real memory
later.
You know what I'm talking about?
I do.
Yeah.
You can definitely manipulate your own
brain.
It's crazy.
Did you can't even trust yourself these
days.
Did any.
Any day.
The human memory is not designed to
recall the past and perfect order is
designed to remember what's dangerous
and what's not.
Keep moving.
Who do you like?
Oh,
I liked deal.
They deal.
What's up dude,
I know you.
You know what I mean?
Like you're.
You were around people that you trust
and care for.
You remember that you remember things
that they did bad,
like I fucking hit me with that rock,
that piece of shit,
and you start saying,
but we're not designed for these
longterm strategies for the world and
remembering what the fuck happened 30
years ago when you were in high school
or whatever.
You know so you're not going to remember
it.
ThAt stuff.
And if you do,
it'll be all fucked up and jumbled up in
your brain.
It won't be accurate.
Do you?
have you seen that show black mirror?
It's about.
I've seen a couple episodes,
two episodes.
There's an episode where the woman's,
a woman's husband passes away and they
have enough audio of him online where he
can now they can take all that audio and
mix it together and she can now talk to
him online because enough of his voice
is in the internet and you having this,
can you even imagine you're going to
live.
You could potentially be interviewing
people forever.
Whoa.
Even after you're gone,
bro.
Yeah,
but it still won't work because I don't.
I wouldn't know what he would have to be
an actual.
Like if you're going to listen to
someone in a podcast interviewing
someone,
it would have to be the actual person in
because you don't really know what they
will say.
I don't even know what the fuck I'm
going to say,
but they'd have the best database of
somebody like you.
To be honest.
They're got a good database,
but at the end of the day,
right.
It's not real time and it's not based in
them.
It's not in the moment at all,
but I thought that that was pretty
fascinating that they could even do it.
It is.
It's only the beginning of what they're
going to be able to do.
They're gonna be able to recreate your
thought patterns to the point where they
could recreate how you would feel and
think and I think how you feel and think
is a lot of time dependent upon your
health.
Yeah.
Like there's been many times where I was
just really tired and I just wasn't the
same person that I would be if I was
really awake.
Yeah.
You know,
so who is that?
Am I the same guy?
Well,
because if you put me in the same
scenario with the same person saying the
same thing,
but have a different reaction to it
based on how I feel,
which is one of the reasons why I think
it's so important to optimize your life,
like your physical health,
it's so important to have as much energy
as you can all the time,
but great.
So then when you're talking to people,
you have a positive excellent response
to it.
You Have like a good feeling.
You take it and like whatever you
experience in life,
you don't have to be weighed down by
your physical body to the point where
you don't enjoy the experience as much
as you could if you were feeling healthy
and happy.
Yeah,
and we're the best part.
You can't even get to the surface to be
there to resonate with the other person.
Cranky tires.
You're hung over man.
Also worse.
Oh,
drink man.
I quit drinking because that hangover
just couldn't take it,
man.
It's the worst drug they think they've
got to fit.
They figured out a way to cure
hangovers.
Some guys said that by 20,
I think it was like 20,
20,
they will have cured hangovers and
figured out some,
some new method to cure hangovers.
So literally.
So what separates doesn't mean you say,
you know,
you're talking about all these things
about the future because you really seem
like a future man,
you know?
Yeah.
I'm going to make a new sHirt.
Future man.
Now they have a cartoon I think called
future or something.
Drama.
Yeah,
futurama.
That's a woman.
I think my spanish.
But what I'm saying at what point are we
no good anymore?
Well,
we're not going to be this anymore.
I don't think it's a matter of us being
no good.
I think you would pose the same question
to Australia.
[inaudible],
however many hundreds of thousands,
if not millions of years ago.
Those fuckers were created.
If you went back then and talk to those
people with sorta kinda people or
communicated in some weird fucking
grunting form about what the fuck's
going to happen a million years from
now,
they'd be like,
whoa,
we're not going to be us anymore.
Well,
I'm going to have clothes on.
How many of going to be the same?
Oh my god,
I'm going to get in a car.
I wouldn't even walk places.
Oh my god.
I'm going to fly in a plane.
You meet.
I'm not going to have to freeze to death
in the middle of the fucking rockies as
they try to cross.
Oh my god.
No.
I mean we change everything.
Changes.
We're going to change.
Just like monkeys change.
Just like you know,
our past ancestors changed.
will we be okay?
Do you feel like,
or it won't be us,
that's what we won't be.
We write because it will be a different
time.
It will be different thing,
man.
We're going to be a different thing.
It's like Jordan can't play coby because
they just weren't the same at the same
time like.
Right.
But if you could get a time machine and
put them together,
be fascinating,
right?
Yeah.
But they can't and they don't and the
thing keeps going.
The thing keeps going.
The thing does not wait and you are a
part of the thing.
You know,
we look at the thing in terms of like
iphones.
I don't want an iphone one take that
piece of shit and throw it right in the
fucking ocean.
But back in the day that iphone one was
the shit.
Excuse me.
Yeah.
My father got aluminum on the back of
it.
Look at that guys like having.
Touching.
Yeah.
I make it work.
When I touch.
It's got a camera.
I can get online,
get online slow as fuck.
But you can get online.
Remember?
Whoa.
Those are good times,
man.
But if you got one of those today,
he'd be horrified.
You'd like this slow,
clunky piece of shit.
How the fuck this thing ever make it?
Probably beat your spouse with it,
you know,
that's how much you wouldn't care about
it.
Did it?
Would fucking hate it.
And skip it across over lake.
I guess I'm just nervous that I'm not
going to be needed anymore in the
future.
You know,
as a comic.
Yeah.
Sometimes there's a comic.
I think about that.
But also this is like a human.
Well,
you'll,
you'll be something whether or not
needed is what you need.
You know,
I don't know if needed is what we all
need.
We think we need needed because we don't
like to feel unneeded or unnecessary.
So we'd like to be desired.
So we want to be needed,
right?
Eventually we're going to have to
probably replace that with fulfilled.
Replaced that with a joyful,
with gratitude,
with enjoying the experience that's
going to be.
That's a tough sell to.
Who knows?
it's got to be some changes.
We might eliminate emotions that might.
If I was going to engineer something
right,
not me,
but if I was someone looking to
ultimately innovate and get us past
where we are now as a species,
like if you're a certain leaps and
bounds of the human race is going to
have to make.
One of the big ones I would have to saY
is we are always tripped up by our
emotions,
man.
We're constantly tripped up by anger and
jealousy and desire,
racism,
mild racism or a serious racism or you
know,
just distorted perceptions of reality
that are caused by the ego,
not looking at things accurately to
protect you from the reality of who you
are versus who you like to pretend you
are.
All those dIfferent variables can hold
back people right now if they come up
with a way to ensure this ultimate bliss
state without any attachment to
emotions,
almost like you exist in a state of
constant,
um,
ecstasy like taking the drug ecstasy
like,
but an intelligent crafty thought,
provoking,
moving forward ecstasy with no emotions
attached to it.
And no,
no jealousy and no anger.
Boy,
who's going to not go into that and be
like,
you want to be a champ?
Do you want to go back to chimp days
when you bite each other's dicks off and
bite your fingers off and killing each
other and eating each other?
Is that what you want to do or do you
want to go forward?
Well,
if you want to go forward,
I don't want to do.
They might be several steps until we get
there,
but I think ultimately we may very well
reach a point where we do not have
emotions as we know them today because
they're not necessary because there are
biological artifacts of a time where we
were living tooth fang and claw trying
to protect ourselves from other
organisms will not.
We might surpass that.
We might reach some new state and that
might be the main tool or the main
ingredient,
the main element that we introduce into
the human species that allows us to take
it.
That's cdm godlike level at because like
our new medium kinda.
Yeah.
I mean,
if you think you become something that
you would never imagine exists now,
like something that can engineer the
future,
something that can change a body turn,
turn something someone into something
that you've never experienced before,
make a mind infinitely more powerful
than the mines that we currently
experienced with the greatest minds on
earth.
If that's all engineering,
if that's all possible.
You think our feelings will be like in a
museum?
Nope.
I think it'd be a relic.
There'll be a relic just like wearing no
clothes as a relic.
I mean you can go back to the amazon
right now and you could find people that
aren't wearing any clothes.
Undiscovered tribes that they're just
going in there and logging and they
discover these fucking people and the
shooting bows and arrows and helicopters
with cameras on them.
yeah.
Eating termites to see some of that.
Yeah.
Whatever the fuck you can stay alive.
That's all a relic,
right?
Let me just makes me nervous.
Sometimes we're going into the matrix
they have on going into the matrix.
It's happening.
I'm going to get my stuff first.
What would you bring?
If I said,
hey dude,
you can go into the matrix,
but uh,
you can bring three things,
I'd have to bring a picture of my family
and then I'd have to bring.
PrObably I bring some water,
would be water in the matrix.
I'm not going to be the guy without it.
And then imagine if you're the only one
smart enough to bring water and you're
like,
well everybody hold the fuck on.
I don't have enough water for all of us.
Need some of that water.
And he give it to some of their local
fight them.
Try to get the water bags like fuck you.
I'm jagging the water of brother.
It's not like a brother would drink all
the water out my grass man.
I'd probably give it out and I would
take a knife in there.
Like a small knIfe.
A small one.
Yeah.
Or maybe a toothbrush.
You're the only person with a fricken
nice grill and the matrix.
They're getting some pussy bro.
Woo.
You think you get posting in the matrix
from having a nice grill?
I hope so,
man.
I don't know if I care about that.
I just don't want to be in there without
some of my little bit of a creature
comfort because I'm feeling
uncomfortable on there because if I take
my same feelings and I feel
uncomfortable when I'm in this matrix,
I understand and I don't want to not at
least have something to clean my teeth
or to,
you know,
maybe like an like a scarf or something.
Something to make me feel more
comfortable or do you totally knoW what
you're saying?
Yeah.
I don't want to be the dude in the
matrix.
And what were you taken there?
You,
I would assume that it physical objects
would be useless,
so I would just go,
uh,
but the water might be a good idea.
An hour even split.
No water in the matrix.
I think the real problem is,
is your life force is what you are
inside,
like is a soul real and what if they can
scientifically isolate the soul if they
can fit science figures out a way.
Like I know we didn't use to know where
the subatomIc particle was.
We didn't use to know where the cell
was.
We didn't use to know the difference
between multi-celled single celled
organisms,
but now we do,
right?
What if one day we get to a point where
like we've isolated the cell in a human,
you could see it the same way a dog and
see that magnetic field,
we've isolated it and in people and we
know what it is and you can actually
take it out of your body and transfer it
into the matrix and you will live now in
the matrix,
but your physical body will cease to
exist and what if that's what happens
when you die,
right?
What If that's exactly what happens when
you die?
What if that's why the dmts released in
your mind?
You blow through this kaleidoscope of
geometric patterns to this other place.
What if that is exactly what happens?
I believe that can happen.
THat feels most realistic to me,
but also I think you could come back and
be reincarnated.
You could probably bounce back and forth
between the two.
Why not?
I mean,
if you can be born,
why can't you be born again?
People like there was no evidence.
I know there's no evidence and you know,
but there you also know that you're
alive.
Yeah.
That's the only evidence we have is that
we've been here already wants.
Yeah,
so it seems most likely that that would
occur.
Again,
I don't know about most likely,
but totally possible.
Would you get with a person can exist at
all if you can exist at all.
If whatever the fuck consciousness is
exists in the form that is thiel vaughn,
you're telling me that you're absolutely
sure that it doesn't pass through to
some next dimension when the physical
body deteriorates in this one.
You don't know that.
I mean,
you might be right.
You might be right.
It might be the end people that are like
nihilists.
They're like the end.
Your body dies and that's it,
and you might be right,
but you don't know that you're right.
So even saying That your body dies and
that's it.
The reason why I have a problem with
that as a,
you don't know,
and b,
the fact that you exist at all is
fucking crazy.
Amen.
The fact that we can talk right now,
people listening,
there's people right now on road trips
right now.
You people out there in that car,
listen to this shit right now.
Laugh children,
they have children probably too high to
drive dan adults to to you.
You were a part of this.
We're all part of this.
The fact that we can experience each
other at all and the reason why we're so
fucked up as a culture,
one of the big reasons why we're so
fucked up as a as a civilization is that
we're somehow or another ignoring the
mystery of being alive as being this
crazy,
bizarre and wonderful and powerful thing
that just that you're alive.
Just that you're hearing these words.
Just that you and I are speaking these
words just that's how a guy like Donald
Trump gets into office.
That's how things like this happen.
When the world gets tossed into
communication were all baffled,
baffled by it all and still figuring out
on the fly and we're stuck with these
archaic models of government and control
that were designed back when people were
riding rafts across the fucking ocean.
With the power of the wind,
I mean literally whatever.
We're doing a huckleberry finn.
No,
now I'm thinking of something else.
Mayflower,
the mayflower pinta,
the santa maria,
all that shit.
Um,
I mean we are bizarre,
but just being alive is very strange.
People don't meet up and talk about it
enough.
Then we don't have time,
man.
That's the other thing.
We're keeping ourselves busy work and
creating these objects and buying these
objects were creating these objects.
If you,
even if you're not well,
I don't work in technology.
So your theory doesn't Work.
Yes you do.
You work to buy technology.
You don't think you work in technology,
but your labor,
no matter what you do,
I don't care if you change tires,
you,
our labor is helping technology innovate
because you're going to buy a new phone
and if you're going to buy a new tv and
you're going to buy a new computer,
you're helping.
You're all feeding.
You're working towards technology.
You just don't think you are,
but everybody is.
Fuck man.
listen,
nervous now.
Oh,
right now there's no need.
See,
I think that's part of the trick of life
is that it's always going to feel like,
oh my god,
this is crazy.
This is going to end,
but you got to enjoy it while you can.
You got to enjoy this because right now
it's not ending.
Yeah.
I had a dream the other night.
It was a fucked up dream,
man.
You get a choice of forum before we move
on.
As you get a choice,
if you move into that matrix or not,
do you think?
Who the fuck knows?
Who knows?
Maybe you get a chance to just stay in
limbo.
Maybe get a chance to go into the dmt
world and just danced with the ils for
all eternity.
Yeah.
Might or you might relax and give into
love so much that all of a sudden you're
opening your eyes and you're looking at
your mother and you're a baby and you
start from scratch and you tried to do
it right.
This time I'm going to moscow,
dude,
that's where I want to go.
Do you want to be born in moscow?
Now?
I just want to go there.
like if you do that at all at the end,
you know,
like if you get a pickup one more spot,
you haven't been,
you know,
you imagine how vulnerable you would
feel if you were reborn as a baby and
you were in any way aware of the.
You already lived this life.
Like,
oh my god,
I gotta do this again.
I don't think so.
I think if you've got to look at your
mother,
I think you'd just be so filled with how
much love you probably have for in a
good.
That's a good attitude.
That's a good perception.
Maybe it's interesting though.
That's fascinating to think that what if
you got to just have just a moment of
like threw a baby was just through a
baby's eyes or through your mother's
eyes and see what you looked like or
through like if you got to just go
through to see what the roots of it all.
Where now,
what's manager?
have you ever heard the stories of a
three year old past lives?
They've tried to tell our parents say
that their kids have told it.
Started saying really weird things and I
always think those people are full of
shit.
They don't know if that's ever true.
Why don't you find out?
See what I mean.
You can't.
It's hard to prove them because they all
seem very anecdotal.
See if there's any like real good,
legitimate New York times source of a
baby starting to speak spanish when it's
born in Germany or something
that they busted a man in our town.
He was trying to be a ghost.
He was to try to make money for his
hotel to get it on the haunted tour.
Oh god.
They called him impersonating a ghost at
night.
That.
Has there ever been a fucking john era
of television that has been more
fruitless than ghost hunter shows?
David silva is one of my favorite job.
What is it?
He.
I saw him last night and he said he
goes,
go sunny.
It involves two of our favorite things,
wandering around aimlessly and
disappointment.
Every one of them is like ends up in a
basement with black light.
Like they try,
they use night vision and then they
always cut to commercial.
What was that?
And then they cut to commercial,
we'll be right back and we need black
goes home is where the black ghost
hunter is that man,
I know that black people don't like
magic and ghost,
but you got to get some brothers and
sisters out there on the hunt because if
anybody could find it goes.
It's a black one too.
Are you still have a bit about that when
it came to big foot you?
Yeah.
I was like,
here's what you don't find when you go
looking for bigfoot black people,
like you are more likely to find big
foot then you are black people out
looking for that is a white man's folly.
Black people like,
Yeah,
go ahead dude.
Fucking idiot.
He looking for some shit that you don't
even know.
It's real.
I'm going to be the guy.
I'm the explorer.
I am To discover I'll be up there on
that mountain.
Like a real man.
But have you ever,
uh,
have you ever went to look for a
treasure or something?
I love very treasured and stuff like
that.
I've never heard of a treasure of being
in any area that was feasible for me to
go look for it.
So no,
I never been involved.
Let's see.
You getting out there one day.
Never found him.
You
treasure man.
Yeah,
I think that would be a crazy thing
known to be one of those dudes that
finds gold from one of them.
Sunken roman chips.
Yeah,
because they found like millions of
dollars in gold at the bottom of the
ocean and the sunken ships that
apparently they used to sync all the
time and certain parts of the world will
think about it.
They're pieces of shit and they put all
their money on them,
invest in it and stuff.
It's like the.
It was like the stock market crash.
It was like.
It was like our market crash boy,
five claims lived a past life as a woman
who died in chicago fire.
WhoA.
That's easy though.
Stories like this that it's not proven
against it.
People have looked into it.
huh?
People comment on it.
So he just had this idea that he was.
I mean,
he,
he was a real person and he had the,
he had the details.
Yeah.
Hot chick too.
It looks like what we just talking about
just before that happened.
Um,
we're talking about aliens looking for
ghosts.
Yeah.
Fuck.
I lost my train of thought.
Oh,
they were talking about big foot and
then we're talking about people going in
the woods looking for bigfoot.
Well,
there's just something about people that
go and looking for things that aren't
there and wants to be the president.
Discuss it.
Yeah.
People want to discover shit,
right?
Whether it's ufo or conspiracy theories
or they want to be the one that cracks
this wide open.
Yeah.
Like even like escape rooms.
That's why people love to go do those
escape room things where you go and,
you know,
it's usually a group of top.
Honestly,
it's a lot of kind of a filipino
atmosphere over there.
And then you go there and they do the
um,
you know,
you go and try to break out of the room
and even when you're in the room with
people you don't know,
you immediately want to be the one to
crack the code.
And do you think that that partially
like kills a little bit of a says as men
and maybe as people that everything
feels like it's been discovered a little
bit?
Like.
Yeah,
for sure.
there's like part of us that longs for
like the ability to be the person that
figure some shit out.
Right?
Or find some shit or discovering that's
what probably led people to America in
the first place.
Yeah.
I haven't got to find the best spot.
Keep going.
You know.
And then they find a spot.
All right.
You ever see like an old homestead area?
You know what a homestead is?
I've,
I'm in Montana,
we,
um,
we came across these houses that were
set up back when,
uh,
on,
um,
the Missouri breaks in Montana.
The river.
I love Montana.
Well,
do you know those,
uh,
ever seen those really old structures
that are up there that are just rotted
out from like the 18 hundreds and shit?
Well,
people,
they would give them plots of land and
they will let them homestead.
So like say,
hey,
you know,
if you stay here,
if you could stay here for x amount of
time,
you can,
you get to keep this land.
So people go out there and try and some
of them didn't succeed.
They failed.
Wow.
And yeah,
and you get to physically touch.
You can get out of your car or you get
out of your boat rather walk along the
shore and go up and put your hand on
this building.
That was built by some guy who took a
chance and didn't make it.
Wow.
He took a chance and he came over from
the east coast or somewhere somewhere
east.
Made it all the way out to Montana.
Took a patch of land and died out there.
And you could find that little house and
maybe sometimes there's a little
cemetery there to where the people that
used to live there buried in.
Do you think he feels any differently
when he died then?
Like you were outfield when we die.
It's a real good question.
Like does his wonder if his a real good
question?
I bet everybody goes scared.
It doesn't like if you die in beverly
hills,
do you think it's any better than dying
in the jungle?
No,
no,
no.
That'S ultimately what's hilarious about
it all.
At the end it's a complete and total
lack of control and that's what's so
terrifying to us because we go through
our lives trying the best we can to
maintain as much control as possible and
fail almost every step of the way.
And then ultimatelY the only thing that
we have control over is our ability to
let go of control.
Right?
Wow.
Yeah.
Right.
Ultimately,
the only thing we really have is this
understanding
that this is a temporary existence and
you're going to come to a time where the
ride ends and everybody's right ends and
you just have to face that and it's
scary
at midnight rider song as pop back into
my head and just saying that doon doon,
doon doon doon doon doon doon.
Doon should end on that.
Perfect deal.
Vaughn.
You're a bad motherfucker alwayS like
hanging out with you at the store.
So I'm glad we got a chance to do this.
Dude.
You're funny dude.
Thank you man.
I appreciate you having me.
I'd like to ah,
this world you created in here,
you know,
this is to think about stuff back soon.
Let's do it again man.
I appreciate it.
And a few vons.
Goddamn I let them do stand up.
He's funny as shit.
And you have a specialist coming out in
june on showtime now.
Have a special.
It's on netflix right now.
That's,
that's rIght,
yeah,
a bunch of trolls attack then when it
came out,
but get it out there.
A bunch of roles yet is some people
wrote like negative articles and like
had people like some sub reddit people
like rank it low and just stuff that
just like kind of I kind of got
attacked,
you know,
virtually attacked.
Was it?
What was it about subject matter or.
I don't know what it was.
Some people call me to compare you to
donald trump's people.
Little understand satire,
I guess.
I don't know,
it just was disappointing,
but go check it out on netflix,
man.
I think you'll enjoy it called again.
It'S called.
No offense on netflix.
No offense.
The avant funding motherfucker.
Thank you brother.
Appreciate it man.
Thank you jo hollow.
See guys.