Live
alright,
the Joe Rogan experience podcast is
brought to you by on it.com.
If you to go to o,
n n I t and enter in the code named
Brogan,
you will save yourself.
What is it?
Ten percent.
Fuck this up.
I don't even remember.
I'm typing and I got chocolate,
Dell,
and enc in any way here.
So I'm confused.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I can't get my shit together.
Go to ron and it used to coordinate
Brogan.
Save yourself 10 percent off.
All right,
get it together.
Bitches hit the button.
Real good
experience Joe Rogan podcast.
My night.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we seriously got to fucking legends in
the house.
This is a ridiculous late night podcast.
It's 12:30
AM here.
Ensign.
Anyway,
just where'd you fly in from?
Portland,
Oregon.
Just flew in from Portland.
Staying with Chuck Liddell and both of
them.
The only way to do a podcast is the
banging out right now at 12:30
AM.
So here we are man.
Speaking into microphone.
Tell everybody what's up.
What's up?
Hi.
People have been asking for this podcast
for a long fucking time and you're
wondering why you're a very unique
character.
They want to hear you talk,
you know,
it's like you're a,
you're not just a,
a pioneer of mma as is chuck,
but you're also a very unique human
being and uh,
there's a lot of stuff that you do both
the inside of martial arts and outside
of martial arts is very,
very admirable,
you know,
and one of the things that I really
appreciate is a,
I keep seeing all this stuff that you're
doing for,
uh,
the victims of Fukushima and you've gone
down there several times,
21 times,
21 times.
And what are you doing when you go down
there?
It was,
it was,
uh,
it was actually a change of different
things that I did in the beginning.
We just went up there just to,
uh,
save people,
help people.
It was like two weeks after the tsunami
hit and then it moved to helping the
people in the evacuation centers.
And then now it's people that are placed
in temporary housing that don't have any
source of income.
We're just turn us,
help them,
supply them with their basic necessities
like water stuff like water,
toilet paper,
tissue,
dog food,
cat food.
I mean,
yes,
a lot of people take things for granted
and there's so much that these people
need,
you know,
and people forgetting a lot of because
they're not news anymore.
Were you in Japan when the quake hit?
I was in Japan.
Yeah.
Everybody craziest earthquake.
Overfilled.
Yeah.
Just kept.
The difference was it didn't usually
earthquakes last few seconds and you're
like,
oh,
earthquake finish,
but this one gets kept going and it kept
getting stronger and we're like,
whoa.
I was on the phone with a friend at the
time in Hawaii and I was like,
Oh shit,
this is huge.
Then shit started falling in my house,
in the cupboard,
my,
my pictures on my walls and the old
these ships.
This is something I never felt before.
It's kind of fucked up because the
videos of the tsunami was,
we've all known about tsunamis for,
you know,
hundreds of years,
if not thousands of years.
People have been aware that that happens
when the ocean goes out,
that you gotta get the fuck out of there
because something's going on,
but we've never really seen it on video.
We've never captured it the way it was
captured in Fukushima,
it's scarier when you saw those cars
rolling over the ground just going with
the ocean and taken out houses and
houses floating that were on fire and
it's like mother nature.
They had it going over the rice fields
and they had like these white of
greenhouses like on it.
You've got to realize those greenhouses
like 12 feet tall,
chaises blake,
little toys,
and there was a screening rate over
everything.
It was unbelievable.
It was amazing to watch.
It was amazing to watch the physical
devastation that,
that mother nature can bring it.
And by the way,
it's shit like that,
which happens every,
you know,
several hundred years.
We just,
we hadn't,
hadn't documented it like this,
you know,
we didn't have video cameras the last
time it happened like this.
What was amazing though to me was not
just that something like this would
happen,
but how orderly everybody responded in
Japan,
like you saw the lines.
Everybody was when they were waiting for
eight or when they were helping each
other.
It was really pretty amazing.
Yeah.
It's a little different than the rest of
the room.
Fuck.
Yeah.
A lot different inner lining of food
when they don't have food.
You know what,
what is the difference is just the
culture of Japan
mannerisms and the um,
the type of,
uh,
they have this,
you know,
the spirit,
you know that to suck it up.
You know,
you see it in the fighters to in Japan.
I mean,
I hate to talk than Americans,
but man,
sometimes they go and go.
My brothers,
Jim,
and he goes,
you got to tell guys to do couple more
rounds within the Japanese guys.
You got to tell them stop.
Or they'll keep going.
You teach them on technique to keep
doing it.
I mean,
I'll do a seminar in Japan,
my technique,
I'll forget them.
When we started talking to someone,
I looked back and you're still repeating
the technique over and over,
but when I go into something in the
states as I'll do it,
keep going,
keep going.
They do it once one is over here next to
move.
Keep going,
keep doing it.
You know,
doesn't tell us a little different.
There's a lot of lazy bitches in this
country.
We got,
we got it too.
Good.
Everyone's fucking soft over here.
It's hard to find like super disciplined
people over here.
It is a fascinating thing when you see
that an entire country has a different
philosophy,
you know,
and I,
I've only been to Japan once,
but it was amazing.
It was really interesting.
It was,
and it was after the,
uh,
the earthquake and it was after
Fukushima and everything's won.
The UFC was there.
And uh,
it's a,
it's a totally different world man.
It's pretty neat.
It's very neat.
You know,
how long you been over there now?
Twenty two years.
Wow.
And you were born and raised in America.
And why and what,
what,
what led you to go to Japan
for extra racquetball,
racquetball,
play record with.
Wow.
That wasn't even fighting.
I was just training because we had a lot
of street fights in Hawaii,
so it was just training just so I didn't
get my ass kicked in Hawaii pretty much
because we were Japanese and back in the
day being big was being strong.
So for me being an oriental,
we're smaller so we just had to really
fight for our stuff.
We either had to give her a lunch money
everyday or fight for it.
Hawaii is one of the last places where
street fights go down on a fucking
regular basis to happen.
So it's kind of crazy man.
Why is one of the rare places that are
left on this earth where things are
decided with knuckles?
You know,
that's,
that's real.
There's a lot of places where there's,
you know,
all sorts of gun violence and violence
and I'm sure so Hawaii hasn't shared
that,
but there's a lot of fucking fights
going on in Hawaii.
It's amazing when you think about an
island in the middle of Pacific and how
many great fighters that come out of
there.
It's both you and your brother,
Bj Penn,
you know,
and just keep naming all the way down
the line.
God,
Kendall Grove and you know,
there's so many.
So many guys came out of Hawaii just
like it has.
There's a certain style of fighter that
comes out.
Hawaii,
like scrappy,
wild chance taken,
you know,
we're in your face.
Does not like conservative fighters from
Hawaii like you don't see like a lot of
stick and move technical,
like trying to get out of there and stay
safe.
Let Me Bond Jackie style,
you know,
there's not a,
not a lot of that man.
Dudes are going after it in Hawaii.
It's true.
It's interesting man.
You and your brother,
I was there for your UFC debut.
I was here when you fought Royce Alger.
Yeah,
I was the backstage interviewer.
I'm pretty sure I interviewed you
because you got injured in the fight and
you couldn't continue to interview.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Let me back.
I'm like,
what is it?
[inaudible] 97,
was that [inaudible] 98.
[inaudible] 97.
Yeah.
All right.
Well I remember,
I remember it is fueled a little weird,
but I didn't think it was hurt.
Yeah.
What happened to you and that went
backstage and I felt that I got hit so I
just wanted to check on.
My nose was bleeding and that's the
basic rule,
you know,
don't blow your nose for nose that I
felt the air come through and push.
Almost like felt like it was going to
push it out.
I was like,
Holy Shit.
What just happened
for,
for functional know when,
when a guy in a fight gets a broken
nose,
they always tell you don't blow your
nose because it creates some sort of
pressure built up
thin plate of bone plate across the face
here.
That's like paper thin.
And if there's any hole in it actually
holds in the air and turn your face
pretty Freaky,
Huh?
Oh.
And if you have a little crack there and
you blow your nose,
it'll just push the Arrow through that.
So that's pretty much it for fighting,
especially for um,
kickboxers boxers.
I think it's a basic,
real simple,
basic root and blow your nose after your
fight.
It's so hard to do though,
right?
Because he can't breathe out of your
nose and bloods
kind of just check if I like,
those is bleeding and they just blew in
this
poof.
Like,
whoa.
That was a fight where Royce Alger was.
Uh,
that was when Mark Coleman was on top
and wrestlers like the high end Jessalyn
was Kevin Jackson and randleman was in
his prime and it was a lot of like high
end wrestlers were just starting to
enter into the game.
The wrestlers were the ones that were
beating everybody here.
But I remember you,
you caught him in the arm born.
I think he broke his arm.
Did it pop.
But I remember you put your bras.
They were like,
they were yelling something at you guys
and as you were leaving your brothers
like,
wrestlers ain't shit like you guys like
having,
there was some thing back and forth
between you guys.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I remember it man.
It was,
it was interesting because you uh,
you know,
in arm barn him,
it wasn't just an upset,
it was an upset,
but it was also like the,
it was like the world got to know you.
That was like your first big fight on
the big stage.
It was Kinda good that they just blew
up.
Royce kind of helped me out.
They made a big deal at them because
they thought,
well here's a
accessible amateur wrestler.
He's probably going to be the next big
thing in mma.
But it turned out that you were,
it's kind of shitty.
It was recording everything.
It was about race,
race,
and even when,
the way the question is,
it's like when I fought randy the same
type of question,
like,
are you going to be okay?
Kind of thing.
Like it gets mistaken.
I grabbed that.
I'm breaking like any other arm,
you know.
Did you find out randy with pants on?
Were you wearing the tights and you
caught Randi with an arm as well?
Right.
So almost the exact same time too.
It was like right after,
because randy was there,
the UFC,
he won the heavyweight tournament.
Yeah.
So I,
I didn't expect that to him to,
for him to make that mistake.
Yeah.
He fought Tony Halma and then he fought
that big,
big black kid who had a lot of promise.
But after that randy five,
we never really saw him again.
A kid was pretty good.
But you,
uh,
you,
you did one thing in that fight that we
hadn't seen up until that point.
It was like in the Royce Alger fight.
It was like we were just starting to get
accustomed to what techniques were
really effective in mma.
And we'd seen hoists.
Gracie,
of course,
Armbar a few guys,
but we hadn't seen them take on one of
these big name wrestlers.
It was just starting to enter into the
game.
So when you caught him with that arm
bar,
that was a,
that was a big deal.
That was like,
oh,
okay.
Like you can't just be a wrestler.
You gotta you gotTa know what the fuck
is going on.
When it got throws his legs up,
like
especially with the hype them up,
you still is the volunteer.
Well then after that fight,
the next thing that you showed those in
the randy fight,
you were kicking the shit out his legs
from like the scoop position man from
the bottom.
Yeah.
You landed some fucking hard leg kicks
from that position when you don't see
that very often,
you know,
well this,
this,
I just have this style that just
aggressive matter where you're at.
And we,
we,
um,
they weren't really checking the leg
tape.
We,
we literally put a whole roll of tape on
my legs and it was pretty much 80
percent of the front and they let it go
and it was like a little castle all
over.
The shit hurt a little more than it
looked.
Sorry.
On the part of the game though.
Well,
back in those days,
you know,
like Chuck,
I've watched your fights.
I've watched some of those valley to
fights where it was no knock holes in
the bottom of the bottom of the ropes
were annette,
that net when you get there,
the stuck underneath the net pen under
hitting him,
hammering them through the net and blood
dripping and I was dosed ivc days in
Brazil.
Some of those fucking fights were not
that show I was on.
They filmed a show before.
At the same time they are doing the 1:55
pound tournament in there and watching
these guys,
the guy that,
the guy that wanted actually had gone
through,
he got,
he got cut in the first fight,
got cut in the second fight and then one
of the 30 minute fighting,
a third fight with two big cuts on her.
I mean these guys are going.
They went at it in there.
It was a different world back then,
man.
It was a different world.
Thirty minutes,
a 30 minute rounds.
Thirty minutes straight.
Yeah,
and essentially no rules.
Do you remember when Gary Goodridge
reached into the Pedro's pants and
grabbed his dick and balls?
He grabbed his dick and balls and
squeezes Dick and balls.
I remember that.
That was like a big deal.
Whatever it is,
like,
can he fucking do that?
Yeah.
He can do this.
No eye gouging.
Nobody couldn't grab the ropes and no
oil,
I think was the,
everything that's growing.
Strategy,
legal,
headbutts elbows.
How many Dudes were oiled up though?
A lot of oil.
God,
I actually called them,
went in the back end,
was taped.
We actually took the oil away from
vandelay and uh,
and uh,
what's his name?
Impella in the back of Coleman's.
Got My,
grabbed it from oil it up enough for it
to kickboxing.
It's so funny how the world has changed
now.
I remember I was there for your first
fight in the UFC to.
You fought that knowingly knowing
Hernandez and he was a boxer and I
remember already didn't know that you
were a wrestler up until that fight
right.
Note to the weigh ins,
because I said the big thing was we,
we're going away in,
right?
And I'm thinking,
I made the UFC for Wayne and Wayne is in
on the bathroom scale,
like cutting weight and
not like a digital bathroom scales.
It was one of them aluminum that she
asked me.
They asked me,
hey,
I know he was two pounds over.
Is that right?
I looked at him and right
scale,
let me get back on here.
I get out how to make weight.
You gotta kidding me?
That's hilarious.
By the.
And I said something about it and he
actually,
he didn't know her as a rather.
He saw,
hey,
you better keep this standard if you
want to come back again because in the
back I'm like,
all right.
Whatever man.
Yeah.
A lot of people don't know about that.
That's some fucking bullshit.
It's supposed to be mma.
You know that someone would say that to
you especially right before a fight.
You better fight a certain way.
Yeah,
it was.
I mean,
he was,
I don't know.
I don't know what his thing was.
He didn't like my hair cut either.
He told me that you can't get rid of
that Erica.
Meanwhile,
2013.
You still rocking it.
Fucking dated.
That's hilarious.
Outdated in [inaudible].
Ninety seven was.
When was it?
Okay.
The fucking time of the pilgrims.
That was the real Mohawks.
I mean when,
when was it?
Okay.
If it's outdated?
Yeah,
I dunno.
I Dunno what he was trying to say.
Whatever you like my hair cut.
Yeah.
Well,
you know what?
Nobody knew you then,
you know in time.
And he would have had to accept it.
I couldn't have seen when you were on
your fucking title reign him coming up
to you.
Listen man,
you fucking haircuts outdated enough
already with his Mohawk cover up that
tattoo in your head to Shit's
ridiculous.
It's funny that the things that people
choose to focus on,
you know,
you guys were there those early days,
talkative.
We were just talking to the car on the
way here,
but I remember like going out at those
covert challenge in Temecula and having
them up muscle.
The guy to get my guys paid $100.
100.
You know,
I,
it's like we didn't make any money on
this.
I'm looking at,
I'm like,
I don't care,
we don't have a kid of the gate and the
case getting two,
$100,
but we're not.
Business partners were private
contractors and it was sold out.
Not to mention your things.
I mean the place is packed.
If you didn't make any money,
you're an idiot.
Was that one of those fights where it
was like a pankration style where they
had to use open palms?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
It's interesting.
We have.
Well we used to have.
We out of me and Scott Adams is come
down with like,
I think that one of them,
we had eight guys on the card,
so we had like a,
you know,
most of the card.
Yeah.
Scott Adams is one of the first guys who
was like a leg lock specialists,
you know,
like he became synonymous with like leg
locks.
Everybody knew.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
It is crazy.
I mean they,
they know,
they like locks as long as fight was in
the use for.
It was three,
three minutes in 3:14.
I think,
you know,
when you guys were competing back then
when you came in and UFC 18 or 13.
Yeah,
I started working at 12.
So you were 17,
so when you guys were back there and
when you look back at that now,
like the where the UFC is now,
it's so fucking crazy.
It's like,
did you ever think that it could ever
get this big talk into the microphone
for you?
Those people are still telling chuck in
the car and I can't believe how huge a
MMA has gotten.
Oh,
it's insane.
I get pulled over on the way over here
and go fast.
You know,
I was trying to get here quick and the
guy comes out,
he recognized me.
He goes,
what are you doing?
I go on my podcast studios over here.
I'm doing a podcast with ensign.
Anyway,
goes,
get the fuck outta here.
Wow.
Yeah,
chocolate dells with them.
He goes,
Holy Shit.
I thought he was going to ask to come
and sit in.
I'm going to hide the weed and this guy
gets in here.
But uh,
you know where it is now.
It's like,
you know,
you could say the word Anderson Silva to
anybody you know,
and p,
oh,
I heard that guy know that guy is,
I get so popular now.
It's,
I never would've thought it would've
gotten to this point eventually.
I just thought it would be a long time
coming.
I mean,
I thought it was going to take or take a
long time as well.
Once we got our free TV was,
it was over.
There's never been a sport in our
lifetimes.
That was complete obscurity in the
nineties.
And then huge today.
I mean,
this is the only sport like that that
we've ever seen and the difference in
the athletes and the difference in the
level of competition from 1993 to your
title reign to today.
I mean it's,
it's,
uh,
it's amazing when you see the evolution
of the sport so,
so fast and it's fucking crazy.
So now you slow down for a second year.
Your,
your,
your past.
You two guys are responsible for some of
the most exciting moments in the history
of this sport.
Man.
Your fight with ego.
Vav changin might be one of the fucking
wildest exchanges.
Somebody wrote a,
somebody had a youtube clip.
It took a clip of just the first
exchange where you guys were winging
punches.
Man.
Everybody thought in that fight.
Well,
Igor is a striker and since probably
going to take them down and try to
submit them the fuck you were swinging
while I watched it live.
I remember that was when you had to
watch them.
They were on like 4:00
in the morning and in America you
remember that because it was Erin live
in Japan and you would.
And we would all stay up late to watch
pride like late night on paper view.
And I remember it was me and a couple of
guys from Jujitsu in the house.
We were fucking screaming at the top of
my.
We were like,
Holy Shit.
Because it was just like a movie scene,
like came in throwing these fucking
bomb.
It's like you just bit down on your
mouthpiece and said,
fuck it.
Let's do it.
Take them to,
you know,
to take him where he lives.
That,
that was a crazy fight man.
Do you ever look back on fights like
that?
Going,
what the fuck was I?
Was I thinking there?
Basically what people don't understand
is my why.
I went into my fight to a little deeper
thing I was thinking of growing as a
person and I didn't really worry that
much about the wind losses because in my
types of fights I never ever was
pressured on winning and losing because
my friends were always fun.
Is always exciting.
So
is that a difference in the way the
Japanese fans view fights as opposed to
American fans who so much emphasis
on victory on winning?
Well,
see,
what's hard now is that,
you know,
I,
I can say yes,
I'd rather have the fighters fight with
more honor and more about the pride and
the deep thing about the fight.
But it's hard because back in the day
when we were fighting,
there are no big sponsors you,
you'd never made six figures,
you know,
it wasn't.
There wasn't much pressure about winning
and losing.
Back in the day,
was you feeding,
fighting for peanuts?
Basically if you're fighting in the ring
and putting your life on the line,
that ring,
it's about pride and honor,
you know,
so the fights are different and you say
you,
you'd say like two fighters,
like,
you know,
is that the,
is that discernible for people to fight
that way now?
No,
it isn't because they have so much to
gain from it.
Now they can make set their life within,
you know,
winning and losing is a whole different
thing right now in this day,
you know?
So for you it wasn't about winning and
losing.
It's about finding what you were.
Well,
it was basically,
um,
for me,
I wanted to learn something.
MMA for me was a stepping stone in my
life as a man to grow.
I mean,
when are you gonna ever be put in a
willingly walk into an area that you
possibly might die that day?
You know what I mean?
The stress and the fears and the
anxieties you got to overcome in that
moment is not something you're going to
ever gain in a day to day,
daily lifetime routine.
I mean,
we're lucky as fighters to grow
spiritually and grow meant in our heart
as far as facing that fear every day.
I mean,
you can get hit with a wrong punching.
This guy can hurt you real bad.
People didn't just respect that,
but they responded to that in a big way.
That attitude Yamanto dementia is that I
said,
yeah,
I was nicknamed in Japan and that means
it means a Japanese spirit,
which was actually used back in the
summer idea,
so I translated as a sunrise spirit
and you became known for that attitude
and people knew that when ensign anyway
stepped into the ring of the cage,
there was no plane.
It's safe.
There will be some wild shit going down
every single time and they loved you for
that.
The ovation that you got in Japan
because of that,
the word jargon.
It was.
It was a real good nickname to.
I'm basically,
when I got it,
I didn't know how,
how big the word was and from,
from being okay,
that's cool.
Kanji to wool,
they named me that too.
Now I'm actually trying to live my life
to be as close as I can to that way of
life,
you know,
which is hard.
So when they named you that,
did you feel like a big obligation
because of that?
Yeah,
at first I didn't know what it meant and
then when I found out what it meant,
I was really questioning myself like,
do I,
you know,
I mean I showed in a ring.
I mean it's not just about being in the
ring and I have my fears in the ring
too.
I mean if you watch the eager for that
first I was,
I think the tackle I through a right and
from there I was going to stand toe to
toe,
but all of a sudden I found myself
clenching,
you know?
So I got my fears and everyone doesn't
see that.
If you look back at the video,
you'll see that I had fear took over me
for a moment and I,
I beat that battle like I released them
through those.
But um,
you know,
I fight that fear too,
so as far as you know,
people say I'm going to do that mushy.
The he the undying spirit,
you know,
never,
never taps.
It never gives up.
But there are so many times in the fight
if you really look at it that I'm
fighting that myself and I'm standing
there thinking,
am I justified to Caritas men because I
think in the middle of a fine.
Yeah.
I mean for me,
when I say Yamamoto,
dominancy the summer spirit to,
to have an experience to grow your
spirit to,
to that level,
every time you have an opportunity to do
it.
It does.
It's not exactly.
I can't tell you that.
Okay,
doing this is going to be with our
experience because it depends on the
person.
You know,
like a,
a driver.
If he,
you tell them to get in the car and take
a hairpin turn at 200 miles per hour,
it will be an experience for him to
build his heart because he does it.
But if I were to do that Shit,
hell yeah,
I'd probably be freaking sit in my
pants,
you know?
So for me,
I mean,
I mean when I go into the ring,
you know,
it's like it's,
it's the situation that happens.
So it was perfect for me for egos for it
because if I went and stood in and just
threw it out and just threw off from the
beginning,
it'd be like cool,
I conquer,
I conquered that anxiety and that fear.
But it wasn't really a phenomenal
experience because it wouldn't have been
if I didn't clinch.
So.
So what happened?
What made me happy was I actually had
that fear take over me,
you know?
So for me,
I did some growing in my heart because I
clenched and I actually hesitated and
thinking of trying to take them down and
sending,
getting top position.
Wow.
Do you think that when you look at like
that,
that attitude towards fighting and you
look at how that attitude towards
fighting was sort of a part of that era
where there wasn't that much money to be
made and there wasn't that much on the
line too.
When do you think that those days are
gone?
Like,
well,
it is.
It is because the rules.
I mean they stopped,
fades away faster.
Now I basically see a lot of fights
where,
where are the spirit will start taking
over someone the fights or stopped,
but I understand it's a sport you'd have
sponsors is,
has to be televised.
It can't be too brutal and that's
understandable.
There's just,
it's like a damn.
If you do,
damned if you don't,
you know,
I,
when I see some of those fights,
I cringe because I think this is right
here.
This is where this guy's heart's going
to have to kick in and they stopped the
fight in the state.
Yeah.
Again,
kind credit bummed at that,
you know?
No one else was big.
Was that 10 minute first round and
pride.
We have fun within 10 minute.
First round was big.
Yeah,
that was great because you know,
five minutes shit just gets interesting.
You're,
you're halfway through,
you've got five more minutes after five
minutes of hell.
That first round was incredible,
but it's not exactly the best thing for
you.
If you want to find sponsors and
televise it and get people attracted to
it that don't understand the sport,
you know,
it's.
Yeah.
It's,
it's a kind of a balancing act isn't.
Yeah,
it's hard man.
It's hard.
I mean,
how do you soften up cage fighting
though?
You know what I mean?
How do you soften up mixed martial arts.
You're stopping the fight sooner.
You know there is bisping Belfort this
weekend,
so I'll stop fight.
We stopped a little soon,
stopped too soon.
He's laying in the fetal position with
the guy behind him throwing hammerfest.
You're not trying to defend you.
At no point are you trying to defend
yourself,
right?
I mean,
he wasn't stopping him from rolling up
to his,
to his belly.
He wasn't trying.
Stopping them from trying to get up and
he wasn't trying to get out.
Yeah.
So what I ended up defending his,
I mean the only question I had was why
do they touch him?
Step back,
it went,
it's over,
didn't last very long.
I mean he dropped him and then,
you know,
you look at the replay you're dealing
with,
you're only talking about
a couple of seconds shots to the body
and he hit him too.
I think it was two times ahead.
And then he went,
went to a couple of others by.
But he had,
he didn't even try to roll back up.
He wasn't trying to get out.
He turned his back.
It was,
it was over here and that was what's
going on with the volume,
man.
What are you doing here?
It's varying.
That was a big fucking head kick.
Those,
those clean.
I mean he wasn't trying,
trying to defend himself.
He,
I,
he didn't look like he was trying to do
it,
you know,
I don't,
I mean nothing against it.
I mean he was,
I don't think he knew where he was at
that point.
Instincts kicked in.
He was defending I and I'm,
I'm all for,
I like,
I think at the top level.
I'm all for letting it go a little
longer.
I've,
I,
I complained a little bit about guys.
I mean I understand stopping real quick
at the lower levels,
but at the higher levels mean these
guys,
that's their career,
their life,
they,
they've been there.
They know you gotta give him a chance to
all the way out of it because we've seen
fights with big,
big nog almost almost out.
Hold on and coming back and winning the
fight.
Frankie Edgar or Frankie Edgar.
Yeah.
Motherfucker comes back.
Holy Shit.
Crazy.
You know,
second fight within a lot of times like
that where you've seen guys that and
then you go,
then you see another fight where you
know that got schizophrenia.
Hold on a second.
We got a real problem with referees.
Have itchy trigger fingers and referees
that get involved too much in like the
telling guys to fight and like when they
are fighting and they just make their
presence known too much,
there's just too much intervention by
them need to.
They need to learn how to step back and
too many fights get called where you
have to look at the incident report like
the.
The controversial this weekend about
hitting the back of the head goes,
oh,
it was terrible.
I didn't get hit once in a band called
the fight,
a no contest and I don't know if it's.
I don't know if the guy was complaining
what happened,
but he hit him once with an elbow to the
ear,
clean elbow and then punch to the side
of the head and saying,
wash the back of the head,
wash the back of the head and I don't if
the dude on the bottom was saying
something,
but it was bad.
It was terrible.
Terrible call.
That's a.
that's happened in Brazil a couple of
times.
That happened with the Eric Silva fight.
When Eric Silva got a same thing.
Mario Yamasaki called it a no contest
from shots to the back of the head
and the guy played it up to.
Huh?
He definitely played it out because he
was holding the back of his head and
then you see the instant replay in the
elbows hit him in the year that his pad.
I was kind of stoked when I heard the
Dana tweeted something today.
I will never find the UFC again.
Really?
I think he tweeted that.
Wow.
I was thinking the same thing.
I think I should never forgetting the
octagon ever again.
That guy's a disgrace to the sport.
Yeah.
It's sad when you see guys do shit like
that and they see
someone looking for a way out and
looking for an excuse,
like,
listen man,
this is fucking camera there and there's
a camera there and there's a camera
there.
Everyone can see what those shots land
like.
I Dunno what.
You can't just pretend that it hit you
in the back of the head.
I don't know what happened there,
but refereeing bad refereeing socks,
but bad judging is even more prevalent
in bad referee.
We got a lot of that.
Okay.
First off with ref ref judging it.
It's hard anyway.
Yes,
absolutely.
But then you put that with a lot of guys
just don't understand the sport.
They don't understand either the Jujitsu
or they don't understand the striking or
you don't.
I mean and they're judging it on the
highest level and the highest level and
they don't really understand.
You know,
when the guys working for summer,
I was like,
I mean you guys,
Oh,
you got to count that.
Attempted submission will hey,
thrown your legs up into a triangle.
Like this is not attended to mission.
You know,
it's got to be closer than that.
If you want to call it an attempt
attempted submission or it's got to be
fights to fight out of it.
I mean in wrestling,
take takedown.
Which takedowns good.
I mean how much,
how much do you can either take down?
I was getting up or getting back up.
How has escaped his escape?
What's the skateboard?
When you were fighting,
you were famous for you take down
defense,
but you're also famous for being able to
get up off the bottom when you thought
if you got taken down,
were you thinking,
man,
how much are the judges gonna pay
attention to this.
Even if I get right back up real quick,
how much does that score?
Well,
I never worried about that.
I mean my thing was I was always.
It's a lot easier to get back up if you
start as soon as I hit the ground.
Right.
You know,
if I let you get on top of me and get
set,
it's real hard to get off my back.
Right.
But if you get to take down,
it's not over.
This isn't college.
You're not.
No one's throwing up two points.
I got.
I'm still,
I'm still.
As soon as we hit the ground,
I'm fighting your take that.
And my thing was always I just always
trying to find a guy,
you know,
I'm saying offensive so he can't hit me
on down.
He can't really score with them down
there and I don't really think of a guy
just tastes guy down and holds him
unless nothing else has really done in
the round.
It doesn't mean that you should,
when you got to take down and you
haven't been able to land a punch having
Atlanta done anything.
If he gets up and land some punches
standing and he just went around.
So
is it a case a lot of times of a guy
trying to conserve energy or trying to
figure out when to explode when he gets
taken down where he like,
he'll hang on for a second and then
start moving.
Whereas you would,
as soon as you're back touches the
ground,
you're scooting,
you're,
you're fighting for under hooks.
The problem I tell a lot of guys all the
time is if you get down and you take
that,
get that,
oh shit moment.
Oh Shit.
Get flattened out.
As soon as he did that.
If I mean you're sorry,
now you're going to.
Now it's gonna.
Be a bitch to get off your back.
But,
you know,
my thing is as soon as you've done,
there's a little space,
even when you hit a good hearts,
good takedown.
UHM,
there's balance.
Guess what,
that is.
Space is that space now I'm pushing
already.
I'm already working and get back up.
So I mean that,
that's,
that,
that helps you get,
continue to get up.
But what's interesting is you guys had
to figure that shit out in the cage.
Like there wasn't like a whole series of
fighters that came before you that have
already figured that out.
Like essentially,
you know,
take down defense and the ability to get
up off the bottom and an mma fight was
kinda written by you.
Yeah.
Well I mean I,
I put together some stuff from John
Lewis taught me how get out one this way
and it's got to have somebody on a role
with that knee bar this way.
And I kind of figured out how to do a
push pull thing with the guys and I just
changed something right at the end of
each thing to get.
Because instead of going through that
knee bar,
I get halfway there and just stand up
and guess what,
if I get halfway there,
so I get people off balanced and I could
go,
I do a push pull and make it so I tried
to get you to push real hard to stop
this one.
I go the other way and you stopped that
and then I pop under the other way.
But it's kind of fascinating when you
think about it because you had to kind
of figure all that out.
Like there wasn't like you came along in
[inaudible] 97.
I mean there wasn't a lot of dudes who
had already done that before.
You were.
There was like,
you look at a guy like Rory Macdonald is
training at Tristar,
has got George St Pierre and his camp
for us a hobby.
They got fucking charts and graphs and
dry erase boards where they're writing
down to every day's workout where
they're trying to break it down to each
individual technique and skill.
We're trying to figure it out.
When we
came in and you know,
everyone's trying to figure out.
Most guys came in with one thing,
you know,
wrestling or striking or some Jujitsu
and then come in and they're trying to
mix them all together and we're also
trying to figure out how to train them
together.
Like,
okay,
how do I train my wrestling and my age
at my am,
my striking in my Jujitsu together,
like how do I,
what's the white balance of working out
here and there?
How well with strength training in how
to,
how do I mix everything,
you know,
it was,
it was an interesting time and
challenging.
It's challenging and you know,
now you got guys like you said,
and you'll see guys get better and
better because you got guys that now
they've learned in mixed martial arts
from the start,
you know,
and they,
and they start and they have and they
have coaches that know how to train it.
They'll have a teaching and then there's
still gonna be innovative.
A little bit of navy guys are still
going to create their own little things
that work better for you or for him.
Whatever body type you off.
No,
I talked to you about this and you don't
know what have you thought about opening
up a gym?
Are you thinking about trying to open it
up,
open a gym?
I mean,
I,
I don't know if I'm going to get into
all that coaching guys to fight,
but I always like working with guys that
are fighting,
you know,
and like working with different things
and showing them things I like or I do
different than what they're used to
doing and seeing someone use it.
You know,
if you've got a guy that show that.
I think my favorite thing,
I remember teaching forest had a fine
point to something you've done forever
and he said,
I thought that was a bullshit move.
It never worked.
I just thought,
oh,
that's what I was doing wrong,
because now it just,
it worked.
It was just a guard,
a guard pass thing,
but it was.
He's like,
Oh man,
damn,
that's what I was missing.
You know?
And that's fun for me.
Will you enjoy teaching?
I was just saying that you were talking
about before the podcast ever started
about glover.
You've been training with glover and
getting him ready for his fight with
rampages weekend.
Yeah.
I've been working with over the last two
fights.
You'll after he got back in the US.
I mean I even away from uh,
you know,
he was training for a long time and then
he went,
went back to get stuck in Brazil for a
few years and so I know when I was
working with them with stuff that we
used to do,
um,
some of the stuff that he's forgotten.
Oh yeah.
That's,
that's why that's not working.
Okay.
You know,
little little fine points and you know,
because I know I had the same thing.
I come back from having done that
movement one I'll be why isn't this
working?
Oh yeah.
Just
you just forget one small little
technical aspects of difference of a
makes a whole difference.
Yeah.
It's fascinating how much when you look
at the,
you look at athleticism and you look at
like just sheer strength and size.
That's all well and good,
but it's really fascinating how much
actual technique is involved and just
subtle variations and changes in that
technique.
Make all the difference in the world and
that's something that the lay person
doesn't understand and that's something
that it's a shame when judges don't
understand it
and that's the hard part.
It's,
I mean even just.
I mean some of them I don't think they
quite understand that.
The basics.
No.
The government workers,
they might as well be working for the
DMV.
They got a Gig and they went in and they
learned how to,
you know,
this is a triangle.
This is an arm bar.
This is a kick.
I don't know.
Times I've watched around and just gone,
okay,
I want to see the judge that gave that
round to that guy and have him explain
it to me.
I just want to watch.
I just want to it just for my own
entertainment.
I want to.
I want to hear him explain.
Justify was an ultimate fighters I
watched.
It was the,
it was the live one.
I remember I went to overtime and in the
overtime it was two to one for one guy
and I'm like looking at it going.
It was all standing.
One guy threw two punches,
didn't land one of them,
the other guy probably landed five or
six punches the hole round,
but chase the guy,
the whole round one of the judges
actually gave it to the guy that threw
two punches in the air.
It never landed a punch and was running
the whole time.
I'm like,
what?
Are you watching?
Any,
any?
I was like,
you gotta be kidding me.
I actually had on Tivo.
Every wound it went okay.
I couldn't.
I,
I must've watched around wrong.
I wasn't paying attention.
I must've saw ms dot.
Let me see what I missed.
Okay.
No punches.
No landed,
none.
Freeze.
They were all guys who,
a lot of them are from boxing,
especially in Nevada.
Nevada has a lot of like Adelaide.
Given Dana a hard time about it.
It's like a guys.
He doesn't pick the referees.
It's not.
It's not up to here.
He can't do anything about it.
Not always out of about
promoter.
You really,
you know,
you don't.
You don't get any say whatsoever.
You can't.
You can't have any.
It's like it's illegal.
You can't have any say.
And who's,
who's judging?
We're not judging,
you know,
that has to be done by the athletic
commission.
No wonder he rips on the referring a
lot.
I feel like the refereeing is,
is a lot of it is just,
it's fucking hard.
It's hard to make the right call in the
moment and the
reference reference.
A lot of guys don't do it well,
but yeah,
the judging is a disgrace.
The judging,
in my opinion is a disgrace.
I think people make errors as referees
and that's just a part of being a human
being.
But I feel like the referees for the
most part know what the fuck is going
on.
There's standouts like big John or herb
dean who like,
you know,
they're always gonna Josh Rosenthal,
they're always going to ref a good fight
and even if they make an error,
it's rare and few and far between.
But some of these fucking judges,
man,
like you got to think they're just
flipping a coin,
like they don't know what's happening.
There's no way they know what's
happening.
They just taken,
just taken a guess.
It's,
it's really a shame,
man.
It really is a shame,
it's a,
it's,
it's when you see guys that are
competing in the highest level of the
game and they trained for six to eight
weeks and they've given every fucking
ounce of their soul and here they are
and they,
they edge it,
they think they want,
you think they pulled it off and then
you,
you know,
30,
27 for the other guy and you're like,
what the fuck?
And it's just nonsensical score.
So you threw away two months of this
guy's life,
two months of fucking eating the right
food and getting up in the morning and
drinking a gallon of water every six
hours and you threw it all away because
you're an incompetent
judge.
It's not even those ones where it's
close.
Like he pulled it out close.
I mean the ones it was wasn't bothering
me.
The one.
It's like,
ah,
okay,
I'll give you.
I'll give you that round was a toss up,
but the rest of the or how,
how did you lose any one of the.
I didn't,
I didn't lose the other side.
They lose them.
Some got them losing all three and
you're like,
fucking crazy,
man.
You took a long time off.
You took six years off and then came
back again in 2010 for one fight.
Yeah,
the,
I came back for that only because I got
to,
I put in prison and uh,
the,
you know,
it was funny
because after I got to prison,
it was on national TV.
It was.
And all the newspapers,
magazines.
Funny how I start fading out of the
media.
All of a sudden I get arrested.
I'm like a hot thing in the media again.
You know what I say
first the shocker.
So that's why the media.
But anyway,
you know,
when I got out,
when I would go to bars and stuff,
he was saying,
oh,
some people would say like,
I seen you on TV.
And I'm like,
fuck,
I'm thinking to myself,
is that the one with me handcuffed
police or wasn't a.
Oh my God,
they hated that,
you know.
So I figured,
you know,
the only way to tell she'll make it up
to my fans and let them know that I'm
back.
You know,
you get drug tested in Japan,
we get marijuana is a big thing now in
Japan.
We get tested for marijuana.
If you have any marijuana in your blood
and Japan,
you're not going to be able to fight.
What did you get arrested for?
What happened?
Well,
I had a 16 grams in my car.
I had a 20 joints I had.
We're going to have a little part in
your and was on the way down and they do
a lot of inspection.
Just randomly.
They walk around and in Japan it's kind
of unconstitutional where they don't
need a reason to search you.
They'll come right up to your car and
say I want chicken your car.
And it's like I was stone and I had a
had a joint.
I mean a real short on the dashboard and
you know when you're still in you think
you're getting sneaky with it.
It's like so bad.
It's like Ah,
what?
What roads?
And I'm putting in my pocket and they're
following me the whole time they send
their parking.
I'm like to put my phone in the pocket,
pull it behind my phone and said
nothing.
Parking.
This is behind your phone though.
So what,
how,
like what is it like?
Is it like being caught with cocaine or
heroin?
Drugs that drug in Japan yet?
So it doesn't matter.
It doesn't matter.
Yeah.
So I,
um,
I was facing some bad time,
you know,
because uh,
I was a famous figure and they wanted to
make an example of me.
So.
Wow,
what was the worst case scenario?
A,
I think it was five years.
Oh fuck.
Yeah.
So I was facing that.
Um,
it all dependent on what came up in my
house and my gym when they did the
search next day.
Wow.
And what came up?
Nothing.
Nothing came up.
So that saved you?
Yeah,
well I was kind of baffled.
Someone stole my fucking weed,
thinking what it was.
Then the,
the interrogation came to finding out
where I got my stuff.
Yeah.
And so when in Japan,
if you throw everything to a foreign
person deal drop,
they won't want to go fight someone in
America.
I told them it was a student from Guam.
They asked me for her name and I said
Tony,
I knew like three tonys in Guam,
so keep it real tony.
And,
and we had like two days of questioning.
I mean he talking interrogation for like
eight hours straight,
just interrogation and lay like the
third day they just so happened,
caught me off guard man.
And they asked me what's Tony's last
name and this fricken ridiculous.
The first name that popped in my head
was Montana.
What?
I said,
so what?
I said Montana.
No,
fuck.
If these guys watched scarf I don't see,
I'm screwed.
You know what?
Because they'll start the integration
all over if I get caught in the lie.
Right,
right,
right.
So he just,
I saw him write it down in Japanese,
Montana and then he just jotted down and
I was like,
scarface get translated into Japanese.
Not that popular.
I don't think it's that popular there.
Yeah.
That's fucking hilarious.
Tony Montana gave me my marijuana.
You know,
how long was where it's worth the trip.
No.
How long was your,
how long was the old deal from getting
arrested to getting cleared?
Twenty eight days,
which isn't a big deal if you know it's
going to be 28 days when you're sitting
in there and you don't know what's gonna
Happen to you and you don't know what's
going on in the outside world because
you're shut off and you're wondering if
you're going to spend five years.
It's Kinda a 20 days is a long,
28 days.
So you went from there and you said,
fuck it,
I'm going to.
I'm going to take on another fight.
I went in there and it was good for me
actually.
I mean I always think back and think,
okay,
I should have done this.
I should've done this.
If I hadn't put the roast,
Jeanette and I keep thinking that and I
catch my son thing.
Wait a minute.
This is a probably one of the best
things that happened to you because the
big biggest thing that happened to me in
that was I a,
I learned how important my freedom was.
I mean,
everyone takes it for granted every day.
Wake up,
but what are you going to do today on
this?
Like shit they got nothing to do is for
overcast the Shitty Day.
What am going to do so hot damn is.
This is a shitty day,
you know,
but man,
just effect that you can choose to stay
at home,
you can choose to eat McDonald's or you
can choose to just hang out or you can
choose to be bored,
you know,
freedom.
That freedom is awesome.
So it was something that really made me
realize that how important freedom was.
Yeah.
A lot of people take it for granted.
You know,
you dealing with a situation like that,
especially over something like we'd
where it's so nonsensical and crazy,
they could take away your freedom for
fucking years.
Yeah.
The thing about that is served the time.
Went to the court.
We got three years probation where I
couldn't leave Japan for three years.
I didn't even get to go to my
grandmother's funeral and I figured,
okay,
I gotta I gotTa be good these three
years and then we'll start up again and
then next thing I know I get a letter
from the immigration telling me that I,
I just lost my green card because of
infringement and I got to leave Japan.
Whoa.
And I'm like,
Whoa,
wait a minute.
I've been here for 20 years.
My whole life is here,
a boiler house there.
I got GMCR,
I can't leave Japan.
So I called them up and they had this
like this road answer.
Okay,
if you're contesting it,
we're going to start an investigation.
You have to come down to immigration
center and Blah Blah,
blah.
Went down,
took a,
it was an eight month investigation.
I mean it was ridiculous.
I mean to go down there numerous times
and just like all day interrogations and
they would start from the beginning,
the name of your mom and dad,
what do they do?
And really flipped the fuck.
Does that have to do anything?
You know?
And I'm just going along with the role
and it's like the next week I go in for
another interrogation to start all over
again to a whole new investigator.
I'm like,
what the fuck's going on?
I just told the other guy,
you know,
and it got to a point,
it was so bad that I got so frustrated
with her as much as I needed to be in
Japan.
I looked at the guy said,
you know what,
I love Japan.
I made this place my home and if fucking
dependence and wanted me,
I don't want to fucking be here.
I told him straight up like that.
And I was like,
I said,
Oh shit,
I just screwed myself now.
But I thought,
you know,
that's so frustrating.
I can,
you know,
I served my time,
man and I'm,
and I'm trying to do,
I'm doing good things for Japan,
you know?
And you guys going to try and kick me
out if you guys don't want me,
you know what?
I don't want to fucking beer for them.
They don't want me here.
You know?
So you know,
the interrogation went on and there was
one guy that was a phantom way when he
was intimidating me and then he,
he,
he kinda did something illegal where he,
he told me that the,
between these two red marker said
linking those two papers.
She said he flipped it open.
He said this is all petitions coming in
for you not to get kicked out of Japan.
And I saw the papers like this thick.
I was like,
Oh shit,
that's a lot.
He said,
yeah,
you got like $4,000
already.
And the petition,
Japan isn't just names,
you got to live your name,
your phone number,
your address and everything you see
here.
It's not a bullshit where you can just
get people to sign their names,
just write some.
So they're writing this 4,000
and every time we get an integration I
see that the,
that between those two red mark is
getting thicker and thicker and I come
to find at the end it came out to be
9,008
months.
9,000
people sent in that they don't want me
to keep the Japan and immigration is
there to protect Japan from dangerous
so-called dangerous foreigners.
So when they're,
there are people that they're supposed
to be protecting is sending you 9,000
letters saying they don't want this guy
kicked out.
So that was the overwhelming thing that
I could have been the board idea.
How much press are you getting over
there because of all the stuff you're
doing for Fukushima victims?
Well,
my,
my movement is Shima isn't like there's
a lot of celebrities that went up there
just once and had a big media thing and
it was just for like,
hey look,
look what I'm doing.
But nod people would even know I'm going
up on the 24th.
The day after I get back from here,
I'm driving straight to Fukushima.
When Nolan radiation like there,
uh,
the.
I went into the,
um,
into the zone twice or three times.
And the zone,
the zone is,
it's from the,
where the plants blew up.
It's like a 20 kilometer zone where the
radiation is actually pretty high,
although 30 kilometers salt.
Wow.
But the town that I'm visiting,
nurses or visiting,
the temporary housing is about 80
kilometers away,
so the radiation's a little higher than
usual,
but it's,
if I'm not living there,
it's not a big deal.
Chuck,
if you want I can take him.
I'll take him home because I know you
wanted to get out of here.
Say Goodbye to the people.
I know you got your kids at home.
Thanks for coming by.
Brother are very good.
Ceos are having anytime,
anytime.
Come on back.
Mrs.
Chuck Odell.
Take care.
She's crashed out.
She's out there on the couch.
Yeah.
Grab some coconut waters.
So when you,
when you go in there,
you bring in a geiger counter.
Like how,
how do you know?
Like what your.
I have a corner and a dusty man.
We'll get you out.
Go see you later man.
Thanks man.
Yeah,
you have both a geiger counter.
What's the other thing that Dr Peter,
what's a docile guy?
Cremator guyer.
Connor.
Co Counsel.
Exactly what you're getting at that
moment.
And the dosimeter it takes accumulation
of which your body is taking him.
Wow.
Yeah.
So,
um,
take iodine.
Yeah,
we take that stone tablets.
Yeah.
Supposedly a protects your thyroid.
Yeah,
just the steroids.
So.
But I mean for your blood chemistry to
change,
you have to take in 65,000
microsieverts and it depends on the wind
and depends on how long you're in the
hot spots.
The first time I went in I took in a
25,000,
which is pretty bad because you're
talking a yearly count.
You only want $65,000
after 65,000
and it changes your blood chemistry
which could cause cancer.
Let me.
Yeah,
so then the second time I went and.
How's this?
I got 19 microsieverts as much as you
get flying from a trip from Hawaii to
New York.
Yeah,
I actually did that.
I brought the dusty meter and in the
plane.
The plane.
Yeah.
That's a lot of things that people don't
realize.
Like you get way more radiation from the
plane that you do from those radar
detectors.
There are those metal detectors rather
when you going through the airport and
everybody's terrified of those.
Yeah.
You just the plane itself probably
sitting in radiation right now with
other electrical equipment.
I mean that's what people don't realize
right now that there's radiation all
over.
I mean the sun gives us radiation when
it hits the concrete and it bounces back
off.
It's giving off radiation.
You're getting ration everything you do.
I mean,
you know,
going into Fukushima that second time
when I got only 19 microsieverts,
it's like getting a,
getting a chest extra now.
Why was it less than.
Because you spent less time where you
want radiation is actually particles of
dust.
Yeah,
and it depends on if it rained,
if turns,
when it rains,
it drains,
it cumulates in a certain area.
It depends if you're in that area.
I mean I can stay right here and see
zero in the Gardner Corner and walk 10
feet and get to 100.
Yeah.
It's like the craziest thing.
You don't feel it.
You don't see it,
you don't smell it,
you don't feel nothing.
I mean,
it's ridiculously scary
and the closer to the ground,
the higher the reading.
Right?
I watched a video where a guy took a
geiger counter and was showing the air
and anyone else.
Yeah,
into the ground,
stuck on the surfaces even could be on
glass,
glass.
There's some radiation that gallon glass
and you can't even wash it off.
Developer into glass.
How do you look at nuclear power now?
Do you look at it completely different
after you've seen that?
It's a hard situation because we don't
Nikila power.
Japan wouldn't be able to run or will be
paying out of our,
our asses in electrical bills.
I mean,
it's literally can't run without looking
at your car.
I mean,
it's important and I don't know,
you know,
it's a hard thing men,
because an incident like this,
you know,
where um,
the tsunamis come in and I mean,
something like that hasn't happened in
100 years in Japan.
So I mean she's,
it's amazing,
but 100 years ain't shit.
When you think about the geography and
think about this,
the surface of the earth 100 years is
barely a blink of the night.
That's what we,
we,
we're so used to what we've seen so far
in our lifetime when we take that as
like,
oh,
well this is our point of reference,
this is what we know.
Don't worry about it.
It's not going to happen.
It hasn't happened in 100 years.
That's nothing.
That doesn't mean anything.
A lot of shit can happen.
I mean,
Japan has active volcanoes,
right?
There's a lot of shit that can go on
global like eight or nine times a day.
Man in Japan if we're constantly getting
earthquakes.
But you love it anyway.
Well,
I love the people and I love.
I love what I was established there.
I've been there for 22 years.
You know how many gyms you have there?
I have A.
I have only one gym.
No,
I actually closed two of them.
Um,
I have a lot of gyms in Guam.
I have,
I have a following there that I a big
following.
That's like family.
I mean got brothers out there to die,
die for tomorrow,
you know?
So it's something that a lot of them
can't leave your pants
now when you,
when you first moved there,
you moved there for racquetball in one
year?
Uh,
it was in 1994.
Wow.
Yeah.
We 22 years.
Let's calculate that.
Yeah,
it was way back.
I fought in 1995.
So it was four years before this.
In 1991.
Actually.
Nineteen 90.
I think I moved there.
Wow.
Yeah.
So it was for record.
What tournament did you speak Japanese
fluently before?
Wow.
I had to learn it with flashcards.
So Holy Shit.
So in writing and everything and oh,
the writing the Kanji,
I understand it a little bit but it's
not necessary in my life.
So I've been learned it.
Yeah.
I mean I teach fighters.
I like shit whenever I did anything I
thought that I don't read the newspaper.
You can't.
There's an English newspaper.
So I read that I'm the most conject can
write is my name.
My address,
Huh?
Yeah.
I can read more than I can.
Right.
Because a whole different thing to be
able to read it into actually have to
write it.
So when you learn how to speak it,
you just learn by talking to people.
I just learned flashcards and lists,
learn vocabulary just slammed as much
figure that I thought I would using as
far as the particles,
I just let it flow.
Wow.
So speaking pretty much just vocabulary.
When you communicate in Japan now,
did they know it's like,
you know,
you hear like Boron Talk English and he
has a Kazakhstan
accent.
Did they hear an American accent for
your Japanese?
Really?
I mean if you hear me treat shopper
needs,
you probably think I'm fluent but
considering our bidding for 20 years,
I suck really.
I'm a fluent as far as I can
communicate.
I have no problem communicating and I
never misunderstanding anything is
pretty understanding everything.
But it's not fluent.
How much of your communicating over
there as English speaking?
Almost zero.
It's all Japanese.
Wow.
How many different fighters are you
working with,
Don?
I know you were working with kids for
awhile.
He's still working with him.
No,
no,
no.
We had a falling on with.
Yeah,
his,
his idea of loyalty is a whole different
thing.
I mean,
he was a super fucking talented guy,
you know that kid,
man,
he's,
he's a super athlete and all he needed
was something behind him that he felt
confident with where he would have his
confidence when he has.
When a kid has his head on,
right?
Man,
nobody can beat him,
but that guy,
they kind of can be broken.
Man.
I seen him break so many times and he
needs that something behind him that
gives him that little extra confidence
that pushes them past that barrier,
but he doesn't have it.
No ma'am.
This superbad because when in his prime
he was a,
just a stunning athlete when were
talking about a guy who entered into a
kickboxing bow with Masato and dropped
him when he was a wrestler essentially,
you know,
and he's fighting one against one of the
best Japanese kickboxers of all times.
He was there the whole time when he
first came in from wrestling.
I mean,
he's defending Jujitsu moves just being
a restaurant,
not even understanding.
It's just on a natural instinct,
which you don't see much in wrestling.
And arresting has this bad habits of
stretching their arms all using their
arms and getting locked up a lot.
But he was just sobbing,
was defending from the arm bars,
took him to Thailand and he started
picking on the standing right away.
I mean the guy was natural.
It was a confidence thing and kid.
I mean,
I still think he has it today,
but he just doesn't have that.
That confidence.
Yeah.
When he first fought in the UFC against
a kid,
Yamamoto and then against or against a
brother,
Demetrius Johnson.
And then against Vaughn Lee.
I was telling everybody,
I was like,
man,
wait till you see this guy.
But then by the time he got into the
UFC,
he had already lost some of his
momentum.
Lost some of its fire.
Yeah.
You know the fire that he had when he
knocked out Hoya,
Gracie or the father that he had when he
was in his fucking shit.
Oh Man.
He was a bad motherfucker when he was in
his prime was like,
you know,
he,
he was just a freak.
Just a real unusual athlete.
And I feel I know what's missing in
them,
you know what I mean?
If I went and started training with
them,
I could get right back.
I'd be there,
I can get them right back to what he
was.
But I don't want to deal with the father
and I don't want to be with the loyalty
issues that he runs a shall issue.
What is the state of Japanese MMA now?
It was gigantic for awhile when Soccer
Rabo was big.
When you were huge.
When pride was filling 90,000
seat arenas.
Huge.
It was like nothing else.
So like I experienced 60,000
at Rogers in Canada when George St
Pierre fought jake shields.
I couldn't imagine 30 more thousand
people there.
But you were there for that.
It was awesome.
I mean if that was a 10 and before we
may actually came out when they were
only had pancreas and that was a one.
It said like a Ford.
Right now what happened is Yakuza
involvement.
I mean,
the thing that people don't realize is
in Japan,
everything is Ya'lls involvement.
Every big company,
every big promotion shooto chose to say
that.
Didn't ever get a yuck his involvement,
but they're there.
They're backed Subito shoe,
which is the second largest group of
Japan,
you know,
so everyone has yakuza connections to
any big Coca Cola company.
Johnson and Johnson.
Any company has yet because the
connections.
Wow.
But it's not public.
So say if Coca Cola goes over there and
they open up a plant in Japan,
they must go through the Yakuza.
They will have that connections.
Yes,
definitely.
How do they negotiate that?
Well,
it's really easy.
It's,
it's,
it's a turf thing.
It's a.
If you know somebody,
it's,
it's a percentage of pay.
It's pretty given thing.
It's almost like taxes.
Wow.
Yeah.
Pink accepted,
accepted,
accepted.
That's why it's.
It's funny how when it became public,
everyone,
it got really bad because it's a,
it's a weird thing is accepted,
but it's frowned upon.
It's something that they know they need
to be a part of in society,
but they don't want to make it public
because the Oculus has,
does have a bad name.
That was the only place where I've ever
been with a.
asked me to cover up my tattoos.
It was weird,
that's why I try to keep them out
from my sleep so it comes up from here,
but after that I stopped because I don't
want to walk around and you know,
be kicked out of places,
you know,
you just got denied to go in a hotel
like last week when I was in Japan.
Really?
Yeah.
Because of my tattoos
with the neck.
Is that what it is?
Yeah,
they saw the Hoodie.
It covers it up.
It helps me.
Yeah.
I got A.
I got kicked out of a gym.
They made me go put a long sleeve shirt
on the gyms.
Big Gyms at Gold's gym on the chair.
That's crazy.
Yeah.
What is it represented?
Japanese.
It
represents the underworld.
Gangsters and you've got to figure when
you have a gang,
there's two or three top men.
Those men are awesome people and then
you got the rest of the hundreds and
thousands that are punks and that's the
ones that you see.
So basically a gangster,
someone with tattoos which equals Yakuza
would mean trouble and they would.
If you go into sports gym and you're
working out next to a guy and you know
you're,
you're working on say you take his
weights by oxen casino in the middle of
the set and if you're doing it to
someone that's a normal person,
he'll just say,
hey,
I was using those ways.
Oh sorry.
Okay,
well it might be different for the
Yakuza and people would rather not work
out in the area if there's a guy working
on there.
So it's a bad rap.
I mean it's justifiable though.
I can that the
UFC,
when they went in and bought pride,
it's kind of a crazy story,
but they paid $65,
million dollars.
They bought pride and they thought,
you know,
hey,
we're going to run pride as well as the
UFC the same way they did with
strikeforce when they bought
strikeforce.
They kept strikeforce going for years.
They thought they were going to do that,
but meanwhile it turned out all of their
contracts are illegal.
They really didn't have anybody under
contract.
They spent $65 million in.
All they really got was a video library
and then while they had offices in Japan
and they were hiring these people and
painful and they were starting up dream,
they were starting up their own
organization,
organizing everything and yeah.
And then,
you know,
the UFC,
it took years before they could come
back and do it.
UFC there they took,
it took a long time.
Dana was getting like some like,
underworld threats and you know,
running.
Yeah,
that's,
that's what I heard.
I sorry I sent an email on that because
if anything I have a lot of pulling that
side and I told him that if you have any
problems with that I can help you.
What would he have to do?
Come to you and then you go to
directed in that world.
So,
um,
I could,
I,
if I don't know the person directly,
I have guys at home.
So if he had any type of problem,
I still,
it still stands today.
If Dana has any type of underworld
problems there,
if he calls me,
I take care of it for them.
It's interesting that there's such an
underworld presence in Japan because it
seems so safe when you're there.
Everything is so.
People are so polite and you don't see
violence.
You don't see like you see drunk people
walking into the street and no one hurts
them.
Everything.
Everyone's fine.
Walk down dark lanes and this.
Okay.
Yeah.
It's a strange sort of contrast.
It's almost like you just have bad
areas.
They can change it.
They have over 300 yards.
Was offices there?
Roppongi only has three.
Wow.
Yeah.
So you got,
these are districts that their
accumulated in.
They have offices,
they have offices.
The Mafia doesn't El Office.
See that's the thing for
me,
I guess I grew up in America.
So for me the mafia just scares me way
more.
I mean,
I,
I have this image that you screw it,
the mafia,
you better change your name,
you were to move and you better hide who
your family is and you better get the
hell out of just disappear.
But when you get in trouble with the
Yakuza um,
I've been in trouble with them before
and it's,
it's,
it's like you can kind of pretty much
deal with them the way you want to deal
with them,
you know,
it depends on how much you're willing to
sacrifice and for what was your issue
with them?
Um,
there was a wonder kid,
um,
when,
when I,
this guy,
this young guy who wanted to open up a
gym and I agreed to open up a gym with
him called purebred Tokyo killer bee and
I just told them that only thing you
have to do is you have to hire two of my
fighters so they can make a living
through fighting.
And I wanted to help them out.
I want no money.
He can use my name or my gym,
but you have to hire my two fighters.
He,
they acquired kid and they're hardwired
and bowl and those are the fighters and
everything was good.
And what happened was kids started,
I guess from the influence of his
father.
He started being,
the loyalty issue in him was getting was
wavering where he wasn't telling me
stuff,
he was hiding stuff.
He's lying to me and then I put that was
the guy in charge of them that ran the
gym.
So I told him,
I called him and say,
what?
What's going on man?
You gotta take care of it because I'll
take care of her.
I take care of.
He's told me that and it got to a point
he didn't take care of it.
So I called him and I was pissed 30 by
now and I called him and said,
you know what?
Call me.
He avoided my calls for three days,
so three,
three,
three weeks.
And I'm sitting there,
this guy to running from me.
I'm thinking this is ridiculous.
So the,
okay,
this guy's running from me,
I'm not going to look for them.
I'm going to.
He's going to pop up is these guys had
charter to run their pop up all the
time,
you know.
So I'm sitting there watching the Uno
kid flight and kid wins a fight and this
guy's in the ring jumping and hug him.
And theme as a mother fucker.
This is hiding from me.
He's on national TV hugging me saying
Hansen,
I'm here.
So I guess is it.
So I called my students until the final
where the after party is adulthood after
part now is literally going to walk in
there and grab that guy with the hair
and pull them out with party.
But my students felt he was going to be
a problem,
is going to be too much commotion.
Cops are going to be called.
So they decide to get them in.
They brought them up and brought him to
the park and pretty much beat him for
like 20 minutes,
which is something he shouldn't do in
Japan because in the Yakuza world they
work by face.
They work by being tough,
being scary to collect money and stuff.
And if you've got all got a black guy
and bruises on her face is kind of goes
against the fact that they're tough
people,
you know?
So I beat him up pretty bad and I did.
But see,
the thing is I never did pick on anyone.
I never did do anything without a
reason.
And I believe that I would die for my
beliefs tomorrow and I believed that I
was right and this guy really deserved
that shit.
So if they didn't like it,
if the top guys didn't like it,
then they can.
They know where to find me.
And so what happened was it was going on
for 20 minutes and when I went down I
let people in,
some people,
all my friends know and they're all
worried.
So they made calls and we had two other
Yakuza guys come down to the scene to
try and stop me,
to kind of get in between,
not stop me physically but to,
to,
to ask for forgiveness for this guy.
And they're kind of like bawling in the
middle of me and the guy that I'm
getting around and just giving them wax
at a time.
And when he,
if he were to fall from a hit,
I'd grab them and standing right back
up.
Oh.
So yeah.
So it's kind of getting really.
He was all bloody.
And then these guys are kind of my
friends too.
So they,
they weren't going to get involved with.
They're trying to stop me from going too
far and when we,
there's this old lady,
you know how you have the old ladies in
the neighborhood that don't give a fuck
who you are.
She,
this lady comes on and starts screaming
at us that it gets on the lady and I
say,
no,
I don't do that man.
Let's go.
So he moved over to the next part and as
you're moving on with the next part,
like three African monkeys disguise
higher ups to find out what's happening
and come out and they're walking up like
these,
you know,
like the movies they walking I,
it was funny because I call them monkeys
because they're walking through bushes
and the trees and they came out and
saying,
Oh shit,
these are the guys,
the hothead guys.
And they came up to me and they're
screaming and Japanese to me,
Oh you were going to hurt you and
because you heard our brother and then
some of my guys came and held him back
and I was like,
okay,
wait a minute.
If it's gonna happen is gonna happen
now.
So I told my guys,
let him go.
I said,
I just want to say one thing to you
guys,
and the,
the,
they came up and they're all there,
you know,
they got this stance and they're all mad
at me and looking at me and I'm looking
to see.
I got one thing to do.
If I got one thing to say,
if I say you don't like it,
we can have it all.
I said,
I'm ready to die tonight.
And then this guy goes,
okay.
So I tell them,
okay,
if someone fucked you over,
I said,
you want to punish them?
Wouldn't that be fair?
He goes,
yes,
but look what you did to him.
Look at him.
The kiddies,
all blood.
He's standing here all bloody.
And I said,
well,
you know what,
let's put it this way.
I'll just ask you one question if flying
to kill him with my hands,
how fast you think I could do it?
He said,
probably five minutes within five
minutes.
I said,
hell,
within two minutes I killed that fucker.
And he goes,
yeah,
but what does that mean?
And I said,
well,
I human hitting him for 20 minutes.
I said,
dude,
this is,
this is like 10 percent of what I could
do.
And I said,
don't you agree for you what you.
If you had somebody fuck you over and
you decide to just do 10 percent out of
respect to the people behind him,
wouldn't you think that's fair?
And they guy just changed straight up.
Bill stopped and he said,
you're right man.
Thank you.
Wow.
That doesn't fly in America.
That's interesting.
Interesting Code.
The believe in the underworld side is
there's two sides of the fences,
the legal side of the illegal side,
the legitimate site,
and you are never,
ever,
if you're in the illegitimate cider,
have a legitimate problem.
You are never ever allowed to go to the
other site to get help you.
If you're going gonna stay,
you're going to get other guys to help
you with this site and retaliate,
that's fine.
But if you ever go to authorities and
you lose face and you can never can
never work in that world again.
So
wow.
So you have to deal with things on your
own
that,
yeah,
you pretty much if,
if you,
if you're someone from the outside and
you're like a regular businessman and
these guys come and bother you,
the best thing to do is go to the
authorities because of the,
the police are just waiting to grab the
buses.
So He's psycho role.
It's like Kryptonite to the adolescence.
If you go say you're going to the police
still back off.
But if I,
I live my life in that side pretty much,
you know what I mean?
A lot of my friends are part of those
groups and a lot of my beliefs run
really deep with their beliefs.
You know,
the.
I mean,
see,
the thing is,
is you,
you and you hear about the Yakuza they
get a bad rap because you talk about
child pornography,
drugs,
you know,
extortion.
Um,
what is that?
Uh,
when they,
when they steal money from people,
you know,
but the thing that they don't see that's
uh,
that's all the things in the media,
but the things that they don't see,
which I feel is a really unfortunate.
The honor and the loyalty they have for
each other and that's where me and then
click really well,
you know,
I mean they will die for anyone that
tomorrow they'll go to jail for 10 years
for their boss tomorrow if they have to.
I mean,
you don't see that type of loyalty
around all these,
you know,
non America and I love that.
I think that loyalty,
you know,
and they.
And that's,
I think that's why they respect me so
much as you.
I will die for my values.
I'll die for my people that are close to
me.
It's just such an unbelievably
fascinating culture.
How different Japan is in so many ways.
It could be.
There's big gaps in it.
Yeah,
it's crazy.
It's really,
really,
really fascinating stuff.
It's just that all these different
cultures evolve independently,
that the Japanese culture evolved
independently from the American culture
independently from the European culture
and it's so different.
Yeah,
it is all you think all the places are
different,
man.
It's hard to really move into a
different country and run yourself in
the way that you learned in another
country because it's,
you know,
when enrollment is,
what do you think about the state of
Japanese mma right now because it's kind
of in a transitionary period if one at
one point in time it was gigantic and
you say Yakuza involvement is why
people,
corporate sponsors backed out and then
they lost a lot of viewership.
But man,
it was jet not that long ago that they
were selling out these gigantic places.
What,
what's going on right now or
right now?
I'm,
like I said,
it's under number four right now.
Just people that are real hesitant.
They're not many sponsors that want to
put money into it.
Um,
on the flip side,
the big things that's happening is
gangster events where they allow
gangsters to fight in the ring.
And yeah,
it's crazy,
dude.
It's like I attended all of those.
I'm like a guest and most of them they
pay me to just to be there and to judge
sometimes to make a speech in that ring.
Maybe in the beginning because I'm so
respected in that world that to have me
there,
a lot of these gangsters toned down,
you know,
when they want to riot,
they don't riot,
you know,
I mean you go to the event and it's not
unusual to see a picture of two stick
figures fighting and has a big
excellent.
So dark.
Don't fight.
Isn't that given?
You've never seen any signs of the UFC
saying please don't fight in the
audience is like,
it's already given this.
Not something you should do,
but yeah,
so that's a big thing right now,
but it's good because the gangster
events,
actually they,
they,
they have headbutts,
they have elbow striking.
You can split Stom,
you can need the groin,
you can do whatever.
Pretty much they have to on one.
They have to one tool.
Really.
It's crazy though.
How often do they have these funds on
the bowl?
Once a month now there's some shit.
Yeah,
and it's like these guys,
it's become,
it's a good trend because it's become
where these guys just came off the
streets singing.
They're tough gassing on in one minute
from these guys.
Actually spending time in the gym though
and being off the street.
So it's a good movement.
A lot of.
There's about three or four gangsters
already.
Now this,
she made their pro debut in deep.
Wow.
These guys are actually gonna run gangs
and start selling drugs and doing
illegal activity.
They're not training and having a future
in fighting,
which is awesome.
As far as the legitimate side of mma,
I,
I see it.
I can see it picking up again and it's
all due to the UFC.
And the UFC has done a couple of events
there now in the last one they did that
when I went to that,
it was huge.
Man,
that's so big.
I mean,
as much as the Japanese fans are kind of
losing hope in Japanese mma because a
lot of productions were folding.
Um,
when the,
when we went to,
when I went to the USC,
uh,
I felt that that energy again,
when I was fighting in pride,
that energy that they had in the
audience and especially when rampage
came out with the pride music,
it gave me goosebumps because when he
came out to that,
I looked around the arena and I was
like,
damn,
this is a psycho pride.
This is a,
this is a pride.
And it,
I,
it's the first time since that big
incident with the Yakuza will vomit and
pride that I've actually seen that
again.
It,
it was surreal to me actually.
And I was like,
damn,
this is gonna.
This is going to be the ticket back.
Is the UFC coming to Japan?
If the UFC did an ultimate fighter in
Japan and Japanese version of it,
would you be interested in coaching?
Oh yeah.
Oh definitely.
Yeah.
I would love to.
That would be perfect.
You'd be,
you would really be perfect for
something like,
yeah,
I would love that.
You know,
I hope they do it because you know,
they're starting to do that in other
countries.
Now.
You saw they did in Australia,
smashes the Brazilian show mean it's a
natural for it eventually to go to
Japan.
Right?
Yeah.
It's probably inevitable.
Yeah,
someday.
Wow.
So as far as like Japanese,
like standouts,
obviously probably one of the bigger
guys right now.
Right.
And how,
what?
Who were the other guys that are coming
up that you see?
I like Ricky Fukuda bias.
Good.
I used to train with them so I'm a
little biased in that very good
wrestling and the guy's still young.
He's a real hungry.
I think he just needs someone in the
corner to keep that killer instinct
going because he's such.
Yeah.
And he's such a nice guy.
I mean it's,
you got to convince this guy to,
this guy is going to try and hurt you.
Got To hurt him first,
you know,
so he has that little titty beers
instead of him that has got to be
ignited the gotta get get,
get that on and get the grizzly on.
You know?
So yeah,
he's going to be a good fighter.
What about a hot so hot.
So He.
Okay.
Yeah.
He's.
He's already good.
Very good.
Yeah,
he's awesome.
I thought it will be call.
It's going to do better too.
Yeah.
One guy was some tough breaks.
Yeah,
he had some bad calls,
but he,
he actually,
the last one he actually did really
loose and it was a week I was going to
do something.
Well,
it's also,
oh my God,
I was at the tail end of a long career.
Yeah,
that's true.
How many years do you think our guy can
compete at a fate or level four?
I mean,
there's only a certain amount of years
where your body can kind of red line at
those high and
keep it going when you were like top
form.
It'll all depend on the fighter.
I believe.
Like some,
like afraid to like me.
I think maybe five,
six years of the fighter that goes in
there training with everything he has
and,
and willing to die in the ring.
I mean not being not accepting the fact
that my,
but fighting with the will to die.
It's a whole different thing,
but then you've got another fight like
Sakuraba schools in there and takes a
fight in two days and it's just having
fun and does this smoke entrance coming
in with this riding a scooter and you
know,
actually literally having fun in the
fight,
you know,
it's first can go on forever,
you know?
Yeah.
Sakharova man,
that guy is.
Had some incredible finding.
That guy's got to retire though.
He's going to eat too much.
Hits the Melvin manhoef fight was
fucking scary when Melvin manhoef was
beating on him.
He like,
man,
he doesn't need that at this stage in
his life.
He's done so much for the sport.
I mean,
they think he should.
You know,
you don't want to do another mom and
Alia.
Yeah.
There's been so many.
This has been so many beat downs and
he's had like in the later stages of his
career,
you got to really look at a guy like
that,
like mail,
but its ability to absorb punishment.
It's fucking shocking.
Yeah.
It's unbelievable,
man.
The one that freaked me out was the,
um,
the Nino,
El Nino and that it was weird.
It's not the same stuff.
I think he's been taking too much hits.
Yeah.
Well,
there's no question.
Yeah,
I mean,
you,
you were honest about yourself.
You're like five or six years.
Your styles,
so fucking aggressive and wild.
It's
like,
well,
I write,
I write letters to everyone that's close
to me before every fight.
Real.
Yeah.
And every time I come back to life in
the fight,
I burned them all.
Wow.
So literally I'm training the three
months that I'm training for a fight.
I'm literally training not to die.
And if you knew there was a possibly
you're going to die in this search area.
Most people would avoid it,
but we have to do.
I have to walk there on my own will and
the stress level for me.
I mean,
I wish I could just take it later and
say it's a sport.
I mean I have to like play it,
you know,
like I had you ever heard the tenacious
d song?
Fuck me gently.
The girl,
no girl fight.
If you look at the girl ring entrance
after the ranch,
I put on headphones.
That's the song that was playing because
it's like a joke song.
It's so it makes it license my,
my,
like you,
you're not going to die today.
You know,
you,
there's going to be tomorrow.
I go into fights if it's the fights on
the 19th and someone asked me on the
21st I got a party,
can you come?
I'm,
I'm literally feeling inside men.
If I am at that party,
I'm super happy because that means I'm
still.
I know I'm really,
really preparing for,
for death that day.
You know?
And for me it's so stressful man.
I mean I actually didn't feel I could do
it anymore.
I mean every time I fought after I
fought win or lose,
I always felt like shit nice to over.
I'm alive because I was willing to die
in the fight,
you know?
So it's a little bit too intense for me,
I mean,
what was the closest you think you came
to New York?
Probably eager.
That was a crazy.
And that's actually the fight where I,
I,
I thought that I should retire because,
not because of the beating,
but because I didn't think there was
anything else in mma that would ever
teach me to be a stronger man.
I am.
I didn't once feel that I wanted to quit
or give up.
I never contemplated giving up at all.
Not once.
And I mean I got,
I had a broken finger out,
a broken jaw.
I had um,
a swollen brain prefer to your drum.
And apparently my liver count was like
2000 times to normal person.
You had a swollen,
swollen brain.
Yeah.
So they hospitalized me for the first
four days because they want it to cat
scan my brain every day because when
the,
when the swelling's impacting the veins,
if tears bleeding,
you can't tell.
And when the brain goes back to its size
and its not compacted anymore,
if there's bleeding,
that's when you can tell the bleeding.
So they were worried that my brain might
be bleeding.
There might be bleeding in the brain.
Yeah.
Well,
so what,
while this is all going on,
how are you feeling?
I feel fine really well.
Well,
I kid.
The thing is is that when,
if you watch the video of the fight,
when it was done,
I remember laying down thinking,
holy shit,
got over it.
Got To the first unit of the big 10
minute Raul,
you know,
say,
look,
you got best wrong second line.
I know I cut him something.
We're going to stand good.
Start standing again almost on total toy
and I'm going to open that cut up.
And I remember Egan leaning over to me
and looking at me and say,
I'm going to stop the fight.
And I was like,
Whoa,
no,
you're not sending the fight and we have
a rule that you don't throw a towel,
you know the tower that we have in the
ring.
And she's always throw it there into the
fancy.
I think it was that bow quite throw it
off.
And when Egan told me that,
I said,
shit,
I wanted to lay down at least seven,
another,
maybe 10 seconds to kind of recollect
and everything.
And he said that.
I said,
Oh shit,
I got to get up because Egan's going to
stop the fight.
So I got.
I started getting up and I remember
getting up and walking to the corner,
but my legs were under me and I was,
it was the weirdest feeling because I
felt like my below my waist was a whole
different machine.
I mean,
I was dragging on me.
I was seeing shit my legs.
And then when I sat down in a corner,
when you see the video,
I mean everyone says,
you know that I'm screaming.
No,
no,
because this guy's trying to stop the
fight.
But we got two minutes between rounds
and that he comes in 10 seconds after I
sit down and sing,
looking at me.
Sagamore stopped the fight and I didn't
realize how bad I looked,
you know,
so I was saying,
no,
no.
I'm thinking,
no,
meaning that there's two more minutes,
give me two more minutes.
Checked me after the two minutes and
then we give your assessment of them.
And I'm screaming.
No,
no,
no.
And the decor,
the fight,
you know,
and it happened to happen was I,
I had a preferred your gentleman a lost
my balance.
So basically I couldn't if,
unless I had like two days or three days
between their own,
I probably couldn't have done the secure
on anyway.
So I didn't know that.
But the thing that made me really happy
about that is when I saw the video on
the fight,
I,
my,
my heart and my spirit didn't die,
you know,
as much as punishments I was taking.
It was never an issue,
which,
which really made me realize that if I
take any more than a beating down,
I'll probably die everything to myself
that,
you know,
in mma,
that as far as the test in my heart and
tests as strong as a man is probably not
going to go any further than that.
So you were thinking that you should
retire because you proved to yourself
that you are willing to die literally.
Yeah.
And I,
you know,
I already knew that wasn't going to be
the best in the world.
I wasn't interested in grabbing a pride
belt.
And I basically was fighting,
if you look at all my fights when I took
fights,
it was always when they were at the top
of their game,
I took a heath hearing when he just beat
Erickson,
took no girl when he was a top of the
world.
I took a marker when he was still
considered a specimen,
you know.
So all of these fights that I took was
when people are at the top of your game.
And I took those fights,
not because I thought I could win.
I thought that there was the fights that
I.
There's no way I could win.
That's the reason why I took those sites
because I thought I was going to put
myself in somewhere.
That was gonna test my heart.
You went to sleep when the Nogueira
fire?
Yes.
You got caught in a triangle and you
didn't tap.
Yeah,
I do see,
the thing is,
is a thing that people always ask me,
you know,
they think that not tapping is about
being tough and being like macho and
being someone who kind of feel pain,
you know,
but the,
the,
the truth of the matter is I have,
I have this saying that always referred
to as a strong man,
feels no pain,
but a man with the summer spirit,
Yamamotoyama she feels pain but can
continue through the pain,
you know.
So it's uh,
when you fish for the recent were first
part of the strong and Field Olympian.
Oh,
that's cool.
That's what I want to be.
Anyway,
read.
The second part is like,
I started really,
really real.
I mean,
but the real man is the one who feels
that pinball works truly pain,
you know,
the,
the strong men fierce,
no opponent but the man of Yonathan and
she fears opponent and sees a challenge
and takes it on head on,
you know.
So that's my belief in the fighting,
So when I fought,
that's what it was all about,
you know,
facing those fears.
You
fought after the ego fight though.
You fought,
you fought heath herring,
then you fought Nogueira,
then you fought and Ashita and then he
fought Tommy.
Yeah.
It was all,
you know,
it's so funny because it was all a thing
of my way of saying goodbye to fighting,
you know,
because when I fought the Igor I
thought,
okay,
I could retire today,
but I thought,
you know,
after all mma has done for me,
I want to give her fight.
And I saw,
I said the hearing and pride,
Neil is going to retire to a fight,
but they didn't want to give me the mic
and no one knew.
No one knew that I was retiring.
I just grabbed the mic and I said,
this is this,
the last of Yamaha mushy.
And everyone freaked out and that,
and the reason why I fucked a girl who
is because um,
when nine slash 11 happened,
I had a friend die in the second tower
and I felt,
I really felt that I was being
hypocritical because I would look into
see the special stuff in tv of the,
the building collapsing and really
literally feeling like Shit,
you know,
I'm pretty much really dawning my day
and I can actually switch off the TV and
walk to the game center and laugh
without a problem with my friends.
And I felt like a real prick and
illegal.
There's no honor.
I mean,
if you really feel shitty about what
something,
do something about it,
you know.
So I talked to him,
I said what I want to do and I felt
really shitty retire.
I had that wave of change and now seeing
I got to be fricking real to myself,
man,
I'm going to lose my honor funnel,
take care of this shit.
So I thought I'm wanting to listen to
army.
So he started running list and I tried
to enlist.
I was 34,
I was 36 account,
the cutoff age is 34 and the biggest
thing I couldn't get her own as a
tattoos are the uniform,
the head and the palm tattoos so I
couldn't enlist and my thing was okay,
if I'm going to list,
I didn't know I couldn't list or I
thought one of the US I want to fight
one more fight because I don't know if
I'm going to die there.
I don't know if I'm going to come back
mentally deranged or I'll never be able
to fight again.
And I figured I wanted to say a farewell
fight and I asked for Vanderbilt and
they gave me vendor.
It was $200,000
to fight vendor and I was like,
are you guys just fucked up?
I would've fought valiantly for free
because that's one guy.
I figured at the end,
my career with a bank,
we'd stand toe to toe dust clear.
Someone's going to be standing with me,
fine.
If it's vandelay fine,
I'm good with it.
As long as it's true.
Total talk to the very end,
you know?
So it was cool because I was seeing,
this is awesome,
this is like picture perfect.
I'm going to fight violent,
going to war,
I dyed hair,
I'm fine,
you know,
and all of a sudden,
two weeks into the fight,
they called me and told me that they
wanted me to fight.
No Garrett.
And I'm like,
you know,
I got my ass kicked by a lot of
heavyweights.
You know,
I,
I kind of want to fight at my weight now
and I'm not interested in.
Or Gary who was pride champion at the
time,
I thought it was more real for me to see
fight Vander Lee.
I mean,
by the way,
why did they change that?
Apparently what I finally did was they
got tomorrow so they tomorrow wouldn't
be able to fight Nogueira with the size
difference.
And also tomorrow,
fod vandalism.
They figured it was a big draw for
tomorrow.
Tomorrow is a huge name in Japan.
So pro wrestling from,
from some of the you,
Uwf,
Uwf the progressing.
So you know,
as much as a fireworks as a world will
love the incident.
Vandelay,
the Japanese crowd would love probably
tomorrow.
Vandelay bigger.
God Damn.
That would have been a crazy fight.
You and vandelay would've been in
Supernova.
I would have my.
My whole thing about fighting van Lewis
to push them backwards because every
time he gets he gets caught and every
one of his fights and I always notice
that he says such fast recovery that as
he's going down to recover since shoots
for a single or double and he'll recover
them,
but I figured if I use me like toward
did,
if you move federally backwards,
he hit them going backwards and he falls
backwards and you can end the fight.
Now knowing your,
your,
your beliefs in this,
your philosophy of Yamato,
the marshy,
how did you feel about the fights that
were.
There was some obvious works over there.
There was,
there was some definite fights where
people were paid to lose and paid to win
and there was a lot of fuckery going on.
Did that drive you crazy?
It pisses me off to our went public on
it.
Did you mean public or autocard occur?
I'm couple.
It's kind of coma was one of the most
obvious.
Yeah.
And you know,
I went public on that and I didn't.
I tried to be nice about it.
I,
I mean for a fighter who's willing to
die in the ring,
that's total disrespect to go into our
ring,
that we're tripping our real blood and
sweat in and willing to die in and these
guys are pulling works in there.
It's just totally disrespect.
And when he,
when he did that day that it was such a
big thing that the,
the MMA magazines,
Japan actually interviewed me about that
really.
And I didn't,
I didn't,
I didn't be blatant and be a dick about
it and say,
you know,
he fought a fake fight.
He's a human.
He's a faggot.
Know I just said that the rules that
Takata fought and the rule set I flight
or two different rules and I believe the
rules that he fought,
she'd be in a different ring.
So pretty much painting it out that it
was bullshit fight,
you know.
So I,
I just stated that way and Tacada got
pissed off at it and he banned all
interviews with me and stuck with Albert
together because Santa Clara was
fighting under Carter and yeah,
he was kind of pissed off,
but you know,
he can go suck my eggs because,
you know what I'm telling the truth.
That's all.
It was pretty obvious.
The Coleman fight was like,
it was like pro wrestling and was so
obvious.
He was like almost going to tap and uh,
like adding drama to it.
It was so silly.
But he had a few real fights.
You know,
Takata had a real fight against Hixon.
That was a real fight.
You could tell Hickson was.
And plus there was no way Hickson was
going to throw a five.
No Way.
Yeah.
Did you ever get to roll with Erickson?
Yeah,
but that was when I was a white belt and
of course he probably would've told me
when I was a black belt,
but he told me he was a white belt and
just kind of went through the whole
school,
you know,
he lines over and squash it.
Everybody.
Yeah,
he did that so,
so
yeah,
I've got a video that of one of his
seminars back when he ended up the
Samurai ponytail and he just lines
everybody up and just taps some over and
over and nobody knew what the fuck they
were doing.
Everybody was essentially a white belt.
Maybe there was like a blue belt in the
mix,
but still it's so fascinating watching
him just gently toy with everybody know,
just choosing how it was worded.
The only,
he's the one that for me,
I go,
God damn,
I wish he had more fights.
He's one of the ones where I would have
loved to see him fight.
I mean,
I had dinner with him many years back
when fader was on top and he wanted to
fight fader.
Oh,
interesting.
Yeah.
Very,
very.
You know,
the real question was could he fade that
ground and pound fate or his ground and
pound the wake.
There was no fight.
Fucking incredible man that especially
that first fight where he got them
stuffed in the corner by the term bokken
was just blast shots and that was when
no Nogueira was at his most durable,
very few other human beings would have
be able to take those shots.
The Window Garrett was taking them,
but I would have really loved to see
Hicks at against top level guys just to
see if.
Because he had this effect on people
when he got ahold of them on the ground
like,
you're fucking done.
Like no one was getting up.
No one was getting out of mount.
Nolan was hip escaping and you know,
getting back to their feet.
There was none of that in his fights.
It was kicks in,
Mtsu you and then he punches you until
you give up your back and they choked
the shit out of you.
That was every fight becomes textbook.
Yeah.
I wanted to see him against hire guys.
To this day,
he's the one guy that,
man,
it just really drives me nuts that he's
in his fifties now and we missed it.
We,
we,
we really missed his opportunity.
Yeah.
That's a great son real what everybody
does in Jujitsu,
the Japan Valley Tudo days,
you know,
when you saw him,
like right after hoists had made his
mark in America Hickson and made his
mark in Japan.
Really amazing documentary choke if you
never seen it.
Folks,
if you're an MMA fan.
Ah,
it's a classic,
really shows you what would Hickson's
all about in a very similar philosophy
to you was where,
you know,
he was,
he was willing to die in there as well.
And you know,
he was fighting with honor.
He would have never thrown a fight.
So what you saw at the Catia setting up
a fight with Hickson and you're like,
well,
he's going to have to fight for real.
Yeah.
That's gotta be weird.
Where some of his fights were fake and
some of his fights were real.
It's disrespectful.
That guy has no business being in their
memory and he won by one body kick.
Who the fuck did he fight?
You kick somebody and it was like you
were watching going like just didn't
look legit at all.
Yeah,
that guy.
Yeah.
That guy got no good works for Carter,
but he was a big time pro wrestler.
Right?
Is that he liked the rock,
like the Japanese were sort of like a.
yeah,
but person is progressing,
but it's big over there.
Right?
Yeah.
It's still going on bigger.
Big here in Japan.
Yeah.
A lot of people don't realize like
American MMA fighter sometimes they go
over there and take fights too.
Like I know Tim Silvia's had mma,
but he said,
you know,
progressing.
Josh Barnett's huge over there.
He does a lot of that shit.
Right.
Josh is one of those few guys that can
do both and do it.
Does.
It will also clear.
I've also.
Oh,
Bob Sapp is pretty good too.
Attitude.
Well,
he doesn't do fighting,
but not anymore as far as,
uh,
yeah.
Josh is unreal.
It's so fun.
He enjoys it.
Josh really likes the program.
He's more of a person.
The MMA fighter,
you think so?
He's an MMA fighter and he's a professor
that,
that just is really good at everything.
Yeah.
I'm,
I'm fascinated by josh has longevity.
I mean,
you look at him,
he's a God that was ufc heavyweight
champion in 2001,
I think it was.
And he still in the mix,
2013,
still top five heavyweight in the world.
Amazing.
Hasn't lost a step.
Said I believe that guy can be the best
in the world.
I just still,
even even at the strikeforce tournament,
was it a strikeforce?
He lost a May,
but he,
he broke his hand in the first round.
I thought I thought Josh hands down even
with further in it.
I thought jostens though.
Really?
I picked justin reading.
That was another fucking lost in the MMA
world when,
when he pissed hot and he couldn't fight
fader and they closed the flushing.
Yeah,
that was huge.
I was a,
that was a big.
That would have been a crazy fight,
man.
Josh Higgins feto would have been very,
very interesting.
And that was,
that was fate or in its prime to after
the Tim Silvia knockout was like,
everybody was terrified of fate or he
just looked like a fucking issue.
He,
it was a destroyer,
but again,
like somebody did a,
um,
uh,
they,
they wrote this thing about fighters.
Will you look at fighters from the time
they entered into high level MMA
competition to the time they started to
fade and with almost all of them,
it's like seven and nine years,
like between seven and nine years.
You see the transition where it drops
off.
Not Josh Barnett,
man.
They're just living every day.
Fifteen plus years still at the top of
his game.
I met that Guy [inaudible] 97 when he
was with.
I was training for work.
She's 90 don't work.
She'd leave.
It was 2000 something when I went to a
gym to train when he was fighting in
Japan,
in Hawaii when you were living there
when super broad,
just like a little fat kid though.
It was bad as big crazy belly buddy.
He was gangster man.
Yeah,
he was.
He was a fucking wild.
That is wild.
You know his trainer.
That's another interesting story of Matt
Hume.
You know,
Matt Hume is one of those guys that was
a pioneer,
was there in the early days and it's
still viable and on top of the game
today,
still on top of the curve trains,
you know Demetrius Johnson,
flyweight fighter,
a world champion.
It was training Matt Brown a lot,
a lot of like top level guys like rich
Franklin spent a lot of time down there
training and everybody respects him
being very well rounded and,
and,
and a great thing.
He's one of the few guys that made it
all the way through and it was in the
early days he fought in shooto.
He fought in that contenders thing.
Yeah,
still still on top of it.
He's still training guys at the highest
level today.
I think that's fascinating that some
guys like figure it all out along the
line and some guys like whether it's the
lion's Dan or whether it's,
you know,
the military fighting systems,
I sorta like disband and you give away
and step away from the fence.
Was AMC pankration still on top of Shit?
He's still like,
right.
Smart Guy,
man.
Very smart,
very smart.
I love listening to him give advice in
the corner because you'll hear like
sometimes in the corner,
like the Qa,
like a fighter will have his friends in
the corner.
It's like you'll hear stupid advice like
go kick his ass,
come on kick.
But you know,
you'll hear Matt Hume like you got to
check that leg kick,
moved to the left.
You got to do this.
When he shooting,
when he shooting,
that's when you're punching.
When he gives you like a real technical
shit,
you know,
you'll see what,
what the guy did that are applicable to
what's going on inside the cage.
Like real point for point instruction to
deal with his very specific situation
that he's facing it.
That's so rare.
When I fought joe is in Japan and that
was in this corner.
Oh,
every time I was trying to set something
up,
tell him.
It was the first time in my career that
I ever felt like shit.
The corpsman really screwing up my game.
Every time I thought of something.
Washer aren't mature and he'd suck.
You didn't really cause shit.
Well,
I couldn't set anything up because Matt
was seeing ahead and he knew when my hip
shifted was with farm.
When they did this to Russia,
the turnover was so hip throw.
He was giving them the heads up one step
ahead of time and so huge to have a guy
in this rare and so used to have a mini
coordinate in Japan where you could
actually hear him.
Yeah.
That's a lot of people don't realize
that.
It's a crazy quiet during these pride
fights.
There would be 90,000
people in an arena and you could hear
everyone's corner.
It was crazy,
so strange and attentive to.
It's not like they're not paying
attention and clapping.
When someone passed the guard,
he would hear like a,
like a group of people clapping and then
everyone's settled down and be quiet
again.
Do you miss that,
that,
that respectful approach to to the
sport?
I think it's good in bed too.
I mean the American public where they're
screaming like idiots.
You know,
they're screaming at the every punch
thrown when he stopped brawling start
bullying.
You know what I mean?
It's,
it's an animal African.
There's also pretty good for the event,
you know,
I mean there's,
there's a give and take to both.
The booing drives me nuts.
Yeah.
I mean sometimes we just say you there,
they're baking awesome.
Transition on the ground bullying and
say get a clue,
you know,
but it's the real problem is people that
go there just to see blood or just to
see an event and they don't know what
they're saying and so everybody knows
what's going on with two dudes or if you
and igor were thrown down in the middle
of the cage,
everybody knows what's happened over the
middle of the ring as it were.
Everybody knows you could see that you
go this crazy.
Someone's going to get knocked the fuck
out,
but when you watching like some high
level transitions in the ground,
if you don't know what they're doing,
you're lost.
You're in.
So people would start booing.
That's so disheartening.
To me.
It just drives me nuts.
It's like,
I love the fact that the UFC could fill
up these big arenas,
but I,
I hate the fact that filling them up
with a certain percentage of Douche
bags.
Yeah,
I guess the money's still green,
but it's like I wish that the martial
arts aspect was respected and
appreciated and I feel like the only way
that's ever going to really happen is
for a much larger percent of the
audience to be martial artists
themselves to be training and not just
to do it isn't a trend and actually see
happening where it's think it's
increasingly not much drunk idiots just
screening for blood.
No,
there's definitely less and it depends
on where you are.
Like there's some places where they're,
they're super polite and some places
where they're just go fucking crazy.
It would be the worst than Brazil is the
most like vocal,
but,
but they're getting a lot better to.
Whereas Brazil,
it used to be that foreigners just got
booed no matter what.
Like Mike Pyle,
for instance,
Mike Pyle,
um,
he,
he won in Brazil and he knocked out.
I forget who he fought.
He knocked a guy from Ludlow,
Massachusetts,
he trades out a team link.
He trains with Gabriel Gonzaga,
but pile was super respectful,
didn't do anything wrong,
just one,
you know.
And uh,
after he won,
he was in the ring in the cage,
it was just,
I was interviewing him and the whole
crowd is chanting something.
So I asked the translator,
I'm like,
what are they saying?
And the saying,
he's a faggot.
That's what they're chanting.
The whole crowd was calling him a
faggot.
Wow.
That is crazy.
And he didn't do anything wrong.
All he did,
Ricardo Punch,
that's what we fought.
All he did was one,
he stopped him and knocked him out.
All he did was,
yeah.
And Mike put my bio but was super.
It was.
Thank you very much.
It was bound to everybody waving and
everybody's like,
Hey,
fuck you.
There was a 16 year old little kids
like,
fuck you,
like yell and scream and given him the
finger to the cage.
And he's like,
Hey,
what can I do to get them to the back
and into the back?
The whole place was chanting,
you're a faggot.
Wow.
Brazil's the most vocal,
but they,
they lightened up about that,
the,
the nationalism because I think the
first time I was there was only the
second event that the UFC had done in
Rio and many,
many,
many years.
So it was a big thing to have the UFC
there and they were like super,
super nationalistic and charged up.
But then after we did two more events in
Brazil that kind of relaxed a little bit
on that and would even applaud fighters
that showed sportsmanship and one who
were foreigners.
You know,
even if they beat a Brazilian,
you know,
they,
they showed they,
they clap for people like rich Franklin.
Perfect example,
when he beat Vandelay,
they actually clapped for rich Franklin
and he tried to address them in
Portuguese.
He had something that he had prepared
and learned.
So it was Kinda cool.
It was cool to see that even though
Richard One and beaten vandelay
they liked it.
They were happy,
happy.
But I guess,
you know,
he had also shown like a massive respect
of Anderson Anderson had beaten him and
you I think,
I think a lot of people had a lot of
respect for rich there.
But as far as the sound they make though
no one's louder than Brazil.
Here I've been in fights where I had to
take my ears,
my ear pieces off and just like
turnaround listen,
because I couldn't believe how loud it
was.
Like this can't be real.
So I took the headphones off because the
headphones mute most of the shit.
You hear what I'm hearing this crazy
noise through the microphone and then I
take these off and you hear the volume
like Whoa.
So I like tap Goldberg and like take
your shit off,
take your shit up.
And like as they were introducing a
Anderson,
you take your,
your,
your headphones off,
you look around like the sound was a
roar.
It was just like a jet was going off
behind your ears.
They're all pounding on the ground.
Anderson the spider,
they weren't going fucking crazy.
I've never experienced that before.
This is,
Dana was saying it louder than anywhere.
They're passionate motherfuckers in
Brazil,
man,
that is a passionate country.
They get excited for their own,
but they,
they relaxed on the foreign hate,
you know,
which was Kinda cool.
Yeah,
this is,
they're the most loud,
but as far as the most polite England's
pretty fucking polite.
They're,
they're pretty polite in England.
Yeah.
I thought,
you know,
they're,
they're pretty nationalistic themselves,
you know,
they're,
they're like,
you know,
root for bisping and rooting for,
a Brad Pickett and anybody who's
fighting.
It's an English guy,
but they're there.
They're pretty polite in England,
you know?
Um,
I just went to New Zealand last year,
the end of last year and it tripped me
out because New Zealand is like 20 years
ago,
America really couldn't believe it.
Man.
These guys will know what the MME is.
And when I finally explained to one of
the immigration officers what it is,
he goes,
oh,
so you beat people for a living.
I'm like,
oh,
that's the animosity you had back in the
day when they were singing.
It was human dogfighting yeah.
And then you go to,
um,
and they were running into the same
problems.
The boxing commission is the one that's
interfering.
It has so much party stopping it because
they're afraid that MMA is going to take
over boxing.
And it's like the whole same thing all
over again.
And the craziest thing about New Zealand
is you got these crazy fighters there.
I mean guys,
it can go the jaws of stone and they
got,
they can hit,
they can mean a lot of stuff.
A country full of mark hunt's.
Oh my God,
there's a lot of them do
the big boys in there.
They're all to fight,
you know.
And I,
I'm wondering how the Hell is this
country 20 years behind?
I mean I couldn't
corruption.
Is that what it is?
I mean,
how is it?
Is New York state's still illegal?
That drives me.
That drives me nuts.
And that's all corruption.
We know the root of that.
It's the culinary union,
the Coronary Union,
they want station casinos to go union.
So they're bing politicians and
politicians are trying their best
New Zealand too because like I couldn't
understand it.
I couldn't understand how this country
would be
behind.
It's stupid too because it's not going
to hurt boxing.
It's not going to hurt kickboxing,
you know,
I,
I really feel like there's plenty of
room for all the combat sports.
I think that there is something to
watching like a floyd mayweather or
watching a guy who's a fantastic boxer
and it's always,
it's always going to be something that
people want to watch.
And I'm a big fan of high level
kickboxing too.
I Love K One and glory is doing a lot of
big shows now too.
I love watching that as well.
I think there's room for all that shit.
I really do.
Yeah.
Oh there is.
And they can work together know and they
should promote an mma.
Don't be stupid.
Don't try to fight it.
Fighting it mean you can go into New
Zealand and half the people will hate
marsh sharks.
Can you believe that?
I mean,
back in the day,
you remember back in the day when I'm
UFC,
MMA was considered.
I mean like we,
when I first started doing post fight
interviews,
it was like 97 and I was on a TV show,
news radio and I would tell people I was
going to fly to Dothan Alabama to go
work at an ultimate fighting
championship event.
They're like,
why are you doing this to yourself?
Like,
what are you doing to your career?
You wrote your reputation.
Like it was like I was going to go do
some porn.
I'm going to go,
I'm going to go and film some porno
films.
They're like,
what the fuck are you doing?
Like why are you getting involved in
cage fighting?
And I was like,
well,
I think some day is going to be bigger
than football.
They're like,
you're out of your fucking mind.
I'm like,
all right,
these here,
nobody would ever thought that.
Nobody would have ever thought back then
that,
that it would happen so fast.
They know it's going to be a trip for
you to have been there and the dawn
and to see it now,
man,
it makes me happy,
because that basically mixed martial art
has made me who I am today.
Everything that I have,
the reputation that I have,
the people that I know is all due to
that and just to see how big it's
become.
I mean I don't even have this mvs thing
where I wish I was fighting this time
where there's more money.
I'm really happy to what I did and where
I was and the opportunities I had and I
just,
you know,
as much as some people like to rip on
Dana,
man,
I got nothing but good words to say
because it's what he's done for the
sport.
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
The people that rip on them either don't
know them or they've got some business
issues with him.
Must Be A.
I love that dude.
He's straight up too.
I liked the way you,
you and him are straight up and if you
don't like the guy,
you don't let the bullshit and you know
that's the only way to be.
Especially in this business.
This is the realest business ever.
This is the real estate sport of all
time.
There's no sport broken down to me more
so even than boxing,
broken down to its raw cost element
acceptable by society.
What is,
what is it?
Real sport.
It's man dominating another man with
discipline.
Focus,
technique will intelligence and heart,
and that is all sports.
That's the route in what people admire
in all sports,
but MMA and bodies that it's the purest
form of sport.
You know if you say you love sports,
but you don't like mma,
you don't really love sports.
You don't know what sports really are
because every man in a fucking football
uniform running into other man wants to
beat those guys asses.
Every time a guy slam dunks a ball on a
guy's face,
he really wants to beat that dude's ass.
Do you wanna you wanna win.
You wanna win when it's most important?
Yeah,
that's the most important.
The incredible thing I like about it,
I mean is,
is that fighter has to do everything.
You know what I mean?
You got,
you got a quarterback,
you got to center,
you've got linebackers,
you go wide receivers,
you got everyone that has a certain job
in the whole sport,
but you,
you,
I mean,
I don't have.
Okay,
I'll do the ground.
Yeah.
And I'll get a ram pieces than my
standing and I'll get maybe chuck to do
my wrestling.
You know what I mean?
To say you can't do that.
You can it off and say,
oh,
okay,
offensive time.
Come in and get the strikers in.
I mean,
you're in there and you got to.
You gotta learn how to do be the
quarterback.
You get to learn how to be the center.
You've got 100 make blocks.
You get to learn how to catch the ball.
I always thought it was weird when you
heard a trainer say,
we,
you know,
we want to win this first round.
We want to go out there and do this and
you know,
wow,
what we worked on in the gym is this
what?
Like,
it's not really a lot of [inaudible]
going on here.
Fucking that guides him.
You really shouldn't be saying we,
you know,
we trained him to do this.
You know,
we showed him that he's been working
hard in the gym.
You know,
we've been pushing him know,
but when it's in the cage,
we want to win this first round there.
No,
he's going to win that first round.
You really don't have any to do it.
Nobody helps them prepare.
But he's going to fight the fight.
Yeah.
If you don't
have the mind for it.
And that.
That is really where it all boils down.
The mindset and the ability to overcome
obstacles.
So much of it is mental.
So much of deciding the right things to
do.
And when you were talking about seeing
guys break and knowing the guys are
breaking,
how many times you seen guys give up a
choke when you know that they didn't,
they,
you know,
they know how to get out of that.
But they,
they tap,
you know that they're just looking for a
way out of the pressure of the moment.
Well,
you know,
when you really think about it is you.
Have you ever questioned why people tan?
Yeah.
It's not because of the pain is because
of the anticipation of what they think
is going to happen to.
That's what it is.
Rarely do you have a garlic Nogueira or
Henzel and Misha tate who gets her arm
broke and then taps,
you know,
these people.
I see a lot of guys tapping out to
armbars and,
and waving to the French,
shaking their hands after with the same
arm.
I see people tap Baltic chokes and glow
and drinking that night.
You know?
I mean,
it's anticipation is basically what it
is.
And tapping all is basically a mind
focus.
If you're focusing on getting up,
you focusing on hurting the guy before
he hurts you and you're not focusing on,
oh shit,
my arm's gonna get broken.
It's going to be all fucked up tomorrow.
Oh,
a hero ligament pop.
Oh Shit.
I'm going to be fucked up to my better
tap.
You know,
it's anticipation and we really,
you really put the,
put it,
you know,
black and white men.
That's kind of funny because that's what
it is.
It's the faster the person tabs to the
earlier he was broke and once you break
it,
you're looking at the.
You're anticipating what you think's
going to happen to you.
That's what it is.
Yeah.
I had a Jimmy Smith on the podcast
earlier today.
We were talking about he's the guy does
a commentary for Bella tour and we were
talking about when Jacques Rey fought
hydro gracie and got his arm broken and
then tucked it into his belt and
defended for the last minute with a
fucking broken arm so that he could win
on points.
I mean,
this dude like let him break his arm.
He knew he was getting out is like,
but I'm not tapping.
Hajib broke his arm and he just tucked
that shit right in his belt and just
start a fight with the other arm.
And did he win that fight?
He won that.
He won that fight with a broken arm,
which is,
you know,
Tim Sylvia,
when Frank Mir broke his arm,
you know Tim Silvia was trying to.
It was making sure that they didn't stop
the fight.
He was telling her,
Dean,
do not stop this fight.
Let me,
let me keep fighting his forearm.
Just got sad discipline Broka,
and he was like,
you know,
whatever,
I'm,
I'm fucking.
I'm going to hit them with the other
hand.
Let me back in there.
That's all about focus.
I think that's about focusing on what
you want to do.
What are you focused on when you're in
there?
Yeah.
Are you focused on losing?
Are you focused on getting out of there
without being injured or are you focused
on finding a way to win no matter what?
That's,
that's,
that's the thing,
and it's a big thing.
One of the most impressive fights that I
ever saw where a guy lost the fight,
but I'm like,
damn,
this motherfucker is trying to win this
fight was when uriah faber broke,
broke both his hands on Mike Brown.
He had no hands.
Oh,
and by the second round he broke both
his hands.
He broke his thumb on one hand,
he broke his knuckles on the other hand
so he couldn't punch with either hand.
So he's throwing elbows and he's
throwing kicks and he did it for five
fucking rounds.
Oh yeah.
He couldn't do anything.
He couldn't,
couldn't grab a hold of them,
couldn't hold on to him,
couldn't grapple,
couldn't,
you know,
all he could do was try and throw elbows
and try to take them out with kicks,
but he still never complained.
And when there and tried to win every
minute of every round he had left,
you know,
I'm,
I'm a big fan of that.
And every now and then a guy will pull
that shit off like rich Franklin when
he,
when he knocked out chuck chuck broke
his arm and rich had a broken arm and he
punched chuck with a broken arm.
You know,
I'm really now know there's,
there's moments like that where guys,
even in the face of that kind of an
injury,
figure out a way to pull it off.
Those are special moments,
man.
Yeah,
that's,
that's what we mean is man,
that is what I'm going to write about.
Love that.
Listen,
man is late at night here.
I know you probably want to get some
sleep.
It's 2:17
in the morning.
I want to thank you very much for doing
this man and thank you for all the
fucking great fights that I've watched
you competed in over the years from
being there live and seeing you onboard.
Worse Algebra to watching the randy
coture fight to all those crazy fights
on pride.
Man.
It was a pleasure having you on this
podcast.
Thank you for enjoying them,
man.
Thanks man.
Thanks for all the people that asked for
this and helped pull this podcast off
man because it was a big one for me too.
I really appreciate you.
Thank you.
And Follow Ensign on,
uh,
on twitter and send in your way on
twitter.
And that's I n o u e on twitter.
And what's your,
do you have a website?
Uh,
I have a brace of the website but it's
destiny forever.com.
But basically if you want to follow me
on facebook,
facebook and anyway,
on facebook fan page on facebook.
Beautiful.
Alright.
Thank you sir.
Appreciate it man.
And I'm going to go drive you to Chuck's
house.
Okay.
Thanks to on it.com
for sponsoring the podcast as well.
Go to o n n I t use the code name Brogan
and save 10 percent off any and all
supplements.
We will be back tomorrow with David Cho,
who is the uh,
the dude who was the artist for facebook
who decided to take stock options
instead of getting paid.
And now he's wearing like a $100,000,000
or something fucking crazy.
So he's going to be on tomorrow with our
pal Yoshi.
So,
uh,
that should be a good time.
And uh,
thank you brother.
Appreciate it man.
All right.
You fucking go to sleep at 2:30
in the morning.
It's over 30 shit.
Hmm.