She,
I'm really looking forward to it.
Boom.
And we're live Henry rollins.
We are live.
All right.
I like how you do the one year off.
That's what Jim Norton approach.
He,
he likes that.
You have always done it this way so I
can hear the room and hear me as well.
Keep your eye on the door.
Yeah.
Little guys.
So listen man,
I heard you on red fears podcast.
Always one of my best friends.
He's a good guy.
I love that guy.
He's funny.
He is very funny.
We're both doing his thing at that club,
right?
We tell the story.
Yes.
And I saw yours and I think I do like
the month after you.
So I saw yours on the Internet and then
I did one and he's the host and that's
how I met him.
This is not happening.
Yeah,
that's it.
And didn't you guys meet somewhere?
Yeah,
last year in August at the fringe
festival he was doing like 30 nights
there and I was doing like five and so I
guess the agents said,
Hey,
do this thing with the shirt.
And so he met me in the lobby where I
was staying and he brought his gear and
we just did it.
It was cool because there was background
noise.
You could tell you it was the hotel
revelers outside.
I mean the whole,
that whole part of Scotland is full of
people for 30 days.
It's amazing.
Well,
what was amazing is the way you're
living your life,
man.
It's really fascinating.
Oh,
thank.
You know.
And this conversation that you guys had,
it really blew me away because you're
really doing it.
You know what I mean?
Like trying.
Yeah,
you're really doing it.
Like you pick a spot on a map and you
just fucking go there.
You don't know anybody there.
You go by yourself and you just fucking
hang out,
see what happens.
Yeah.
And that's usually like sale.
Go to a place like Ulaan bought tour,
Mongolia for like five days or whatever
for two days.
You get a tour guide just so you can get
the history like this museum,
not that one,
this temple,
not those two.
Just whatever.
And what I was trying to do in a place
like that is get the tour guide and
break them.
And I'm like,
okay,
so tell me about the corruption in your
government.
Well sir,
we don't have any,
ma'am.
I'm going to ask you one more time.
And you know,
by the afternoon they finally submit and
they're like,
okay.
And like when I was in,
uh,
in Mongolia,
the woman by the end of the day,
she said,
you know what,
I,
I called this guy,
he's like this total like insurgent,
like rebel guy.
He wants to meet you.
I'm going to be the translator because,
you know,
he and his guys are starting movements
in this country to overthrow the
government and he really wants to meet
you.
I said,
I really want to meet him because
they're rebelling against the government
who's selling out that country for the
titanium,
the copper,
all the mining.
Uh,
I think to some Ivanhoe,
some Canadian extractive from.
Anyway,
we go like an hour out of town to some
like spy bar where there's like nobody.
And you walk in and I was like,
you must be on the up and up and I sit
at this table with this guy just because
I was able to take the tour guide and be
like,
tell me everything.
And I'll do that for a couple of days
and try and get a real understanding of
where I am.
And then I just leave the hotel or the
tent,
whatever.
I'm staying in with my camera,
my backpack with some water and I just
start walking.
I go,
well,
here's the street.
Look at that slum where that village or
that souk or that bizarre and I go.
And so far all 10 fingers still work.
And I've been to about 100 countries and
all seven continents.
And the only times I've almost been
killed,
which was twice was,
was America by comparison.
The rest of the world has been very
friendly.
Where were the places where you're
almost killed in America?
In California a couple of times nearly
stabbed to death.
And uh,
a guy shot at me and my friend and he
killed my friend but didn't kill me.
And so that was a real close,
you know,
that's real,
but the rest of the world by comparison,
I was in Pakistan when Butoh was
assassinated,
she was killed in Rawalpindi.
I was in Islam of odd,
like few miles down the road and I was
there for a week because they are port
shut down and I went outside every day
and no one,
they just asked if I was lost,
if I needed help getting back the
thought it was like a journalist or
embassy.
I went,
Nah,
I'm just a traveler.
And they said basically,
sorry,
you have to see our country in this
state.
And I'm like,
no,
you know,
I don't get to judge.
And so I,
I've had the travel experiences all over
the world where I'm met by just amazing
generosity and kindness and humility and
informs kind of how I comport myself.
But that's what I try and do.
I,
I try to live an eventful life.
Like I,
I work at it.
It's not by chance like you give me six
weeks off right now.
I'm clear.
I just whip out my high Rez jeff file of
the map of the world and I pick one
country and go,
okay,
then I'll just go east from there.
Like China,
Mongolia,
Bhutan,
Tibet,
Vietnam,
back to La.
I'll just go do that.
I want to get back to this.
But what happened with your friend that
in California was this same sort of a
thing where you just wanted to check out
a place?
No,
no,
it,
we,
we were robbed and the guy started
shooting and uh,
they,
uh,
the guy killed my friend and put shot at
me and just missed me very closely,
but that,
that was a big turning point in my life.
I mean,
that changed everything for 25 years
ago.
But uh,
it,
you know,
it changes everything that you think
about everything.
I mean it's every,
I think everyone goes through trauma
like that in their own way because it
taps into everything you've ever done in
your life beforehand.
Uh,
but that was a,
you know,
not to be crass,
but that was a game changer.
But on the bigger topic of danger,
the world is a dangerous place as you
know,
but at the same time,
I don't think it's to be feared because
then you don't get anything done.
I mean,
you live in America.
I live in America.
Were the roughest room I've ever been
in.
I mean we're,
we're a coast to coast,
philly's flyer game,
you know,
we are blood and teeth on the ice.
I mean we are because of freedom.
We very free and people just walk up and
smack you.
And I've never been to a country as free
as America.
I've been to countries that way.
More hectic,
like don't get caught outside at night
like downtown Nairobi or you know,
parts of Russia are kind of scary just
because they're living hard.
But as far as a place where anything can
happen,
America is like easily the hairiest
place I've ever been.
Day to day.
Baghdad was intense.
I was in Iraq for a few days,
but um,
that wasn't real.
I was there on a Uso trip.
So you're just kind of camping out in
the Green Zone.
What
initiated this crazy thirst for travel,
this wanderlust that you've got
something you've always had
emanation of things.
When I was young,
I was born and raised in Washington dc
and I lived down the road from the
National Geographic Museum with the big
whale in the front and the Smithsonian.
It if whenever there was a snow day,
my mom,
she worked for the government downtown.
She'd like,
I'd get on the bus with her and we'd go
downtown.
I spent the whole day at the Smithsonian
dinosaur bones astronauts.
They all,
you know,
all that kind of stuff.
It was fascinating and my mom would save
up her meager pay and she would save up
for years.
She was like,
art nut.
So we'd go hit the museums in Italy,
go to the museums in France,
go to see all the islands in Greece,
go to England,
see the National Museum,
look at Shakespeare and chaucer his
handwriting.
And so by the time I was a little kid by
11th,
11 years old,
like fifth grade or thereabouts,
I had been to Greece and Italy and
England and,
and different countries.
And so I kinda wanted more of that.
And when you grow up with National
Geographic magazine,
you look at the pyramids,
you look at the sinks and you're like,
I want to see that.
Like,
that doesn't look real.
And then eventually I did go to all
those places.
You know,
I,
I stood in front of the stinks more than
once.
And the Great Pyramid in Giza,
it's bigger than you think.
It's like you kinda just,
it hypnotizes you stare at it all day.
Have you been recently?
I haven't been for a few years,
but I've been there like three times I
want to go.
But it's just keep hearing sketchy
things about Egypt right now.
Yeah.
Yeah,
it is sketchy.
It'll always be sketchy because their
GDP is you showing up and going to the
pyramid.
It's like Las Vegas,
but pyramids like you can see all,
you can see your hotel from the pyramid.
They've made a highway that goes from
the cluster of hotels,
right?
It's like the Giza highway because like
what do you want to see the pyramid.
And so they take you right there like
seven minutes.
You're standing in front of these things
and people are trying to sell you stuff.
I would go without hesitation.
You would never
problem.
I need to go.
I have a buddy of mine has been on the
podcast names John Anthony West and he's
created these incredible DVD series
called magical Egypt.
He's an egyptologist,
uh,
like one of the most knowledgeable,
but there's lots of noise
you can spend your whole life to
studying.
One Dynasty.
There's so much.
Yeah.
I'm just a casual fan.
I was planning on going with him,
but unfortunately it was just diagnosed
with stage four cancer.
A lot of you might not know about that.
If you do know and you hear you can,
you can google it,
but I put a link up before to try to
help him and that he's not good.
He's an older gentleman and he's been.
He's been trying to educate people on
Egypt for a long because he's
a,
he's a scholar when it comes to ancient
Egypt,
like,
and he's one of those people that's a
actively trying to kind of rewrite the
history of Egypt as far as like how far
back it goes.
They've got some pretty rock solid
evidence to point to the idea that Egypt
is a civilization that was probably
very,
very advanced many,
many,
many thousands of years ago.
And then some sort of a natural
cataclysmic disaster,
probably asteroidal impacts or something
like that around 10,000
years ago.
Sort of reset society and civilization.
And then they rebuilt from there with
whatever was remained.
That's interesting.
I mean they benefited from having denial
because denial,
you know,
the water's rich with nutrients.
So agriculture was huge and people lived
good lives.
You know,
the Nile is,
it's massive.
It's a,
there's parts of it that are like still
like a lake.
And then when you see it,
like in,
um,
in northern Uganda,
south Sudan,
like right when you cross the border,
you go across this river,
like,
you know,
category five Whitewater roaring.
That's the Nile has a lot of different
phases to it.
Now this,
this wanderlust that you have this like
crazy touring thing where you just pick
out a spot and go,
how long have you been doing that?
Uh,
I did conventional,
you know,
I used to do a lot of rock and roll and
rock and roll.
We'll get you all over Europe,
Japan,
Australia,
New Zealand,
places like that.
But it won't get you to Egypt,
Morocco,
Tunisia,
Mongolia necessarily.
And so in the nineties,
you know,
I'm like,
anyone else in this business you do
every interview.
And they said you're pretty well
traveled.
And I'd always have to say,
well caveat,
I've never been to the African
continent.
And then one day I went,
well why not?
And so I,
I did some research,
what are you gotTa to do?
You gotta go get a bunch of shots.
Like a lot of them makes you sick for
like a whole day.
They put so many vaccines into you and
so you go to the travel doctor and you
show him what countries you're going to
go.
Well,
and they just line up syringes and they
got on either side of me and just like
just were just Charlie Horsey me in both
arms and they said,
now you're,
now you're ready to go.
So I just said,
well,
I'm going to go to Kenya.
I'm going to go to a Maasai Mara and the
Tanzanian border to see giraffes and
zebras and lions and all of that and the
Messiah.
It was all.
That was great.
I went from there to a Madagascar
because I just had Madagascar.
You'd better go.
So because I saw it one day I was on a
flight from Melbourne or Sydney to Perth
going across Australia and I was
whipping up the map on the airplane
magazine.
I said,
so there's Madagascar.
I did not know I better go and,
and it was one of the better trips I
ever did.
I was at my office one day,
near the end of 1997 I think.
And I know that black Sabbath is getting
back together with the original lineup
to do two shows at the Birmingham Nec in
England.
So I called Sharon Osborne.
I said,
Sharon,
I got this great idea,
I fly out and hang out with black
sabbath and broke down with a band and
go to band practice and have a really
good time and you put me on the guest
list for this shows and I hang out for
free.
And it was like the best time I've ever
had knowing she'd hang up on me.
She said,
let me call them and ask them if that's
okay because I already knew it,
but I didn't know the rest of the guys.
And she called me later that day.
She said,
oh,
they think it's fine.
Here's the address,
just let us know when to expect you.
So I booked it,
I booked it around my trip to Africa.
So I went a USA London bus up to Wales
where they were practicing a taxi.
No,
no,
Ozzy.
His assistant came and got me.
So I hung out with Sabbath at band
practice.
Me and the band full band rehearsals the
best,
uh,
watch the shows,
the two reunion shows at the soundboard.
And then the next day I flew to Kenya.
And so it was just a good,
you know,
that was a good chunk of travel and I
ended up in South Africa after all of
that and said to myself,
okay,
I'm going to come to Africa once a year
and I just started picking out different
chunks of it and it just started going
and that was 20 years ago and I've been
there,
I don't know,
like 20 sometimes.
Wow.
Yeah.
And you never don't learn,
you know,
I call it the big book.
It's where you learn about life and
death and you can learn that anywhere,
but you see big stuff,
you see people who suffer,
people who have no food or water
security.
Like you and I,
we talk about retirement and life
insurance and vacation.
A lot of tribes,
there's no words or even ideas in their
lives.
Like I was hanging out with some
maturity people once in Uganda a few
years ago and I had a translator is a
Dinka guy who spoke I guess whatever a
truly people speak.
And I said,
can you ask them if they have any words
in their language for life insurance,
retirement or a vacation?
And they understood retirement.
You get too old,
your kids take care of you,
but a vacation,
they said you leave somewhere and you
come back.
Why would you want to leave your home?
It's where all your friends are in your
family and why would you ever do that?
Or like life insurance,
like what the hell are you talking
about?
And you start meeting people who their
sense of time and space is,
I've got a bowl,
there's some rice in it.
So like today I got tomorrow,
we'll see where you.
And I think,
okay,
in December I'm going to do this.
And we really have a realistic
expectation of being alive and breathing
in December and in your life,
you've no doubt thought of,
okay,
when I retire or whatever that means to
you money,
some kind of security up the road.
There's parts of the world where people
live their entire life 37 years and then
they don't have a day of that kind of
security.
They got the t shirt,
a stick and some shade and I try and not
as some voitier I'm trying to understand
the world and I can understand it by
reading some books and seeing some
documentaries,
but there's nothing like getting out
into what Mark Twain called the
territory of phrase I stole from David
Lee Roth when he said it to me and David
Lee was actually a real inspiration to
do a lot of traveling because one time
we were talking and he just come back
from open sea kayaking in the Pacific.
So I said,
so why is it Henry is because don't get
eaten today is a great thing to have on
your to do list every once in awhile.
I said,
damn,
that is profound.
You what he was doing up until recently
he moved to Japan.
I didn't know anybody there and he was
taking Kendall lessons.
So learning how to sword fight yet
Japanese master?
Yep.
With this dog.
No,
no.
He told me.
He called me one Sunday a while ago.
I helped him with his autobiography,
so I worked with Dave really closely for
many,
many months.
I met him when I was in black flag 30
some years ago.
I walked by him at an art gallery.
I went,
wait a minute.
Anyway,
black flag,
right?
Like no way.
It's the van Halen guy.
We became best buddies,
but he called me from,
from Japan and said,
uh,
he was,
he's learning Japanese.
He's very smart and he is like learning
Japanese and started speaking Japanese
and he's just taking lessons,
you know,
you said the,
the sword guy was just like every day
just like you're stupid and just like,
just breaking them down.
Yeah.
And he just got an apartment there.
It,
rockstar just gets like this normal
apartment with his dog and just starts
taking Kendo lessons.
Everything.
David's always had a greater
appreciation of,
of,
you know,
that kind of discipline in me comes up
through martial arts since he was a kid
and I think as someone else in his
family's into it,
but he's been that way,
you know,
that kind of discipline and you can see
it on stage.
The guy is very physical,
but it's coming from a real disciplined,
not messing around kind of aggression
and control and Dave really loves Japan
and he says,
he called me,
so I'm living in a small apartment.
I'm taking my language lessons,
I'm taking my martial arts stuff.
And he was doing sword stuff for quite a
long time though.
Yeah,
he's always been involved in martial
arts and even the way he sort of
approached hedonism,
I always felt like it was sort of like
an applied approach to hedonism,
like his rock star lifestyle thing,
what he was doing.
It's almost like,
look,
not a lot of people get a chance to do
this.
Yep.
I'm going to do it.
Yeah.
One time he,
when we were working on his book,
he said,
you know,
I go home to pass the dean and now and
then where,
you know,
born and raised in some of his high
school buddies,
seemingly like,
well Dave,
you know,
must be nice,
being David Lee Roth and he.
And he said,
you know what?
On graduation day from high school,
we all were on the same starting blocks.
You chose the bank job,
that's a sure thing.
You're going to die in that cubicle.
I choose to sail the seas of
consequences.
I was like,
I love that.
And I was like,
yeah man,
that's daring.
And so he won.
I mean like he said it pretty good ride
I reckon.
And,
and so in my own way,
you know,
I,
I come from minimum wage work,
I'm nobody from nowhere and I got into
music via punk rock because the band
black flag said,
hey,
you're a crazy guy.
You want to try out to be our singer.
I'm like,
what do I have to lose?
Yeah.
And so I went for that and it led to
everything else and ultimately why I'm
here in this room with you today.
Do you miss rock?
Do you miss touring as a musician?
No,
no,
because I did it.
I did it really hard until I had nothing
left to give to it.
And so now if I went back to it,
it would just be repetition and it might
be repetition,
but it wouldn't be meaningful in that I
wouldn't be putting out anything new.
And for me,
the day I stopped doing music was I woke
up one day and I just sat up and was
like,
a light bulb went on.
I went,
wow,
I'm out of lyrics.
And it wasn't like,
oh no.
I'm like,
okay,
well give me my scroll.
I guess I've graduated.
When was this?
Two thousand three years.
And I just called the manager.
I said,
Hey,
I'm done with music.
And he saw a 15 percent of that though,
poof.
And he's like,
no.
I went,
yeah.
He goes,
why?
I said,
because I got nothing new to add these
as well.
Then just go out and do the hits.
I'm like,
man,
that's not what coltrane would have
done.
It's not with miles Davis would've done.
I just can't.
I don't want to repeat.
It's not artistically brave to me.
And so I'd much rather just try new
things.
But thankfully by that time I was
already doing talking tours all over the
world and they do very well,
uh,
tons of acting voiceover.
I had all this other stuff I was doing,
had the book company,
a record company,
music publishing.
I was,
had all this other stuff and so I just
kind of let all of that stuff fill in,
put it this way.
I'm busier now than ever and I don't
miss the music.
I see bands in the airport all the time,
but like the laminates in road gear,
I'm like,
yeah,
rumble young man rumble.
I had my fill.
Well,
it's beautiful that you did it on your
terms.
You decided to do it.
It wasn't just,
it wasn't like there's a lot of aging
rock stars that have that sort of
existence where they have to go out and
do the head.
Yeah.
No one wants to hear.
He knew shit.
That's a big part of the problem.
And so they have to do that weird circle
the wagons thing,
like we're going to play this album in
its entirety.
Okay.
I go to some of those shows.
I,
I throw my money down and go see that
band,
do that album in its entirety.
It's cool,
but it's not for me.
Well,
I've heard the stones still put on an
awesome show.
I think one of the cool things about it
is that like,
wow,
mick jagger can still fucking do it.
He still apparently works out twice a
day.
Yeah,
he's amazing shame,
great shape.
Um,
there's some people and,
and they're,
they're rare.
They actually,
it's not about money.
That's when I really start trusting
those old rock stars.
Like Rod Stewart doesn't need a dime.
I mean,
that guy can buy four countries right
now.
He's probably playing tonight and Las
Vegas or somewhere.
Elton John.
They just really liked doing the thing.
Mick Jagger and Keith Richards,
there'll be rock.
It'll die on stage and it's not money.
It's not like,
Hey,
we might get popular.
It's like,
man,
we really want to play brown sugar.
I don't,
but I admire them.
I think it's what I'm saying is I think
it's real.
Well,
I'm sure it is real.
Yeah.
I'm sure it's real with a lot of them,
but what I liked with you,
with what you're saying is that you had
already figured out all these other
paths in life that you were enjoying
putting your creative energy and you
just decided,
and I just.
I know it was summer 19,
84.
I was 23.
I was in black flag and we were touring.
We were staying out of California
because the Olympics were coming and we
knew the cops would just be looking to
smash down any supposed do wells.
So we just stayed on tour of the whole
year pretty much and I noticed all these
great bands around the very talented
people and everyone we're all broke
between tours were like living like
sharks.
If we don't like tor,
we don't eat.
And between tours the guys in that band,
they're all waiters and not putting that
down and say,
but the music wasn't keeping you in rent
12 months a year and I'm not nearly as
talented as any of them.
So I said,
man,
if there those guys are struggling,
then what am I going to do?
I better get plans B,
c,
d,
e,
F and g together,
and in those days I just started my
little book publishing company,
so I'm going to work harder on writing.
I'm going to become much better.
Start doing the talking shows.
I'm going to get much better at that and
I'm going to start saying yes to things
when they come along.
A couple of years later,
Hollywood started calling,
Hey,
can you act them because well as I can
sing click,
but I started,
you know,
acting is crispin glover,
the actor.
One day he said to me,
he said,
Henry as a just please consider acting.
Just like just if you get an audition,
don't necessarily say no just because
you're the music guy.
Like he said,
I think you might really like it and you
could probably do it.
And so I said,
okay,
and within a year I was doing film and
then,
Hey,
can you do a voiceover?
I'm like,
yeah,
I got a voice.
And so I just started saying yes to more
stuff and that was the plan.
Just have more things to do,
which is fine because I don't like
sitting around anyway and then
ironically music ended up being very,
very good and all of that for me.
But I had plans,
other plans and I've noticed that a lot
of old geezers around my era,
they didn't come up with something else
and they just,
I don't know why and they didn't make
another plan and they get put into those
weird tours where there,
you know,
you bring your kid all of that and it's,
it's more that they got to more than
they want to and I'd rather wake up
wanting to do stuff not having to do
stuff.
I think like you were saying a while
ago,
like less obligation just so you clear
the deck so you can really do what you
want because life is short.
I mean last week I was 20 and now I'm
56.
I mean it goes by really fast.
It doesn't matter if you're in a cubicle
or a prison cell and then you wake up
one day,
you're like,
damn,
that was fast and so you might as well
make it as much as what you wanted to be
as possible because all you're getting
is older.
I don't understand why people don't fear
that I wake up everyday.
But with the,
uh,
the grim reaper side whistling by my ear
going,
you better get up man.
And it's all the up I need.
I don't ever sleep in.
I mean,
how many hours a night between a four
and five or six that's going to age.
I don't like it.
Don't like sleeping.
Are you sleeping?
I just,
you know,
I,
I get up,
I'm like,
damn man,
I got to do stuff.
But does not diminish your energy when
you.
Sometimes,
yeah,
I have those Uzi afternoons where I,
I,
I take the seven minute power naps in
my,
in my chair at the office.
But um,
I,
I just try and,
you know what I have found,
if you want to not have to sleep eight
hours a day,
you maintain a really good diet.
You can shave about an hour of sleep off
you,
keep your proteins and your
carbohydrates lean and stay away from
food that's really fun to eat burgers,
French fries and all that,
which is,
I'd live on that if I could.
But if you keep your diet really
together and you keep your workouts up,
I have found that you want to like not
get tired during the day,
workout at five in the morning and the
rest of the day you're just kind of
buzzing where you think you'd face plant
onto your desk.
Sometimes when I'm really humming,
I'm up at 4:30
and I'm in the gym by 4:55
PM and I'm just,
you know,
on the 5:00
AM you mean?
Yeah,
for 55,
eight.
Oh,
5:00
PM.
Oh,
sorry.
No,
uh,
yeah,
early in the morning figuring,
you know,
oh by noon I'll just be like dead
asleep.
Aww Man.
I'm wired and a to go to sleep at night.
Like last night I was uh,
it was,
I was kind of wired,
so I just started doing.
I'm like,
yeah,
people have drinking games.
I was playing a 45,
so my record player,
so when I would,
when I'd have to flip the 45,
I would do a set of pushups and so I
played a bunch of 45 last night,
so I did a bunch of pushups and by the
time I'm done with a 45,
I felt like I'd been caned by a pro in
Singapore.
I was so tired,
man.
So I slept dreamless sleep last night.
Looks like a dead man.
You wrote a piece a long time ago that I
really enjoyed about power lifting and
it was something on the lines of the
iron never lies.
It doesn't lie.
Yeah.
I love that.
Oh,
it was great because it was put that in
gyms all over.
It was.
So you nailed it because it was so
honest and it was.
It's so highlighted.
What is so beneficial about forcing
yourself to do hard work?
Yeah.
And the fact that you are going,
okay,
I don't,
I'd rather not,
but here we go and it's a.
I like to build that muscle,
not,
but here I go muscle.
And that's more important than any brand
you're going to have.
You know,
it's,
it's for me,
the workout is all I go to the gym to
get my head right.
The benefit is I,
you know,
you,
you get in good shape.
But like I just finished a bunch of
shows.
I did 27 shows in America.
I just finished a bunch of shows.
I did 27 on one day off 27 on two and a
half hours on stage and night,
no notes,
talking at a high rate of speed.
The only way I got through that was
really good diet and three days on,
one day off workouts it was,
it was the workouts that alleviated the
stress that made the sleep,
restorative the muscle tissue,
uh,
absorb it into nutrients,
et Cetera,
and made the show's good.
And so for me,
the workout since I was about 15,
that's been as much a part of my day as
anything just to.
Otherwise they get kinda mentally
clogged.
They get depressed now.
You still doing all those,
you still doing power lifting?
No,
no,
no.
My body left the building on that.
Years ago when you,
when Beavis and butthead made fun of one
of your songs.
Do you remember that?
Oh yeah.
Fucking great.
It made a seller.
It sold.
It wasn't the worst thing that ever
happened.
God Damn Dude,
your neck was as big as my waist.
You were huge.
It was actually a fatter than my ears
really has to.
There's just those,
those muscle groups that just jump up.
You know,
if you do a lot of shrugs all sudden
death traps are like equal to the top of
your head.
Their muscles is this blow up.
And those.
What are those?
Like the sternomastoid muscle,
whatever that big one is on the side of
your neck.
I just,
everything I did seem to hit that muscle
group the way I like pull up a dead lift
or the way you hold a bar during squats
that neck muscles,
always doing something to support a lot
of weight.
And so it just got worked and worked and
that's when the Beavis and butthead
like,
oh,
he's got a big neck.
I liked that.
Um,
but when did you stop doing the.
There?
There is or there?
Yeah.
Oh yeah,
that's 94.
We shot that in the desert and we shot
that in the Mojave desert.
Um,
when did you stop doing the power of
that in the,
in the,
uh,
early two thousands just because I felt
a problems in my back and,
and you know,
for squat day I'm like,
you know,
belt belting up,
I'm wrapping my knees.
I was like really going for it and like
my frame,
it just can't support my attitude.
And so my attitude is like I'll lift the
whole damn gym and my,
I was reminded,
my body went and then not really,
you're more of a swimmer,
runner type,
you're not trying to.
And so I was lifting a lot for a guy my
size and my,
my bone mass and so at one point my back
and shoulder started hurting and like a
different kind of pain,
like,
you know,
that you shouldn't be doing this
anymore.
And so the workouts I do now,
if I can't lift a 10 times,
I just don't,
I just pull the way down so I can.
So a lot of it's um,
you know,
treadmill,
elliptical,
and a stationary bike and a lot of
pullups pushups and uh,
like,
you know,
a lot of compound lifts,
bench press,
stuff like that.
But mainly a lot of pull ups,
a trx straps that the guy who invented
them gave them to me as a gift.
And that's great.
And they're great because it's just you
and your body.
And not that natural resistance.
I have found that it makes me a bit more
limber and I dunno,
I don't need to lift everything in the
gym.
I'm 56.
I,
you know,
I don't it,
all I can do is like blow out that one
day and never be able to raise my arm
over my head again,
you know,
blew his shoulder out so I don't need
it.
Do you fuck around with Yoga at all?
Uh,
but I admire it because you see people
who do yoga and there's,
so not only are they flexible,
but you can tell they're really grounded
in themselves.
Like they're really,
they're,
they're coming on with an energy that I
don't have.
Well,
it does something to you,
uh,
the alleviation of tension to increasing
range of motion and flexibility.
It also does something to your mind.
Yeah,
that's what I noticed in their group.
They're grueling classes,
like an hour and a half in a hot yoga
room.
It also does something to your body
that's probably related to sauna
treatments,
like they've shown it.
Sauna treatments and heat shock proteins
do amazing
things to your body to reduce
inflammation and,
and,
and just the grueling physical and
mental grind of getting through a class.
I've heard the hot yoga is brutal.
It's brutal.
People.
I've met so many people as you do and
girls.
I said,
you know,
you think you work out hard,
you should come to a yoga class.
You will cry.
You won't even make it like they try and
challenge me.
I'm like,
I actually got scared of all that.
They said,
you want to work out.
You won't be able to pick up your car
keys at the end of it.
Well,
I'm sure you can pick up your car keys,
but it is really brutal.
While you're doing afterwards,
you don't feel the same way.
You feel like if you lift weights too
hard,
you know that feeling like,
oh well you can't move your body.
You don't really get that,
but you do get just fucking to the point
where you're looking at the clock and
you realize there's 20 minutes to go.
You're like,
I don't know if I could get 20 hours a
year.
Head is hot.
You're your body's pouring water.
Wow.
Now you can lose five,
six pounds in a class easily.
Yeah.
I've heard that about those spin classes
to people lose too much weight.
They have to stop and like the less days
a week.
Yeah,
it makes sense because you're also on
the momentum of the energy of the room
and the.
If the instructor is really good,
you get hyped up and then start pushing
a little too hard.
I've never been in a class like that.
I'm not the biggest people person.
That's why I started working out when I
was in high school.
I couldn't throw the ball straight so
the gym was always empty so I just went
in there,
but I've never,
you know,
been like,
hey class,
I've never done that.
Well,
the good thing about yoga classes,
no one talks so you know,
you're around those people.
There's no interaction.
It's just you kind of feel each other
and it's kind of cool because he pushed
each other a little bit without
communicating,
but I'm a big fan of it man and I think
as far as like increasing your longevity
of your body,
the use of your body,
it seems to me that it does,
is kind of forge all the connections
between your joints in your body and
your core and it just makes everything
better,
right?
Like I don't have as much,
nearly as much back pain as I used to,
a more flexible than I have been in
years.
I've been like a year and a half,
maybe almost two years I've been really
into it.
And how many days a week you go?
I tried to do three.
I usually wind up a lot.
One,
I usually wind up one or two,
but I try for three when I can get three
and I do it.
But um,
between that and all the other different
kinds of workouts,
slinky,
really what I like to do is I like to
wake up and decide what I'm going to do
when I wake up.
Some days I'm like,
I want to go kick box,
I want to go to Jujitsu,
I want to lift weights,
I want to go to yoga.
That's cool.
Yeah.
I just like we were talking about before
the podcast started,
what I'm trying to do with my life at
this point I'm almost 50 and 49.
I'll be 50 in August is to have as few
obligations as possible and as much
passion and interest as possible and
just sort of pursue the things that I'm
really enjoying.
That keeps you ageless.
I,
I just have met so many people by 23
they're kind of retired or then you meet
some 75 year old guy who just run rings
around you and it's all in your head and
the choices you make and I've seen both
ends of that spectrum or the old guy is
like younger than you'll ever be and the
young guy
is just like so pouring into.
So he turned into his dad or something
like,
damn man,
who,
who got to you.
What I take fuel from is like things
like your podcast with Ari,
because I was listening to you talk all
about the adventures that you've had and
the travel and the way you go about it,
and I got fired up,
man.
I was listening to that.
I was like,
I love this.
I love that.
No one's telling you to do this.
This isn't a fucking cubicle job.
Oh No.
Just starting.
Yeah.
He was deciding to do this.
Realizing the most gratifying thing in
my life consistently as coming up with
an idea,
you know,
where it goes from the cerebral to the
physical,
like I'm going to write this book.
Okay.
Three years from now I'm still going to
be working on this thing,
so long journey,
so here we go,
or I'm going to get to this country or
I'm going to get back to this country
and come in through that way and you
just make these plans and then months
later,
boom.
There you are.
Like I was in Thailand making a
documentary years ago and I was reading
in the Herald Tribune at breakfast one
morning.
I was in Chiang Mai that the following
year is going to be the 25th anniversary
of the Bhopal disaster in Bhopal,
India when you need carbide,
India Limited,
uh,
the methyl methyl isocyanate tank
exploded.
Killed a bunch of people.
I said,
I'm going,
I'm going to be there for the 25th
anniversary.
So I took out an entire year and
researched and I was there for the 25th
anniversary.
I was in the march.
I snuck onto the,
uh,
the,
the uh,
Union Carbide India Limited site.
I found the exact panel where tank 6:10
blew up.
I found the switch.
I went all the way to where I was
standing in front of it with the tag on
the thing says mic methyl isocyanate.
I think that's it.
Uh,
that was the gas.
They hit the water and went and blew up.
They're making bug spray there.
And so I went all the way to like,
here is where the guy was flicking the
switch going.
Oh No.
The guest scrubbers,
the neutralizers aren't working.
Uh,
and I was sneaking around.
There's like armed guards,
they're not going to shoot you,
but they'll tell you,
they'll kick you off and so I just make
these decisions and then ultimately
you're booking the tickets,
you're booking the hotel and then one
day you are crawling through the weeds,
avoiding security guys on there,
motor scooters with your camera,
sneaking in at a buildings,
getting your shots.
I mean,
I love to take these things from like
sitting in a coffee place going,
oh,
to like,
wow,
here I am in Laos in Zen Queen at the
plane of jars is a place I've always
wanted to go to.
I saw it in a documentary and then two
years later I'm at the plane of jars and
you're writing about all this stuff.
So this is a thing.
You're taking the photographs and you're
writing blog entries A.
Yeah,
I write for the La Weekly.
Once a week I write for rolling Stone
Australia once a month and then I've
read about 27 books and they're in
translation.
Yeah.
Um,
so.
And I,
well I own the company so I sleep with
the owner every night.
And so a lot of my books or travel,
I do like two years of journal at a
time.
And the middle sections,
photographs,
uh,
I'm working on my second photo book.
My first one came out and uh,
the second one is going to be pretty
cool because all my North Korea shots,
that'll be crazy.
Oh Wow.
You went to North Korea to where we're
used to get that visa few years ago.
So sad he was doing Kim Jong.
Il was still alive.
It was Kim Jong,
Il.
Yeah.
The lit last days of Kim Jong Il before
Kim Jong wound.
Yeah.
And it was just a,
you know,
like when I was in Iran,
just like they point you in what you're
supposed to look at.
Don't look over here.
It's a propaganda.
How much time did you spend in North
Korea?
About a week.
I was in Pyongyang and the areas around
Pyongyang and then I went there via
Beijing and then from there up to
Mongolia.
Then over to Butan was North Korea.
Like just sad,
you know,
this poor people who are scared of their
government.
And uh,
my tour guides since I went there alone,
they were very suspicious of me.
So they put two tour spies on me,
the Nice one who talked to me and the
mean one who does scaled and took notes.
And every day that guy would ask me
basically the same question.
It's like when a detective is trying to
peel the layers of onion skin off.
So you said you're a businessman.
I'm like,
yeah,
like,
so what do you do?
Like,
you know,
I edit books,
which is true mine.
And it's really,
what are the books about?
I said,
well,
you know,
uh,
often they're not that good.
And so you're all putting one hotel,
a you and the Dutch tourists and the
Australians.
Everyone's in the one hotel across the
bridge that's with men,
with rifles.
You're not going anywhere.
And so every day they go on their buses
and I get in the car and the Australians
recognize me,
the Brits recognize me and they all want
photos were walking to the um,
uh,
whatever that room is the,
um,
the room where the north and south meet,
uh,
where they come in through the northern
Jordan,
the southern doors,
that blue room on the DSJ.
Uh,
I'll,
I'll come up with the joint,
the JSA,
the joint security area,
something like that.
I pulled one of the Australians to the
site.
I said,
can you please call your friends off me
because my tour spy is starting to ask
me really weird questions about why
people want their photo with me.
And if I'm caught being in movies,
writing books,
rock'n'roll,
I'm going downtown for a meeting that I
might not get out of.
And so he cooled out all his Australian
friends.
But then there's this one British guy
who does kept getting in my face with a
camera because you're all getting taken
to the same places.
And I'll never forget this.
My tour guide,
who for the previous three days was
like,
his English was from school,
like how Henry he went from that to how
does this guy know you and all of a
sudden his English was as good as mine.
I'm like,
oh no,
and I'm not good at lying.
So I said I met him in the breakfast
room.
I don't know,
maybe he's hot for me.
I have no explaining it away and I just
had to kind of go,
I don't know,
and I had to try and avoid this guy and
I was getting overly nervous.
The last day I was there when they
finally took me back to the airport in
Beijing.
I'm like,
damn man,
am I really getting on this plane?
And when the plane took off man,
I just like,
okay,
I did that,
but why wouldn't you just say I'm a
musician.
I'm a feeling.
Will let you inform.
I went on a tourist visa and if you
claim any of that,
you're going to get tons of scrutiny and
they're not going to let you in.
They won't let you in if you're an
artist.
Absolutely.
Because they fear it,
they fear what?
You'll go back to the mainland with
something and you're wrong because
you're a public person.
I don't want to lead a basketball
player.
What the fuck?
Broaden.
Yeah.
How was he towed the party line and just
told Obama,
you know,
just just call your pal Kim.
Sure.
That'll work out great.
And same thing when I was in a,
I was,
I went to Tehran via Dubai and the guy
who met me at the airport after the
airport people got done grilling me.
Uh,
he said,
look,
I got your visa.
I know who you are.
I'm not your tour guide.
He's a government guy.
Don't tell him what you do for a living,
will never get you outta here.
So the last is the last time in that
country.
I'm eating dinner with this guy and his
amazing wife,
they're both like rocket scientists and
they,
you know,
they get by with a website that gets
thesis done.
So his cousin,
her cousin Anousha the woman,
her cousin calls her and says,
your friend Henry's on TV.
And uh,
he dropped his fork and said,
we've got to go.
We had to get you to your hotel.
You got to pack up right now.
We just go to the airport,
check in,
check your luggage,
find a corner,
put your face in it and wait for the
flight.
And I got to the,
I got to the airport like four hours
early because he said you just,
you got to go low.
And so I just sat there in the airport
with my face down and then eventually
got on like,
you know,
the,
the 3:00
AM to Dubai and I was outta there.
Holy Shit.
Yeah.
What would have happened if you got
caught questions which leads to more
questions and you just don't know.
It turns into like,
well he's been interrogated for the last
three months and we don't know.
And since I'm not a hot looking girl,
a president Clinton's not coming to
rescue me.
And,
and so those are the two countries I've
been to where don't tell them what you
do with what I was instructed before I
left.
Wow.
Yeah.
Because anywhere else,
you know,
you just go and show up now.
Every dude,
do you go to every,
all these places that you go to,
do you pick places where there's like
high populations of people?
Do you ever go to like really nomadic
places?
Um,
I,
I tend to choose places where there's
just been an election or there's going
to be an election or there just was a
war where there's conflict,
where you see signs of a,
with the wrath of globalization,
the wrath of global climate change,
uh,
places that are politically hot.
All of these are of great interest to me
during the Bush administration.
He said,
don't go to this country,
this country,
this country.
I went to,
all of them went to every access country
they had and I went to the ones that ms
dot Condoleezza Rice to me not to go to.
I went there too.
I told you personally,
no,
don't go to Bella,
Rosa bellaruse.
And,
uh,
and so I,
I try and I tried to go to all of those
places and,
and I,
I'm fine,
I came back in one piece,
but in the last few years I started
doing more eco travel to learn about,
you know,
coded bio diversity,
codependent ecosystems.
So two years ago,
some are 16,
15,
I had time off because I wasn't on tour.
And so I went to Easter Island,
uh,
via,
I was in Ecuador for a while on the Napo
River,
which is a tributary of the Amazon.
And I went on a science boat and I just
sat with scientists,
botanists,
bird people,
and learned about how the jungle
interconnects and how this parasite
kills that tree,
which fertilizes that tree.
And it's really integrated.
It's amazing.
And they're losing their forest because
of timber and oil,
you know,
the big money and cattle production to a
that I did,
I did not know about.
But when I was in the interior,
and it's all about hardwood and oil and
all those,
uh,
you know,
the Ro one,
people,
the interior tribes are just getting
discovered and,
and you know,
their,
their land is getting cleared out and
the government's making a ton of money
off it cannibalizing their own land.
And uh,
in November of 2015 I was a,
I went to Antarctica and that's the most
substantive trip I've ever made.
That was the most mind blowing trip I've
ever done where,
you know,
you see either you go on deception
island and you look down and there's
bits of broken glass from the whale
killers.
They use that island to process and
render Wales.
So it's like chips of bone of whale bone
and all the crap these people left tin
shacks.
Uh,
there's like a transmission in the sand
from some vehicle and you see what
unregulated slaughter looks like with
his,
like,
hey,
let's make a bunch of money.
Screw the animals will grow back.
And they nearly hunted down the seals
and whales,
those particular species to extinction.
And so I did,
uh,
I got on a ship full of scientists and
you take lectures every day and you walk
around amongst the Gentoo and the Chin
strap and the Adelie penguins and you
learn a lot and it's hard to take
because it's almost destructing in front
of you and it's sad and it's beautiful.
It's like being on the moon.
I mean,
you didn't want to sleep just for
looking out the window or walking around
with some penguin.
Walking by you is surreal.
And I'm hopefully November of this year,
I'll have some time.
So I want to.
I made friends with the scientists on
the ship and they said,
look,
obviously you're really into this.
You should come back because we have a
longer trip.
We do.
That starts in the south Georgia and
islands.
I went,
oh,
I'm there.
So I'm going to see if I,
if I'm not working in November,
I don't have my schedule yet.
If I'm free,
I'm going and you go,
uh,
you go down through Argentina and you
leave from there.
Oh Wow.
So it starts in Antarctica.
You work through Argentina.
How long will you go down the first
time?
The one time I went,
I went to our point of,
sorry,
it's down to [inaudible],
which is the southern most city in the
world and that's where you pick up the
ship and you go through the drake
passage and by day four finally you
start seeing ice and then you look off
and like,
Whoa,
those are penguins and there you are.
But it takes days to get there and the
days to get back.
So there's like three days on either end
where there's kind of nothing to do,
but take lectures in the lounge about
history and all of that,
which I did with my notepad out and
questioned,
uh,
the lecturers afterwards and got a ton
of information.
I keep in touch with him actually.
What a fucking bizarre and exciting life
you live now.
I love it.
Uh,
you know,
knowing I was going to be meeting you
and I must say,
uh,
you know,
this,
you have a lot of fans and I wish I had
a dollar for the last few years.
So many people have been writing me
saying like,
you should be on Joe Rogan's podcast and
like,
or have you done it yet?
And I missed it.
I'm like,
finally,
this was like.
And I knew who you were.
So it wasn't like,
who's this Joe Rogan Guy?
And I'm like,
enough already.
But man,
people like you and I used to.
You remember that show UFC primetime?
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
I was the voice.
I was,
I did that voice.
So I don't know a lot about sports,
but I learned a lot about mma just
because I'm these people.
These fighters become relevant to me
because I'm saying their names over and
over and I'm watching the footage and
you know,
I met Bj Penn.
I interviewed him once for the
independent film channel or no,
for a participant media.
I think it was.
Anyway,
I started being more aware of,
of these fighters and all of this stuff.
And then that's when I,
I saw you and I,
I was thinking about you the other day
knowing I was going to meet you thinking
like here's this guy with this,
you know,
very interesting life because I've seen
the standup on,
on,
on tv and there he is in the middle of
the octagon with some guy who just got
finished knocking the other guy.
Like that's a very eclectic life.
You've got.
I mean you,
you,
you are doing,
I'm sure you didn't grow up anything
like the rest of your family and all the
kids you went to high school with you,
you went to a different way,
right?
Yeah.
obviously.
So when did you decide it's not,
you're not going to be a realtor on your
face isn't going to be on the bus bench?
Well,
I had zero work ethic towards anything
that I didn't enjoy,
but anything that I did enjoy with I'd
become obsessed with just it would
occupy all my thoughts and I couldn't
wait to do it 24 hours a day.
And then when I got out of high school,
I took a year off before I went to
college and the only reason why I went
to college was because I didn't want
people to think when I was a loser,
I was tired of people telling people
that I wasn't doing anything.
So I went to college.
I went to boston,
umass boston for.
The only reason why I went was because I
didn't want people thinking I was a
loser.
And I knew that I could not exist in a
regular job.
I just,
I didn't have it whenever it was.
Yeah,
it's a thing,
you know,
when you know you don't have it,
it's kind of scary.
Like,
oh no,
I'm not going to have a straight life.
Oh no,
what am I going to do?
It was like,
it was radioactive.
Like I would take
construction jobs.
And it was like I was being poisoned,
you know?
It was like,
it was literally like I was getting
ready.
I feel like you're dying.
You're,
you're young and you're awake and you're
like,
I'm dying.
This is killing me.
I thought I was gonna.
Have a life of those jobs.
So I went out of high school.
I went one semester at american
university in Washington dc trying to
see if I liked college.
I liked learning.
I just didn't like,
you know,
I hated school so another four years on
a student loan,
like one semester.
It took me so many years to earn my way
out of that debt.
And so I just kinda went into the
working world going at this is,
this is going to be rough.
I mean this is gonna hurt.
It's gonna be swollen feet and a lot of
top ramen noodles and no sleep and my
crap apartment,
but this is my life.
And I felt like someone was strangling
me because I just knew I didn't know
where I was going to go or what I should
be doing,
but I knew that this wasn't it.
ThIs was going to kill me.
My thing.
There's a lot of
well out there like that and for some
awful reason they never find whatever it
is that can break them free.
They never catch a ride on that river
out,
you know?
and I got lucky,
I found standup comedy and uh,
I had heard already,
I think I love how a lot of it had come
from martial arts too.
I'd fought A lot and I competed a lot in
martial arts tournaments.
And I think that from that I realized
that like these unconventional paths,
they brought me something that I wasn't
getting from regular life.
I get brought me self esteem.
It gave me this feeling that it wasn't
a,
it was the only thing that I'd ever done
my whole life where I've said,
wow,
maybe I'm not a loser,
but I kind of thought I was an outcast
and a loser.
And then all of a sudden I was
successful at something only because I
was obsessed with it.
But then I knew there was no way I was
ever going to be able to hold a regular
job.
And then I got lucky when I was 21 and I
found standup.
And so from then on,
I'd kind of like locked into this thing
where I'm just going to do what I like
and fuck what everybody says because
everybody's given me advice to do this
and advice,
do you do that?
And it never seems to be what I want to
do.
And their advice is coming from a
different world,
you know,
and they mean well,
but they're coming from the whole other
value system at a whole other
expectation of their own lives and what
your life should be in all of that.
And all of it is,
it's not poisoned,
but it says kind of,
uh,
a naphtha to every breath you're taking
and is ultimately useless because
they're always going to tote that line.
That's what they've got.
Like you've got what you've got.
So when you say,
here's how I do it,
they're like,
you're crazy man.
And then you look at them in that job
and you're like,
the,
you're the crazy wasn't amongst us
because I couldn't handle wearing that
tie everyday and taking it from that
dude.
Yeah.
And some people are just like the
corporate world.
I just,
I got lucky and I found a bunch of shit
that I like and if you had said to me,
you know,
if you asked me if I was outside of my
life,
if I didn't know that I existed,
and you said you think it's possible to
be a cage fighting commentator slash
standup comedian,
I'd be like,
no,
they don't go together when you travel
and they say they,
they,
they say occupation,
what do you.
Right,
that's a good question.
What do I do if
I'm going somewhere for the ufc,
I always write ufc commentator.
OkAy.
The easiest one to do because then they
go,
oh yeah,
I know you.
And then they let me in and it's easy,
you know,
if you're getting your passport stamped,
but most of the time I write comic stand
up comedIan.
Okay.
Yeah.
So that's one thing that I definitely
do.
It's that everything else I could kind
of quit and even that I could kind of
quit.
You know what I mean?
You kind of quit everything.
Yeah.
Sometimes.
Maybe it's a good idea to clear the
decks citizen of the world.
That's what I would say,
professIonal citizen of the world.
Yeah,
and also I think if there's a bravery
that one takes when one embraces the
straight world that I simply don't have.
There's a level of guts where you're
like,
well,
I don't really like this job,
but I love my family.
I'm going to do the rIght thing and I
don't have a family,
so I don't really.
I'm not tethered to that value.
I admire it and if I was a dad I'd be
standing up,
but there a kind of guts where you just
get on that bus every day like,
damn man,
I don't like this job and you grimly
hold onto your sack lunch and you just
go do it.
I think like my mom and my dad,
I don't know them that well,
but they were very hardworking people
and I'm not sure how much they ever
really loved their jobs.
Like I can't wait to go to the office.
They just kind of what I'm an adult and
this is what you do.
And they just kinda put,
put themselves through that grinder and
turn the handle themselves and they just
get,
I think a lot of people all over the
world is kinda grimly set their jaw and
go,
I'm an adult,
uh,
and they go out into it and you look at
a guy like iggy pop who could never have
a straight job.
It would just be the thing would fall
over because he's an artIst too.
He's the real thing and it's,
it's innovation,
but it's an intolerance and it's for me,
a,
just a lack of courage to tow that line.
I'm like,
man,
I just don't have it.
I don't have the stamina to go into that
building every day for 28 years.
Like my dad went to one building for his
whole life was one c,
one corporation he worked for.
And then he stopped.
I don't know if he's alive or dead,
but he was that guy in that building
every damn day,
like hours and hours.
There is a dance that when you discuss
these things,
like you don't want to disparage anybody
that had genuinely has shown courage and
grinding it out because for their
families does
take courage.
I just don't have it.
I'm saying I consider them people in the
real world and in my life,
I don't think I really live in the real
world that much.
I live in myself,
invented henry world.
Right.
And uh,
I saw this video with lady gaga.
I don't know much about our music,
but she did this long intro,
the $80 million dollar thing.
And she said she feels like reality.
I hate reality.
I was like,
there you go.
I just can't handle a lot of it and I
don't shy away from it.
I go into situations that are hyper
real,
but I'm that kind of flatline existence
that a lot of we adults engage in.
I think that would have destroyed me.
I would've found alcohol or something
really destructive.
Yeah.
It's a droning,
resonating existences.
Bob,
yeah,
and some people go,
hey,
suck it up and you'll get get in there
and it's not that bad.
Share up and it's not that bad.
I just don't want it.
I just want,
I don't want it malleable.
They,
some people can get through it.
Yeah,
they have,
they just have a different mind.
But if you were like,
if you had a friend that was doing that,
but you know,
that friend really wanted to be a
novelist,
will you just fucking go to try to poke
in your spare time but get out of there.
But the thing is you've said that to him
or her before.
Right?
And like these people write me,
hey man,
my band is pretty good.
Should I,
I'm two years into college.
Should I quit college and take my band
on the road?
And the truth is if that person really
had the thing,
they wouldn't be writing me.
They would just be telling me when they
were playing.
Yeah.
I never asked for advice.
I never,
I just said either I'm going to play
this music or I'm going to die tryIng.
It never occurred to me that there's
asked advice about what and so I,
I never had any fear.
I ran at it and I didn't care if there
was a wall there or the cops I just ran.
But surely you must have had heroes that
did it also before you.
So you felt like death?
No,
no,
not definitely.
Not like you did it,
but a lot of rock stars,
a lot of bands,
a lot of musicians,
a lot of artists.
They pursued their goals.
They went out and chase things and we
knew that it was a path.
The ones I had met before I was doing
music full time.
We're all broke.
Like I met some punk rock bands like
from england,
you know,
like whoever and you're like,
yeah,
you're broke Too.
And they're just crazy people.
And I identified with that,
but sometimes if,
if,
if you eVer been done a show where you
meet that,
that actor who has had like 80 years of
acting class and all,
they talk about their acting coach and
I,
after I get off the set today,
I'm going to go back to my class and
like all they do is take classes.
You're like,
man,
if you're all you're going to do is ever
take classes,
you're never going to.
The rubber's never going to hit the road
because you're always in the on pause
with the acting.
Some days you just gotta go like,
I'm doing this.
And like that's me.
And if it doesn't work,
man,
it's really going to hurt.
Yeah.
So here we go.
Like with music,
I never like,
oh,
are we going to make it make what?
I'm just trying to do a good shot.
I never thought I would ever make money
doing music.
I never thought I'd ever be able to pay
my rent.
I just reconciled my life to a life of
fighting bad tasting food and sleeping
next to the drummer,
snored all night in the back of the van
hoping the bass,
the bass player,
the guitar player didn't drive this into
a tree because we didn't have a driver.
It is what it is.
It's independent music and you just
crawl through these tours that makes you
pretty tough like a junk yard dog.
But I never thought it would ever
change.
I just figured this is your life and
eventually,
you know,
the guy hits you with something and you
die in the hospital.
I just was not a fatalist but I'm like,
this is it.
And I never saw past that.
And then in the eighties,
you know,
the band got bigger or whatever.
Um,
but I,
I've always run it things going,
well,
this is,
this is it or die or I never thought
there was any wiggle room or any cushion
or much alternative.
I'm not that resourceful.
I'm just kind of,
you know,
crazy enough to run at it.
And by running a really hard,
I've gotten through it,
but it's not because I'm smart or good
looking,
it's just because as richard gere once
said,
I've got nowhere else to go and that has
really helped me where I'm going to get
through this tour.
So I got nothing else going on.
I'll stay in this band because I got
nowhere else to go.
But being this incredibly hard to be in
band and that's been very helpful to me
like this.
This really hurts.
Well that's better than the painted
standing there with the apron behind the
counter.
That was a different kind of pain.
Yeah.
But you've managed to transcend that,
obviously
managed to find this very unique path in
life where you're doing all these
different things.
You're not no longer in a band anymore.
And now you're this worLdwide travelers
slash performance artists.
Were you doing these spoken word things
or.
They're really funny.
It's kind of like stand up and I had a
lot of comedy.
Yeah.
I had a bought a couple of your cds way
back in the day.
It was like in the nineties.
And uh,
cause I thought it was music and uh,
I saw that you were.
And then as a spoken word like what the
fuck is this?
And I listed,
I was like,
it's this kinda like,
stand up.
But,
but in a freer form.
Yeah.
More anecdotal.
Now,
did you do,
did you,
when did you start doing that?
That many,
many years ago in 1983 a,
there was a local promoter in hollywood
and he would take like 20 people it give
everyone five minutes and it'd be the
singer and the gun club.
The guy from the minute man,
the guy from this band,
the girl from that event.
And I would go to these shows because
even when was bad it was great.
And everyone's cheering,
you know,
all these people.
So if it sucked,
you know,
you,
you to applaud even harder black flags,
bass player would be on these gigs and
he'd go up and read from his notebook is
an amazing intellect and I would always
go hang out with him.
And,
and one night the promoter said,
You got a big mouth.
Let's get you up there next week,
and I go,
ah,
yeah,
when am I going to do?
And he said like,
you know,
10 minutes,
10 bucks or whatever it was.
I said,
I'll take that money and the next week I
got up there and I read something that I
had written and told a story about what
had happened at band practice the day
before when the white supremist try to
run over our guitar player with his car
and the audit is like,
I go,
yeah,
that was tuesday in the life of black
flag.
Well my tIme is up.
I got to go.
and so I walked off stage,
big applause,
and everyone came up to me and said,
when's your next show?
I said,
well,
I'm going on tour.
I thought they meant the band.
They went under this the next year where
you just talk.
I go,
well,
I got this $10 bill.
That was it.
And the promoter said,
you're really good at that.
You're a natural.
How about you opened for two of my poets
next week we'll give you 15 minutes and
a few times around the that there,
those poets are opening for me,
whIch they didn't like and 1985 I had
done a cross country tour and you know,
12 to 15 people a night and they called
it spoken word,
which I thought there's a way to
starvation was I don't want to go see a
gig,
this spoken word,
the snore fest,
so I've always just called it a talking
show.
So I would read things and anecdote
between pages and then one day I just
started,
stopped bringing the things to read on
stage and said,
look,
here's what happened when I was in
holland and the thing and I just tell
stories.
And by the late eighties I was doing the
entire continent of europe,
scandinavia,
Australia,
New Zealand,
and then it went on and on with the last
tour is 19 countries and 165 shows.
That's why I came back from last week.
It's like it traveled at comedies like
me and a microphone and.
But I,
it's more general admission theaters,
but every once in a while I'll do like
the melbourne comedy festival,
the sydney comedy festival,
or like three nights of comedy and I'm
like doing an hour on one of those
nights.
I did a comedy club on this last tour.
There was a night off or doing a thing
at the last bucket or one of those
places.
And you know,
with the pa,
the pa is like bolted into the wall.
There's no monitors.
There's one light.
And uh,
me and my big tour bus out front,
it's like right next to the strip bar.
And I went in there and went,
okay,
all those little eight by 10 frame
photos on the walls.
I don't go into places like this right
below me.
It's just not my world.
Sold the place out.
The audience couldn't have been nicer.
And the owner thanked me and I said,
man,
if I'm ever back in this part of
Illinois,
I'll do this venue again.
And he said,
we'll be here.
And it was a really good time.
And so a lot of what I do kind of lends
itself to comedy in that life plus time
most of the time it's funny and comedy
don't try and I don't write material
really,
but when you try things that are.
I just basically report on that which is
funny and many things occur to me either
ultimately or eventually to be funny,
like almost anything.
Then obviously some things are never
going to be funny,
but most things are like,
I don't know which way your politics
lean that much,
but you can look at the president
administration go like eat,
we're all going down the drain.
Or you can go,
man,
this is the lowest hanging fruit.
This students has jumped up on a table
onto the silver platter with his ass in
the air and an apple already.
His mouth like,
this is going to be great.
Like he's serving himself.
He's jumped into my lap.
This is great.
And so there's different ways of looking
at all of this.
And I guess comedians just look at
things differently.
I've met many of them.
I'm not one,
but there's a lot of comedy or at least
humorous moments that inform what I do
on stage,
which allows me to go for a long time
onstage because they had no humor in it.
It would be stultifying boring for me
and for the audience and a lot of ways
when an administration has really fucked
up,
comics do take joy in it because they
know like,
like when the book during the bush
administration,
like there was eight years of gold and
trump is that times five or 10,
you know,
it's,
it's this,
but it's also when you find that gold
mine of humor,
it also equates on the other end to a
disastrous time for the country and
that's where it gets scary.
Environmentally.
It's getting scary.
There was a,
there's a proposal now to get rid of
public lands and to,
to make public lands private and start
tapping into them and sucking out the
resources and ruin all these places that
people go and hunt and fish and hike and
it's been,
you know,
I,
I think it's a really beautiful thing,
what they call the comments in this
country where you can go to the park and
I don't know if you ever spent time in
parks,
there's a decency that you'll often find
where the family picks up the garbage
and you'll even see the little kid
picking up the cup because it's our park
and I'm not mr kubiak necessarily,
but I love that idea.
Like don't screw this up man.
It's yours and mine and while we're
here,
let's cut the crap and be really cool to
each other and really appreciate these
trees.
So I grew up in Washington dc and you've
been there.
It's a small town,
dropped into a park.
Everywhere you go,
you run into a deciduous tree and he's
rock creek park with the white house
near it.
I mean it's just park park park.
And so I grew up every day I'm outside
looking at bats and finding toads and
like outside of my apartment is a park
and I was outside all the time and I
really came to love that ethic of this
is ours,
like when you're on the subways and in
Russia there's no garbage.
She,
they really take pride in their soul
with their beautiful and it's our subway
don't litter.
And I,
I think there's a rectitude and a moral
decency that we americans skew towards
when we're in these places that we're
all somewhat responsible for.
And to take that away.
When everything becomes me,
mine,
I drew the line,
you step over to kill you,
all that stuff.
It doesn't bring out the best in us.
And I think those public lands are
really part of what keeps us from,
you know,
going crazy and to see them the,
because you know,
there's,
there's people like trump who look at
central park,
go,
what a waste,
what a waste.
The it.
I can put nine hotels for casinos in a
theme park in there.
Well,
teddy roosevelt and a lot of the people
that established the national park
system in this country many,
many years ago,
they had an incredible vision.
They realized that we have this amazing
landscape and they decided to preserve
it and put it in the trust of the
public,
make it a public thing where anyone can
go,
anyone can go and hike,
anyone can go and and some beautiful
things.
Amazing and it doesn't exist anywhere
else.
It's a really,
really rare resource that we have here
in America and right now during this
administration,
we're in danger of losing that.
It's,
it's very scary.
You know,
it's,
you know,
not wanting to get up every day with a
hate list of people and I don't think
Donald Trump wakes up every day going,
how can I screw up a bunch of people?
I reallY don't think that's on his menu,
but I do think he's a businessman who's
looking to make deals that the tell for
me was when the president said,
if vladimir putin agrees to help us in
the fight against isis,
I'll consider lifting those sanctions.
It's nOt,
you know,
we'll make a deal.
He does that,
I'll do this,
we'll get that here,
gets that.
That's a deal.
He's a deal maker.
That's not really a deal in global
affairs necessarily all the time.
Certainly not with that guy on that
particular issue and I think he's kind
of tone deaf to some of the more nuanced
things that it takes to be America in an
ever more interconnected world with
evermore diminishing resources and to
start privatizing a America chopping up
the parks and all that.
It's real sad if that happens is I
really enjoy,
uh,
being able to go into a place like I can
walk in here or even though I grew up as
a shy kid who didn't play well with
others,
so I would go to the library all the
time that,
that library card and I can take this
book home.
Well,
yeah,
you got to take care of it.
Okay.
And I read the book and take it back.
All thoSe alfred hitchcock,
you know,
stories for kids or whatever.
I read all that stuff and the library is
a big deal for me because I felt like an
adult.
I have my card,
I can walk into this massive,
interesting smelling cool building and
it's mine.
The whole thing is my.
I couldn't believe the freedom I had in
there.
These ancient seats in the place smelled
of books and it was mine.
I never got my head.
It was never not amazing to me to walk
into the library and like any damn book
I want,
I can walk into any section and no one's
going,
hey kid,
get out of here.
Right?
And I.
That's what you get in a park and you
know when you're in New York,
there's a lot of that.
They're like,
look,
it's our sidewalk.
It's our subway.
Be cool man.
And there's a.
There's an inherit a lot of people fear
in New York.
If they never spent time there and
there's an inherent decency amongst new
yorkers because you are so smashed
together,
you're going to make human contact,
right?
You're going to bump into someone.
That is what it is,
so you better bring some humor and a
little bit of like,
hey,
it's okay and I see that in new yorkers,
just really great greatness and when you
you make us cheap and petty and we
turned into some twilight zone episode.
That is what I fear in this country is
us kind of cheating ourselves out of how
great we are when you don't scare the
crap out of us all the time.
Yeah.
Well,
I mean trump has just such a polarizing
figure.
I hope that it unites us in a lot of
ways so we realize how good we have it
and we realize what really is important
and that having this guy who so many
people were opposed to and having these
policies at so many people are opposed
to even if you're not opposed to him.
I know a lot of people that supported
him that now looking at some of these
policies,
particularly the public land policy and
they're kind of freaking out.
I think a lot of that is gonna unite
folks and it's gonna make people
understand what is important.
Like that gigantic women's march here.
That was impressive.
Incredibly impressive.
I mean,
who saw that coming out of nowhere.
I mean one,
one statement that he makes goofing
around with,
uh,
a guy that Billy Bush character on a bus
essentially led to that movement.
Otherwise,
why else would it be a only a woman's
march when he gets an office?
It Was because he's got this perceived
attitude about women and this is a
rejection of that.
Yeah.
And uh,
I think he's getting used to being on
the global stage where,
you know,
every hIccup,
every cough shifts the world's markets.
And I think other presidents have rocked
that responsibility far more gracefully.
Even presidents I don't necessarily
agree with.
They really understood the awesome
weight of that job and they really kind
of feared it and tried their best even
presence I whose policies I disagree
with,
I think they really got the magnitude.
When you think about your life,
where you have this wander last and this
passion for exploring new environments
and learning about new cultures and you
know,
and you were also talking about just
the,
the fucking great poll of death because
it is there and it's always to be
considered when you're looking at a guy
like that who was older than us.
He's 70 something years old,
right?
And that fucking life is a meat grinder.
That job is the greatest aging job
you've ever seen.
People.
We've seen people go in and they see the
beat barack obama before and after
pictures know it.
That's crazy.
So what is going to happen to trump?
I mean he's a fucking old man already
with bad die and why?
Like what is what,
when you have $4,000,000,000
or whatever the fuck he has,
when you have your name on all these
buildings all over the world.
Like what is the motivation to continue
that?
That that's what I've.
I've always wondered with the koch
brothers,
like the two angriest man in America and
in the obama,
the tyranny of obama,
they'd always opine about like,
dude,
you got $34,000,000,000
you can have me killed right now and all
the pizza you want and what?
Why are we so angry again?
Oh,
well,
where's,
where's the tyranny in your life?
thIrty 4 billion a shut up.
And I think with some people,
I did a movie many years ago,
one of the first ones I was ever in with
a very big movie star and someone told
me how much he makes in a year.
And I went,
that's wow,
and why does he,
what's up with that?
He said,
well,
all his friends have 100 million and so
he wants to catch up.
I said,
but after the first 50 and it's like
going out in the rain while you're
soaking wet,
going out.
It's raining like pal,
your warranty wet.
Like what do you do with the other 80
billion?
Like what?
What is it?
And I think with some people it's maybe
coming from some knowing insecurity and
nothing's ever big enough like you've
been around famous people.
I've met a number of big actors or big
rock stars and the big,
the bigger the rock star,
it just my experience,
the more humble and cool are the more
they love music and they're like,
they're humble in front of it and they
ask what you're doing.
And,
and I've met some,
I've been lucky,
I've met a lot of my rock heroes and
they're like,
just really hoping.
Like I met george carlin once,
I just on the beacon theater and he was
about to go do one of hIs hbo specials
there.
And he said,
did,
did people get the jokes?
I said,
what do you mean?
So people understand you when you're
onstage,
do you eat?
Do you think it'll be okay?
I was like,
you're asking me if your show will be
okay,
your church fricken carla and man,
I mean like,
are you kidding?
And to see that kind of not insecurity
with that kind of like,
hey,
did it go okay?
Because I got to go there next,
yikes.
Like george carlin,
you walk on water,
but the fact that he was still wanting
it to be okay that he didn't think I've
got this on george carlin.
I was like,
damn,
he still open.
He still look knowing that it could go
south.
You might have a stinking night while
the cameras are on and he's still fears
having a bad show.
It means so much to him.
And I think if you're in that mode,
you can greet the day better.
But when you look at things like,
well,
I don't have as much as he has or some
guy made a nasty tweet about me and I'm
going to get on twitter and answer back.
Oh no.
And I'm the president.
No nothing.
The point I'm making is nothing satiates
that thirst,
like the,
he's in the top executive slot and he's
still probably grumbling about something
or just wanting to win.
Uh,
and now that he's got it,
I,
when he did his acceptance speech,
I was in Washington on the night of the
election onstage at the lincoln theater.
I watched the whole damn thing until
five in the morning when he made his
acceptance speech and the look on his
face on the,
on mr trump's face was a wow.
I've just saw off a big chunk of meat
for myself.
Oh no,
it wasn't joy.
it was like,
now I got to go to all those meetIngs.
Oh damn.
This is a big dog I just bought.
This is a lot,
a lot of,
you know,
a big deal.
And I just,
I think one of the ways he's,
he'll escape the stress of it is I think
he'll put it off on other people.
He'll delegate.
Mike pence will be,
it'll be president pence and you know,
the other guy just looking good for the
cameras.
And so I think that's how he'll get
through it because it destroyed bush.
eight years of the presidency took bush
was a very handsome man.
When he walked into office,
he came out of there destroyed and it
was far younger.
Right.
How old was bush when he was in his
fifties when he got into office?
Late forties,
I think a little older than Mr.
Obama.
And obama to heroin gray,
he just got skinnier somehow just get so
tired.
It's just because you don't get saying
this on stage the other night,
the presidents don't get that.
Three in the morning phone call,
mr.
President,
uh,
in Maine,
the cat that was in the tray,
the fire department got the cat down.
The cat's fine.
God bless you.
God bless the United States of America.
They get come down to the situation room
and look at the high resolution video
footage of the girls and tests and
sailing through the air for the drone
strike that went.
It's zig when it should have zagged.
They get bad news and then they gut
wrenching decisions where they log.
Yep,
go,
we're going in and all those people are
going to die.
That there's every president makes those
decisions and it's a job.
You'd have to.
You couldn't pay me enough that I
wouldn't want a day of it.
And I think you either have to be either
a nut or truly think I've got this.
I'm neither a.
And so I'm not that kind of megalomaniac
and I just don't ever think I got it.
And I don't know what trump is going to
do with a job that has not.
you see the last days of johnson and he
didn't even serve two terms,
like via the Vietnam war,
destroyed johnson.
His face was falling off his sculpt,
those sad shots of him and mcnamara in
the situation room with his,
his,
his hand is on his cheek and his face is
falling down his chest because every one
of those deaths I think really aggrieved
the presIdent.
He's an interesting president of the
more you read about him,
more interesting he becomes.
But I think it's a job that fairly
destroys.
The only one that didn't seem to really
destroy was clinton.
I don't dunno why.
He seemed to kind of walk out of there
like,
you know,
hey,
yeah,
but he looks like shit now.
Well,
I mean he's paid for it now.
yeah.
But some sort of the last few
presidents,
it's damn stressful being running this
country.
And,
and because we're so free,
I mean,
you've traveled.
No country in the world enjoys our level
of freedom and not our kind of freedom
like even Germany,
england,
where you know,
it's the western world is free,
is not nearly as free as this,
and we're so free to try and tell us
what to do.
you don't tell an american what to do
and sadly the president is part of the
federal government and so the states are
already pissed off at you and any
president,
you know,
you get bucketed,
you went on vacation.
Well,
it's christmAs.
How dare you go on vacation?
Uh,
I went to my momma's house.
Oh,
you're seeing your mom now.
I mean,
think a president can do where half the
country doesn't get mad and we'll see
how our new president takes It.
I want them to be successful because I
want every boat in America to be lifted
by the tide.
I want good for people.
I disagree with people.
I'm not.
That guy was the same.
Yeah.
I don't want some state to go into the
toilet because they don't read good or
something.
That's just not how I want to run it.
Well,
I like the fact that he's talking about
rebuilding the infrastructure and
putting people to work in that regard
and rebuilding a menu of american
manufacturing.
I hope that really does happen and
people do get good jobs and the economy
does rise up.
What I worry about is all this corporate
raider mentality backed by these people
that think that he's somehow or another
looking out for the little guy.
Like I just,
I just wonder,
you know,
I wonder what his motivations are and I
wonder what houses all gonna play out,
but I guess everybody does,
but you know,
to me when someone says,
oh,
this,
this new president,
what he's doing is unprecedented.
I'm like,
no,
america's have broken 45.
We just keep repeating.
Trickle down economics would more parts
or less parts per million in that.
In the early days of slavery,
to be well landed.
Gentry in America was great.
You bought land,
you bought the materials,
and you built your plantation.
You bought livestock,
human and animal.
When they bred,
you kept the offspring,
human,
offspring,
chickens,
all of It was yours and you got free
labor.
Things were great until 18,
65,
the 13th amendment,
the abolishment of slavery,
and so that mentality of like you had a
good day to day because I didn't beat
you.
That's your good day and here's your
rule and what do I pay you?
Your here's your rule,
get back to the field and have another
day where I don't beat you.
That's a good day for you.
That was an un bothered road to a brutal
utopia.
And what you have over the years as
these speed bumps,
civil rights,
and that's where you get
institutionalized apartheid.
You get jim crow,
you get an expansion of the clinton,
you get segregatIonist laws that sat on
the books until like brown v board of
education,
1954,
uh,
Virginia versus,
what v Virginia,
that's the message donation laws,
1967,
oboe,
obergefell v hodges,
marriage equality 2015.
And these are speed bumps.
If you're oppressive and you just want
to get paid this guy what you feel like
giving him minimum wage and all that
stuff is your enemy because you don't
want these people have been able to
stand up.
And when I think when Mr.
Trump said,
make America great again,
I hate to say,
I think he was talking about 18,
61 in the years before when I paid you
what I want it to.
It's my factory.
How dare the government tell me what,
what to pay you minimum wage.
That's what he means,
I think.
What do you mean
wait?
Like I don't want you to have a bad
life,
but look,
I have a great factor.
I'm giving you a great job.
Here's what I'm going to pay.
Rejoice.
You've got a job.
But it's not enough to feed my family.
Well,
you know,
beans on the weekend shear up and I
don't,
I don't think he wakes up every day
going like,
I want to kill people.
I want to murder americans and have them
have a crap life.
I just think he thinks like,
look,
we'll own stuff and you'll be the
benefIciary as it falls from my mouth
and trickles down to you.
You'll be happy that I have so much
money because I'm a,
a beneficence master.
Now you're a guy that's really seen
probably more of the world than one 10th
of one percent of the population of
America.
I mean,
you've been to so many different places.
Yeah.
Now,
do you thInk that because of that,
you have a unique perspective on what is
possible today because like in 2017,
if you just live in America,
this is the only thing you've known you
think of the world is sort of this sort
of state that we exist in,
but you haven't gone in North Korea
having on a Mongolia having gone to all
these different places,
we see oppressive regimes.
You see very bizarre cultures where
people are rigid in their ability to
move around and rigid in their ability
to behave and express themselves.
And you see that that could have turned
out like that here,
you know,
but it didn't.
We,
we have this sort
of experiment in self government and
it's sort of hobbled along and patched
up with duct tape and gorilla glue,
but it's here.
It's here we are a miracle.
The fact that there's not been a second
civil war,
more catastrophic than the first shows
you how amazing the constitution is and
even though we disagree a lot between
the states and all of that,
that we do ultImately get along.
we're all still united.
Who did we argue a lot,
but we're still here and I did two years
of programming for the history channel.
I was talking to one professor and he
gave me that sent to me.
He goes like,
we are a miracle because think of all
the people in this country you disagree
with and yet here we are and what I have
found by travel is what humans can still
survive when somebody go like there's
poverty in America.
Sure there is,
but not poverty lIke you see in
Bangladesh,
not poverty like you see in the streets
of cairo.
I mean there's.
There's poverty that no american will
ever experience on in this country.
It'll never happen.
Like no way.
There's,
there's a,
a stick of poverty stick that this
country will never really whooped with
that for other people in the world.
Millions of them.
That is their entire life.
I was on a boat years ago on my way to
timbuktu with this guy I traveled with
before,
a twitter egg man named mahmud.
I've been to,
I went to the desert music festival
twice to see all these african is the
desert music.
There was a festival that had it.
They had in Mali,
in the,
in the sahara desert.
And now it's too dangerous of the
festivals no more.
But I went to go because I buy all these
records from molly and bands.
So I wanted to go see them do it in the
desert.
So I went in 2008,
nine or nine and 10,
something like that.
And Uh,
I went overland through doggone country
one year and then the next year I hooked
back up with this guy,
my mood,
and we took the Niger river on a boat.
The guy chain smokes every day.
And I said,
mark,
mood man,
like you're a freaking chimney.
Like,
what are you trying to do?
And he laughed.
He said,
I'm like,
I'm 30.
I was supposed to Be dead two years ago
because people in his tribe get about 28
to 30 years.
It is.
Hunter laughed and kept smoking like
okay.
And so what I've learned by travel is
what humans can still,
how they can still live in spite of what
they,
what their circumstances are and what
that means to me when I get back here is
you have a lot to lose.
I mean iT can get so much worse and
you'll still get by because he was just
so resourceful and were so tough.
But w,
w we shouldn't ever have to go near that
because we're smarter than that and you
know,
me and this other guy might disagree and
he might call me a bunch of nasty names
on the internet,
but ultimately does he really want to
kill me?
Nah.
If I was in a burning car,
would he try and pull me out?
Probably If I had a sandwich and he was
hungry when I give him half.
Yeah.
And I think to forget that aspect of us
and since at least the bush
administration with the polarization in
this country has been so extreme,
I think we have started to forget that
we can be there for each other and I'm
not saying we all need to have a big
group hug,
but when we are having such vociferous
dIsagreements about healthcare,
we're talking about people being able to
stay alive.
Why are we arguing?
Right?
Instead of just making a system where
like the little old lady doesn't have to
be in fear of dying alone with heaters
that don't work or whatever.
Like,
come on,
we have such a beautiful patch of land
because you know,
I've been all over the world.
There's some parts where people live
here.
What are you people doing here like
this?
This part of africa wants you dead.
Why are you here as where we live,
where America by we are.
This is one long vacation we have in
America as far as climate.
It gets cold,
but you can always boogie down the road
to miami in a greyhound bus in seven
hours.
Be on your shorts.
I mean,
we've got a good here in every possible
way.
Yeah,
we,
we certainly do.
We really do.
Now.
I think it's really important what you
were talking about,
about people on the Internet and that
sort of bizarre communication that we
experienced today.
Yeah.
Do you remember pre-internet,
me,
you were a grown man before the internet
came around.
Don't you think that this,
this existence that we have right now,
what we are sort of communicating
without looking at each other without
being there,
let's be really cowardly.
YeAh.
Without social cues,
without it feeling emotions because of
cruel statements without like looking
each other in the eye.
I don't really feel lIke we're designed
to communicate like this and it's.
well,
it's certainly goes against how I was
raised.
It's very strange.
It's a very strange time in that regard.
Yeah,
and it leads to a lot of pettiness and
just really mean stuff where the issuer
of that,
whatever that means,
email or whatever.
I wonder if they look back at that a
week later,
you're like,
well man,
who was I that afternoon?
Because you.
There's stuff you can read because it
peels the paint off your car.
I mean I go on these chat room websites
and I just read.
I don't ever post things.
I just read and when we had our last
president,
there is things said about him and his
family.
You're like,
did you just write?
That was depressing.
Like I read like three hours one night
and like a 2000 and something like a
baboon's.
Oh man.
I mean it really like you.
That just happened.
Like someone actually thinks that I
don't know.
Well,
what's interesting is when they get
found out and someone exposes whoever
wrote that and then they focus on them
publicly and you see the scrutiny of
thousands,
if not millions of people come down
those folks and how they fuck those
people turn into that.
They turned into that same monster.
They have the green light to go after
that and and all of a sudden know it's
like a twilight zone episode.
Like now you got the stick.
Like,
you know,
why are you hitting that guy?
Because he was hitting a guy with a
stick.
And so I come and I'm sure you can
identify with this,
I come from the world of if you say
something,
that guy comes around the corner,
go like,
what'd you say?
Wham.
And he just broke your face.
And so I never say anything about anyone
not expecting to turn the corner and be
face to face with that person.
And so If I ever talked about a
politician or you know,
I had a lot of disagreements with judge
scalia and people like that and I'd
write about it in the la weekly,
I would have loved to have debated the
14th amendment.
The antonin scalia has said it didn't
have any of the traction that I think it
does.
And at any politician like bucket on,
including trump,
which I have the 14th amendment again,
the four equal protection under the law.
18,
68 is basically if you're born and
raised here,
you get all the same protections as the
wealthy land guy is basically slave
protection.
It was one that came after the 13th.
There was to shore up the 13th
amendment.
SlaverY is my favorite amendment of the
constitution.
It's five clauses,
the two,
three,
four,
and five are basically governmental
mechanics,
but it's the first paragraph and it's
beautiful.
Uh,
the all,
all people born and naturalized in the
United States are a resident of the
United States and of the state wherein
they reside,
et cetera,
et cetera.
And it's a beautiful thing and I think
that was put in place to make sure
racists,
uh,
understood that the 13th amendment
wasn't going anywhere.
And that's what gives like,
you know,
people like,
well,
you're an anchor baby.
That's just the 14th amendment and
scalia didn't,
he is a,
uh,
a descent on obergefell v hodges.
He came down very hard on the 14th
amendment,
which is my personal favorite.
So,
but my rationale is if I talk about
somebody,
I expect to see that guy within five
minutes and have to answer for what I
said.
So I,
I am very careful with what I say
because I,
I take responsibility for what I say.
Like you said something mean about dick
cheney.
Yes,
I did.
He's right over here.
Really?
Can I talk please?
Let me,
I want to talk to him.
If you stare at him,
he turned to stone.
Well,
you know what I mean?
I just don't say anything that I'm not
ready to because I just met ann coulter.
No,
after you wrote that thing about her,
you know that thing I wrote about her
and then there was a video.
You writing it?
Yeah.
I really,
really enjoyed that,
but thank you very much.
I'd love to meet ann coulter and just,
you know,
spend an evening with her.
Just figure out,
you know,
what the fuck is going on?
He gets so much self loathing.
How do you do that?
She's so odd.
I know one,
a female comedian who I'm sure you're
very well aware of.
Um,
and she knows her well,
you know,
they've met on like bill maher or
something and I said what she likes.
She said the self-loathing is like just
off the charts.
She's not a bad person.
you feel kind of sorry for when you're
in the green room with her because she
does hates her.
And I,
you know,
I'm ms dot cuLture is not here to defend
herself.
But um,
that's what I've heard,
that she's not a bad person.
She just,
uh,
you know,
reads every tweet about herself and she
stays up at night with all of that.
I don't know,
bill maher's friends with her,
which I've always found very odd,
like he talks about early as his friend
and he has her on and they joke around,
they're jovIal together.
And I'm like,
well,
what the fuck is going on?
they're well,
who is she?
Is she that?
Is she this thing?
She's a little bit of both.
Yeah.
So a little bit of both.
Bit of an advocate.
She knows that she says stuff that's
over the top.
It helps her sell books and gets her
anytime.
Recent one with the trump book she wrote
me,
just the cover alone was like so
bizarre,
but it's there to piss you off or get
you inspired and eventually you can go
to some market and buy those books for
$5 because honestly they don't sell and
not really.
That's why you can buy them for five
bucks.
I have a few of her books.
I bought them at places like costco with
a big sticker on them.
I've read like a couple of her books.
They gO through fast.
I read,
um,
the bushes,
autobiography.
I got that at costco.
She wrote a bush hog autobiography of
George W.
Bush.
Yeah.
It was a krill,
a coloriNg book for adults.
There's no footnotes.
There's no index,
but you kind of ended up liking him
after the book is over.
But I.
Yeah,
cause he just did.
It doesn't seem like the worst guy,
but I,
I read um,
sarah pailin,
his last book,
amerIca by heart.
I got that crayon a no,
but it's like,
you know,
80 point type.
It's like a,
it's like a 5,000
word feature in a skinny book and it's,
it's funny.
But I,
I read these books.
I want to see sometimes where these
people are coming from.
Like there's that fellow,
that internet terrorist guy.
I'm the guy with the long polysyllabic
greek,
last name internet terrorist.
Papa,
papa,
papa hippolytus.
He has that book.
He's,
he's on his spoken word tour right now.
The dangerous faggot tour.
Oh,
milo.
Milo yiannopoulos.
Yes.
I've had them on a couple of times.
He's interesting to me.
He's a fucking weirdo.
Oh,
was a very interesting guy.
He has incredibly smart in march and I
wrote in the only weekly,
two weeks ago I said,
I'm going to read his book.
I want to read it.
I don't think I'm going to find
consensus,
but I'm honestly interested in finding
out where this guy gets off because he
doesn't offend me.
I just kind of feel bad for them.
Why do you feel bad for them?
Just because It's a lot of ag rhoda,
to kinda drag around.
I mean you have to kind of invent all of
that.
She sat.
Just say it pal.
You're just manufacturing stuff.
That must be a real drag to.
I would like to see the two of you guys
talked together.
I think that be kind of fascinating.
I actually enjoy milo.
I enjoy his company.
I enjoy talking to him.
He's not a bad guy,
but a lot of the stuff he says is
retarded,
but I think he's.
But he's trying to get somebody to jump
out of their seat for sure.
Yeah,
and he has a book coming out called
dangerous.
I think it's on amazon.
His whole thing is the dangerous faggot
tour.
That's,
we can't have that on the cover of a
book,
so it's just dangerous.
But,
um,
I,
I went to amazon and sho nuff it's
coming out next march I believe.
And so I'm going to read it.
I'd probabLy be a best seller.
He's smart.
Yeah,
I,
I know he's smart,
but I was just interested to see.
I mean,
I,
I read,
uh,
a big part of dick cheney's
autobiography is fascinating because it
in latin,
like ancient latin,
but like,
you know,
the guys had 80 lights.
I mean he's like served under like five
presidents or something.
I mean,
he's not a boring guy.
It's been a very interesting life.
You know,
nixon,
ford,
reagan,
he's been in the oval office a lot.
It's been in that building a lot.
He knows where all the bodies are buried
and I don't want to live with these
people,
but as far as like seeing,
you know,
reading what they have to say,
I'm,
I'm curious in that way and that I want
to know what's on someone's mind I might
not agree with all the time.
Right.
Well,
it's a good way to broaden your
perspective,
get an idea of how they're actually.
Yet everyone is essentially coming from
the truth,
their version of it.
That's acting class,
right?
You got to be in that moment or
whatever.
And when I'd see these trump rallies,
these people really do hate hillary
clinton.
They hate barack obama and they really
do want to build that wall.
It's all his real is me sitting here
with you right now and I might not
agree,
but you can't not say they're sincere.
They're burning analog.
It is as real as anything you've ever
felt as real.
I don't necessarily want to get into the
inner mechanics of,
of that person because I kind of already
know where it's coming from.
A lot of scene of phobia and half
knowledge,
but you can't say that they're not legit
and you just saw that they spoke quite
loudly and Mr.
Trump one,
well not the popular vote but the
electoral college certainly.
And so I want to know more about who I
share a country with.
I cAn't spend all day with it,
but I do designate some bit of the day
to try and figure this out.
Otherwise,
how do you get up the road if you don't
know?
Because I don't want my enemies in
America.
I don't want to.
I don't want enemies in my own country.
People that disagree with.
Yeah.
But ultimately I want to get up the road
with them in order to do that.
I can't be,
I don't want to get beat up by some guy
getting out of his pickup truck to drill
some freedom Into my forehead with his
fists because,
you know,
I'm just not built for it.
And who is.
So I'm looking for a higher way to get
up the road.
I don't,
I'm not all that hopeful,
uh,
but I,
I still try and dissect it that were
forensically go through that,
that american id because I travel
through America.
It's what I've been doing for 36 years.
I meet more americans than any
president.
I hear the stories,
like you hear the stories,
henry,
my friend died in Iraq and he loved you
and I hear that story.
It might.
My friend killed himself last month and
I'm really screwed up about it.
I want to tell you about it.
So I hear I get a lot of input and it
makes you like all these people,
like on the fat gay guy in Utah.
No one likes me and my parents kicked me
out of the house when I was 18 because
I'm cain and like,
you,
you go,
oh man.
You don't want to be that at anyone.
When you hear stories like that,
all you want to do is like give them a
divo record and keep breathing.
Kid don't,
don't self harm.
And so the more stories I hear,
it makes me want to be more decent to my
fellow americans understand us better.
And that's one of the reasons I travel
globally.
It's one of the reasons I do a lot of
shows in America
and I do a lot of listening and I think
that's what we don't do anymore.
We listed.
But when you logged on at patriot one 85
and you give some liberal snowflake,
whatever they call these people,
uh,
some grief on the internet,
you're only listening to yourself.
You disliked disagreeing with people in
piling on.
It's very frat boy.
Yeah.
Well you definitely can get it into an
echo chamber and lose perspective and
you don't get out.
Yeah.
Well,
I think what you're saying is beautiful
because I mean,
it is a good idea to have an open mind
and try to find out why these people
think in diametrically opposed ways to
the way you think or what.
Find out what,
what is the motivation,
what was their background,
what would cause them to reach this
conclusion?
And ultImately,
how can we get going because life is
short and I want renewable energy and my
time.
I don't want it to be feared.
I don't want solar panels to be,
you know,
I'm sick of this.
Who says so panels.
Just,
you know what I mean?
Like that whole idea of like,
oh,
what are you a science guy with your
pussy?
like,
yeah,
right.
Yeah.
That's what scientists are,
you know,
that's one thing.
Whenever you tweet something about
global climate change,
one of the first things that happens is
these trump ets jump on board and they
start attacking what you're saying.
And then tweeting,
like,
I don't know if they've researched it or
not,
but it's just like immediate attitude
that the people on the right seemed to
have where they had.
They immediately want to dismiss
anything that diminishes industry.
Anything about climate change,
anything that protects the environment,
whether it's about this dakota pipeline
access thing,
that's just,
you know,
the trump has just getting involved
with.
Yeah,
he green lIt it.
I mean that's a,
that's intense.
Oh,
you know what that was going on during
the obama administration.
That's something that people need to
recognize that there's not a single
fucking president that's really looking
out for you and never has been won.
There's not one that you could really
enjoy.
Every single one of them is doing some
creepy shit and that whole thing where
they were.
They were cutting easements through
private land.
They were arresting people on their own
fucking land.
They were saying that they had the right
to drill through their land.
That was during the obama administration
started during his administration,
supported by administration and they
stopped at towards the end,
but it's almost like I kind of know that
they stopped it knowing that trump was
going to start it right the fuck back
up.
As soon as he got in office,
I think the last few months of obama,
that's why he kicked the russians out
because you're like,
let trump bring them back and let let,
let me be the bad guy and get that
headline and he'll green light that
pipeline.
I think obama had some fun on the waY
out,
knowing that trump is,
you know,
first week is going to turn it all
around and everyone gets to point the
finger.
That's politics and that's why I don't
love any politician and I've never
wanted to meet one.
I,
I've,
I wouldn't walk.
I come from Washington dc,
you'd see them all the time,
you know,
they got to eat somewhere and I've
never,
I wouldn't walk five blocks to go meet
one.
I'd like to meet jimmy carter.
He's
probably the only guy that I really
wanted to see him speak just because,
you know,
I've never watched a president speak.
I think it'd be interesting,
but I,
I wouldn't mind meeting jimmy carter,
but I just kind of know they're all kind
of cut from kind of the same bolt of
cloth,
just the different amounts of puke on
the cloth.
Right.
So like if it's raining outside and
they're outside,
they're wet.
Yeah.
Because everyone's score.
Vidal said by the time you get to the
executive office,
you've been bought and sold at least a
dozen times willfully.
How do you fix that?
By being a good person,
because there's so much of it you can't
fix,
the only way to fix it is to go local
and like when trump became president,
I just did eight shows at largo in la
and a lot of people were kind of failing
and I said,
look,
when they start pushing against lgbt
rights or women's reproductive health
rights or freedoms will neutralize
benefits.
We're going to,
you know,
planned parenthood,
a clu,
a southern poverty law center,
and the lgbt activist group.
We can get involved and start kind of
neutralizing this and slowing it down.
And this is not a time to be dismayed.
This is,
thIs is punk rock time.
This is what joe strummer trains you
for.
It is now time to go.
You're a good person means that means
more now than ever because as a voter,
you know,
you throw your penny throat in the seat.
That's all a vote is.
It's just like nothing.
Like you don't even hear it fall,
but you can.
You can be thunderous in your own life
and being cool to the eight people
around you and that,
you know,
it rubs off.
This is viral,
it resonates it really.
And,
and so I work locally,
right?
As far as my eyes can see.
I worked there,
there was an orphanage in,
in los angeles I contributed money to
for years.
They've kind of morphed into something
else now,
but I work locally and if everyone did,
everyone worked like,
you know,
a yard in front of them.
It started looking really good.
So you don't have to change the world.
You can just change your,
your street and changIng the world.
What a daunting task.
But it happens when enough people change
theIr street.
And so as a los angeles resident,
I'd be happy to work inside the county
of la doing good stuff.
Whatever I can figure out to do,
you don't have to you because you,
you're not going to push congress
around.
THey seem to be loving to sit,
sit still.
Uh,
so you can work locally and so going
forward in this country,
it does.
When it gets better is when the electric
gets better.
As with jefferson taught you a vigorous,
educated electorate who votes and votes
and votes to keep an american government
and democracy,
a transparent lens as transparent as
possible,
and that's what you can do in this time
like don't.
You're not going to move to Canada like
the canadians are going to have you,
but you can be.
Your decency now means more.
It's a it.
It's a more into a fruitful currency.
It just means more now to help that guy
out.
It's it's healthier help basically.
I feeling great things get done in times
of conflict.
Absolutely.
We have something to push back against.
People organized like that woman's
march.
You know exactly where you go,
wow,
decency is under threat.
I never thought about that.
Let's go and all of a sudden your life
has some definition or like I like add
the serial relationships.
I'm not looking to get into an argument
with you.
I'm just saying like when I go on tour,
it's not me versus the audience.
It's me versus the stress and the
magnitude of the tour.
I've bitten off for myself and I get the
fear of failing my audience.
I love that and I battled that fear all
day.
Go to the gym becauSe you better put
eIght miles on that treadmill because
you got a show tonight.
There is a sort of damocles over your
head.
Don't eat the pizza.
Eat that because you've got a show
tonight.
Don't this up.
When you decided to do like eight miles
on a treadmill,
how do you feel like that benefits?
You want to do a show mental toughness
like I'm tired,
I'm jet lagged and I'm going to be
onstage and 40 minutes I'm so damn
tired,
and then all that training comes in and
you're like,
man,
this can probably be the best show I've
ever done.
They start laughing like,
man,
I'm really tired.
ThIs is going to be awesome,
and you go out there and crush it.
Now when you do your shows,
do you write it out in a long form?
No,
but you know I've already written yes.
I've already written out in my journal
because those journals become books.
I tAke tons of write longhand type.
Both on my leisure days I'd like to hand
write,
so I just like writing,
but mainly I don't have the time so I
got to type it up.
Left.
He left.
He left headed.
Yeah.
So,
and so I,
I've learned that you can't take too
many notes.
YoU can't write enough like you have to
take add details of the last hour,
forget it the next day because you're
tired.
And so when I'm on stage I have no notes
and it's all in the front of my brain
pan.
So if I'm going to quote the
constitution or quota precedent or years
that the supreme court did Whatever,
I just have to put it.
I memorize all of it and I just carry it
around with me.
And before I go on stage to center
myself,
I,
uh,
I quote lincoln from,
his speech for the speech to the
perpetuation of our governmental
institutions.
I think it's calleD,
is the,
the speeCh to the young men's lyceum.
It's been quoted.
Florida's first ever speeches.
He's really young.
Eighteen,
38.
I think it was in early january.
And it's,
I just quote parts of it to myself and
kinda get ready to go out there and so
does that help you?
Just eliminates the rest of the day.
So It's like all I have in my life as a
show,
I don't care about anything else.
My whole life is tonight and it's,
it says I don't want anything else in
the way.
I think it was bjorn,
bjorn bork,
some elite tennis player.
He said,
I've read this in sports illustrated
when I was a kid.
He said,
I just basically concentrate to
eliminate everything that's not the
match.
I was like,
that'll work.
Then I was hyperactive.
It didn't.
It took me years to be able to really
embrace that.
But when I go on stage after a show,
25 and 25 days,
man,
the only thing getting you through it is
your love of being onstage.
My of the audIence.
I love them.
Like just crazy obsessive and just the
fact that I'm not thinking about how
tired I am and how tired I'm going to
be.
I just all there is.
They go and go and I walk out there and
I've spent the last hour eliminating the
other parts of the day.
So do you have an outline of what you're
going to talk about in my mind?
Yeah.
Only in your mind.
Sometimes I'll at the beginning of a
tour just to kind of get back in that
groove all I'll write a page of notes.
I'll talk about this into that,
into that and I look at it and I kind of
walk it through in my mind and like,
okay,
you basically memorized all the
furniture in the living room so you can
run through it with your eyes closed and
not bump into anything.
And so when I go on stage one thing,
so tends to go into the next and I just,
all of a sudden I have a stopwatch.
I bring it on stage and put it down for
the audience's benefit,
not mine.
Because if I don't,
uh,
if I'm not careful,
the shows we'll go well over two hours
and I look down like,
oh no,
these poor people,
I got to certain landing this thing in
any story takes you like 20 minutes to
get it,
Intend to get out.
So I'm like,
okay,
we're taxiing.
I can see the runway and I'll let him go
in 15 minutes and I apologize I've kept
you here for like two hours and 20
minutes.
I'm really sorry.
I swear I'll be done with you and like
10 more minutes,
but I would imagine they'd want you to
feel like no dude more.
But uh,
I,
I just don't want to keep them there for
three hours.
I do,
but I can't write.
You don't want to abuse.
Well,
it's want to leave them wanting more and
just don't leave them going.
Like,
that was really long.
I'm never coming back to this again.
That was like having four molders being
pulled because I always tell them I'm
desperate for your attention and your
approval.
I really need you to keep showing up
because without you on the tree,
that falls in the forest on witnessed.
and uh,
if,
uh,
you're not here,
man.
I got no,
I got nothing going on now.
When you would do say if you do a 25
show tour,
if you go out for $25,
are you doing the exact same thing
verbatim knowing?
No,
no,
no.
I'll have one or two big centerpiece
stories like on the last tour,
uh,
many nights of the week I talked about
the time I had lunch with david bowie
because he had passed away last year and
he was really,
really cool to me and it's a fun story
and I told some lemmy stories because
let me from motorhead had died.
Uh,
in the weeks before the tour started.
I said,
well,
you know,
lemmys gone and my fans are very big on
lemmy and motorhead and I have a lot of
stories.
I hung out with lemmy a lot and he's
just a wonderful guy,
really amazing guy.
So I would tell some stories and those
would kind of fall in and fall out and
then things would happen in the world
and that would come into the mix and I
sometimes if something is really
relevant,
I can connect it to something else.
Like almost any country that falls down,
I've probably been there and I go,
well,
okay,
here's what happened in Syria today.
Now when I was there,
like in pull my afternoon and the l
hideous story out.
Uh,
and so I have,
like I,
I was on route ru paul's a longtime
palomar iso,
one of my favorite humans.
Just,
yeah,
just an amazing human being.
Smart,
funny.
And his had to run more than once
because he's a big black guy in a wig.
I mean someone wants to beat him up and
he's just one of the more extraordinary
people I've ever met.
And I met him at band practice in the
nineties.
He prActice down the hall from us and we
became pals.
And so I talked about the time I was on
rupaul's drag race is a judge,
which was hilarious.
But I talKed about that story because I
was just on his show.
Ru paul,
dr three,
dr he puts a microphone on you in a
gopro camera and he drives you around la
doing errands and he interviews you and
he chops it up into content and so was
able to tell my being a judge on
rupaul's drag race story because I could
segue into the day we ran errands,
the normal places I go because I live
alone.
I'm very much a solitary type.
I'd made this story about how I walked
into all these places and the only time
I've ever come in with someone else's.
The one time I walked in with a six and
a half foot tall black guy and everyone
who knows me and all these stores skills
like,
oh,
henry's finally found someone,
and it was.
It was a story about perception because
you'd see the looks on their face like,
oh,
hey henry.
Right.
I always thought so.
it was hilarious and rupaul and I would
leave these places would just laugh
hysterically because they think we're an
item.
And we eventually had lunch in west la
and we were recognized by everyone on
the sidewalks immediately.
People are taking photos.
And I said,
ru paul,
I think we've become a power couple was.
And this to me is an anecdote I would
tell onstage.
And it's funny,
but I'm not making up humor.
I'm telling you,
uh,
something that happened that was funny.
That's how I get the humor.
I basically stumbled into it like,
whoops,
I got humor on my shoe.
And it was funny because I got email,
dude,
you're not going out with ru paul.
And I would write back these really
funny,
ambiguous email letters back.
I'm like,
well,
as a new couple we don't want external
factors to determine what this thing is
going to be.
So right now we're just going with the
flow and there's some kid in the midwest
who's head just exploded because I wrote
him back.
Well,
you know,
we're just checkIng it out,
let him post that wherever he wants.
I don't give a damn.
And so that's what informs the shows.
As the tour rolls out,
that story will be in the,
you know,
I'll do like 20 nights with that and
then it falls away and it comes back
like three weeks later because I tour
for months at a time.
Like he does fiscal quarters go by and
you don't have an opening act.
You just go right on by herself.
I'm by myself.
Yeah.
Sometimes like in Australia they have a
rule where if you know,
for people in your band,
your american band than you for
australians have to play to.
And I liked that.
And so a couple of times I've had a
comedian,
really good guy he opens for on some of
my bigger australian shows.
He didn't do it this last time,
but he,
his name is bruce and he'll go do like
20 minutes so we can say we did that and
he's a great guy.
So when I was going to Australia and I
bring american comedians to open for me,
I don't,
I don't understand that well,
they just have this one to one thing.
The canadians have it too,
like if you're going to play,
they want a local band playing too,
so you'll use lever canadian opener,
but I,
when I go to Canada too,
I bring american comedians,
dope and I've done tours were that they
didn't make me have an opener who is
australian and I've done towards what
they did was there last year in 2016,
like for a month of shows,
no opener.
I thought it was going to be my buddy
again.
And they said,
no,
no one does this,
do I go,
how am I doing that?
But not last time it was explained to me
and I didn't care that much.
Like why don't they have that canadian
content rule?
and it comes to television right in
radio as well.
I think canadians,
I think there's a certain amount of
canadian content you have to have on the
radio and in television in Canada,
but usually I'm just on my own.
Uh,
like the last one,
hundred and 56 shows.
There was no openers.
Do you get lonely on the road?
Like,
no,
I don't have that chip.
I used to get really anyone else again?
I got lonelier.
I got lonely when I was young,
you know,
he had a girlfriend or something and now
I'm kinda like a,
a lizard.
He like,
you know,
this lizard has had no one in a
terrarium for 80 years.
It's still keeps eating bugs.
Yeah.
Like I'm Henry Rollins and I still keep
eating books.
I know I don't get lonely at all.
Wow.
I just don't have the,
the iaf faulty wiring or something?
No,
not at all.
Depressed.
Super unusual.
Depressed?
Yes.
Sure.
Depression,
feelings of blankness I have in combat,
but that's one of the reasons I go to
the gym that kind of blows that away.
Music helps but lonely.
No.
Uh,
I missed people who are dead.
I missed ed people because he can't talk
to him anymore.
like with my best friend's mom died.
I miss her A lot,
but I'm now.
Otherwise I see people when I see them.
You have to remember I'm basically,
I'll be 56 in a couple of weeks.
I've been touring since I was 20.
I've been playing the away game.
That's kind of what I know we're being
off the road is difficult.
I live in a nice place.
It's cool.
A lot of records,
a nice stereo.
It's got all I need.
Um,
but after three days home,
I'm bored.
I'm missing the tour bus.
I wish I was back on tour,
man.
There's a lot of people like that that
have that wanderlust thing.
Anthony bourdain has that same thing
going on where he can't be home for a
couple of weeks.
She's home for a couple of weeks.
He's got to get the fuck away.
Yeah.
I feel like I would like to leave.
I don't want to run out of this building
now,
but if someone said,
hey,
you want to go to Iceland tomorrow?
I'm like,
yeah,
I can be packed and give me 20 minutes
man.
Just keep the car on.
I'll be right out.
Yeah.
And I'll go.
I'm hoping for some good location work
this year.
If they said you wanna go move to the
czech republic for a year and a half and
make a,
you know,
a two seasons of a tv show,
I'd say yes.
Before I asked what the part was.
Really?
Yeah.
You're going to get an offer now from
the czech republic right now is banging
on his keyboard.
Well,
you know what I mean.
There's like these gigs.
You get really like,
hey,
do you mind going to live in this part
of the world for six weeks to make a
movie?
I'm like,
I'll be there in two days.
Oh yeah.
No,
I run and stuff like that.
Man.
I'm just totally opposite.
Everyone's different.
You have a family.
Children wife will do that.
That's,
that's,
that's your home you have.
Even if I didn't,
I just never really before I had one.
I just never really enjoyed being out
that much of like going away and coming
back.
Yeah.
I get you and I like being home for long
stretches.
I feel more productive at home.
Huh?
Yeah.
For me,
all the good wrIting,
the good thinking,
the good workouts.
It all comes from being on the road.
I just burned cleaner.
My mood elevates.
Let him off the road.
I everyday I wake up in my own bed,
I feel I'm kind of failing and I'm
wimping out really home,
you're failing and wimping out at home.
Why?
And that?
You know what?
I put that on me.
I'm not saying anyone else's.
I wouldn't do,
I don't get to tell people what to do,
but for me everyday I'm not out in the
world.
I'm like thinking I'm trying to dodge
the ball instead of like deflecting it
or catching it or getting hit by it.
Yeah.
I'd rather be out like,
oh my,
the people I traveled with my road
manager and our merchant guy,
we'd been travelIng the world together
for about a decade and we all like,
wow,
we're,
we're off this bus in two days.
I guess I'll start packing.
None of us want to go.
Wow.
My road manager,
he has a family,
so he's looking forward to being back
with them of course.
But me and the merge guy,
man,
we're just,
you know,
to solo acts,
swinging from vine to vine.
And so this year I don't have any.
I got like a few talking shows.
I'm going to key note this cannabis
thing and a couple of weeks in san
francisco.
What is the,
what is it?
It's a thing of for cannabis
entrepreneurs and since I don't smoke
marijuana or any cannabis product,
but I'm pro legalization and
decriminalization,
they want me to speak on that and I said
I'm in and so I've got a couple of gigs
but beyond that I've got nothing going
on this year so I'm waiting for an
audition or a meeting and someone gives
me a gig and if I don't get any of that
then I'm just going to pack my bags and
find some jungle in some desert and go
dig it.
Now when you're writing something about
cannabis and you don't use it,
I mean you obviously had a long history
with drugs before you got clean me?
Yeah.
Oh no sir.
never know.
I got drunk like four times in my life.
I smoked marijuana once,
7:11
hamilton street in trenton.
New jersey is after band.
Practice was really boring and my
bandmates were smoking a joint.
I said,
can I try that?
And they said,
you one,
I'm so bored.
I'll try it.
I haTed it.
So he never,
he never really had that time in your
life where you're not fucking around
with drugs.
I did.
I think I tried weed once.
I had a few experiences with michelob
and 10th grade.
I just didn't like it.
I tried lsd a handful of times.
Interesting.
But easy to lose your mind.
Tried mushrooms a few times and when I
did that thing at the strip bar with the
red show,
it was drug stories and they said,
do you have when I go,
yeah,
I'll talk about the time of me and this
girl were on acid driving her car and
damn near got killed.
And so,
you know,
she was crazy.
She's dead now.
But um,
I told that story about being on acid
and latina.
That's probably where I got it froM
then.
Oh yeah.
Other stories of my,
like six acid trips.
So when,
when did you just decide to go
completely clean?
Well,
I never really got started in my career
as a drug addict.
I mean,
noT even an avenue saying addict.
I'm saying someone uses it.
Oh no,
no,
it never.
I,
I'm wired to such a in such a way that
any stimulant is kind of a depressant,
like beer and the times I drank,
I just,
you know,
for beers I'd throw up on my shoes.
I wasn't good at it,
I didn't enjoy it.
I just did it because I wanted to hang
out with the gang,
like my,
my dumb ass friends at school and I
didn't like it.
It just,
I didn't like the dizziness and it
didn't make me happy.
It just made me stupid.
That time I smoked marijuana.
I just sat there waiting for it to be
over.
I sat trying to figure out how to pick
up a glass of water is sitting on.
I'm like,
how do I do that?
And all my,
my bandmates are experienced stones and
they're like,
you do that henry?
I'm like,
thank you.
So you couldn't understand picking up a
glass of water when you went too deep.
Like I said,
how,
how long does this last for?
They said,
about 20,
30 minutes.
I said,
okay,
and I just sat and stared at my watch
and waited it out.
Acid was interesting.
Were you like,
wow,
I could lose my mind so I just better
like concentrate so it doesn't run out
of my skull.
Mushrooms are fun.
You laugh your ass off for three hours
and that wasn't so bad,
but I just didn't see anything to
pursue.
I tried it.
It was the same thing every time.
and that's kind of my entire history
with drug use.
That was it.
Like caffeine,
right?
Well yeah,
but this I would drink like I'm,
that's a small cup of coffee.
This will last me,
believe it or not,
all day and one cup.
I drink a cup of day,
I make a cup of coffee and I just sip
it.
So what I'm thinking is that I'm
medicating with caffeine like an
antidepressant and I use it as an iv
drip because I never drink cups of
coffee to start off hot and by the end
of the day it's just this cold.
Yeah.
But I sip it and I think it's just a
drip,
ivy of caffeine and it must be because I
always have a cup of coffee with me and
it's always half full,
like on the weekends.
On the weekends if I'm off the road I go
to coffee places to sit and write for
hours and work on book manuscripts and
I'll buy the small coffee like this one
and three and a half hours later I'll
leave and I'll just drop it in the trash
because it's still about three quarters
full.
So I don't drink a lot of coffee in the
wintertime.
I'll drink a cup of tea in the morning
and have a cup,
a part of a cup of coffee.
I'll drink all of the tea.
What,
what makes what?
What fuels you to be so prolific?
You know you,
you're saying you write an article a
month for the la weekly,
so once a week.
A thousand words a week?
Yeah.
Which is not do that.
You write for rolling stone Australia
once a month and then I write,
I try and write a thousand words a day
for myself and I have right now five
different books in various states of
completion of some college guy saying my
manuscript,
these are done and I'm by day I edit,
I'm editing the next journal book travel
book and then at night I'm writing
another journal book and working on one
of two different music books.
I do a series of music books called
fanaTic where I,
you know,
rare records and labels like music geek
stuff.
And so I work on those at night.
And you also host a radio show and I
have the weekly radio show I just filled
in.
Oh,
tomorrow in england.
And bbc radio six.
I'm filling in for iggy pop.
He took a vacation from his show.
So I filled in for him last week and
this week as well.
So I did those shows.
So I'm,
I'm always busy.
Um,
and so stimulants would get in my way.
What powers me.
it's not money,
it's not ambition,
it's anger.
I'm one of those people.
I,
I wish there was a better way to say it,
but it's,
it's vengeance.
He laughed at me in high school,
man.
He said I wasn't going to be anything
really.
Like watch this,
like that's still pushing your 56.
I hate to say it.
Oh yeah,
40,
40 years later.
Oh yeah.
All of it.
Like my dad,
you know,
he was a big money guy.
I'm like,
okay,
you love money so much.
Watch me outgrows you and your whole
damn family two combined and I don't,
I don't even care about.
I just like achieving it and it's one of
the reasons when the agent goes,
okay,
five shows on one off.
I'm like,
oh no,
no man,
no,
that's a day off.
You put a show in there.
Like why?
Because like,
screw that man,
watch me put two shows on that night.
What you think?
I cAn't.
I'm just,
like I said,
I set up adversarial relationships.
I'm not against you or anything.
I'm just saying like I have to have
something to push against,
like a schedule that is like the
schedules,
like godzilla,
like you can't finish this all like,
really man,
I'm going to serve you up and eat you
everyday like a steak and I just have to
have that and so I'm getting back and
it's a.
I think of all the people I was in bands
with,
I have to crush them.
Everyone grew up with.
I have to powderize them.
Why that's such a weird motivation is it
sucks.
It's immature.
It's like it's 11 year old sandbox.
Wow.
You're aware of it.
Yeah.
That which makes it even stranger
because it's not something that you're
just operating under.
Well,
you know,
you have,
it's,
it's controlling you and you don't
understand why I quite enjoy it.
Yeah.
Like if I,
you know,
I,
I'm not an actor but I go up for acting
parts on bike basically going in there
and winging it and I get,
you know,
I get to go up for like really big parse
this a little bit of trepidation knowing
I'm going in there,
but then I'm thinking like,
oh yeah,
sony,
whatever,
man,
line it up and I almost like run out of
my car.
Like,
yo,
where you at man?
And I'm not trying to impress you.
I'm a tough guy so I'm not,
I just need,
it just needs to be trying to tell me I
can't and I that informs everything I
do.
Like instead of just dialing my radio
show in,
I will work on that sucker for like five
hours.
It has to be all handpicked.
Know that song,
not that one.
This one and I make like three drafts of
it.
It's intense.
It's one of the reasons why I live
alone.
It's like I work all the time like,
hey,
come out on this weekend,
now it's 7:00
PM on a friday.
I'm working like I'm not a constant.
Yeah,
nah,
I'm not fun to hang out with.
Do you vacation ever where you just
chill?
I can't intellectually and
existentially.
I can't understand the idea of a
vacation.
I make a joke on stage and saId I want
to come back 10 pounds lighter with an
internal parasite.
I,
I want to come back with like a scar
where the spear kind of grazed me an
eight grade stories and a dangerous
insect in my bag.
I don't want to sit on the beach and
soak in the race.
I want to get sunburned by,
you know,
being in the desert and,
figuring out how the sun won't try and
kill me by noon.
That's the sahara.
And so that's how I go about it.
So part of your motivation is actually
the perception by other people,
what you're doing,
like understanding that what you're
doing is so undeniable the volume that
you're putting out and the intensity,
the intensity.
So undeniable.
Like I'll show you motherfuckers.
Yeah,
absolutely.
Wow.
That's so weird.
Even with people who like me,
like,
yay henry's here.
I'm like,
yeah,
I'm here.
Check it out.
Pitch.
So here's a place you won't go and not
that I have any aggression towards these
people,
I just,
I just want to burn brightly and it's
not about money.
It's not about,
I'm better than you because I,
I don't think I'm better than anybody.
I just want to explode as much as
possible.
And I think to my audience,
it's to their benefit.
He's like,
that dude's going to go out there to a
place I don't want to go.
It is going to come back with 10 great
photos and a story about how he nearly
lost his foot.
It's great.
And like put me in coach.
That's the game I want to play.
That's what I go for.
And I'm not trying to.
I'm just trying to like,
like in the high school I was like,
you know,
the wise ass kid who had awful grades on
ritalin.
I was a mess.
And so ritalin and high school who I was
on ritalin since like,
uh,
like right at a preschool.
Oh shIt.
Look at the early.
A government documentation on,
on ritalin.
This is not a joke.
Oh,
there's these big books.
My mom had them,
there's photos of me.
They tried ritalin out.
I was part of the test group and we
would get little orange tablets and then
we get little yellow tablets and we have
triangular orange tablets for awhile and
my.
I went to a place called the national
research center and I was a hyperactive
kid and they said,
here,
we're trying this stuff out.
my mom had me on ritalin from preschool
all the way to twelfth grade.
Holy shit.
In the summertime,
summer vacation,
I wouldn't take it,
and within a day of this of kick and his
self out of your system,
man,
your appetite comes back and in ninth or
10th grade I started weightlifting and I
started like throwing the pills out
because it's.
It's an app at that speed and so it
suppresses your appetite and so I'm
going through puberty.
My hormones are raging and I stopped
using the tablet and all of a sudden I'm
that guy at lunch.
We're like the,
the,
the line of milk on the outer edge of
the tray because I'm eating like,
you know,
tons of food in the locust.
Phil,
I'm going to the gym And I'm just
getting really,
my frustration is now being informed by
a physicality that I'm getting by
lifting weights,
so all of a sudden I'm putting muscle on
and I'm angry at the world and I'm a
spazz and so by twelfth grade I was kind
of a maniac and then I got into punk
rock and you know,
just got,
got into that slug fest and just kind of
went into the world just kind of wildly
swinging away.
Who the,
why did they put you on ritalin at such
a young age because it's what they were
doing in America with a lot of young
people who talk too much or you know,
had that socIal skills well on energy,
at attention deficit and I couldn't
concentrate and I got thrown out of the
dc public school system,
uh,
for being,
you know,
he's yelling,
he's doing this.
And I actually read a couple of teachers
reports about me years later and I said
I had no memory.
I said,
I did all that.
My mom went,
yeah,
that's why they kicked you out and they
kicked you out of school?
Yeah.
And uh,
I got kicked out of a few schools until
they put me in a,
in a prep school where the advertising
is like,
oh,
your kid has problems with studying,
will cool them out.
And I,
the first few days of school,
some kids spoke at a class and I watched
this one teacher picked this kid up and
just kind of toss them into a
blackboard.
I went right in his class.
You shut up.
And so I,
I didn't want to get,
you know,
a thrashing by a teacher,
so I was always really careful.
But having that difficulty sitting down
and I was fine with topics I liked.
I didn't know,
I didn't groove on math or any of that,
but at lunchtime I'd go to the library
and start memorizing the latin
nomenclature of every north american
snake.
I had to learn them all.
And by like 10th grade I had,
and I have,
most of it's still in my head,
but I'm always,
always
very confused at these medical
distinctions.
Whether it's adhd or hyperactive or add
whatever the fuck it is.
Is is that real or do people just do.
Some people just have a different
composition,
a different passion inside of them and
they resist doing things they don't want
to do and they don't want to be a part
of any structured school curriculum.
I think all of it.
But it.
Yeah.
And is that a disease or is that or do
you just have more fucking.
They're looking right now.
If
you have any pills,
you're not on anything.
And yet.
Yeah.
Well his passion for life.
You have all this.
Isn't that the same shit that you had
when you were six?
Just was undisciplined and unfocused.
Right?
But that doesn't,
that's not a disease,
right?
I,
I dunno,
I mean I wouldn't call it a disease I
think is this wiring.
Right,
but why the fuck is it named?
Why is it adh?
So they can.
So they can sell you a pill.
I know,
but isn't that crazy when you look back
at your own life,
the fact that you were on that shit for.
I mean what,
how many.
A lot of years,
eight years,
nine years.
It really screws with you because you
can feel it.
When you take the t,
the pill,
you can.
You're basically,
you're a propeller that spins so fast.
It looks like they're like spokes of a
wheel wheel.
We'll still,
but it's actually going really fast.
That's how it felt like on the outside
I'm like this pale skinny like eh,
but inside I'm like the last few minutes
of a dave in 2001 was coming into the
space time continuum and everything is
flying by.
that was lIke 10th grade for me.
Right.
It's kind of held onto my desk and
fairly flew through classes like not
being able to retain much because I was
speeding my brains out and then the pill
would wear off around dinner and all of
a sudden you're like eating two meals
and the next morning you take the pill
and you don't eat again for hours.
That is fucking crazy.
It was nuts and scares the shit out of
me too because my parents didn't put me
on anything like that,
but I know I would've.
I know I would've been diagnosed.
I know I would have been put on
something if I had the wrong parents.
Yeah,
they put me on my.
My mom put me on this stuff probably
because my doctor said,
you know,
hey iris,
this helps a lot of kids,
but I was in these classes and I'll
never forget one day I'm going through
my mom's books.
There's just thIs big honking hardcover
book.
And I opened it up and I saw these,
like a contact sheet of me.
I'm like,
wait a minute.
That set place.
And then I saw the camera angle and I
realized there were these mirrors on the
wall,
their observation rooms.
I'll never forget one day I'm looking at
that mirror and a door opened from the
side and my mom walked out and they
would,
we were being observed and the camera
angle was from that observation room and
there's me playing with blocks and
stuff.
I'm like,
I remember that sweater.
Oh man,
I'm like four.
And that was part of that research
group.
Wow.
And maybe because my mom was a
government employee,
I don't know,
but I was uh,
I went to a place called it for two
years,
called the national research center.
I got thrown out of their wow for
wounding a kid,
which due to them through a bunch of
powdered.
Submitted his face.
Yeah.
Now when you started lifting weights
when you were in twelfth grade and you
want more like a ninth or 10th?
Ninth and 10th.
Yeah.
Early to when you stopped taking the
pills,
did you feel like the exercise did for
you what the pills were kind of supposed
to do for you?
The weightlifting,
you know,
I had a,
this coach,
when he's mentioned in that article that
you were talking about the ira and I
talked to mr pepperman and he is,
he was in his car pool.
He was a Vietnam vet.
And uh,
he once said to me,
uh,
I have to quote,
he said,
uh,
you're a skinny little faggot.
She thank you sir.
And he said,
I'm going to teach you how to lift
weights.
And I said,
okay,
it's more attention than my dad gave me.
So I said I'll take it,
and so he taught me compound lifts at
the school gym,
so I bought a sears and roebuck sand
filled weight set,
which I couldn't drag too.
My mom stays a vw fastback and
eventually I did a buy three months of
that weight set.
I'm fairly throwing it across the room
because you know,
you're growing so fast,
like your muscles are recovering
overnight.
You just do the same workout every day.
You don't even feel it.
And he said you're not allowed to look
at yourself until christmas break after
christmas exams.
And this was like in september.
So I didn't.
I did everything he told me to.
And then he dropped me off before the
christmas break.
He said,
now today you can look at yourself in
the mirror.
And I ran home,
I ran home and I tore my stupid school
uniform off and I stood in the mirror
and my body had definition.
I'm like,
well,
those are packs of those.
I mean like I looked like I was a guy
who lifted some weights and I've.
It was self valIdating.
Like wow,
I'm here.
I did that.
I'm looking at myself going,
I did that no one can lift those weights
for you.
And the feeling of achievement it gave
me,
that I accomplished that was a shot in
the arm that I still feel to this day,
mile.
I mean because it was so like,
wow,
you can do this.
That's possible.
Because every other time I'm trying to
meet girls at the school dance.
I had no guts to talk to the girls.
So they were alien creatures.
Um,
I didn't do well in school so you can
make fun of me.
I couldn't throw the ball straight so
they would throw it at my head to watch
me run.
And so I,
I,
it didn't have any traction anywhere.
And then when I had the weights I'm
like,
wow,
I'm filling out my tee shirt,
man.
Noticeable improvement.
Hell yeah man.
Plus effort equals results and I
couldn't,
didn't make my grades better.
[inaudible] I still,
you know,
is all of swahili to me is a school of
business.
It was probably too late.
I just,
yeah,
I was not good at sitting still,
but when I had the summer jobs,
that's when I kicked ass.
I never had an allowance.
I never.
My mom said,
you never said here's 20 bucks.
I'm like,
weird.
Henry go.
He's got three jobs over the weekend.
I'd wake up in the morning,
go to the pet shop,
work all day.
They're run home,
shower,
change my clothes,
do the night shift at the movie theater,
take the bus out to the surf shop In the
suburbs and,
and repair skateboards and whatever on
sundays.
So I always had pocket money because I
always,
I liked having working a cash register
on my key chain in school.
I had the keys to stores,
bosses trusted me because I'd never
steal and I so I would work like 20
hours a week and go to school in high
school and part of that was informed by
the weightlifting and I like getting out
of the house and being responsible,
but in school it didn't mean much to me,
but showing up on time at the pet shop
and cleaning out 20 cat pans.
Man,
that was like I had to be there at 8:00,
not eight.
Oh one man.
because we got thIngs to do.
I felt a real fealty and to this day,
like if I'm ever on a film shoot,
like who's the guy who's there early
man,
that's me.
I'm,
I'm there.
I memorized the whole damn script.
I'm so happy to have a job.
I'm like amazed.
Anyone cares.
And so all of that,
it keeps me on the straight and narrow
as I call myself.
A human frozen yogurt machine is output.
You know,
I don't want the applause.
I don't.
I like to build ships.
I don't want to in them.
And the best part about finishing the
ship is it sales off to see and you can
build another.
so I love finishing a book.
He'll get this thing off my desktop.
Now I can start a new one,
like where can I go now?
And so that's how I,
I live to achieve and to output,
but it's not.
I don't ever look at.
I hAve a thing on my computer,
it's called the list and I keep a list
of like every show,
every book I've written,
every movie I've been in,
every album I've ever made.
And when you look at it,
it's intense.
It's like you keep a list of every show
you've ever done.
Oh,
hell yeah,
of course.
Wow.
I don't know anybody who does that.
Yeah.
And sometimes I write down a set length,
uh,
take a lot of notes.
Wow.
Yeah.
Write them all down.
But um,
I have this one thing called the list
and It's just like,
you know,
every film,
every tv show,
every voiceover,
every book,
every record on the,
on and on.
And sometimes I look at it just because
I have to input like the new book comes
out,
I have to go to the thing and input and
I look at this list and my bone start
aching.
Like,
man,
this is a lot of,
there's a lot of shit,
a lot of crap this came out.
Yeah.
And I don't wave it around and see what
I've done.
I just kind of go,
I'm only interested in what I'm doing,
what I'm doing next.
so why do you record it then?
Why do you write all that stuff down?
I like leaving a good trail of evidence
and I like to be able to,
uh,
when someone will say,
um,
I saw you in 1985 in champagne,
Illinois.
I'm like,
no,
that would be 1983 or 1986.
We didn't play there in 1985.
How do you know that?
Here?
It's right there.
See?
And they're like,
whoa.
Yeah,
you got to fucking list from 1983.
Oh,
I have every show since I was in
Washington dc with my,
with my first band.
So you've,
you've written down every single show
you've done in your life,
you should publish that.
Well,
it's in,
you know,
my,
my journal books of the years.
I was in black flag that came out as a
book.
I did a good.
I mean you should just publIsh that
list.
You should put it up online or something
just so people could look at it.
Yeah,
I,
I have a lot of,
there's a lot of those kind of things,
so I just want to just so people could
feel lazy because just to look at that
and go,
what in the fuck,
because sometimes you know,
something like that will change the way
a person looks at the world to know that
someone like Henry Rollins is out there
recording
every single show and here's,
here's all the,
like you get this feeling like I'm
getting this feeling when I'm talking to
you,
like I want to go do something for real
to get out of this inner.
No,
no,
no.
I love this interview.
I want to accomplish something like
this.
This is something that I like when I
talked to people that are really
motivated and really passionate it,
it gets me fired up and I'm listening to
you talk aBout this stuff and I want to
go do something.
Yeah.
That,
that's all you get to do In life.
You get to do stuff and then you die.
You know,
it's over and it's over fast enough.
Anyway,
so for me,
I don't,
I don't tell people what this is a very
compelling and attractive attitude.
You have those.
It's very,
very interesting.
Yeah,
it keeps me going and it never gets.
I never get to that point where I've
been to enough places where I've written
enough books or have done enough radio
shows or I bought enough records.
There's never enough records,
there's never enough time to do
everything.
and I like living with that kind of,
um,
aspect of desperation where you're
always kInd of like,
oh,
come on man,
let's go.
Uh,
and I liked that because it keeps the,
as I say,
it keeps the blood thin and it keeps
complacency at the door.
And I said,
I have my bad days.
I'm like,
anyone else?
I'm just a,
you know,
an example.
Your,
your bad days would probably ridiculous.
You're burning so hot.
I mean,
your bad days.
It probably like an average ambitious
person's quality time.
I don't know.
I mean,
I don't know,
man.
It's pretty intense,
but it's one of the reasons why I picked
the people I work with.
Like today you met heidi who manages not
only me but all my companies and she's
basically,
she's,
she and I had been working together for
damn near 20 years.
She's amazing and she's air traffic
control.
Cause if I'm not,
I've never careful.
I say yes to every damn thing and she's
like,
you can't say yes to that because you're
going to be over here on this day.
She goes,
stop answering the phone.
I got this.
So she like,
she's the one who coordinated all this
with you because I,
you know,
I'll go and do it,
but I'm not good at setting it up.
And so she locks in the coordinates.
And so I work with people who are used
to kind of my velocity,
like the road manager in a way.
I'm very easy on road manager ward.
Same.
I wake up,
I go to the front of the bus and he's
already written out the map for me to
walk to a gym.
So I wake up,
I go right to the gym and I always want
the same thing.
I want to jim,
I want this,
I want a gig.
And then I want some sushi and I want to
go to sleep and so,
but it's intense and there's hardly any
days off so he knows how to keep all of
that going and the phone is ringing
because I work in different media all
the time.
And so heidi is always juggling a chain
saws and so I'm around people who can
allow me just to really run at it and go
as fast and as hard as I want to.
I call it living at the speed of life.
He just kind of go,
you let your Imagination in your resolve
dictate everything and to be able to do
that and still keep the lights on.
I'm just a lucky bastard.
And so I,
I try and be really cool about it.
So with this humility is very contagIous
too.
It's very nice.
It's very nice to hear that you have
this attitude in our line of work.
I don't know everything about you,
but you know,
you and I do enough for the same stuff.
Come on man.
we get in free to stuff all the time.
Doors open stuff that other people pay
for.
They just give you a tour of a man
because they disliked the fact that you
came by and so the only way not to be a
jerk wIth all of that is to don't take
it too seriously and to be as grateful
as possible.
And that's what we're.
Several minutes ago I said I've met,
you know,
some big movie stars and rock star
types.
The bigger they Are,
the more grateful they are because they
know they are just lucky bastards and
all like the,
you know,
the,
your acd season,
black sabbath that I've met that are
like the most humble know.
They're just so happy.
They got a gig and it's going pretty
well and they just know that they beat
the grind.
They obviously had something to bear.
Uh,
they had something that the world says
wow about,
but they also at the same time know that
they're not going to take the same
training,
that a lot of really good people who
don't deserve it or going to take what
boot koski wrote about.
He says,
man,
you got to beat the grind because man,
this life will kill you.
It'll just use you up and so I'm not
looking to escape any beatings,
but to have an Idea and get to do it and
turn it into something that kind of pays
me like I can go into the world,
has these crazy things happen.
Come back with photographs and a story.
Take it on stage.
I can tour on that and people show up.
Damn man.
I should just be saying thank you every
other breath and that.
That's what I try and maintain.
Well you are,
you're obviously very prolific.
What do you do with all your money?
You seem like a guy who probably were
those kinds of clothes everyday.
All the time.
Probably living in a pocket.
Trying 20th.
These.
Yeah.
A little bit of department now I got a
house.
Yeah.
Wow.
So I have a lot of records and so,
uh,
you need some room.
Um,
I,
I spend money on records,
plane tickets and the occasional lens
for a camera,
you know,
but by and large costs a lot.
No,
I drive a mazda six watts.
Yeah.
Do you do that on purpose?
I live in la,
man.
Do you fly economy,
you one of those motherfuckers?
I have over a million miles on united
and I probably tried to upgrade you
like.
No,
no,
no.
The ilc?
No,
I,
I save them up for when I go on tour.
Like last year I was in Australia twice
and so that's where I use the miles.
But Australia economy.
Well no,
I upgraded into business because I had
already saved up the miles,
but usually I fly economy.
Yeah.
Why do you do that?
Because I will not justify spending
$2,000
for more leg room for seven hours
because you can buy like a truckload of
records of that money.
Right?
But you already have that $2,000
in the bank.
I need that $2,000.
I was really broke ass in a band for
many years and the,
all the money I made it came with a lot
of sweat and a lot of pain and I,
I must respect it and to.
And I'm not saying to put yourself in
business classes being disrespectful to
money.
What I'm saying is I can't justify it.
I simply cannot go.
That was worth it.
I can't do it.
I just can't.
How many records do you think you have?
I don't know.
It's like triples.
Mandate is keep showing up.
Wow.
I last night I listened to 10 records.
five lps in five singles.
And when you sit down and listen to
records or is this a solitary pursuit?
Just headphones on.
Oh,
no,
no.
I'm in front of a pair of,
uh,
wilson xlf.
Sophia three's a.
Yeah.
What is that?
They're like,
they're like,
he's an audio engineer.
He just started typing as soon as you
said that.
Yeah.
You type them in and your laptop will
go,
damn,
I'm there.
It's a good system,
but it's a.
The one thing I miss when I'm on the
road is my music just easy access to
analog and so on and off the road,
I have a file on my computer called.
I heard that and I write down every
record I listened to in the order.
I listened to it the exact pressing.
Like last night I listened to a david
bowie single golden years with,
can you hear me?
But with the pressing from El Salvador,
and I had to write that down because I'm
that guy.
You have a picture of the wilson?
Uh,
alexandria three's.
Wow.
So you just.
So when you're sitting down and you're
enjoying this music,
you're just sitting down and enjoying
this music.
You're not doing this.
Oh wow.
Those are bad ass.
Oh no,
no,
no.
A few.
A few models up my friend.
I've got those two.
Those are,
those are.
So sophie is go to the out,
go to alexandria.
There you go.
Yeah.
They're so big.
It tastes.
It takes a while to buffer.
Whoa.
Yeah.
There's 660 pounds each wax.
These are in your living room.
Holy shit.
Now what is the benefit of these?
Oh,
they sound good.
And frequency as realized without even
pushing the system.
It's a system.
You don't play loud,
you just,
you can play it at medium and it's full
saturation of frequency.
What the fuck?
Look at these goddamn things.
Miners,
silver coins,
this website.
So shit.
It's not our,
our internet services.
Fast as fuck.
Let's just get a shitty about the web.
These are probably some weirdos,
just like ham peak because they're just
meticulous builders and it takes a
while.
Look at those speakers.
That's insane.
It's a stack.
So you have two stacks and you just face
him towards you and you said in your
couch.
Yeah.
And then I'm looking at those and the,
uh,
that is uh,
a maniacs stereo system there.
Yeah.
Okay.
So you.
And so that's what I miss when I'm on
the road are those two.
And uh,
when I come home I play a lot of records
and so last night,
uh,
to listen to all that music,
it took about four hours or so to get
through all that music.
And you're just sitting there taking in
the songs.
I'm writing your writing.
Yeah.
I'm taking notes on things and I'm
working on writing in my journal and uh,
just writing and listening.
I got a cup of coffee and a cold cup of
coffee.
Yeah,
it's from.
I made it a the night before actually.
And uh,
and so I'm drinking the,
the low at the second half of this cold,
stale coffee.
Jesus christ and a half a glass of
perrier water.
I liked that line.
Bubbly water.
And that's uh,
that's my big kick ass night.
Like this weekend,
a band called sleep is opening for the
melvins and they're playing two nights
at the fonda,
so I'm going to both nights because I
love both bands.
And so if there's a gig in town,
I'm going,
if they play in two nights,
I go both nights.
So you're still deeply involved in music
and as far as you being a fan.
Huge,
but you just don't have the desire to
perform.
And you know,
I,
I came into music being a fan and I
left.
I,
I will always be a fan.
It,
it,
it's,
it's a drag when you meet a musician
who's not a fan of music,
like,
oh,
come on man.
Like no one's like,
oh,
these bands all suck.
I could really don't.
I feel the same way about comedians that
aren't a fan of standup.
I love standup.
It's still loves,
stand up and it's,
it's.
I think that's something that people
lose somewhere along the line sometimes.
Some of them do it.
It's really sad when I go to gigs all
the time.
It's funny,
but it's also sad a lot of times these
bands,
right?
BecAuse I play them on my radio show.
Hey man,
we're coming to the echo next week.
We're going on at 1130.
I'm like,
and it's a tuesday man,
I can't,
I can't go see you at 1130 at night.
Why is that?
Just too damn tired.
And I'm like,
damn,
I'm really my age because you say 1130
on a tuesday to start a gig.
I'm like,
I'm sorry,
daddy just got really tired and I just
have to go.
Sorry man.
You know,
I can't do that and be at my office the
next day.
wow.
I want to uh,
it was a friday.
Yeah.
Or christmas break.
But um,
I'll,
I'll go.
I'll be at the fonda both nights this
weekend.
Seeing those bands.
So when you say if it's a friday,
so on weekends,
do you have like a,
like a relaxed schedule on saturday and
sunday?
Do you allow yourself some leisure?
I'll sleep as long as I want and I
listened to different records during the
week.
I listened.
I do protein listening,
which is records I hAven't heard yet.
And so just,
you know,
you have to really concentrate on the
weekends.
I do carbohydrate listening,
whereas the records that I'm familiar
with that I just like to listen to.
Wow.
So just like a sort of a light thing.
Well just like songs,
like,
you know,
albums I've had for 25 years that I
still liked to listen to and that's
like,
you know,
Chile and soup and bread and potatoes
and then during the week it's just
shimmy me,
clap pushups.
You know,
what a strange life you have men.
Yeah.
it's very original.
Tell you that it's different,
you know,
be weird.
Live where you know,
weird,
this is weird does I guess.
Well you get involved in relationships,
you getting a girlfriend or something
like that and they realize failed what
they're getting involved with.
They're like,
oh,
jesus christ was more what I'm getting
involved with.
And I realized I can't hack it because
here's the awful thing about being an
adult in a relationship,
seeking to be an adult in a
relationship.
I have found,
uh,
when I was young and I was a boy and I
was dating girls,
it's boys and girls and she's an idiot,
you're an idiot,
you do dumb things and if cheats and
whatever,
then you hit a certain part of your life
where she's a woman and you're a man and
you have adult expectations and you
can't be running around being an idiot
with someone who kind of wants you to be
at the table because they are sincerely
giving time of their adult life to this
thing that you were doing together.
And when you come in still thinking
you're in ninth grade and she's coming
in like,
this is part of what my life is being
with you.
I have never been able to answer that in
a mature enough way to where I would
have been able to maintain it.
Because like say next weekend if I had a
girlfriend,
she might say,
it's friday.
What are we doing?
I'm like,
oh,
watching me write for four hours,
and so that's not the way to be.
You can't do that.
And so I can't be a good persons other
half because I'm always,
the work has always attracted me more
than coming home to someone.
Wow.
Like I can't stand the idea of someone
of living with a person.
I can do it on the bus because it's das
boat and work,
you know,
going down the road.
Um,
but I,
I never would want to like wake up and
she's there and I have no aversion.
Get expressed to,
to look to your right.
She's,
well,
it's every day here we are together and
I'm just not wired that way.
I would be a drag like,
you haven't spoken to me in 20 hours.
Huh?
I didn't notice and I'm just a work
oriented and so,
and I,
I'm not interested in wasting anyone's
time.
I'm not interested in being mean.
I'm really not into it.
And so I'm not.
The woman was hitting on me a while ago
and I said,
ma'am,
I call her ma'am.
That's a problem.
She was very persistent and I said,
ma'am,
I'm,
I'm like a hunting dog.
I'm a dog.
Just not the kind you pat,
you know,
I'm just not,
I'm just,
I'm sorry,
just,
you should stop this.
She's imagining holding your hand,
coming to your spoken word shows,
going and going to dinner with you and
talk about your day and um,
and you're like in front of your fucking
crazy speakers and your writing and
hoping the phone doesn't ring right.
Uh,
I unplug it on the weekends except on
sunday.
my best friend since I was a 11,
12 and he was 11.
We're still best friends.
Ian,
you ever heard the band fugazi?
Yes.
okay.
Well ian mci the now he's my best friend
and we grew up together doing music and
everything and we talk almost every
sunday.
And so,
uh,
we've been best friends since the carter
administration and so ian will call on
sunday.
We'll talk for awhile.
Otherwise the phone doesn't ring if it
does,
I'm like,
oh no.
Why?
Well,
I thought you liked me.
Why are you calling?
I,
yeah,
if you liked me,
he wouldn't write me.
But meanwhile,
I'm contentedly just working away and so
I'm good for like a race horse,
uh,
just watched me running around the
track,
but don't,
don't,
don't need to feed me any trainer.
Rigid in your behavior pattern.
You mean you've got it locked in,
he know what you enjoy,
you know,
it makes you content.
What gives you happiness and
appreciation and it's kind of a
replicant vulcan,
you know,
it doesn't.
Humans don't have play a large part in
it.
Like I don't need to go hang out with my
friends on the weekend and hey man,
you didn't call him man.
What's going on?
I don't,
don't,
don't call.
But you do appreciate those humans that
come to see you perform and you feel a
deep obligation to them.
Absolutely.
Yeah.
And I serve them and I love.
I like servitude.
I like wanting to give them something
good.
I make the best hash I possibly can.
And then I sling it with everything I've
got.
I just don't want to hang around
afterwards and talk about it.
Has to do it.
If I,
if I could just say thank you,
goodnight.
Walk out of the building and do a moving
vehicle and be 10 blocks down the road
before they get up out of their seats.
That would be fine.
It's just,
I don't know what else there is to do
except hit it and then quit it.
And so it makes some interactions a
little uncomfortable and that I liked
these people write a lot.
They have no idea how much I just want
to just rock their world with like a
book or a show.
But beyond that I,
hey,
come and hang out with us on it.
I don't know how to do that.
But you do get appreciation from hanging
out with people that you meet when you
go on your journeys.
Sure.
Uh,
you,
you meet someone on the road,
like some guy in his village.
All right,
so man,
how's your,
what's your day like?
You know,
what are you eating?
Okay.
Where you get your water from.
Show me that.
And then like,
do you differentiate them because
they're so unusual and their life is so,
you know,
it's information extraction.
You're just,
you don't really know that person and
they're not.
It's just a different relationship.
You don't feel that connection to
someone that you meet in real life in
America.
Like I meet them and I'm polite is a
sit.
Some people want to like hang out and be
your friend all the time.
I just don't understand it.
The same expression she's there and I'm
not trying to be a jerk just doesn't
compute.
And so instead of like,
hey,
we're all going to go down to the park,
come with.
It's like,
well how about I just,
I just make you a really good book and,
and I'll,
I'll,
I'll price it as cheaply as I can and
we'll just let that be okay.
Wow.
How about I'll just email you and say I
hope you're having a good day and we'll
just let it go and you don't seem to
have any problem with anything that
you're doing.
like there's not like some things you're
trying to resolve or work through.
Like this is what you found,
this thing you found this way.
This is my groove and I come from
Washington dc and I love that.
I love that city and I go there every
once in awhile to visit and some nights
I visit with my good pal ian of course,
but some nights I just want a mom my own
and I walked all my old jobs and I
walked by apartment buildings I lived
in,
but I walked by people's houses who
people who grew up with these amazing
musicians.
They all became big musicians and I know
they're in there sometimes I can even
see him in the window.
I don't want to go in.
I just like walking by their place and
knowing they're in there and like
literally I walked.
I've seen someone I grew up with like on
the street and I go out there.
He goes,
okay,
well henry,
why don't you run up and tap on the
shoulder and say,
hey man.
No,
I just liked the fact that I just saw
him walking.
ThAt's all I need.
Yeah,
it's weird and I,
I've been like that since I can remember
and it gets more like that the older I
get.
Well,
that would make sense because as you get
older,
you're more rigid in your ways and your,
your,
your groove is cut deeper and deeper and
a lot of this stuff I do,
it takes a bloody long time to finish
it.
You want to write a book,
then you better get ready for the long
haul because you'll be working on that
sucker two years later and you know,
it just never ends.
Like editing revisions in the tours.
I go on,
it's not like two weeks.
It's like it's like 13 months.
Like I'll see you next year that you do
that and then you take time off.
Right.
You didn't let go the long stretch and
they'll take time away from the tour.
Yeah,
and the only reason is if I had my way,
I'd be on the road every year and I'd
have hours of new material and no one
would ever get tired of me coming to
their city once a year and I used to
tour like that for years.
It goes out every year and people are
like,
henry,
we love you man,
but you got to start coming here.
Less often,
so a little offensive,
but he just keeps going like,
hey,
it's me again.
And so then I started doing it every
other year and then the,
my promoter types who are happy to take
their 15 percent.
They said,
henry,
we love you man,
but you got,
you can't,
you can't keep coming.
So often people just getting a little up
to here with it even every other year.
Yeah.
And so,
but spoken word and so I would think
that that would be enough time for me
too.
I wish it was.
And so I did what everyone told me to
this time around because I know these
people are all smarter than me and they
said,
can you wait a little while longer?
And so the last big tour is 2012 and I
went out again in 2016.
That was four years basically.
I went from one presidential election to
another and the ticket sales spiked
everywhere was like london was like
$1,500
more tickets than I've ever done there.
I sold out two nights at the sydney
opera house in sydney.
It was amazing.
And I said,
what's that about?
Is that you waited,
he just,
he gave people a time to,
to,
to forget how long you talk for them
and,
and so it's sad to think that I have to
wait until 20,
20,
but I can do little weekend here,
a weekend there,
but I can't go do the lap.
I just did next year.
No way.
But you want to.
Oh man.
Yeah.
I like being on stage.
I love being in front of those people.
I like giving.
I guess getting is the hard part.
Like when people applaud at the end of
the show,
I just get nervous.
I just want to run.
I stand there like one,
1002,
1003,
1000.
Okay.
I'm out of here.
Wow.
Yeah,
it just makes me uncomfortable.
Wow.
Listen,
Henry Rollins,
your unique motherfucker.
I don't think I've ever met anybody
like,
you know,
I know I have not ever met anybody like
you,
but I appreciate you.
I appreciate what you're doing and I
appreciate your attitude is very
contagious.
It's very exciting.
Thank you.
So infectious.
And thank you very much for doing this.
I really,
really appreciate it.
Thank you.
We got it.
Henry rollins,
ladies and gentlemen.
Great.