The joe rogan experience it.
I mean obviously it seemed way worse
over on your side,
but I was more worried when they made us
leave because the further up you got in
the bleachers and once you got out into
the concession area and in the
bathrooms,
that's where stuff was going down.
Like just people from the crowd.
Um,
you know guys with Irish flags all
obviously we're getting trashed,
talked to them and there was a big brawl
right next to me on the other side from
where they were sitting.
Right.
There was one just to our right.
I was looking left,
believe it was the guy that jumped in
and the registered on Khabib's team when
they were trying to leave,
when they're getting them out,
people in the crowd were like,
ah,
they start throwing shit at them first.
That's how the,
that's where the first shit was getting
thrown down and letting people know that
it was them.
We,
we all saw it was like,
that's the guy,
that's the guy right there right now.
It's like,
I don't know.
And he went and tried to do something
and I was
doing,
but you know,
there's a price to be paid for all this
shit.
Like all the,
all the drama and the trash talking.
That makes it so fun.
It also,
you know,
it has the potential for blowing up in
your face ultimately.
You like a couple people got punched,
but it was in an event where a bunch of
people got punched.
You know what I mean?
It's like way more than that.
It was awesome.
Yeah.
But you know what I'm saying?
It's like we,
we've made it seem,
it seemed like it was way worse than it
really was because in any other
situation it would be way worse than it
really was.
Like if it was a rock concert and some
dudes just from,
you know,
let,
one band was the opening band and then
there was another band that was in a
brawl with them and they were,
they were the main event and then the
fans of one band through down with the
fans,
the other band of beat the shit out of
each other.
That would,
for whatever reason,
be way worse than when it's at a fight.
Cause if it's at a fight,
it's just fighters.
Oh,
I saw this in St Cloud.
This was going on,
this insane clown posse guy tried to
drop kick Fred Durst,
he,
Fred,
there's wasn't even looking at them
running headstart and misses and look at
it.
It turns around like what?
And he just kept going.
I haven't seen they drag that dude off.
I mean that is maybe the worst public
dropkick in the history of the world.
I think they meant he dropped when he
tried to kick even after that.
Um,
you know,
were,
we were working very hard for this fight
in the limit,
you know,
somewhat limited period of time.
Um,
so we did,
didn't taper off quite the way we
normally do,
but roughly two weeks if you wanted to
do a rematch and if the UFC did grant
agreement,
this is obviously dependent upon how the
Nevada state athletic commission handles
the legal ramifications of him jumping
out of the cage,
attacking Dylan Dannis a subsequent
brawl.
The chaos that ensued.
Visas.
You mean you're,
you're dealing with a lot of legal shit
in his fight that that could hold things
up?
I mean,
they held both is correct.
Uh,
well he held a Habib's kind of got his,
yeah.
Okay.
Kind of got his purse paid so he gets
his first and Qbb.
Who the fuck knows what's going to
happen with him,
you know,
and uh,
yeah.
I,
I hope they're,
they're lenient on them and I'm not just
so we can get a rematch.
I mean,
I love watching him fight for his diet
and I can,
I can stretch myself to understand his
reaction.
I can stretch myself.
I can't stretch myself to understand the
other guys' reactions on what they did
leave.
He jumped over the cage and he jumps on.
It's,
it's not the end of the hall.
The guy that jumped in there was wearing
red who punched on her.
Yeah.
I'm not sure.
I think that's a boxing and coach,
but I'm,
I'm guessing he's a fighter.
He fights with the UFC,
uh,
into red was done not an old,
he wasn't older.
He actually worked with them.
Oh,
okay.
You work?
There you go.
Who is he?
I don't know his name.
Islamorada son.
Yeah.
It was either his Llama.
I don't think it was either one of those
guys like I know is laughing guy.
He was,
you know,
he hit done and a guy in a suit that
heritage is Russian manager.
He hit dylan either way.
Um,
but actually indicates when your mind
went in and,
and hit him from behind then.
Yeah.
You know,
I kinda,
I can't understand that.
Like I said,
for,
for Habib,
I didn't think it was,
you know,
it was,
it's just,
it's such a foolish thing to do because
this thing to do,
I know that Dylan was talking shit and
he was angry,
but like she didn't say anything because
I heard a few people saying that.
No,
I was standing beside dylan.
I didn't see what he did,
but I could hear.
So he didn't say anything now.
And I watched the back.
I seen,
he kind of beckoned them on.
Yeah.
You know,
just stupid end the fight stuff.
But it,
I didn't think it justified that level
of response.
And maybe there was something else in
the lead up,
you know,
dealing as a bit of a troll online.
So,
uh,
there was probably a bit of a buildup of
voter stuff,
but um,
yeah,
like I said,
it,
it wasn't that big a deal to me.
What had beaded.
Yeah.
Just really wasn't,
there's something I like love about a
man so deeply out of touch.
I mean that's the thing is like,
yeah,
look it up.
Fucking thumbs fucking up.
Me and my wife's just as Sarah Palin,
I love this fucking city by the,
the sexual chemistry between them is
palpable.
Probably Real,
super rich.
You were talking about at the beginning
of like,
like cults and I'm like,
I'm thinking about,
I'm thinking about Tom Cruise and
scientology.
There's a man using every ounce of what
scientology is offering to make himself
the best available man that he's capable
of being.
Yeah.
Then you've got Travolta,
you know what I mean?
Like you've got two versions of like,
like Amanda is becoming slightly out of
touch with what he,
you know,
Eh,
no,
look at my fucking wig bank.
It's a good way.
How amazing our wigs these days.
He's got great legs.
I mean,
that's a fucking incredible wig.
Wig thinning.
Just a little bit upfront.
You would think that's his hair.
He's living the dream.
It's incredible.
He's living in the goddamn dream.
Uh,
you okay with time?
We can wrap this up or whatever.
Yeah.
I'm 33 30 yeah,
we're,
what does that appear on the Oj thing?
Oh yeah,
that was,
I saw him.
That's amazing.
That little,
that Little Chin is that his,
he wore a little chimp.
He got like a little Chin Yamaka there.
It's unbelievable.
I remember seeing him at an award
ceremony that and then that when he had
that Little Chin thing and I was like,
did he put that on after the thing?
I met him when his wife was on fear
factor.
Really?
Yeah.
Kelly Preston was on fear.
She was on fear factor.
Yeah.
Celebrity fear factor.
David Hasselhoff.
Kelly.
Wow.
Preston.
How were they?
She was really nice.
She was super friendly,
but I felt like I felt like they
recruited people.
Yes.
Yeah.
I mean they were there.
Scientology was sort of a stigmatized,
it was,
there was a lot of people that were
joining it.
What is going on there?
What we see is a black cap on that hair
is so crazy fake looking.
That's like that magnetic man that you
could like move.
The magnets are on the Korean hair.
Like who's fucking hair looks like that?
That's crazy,
man.
That's,
I mean,
the color,
everything is wrong.
That's madness.
Like when someone says Stephen Hawking's
identified as a British,
he identifies a dead or dying when he
was alive.
Yeah.
Brilliant.
British physicist slash heterosexual
atheist,
a heterosexual identify who by the way
was,
um,
uh,
rebuttal.
The freak riddled with infidelity.
I've never met a guy,
so not capable of,
of cheating and found a way to cheat on
his wife.
Well,
apparently you can still get it up.
Oh,
well apparently even though his body
didn't move,
could feel things.
That was his son.
He is the scientist he used to go to was
Eric Weinstein told me about this.
I was like,
what?
He's like,
yeah,
he's a freak.
And I was like,
wait,
what?
And he's like,
yeah,
he used to go to strip clubs and there's
like videos of him like rolling into a
strip club in the wheelchair.
Like he would go.
That was his thing.
Where'd you get littered with
infidelity?
What'd you hear?
That he cheated on his wife all the
time.
We w we in that fucking movie.
The whole reason that he,
well,
I mean the whole reason that he left his
wife was because he fell in love with
somebody else.
But wasn't it like a nurse there was
taking down what the truth was that he
was my boss and the nurses,
if you google,
if you Google Stephen Hawking,
he was affiliate of,
he was always fucking around.
Oh.
You know,
come on man.
He was always fucking around.
Um,
yeah.
That's once he got to love the good
pubs.
Yeah.
Once he got to take the good gosh.
Mad that cosmology cash.
Yeah.
You know what also,
he's probably like my cock and a play by
the rules.
The world dealt me the shittiest God,
please.
I'm a super genius and you know what?
I fucking agree.
Do whatever the fuck you want to do and
you want to leave me,
you should leave me.
Why would you only fuck me?
Yeah,
I'm,
I'm barely here.
I'm a machine now.
I use this finger to talk.
No,
it fell apart.
It was his eyes and his fucking in his
mouth.
At some point you can even use his
hands.
It was just nice,
right?
Yeah.
Wasn't it as ideal?
I kind of a thing where he could kind of
click.
He would do.
He would,
he would look at something too.
He had a thing where it was taken away.
Then I dug.
He would look at Shit and it was maybe I
want to see your ass hole.
Can you sit on my face?
Face face.
Don't kill me though.
I'm going to figure out the universe.
I don't,
don't smother me with your pussy.
I need to figure out how stars work.
Is there are black holes real or is it
just a brown star?
Please.
I don't want to drown in your pussy.
I'm still on the subject of dark matter.
I'm trying to figure out the universe
before.
I know in my pants,
that's what the,
that's one of the strippers that he got
hooked up with was called dark matter.
I'm trying to think around dark matter,
dark matter.
I could see her with a big Ole fur coat.
Hell yeah.
He's going to say for a big Ole for
Bush.
Yes.
Take a message with a,
with a,
a pencil because her nails are too long.
Long that dark matter.
That's what it was.
But that was one that got brought up as
well.
That was also in the middle of a huge
conversation about,
you know,
Ben Gazi and the Iran deal.
Those are the two things or two of the
three things that I like to do on
twitter,
although I'm no longer on there.
You got off.
Yeah.
Bad for you.
I was glad to see Kanye West got off
too.
Did he?
Yeah.
Delete all his accounts last week.
And I was glad too.
Cause you're just like,
once you're a target it's just too
painful.
Yeah.
Well definitely shouldn't be reading
that shit.
No,
I don't read it.
Yeah.
But,
um,
well,
when you become a target,
how do you know if you don't read it?
Well,
I know what I'd lived through when first
happened and that's been like four or so
months ago,
so I just know how I've reacted in my
locker or real life since that happened
to me.
How long did it take for things die off
to die off?
What do you mean slow down?
Where they weren't just coming after you
constantly,
like I told you that news crews,
when they found out that you were going
to come on the podcast the first time
they were trying to show up at my house,
they were trying to show up at the
studio.
They were trying to find me at the
comedy store.
Yeah.
I mean they were just trying to hunt
down.
Yeah.
Anything about you?
I know I was sneaking segues from my
boyfriend because we were at my mom's
house when I did it.
You know,
w we were at home in Salt Lake City.
When I tweeted at 2:11 AM I just woke up
and I had this thought in my head,
oh my God,
this can make so much sense.
And then I tweeted it and I went right
back to sleep.
And when I woke up at seven,
the shit had hit the fan,
you know?
Yeah.
But I was like,
I'm going to expound on this later.
That was one of those kinds of things.
You just want to get it down.
And I,
you know,
always slept with my computer and tweet
when I wake up.
Like,
you know,
when you're old you have to go to the
bathroom a lot.
So I always tweet and fall back to
sleep.
C and I,
and then on the Ambien tweets,
my daughter,
I used to always,
when I took my Ambien,
I called my daughter and she or she
called me,
she goes,
mom,
you,
you're starting to do the Ambien tweets.
Get off,
get off the twitter,
you know?
But,
uh,
I,
so I just called my daughter.
Then every night when I,
when I was doing the Ambien and I'd go,
you know what,
here comes a big fish.
She recorded it.
Here comes a big fish right through my
window.
Oh,
he's getting stuck in the mirror
and she,
that's where she goes,
mom turned it all off and go to sleep.
I have to have my family telling me that
because neither standing guard by your
bed.
Yeah.
Hold on.
Let me read that before you tweet it.
No,
no,
no.
That's what she does now.
She don't,
she took my twitter account away.