Three, two, one and
[inaudible] we're live. So, uh,
you have a wonderful nickname,
Ms. Summers. Uh, is do people use,
still use MS as ms gone?
I don't see that anymore.
You see it on forms ms as like a possible,
but like Harvard, was it Harvard? What,
which one of the Major Ivy League schools.
What's adding a bunch of different gender,
different gender neutral pronouns.
Like Zi,
h e and they were adding a bunch of
crazy new ones that they have invented.
Have you seen these things
like Gyno American, that's an,
does that mean I know Mac
and I think I want to be one.
Can I be a Gyno American?
Is that okay?
Do you have to be one of your
nicknames though is a based mom? Yes.
Which is, I know that term from the
rap world, like based like there's,
what's that Dude Lil B, the Bass
God, is that his name? Um, and,
but I didn't know what based means,
but I've heard it used a bunch of times
and it's always a positive descriptive,
right? Yeah, that's right.
I had to Jamie's very,
he's into the hip hop world. If I
have to go to him and young kids. Um,
so I had to Google it and there's an
urban dictionary definition based is all
about being yourself and not caring
about what anybody else thinks. Right.
So they use it as an excuse.
I'm sorry. They use it as a, um,
an example.
It's when you don't care,
like that bag looks gay on you.
I don't care based,
oh, I didn't know that.
That seems like, I thought that I
thought it'd be a different Devin.
I thought like based mom is like,
you're cool. That's what I thought.
And I said so because they
called me that for quite a while.
Is it mainly the gamers
and then they explained that no,
it means to be authentic and you say
what you think you're not hypocritical.
So it's that, I mean, I,
I think it's a great compliment
being based and being a mom,
it seems quite positive. Yes. But uh,
it, it was a very funny nickname. Um,
so you got involved in
this whole gamergate thing
because I found out about you
through a guest through
the whole gamergate thing
because someone had called me
an Mra once and I don't remember
what the context of it was,
but it was something involving
something that had to do with feminism.
And, uh, they, they call it to me
as a pejorative. And I was like,
what does that mean?
What does an Mra?
So I had to Google it and then when I
realized it was men's rights advocate and
I was like, I can't believe that
a feminist is making fun of me.
It's using a negative term men's rights
advocate so that it gets bad to care
about men's rights, like
what, what's going on?
So that made me get deeper into the
rabbit hole of Ms. Christina Summers.
And then I started watching your
factual feminism videos and I started
listening to some of your conversations
and I became very impressed.
But I also became very perplexed
because you face a lot of backlash.
And, uh, I found that perplexing
because everything that I saw,
you seem to be very reasonable,
very measured, very informed.
Like how did you eat? Polite, very polite.
How did you get on this kind of
crazy journey? Almost as like a,
it mean, correct me if I'm
wrong, but it seems like,
I don't want to say you're
redefining feminism,
but you're redefining it
after it's been redefined.
Does that make actually taking it, taking
it back to its original noble purpose,
which was about equality,
basic fairness to women that women
and men should enjoy equal liberty and
dignity. Right? Of course.
But feminism has drifted into I think a
kind of female chauvinism and I became a
feminist many years ago,
decades ago because I did not appreciate
male chauvinism. I still don't,
but I don't like female chauvinism. That's
what we have today. Too much of that.
And is there an origin of all this?
I mean there's a one thing that you could
point to where this all started cause
it seems like the,
the origins of it.
Like if you go back and watch like old
movies and take a look at old culture,
it's very clear.
There's a lot of sexism going on.
Like men would smack women and old
movies and it was, it was like,
it seemed like that's like
in other than reading books,
that's the best
interpretation of the time.
So if you go back to those 1950s films
and look at how people treated each
other,
it seems like there were much clearer
definitions that women were struggling
against like this, this idea that
women were inferior, that the,
the whole stereotype of women belong
barefoot and pregnant in the kitchen like
this. This was, this is what young women
were fighting against were women, period.
We're fighting against when feminism
sort of started. It's march.
That's right. And then what happened,
particularly in the academy,
and I was teaching philosophy in the
1980s and the chairman of my department
asked me to teach a course
in feminist theory and I
thought, fine, I'm a theorist.
I'm a feminism.
I sent away for the textbooks.
I was shocked by what
came through the mail.
I spent the summer reading these books.
And as,
as a philosophy professor of many years,
I thought there was a sacred
commandment about college teaching.
Thou shalt teach both sides of the
argument. It never occurred to me,
it was my job as the teacher to take
my views about the world and, and,
and implanting them in the minds of my
students. I wanted to give them the,
the techniques to make their
own decisions. And you do that.
One way to do that is to give them the
best that was thought and said on both
sides of a contentious issue. Well,
these textbooks were not like that.
They were a series of
mutually reinforcing readings.
And it was a conspiracy theory about
the patriarchy buttressed by statistics.
So I, after spending a
summer reading this books,
I wrote a paper and,
and gave,
I went to the American Philosophical
Association and presented it.
And I will tell you, typically at the
American Philosophical Association,
if you give a paper, people
are, it's very combative.
Uh, but then you go out for drinks.
Well, we did not go out for drinks. Uh,
I gave this paper, women, mostly women
in the audience were hissing and booing.
And I was excommunicated from a
religion I didn't even know existed.
The church of feminism, I
was, I was considered a,
that I'd committed an act of heresy.
What was your take on it that was
so offensive? Well, I said that, uh,
that feminism should be about mutual
respect. It should be about equality,
not the demonization of men.
It was as if they had,
if you could reduce it to a few phrases,
it would be women are from Venus,
men are from hell. And I
thought, that's absurd.
Why would we want to teach courses
like that? The demonize men,
let's celebrate humanity and have an,
you know,
and also accuracy because these texts
were filled with what I've come to call
advocacies statistics or in
some cases hate statistics,
sort of designed to create
a just anger in women.
And they happen not to be true,
but they work very well as propaganda.
So as a philosophy professor,
I was very upset to see classrooms
being used to disseminate propaganda and
twisted conspiracy
theories about patriarchy.
So I tried to correct it
and what happened was I,
the radicals were already there in the
academy and they do not tolerate dissent.
Well. I mean, you see it today on campus.
What you're seeing happening
on the campus today at Yale,
these terrible
confrontations between these,
some are calling the McRib
bullies now, um, and,
and professors and so forth.
These, these angry mobs.
I have been confronting them for years,
but now the public is beginning to notice.
Well, you've been confronting them only
from the standpoint of feminism, right?
I mean,
what was going on and Yale was a
professor had written a letter saying that
children should probably have the
right to be a little bit outrageous and
perhaps even offensive in their Halloween
costumes and just Halloween costumes.
This led to this massive outrage lotion.
It's hunger.
What seems like to me that
there's something about,
it just seems really fake.
It's something about, it seems like
there's people that have the green light.
This one I like.
There's a lot of these issues where I
feel like the reaction that people have,
it's not a genuine reaction that what
the reaction represents is a green light
to be an asshole.
It's like if you think that you
really mean, it really means these
people and they want it people's jobs,
they want their heads on a platter.
We ever argued with anybody that
I wanted there to fire them.
You want convince them
but this is something different.
This is a fanatical well it's because
there's a certain amount of power that's
involved in social media is a certain
amount of power involved in this.
It is in fact a mob mentality and
a mob mentality is a very real,
real mentality.
Whether it's an actual mob out on
the street in the middle of a riot,
or whether it's a bunch of people on
Twitter to get riled up into a frothy rage
danger and start attacking people the
way that this one girl was screaming at
that professor who was speaking and
very logical and very measured tones,
and she was screaming at him and mob
can't be reasoned with and it's the worst
possible display of irrationality and
to have it on a campus. And right now,
the deans,
the college presidents,
they are so craven and they're
writing these, you know,
self abnegating letters and
saying, oh, I'm so sorry.
And I honor this conversation. Honor the
conversation with, uh, with an angry mob.
I mean, it's, well,
it seems like what that woman did when
she wrote that original letter was tick
take a little bit of a chance against the
mob was take a little bit of a chance,
and this is the reaction.
The Bob was like, fuck you.
You know, know we're the mob.
And that woman's screaming at her husband,
oh, I believe it was her husband, right?
Yes. A distinguished, uh, uh,
I think he's a sociologist and
he was being very fair and,
and engaging them outside in the open,
in this incredibly large group.
But it was funny how he,
he had to do it because there was so many
people round and some of them couldn't
hear what he was saying.
He's saying, well,
I will raise my voice so that
you will be able to hear me,
but I'm not yelling at her and
I'm raising my voice. Factly,
he would turn to one group of
students because they would say,
you're not looking at us. He would
turn and then the state was behind.
You would say you're not,
you know, this man could not,
when he was in a terrible situation,
all because of Halloween costumes,
these children, these chill,
I call them children, they,
I'd wouldn't have called college
students shelter, but now they, they,
it's so they're so infant tile, but
it's worse than that. It's, it's,
it's infant tile. Yes. But
it's infused with bitter,
divisive, hardline politics that
they learned in their classrooms.
And that's how I tie it to
what I read in these textbooks,
these paranoid theories,
these theories that I read incited a
fair amount of women, not, uh, not most.
I mean, I think most college women
would read these texts and just move on.
But about 10 to 15% will become fixated
and sort of intoxicated with rage.
And I thought over the years,
and now I, I mean the same,
similar things have gone on
with race, scholarship and, um,
and gender politics. There's
similar phenomenon. Well,
it seems to me that certain
ideologies can become, like, they,
they can become contagious.
And they're also very intoxicating.
It's very intoxicating to be a part
of a group that's being opposed.
And that is opposing.
You're on a team,
you're on or you were in a war,
you're on an army and you
were against the patriarchy.
You have an enemy and you're
against whatever the hell it is.
Like when those kids storm
that, did you see the uh, the,
the latest one where they,
there's a study hall and these kids in
there are studying and these guys came
into his sign screaming black lives
matter. Black lives matter. Like, okay,
do you,
are these people who are studying or
they're the ones who are oppressing you?
Are they, who are you trying to impart
this wisdom too? I know they wouldn't.
It was ridiculous. I saw it. And, and if,
if the students didn't get
up and join them, they came
over and accused them. Yes.
It looked like our struggle section
session or something in a fanatical
government and, and they don't have
power. But what if they did? Yes,
they would be very scary.
Well,
looked like an onion article come to life.
I know the world has become an end and
the on campus is an onion. It's all right.
Yeah. It's almost impossible
to distinguish it. So what,
what caused all this though?
How did this happen?
Why are there not more measured,
intelligent people that are trying to
raise children and teach them how to be
measured in an intelligent adults and
look at things objectively. Like what is,
what is causing this underlying
sort of theme that's right. This,
this delusional theme
that's repeating itself.
Well, first of all, there are
lots of reasonable professors.
Even in women's studies, there are
reasons, reasonable professors,
but they are not the vocal.
Uh,
there's a vocal minority of professors
who are apparently for certain students,
charismatic, and they have
for years been teaching these,
these paranoid views of the world
and inciting rage against men,
gender profiling of men.
And,
and they have a following.
And this little following has been
there all along. But about, um,
two years ago,
the Department of Education sent out
essentially an edict warning colleges that
if you don't take strong measures
against, uh, sexual harassment and,
and the rape culture,
and they didn't use the word rape culture,
but they alluded to it. If you do
not take all of these measures, uh,
you will be held accountable
and can lose your funding.
Now to the department's
credit, they wanted to do
something about campus assault.
That's fine.
But they went too far.
They believed the propaganda about
what's happening on the college.
And they gave a cure that was
worse than the disease. I mean,
the cure was to turn campuses
into a little pink police state.
Some column, feminists, police dates
where every joke is now monitored and,
and you're supposed to be reporting
other students. If you hear a remarked,
it could be interpreted as sexist.
And this isn't happening.
It's at public universities where the
last time I looked, we were, you know,
part of, you know, the, the
US constitution applies,
the students are being policed by
people that have no right to do it.
But this was a incited by the,
by the Department of Education.
How bizarre. Uh, so that's,
that's the original,
that's the route. If you go back and
look, when did words like trigger warning,
safe space, micro aggression. You know, we
didn't hear these three, four years ago.
What happened was that these angry
groups who've always been there,
they were empowered by,
um,
the assistant secretary of education.
The Department of Education,
she basically told them you can make
a federal case out of, uh, you know,
someone walking by and you know,
a,
a micro aggression and they consider
everything Amanda's at micro aggression.
What is a micro aggression?
Like can me a definition of what an
aggressive thing would be to punch
somebody's right or to use an obvious,
you know,
just intolerably sexist or a racial slur.
A micro aggression would be,
um, what's something that
is demeaning but you know,
prison doesn't necessarily intended
and they, they would say, you know,
somebody saying hi, beautiful.
That's a microaggression. Oh yeah.
A man holding a door open for girls.
That would be,
that's benevolent sexism and those
are micro aggressive. Maybe not micro,
maybe a nano aggression.
What if you're a straight man and
you hold open a door for a lesbian?
Well, she's a nice person. She'll be
grateful. But what if you're a gay man?
You hold up at the door
for a straight man.
Do you get accused of micro
aggression there? It seems like,
you know,
you're trying to tease out the logical
implications of their mess with it.
You can't you, yeah. You said
before it's a rabbit hole.
You will never emerge is a sane person.
I've paid over the last two years or so.
Uh,
when I started going
down this rabbit hole,
I started visiting these websites and uh,
visiting a lot of forums that you could
easily just called echo chambers and
looking at what happens,
first of all,
when someone disagrees even politely,
they're banned instantly.
When someone had any, uh, there was, uh,
there was one was a topic about,
um,
sexual assault in terms of drinking,
about what is,
what is rape. And the, the, the
subject was they were discussing,
they were accusing someone,
a man of rape because he and a woman
had gotten drunk together and had sex.
So the man had raped a woman and it was,
it was very bizarre.
They say that and you'll
say, what, wait a minute.
What if they are both equally drunk?
They do. We, and I asked this,
I was at a debate at the University of
Virginia. I debated a law professor.
I said, then are you saying to people
could rape each other at the same time?
You know,
they're both drunk.
And she said she thought
that was a perfectly possible
situation. And that is such
a degradation of language,
a trivialization of a serious,
but they have an expanded the meaning
of terms so that now sexual assault
encompasses just normal
behavior that people enjoy,
which is a,
it has been known to happen that people
have drinks and then have sex. Well,
it's a Gi and percentage of the
culture becomes rapist then a yes,
most of the people, even even throughout
history and throughout the world today,
90% of the world would
probably be deemed rapists.
And I also don't understand why it is
automatically the guy's fault if it's,
if it's consensual.
I'm not talking about someone being
incapacitated and blackout drunk.
That's reasonable. People would see
that as an, as an assault, but just it,
you're both really drunk and you
have sex. Um, why is he the rapist?
Because that tends to be what happens on
the campus. They do blame the young man.
They don't say you raped each other,
that they will take her side if
she can show they'd had drinks.
And I find this,
uh,
another strange thing that's happening
with feminism today is that it's going
the,
I call it fainting couch feminism.
It's almost as if we're going back to the
Victorian era where there was delicate
ladies preyed upon by men and as if
the women aren't moral agents. I mean,
if you take a lot of drinks,
a,
you're probably have made a decision to
lower your inhibitions and be wild or
all kinds of things are going on that
would explain that you're still an agent
in, in charge of if you're, you
know, yourself self mastery.
But they denied this of women.
It's all is a women have no agency
and are constantly triggered,
need safe spaces at Brown university.
By the way,
they had to feminists debating.
One of them was the libertarian,
a great Wendy Mackelroy and she didn't
believe the statistics and another was
Jessica Valenti, hardline feminists.
They were debating, but that was fine.
It was a debate. You think that would
make everyone happy? Both sides.
Well represented.
No,
the brown feminists were traumatized
by the very idea that someone would be
invalidating our experience.
They use that phrase and they
ha they formed a safe room,
a safe space where you could go,
which had videotapes are
frolicking puppies, coloring books,
bubbles,
stuffed animals.
And this was described
in the New York Times,
but it was a cover story in the
New York Times magazine by Judith,
Judith Shulevitz and this was the safe
space. And you read it and you're,
you're astonished that the of
the infantilization puppies,
puppies frolicking puppies, safe levels,
coloring books. I get it.
It's kindergarten for college,
girls hurts. My brain hurts. I just don't,
I think there's,
there's a connection that a lot
of people have that somehow or sax
with regret is bad.
It's negative.
And that sex with regret
when it comes to alcohol,
that perhaps since men are
classically the pursuers,
that there's coercion involved and
even though the man is intoxicated,
he did that on his own.
He didn't need it.
Did that in order to sort of lure the
girl in and then have sex with her,
but that's not rape.
And at the end of the day,
even though that's kind of
sleazy behavior, at the end
of the day, it's just sex.
Like why is sex so bad?
Like it's sex is not terrible.
What's terrible is rape actually rape,
it's terrible,
terrified thinking here to be killed or
what a horrible experience and this is a
bad date, you know, or a bad
hookup I guess you would call it.
And where are you are, you
know, you didn't know you did.
Maybe you regret it the next day.
And we do see on campus,
I've watched these cases where these
young women will, they wouldn't,
they don't report these
things and sometimes it,
they have to take a gender studies
class a year later and then they bring
charges and there is no
way it's metaphysically
impossible to have any evidence
of what happened.
But if she can and,
and young men had been thrown
off campus and, or you know,
sort of tarred with the, with the,
uh, the stigma of being a rapist.
I have Thaddeus Russell on who's an
author and a professor at Occidental.
And he was talking about how there was
a case where a man and a woman who were
going to school there got drunk and
had sex and the man was accused of rape
because of this and kicked out
of school and the girl stayed.
They were both equally drunk. She sent him
taxing, you know, c'mon over. Oh, I know.
Do you have condoms? Like the whole deal?
Yeah, it was, but somehow or another,
you're not responsible for sexual
activity when you're drunk,
but you are responsible for driving.
You're responsible if you commit violence.
You're not exonerated from any of those
things if you're drunk. But somehow,
what if a woman has sex when
she's drunk with a man? Yeah,
we'll try this out on the,
on the LAPD, you a, you know,
you drink a lot and let's
say I get stopped by the
police and then I say he gave
me drinks, he gave me drinks. Is I have
you right. Oh, then they arrest him.
I don't think so. I think,
yeah, we recognize that. Uh,
I would be the guilty, yeah.
Well when I,
in this article that I was,
or this a forum that I was reading
where they were accusing this guy, uh,
his name is Michael Shermer.
I don't know if you know his,
you know his story as a famous skeptic.
Oh yes, of course. I know his story,
but he was, he was, uh, the guy who
was accused and he was accused of, um,
being,
uh,
a womanizer and a drunk and that he got
some girl drunk and had sex with and
they were calling it rape. And, uh,
one of the things that they were saying
during this whole thing was someone had
come in and said, well, why is it
that when you're drunk, you're,
you're responsible for all these other
things but you're not responsible for sex.
And that person was immediately
banned from the forum.
They were immediately kicked out.
Like, you can't entertain that angle.
Right. Can't entertain that possibility.
That's what the, that's, that's why it's,
I would call these people fanatics
because the, it's not simply that they,
you know, want to do all they
can to promote their side.
They don't want the other side
to get a hearing. Right. They,
they do not believe in intellectual
pluralism or political pluralism.
It's my side and only my side. And
everyone is discredited in immediately,
simply for not agreeing with them.
And they're being reinforced by
these incredibly bizarre men,
the male feminist men and not all of them.
I mean,
some of them are doing it
for all the right reasons.
So when we were doing it because they
want quality and they think that women
should be treated as equals,
but there's a lot of them are doing it
for Social Brownie points and they're,
they're doing it to be
considered as like a, the, the,
in a higher ethical or moral standard
to the, the women that they're pursuing.
Well, I think a lot of them do it also
because they believe it. Yeah. And they,
maybe they had very feminist
mothers reinforced by teachers.
And then if they took gender studies,
my goodness that, that, you know,
it's all there and the
texts and so people,
I mean it,
I forgive students because I know
that they have gone through relentless
propaganda when it comes to gender because
there's the, the gender police have,
the gender activists have not allowed
dissident voices and that we are here.
There are many professors
that agree with me.
People like Camille Polya and Wendy
Kaminer, many journalists like the great,
you know, Cathy young and on
and on. But we have been, uh,
you know, demonized and our
voices are not, you know,
we're not invited to the table.
Well,
classically feminine women are also
demonize women who wear skirts and high
heels and like the just painted
nails and makeup and things that,
you know,
people may enjoy that look for some
reason that's a negative thing.
Like some reason you're,
you're falling into what the Patriarchy
is set up for you. You're, you're,
you are fulfilling their self,
demeaning stereotypes in some way.
That's kind of like it. You
can't like lipstick, you know,
you're not allowed to like fake eyelashes
or whatever the hell you like wearing.
It's unless you're a
transsexual transsexual,
you're allowed to go full whole hog
Bette Davis from the 1950s you could do
whatever you want.
Yeah, there are different schools.
I mean some of them don't.
They don't go after that,
but there.
But they want you to know that
femininity and masculinity are strictly
performances that none of it has a basis
in biology. That's where it gets crazy.
Right? I think it's very crazy. Social
Constructs, all the social construct.
Well there it's hardly as,
of course culture plays a role,
but biology does too.
And there's a kind of nature nurture
divide and it's just not sensible to teach
students both.
And
it's, if you look at the
biologists, the physiologist, you,
many of the psychologists,
they'll tell you they're a very
clear male female differences.
And not that everyone embodies them,
but most of us do.
And so they're denying what almost
everyone can see with their own eyes.
So that's also people that
can really buy into this,
this sort of gender
intense gender activism.
They have to be able to believe what
they're reading in the text and not what
they see with their eyes or even in their
own hearts so that it has the makings
of, as I've said, sort of
fanatical movement was loony.
It's not just financial.
It's like you're,
you're listening to some of
the things that people say, oh,
I watched a video where a woman was
talking about gender being a social
construct construct and she was talking
about the differences that are often
cited between men and women physically
and they're just because of physical
activity that the activities at the
men choose versus the activities at the
women's shoes and if the women engaged
in the same activities that would have
the same physical abilities as the man.
I was like,
what the fuck are you talking about?
That's denying testosterone.
The role it plays in muscle development
and the difference in bone structure and
it's denying it. People talk about, oh,
on the right there's there anti
science and there's some of that,
but on the left it's more consequential
because these people are in the
universities, cooks on the right
tend not to be on the campuses,
but these people are teaching
and in our most elite schools,
well gender is the only area where it
doesn't seem like you are allowed to have
an objective conversation about
the statistics or the facts.
Like if you question things or if you
have any questions about the facts or the
statistics, you become like, you
become questioned. Like you're, you're,
you're a bad person. You're, you're,
you're a person with alternative motives.
You can't just be looking at objective,
like how, what is the number one?
Like someone had told me one in four
women have been raped and I'm like, wow,
that,
that doesn't seem right.
Like one in four women have
met creeps a hundred percent.
It's probably more like 90 90%
of women have met creeps, right?
How many have actually been raped
as it one in four this out real.
So we started googling it and you know,
we found all these different numbers,
but there's no hard line numbers and
that could be attributed to a bunch of
things.
First of all,
the very real fact that many women
that have been involved in a horrible
situation like that don't want to
report it. They don't want to be shamed,
they don't want to,
they're just,
they would rather pretend it didn't
happen and move on with their life.
They'd rather barrier that is a
certain percentage of the population.
And then what, how many have
actually been raped? I mean,
how many have been,
how many of falsely accused men of
rape when nothing really happened?
You can't even say that. If you say that,
if you even admit that that's a reality,
you are some sort of an apologist
or rape apologist or you're
a rape enabler, right? Yeah. There's
something, but this is, these are facts.
It's happened to friends of mine.
I've had friends that have absolutely
not raped someone and been accused of it
and had to go to court and had to deal
with much of things in hire lawyers.
And eventually the charges were dropped,
but the fact remains that they
were accused. Of course it happens.
This one and four and one in five.
It's been around for years.
What is the origin of it? Oh,
it started with research, uh,
promoted by MS magazine. It was one of the
original, what I call advocacy studies.
It was someone that did a study,
not to find the truth,
but to buttress an ideology
about patriarchy. And this case,
uh, I don't want to keep going after,
but it was a professor at the time. Uh,
I think she's at the
University of Arizona. And she,
if you look at the survey,
she asked a series of questions.
So some of them were good and,
and she didn't ask where you ever raped.
If you ask people that you
get a very low number, so you,
what they've learned to do is ask around
and say, have you ever been, you know,
violently threatened and then someone
had sex, you know, well, that's fine.
But she also said,
have you ever had sex when you didn't
want to because of man gave you alcohol?
And anybody that said yes
was counted as a rape victim.
Now I could imagine cases where you had
sex when you didn't want to because you
know you passed out.
No one denies that his rate,
but this question invited
people that think, well, yeah,
I did have sex. I really wish I
hadn't had it, and yeah, I was drunk.
All those people. Now the set,
and this became the basis,
this study became the basis
for the one and four number.
Now it's one in five because there've
been other studies that sort of copied
this methodology.
The second thing she found is the vast
majority of the women did not think it
was rape. They thought it
was miscommunication. So
they did not agree with that.
She was classifying it as rape
and put that number out there.
And I think a majority dated
their alleged rapist. Again,
not not what you'd expect from someone
who's a victim of a heinous crime.
So they ask vague questions
and then they get,
they get their numbers and then it
gets into the media in the media.
Doesn't realize, I think that the gender
scholars have an agenda and they're not,
like if you teach in a women's studies,
I don't want to say women's studies
because there are serious scholars,
but if you're in a gender studies
department or gender theory, your,
your views are not checked
by objective scholars.
They're just checked by other
people that share your worldview.
So there hasn't been this quality
control. So we're getting, exactly.
So we're getting a lot of, of, of just
specious statistics that are out there.
This one and four is the classic case
when the Bureau of Justice Statistics,
which sets the gold standard
for research on, on crime.
They find on the campus that the number
is closer to one in 50 or one in 53 for
sexual assault. And they, did
they define sexual assault by,
is that rape? It's both
rape and it's uh, you know,
some kind of serious physical that's
still pretty horrible. It's terrifying.
It's terrible. That's
one. One in 50 is awful.
It is. But, but one in
50 versus one in four.
It's the difference between like
war torn condo and the, you know,
in the United States, one in four is
the Congo, right? It's probably not,
it's probably more like 90% net
probably like, uh, there are,
there are places in time of war where
rape is used as a weapon of war and the
rates are, but Swarthmore
college, Yale University,
Berkeley, they are not the war tour
in Congo. So yeah, there is too much.
I always say there is too much sexual
assault on campus and it is probably part
of the, the combination of the hookup
culture and the binge drinking culture.
It's a big problem, but it's not
a problem. The if patriarchy,
it's probably uh, you know, just,
it needs a different solution.
But what they do is want to make it seem
as though we have these sex criminals,
these predators hunting for
young women on the campus.
And it's probably,
you know,
an awkward 19 year old boy who thought
this girl liked him and they got drunk
and had sex. And then she can
say that he was a rapist and Eda,
he had no intention and no awareness
of doing anything wrong and he could be
ruined.
I mean instantly ruined.
I hear from some of these young men and
I know of a psychologist in psychology,
a psychologist or getting to get these
young men in their practice because they
come in, they are devastated.
You become a nonperson, uh,
and you are shamed. I mean, it's one of
the worst things you can do to a person.
If you're a victim of a crime,
it's a horrible thing.
But people will sympathize with
you and your dignity is intact.
But if you are accused of being like,
I mean,
it's like being accused of being a
child molester or to be called a rapist.
It's not much better
and people revile you.
And now we're doing this very casually,
young men on our campuses can be called
a rapist because of a drunken hookup.
And then he will bear that stigma for
life because the Internet never forgets.
And in some cases of colleges,
we'll put it on his record
and when he goes to transfer,
I'm just going to get out of here and
start over. He can't because it's there.
So we've got to change this.
This is a terrible miscarriage of justice.
Now this person,
you don't have to name her,
but the woman who created
this stunning Mary costs it.
Actually, she's become more
reasonable lately with the,
but that's probably blow back.
I think she shocked her
statistics are kind of shit.
I think she shocked by what's happened.
She became quite famous and quite
sought after because of this as well.
It's very intoxicating as
well. Yes, you can. Here's the
thing. Know about academia.
You can make a career on
documenting victimization,
especially if you can get high numbers,
uh,
victimization of women you can make.
Now, if you come in with low numbers,
it's the opposite. It can be career
diminishing. And there are very serious,
wonderful criminologists who did studies
and came up with relatively low figures
and they become demonized. They found
themselves not invited, you know,
to apply for jobs or,
or, um, denied tenure.
There are no motive.
There's no motive right now to tell
the truth about women's victimization.
There are huge incentives
to exaggerate it.
And so it stays there unchallenged.
And I think the journalists don't
fully understand this. They sit up,
but I got this from a scholar
at the University of Arizona.
I got this from a scholar at Cornell,
but what they don't know is this scholar
may be an idea log or had an agenda
that's it got in the way of her
or sometimes his objectivity.
Well, it seems like this is the
type of cyclical thing, this, this,
this,
these reinforcing ideologies that
you're going to teach these children,
these children will grow up to complete,
complete their education and become
professors and continue that sort of cycle
without ever breaking this pattern.
And it can be a real problem if,
if the universities continue to teach
these ideologies without question,
without some sort of a,
some sort of a peer review.
But it seems like their peers
are just reinforcing ideologists.
So what, what, how does that, how
does this ever get fixed? Well, I,
I don't know.
It has your name.
It gets fixed from you maybe doing your
videos. Well, doing those videos, you're,
you're so calm and logical and he,
you know,
you're very reasonable and they have a
tremendous amount of views. And I think,
I think there's a lot of people that when
they get called a rape apologist or a
bigot or whatever, that they don't,
when they don't agree with it,
they get angry and then they join
the other team. They were like, well,
fuck these feminists. They're
all crazy bitches. You know,
I'm on team men like Alfalfa, join the
heat man, woman haters club. You know,
remember that our gang, most
people don't, I'm old. But the,
the reality is most people,
I think most people just want to
be around nice people. Most people,
most people and most people that
they don't want to discriminate.
I think most people don't
want to discriminate by about
when it comes to race or
when it comes to gender,
when it comes to anything.
Most people just want people to rise
through their life or get through whatever
they're trying to get through by virtue
of the quality of their, their acts,
by virtue of their behavior,
by virtue of their work like you will.
You want to treat people the way they
deserve to be treated, and we all want to
sort of elevate through this existence.
So this idea that there's these teams,
the problem is you get,
you get pushed back from one side and
then you just join the other team. Well,
it's making, it's it, it is creating
blow back. But it, most people,
I don't think even joined another
team, they just withdraw, right?
Not everybody's temperamentally suited
to be in this. It's, it's combat.
Right? And I believe me, I did not,
I didn't consciously think, oh,
I'm going to confront these people
and be a, you know, a lawyer.
I thought naively I'm going to confront
them and then maybe I'm a little bit
wrong that they're a
little bit wrong and we'll,
we'll we'll meet in the middle meat
in the middle or, or who knows?
That didn't happen so that's why I
just don't like bullies and we are,
there's just the,
the gender studies is the result of sign
of a massive endless bullying campaign
by those who will not.
They just except dissident voices.
Yeah.
It's very strange.
It's a very strange predicament because
I don't see a clear exit strategy.
I look at this confusion and one of the
things I also started doing after being
called a men's rights
advocate as to find out what,
what are these fucking
crazy bastards into years,
men's rights and well then they've
got some goddamn good points too.
Unfortunately.
You know,
you go to men's rights advocacy websites
and you see these horrible stories of
these guys getting destroyed in divorce
court and losing everything they have
being preyed upon by unscrupulous women
that go after them and marry them and
take all their money and they have no
recourse and that there were set up.
But women set up some sort of uh,
got some restrain restraining
order against them by a judge.
And that that sets up the idea that there
was some sort of an abuser and without
any physical proof they can
be accused of these things.
And then when they go to court,
this all comes to light.
And then I've seen some crazy shit that
I've read online about child custody
battles where the men were accused of
sexually molesting their children by the
woman where there was
no evidence whatsoever.
And the women coached the kids in
the saying these things, horrific,
horrific stuff on both sides.
And then these men,
they all lump into these
men's rights groups,
these guys that had
been destroyed by women.
And then just decide that
women are assholes, decide
that women are, are, you know,
the enemy.
Right.
And that they just want to go to South
America and get prostitutes. You know,
I mean,
I've,
I've literally read articles where
these guys are talking about like,
this is how you do it. You go to South
America and you find a girl, you know,
that she's willing to have sex with you
for money their way hotter than American
woman. I'm like, what the
fuck is going on? Right.
Well, you know, they need
to know a couple of things.
One is that believe it or not, most
women are still nice and they love men.
And I want to say most women, it's a good
percentage, a good percentage, right?
And 60%. I don't know a
percentage, but, um, uh,
let me put it this way.
It's unusual to be that carried
away with gender politics. Yeah.
There may be more today because it's
getting more currency and it's become sort
of fashionable.
So to be snarky and an unpleasant,
um, but it's still, it doesn't,
you have to be temporary.
You have to be a little neurotic,
I think to be that vulnerable
to these hate ideologies.
So it's not the average young woman that
would be vulnerable to these ideologies,
but a lot are,
you should have to stay away from them.
But there are many sweet women out there
who will not behave that way and her
fair minded.
The other thing is that I don't
call myself a men's rights activist.
I'm not, I'm not advocating for
men. I'm advocating for truth.
It just happens that most of
the misinformation, not all
of it, but most of it is,
uh, now, uh, targeted against men.
So I do this weekly video series that,
you know,
I just tried to correct a myth each week.
And most of them are myths that are,
they're feminist myths,
um, about how bad men are.
And they're almost always wrong. And
I correct them. So people say, well,
you're a men's rights activist. No,
I'm not. I'm a human rights activist.
I'm a truth activists.
A common sense activist.
And if you want to call me a
men's rights activists, fine,
but that's not actually what I'm doing.
Well,
I have friend Kara,
Santa Maria who's a brilliant
scientist and neurosurgeon,
or she was a neuroscientist rather, and
just a, not a surgeon operating on brains,
but she called, she said you're
a feminist. And I'm like,
I'm definitely not a feminist. I'm not.
I'm, I'm a, I'm a humanist and that's a,
it's a, it's a term that people
like to use, but I'm an Aye. Aye.
I like people. I like smart
people. Whether they're
men or women, I don't know.
Me Too.
I don't,
I don't want there to be only men
in power are only women in power.
I think that's stupid.
I think I like Chinese people.
I like people from Vietnam. I like
people from everywhere. I just,
I like people that are interesting
and I just want you to be,
I want people to actually
be judged or to be, uh,
to be considered based on their merits.
Not based like instantly
judged or demonized because
they happen to have a penis
are instantly demeaned
because they haven't have a
vagina. I think it's stupid.
It's stupid. It's identity politics
and it's, it's going nowhere, right?
Except all it does is divide
people and make people bitter. Yes.
And it has to stop. Now you say,
well, how's it going to stop? Um,
I'm a mom. Well, I'm trying, but
I'm also optimistic that there,
there has to be a limit to irrationality
and eventually it will fall.
I just wish it would be
sooner rather than later.
Well, I think what we're
dealing with today, um,
with our new access to information that
we've enjoyed over the last decade or so,
I think w two decades,
but really it's sort of taking hold with
social media where people don't just
have access to information, but they
also have a voice. Um, you're, you're,
you're finding echo chambers like we
discussed earlier, we get these groups,
these radical groups on both sides
is the red pill, men's rights debate,
debate people and the people that are
on the side of women's rights and then
these male feminists and there's
a thing called atheism plus,
which is fucking hilarious.
He can't figure out atheism.
Plus they can't figure it out.
Is it like it's a religion?
It's basically a religion.
It's atheism.
It's no note wall k there's no they're,
they're not,
they don't consider deities,
but they want a group of core
ethical and moral values.
So I think if you wanted to boil it down,
a lot of people would be
atheism plus inclined.
The idea being that you are want to be a
good person and you don't want to be a,
you don't want a sexually
discriminate or racially discriminate.
And you a also don't
happen to believe in a,
a magic person that lives in the clouds.
Like that seems fairly reasonable until
you listen to these fuckers talk and
they give the most pedantic
boring fucking lectures.
All my God,
I sat down,
I smoked a joint and I watched this
one guy's lecture and I'm like,
this is like the longest,
you know how they have those videos they
do on dating sites where people, hi,
I'm Mike, I like to play tennis.
Like this is like his version of it.
Just saying, you know
how boring, you know,
a sexual discrimination was
a racial discrimination was,
it's basically like just open. It was
Duh. That's what it was. It was like, Duh,
you shouldn't murder people.
Duh. You shouldn't steal,
Duh. Like what you're taught.
What the fuck are you talking to?
Your, you're preaching to the choir,
I mean are had a fucking atheism
plus conference and you're, you're,
you're preaching about the idea
that you shouldn't sexually racially
discriminate and that's
a good thing. Dot. Yes.
It's fucking boring.
What he's saying is boring.
There's no original unique points.
It's just reinforcing the idea,
which is better than a hate rally.
It's better than going to see a bunch
of skinheads talk about the white man
needs to get back to power.
It's definitely better than that,
but it's still a lot of de and
what's the point of that? Really?
Days get together. They have these
conferences, they have conferences.
The point is these are social gatherings
where they all reinforce their ideas.
They get together, they drank and then
they rape each other. That's what happens.
They drink and then they have sex and
they're both raping. That's what happens.
It told a lot of what these things are.
Social Hookups,
these people get together and
it becomes a main focus of them.
They also make a certain amount of money
because they charge money for people to
come to these gatherings.
So they come to these gatherings or rent
out like a conference hall somewhere
and they come and they hand out pamphlets
and they sell t shirts and then they
have these little parties and these
little events and then they, you know,
you have to pay money to get a badge and
you go to this fucking thing and these
people talk and then they drink.
It's hilarious. Nothing gets done.
I mean literally,
absolutely nothing gets done.
But what they're doing is they're
sort of reinforcing their ideas. No,
not negative ideas. They're,
they're fairly positive
ideas. It's like it's not bad.
The saw horrible. They're not
bad people. They're good people.
When the guy was standing there on that,
the Ds and he was explaining all his
core values and I'm like, oh good.
I believe I agree with you on everything,
but fuck man, you can't just say that.
I think you should eat healthy food.
I think you should get eight
hours sleep at sleep at night.
I think if you are driving in your car
and an old ladies on the road do not run
her over. Yes. Don't run the old lady
over. You know what the fuck man,
don't shoot puppies. You know, don't
fucking drown kittens. Ha. A lot of,
there's a lot of that in I think
in the academy where they will,
it will be just bromides and pointless
truisms then mixed in with harsher
thanks. So they'll say, and
we all agree you should,
you should be respectful of other people
and not demean them with costumes and
fine, I don't want to see
someone in black face or, or,
or humiliating someone with a costume,
but then they will. So that sounds fine.
And we all agree.
But then they will go after a museum
because they have an exhibit of, of,
you know, uh, chemo nose and say,
that's cultural appropriation.
This is the new thing I saw about
appropriating costumes. So we can't, well,
cultural appropriation, that is what
most of the history of culture is.
What was a Komono night at a museum
raffle thing they were doing at the Museum
of fine arts.
They were bringing an exquisite Kimonos,
public was learning to appreciate
them and you could try one on,
which I certainly would have wanted to
do and have a picture because they're so
lovely. And I'm sure the
Japanese love this. Most people,
if other cultures are interested in yours,
art forms, you're, you're, you're proud,
right? Well, people with too much time
on their hands staged and you know,
an angry intervention. This was a
micro aggression or a macro aggression.
And,
uh,
and I think the museum had to apologize
and they're not going to do it anymore.
It's so stupid.
It's like if you go to a Hawaiian hotel,
lot of times they'll give you one of
those grass skirts. They're pretty cool.
They don't get mad.
Oh, maybe we can't wear leis anymore.
When you were, when you get, well,
they give us the deer. They put them on.
Let's see. Welcome. If you go to, um,
over the border around in
California to Tijuana there,
everyone's selling sombreros and it's,
they're going to drive
them out of business.
Well, they'll go cultural
misappropriation. Oh, this is horrible.
This is the patriarchy.
Well, black lives matter,
Brown lives, Brown lives matter, fuck,
they'll have thing is ridiculous.
But it's, I think a lot of it is
what we're saying is that when,
when we have social media and when you
see these people that are saying all
these things on social media that are,
you know,
a lot of people agree with a lot of
really relevant points when it comes to,
uh, racism or sexism or all these
things. Why are they these things?
Are they saying these things because these
things are actually important to them?
Or are they saying these things because
they know people are going to read them
and they're going to like them because
of what they said. It's almost like,
it's almost like the whole world is
becoming slowly but surely a giant reality
show.
Because if you watch reality television,
when those people behave on those
shows and those cameras are on them,
they're very aware of those cameras
are on them. So they say crazy shit.
They do crazy things. Like, um,
I have a friend who has a friend
who is one of those housewives,
the real housewives. Right? And it's
a sad story. The real story. Sad.
She's just trying to get attention and
she wants to write books and tried to
make money and she's a
single mom look like there's,
there's a lot of sadness behind it, the
reality, but when you see her on the show,
you see this big boisterous, you see a
lot of acting out, a lot of craziness,
and you would go, oh, well that girl is
a this, but if you, in reality she's not,
she's not a bad person,
but she's being this bad person because
she knows it's going to get a reaction.
It's not a good reaction.
It's not very well calculated one,
but I think that's a lot of what you
get from the so called social justice
warriors on Twitter.
He's Hashtag activist where you're getting
from a lot of people is they're in a
fucking giant reality show.
They're in a giant reality show and
their method of communication is through
Twitter or through Facebook
posts or through youtube
videos or whatever the fuck
it is, but there were there,
when they're saying these things,
they're not just communicating,
they're communicating to try to get likes.
They want to get up votes. They want
to, they want people to favorite,
they're twins, they're twins, and
they're, it's calculated, it's fake.
There's a lot of bullshit to it and I
think you get a version of that in college
campuses because to become like a really
radical advocate and a radical activist
and really become a part of this sorta
even, I'm going to have a hunger strike.
Go for a Johnny there,
strike 5 cents on the dollar.
I'm going to starve myself.
Like, fuck yeah, you know, let's,
let's fight back against white people.
Whatever you're doing, you know,
this is the thing. When they
say when they're only making
75 cents on the dollar,
I just want to politely raised my hand
and say, that's not quite accurate.
It's accurate in the
sense there is a wage gap,
but it can be explained innocently.
Women major in different
topics in college, they were,
they work fewer hours per week and the
men take the more dangerous jobs with
impossible hours. It's
simply a difference. When
you do all those adjustments,
the wage gap narrows to the point
of vanishing. So they are in,
they're enraged their virtue signaling
one another. True. That's true.
So I thought though,
in specific occupations that women
would make less money than men.
Let's look at the occupations.
For example,
you will see doctors in male
doctors make considerably more.
But then you look at the, at the uh, sub
specialties,
men tend to go at far more men go into
the higher paying specialties like
cardiology, uh, anesthesiology,
the lower paying fields are
pediatrics and family medicine.
Women are more likely to work part time.
They are more likely to take a few years
out of the workplace or cut back way
back.
These are differences that have to be
calculated in it have to be factored into
this calculation.
And the gender activists for years have,
have just put out this statistic.
Women are being cheated out of almost a
quarter of their salary. Uh, by you know,
the,
this,
this system rigged against them when in
fact if there are innocent explanations,
he look at what men and women
major in in college. It's amazing.
After all these years of feminism,
you will not make very much money.
If you want to go into early childhood
education, you will have a rewarding job.
If you love that and you know,
many people do love it and
do very well personally,
but you will not make
money if you want to close.
I lectured at overland college and they
were hissing and booing and carrying out
crazy on you. They went crazy. Yes,
they had a safe room and I triggered them
and I know in the first two rows there
were young women with duct tape on their
mouth, duct tape, red duct tape. It was,
I didn't know what to say.
Duct tape their mouth and they stayed
there for the whole lecture. I mean,
how could you recovery two rows?
It's of hot.
Why did they do that?
I still don't know.
I guess I could only think of there was a,
a novel and I don't know what it was.
I still don't know. I didn't ask him,
ask. I never saw them. I mean they
were, oh, then people rushed out.
I triggered people and they went
to the safe room. I triggered,
triggered about 30 people and a dog.
There was a therapy dog
and they went to this safer, I feel
bad about the dog. I do. But uh,
this was at Oberlin college and they were,
and what was interesting is
they had their safe room,
but the college administration
was looking at their Facebook,
Facebook postings in their antics
and got worried about my safety.
I had to have armed guards. I had two
armed police women squirting me around.
How you police women though?
Yeah, we went with police.
When and why did they go and please
one Berlin, they had to be better,
be perfectly correctly.
If you get more correct than Oberlin
College, I mean, you will vaporize.
And I know, I dunno. What is the next
step? I'm just, I can't think. Yeah.
And I speak now. I grew up in
California, I was there for, what was,
my sister's generation is a little older.
That was the free speech movement in
Berkeley. It was all about liberation.
Leave us alone. We do not want
authority figures or deans or you know,
assistant librarians on committees
making rules. We did not want it.
We were belt and there was this period
when I was in college where we were just
free. We had, I don't think
I ever met a dean, you know,
except it was something academic, but
it's certainly not in my personal life.
And we've, we drove out the dorm
advisors. There was no dorm advisor.
We were there. Well maybe they were then.
We never saw them. They had no power.
And now they want them to there. And
again, it's this going back. But anyway,
I just wanted to finish about Oakland.
I told the overland students,
they were saying, but women are
being cheated out of their salary.
And I explained and I said,
right now,
today you can take a step to
closing the wage gap. No, no.
Don't major in,
you know,
feminist dance therapy major
in electrical engineering.
And then so more minutes dance therapy
is so necessary for our culture.
Well they think it's an injustice.
You should be,
why can't I be in dance
therapist and you know,
why shouldn't I be rewarded
for that? And we do, you know,
people aren't paid for what
their jobs are worth. Well, um,
that's probably true.
And I said, I mean I,
I agreed with them that I don't
feel I am paid as a philosophy phd.
We are not well paid compared to other,
you know,
people with PhDs in computer science
or electrical engineering or petroleum
engineering. There's with
the money is, and I said,
I'm considered unfair is a philosopher
because we should be valued. But you know,
you realize there is
something called the market.
There are forces that
determine what people will pay
important for this as well.
There's in socialism, the feminist
stance therapist would get there.
Do they get paid as much as the electrical
engineer? I'd like what'd you get?
Oh,
well how much do you think it's worth
for feminist dance therapy does that real
thing? It might've been,
well, I'm being fanciful,
but there are crazy majors and you know,
and they waste their time.
And I,
I was one speaking at Bryn Mawr while I
was actually at Haverford and the Bryn
Mawr girls came, is it still a women's
college? And they, first of all,
they were knitting the
whole time I was talking,
they were knitting and I didn't
know what that meant. If it was a,
and they turned to be a number
of wiccans in the audience.
They weren't on my side. They weren't
against me. They seemed it. Yeah.
They weren't mad at me. So I didn't want
any headaches. Any name spells Catholic.
The real witches.
Wiccan.
Yeah. I don't think they're
witches. I think they are.
I think Wiccan is like a,
it's almost like a pagan worshiping
the earth sort of a thing.
Well, they defend witches.
They do. Yeah. Because I, I,
I read it.
Something about the witch hunt
on the campus and a Wiccan came,
was angry about it.
Here's a Wiccan as a member of the pagan
revivalist religion known as Wicca can
be a male or female
practitioner or lay follower,
either solitary or members of a coven.
Um hmm. Hmm. No with
no word, which no long.
I'm sure there's more followers
of neo pagan religion.
Wiccans are a polytheistic
nature worshipers.
They worship a moon goddess and a
Horn, God, the observe eight Sabbaths,
Blah Blah Blah. They are based
off seasonal changes in harvest,
which are also represent changes in their
God and goddess wiccans are not evil
and generally did not do bad badge.
So I guess it's saying that
they implying they do do magic.
They follow rule of three,
the belief that whatever you do comes
back to you three times as bad or good
depending on what it was you
did in some respects, Wiki,
whatever. Well, they sound fine. These
young women were fine I guess at the at,
but um, one of them, not one of them,
but a young woman in the audience said,
are you telling me I'm a gender
studies major at Bryn Mawr?
You telling me I've wasted four
years and I didn't know what to say,
but then I just said yes. Oh, and it was
like, and the audience would have laughed,
but I'm just telling anyone who's even
thinking of wasting four years studying
gender theory,
which has not,
which has no basis in reality
or in in serious scholarship.
I'm sure there's some exceptions,
but those exceptions don't come close
to the rule, which is that it's,
it's a waste of time.
I would have told young lady that anything
that you do where you're thinking
is not a waste of time. Right?
But if you're trying
to make a lot of money,
gender studies is not
necessarily where it's at.
Right? Well, this is the thing. If you ask
men and women, what do you want you and,
and we have great data on this
from vocational counselors.
You remember in junior high
they were vocation counselors.
It would tell you what you should be
based on your abilities and interests.
We've been giving these tests for years
in men and women answered somewhat
differently.
And women care more about fulfillment.
They care about more about jobs.
Where they can be.
Women are very attracted to jobs that
involve caring and nurturing and men
considerably less. So you do find
far more men in sort of people.
Free zones are jobs where they, oh they
asked people, would you rather spend,
you know a week taking a part of machine
and putting it back together or would
you rather spend a week sitting with
a group of people talking about their
problems and far more men say they'd
want to be with the machine and far more
women say talk about the problem.
So you have to factor those in.
Now it just turns out that overall if you
are working with say computers and you
are, you're an engineer, you're at
that high level with the education,
you get paid well. People
need those skills. If you
have the skills of a nurturer,
you do need the education in
the background. But a lot,
there are a lot of people that
want to do them and there aren't.
There just isn't. Where is the money?
Who's going to pay you that kind of money?
So they do not earn as much and
they resent that. But as you say,
you would tell the young woman,
you, I would tell them, you know,
you're not gonna make as much,
but she probably would say, but,
but it interests me. I mean, I, I,
someone could have told me don't major
in major in metallurgy or petroleum
engineering. I wouldn't even want
to see the textbook for that.
I loved my philosophy books and if
they told me you won't hurt as much,
but it didn't, if it does matter to
you, then change your major if you,
if you're going into one of these fields.
Well,
I think what you're saying,
it highlights a real problem that human
beings have and choosing an occupation
and choosing what path they
want to go to in their life.
And I think oftentimes people,
they,
they go the way they think is going to
earn them the most money instead of going
the way that's gonna make them fulfilled
and happy. And you, you, you're gonna,
there's a lot of things that I could do
that I should maybe have done when I was
younger, if I wanted to
make money, just make money.
And there's a lot of people my age that
are way more successful than me and make
way more money than me. I don't know
if they're happier than me though.
And I think what I figured out how to do
somewhere along the line through trial
and error is do things I actually enjoy.
And somehow or another that's lost
in a lot of people and people say,
oh well you go look you and you
can do that and this and that.
It's not available to everybody,
man. I don't know that that's true.
I don't know that that's true.
And I don't know that this is the only
thing that what I wound up doing is the
only thing that I actually love. I
love a lot of things. I love writing,
I love art.
I love,
there's a lot of things that I loved
that I probably could have been equally
happy pursuing. I don't necessarily
think that when you look at life,
you should look at it in terms of what
is the best way to make the most amount
of money. So when we're talking
about things like that, the wage gap,
what about the happiness gap? Because men
are much more likely to commit suicide.
That's one thing. Men, uh,
I think a lot of men suffer
from depression as I'm
sure a lot of women do as
well.
But I don't necessarily think we
should look at it in terms of what is,
what's going to earn you the most money.
And is that what you're
preparing for in school?
Every time someone uses
that wage gap statistic,
that's how they're judging society and
they're saying women are cheated. No,
what you want to know is what they should
ask is how much do you like your job,
how fulfilled you are, and then look
at the sex difference and see what,
what it turns out,
maybe there is a happiness gap.
There certainly is a fatality cap,
which is that men are vastly more likely
to die on the job because men occupy
the gritty, dangerous jobs, you know,
working as loggers and roofers and it,
you know, on uh, out, outside and
in, in uh, you know, on uh, you know,
if fishing and fisheries and things,
the dirty gritty jobs are done by men.
It's like there's an invisible
army of men doing all of this work.
There's a big construction
site near where I live in,
in Washington DC and they
are building a big complex.
I have seen dozens of men out there ever,
not a single woman every day for a year.
It could be cold, it can be really hot.
They get there early, they stay. It's
just hard. BRAC backbreaking work.
You never hear about
that, about the, you know,
the unpleasantness gap or the or the
danger gap and all that has to be factored
in when it is. What you find is that
in the United States for the most part,
people are able to doing what they want.
Well,
are there jobs though that are closed
off to women that are very difficult for
women to enter into? I'm sure that
there are the old boy network,
the glass ceiling and
those are the the drops.
But here's the thing about
that. People say, well, uh,
there aren't as many female physicists.
If you look in the sciences,
women are flourishing in fields like
biology that we've all been taken over a
veterinary medicine.
These used to be male dominated,
but women once women,
once the gates were open and we
could sort of do what we wanted,
there weren't these arbitrary barriers.
Women just moved in and into areas
that had been once just more or less
restricted to males.
They did not do that with engineering.
They didn't do it with computer science.
And what I want,
I need to know as well are the
computer scientists and the engineers,
are they really sexist in the way
that like lawyers that you wouldn't,
men used to be all the lawyers.
Lawyers aren't known to be particularly
sensitive and where they so much more
receptive to women because women are
approaching parody with men now and in law
school for sure.
And so you have to look at the where men
and women are in our society and I as a
free society and an an educated society.
I credit it to personal aspiration
and I think in the road to happiness,
men and women take
somewhat different paths.
College seems like such a mad dash to a
mad dash to figure out your path is four
years and then graduate school.
But the but the four years
of trying to figure it out,
like figure out what your
occupation is going to be,
where you're going to go and what you're
gonna do and then you look at all these,
suppose at barriers and boundaries that
are in front of you that are going to
prevent you from doing what you want
to do or getting the way of you being
justly rewarded for
what you're going to do.
That's why I get mad at some of my family
has colleagues for constantly telling
Young Women, oh, tech tech
is rigged against you.
No it's not the guys in
tech for the most part.
There are exceptions but for the most
part are welcoming and many of them have,
you know,
want to have more women because there
it looks bad and not to have them.
So they're doing what they can and,
but we're telling young women,
oh you're not welcoming the tech.
Well there was a time women
weren't welcome in law or
medicine or philosophy and
things changed and it,
and,
and I suspect by now that the reason you
don't find high percentage of women in
tech is because women just aren't as
interested in tech as they are and other
things.
Well and be careful what you wish for
because I have a friend who's an executive
at Google and she makes a shit ton of
money, but she works ungodly hours.
I mean it is essentially her life.
She is glued to her phone when she's
not at work. When she's at work,
she's there all day long, 14, 15
plus hours a day. It's, it's brutal.
It's backbreaking. It becomes, it's
not, it's not a career. It's your life.
You're giving up your,
what you have afterwards.
I don't care if you make $5 million
a year, whatever the fuck you make,
your life is nonexistent. I mean, what
are you gonna do? You gonna fill it up.
I've got to buy a new Tesla.
You're gonna feel great staring at your
TV for the two hours that you're awake
before you pass out and
you have to go to work
again. You never home. I'm
sure that for those who do it
and get, you know, they're,
they're probably having a, yeah, a
great ride. Here's what we do know,
and this has been shown over
and over again by researchers,
including a research at the Pew
Research Center, men and women.
Um, if you ask as a pew has
done, you ask mothers, like,
what is your ideal life? Mothers of
young children, a large majority of,
well actually with Ltl,
first start with women because this was,
I'm a researcher at the
London School of Economics.
You'd studied women in Western Europe.
What do women want?
She found out about 20% want to be full
time careers. Like your friend at Google,
they are out there, they want the
money, they want the power, they want,
they want it all. 20% about 20%
want to be stay at home mothers.
They want to have a bunch of kids stay
home, be a house, what you know they,
and they will not work unless
they're for 60% are she calls.
So they're sort of in the middle.
They want to work part time.
When they have little kids
they want to go in and out.
So I think that right now we have a
women's movement that works very hard for
that 20% for their life,
you know,
preferences and the majority of women
are left out and majority of women don't
want that. What your friend has,
that's good, but a lot of women won't,
will not want that.
And there is just about as many women
that would want the quite the opposite.
So what I want is a feminism that
accommodates preference and what do,
what do people want Brian?
And if I found out that all these women
wanted to work full time and the men
wanted to stay home with the kids,
fine.
But what you find is that
that works for a few people,
but it's not something most people seem
to watch and it's regardless of gender
really.
I mean,
don't we want that across the board?
I mean there's a wide variety
of human beings on this.
Yes. For men too. I, yeah, I
call myself a feminist, but I do,
it used to mean that you believed
in equality of the sexes. Right.
And I'm so I try to hang onto the,
it's classical meaning,
but now it's come to mean,
as I said, female chauvinism.
You only care about women.
And I'm not that.
I do not want it.
That kind of feminine. One of the things
that I have found that's hilarious,
it keeps getting repeated over and over
again in feminist blogs and websites,
is they want to dress men's issues
until all women's issues are that they
believe that feminism
addresses everything.
There's no need for no need for men's
rights advocacy because feminism addresses
everything.
And once a women are equal and
treated equally and supported equally,
and you,
you won't have any problems with men.
I don't understand the
rational basis for that.
We can't do some good and in many,
many places at once. Of course. Yeah.
Well,
you can't even acknowledge that there's
issues because until the women's issues,
which are overwhelming,
all right. Until their address, if every
person out there that thinks that way,
that is a sign that you are fanatical,
certainly are. But it's also a bit of
trolling because it's, uh, you're, you're,
you're trolling support
from the people that read it and go,
yeah.
And you're also trolling
for an overreaction from
the men, which we'll go see,
these men are assholes and
they hate women. You know,
I read this one woman's blog
and she was, uh, she was,
she was saved up all of her mean
tweets that she got from it.
He's anonymous retards out
there. And uh, she said, uh, the,
what are these men have in common?
These are all men who hate women. No,
these are all men who tweeted you and
you responded to them like they're
trolling you. They're saying mean
shit. You're a public figure.
You write a public blog, you put
your, your public Twitter out there.
So every day you're going
to, if you have a net, okay,
you throw that net in the ocean every
get day gonna catch a certain amount of
different species. Okay,
you're going to catch tuna,
catch a Marlin or two and you're
going to catch a few retards.
You're going to catch some really dumb
people and those really dumb people are
going to tweet you and you're going to
copy those down every day and accumulate
them. Well, how many really smart people
read what you had to say, disagreed,
agreed, whatever, and didn't tweet
you. You know, like what, what you're,
what you're getting is,
is it's a bias sampling.
And by saving that bias
sampling and putting up there,
it's not proof that you're being
somehow or another you being oppressed.
It's proof that you're, you're crazy
and you're, you're paying attention.
These dummies, you're, you're
tapping into a well of human beings.
If you have something that
reaches a million people,
if you have a blog or a youtube video
and you read the comments on them,
you're reaching a phenomenal amount of
human beings and you're always going to
have a certain percentage of human beings
who are unbalanced or they're fucked
up in the head in some way or the
really dumb and those people there,
they're going to be more
likely to comment you. Right?
So if you have a a million people
that read a 1% is a lot of people,
that's a lot. Yeah. You
know, if you have a hundred,
one person out of a hundred is going
to be done. You have a thousand,
you get to 100,000 you get to a million.
That's a giant number of people that
you're probably catching in your net that
are really stupid. And that's,
it's a part of this life we live,
it's a part of this new
era of social media,
this new era of this open access
to everyone and everything.
And I think it's beautiful
and a lot of ways,
I think it's exposing all the
holes and flaws and our culture.
It's exposing how there's,
there's marginalize and unrepresented
people that are just sort of,
they feel disenfranchised,
they feel left out and they feel like
the only way they can get attention is to
scream or yell or to say misogynists
things are hateful things and they're just
trying to get attention
the end of the day.
That's a lot of what they're trying to do.
They're trying to end it.
But I'll also say the things that I
write about because I do think, uh,
I am just speaking common
sense about gender.
And then I have a lot of followers on
Twitter and people that I encounter who
are from the factual feminist who are just
happy. They were able to find someone.
And it's of absurd that you can
can't find a professor. I mean, I left
the university to go to a think tank.
I could still be there teaching,
but it was lonely.
I didn't really have that many colleagues
who were agreed with me and I had some
that were very annoyed with me.
So it wasn't a comfortable place.
So there's for a dissident feminist
or just a, I think as I said,
the voice of moderation,
they will not hear that if they're on
campus and now you don't hear it in the
media.
So social media is a place where you
can tell the truth and people can be
exposed to ideas that have been edited
out of the curriculum where you're an
author and you've written books and
you've written papers and people have read
those, but they're not going
to have the near the immediacy.
That's something like a youtube video has.
So what's,
what's fantastic about than
anything like these videos,
they've had over 4 million views,
I think if you add them all up and
some more than others. But, uh,
we have a good one coming out tonight.
On the myth of male power.
I think you might like it. So men
are in power. Well, this whole thing,
men are supposed to, uh, well it's
not, it's not the myth of male power.
It's about male privilege. They
tell man, check your privilege.
And so I look at men's,
how privileged are men in our society now?
In some ways they are just to be a
man does afford you certain benefits,
but so does being a woman like big time,
we're better educated. We live longer,
we're farming better educated.
So, oh, majority of degrees.
Go to women.
Women now earn 57% of bachelors
approaching 60% of master's and uh,
52% of PhDs.
Wow.
It was used to be the reverse that you
had more men getting the degrees and
women where the have nots.
When was the shift? Well,
it started to shift actually
in the eighties in the
nineties you know, it's just,
it was an upward trajectory for women.
And here's where it really
counts among working class kids.
The girls are better
educated than the boys are.
If you look at different ethnic
groups, African Americans, Latinos,
working class, white kids,
um, their sister, the boy,
the girls are doing better,
the boys are in big trouble educationally
and it's creeping into the middle
class. The girls are way ahead.
They're winning the prizes.
There's a gap in education and
boys are on the wrong side.
Do you attribute that to the women's
rights movement and the, the,
the gains that were made in awareness?
We like during the 70s and the 80s,
I attributed to a number of things.
First of all,
girls have always liked school better
and teachers that feel like, like girls,
girls are better behaved on average.
So it was always a trick to
interest a boy keep his attention.
Um, but teachers use to make a
big effort. They don't anymore.
If they go to a school of education,
they may be reading these fashionable
texts about how women are,
the silenced underprivileged.
And so they think that they have to,
you know, uh, focus on
the girls and the boys,
that the typical behavior of little
boys has been redefined as pathology.
So you'll find little boys being
suspended for playing cops and robbers or
wanting to play, uh, a raucous
game in the playground,
dodge ball or tag.
Now girls like to play to
a outdoors and have recess,
but typically they will do a little
bit of that. They will also do that.
A lot of theatrical imaginative games,
playing house,
playing school or sharing confidences
with your best friend. You know,
girls do that.
Boys hardly ever do that.
They want to go out there and this rough
housing or it's called rough and tumble
play schools who are making rules
against it. They don't understand that.
It's very different from aggression
when boys are being mean and aggressive,
violent, let's say. Uh, there's, there are
tears, there's anger, there's, you know,
it's, it's not a happy site when
boys are rough and tumbling,
there's joy there. Forging
bonds, they're learning limits.
It's critical part of their socialization.
And we are a society that has lost touch
with that and we are defining it as
pathology.
And it happens as early as preschool.
And parents should know that when
your little boy gets to, you know,
the kindergarten class,
it is geared towards the girls.
What do you think is the cause of
this lack of understanding between the
difference between the way
boys play and girls play?
Because I have all daughters,
but I have a buddy that has all sons and
when I'm around his house and I see his
kids, it's fucking houses. Chaos is cal.
Everything's broken. Broken. Yeah. And,
and he's not an aggressive guy at all.
He's a,
he's a professor actually at Stanford
and he's like super mellow and like he's,
he doesn't, he barely exercises. He
rides his bike. He's not aggressive.
It doesn't watch any sports. And these
kids are fucking maniacs right there.
Run around.
They'd throw jumping sidekicks against
the couch and they're just fucking crazy.
And that's how the my, my little girls
come over his house and they're like,
Jesus Christ. Like, what is
going on with these apes?
Well, I have two sons and for years,
anybody who would come, the main thing,
as long as it was get a football
and go outside and throw it around,
they want to know. I just don't recall
wanting to do that at someone's house.
I mean, we might do that, but we'd
probably go into her room and you know,
be talking and listening to
music or something. But these,
and the other thing I learned
too about boys with video games,
my parents were very disapproving
teachers don't like them,
but I always remember I'd go and see my
son downstairs at playing these games.
And uh,
I was writing my book,
the war against boys and people
were worried about the games.
And when I looked at the
boys and I didn't see it,
and some of the games were wild and
violent and I didn't like what I saw,
but they were cheering each other on.
They were teasing each other
the way boys do. I mean,
men show their love by insults and razzing
it, you know, it was, it was comradery.
It was, it was just bonding.
It was a happy, if you know,
group engagement and it would have been
terrible to say you stop playing these
games and this is bad. It wasn't bad
behavior. But people don't understand it.
They hear putting each other down and
you have to listen because when men put
each other down, including men and boys,
it's often the way they show friendship.
You tall man, I'm a comedian.
That's all we ever tell you do.
If I ever based my own self esteem and
how my friends have talked to me, right,
I'd be fucked. No, my two sons, all they
do, they get together. It's immediately,
but it does, it does make Ben Funny Cause
they learn it starting in, you know,
first grade because there's this
the way boys are with each other,
but we have psychologists and say,
oh no,
it's a culture of cruelty
and they think it's bullying.
You've got to know the difference
between affectionate, you know,
kind of joshing and teasing
and violent bullying.
It's something, and we, again,
we're not making good distinction.
And I think there's also,
there's something to be gained from that
type of insulting behavior with boys
and even teasing each other back and
forth as long as it's good natured.
Because even though it does kind of sting
when someone mocks you and makes fun
of you, it also motivates you to do better
at whatever they were mocking you out.
And it strengthens you. And men
are a little more stoical. Andy, I,
I read this great study by
the psychologists. They,
they, we always hear, well,
men have to talk more about
their feelings. Men have to be,
and they interviewed hundreds of kids,
adolescents,
and they asked the boys and the girls,
how does it feel to talk
about your problems?
And for most of the girls that made
them feel better just talking about the
problems, the boys said it didn't make
him feel better. And they, and they said,
and it was weird, and, and
they, and, and I thought, oh,
the psychologists are going to say,
the boys have to learn to do it.
But they didn't. What they said was,
hmm, maybe it's adaptive for young men,
you know,
and,
and because they don't ruminate so much
and there is a lot of depression in
adolescent girls, there may be to
interiorize they, they're ruminating,
they're going over and over.
And these psychologists said that they
thought it was probably, maybe the girls,
we should see what looked like
the boys are doing that, you know,
it's not necessarily the boys
have to be like the girls.
And then they said something very
interesting. If a boy does have a problem,
he's got to talk about it. Don't say, oh
well let's sit down and talks. We are,
you know, tell me your feelings.
He is going to re, you know, Bolt.
You have to say, you have to engage
his problem solver, you know,
and you have to say,
we've got to do this.
We got to conquer it and
turn it into a a challenge.
And then when I read that I thought,
my God,
there's probably a whole field of
male psychology that's been ignored.
It's almost as if modern psychology and
clinical counseling has been based on
women and their needs. And what
works for them. But what about what,
what works for guys? Fortunately the
Australians are actually working on this.
The Australians, they're working on male
psychology and veil, you know, counseling.
Well, school is a very strange
place for everybody, right?
I mean you're, you're forced to
sit in a class and listen to uh,
a course and the teacher's teaching you
the facts and Statistics and a might be
anything you're even remotely
interested in.
And we were seven years old or eight
years old and you're a little kid and you,
you want to play, you're filled with
energy, you want to bounce off the wall.
It's strange to have to sit in some
class and listen to someone talk to you
about arithmetic or listen to you talk,
talk about listening to someone,
talk to you about grammar,
reading. It's hard.
It's hard for kids to sit and pay
attention. And it's hard I think when,
if you are a boy and you have all this
extra energy and you are told there's
something wrong with you because of it.
I have my, uh, my old next door neighbor,
they moved out but they had
their kid on Ritalin and uh,
I was around this kid all the time.
He wasn't, he wasn't fucked up.
He just had a lot of energy and he was
kind of being ignored by both parents
worked all the time and you know,
he was bouncing off the walls and he was
just not paying attention in school and
acting out and wasn't, it wasn't very
disciplined like a lot of young boys are.
So they just medicated this kid,
oh,
this makes my heart and
it's so sad because a good
teacher who was in tune with
boys, we'll find a way to
capture his imagination.
Right now,
for example,
most of the reading assignments are
fiction and is one just wonderful guy who
goes around teaching how to engage boys.
He said,
it's almost as if teachers only
like kind of the confessional poet.
You ask a 12 year old boy
to be a confessional poet,
he's not going to do it.
And he'll act out and he'll,
you know, won't do this.
But I let them write what he wants.
And there was a,
what happens though is little boys,
five or six years old,
they'll be asked to write something and
they want to write about something like,
you know,
I don't know a monster destroying a
city or about their skateboard or their
video games. And the teachers don't
like it. They get mad, they get mad.
And fortunately there are some that are
beginning to notice because now people
are getting worried about what's
happening to boy's education.
Cause it has all sorts of
ramifications for the economy.
And you have to worry about having a
large cohort of boys disengaged from
education because they're not going to
have a future in an information economy.
We've got to solve the problem.
So there are teachers thinking about it.
But one thing they noticed is you take
a little boy and girls that are playing
and play is the basis for learning.
I mean that's how we learn is
as animals we learn from play.
But boys are disapproved up. So they
want to play superhero, which every,
not every but most four or five year
old boys, that's what they want.
And vanquish the bad guys. And there
are, there's a lot of, you know,
sound effects and what
seems to be violence.
It's actually something very different
going on in his imagination. But we are,
we are,
we are policing the imagination of little
boys and calling them pathological.
And I just never forgot the story.
I read about a little boy named Justin
in California and he was well behaved.
He loved sword fights and pirates.
The teacher called his parents.
She was very worried about Justin.
He'd written a story and illustrated
it with a scene with pirates having a,
a sword fight. And there were, there was
chop heads and all sorts of things. Wild.
And the parents came in and
said, yeah, what did he do?
They were shocked because he was
never in trouble. She said, well,
look at this drawing as if
Justin was a Prodo sociopath.
And his father said, yeah, well
he likes pirates, you know,
it makes me read them stories. And the
teacher was very worried about his values.
Will,
the father said,
I'm very worried about my son's fate in
a classroom with a teacher that has no
sympathy for his imagination.
What that father said about Justin.
That's,
that is pretty much describes
the predicament of a majority of,
of boys in our schools right now.
The teachers don't have sympathy.
They haven't been taught.
Now most teachers are just,
they'll adjust and they like boys,
they'll do their best.
But that is despite what they
learned in a school of education,
does this coincide with larger classrooms?
Cause if you have 40 kids in a class
and one of them was a rambunctious boy,
you want to silence that kid because he's
disrupting your educating the other 39
kids, some of it, it's everywhere.
It's in, it's in schools.
The majority of teachers,
it's a feminine profession.
And the classrooms had been
feminized. The readings, the um,
I mean there are books that are
irresistible to a typical little boy,
but we don't assign them.
The British got so worried about the
reading gap cause girls are way ahead in
reading. They now have a list of books
that, and teachers are aware of that uh,
books that a kid can't read a little
bit. I can't resist. We don't have that.
We would immediately have
dozens of feminist groups.
They would be hearings on Capitol Hill,
the books and one of the subjects,
well that does it. Just a few that I
remember. One is that a boy's like books,
a lot of little boys like nonfiction and
if you give them the Guinness Book of
Records, he could be lost for days. They
like things like that list of, you know,
arcane information. Give
him, give him a choice. And,
and yes, sometimes stories about
a monster devouring a city.
There are lots of books.
There's actually a website called guys
can read and they have books and the best
of books for little boys with girls.
He really, you know, delegate there.
There's so many books written for them.
They're going to find them.
Their teachers are going to assign them.
You can't assume that with your son.
I sympathize for teachers though and
a lot of ways because if they are,
especially a lot of teachers don't have
children and if they don't have children
of their own and they're teaching a group
of boys and there's 40 kids there and
one of them is a really rambunctious boy
who's a little maniac and he's running
around being crazy.
I could see how you would want this
little kid to calm down and be silenced.
I totally agree with you.
But what if it turns out that there
are just ways to do this and that.
What if you had a lot of assignments
where the kids have to stand up?
What if instead of in desks they have to
be sitting up? Boys, if you use humor,
boys will love you boys like jokes.
Teachers have to try to be funny
even if they're not that funny.
I read about this one male teacher,
he'd give back papers and you make
them into paper. Airplanes is,
I mean there are just things
that are amusing to kids.
My favorite example was a school
in uh, west, West Virginia.
The boys in that school were not reading.
They were the low of the West.
Virginia is the low. There are some of
the lowest scores in this school was bad,
this wonderful.
It was a female teacher.
She started an all boys class and she
had a 10 they called battle of the books.
They had to read these books
and then have a, some kind of a,
I think it was like a jeopardy
battle or some kind of game.
The boys loved it and they, they
wanted extra books to read over summer.
And she said it was the first time
in the history of West Virginia.
The boys asked for extra reading over the
summer and they came back and the, the,
like the sixth grade boy class did better
than the eighth grade coed class does.
This was working with,
or the ACL went in there
because there were uh,
gender activists in the Eselu that
said separating by gender as a kind of
apartheid, gender apartheid.
And they sued, they apartheid,
they call it gender apartheid or gender.
They compare it to discriminate.
It's crazy.
And they stopped this class.
There is no boys class with
battle of the books. Oh God.
So that's where we are.
There was a young boy that
was recently suspended.
It was a big national story because he,
uh,
had a fake bow and arrow.
He was using an imaginary bow and Arrow
and shooting at boys in his class.
And so they suspended him. I think he
was, it was very young. He's very young,
younger than 10.
I've seen, I've heard stories about six
year olds. That's how they're playing.
And then when they play,
they want to write stories.
So that's where you get kids like Justin,
he'll, he'll want to write about it.
If you, we have a bunch of little
boys, the moment they set pen to paper,
there's disapproval. That's probably
the worst thing that we can be doing.
And that's what's happening.
When I was in high school, I wanted
to be a comic book illustrator. Right.
Even before high school.
And if any psychologist got
ahold of any of my illustrations,
it was all like axe murderers,
like werewolves,
dragons. It was all crazy like,
but I, that's what I enjoyed.
I enjoyed reading those kind of comic
books and I enjoyed drawing those things
like, and uh, I didn't turn out to be
serial killer. They don't look
my best majority don't. And it's,
but we tweeting them that way.
Just the argument about
Gamers, right? I mean,
isn't that the argument about gamers?
That was a big part of the
whole gamer gate. Um, the, the,
the response that gamers
had, I was like, no, look,
just because we'd like engaging in
this fantasy and just because we, like,
we enjoy playing grand theft auto doesn't
mean we're going to go out and shoot
people. This is stupid. It's,
it's fun to fake shoot people.
It's fun to play call of duty and have
your friends on the other side and you're
shooting your friends. You don't want
to shoot your friends. But guess what?
When you shoot your friends in the game,
nothing fucking happens to them.
Okay.
It's very different
cry, you know, this, know
that, you know, their,
their children don't grow
up without a father. No,
they regenerate and they're back
in the next round. I mean this,
it's this idea that when you play a
game or what you engage in any sort of a
fantasy activity,
that that automatically equates to
how you're going to behave in society.
And that we have to stop that and we
have to limit that instead of just
addressing like what is it about these
fantasies that exciting is exciting for
people. Is there some sort of inherent
need that men have for adventure,
for
certain amount of like carries violence,
you know, even if it's just cathartic,
some sort of a fake release.
Absolutely. And the, there is not,
there is no good evidence that playing
a violent video game makes you violent.
But God knows people have tried
to prove it and they have failed.
And they even tried to prove that to
the supreme court a few years ago. And,
and Justice Scalia just head, he
wrote a beautiful, uh, you know,
opinion about how they just did
not make their case and it's,
it's no one has been able to do it.
Now they've come along and say,
oh well these games cause sexism.
Well,
the first thing to know is since kids
started playing video games in great
numbers and the nine days video game,
nation crime has actually gone down.
I'm not saying there's a correlation,
but there's certainly no correlation
between playing games and visor or you
would expect that it would have gone up.
Well,
games are addictive and they spent all
the time just playing those games and
they don't have time for violence.
That's what's going on. Possibly end.
And it's the millennial generation,
they're the last least
sexist and homophobic and all
that than other generations
such as games. Yeah, they
have more. Oh yeah, sure.
So the newest kids coming up are the most
open minded you took. Yes, absolutely.
Beautiful.
You questioned their attitudes compared
to kids from the 80 [inaudible] or
certainly baby boomers you'd
find they're more open.
Isn't that amazing couple that,
well that speaks to my optimism because
my optimism is that what we're getting
out of the internet or getting
out of this a open forum,
this ability to communicate
with each other is,
even though there's like there's the,
the sort of ganging up mentality on
someone when they say something wrong,
the attacking.
But ultimately I think
people are communicating in
a freer way and we're getting
to understand what is
offensive about racism.
What is offensive about
homophobia or sexism or,
or any of these things that were sort
of a cultural norms or would they had a
place in your particular neighborhood
or community and now you're community is
sort of the world.
And in doing so and in expanding our
community like that and creating this one
world community,
I think we're,
we're learning the differences that we
have between each other or more imagined
than they are are real.
Yeah. And I, it's, so I think that
anyway, about with the, with the Games,
uh, they had just made all these
false assumptions and I think people,
people try it, they do it
for you. We hear, oh well the
p the people are being destroyed by
the internet or people are being,
some people are,
some are actually anything you do.
They're going to be some that
are destroyed playing cards.
There's some people that are, will have
addictive personalities. I once met a sec,
can I just, he told me he was
studying people in their addictions.
He said almost anything people do about
5% if it's gambling or if it's bicycling
or dog racing are about 5% will become
uh, compulsive. Well, you know,
I work with a lot of fighters and martial
artists cause I'm a commentator for
the UFC and in the comp in,
in working with these people,
you find correlations
between people that are,
they become very excellent at at
fighting or something like streaming,
extremely dangerous and
they become more subject,
are more suspect [inaudible] they have
more potential for addiction I think in a
lot of ways. Outside of that,
like it's famous amongst fighters.
Like Joe Louis went on to become a
cocaine addict and he had a lot of issues
before he died.
Sonny Liston got involved in heroin.
They become addictive behavior is
extremely common with fighters.
Alcoholism is extremely common.
And um,
ballet dancers really, well, certainly
for a while they'd have a lot of,
there's high levels of Anorexia,
kind of an obsession about food,
but also of a cocaine use.
So maybe that a combination of
obsessive perfectionism. Yes. Well,
I think the obsessive
focusing on something,
even focusing on a negative
thing like gambling,
it becomes a part of how they
transition out of this work.
As the world of mixed martial arts
or fighting in general is very,
it's very intense,
but very s there's a short amount of time
where you could do it and compete at a
high level. It's a percentage of your
life and you, if you get really lucky,
you can get 10 hard years in.
You know, if you're an outlier,
you can stretch that out. But a lot of
people that compete, like in the UFC,
they're gone within a couple of years.
And so you find that in a lot of sports,
the NFL as well,
a couple of years for most of them and
their bodies just can't hang on anymore
and they're gone.
And they had this one thing that
occupied all their thoughts all the time.
Now it's gone.
And they have to figure out a way to sort
of transfer that energy in a positive
manner. Yeah. And what makes you really
good at things can also be a trap.
I had a problem when I was young, uh,
with video games and uh, it's not,
the video games are bad,
but I have a very addictive personality.
And I used to play video games eight to
10 hours a day. I used to play online,
I a game called quake quake game
online. And I recognize, I go, okay,
there's this is, I just can't do this.
Like my brain and this is a fun game.
I love it,
but my brain is just not good for this
because my brain had developed doing
martial arts and competent and competing
and I went from that to stand up
comedy. And then this, this other thing,
this video game thing got implanted
in my brain and recognize like, okay,
this is not going to be productive for me.
It's enjoyable,
but I'm too crazy for this so I've
got to put it aside. But for a lot of,
a lot of people that get involved in
like the singular pursuits where they
become so dedicated and
so focused on one thing,
it's extremely hard when that thing is
taken away from them and sometimes they
fall into negative things,
but that doesn't mean that
the video games or negative,
it doesn't mean that video games are
causing them to live their lives.
What they need is some sort of mental
management and we need to recognize that
there are certain people,
especially people that are,
that excel at certain things or people
that become obsessed with perfection or
obsessed with success,
that those things you can get
diverted down these paths,
whether it's gambling or if there's a
lot of different, I like that phrase,
mental management that that's right.
That's what they,
that should be more available. So it's
not video games and it's not video.
Video Games don't turn you into a sexist
if video games don't turn you violent.
It's nonsense.
I mean,
if this is arguably we have the
most access to violent information,
whether it's a, you know, in
a media form online, you know,
more more access to it than any human
beings that have ever lived before.
We have more access to
instantaneous violence,
seeing things online, seeing thing,
being able to play video, violent games.
But it's arguably the
safest time to live ever.
And some of the most violent games I hear
are in Japan and they are not violent.
They played the most violent game. Like
what do they play? Violent video games.
And they have a lot of,
uh,
a very permissive internet presentation
of pornography and wild things during a
tentacles and stuff. Right.
I don't know. And I'm a
strange, yeah. Yeah. It's a,
it's a weird culture. Japan,
they also have, um, they have
weird things that you could do.
Like you can buy women's
panties that women have worn.
You can buy them from vending
machines certain places. Yeah.
Buying them at all is strange on
vending machines is a deranged.
It is, but is it, I mean if, I don't know.
I mean what is so horrible about
that? It seems like, you know,
if you wanted to buy like severed
feet, yeah, that'd be Kinda fucked up.
But like if a girl wants to wear a pant,
I've,
I have a girl was coming on soon Tuesday.
Uh, she's a professional, humiliate her.
She is hired by these um,
like uh,
CEOs and these people that have tremendous
power and they want to be dominated.
They want to be taken and she has all
these things that she does with them.
Like she makes them give her their
bank account information so she can,
she can, she can steal money from them.
Oh, well I'm not saying anything hard.
Come on, I'll shield you
from any unpleasant thoughts.
But it's some people like
have these bizarre needs for
like things that you or I
would have no desire for it.
But at the end of the day,
it's an agreement that these two have.
She's does it professionally.
There's no confusion here. It's like, this
is all, I don't see what's bad about it.
Um, I'm trying to explore it. Have
you heard of that? Furries? Yes.
I don't know about it much,
but a nice furry told me on
the Internet that not to worry,
that most of them don't. And I don't
know that every time I bring it up,
people are, won't really tell me what
it is. And I don't fully want to know.
But from what I've learned, there
are many different kinds. Yes.
So that will go deep with it. And some
people, it's just fun. It's just fun.
I was accidentally at a furry convention.
There was a time where I was in
Pittsburgh and it coincided with a furry
convention.
And while we were driving down the street,
we were looking out the window. We're
going to, what the fuck is going on here?
So it's everyone wearing mascot costumes,
like they're all like big squirrels
and rabbits and stuff. And I'm like,
this is so strange. And then when
we got to the hotel, the hotel,
one of the guys that worked there, he, uh,
he opened up to me as we,
uh,
as we stayed there and he started telling
me the weirder aspects of furries like
that they had requested a litter box.
I'm, I'm not a shield. You nothing crazy.
The sexual stuff I'll shield
you from. Okay. All right. Um,
they had requested a
litter box for the lobby.
Like they literally wanted to go to the
bathroom in the lobby in a large litter
box. They were going to set it up and be
ready to hear about the sex part. Well,
they own, they not, not owned,
but rather they rented out the entire
hotel except for a couple of rooms.
And I was one of those fucking
rooms they hadn't gotten
because I had made my
reservation in advance.
And so I had done it like a few months
out and the firies hadn't taken over the
hotel yet. That is so funny to imagine
you at a furry convention. Hilarious.
They're friendly, they're all nice. You
know the high five me and stuff, you know,
and you don't know who your high five,
they could be making the meanest evil
face in the world behind that big smiley
chip Monck mask. But it was very
strange. They requested bowls.
They wanted to eat at a bowls
on the ground like a dog.
See one of their food to
be served on the ground.
Human mind is so complicated.
Yes it is.
Oh No.
Let's go back to your point of
a focus. Um, gender studies.
Yeah.
Um,
how did gender studies become like
primarily something that women focus on?
Like cause gender studies is
not really gender studies.
Like gender studies is like when you,
when you talk to someone they say
they're involved in gender studies.
It's either a guy who's some
fucking Weirdo feminists, dude.
Or it's women, right? Well,
probably there's a healthy instinct
to avoid a major that entails your,
you know, just shaming, you know,
feeling ashamed all the time.
Is that what it is? Why does it have
to be that men don't major in the,
they don't major it anywhere near the
same numbers in these somewhat peripheral
men are more practical.
They come to college, they overwhelmingly
are the engineering majors,
the ECON majors.
If the practical majors,
liberal arts majors mostly when it's
majority will philosophy's a little
different. Uh, but in the most of
the humanities it's more men. I mean,
I'm sorry, more women Ms.
French literature and I've
often thought it's partly,
sometimes people have said to me,
well,
you're suggesting that women are more
interested in the humanities and men are
more interested in the sciences, but
in, in Mexico or India, you know,
they have just as many big,
give me some example of places
where women have the same majors.
They're typically societies that where
people are very at risk economically.
Societies that are not as prosperous.
But if you get to a prosperous, you know,
advanced democracy where you can,
it can afford you the opportunity for
sort of high levels of self realization.
You then people do what they,
what they most want to do.
And so women get to college, they
don't have to be an engineering major.
They can major in art history or feminist
dance therapy if that exists or you
know, whatever they want and women, I
think that women feel a little freer.
I think there are a lot of men that would
prefer to do something other than what
they're doing,
but they're a little more practical.
I think most men think they are
going to work a full time job.
They don't have options. I think a lot of
women suspected they might not have to,
so that's why they're getting involved
in gender stone is because they don't
think they're actually going to have to
make a living. I don't know what would,
what would a big generalization
to say to look at it at all?
Because if it is one person,
yeah, I'm sure there are many
different reasons actually.
Now you can make a little career
for yourself by working, you know,
there's a little network
of women's organization, I
mean quite a large network.
So they'll find a place there,
do conferences and stuff like that,
but you can't expect to make much money.
And if you care about that,
that maybe it will be fulfilled if you
care about carrying on this campaign,
this twisted propaganda written
campaign against patriarchy.
Um, so, and by the way, I
should add that it's too bad.
Gender studies is that way because gender
is interesting and we should study it,
but it should be done by objective
people who will camp and from different,
with different agendas.
We all have agendas,
but you want to have a field where you
can kind of cancel out one another's
agendas and get closer
to true understanding.
Yeah, that was why I wanted to ask
you about it because it is, I mean,
the whole idea of men and women trying
to figure each other out has always been
problematic because we're doing it
under the guise of trying to mate.
We're trying to mate with each other.
So we're trying to figure each other
out while we're both bullshitting each
other. Right. You know,
it's like bald people are wearing a mask
and trying to figure out what they look
like underneath that mask.
And that's,
that's how a lot people get to the
point where they're married and even,
you know, they get divorced while
I'm never fallen for that shit again.
And then they fall into
another nice little trap.
And I think that it would
be really fascinating to
have an honest class on what
is the difference between men and women
and what are the biological reasons for
certain reactions.
Honest and helpful. Yes. To know what to
expect when you, when you get married,
you know, your husband's probably
not going to be like your,
your college room mate. They,
you know, when you have children,
chances are for most women, it's
not all the majority. This is,
uh, the, you know, the most,
you fall madly in love and you become
obsessed and it really hurts you to go
away for very long. Uh, you know,
40 hours a week and a lot of
men couldn't go away. I mean,
they can go away forever.
Men Do abandoned children or they're
less fixated on them. Then women.
This is just a fact of our nature.
There are exceptions.
I'm just talking about overall.
You don't find women abandoning
children unless they're usually,
unless there's um, mental illness
or a drug, a drug, something.
But men do it all the time. I
think fatherhood, you know, it,
it has to be supported and
encouraged and it's better.
We're better all round,
but it can't be taken for granted.
And the worst thing we can do is
to set people up, just to be it,
to be angry at each other because you're
going to be married to a man who's not
going to see the world exactly as you do.
Who's not going to care as much
about your, I dunno, your, your,
your window, uh, treatment.
Sure. Right, right.
It's not going to care as much and
especially after who have babies.
A lot of you, you can, a lot of girls
were slobs, but when you have babies,
there's something that
changes and you really,
you want the house clean and you want you
feathering the nasty shit in your nest.
Your yeah. And men don't seem to
have quite the same experience.
So people need to learn about
it and learn how to argue.
Don't like if people like there's so
much insulted, like a lot of women,
I see this happening, they become their,
their husband's mother did come nags.
Yeah. Which is just a recipe for
either misery or divorced. Right.
Because he doesn't want to be very to
nagging mother and women should know that
it's going to be frustrating because he
will not be as much help as you want.
But you're frustrating to him because
he probably has to do a lot of things he
doesn't want to do. So it's
a big compromise and young
people should know this.
Well, the, the biological
implications, the,
the biological reality of being an
animal is that most animals are raised by
their mothers.
I mean and we would all do much better
if the father was a loving father and was
around and it's a great
thing to concentrate on,
but human beings and a lot of ways mirror
the activities that we see in other
mammals and other mammals.
The women primarily were the females
primarily take care of the babies.
I think that if we looked at gender
studies from a biological standpoint and
then looked at them from a sociological
standpoint as well and tried to
figure out like what's the comfortable
middle ground and how can we better
understand each other from the biological
perspective and from the social
perspective.
It'd be really interesting.
It becomes a battleground for ideology
more than anything else. Doctrine,
nation as you say,
and,
and it's not w another thing we need to
know is what's easy to change and what
is it? For example, males are,
we've got very good evidence there.
Greater risk takers and rule breakers
and you see this even evidence from the
earliest ages,
little male toddlers have more accidents.
There had more in the emergency rooms,
more they're doing crazier things.
It's more of a challenge.
So you need to know that and
then what do you do with it?
And I see the need to channel that.
You take that mail risk taking,
which is very valuable for our species.
That risk taking and that rubric and you
direct it to good ends and a father is
helpful or a male role model or a coach
athlete, you know, they're all things,
sorts of things we do to socialize male
energy and a society where the males are
socialized to most of them to
do good. You'll build, you know,
you build the, you know, the
United States of America.
I mean that's a healthy society.
But if you have a society,
like we have these dysfunctional
pathological societies,
you get destruction in May. And because
there is a pathological masculinity,
most men aren't like that, but it exists.
Uh, so you need healthy masculinity.
You need to nurture that. So we need
to understand it, not resent it,
not pathologize it,
not criminalize it.
And yet we're doing this toxic masculinity
is one of my favorite and unexpressed,
oh yeah, there's toxic femininity to know,
especially when men are using it.
When men use a term like,
oh Christ and talks got
silly. But no, no,
it would have been interesting to
study gender objectively and it'd get,
you know,
and it should be based in the sciences.
You should have input from is universal,
the genders taught in school and
gender studies or feminist based.
I there could be exceptions. I
haven't seen them even in, you know,
even in Norway and Sweden and you go to
the departments in there full of people
that, you know with the
degrees in sociology and,
but who are very soft
and who are I strongly,
I lodge ideological well how do they get
away with saying things like gender is
a social construct because there's
so much evidence to the contrary.
The question is how do you get
away with questioning it and,
and have a career in the academy?
That's the question.
I questioned it. And um, I,
I had a colleague when I was,
I told you earlier about reading these
feminists textbooks and being horrified.
I remember one of them,
first of all,
the author dedicated it to the women in
my women's studies of ELR in the spring
of whatever year it was 91 and I
hadn't seen the word Avia Lara.
And I always like to look up
new words and I has it. I was about
to look it up until it hit me there.
I would not find it.
She made it up.
She didn't like the word seminar with
its root word associated with the very
essence. Yeah. Don't ask. Yes, yes. Don't
think it through because it's annoying.
But she wasn't, you know, thinking as
you called it [inaudible] seminar. Right.
Oh good Lord.
Now the thing is,
how about group would just
forget it. Neutral. Why is that?
There was another woman who said that
she had a theory that we were all born
bisexual. And then through
socialization our, you know,
our parents and society turn half of us
into female human beings and half into
male human beings.
And then she said one destined to
command and the other to obey. You know,
I remember reading that to my
husband or fun day and he said like,
which one commands in which
one obeys and yeah, but no,
but I'm just saying they have these,
these views that are,
that would not survive in any kind of
functional academic environment where
people could freely access. It's
not that they can't voice them, uh,
because sometimes people that are
have Kooky view sometimes, you know,
people test it and they can't
find fault and it, you know,
it ends up they ended up being
right. Right. So you, you,
you have to be polyamorous relationships,
things along those lines.
It actually do work for some, for some
people you have to be open to that.
You have to resist,
um,
close mindedness and then
the ideal university,
that's where you have some people bring
in people that challenge and you're
constantly either reinforcing what we
already know or challenging it or bringing
in new ideas. It's,
it's an exciting thing.
What we've done to our
universities is so sad now.
It's still that what I just described
that's going on in computer technology is
going on in the sciences.
It's been shut down in the humanities
and to some degree in the social sciences
and in education.
Is it possible that as we,
you said the millennials today
are the most open minded,
least likely to be racist or
prejudice, that the, the, the,
there's a good trend going on.
Is it possible that this same trend could
eventually extend to the universities
where these kids will realize how
preposterous some of this behavior is and
they'll reject some of this teaching and
they'll, they'll understand that like,
yes, there is a certain amount
of prejudice as some people have,
but let's get to the root of it and find
out why they have these misconceptions.
Why do they have these ideas in their
head that are ultimately biased and wrong
or or degrading or whatever it is.
But is it possible that through
conversations like this,
through things like your youtube videos,
through more people discussing these
ideas and an open form and more people
mocking things like what happened at
Yale or what happened at [inaudible] name
the college,
there's probably something going on
right now where someone's screaming at
someone because they want to go to a
lecture that's being taught by a man who
said something offensive about women's
roles and where the wrong shirt or
something like that.
Scientist
the war. The, yeah, yeah. Yes. Uh,
the problem is that these, uh,
these bad ideas have tenure. The,
the, these tents, they have
tenure. They are there. I mean,
so it's,
it's going to be hard.
I think what's going to happen is the
universities are maybe going to become
obsolete.
I think a lot of education is going to
move to web based education and cyber
courses. I know, I think it's sad
if we lose our tea, our colleges,
but the colleges I'm telling you they
will vaporize. Yale is at risk right now.
Amherst College, some of our best
universities, they are in there.
It has to soak deray so crazy.
What's going on there. And they've,
they have,
it's as if they've weaponized
the sensitivities of the
most neurotic students on
campus. And these kids are now, you know,
riding rough shot over
everyone else that can't go on.
So they will become so dysfunctional.
They need to film it.
Like when they fill me films, films,
when they filmed that one kid,
who by the way was an Asian American,
it was trying to take photographs of
the African American guy who was on the
hunger strike and they were accusing
him of being a part of the patriarchy.
And he was a fucking student. He
was a student. And then that woman,
she was a professor of communications.
She had, we need some muscle over here.
Oh,
that was nice.
She had requested the media come
and cover this just the day before,
the day before she had questioned the,
she tweets talking about
this hunger strike. You know,
this is a really important cause. Can the
media come and cover this? So the media,
cottonwood, we in the form
of student media Comms, this
kid, and this lady's like,
you have to leave,
you have to leave.
They had decided that a public place
was now private because this guy had
created a safe space and they were going
to do a hunger strike. They're like,
what in the fuck?
What are they protesting video.
But the video got out and the video
got out, the whole world responded.
She had to resign the whole world realize
how preposterous this behavior is and
but when we get a chance to see it,
we meaning people on the outside get a
chance to see that video and comment on
it in, in, you know,
from our own perspective,
not from the perspective of someone in
grossed in that sort of ideological trap.
Then you get to realize like that these
kids get to see how crazy we all think
it is. I think that there's a benefit,
there's a benefit in that and,
but there's also a benefit in,
in uh,
kids on campus to join us who
are sensible and who believe,
who do not want to be the generation
where it freedom came to die because
believe me, millennials out there,
you are that generation now.
Every generation has had
big challenges to liberty.
Everybody finds new ways
to challenge liberty.
You're tested and you have to meet the
test. And we had, we've been through,
you know, the McCarthy era and you know,
all sorts of things. They were in the,
in the Vietnam era and
it had to be worked out.
This is your challenge and I say
start the resistance and there's
a wonderful group called the foundation
for individual rights in education fire.
When I like about it,
it's bipartisan. It's,
it's liberals and conservatives who
love freedom because I think that's what
unites most Americans is that we
can have our political differences,
but we have this common commitment to
freedom and to try to increase it and
preserve it.
Now this group fire has replaced
the HCLU for civil liberties.
The ACO use asleep at the wheel. We
never hear from them about these campus,
you know this zealotry
you don't know how to
approach it because the,
the very people that are involved in that
zealotry will also support the ACL you
every step of the way because I think
it's pretty universally acknowledged.
The ACL does great work.
They, they're very variable.
I, I, my mother was a member and I
don't know if I met ever been a member,
but I love Nading Strawson she used to be
the president and we, you know, that I,
it was, it's great, but it, it
has been silent. Relatively cider.
Scared the ACL. You can't be scared. You
must be scared. They can't be scared.
While I think they are intimidated. Yeah.
Here's what I seem scared, isn't it?
Well, it's a little more complicated
because I think they also, maybe,
I don't know,
I'm not a psychologist,
but I will tell you that there are groups
like Libertarians, I noticed atheists,
you know,
the ACLU lawyers where they have a small
cohort of very angry women and these
are thoughtful that the majority of
people are thoughtful. Well meaning,
and they listened to these angry where
they think maybe we should be respectful.
Maybe they're, maybe they really are.
And they don't realize that they,
that it's a small group of bitter people
who believe twisted theories and false
statistics and they're imposing
that on the whole. But these, this,
these groups of women have been
very divisive for Libertarians.
They did it to the atheists. I think
they did it through the ACL. Ooh,
the mighty ACL you fell before a small
group of zealots and they're more likely
to be suing a school for having a boys
class to help boys read than they are to
be going on the campus in calling out
hordes of a, you know, vigilante group.
There was one professor that I follow
who is a, a, it's kind of a radical,
almost communist, very
socialistic. But, uh,
he was saying that the only mistake
that the woman made was that she did it
before she got tenure. And I
was like, that is hilarious.
You know what, he or she will get
tenure this, this will not hurt her.
This will help her. She's a celebrity.
Yeah. She'll get a better, I have seen,
I mean, I don't know, but I didn't,
she resigned. Oh No, she was,
you're talking about the one
at well muscle? No. Yeah, I
think that she was asked.
She had, she has an appointment
in the communications,
but I think she was teaching by invitation
for the School of Journalism. Right.
And University of Missouri has a storied
wonderful, you know, journalism school.
And I think they were horrified to
have on a public university to have a,
a professor. Yeah. Going out the police.
So she was disinvited from being
part of that program. But no, no.
She'll be, she'll be at a, at, at, at,
at Wesleyan. That's very cynical. It's
not cynical. It's the factual feminist.
That's horrifying though, that someone
would, that kind of thinking that,
telling some person that, oh, do
you remember the Duke Lacrosse case?
How about the University of Virginia Case?
That was in rolling stone and all that.
But even before that, Duke Lacrosse,
these young men falsely
accused a flagrant lie.
We'll 88 professors long before
anything was known about it.
They came out with an advertisement
on who was in the school paper,
a local paper as siding with the accuser
against the boys and some of them in
the, we're very viciously
outspoken and, and,
and they basically were part of a,
a vigilante group that, you know,
it conducted the equivalent
of a witch hunt and they,
there were no consequences. They've gone
on to better jobs, some of them. Wow.
Really? Yeah, that's absolutely horrific.
That was one of the things that
made me hate Nancy grace. Oh,
Nancy grace was terrible
because I don't know her,
I hate what she represents on television.
Maybe she's like one of those
people that's just reality
TV acting out and she's
Nice Lacrosse boys. Yeah,
she was horrible on that.
And it turns out that she was absolutely
wrong and never apologized. And those,
those kids didn't,
well I don't know what they did really
come just that day and that night they
did nothing. It apparently,
I mean one of them wasn't,
it wasn't even there.
He had proof that he was not
there and it wasn't enough.
Well,
it's again,
it's the lynch mob mentality and trying
to keep them away from you, you know,
and trying to turn them away from you.
So you have to say something
that's going to exonerate you from,
from being guilty by
association or guilty. By the
way you know, you, you, you,
you view the case, you know the you
are, you're not a part of the problem.
You're a part of the potential solution.
And I think liberal students
and conservative students
could unite on campus.
It just in favor of free expression.
Are they the most maligned
students on campus?
Conservatives concern.
Here's the good thing for conservative
students and libertarian students,
when you get to campus, uh, you're going
to have your ideas challenged morning,
noon, and night. And that's probably good.
You're going to become very conversant
in the ideas of the other side,
which might, one of my favorite
philosophers, John Stuart Mill, said,
you can't understand your own position
unless you understand your critics.
You have to understand your critics almost
as well as you understand yourself to
truly be able to defend a position.
So conservatives have that advantage
in and their professors, the majority,
we have very good data,
vast majority liberal.
So they will hear that and then
they're going to make good friends.
If they hang out with each other,
they'll make buddies that, you know,
it's like comrades in war,
there'll be friends for life. Uh,
then there are a liberal
students that go there and there you
have to be careful because they're just
going to be in an echo chamber,
you know,
and they'll hear it and
it'll be reinforced and they
better be careful and try
to make a point of attending a lecture.
If someone comes,
it's offering a different point of view
because they won't hear it. And uh,
that they, that the conservative kids up
til now, up till a couple of years ago,
they were fine. I mean, people
would occasionally be mean,
but now I'm a little worried because
they, this, this outburst of fanaticism,
this outbreak of cri bullies who could be,
they could be very punishing.
And can you even have a young
Republican's Conference on, on a,
a major campus? Well, it's an
interesting question. There are,
they do have college republicans.
I was invited to, um,
even though I'm still a
registered Democrat, the,
the College Republicans and Libertarians
and Oberlin invited me and it was the
college Republicans said Clare Booth
Luce set after you had already been like
triggered the dog triggered and you,
the people came with a tape over
their fear that was the same.
They were the ones that invited me to
all these kids found out and the same at
Georgetown.
So that you were invited to speak
to Republicans and Libertarians.
Well that's probably a big
part of what went wrong. Right.
They just assumed you're were part of
the problem because of who invited you.
They didn't even care about that.
There was my name and they, what they,
they'd seen a,
you know,
a snippet of as something from the
factual feminist and said that I was
a bad person. They didn't want to hear
it. They did not want me on campus.
And, you know, I try to, I try,
I always try to put myself in
the other person's position.
And I think what would upset me like
that, who would, I know a lot of people,
I would be very upset if, you know, if a
Nazi were coming or even someone who I,
I, you know, I just
thought was reckless and,
and defamed people who, first of all,
I don't, I'm not like that at all.
I haven't done anything like that.
Uh, but I can imagine being upset.
But even then, what would I do if
someone invited a horrible person?
I would not, I would, I would
write an op ed or having, uh,
you know, uh, you on
the campus, you have to,
that's the place where you should
learn to fight these things.
You fight bad ideas with good ideas,
not by spitting on them,
which happened at Yale and
not by intimidating them,
which I happen to Yale and Missouri and
not by this kind of mob hysteria who got
spit on it. Yeah, I think
it was, um, it, this is, so,
this is typical of what happens.
Uh,
Greg Lukin off from this group fire that
I urge people to check out because they
were really taking their,
they're leading the way,
fighting this nonsense on campus while
he was speaking at Yale and as a,
and he, he's actually the one
that filmed, wait a minute,
am I confusing my schools? He filmed a
student, oh yeah, yeah. It was at Yale.
He was speaking and he had an iPhone
and he was with the professor whose wife
had challenged Halloween costumes and
he actually was put on his iPhone, not
because he wanted to make a viral video,
but because he'd seen things like this
happen and then students misrepresent
what happened. He was afraid
they'd say the dean got, you know,
it was screaming at obscenity. So
he filmed it for that reason. Well,
before that he was giving a talk about
free speech on campus and he was talking
about some of the craziness going on.
And you just said in passing,
they're treating, you know, the Dean's
wife, I'm not sure this was an example,
but it was something like this.
They're treating the dean's wife as if
she's some kind of war criminal is if she
burned down of Indian village,
that like she's a genocidal maniac.
Some protesters said Indian village,
you're making a joke about genocide.
And then they,
he went crazy and had to
be removed from the room.
Then word got out that somebody had
joked about genocide and it was complete
nonsense. A complete mangling of
what Greg Lukey and off had said,
this is what's happening. They take
a little comment to out of campus.
Then the hysteria spreads cause they're
just ready to be, to be triggered.
Well I think it's again,
when we said there's just people
looking for the green light,
they're just looking for the, there's
a green light. I see Indian go
rational response to someone saying
something that's a callous or rude or
prejudice. It's a green light. It's this,
these are certain subjects where you're
allowed to be offended and now what's
anything will offend these groups.
So it's more and more, you know,
there was a time where our campuses,
we're so segregated and they were
being integrated and these, you know,
you see videos of, you know, will you
see footage of what it was, you know,
in photographs,
famous photographs of when they first
integrated the University of Mississippi,
and I guess it was James Meredith going
on campus and just horrible behavior and
that that is so offensive.
That is racism now that
there has to be these tiny,
somebody drives by in a truck and maybe
shouted something that mobilizes the
campus.
It's interesting to decades later,
things have changed so much that they
have to search to find things to really,
truly be able to be offended.
I think that's, these are
your grievance collectors.
They just want to be, they're
chronically offended people. I mean,
what is that that would motivate someone
to want to have to be in that mode?
I don't know. I, I, as I said, I'm
not a psychologist. I'm a philosopher.
I recognize bad ideas and nonsense,
but I don't understand that attraction.
Assume that they need real problems.
I assume that they need real,
some real adversity in their life.
They need something real to do battle.
And some have said it may be the result
of the helicopter parenting and self
esteem education.
So they,
they hot overprotective kids were,
you know,
every little setback, you know, there
were parents and teachers and everyone,
you know, oh poor thing. So they never
developed that healthy resilience.
They go to campus,
they hear the Dean's wife writes an
email about Halloween costumes they don't
like and they flip out or does anybody
really believed that that girl who
screamed at the Dean when yelled at
this is my home. You're, you know,
like all that crazy shit that
she was yelling out crazy.
She would she have done that
if they were alone with it?
Does anybody believe that?
Does anybody believe that if they had
met in an office somewhere and had a
rational discussion,
she was acting,
she putting on a theatrical performance
for all the people that were involved
kind of worked up by the
energy of the crowd crowd.
And you have to be careful of that.
I just warn people,
be careful of that emotion of,
of rage doesn't lead to good places and,
and,
and you know,
feeling really self righteous and
grandstanding and grandstanding.
There was a lot of the bad history, all
of that behavior. You have misinformation,
twisted theories, moral fervor, histories,
one long lesson and the dangers of
combining these things and what we talked
about before,
that life essentially has become some
sort of a bizarre open-ended reality show
and that these people are jockeying for
a great position on the social ladder.
And by being the person who yells
at that guy on social media,
that girl got a lot of pounds
the next day at school.
Girls give her knuckles and hug her.
That was amazing.
Did you see you got a hundred likes and
I'm just glad there was no social media
when I was in college
because I was a crazy,
crazy and we're not that
crazy but a little crazy.
And I was on the periphery of a mob
at Nyu that occupied a computer.
It was a big deal. It was a big, there was
a computer. You're occupied a computer.
Yeah, it was real. It was a big thing.
Now they're are current. The whole street.
This was the courant institute and we
were going to destroy the computer. What?
I hadn't thought it through.
Why are we going to destroy the computer?
Because we thought they were
doing research for the war.
This is a long time ago.
Okay. This was 69, I believe. Maybe 70.
And I was on the periphery of a crowd.
And I do think there was a moment where
a dean came and I may have had words
with him and I am telling him like,
that girl yelled at like that,
but he just said something,
young lady at however the differences,
once I knew he was a dean and I
ran away, I didn't want to, uh,
I don't know.
I'm just glad there isn't a videotape.
So how were they using the computer
for the war? I think that was the,
it was a mathematical institute
called the courant institute.
And they had a computer, which
was a big deal. That was huge.
And I think they thought they could go in
and destroy it. And, but I'll tell you,
it was probably one of my first moments
of awareness about the dangers of the
left. Even though I was an
enthusiastic participant,
we did break into the building and we
were in someone's office and I was kind of
thrilled. Ah, I met the, the, the,
the military industrial complex
and this is the brain center. And,
and I was in an office and somebody
punching out somebody slides.
They were, you remember a slide
you've on? They were punching him out.
And I thought, Oh, what is that?
And I looked and it was like a professor's
photographs of his kids and they were
destroyed. They were destroying them.
And then I looked around and thought,
this is just some person. And I kind of
slowly retreated. I felt very ashamed.
I didn't know what I, there were
thousands of us there. All right.
I'm not confessing to
a crime. Right. But I,
I was part of a crazy mob
and I never forgot that. And,
and then I started,
you know,
I mean I still remained a or for a while,
but never was I ever on the
part of anything like that.
I think then you uniquely understand
the whole hysteria behind it.
You can get caught or caught up in
it and I understand something else.
Some of the craziest ones are going to
defect to to my side eventually because
in uh, among the Marxists, for example,
some of the best anti Marxists
antibody were, were former Marxist.
Some of the people that had the most
penetrating analysis of what's wrong with
totalitarian systems,
they were once people who are part of it.
I think there are a lot of
smart kids who had an education.
They would robbed of a serious education.
They're going to realize it and they're
going to reflect and they are going to
be radicalized in a
good way for the truth.
People who were former cult members go
on to become members of cult awareness
groups or lead call awareness groups are
actually had a couple on that have been
in Colton have talked openly about their,
I think they share something and that
people love to be a part of a group.
It's a tribal thing. It is tribal. I
remember chanting and, and you know,
being in and it was exhilarating.
Hell no, we won't go, hey,
hey Lbj, how many kids did
you kill today? Did that,
and um,
you went to you march on Washington
because though that made sense.
It was it, you know, I don't think my
understanding of it totally made sense,
but in retrospect it was a,
a messed up what I do,
but it'll just be coming.
We'll take it out on the HDI
website where interesting.
If worry about that. That's a
beautiful thing about being a comedian.
I don't have to worry about that shit.
You know,
I don't worry about it because
I just worry about it because I,
it's been done so many times and every
little thing they'll take. And then,
you know,
there's always my 92 year
old mother who will somehow,
she's on Facebook and she sees these
things. She'd say, what were you doing?
Like she's to, well she knows I, but
she's very left wing. So she, yes, she,
but she like, she totally
gives it reason the about, uh,
my critic critique of feminism
because she likes men.
She's never been that kind of a feminist.
She's a feminist. Who, who? She humanity.
She's a little naive I think,
you know, in her politics,
cause she's still very left wing,
but she's great.
It comes from a good place.
So I'm sympathetic. Not
only was I once a radical,
but I'm sympathetic to left us
because the people probably close.
Some of the people closest to
my heart are very left wing.
But they're not haters. They're not, no,
they don't take a whole groups
of people impugn them as evil.
Well, I'm, I'm very sympathetic to a lot
of the ideas that left wing people have.
And I don't know if I consider myself
left wing or libertarian or what, but I'm,
I'm Kinda in the middle on the
line. I'm homeless politically. Yes.
I tried to think, well, maybe I'm,
maybe I agree with the Republicans and
then they'll say something that's so
unacceptable. Yeah. And then I
think, oh, maybe Bernie Sanders.
And then 90% of all we wouldn't
mind is you'll say something.
And um,
and I thought I could be behind Hillary,
but she's kind of irritating and
I think on these women's issues,
it's going to be, I don't know, she
could be very, very bad for, you know,
issues I care about how so
she might not be, but, well,
in the current administration, there's
an invisible government, uh, in all,
in all administrations, there's
an invisible government of, uh,
people who,
you know,
regulators and people who work in little
agencies in the government and they
write policy, they white right?
Regulation. And so we've seen our schools,
a lot of the things I've been talking
about that are contrary to the interests
of boys.
This is coming out of government and
it's coming out of these agencies than
Democrats.
There they exist.
Both Republicans can't stop it and they
do it in other areas that I don't know
as much about it.
But in the democratic,
the social issues that anything
that affects education or media,
they're doing things that I just find
very problematic and not in the interest
of liberty or wellbeing.
And so that's when I worry
that she might not do it.
She might surprise us.
Why was assumed that those directions
are being prompted by special interest
groups and people that have gotten
people into power in the first place.
By the time you get to be a president,
you have so many people.
You're beholding to so many people
that have spent so much money.
You almost have very little time to think
about anything other than reconciling
that
right. And it's probably not your primary
interest, but you're, you're, you're,
you want to help out the American
Association of University Women
and you assigned people to deal with
that when they run with it. Yeah.
And then they run with it and make
policy that you may or may not even agree
with,
but you kind of committed to it.
Bad policies in edge in my opinion,
in education.
So I worry about the Democrats there.
So there's a lot to worry about in both
parties. So I'm kind of a homeless.
But hmm.
Do you take satisfaction
in what you're doing?
Do you enjoy making these
factual feminist videos? And
I do too. I wish I weren't doing
it. I do not in this sense.
There's so many things I,
a lot of interests and I would also like
to spend some period of my life just
being Adilla taught because I
love music and literature and art.
Love to go to travel and
this takes a lot of time.
It takes a lot of energy and not always
good energy because you're dealing with,
once again,
I have to read something that is so
problematic and sometimes it takes a long
time to untie knots in the truth.
It's easier to tie a knot
and the truth and on Taiwan,
so I'll have to write a long article
explaining why someone was so wrong and I
have to do it over and over again.
So it's tedious. On the other hand,
I don't like,
I don't want to see bullies winning.
And so I'm, I'm, I welcome the time where
more people come forward, but it does,
we do need to have more professors coming
forward because you need scholars and
you need people who can look at
the data. You need. Statisticians.
It's not enough to have activists. So
this can't be done by pundits. The heart,
you know,
the heavy lifting to push back the
political politically correct forces of
unreasoned on campus. It's going to
have to be other scholars that, that,
um, put up the stop sign or
you know, that, that encourage,
uh, uh, move towards, uh, you know,
we're more rational worldview,
but what's going to motivate
them to do that, to make a shift?
It's possible that things are getting
so bad that more will be emboldened,
the more realize like what happened
to the Yale. Yeah. Now, now there's,
for example, there's Steve
Pinker, uh, I, he, yeah,
he's at Harvard and
there's Jonathan Heit at,
I believe he's now at Nyu was
at the University of Virginia.
They've been outspoken for a long time,
but they are really starting
to come out and call, cry,
foul about what's going on.
And they're powerful and they're
brilliant guys and tremendous command of,
you know,
the literature of their fields and
they're able to bring that to bear and
fantastic lecturers and
essays and books and so forth.
So there's Jonathan Heit there,
Steven pinker. But I want more women.
I think that it's going to take women's
scholars to challenge the head Gemini of
the, these, this hard line, you know,
male averse feminists
that, that, you know,
have a monopoly now on gender studies,
going to take some women's scholars.
So I'm waiting for them to come.
I'm, but they just, so far it hasn't,
it hasn't had, there are
a few, but not very many.
Two is there a single man out there?
The teacher's gender studies? Oh yeah.
One of those.
I'm thinking of one person,
I won't mention him, but he's so
frustrating. Reacts so quickly.
Those have such a visceral builtin.
Oh,
I'm thinking of a particular individual
who is so frustrating, so frustrating.
You don't have to name his name,
but what's wrong with this poor bastard?
You know, I will say what's wrong with
him? And His name is Michael Kimmel.
And what frustrates me,
he is a male feminist as radical
as any that I've mentioned.
And he was given a fortune,
or maybe not a fortune,
but a sizeable amount of money.
You should start one of the first
centers for the study of men. So he's at,
I think it's sooner,
you're one of the New York campuses and
he has all this money for a center to
study men. And he just said it
like men in my life, well in mine.
And he's a hardline feminist.
He believes that in toxic masculinity,
he loves to talk about things like that.
He takes the worst case,
male, um, you know,
a school shooter or some
deranged sociopath and, and,
and makes that a metaphor for all men.
He does that sort of thing. You know,
the Columbine killers, those are our
boys. All our boys. No, they're not.
They are psychopathic
killers and they are extreme.
Even among psychopathic killers.
They do. No, they don't.
They don't represent our boys.
And I'm overstating a little bit,
but not by much.
So we finally get a center that's
going to study young men and,
and it's run by him.
And who does he put on the board?
He's got eve Ensler who
wrote the vagina monologues,
which was kind of male averse. I
don't think there's a very, any,
any po Po, a positive males in
that they said maybe Vagina Bob,
but he's not very sympathetic.
And then there's a Gloria
Steinem and Carol Gilligan there.
The, it's, it's not
go and do work. So He's a male
gender studies professor. He's a,
he's a feminist. Sociologist, feminist,
sociologist w what does this
gentleman looked like? Silk.
Like what you would expect. Uh,
I dunno what you're imagining.
Is he overweight woman with
pink hair? No, no, no, no.
He knows normal cause it just,
no, I don't know what he's,
I don't know what forces created it,
but he, that's what we're dealing with.
So there's a few, a few of those.
They're like vampire familiars.
That's what they're a lot of speakers.
Yet when be played,
he would have these little,
uh,
set these sycophants around them
that were not really vampires,
but they want it to be vampires.
They were hoping the vampires would
turn them and they would say anything.
They'll say, well, he believes it and
he believes the statistics and, and
no, I was thinking maybe when he started
this center or he'd become a little more
sympathetic towards and I
don't see evidence of that.
He's still, well, you could certainly, if
you looked around, I mean the, the, the,
the problem is the, the, the numbers
of people that you're dealing with.
You're dealing with 300 plus million
people in this country and decades of new
stories. And if you want it to
look at the numbers in that way,
you could find a lot of evidence that
men have done horrible shit. I mean,
there's no, there's no doubt about
it. You look at our buttons since
we talked before that male violence
sure are more violent and a society that
doesn't take in account the male capacity
for rule breaking and risk taking and
wreaking that you,
you know,
the boys who are insufficiently socialize,
have very unpleasant ways of making
themselves noticed and you have to be
careful.
But,
but it's this tiny minority and it usually
takes other men to protect the rest
of us from them. And I always wonder,
like just the other day in Paris,
there was this horrible terrorist attack.
And there was a little story
about in the news about, uh, this,
this cafe and these people
were slaughtered in the
cafe and there's this lovely
young woman who was in the hospital from
trauma and there was this beautiful man
who thrown herself on him.
His instinct was just to protect her
and protect as many people as he could.
His beautiful guy.
And I thought,
why can't we take him as emblematic
of what men can do, you know?
But the gender scholars never,
we never find him.
We find serial killers. They
say, well, that's what men do.
Well, there certainly are a
lot of men serial killers.
The problem is I think when you focus
only on the negative aspects of it,
you also run the risk of self definition
by the people that listen to what he
has to say and take his class. You,
you become guilty by association.
You are a man like you.
You get those,
those guys who make those videos that I
am apologizing for every man ever before
me and they want to distinguish themselves
as being different and they want to
go way out of the way. Have you ever
seen that dear woman video? Okay.
God, yes I have. And it's the worst
kind of gender profiling, isn't it?
I mean it's
perfect. It's perfect.
Cause those guys are,
those guys are the guys that wouldn't
survive if you took those guys on like a
track through the woods,
those the guys who would have the sprained
ankles and they would start weeping.
Those are the guys.
And those are the guys that if you'd left,
they would be at home with
your wife and they would, uh,
say horrible things about you and
what a terrible person you are.
And Try to get her to love them instead
of loving you because they're weak.
They're what?
Pardon my French weak bitches.
That's what Ben Likes
to call Ben like that.
And that's why they make those videos,
those videos, they're not made by normal.
Why? Why would a man apologize
for things at other men have done?
Have you've done something horrible,
you should say, dear women, I,
I've done some fucked up shit.
I've,
I've made some horrible
movies that portrayed women
in a very unfavorable line.
I didn't consider the fact that some women
would watch those movies and it would
somehow or another define them in their
own way. I shouldn't have done that. Well,
this isn't what they're doing.
What they're doing.
They're apologizing for the other men.
Right.
And there's therefore setting
themselves up on a moral high ground,
which is what a lot of male feminists do.
Their weak men, they're really weak, man.
They're unfavorable
sexually and they're there.
They're not the type of men
that women would choose.
So what they have done is they've tried
to figure out a way in the game too to
be like what men want is people
to love them. It's women wanted,
everybody wants people to love them
and what when they don't have any
particularly outright masculine
characteristics, they're not attractive.
They're not handsome than not
bold and daring than a creative.
They're not profound or charismatic.
They male
feminists and that's what they do.
They become these sort of
gender traders that they dig,
call out all of the weakness
of all the other men.
Sort of highlight themselves
as being different.
I'm not saying it's all male feminist
cause again I think there's a lot of male
feminists that they take on this
idea because they do see sexism.
Yeah,
they do see they want people to be equal.
They want to be judged based on the
merits of who they are as a human being.
I respect them.
I just would like them to consider that
things are not exactly the way they
think. Then they might've been
taught by a charismatic, uh,
women's studies professor.
They might be more complicated and they
should know that there was efforts to
keep people like me and Camille Polya
and Wendy Kaminer and a long list of us.
They were,
there were a group of feminists who were
not male averse who were sex positive
and we were driven, you
know, we were not included.
We were not invited to the table.
And there's a reason why kids,
they don't read us or if they do,
you know,
it's immediately just savaged and,
and very selective in what they sell.
So they had,
they haven't had the advantage on these
issues of hearing from a range of, uh,
a full range of opinion.
Yeah.
It's fascinating because none of
what you're saying is offensive.
None of what you're saying is derogatory
in the idea that you would somehow or
another trigger people or caused
the creation of safe spaces.
This is preposterous.
It's observed needed.
I needed an arm guards me to protect
the love it how there were women.
I love their women armed guards,
but they weren't protecting
me because they both,
and this happened at Georgetown,
they gave me security guards
at Georgetown as well.
This was happening at Georgetown.
If for whatever reason among
social justice warriors as
they're sometimes called
clapping is thought to be triggering and
so when they approve of what you are,
their comrades say they do jazz
hands or gloves clicking and yes,
if you watch some of the mob's on campus,
they're clicking their fingers.
I just want to say even as a
former radical like don't do that.
Clapping is like beating me.
Like someone could be beating you.
Is that what it is? Maybe
it's this, it's just whatever.
It's just upsetting and distressing
and otherizing. It's otherizing navies.
That real otherizing nail term otherizing
tweeting as the other and by the way,
nobody does more otherizing
and demonizing. Then
these hard line feminists,
it's like everything they
say men do not everything,
but most of the things they say men do.
They do.
They stereotype demonize other eyes and
they don't just do micro aggressions.
They're macro aggressive.
They're very rude.
What is this fashion now among so many
feminists to be so snarky and mean and I
don't think being mean,
I mean men didn't,
we didn't succeed in
the world and you know,
universe because they were mean
and vicious. I mean that's,
why do they think that that is a recipe?
Cause it gets effect. It has an effect
today with our social media climate.
The fact that we have this new world,
this new environment,
those snarky posts get the most reaction
to get the most retweets and favorites
and they get the most likes.
And that is seen as currency is seen
as like a social media currency.
And so by attacking people you can also
get them to respond and engage you.
And it's a way they seek out a high
profile people that might be a,
that might have a difference
of opinion with them.
They'll seek them out and insult them
and force them to engage because someone,
you read something insulting about
you like, Whoa, like I told you,
like when I had been called a male
rights advocate by this really obese,
a feminist woman, I was like, what
is that mean? What does an Mra?
And I had to read it, I
just blocked her. I'm like,
I'm not gonna engage with someone who
just insults me and just says a bunch of
insulting shit and calls me a moron and
asshole and all these different things
where I never even communicated with them.
I had no communication with her
whatsoever. She just decided to single.
And it wasn't just one, it was a,
there was quite a few of them. And um,
it's because a lot of people will react.
You get that and it's your automatic
reaction to react to them. You know?
That's why they're yelling things at you.
They trying to get you to react to them
if they just talk to you in a normal way.
Bunch of people. I used to be
drawn it on Twitter because not,
not because I wanted to
react. I always, I am, uh, uh,
is the mother and the professor in
me if someone's carrying on right.
And then I want to reason with
them. Right. And you know, and then
I have learned that it's a waste of
time in some cases. Not all learning.
We're all learning how to handle this,
this name definitely do not write,
engage late at night. It
keeps you up. I can't, I,
I've been tweeting like
at three in the morning,
I think this is insane because I'm,
I've gotten some exchange or,
or I'm watching an exchange.
It's not a good thing to do.
Do you not to eat after midnight.
Wonderful. And a lot of ways. All
right. And I, I'm a, I'm home. I have,
I hope that all this ridiculousness is
something that's going to be ironed out.
And I think that this is something that
all human beings are starting to learn
how to navigate the world of
social media and that these,
this kind of behavior with someone
just immediately get snarky and becomes
insulting just in order to get attention.
It's going to be laughed at.
I think that's a good
point that we're going to,
it's going to evolve and
there will become, uh,
sort of unwritten rules of the game.
And I hope one of the rules is don't
join a hitter at a Twitter hate mob.
Yes.
And attack some hapless
professor or someone that you
heard from somebody told a
joke and, and by the way, can we just
leave jokes alone altogether? I mean, let,
let comedians tell their jokes that
you can't now have a comedian on campus
because everyone will be triggered.
Well, comedians are bullies. If you
make a joke about you're a bully,
someone disagrees. People like George
Carlin were, that was where they were.
They were on campus and,
and you know it,
most of us won't work on campuses now.
I know a big percentage of
comics won't work on campuses.
And apparently their little committees,
I read the story about little committees
that decide which comedian to invite
and they have to try out and, and there
are so many ways you can strike out.
I mean forget the obvious ways you can,
everything is offensive.
Jokes are offensive, jokes are
triggering. I had a guy, I mean this,
this is going way back.
This is going back to the early nineties.
I used to do a lot of
colleges when I was coming up,
but it was way easier back then.
There was no social media and it was
not hard to do. And this is like, um,
Earl like 1991, 92 pre-internet, uh,
ice do a lot of them because it was
a great way to make money. But, uh,
I remember one time I used to
do this Q and a thing with kids.
They would ask me questions and you know,
I would just joke around after the show.
So I do my show.
Like I didn't have anywhere to go
so down. And so the guy goes, uh,
the guy goes, I forget what, what
he said something about tell a joke.
So I said to Jews, walk into a bar,
they buy it. Thank you very much.
You know it's a joke.
It's a joke.
And he came up to me after the show and
said that was really offensive what you
said about you.
And I could tell he was like testing
the waters of whether or not he should
actually be offended. I go,
are you really offended? I go,
what's offensive fence by that?
It was the stereotype.
It's stereotypical and I'm like, well
it's about Jewish people buying things,
being successful in business.
Like it's not negative at all.
Like he was perplexed, funny but, but
it's, it's a stupid old street joke,
but stay saying that it's offensive was
an automatic reaction to this young kid
that hadn't yet experienced this wave
of social justice warriors that were
reinforcing these stupid
ideas he has in his head.
Like he had decided that since I was
saying something about an ethnicity or
minority and they're just even
saying a joke about it was offensive.
But it's clearly not an offensive joke.
It's,
it's about Jewish people being
good at business. I mean,
that's the whole, it's a,
it's not even a good joke. It's, it's
terrible. But I, I'll never forget it,
him coming up to me and saying that, I
found that really offensive. I'm like,
get the fuck out of here.
You didn't think that was offensive.
That's not offensive. It's
just not, it's not good.
But it's certainly not offensive to
see any Mel Brooks movies or listen to
Jackie Mason or, you
know, well, it's just,
it's that thing where you're young and
you want to kind of establish your,
your viewpoint and you want to
separate yourself from the, the,
the fools of the world and say that,
you know,
you're going to be different than your
parents and you're going to branch out on
your own and you're, you know, you're a
fucking young mind. They're 18 years old,
1920 whatever they are there.
They're off, away on their own,
staying in dorms and reinforcing
each other's terrible ideas together.
And some of them more
sensitive than others.
And some of them grew up in a more
suppressive environment than others.
Some of them more easily led than others
and some of them will have ideas that
they will nurture when
they're 18 or 19 years old.
They will completely abandoned when they
get into their 20s and they realize how
preposterous those ideas were in less.
They get completely indoctrinated and
then they go on to become a part of the
very system that indoctrinated them
themselves. I think that's a lot of the,
the fears that a lot of people looking
at it from the outside like me,
that's a lot of the fears that we have.
Like we,
we wonder like this is sort
of a closed loop. The the,
the closed loop of becoming an academic
yourself and reinforcing these ideas
without a whole lot of
interaction with the real world,
without a whole lot of interaction with
people that have differing opinions.
It may be just as intelligent as you and
maybe you can learn from each other or
come up with some sort of a middle ground,
but that's not tolerated. There's no,
you can't, you don't tolerate anybody
that looks at these ideas from a different
perspective or from a singular point of
view like it at all has to be in this
very rigid ideological,
predetermined pattern or behavior
that everybody locks into. Yeah,
well we need a rebellion
or youth rebellion.
Well is that w do don't you think
that's kind of going on though?
Like the reaction to these videos,
there's a rebellion,
the Olsen,
it is a rebellion and this will give
you heart when you read in this as I do
because on Twitter people
send me these things,
you'll read an article in the Yale Daily
News or the Amhurst whatever newspaper
they have.
Um,
people will write something very annoying.
The PC to the extreme and then you'd
read the letters and those give you heart
because you still see there is still
very reasonable people in these colleges
who are not buying it,
but they have to
be somehow empowered. I don't
know how to do that. Yeah.
I don't know how to do that either.
But I think information and open
discourse and just those that's,
that's exactly what's going on right now
with the Internet and with social media.
Those two things are the most important
aspects of a society evolving and a
society without really
without any buddy running it.
I mean,
the thing about colleges and the thing
about a university courses that you have
a professor,
you want to get a good grade,
the professor has an ideology that
they're sort of passing on to you and you
want to try to manipulate them a little
bit and right in a way that you think
that they will, that will appeal to
their sensibilities, their ideology.
While the Internet doesn't have that,
I mean you have,
you've giant groups of people,
but ultimately just have people.
I mean that's really what it is.
There's a lot of different kinds of ideas
that are floating around out there and
you're going to find people that resonate
with your ideas and people that don't.
And along the way you're gonna,
you're gonna have people that read some
of the things that you've written or
some of the things that you've said.
And take it down and call you a fool
and you're going to have to look at that
and you're gonna have to go, wow.
Maybe when I yelled at that Yale Dean,
I was being a fucking idiot.
Maybe that his grandstanding,
maybe that is preposterous,
you know,
and maybe I would not have done
that if I was alone with him.
Maybe that is just something that I did
because I was caught up in the fervor of
the [inaudible]
group, by the way, that professor who
really shamed herself by acting
out, but, and it got on the media,
the one from University of Missouri.
Yeah. The communications professor. Um,
she did write, she wrote an apology
and I thought it was, I mean,
I'm willing to forgive her because it was
heartfelt and she did say that she was
sort of horrified to watch herself.
And so I'm thinking now she may be just
a hard, but I thought people were saying,
oh, she's just trying to keep
her job. Well, first of all,
I don't think we should be after people's
jobs. And you know, in that way, I mean,
not that she did teach
a lot of weird courses.
She taught a course on abstinence
and no, no, 50 shades of grey.
Is it 50 or 60 whenever 50 she taught
us a course on 50 shades of gray and she
taught a course abstinence and the
twilight series. Oh, she did? Yes.
About how Edward didn't have sex
with her and Bob Midwall, she wrote,
Edward was 17 years old. The fuck he
was. Okay. He was a hundred years old.
He just died when he was 17 he became a
vampire. That's a Goddam pedophile movie.
Wow.
The change. 17 years old. You should check
your privilege lady and her privilege.
But I did.
I didn't.
I need a jazz hands it, but it's hard to
do that for audio. Most of our audiences,
audio only.
Oh, really? Massive trauma. They
don't see my ticks. Great. No, no,
but I don't worry about it. My hair too
much in it. It's not a bad thing. Ah.
I've had fired head constantly.
I'd throw it on my shoulders.
I flip it. Don't you hate
some, I'm seeing yourself.
I'm so used to it. Oh, you're used to it.
So I wa I've watched some lectures and
I have ticks and I sh I don't know what
to do and I thought, oh, but my age,
I'm not going to go change. So yeah.
I mean you learned a lot
about what's annoying to you.
Like a lot of people do things
that are annoying to other people.
They don't know it.
You learn a lot about like speech ticks.
We were just talking about that in the
last podcast we did though the expression
like,
like people say like all the time,
like there's like a thing
like that you do like,
just like a sophisticated version of, um,
and there's another one. I'm lecturing,
I do a lot of ums. That's
normal. It's your, it's your
thinking, you know, and we,
we sort of accept.
That's why it's so impressive when you
meet a guy like Sam Harris that can get
through hours long conversation with
no preparation whatsoever and never
[inaudible] and speaking
perfect pair. Perfect. Yeah.
I don't know how the fuck he does it.
Yeah.
Did you ever hear Christopher
Hitchens? No. No, I ever had a chance.
I would loved to get drunk with
that guy over there. I know Lowe's,
it didn't say anything
stupid and him eviscerate me.
I remember him with most deaf,
he was on a real time with Bill
Maher with most DEF, most def,
didn't know what the fuck
he was talking about.
He was still who I love as a rapper.
I think he's an Austin musician,
but he was talking about the difference
between that Taliban and al Qaeda and he
didn't understand the
difference between two and
Hitchens just lit him up.
He was drunk.
He got a couple of drinks in him
and he just decided like this is,
this is the problem.
These people with opinions that have
never bothered to research exactly what
they're talking about
and he just lit him up.
Yeah,
he,
you do not want to be taken down by
someone like Christopher Hitchens. Yeah,
he was. He was very funny and
provocative and a lot of ways too.
He wrote that a vanity fair piece,
which is very funny about women not being
funny. You know why women are funny,
which of course is not
really true. There's a lot of
women that are really funny,
but he was pointing the fact that women
that are funny or kind of like their
butchy and almost like a
masculine sort of a way.
Yeah.
He's not really right about that,
but he's not right about that because
Sarah Silvermans one of the funniest
people on the planet and she's very
feminine. She's not butchy at all. Yeah.
But even going back people to, do you
remember? Do you remember Madeline Kahn?
Sure, sure. It's so funny.
[inaudible] was fabulous and you know,
and be Joan Rivers. I mean,
look, Joan Rivers is one of
the best all time comedian.
She was miss her. Yes, but
she was going on a campus.
You'd be so great. Yes. Well she was
back then even she was talking about it.
I mean, when she was alive, she was,
she was talking about how ridiculous it
is that these kids are fucking babies.
You know, she would be, and, and young
women need to see people like her. I mean,
she's, she was funny and she was
smart. She was fast. And Yeah,
there's a lot of young up
and coming comedians right
now too that are women that
are really hilarious, that are very
feminine. It's, you don't have to be,
and then they should be one thing.
They should, they can be feminine,
but they shouldn't be politically correct.
It would be terrible if we had a group
of feminists that did that to actually
practicing comedians that within
start policing. I don't see that.
But it has happened in other professions.
Well, there are some male feminists
comedians and they're fucking Baroud. Oh,
Ooh.
The brutal,
it's like are they listened to it and
going to have small groups of people that
subscribe to their ideas and you know,
they're happy to join in.
They think they're great and they're
being forced by the echo chamber.
But you know, they're just,
they're saying nonsense.
But I would think comedians like,
and like the atheist, these are,
these are skeptics there.
People who thought through for them,
you would think that they
would not be vulnerable to um,
sort of a political hijacking by a group
that believes a lot of things that are
demonstrably false and yet they
were vulnerable. They are, I think,
not all of them.
I mean there was a division very divisive,
well, people don't like
being criticized, you know,
and if you're criticized in your,
you're mocked and you're taken
down because of your ideas,
you'll soften those ideas.
You'll bend with the wind.
You get what I'm saying? If it happens
to Comedians, it'll be, it won't happen.
They know it just can't because it's going
to be so tempting for someone to come
in and you just blow it away.
The way we
got to be comedians in the first
place is by resisting all that stuff.
With the real problem becomes when they
become successful and maybe another
arena,
like maybe they become a talk show host
or they have a big important job with a
network on some or something like that.
And they don't want to rock
the boat. Like, you'll know,
it's like a lot of comedians.
They get sitcoms and then the city comes,
you can really popular and they
pretty much stopped performing. They,
they stopped doing standup.
That happened with a lot of them.
Jerry Seinfeld didn't
perform for a long time. Um,
Tim Allen, same thing. You can
get in trouble. You can get like,
I know guys who had sitcoms where there
the network actually told them to not do
stand up.
Just put it aside for awhile.
That was a fuck's his name from uh,
John Stamos Sitcom that Bob Saget.
Bob Saget who has like a really dirty act,
but it was on like a family sitcom.
They look shut him down. Like he
stopped doing standup for a long time.
Well, I wish we had George Carlin
and wish we had more at Saul.
It meant more salt. He's still around.
Yeah. You Miss tweeted at me a couple of,
yeah, he's an him 20 year ago. Yeah.
More cells on Twitter is
still doing some stuff.
A few of those guys that are
still out there, you know,
a Dick Gregory's actually at the comedy
store this Sunday. I think I'm going, man,
I'm going for sure. I mean, while he's
still alive, I want to come see him.
And Dick Gregory is the guy who, I mean,
he's not just a comedian and an activist,
but he actually is the guy
who brought Geraldo Rivera.
This is approved or footage
where he showed it on
television like I think it was
10 years after Kennedy was assassinated
that showed Kennedy's head violently
going back into the left and made people
start to consider the fact that maybe
he was shot by someone other
than Lee Harvey Oswald.
And it's hard all those conspiracy theory.
So you a fascinating kind of a guy.
He is it. My father was a big fan of his
and it lately. And you know, I don't know.
He's, he's taken some odd positions,
but on what Dick Gregory on what?
I don't remember, I just remember
thinking what happened with him. But he,
but people do that and then they
come back also, they get really old.
He just got up, but he could,
sure he's, he was in his
prime. He was so funny. Yeah.
And while he's a very important
guy and it goes back, he's gone.
But yeah, those, that spirit, it's, I'm
sure it's alive. It's the spirit of cars.
A lot of those up. Bill Burrs,
a great guy for that today.
There's a lot of those people out there
that are just, they need to be mocked.
And you know, that's for comedians.
That's fuel. That's like we, we,
we feed on dry wood, you know,
and fire catches dry wood,
comedian invasion of the campuses.
But we're not going to do it.
It's not worth it.
It's like the too many angry people
like would crack one joke and we'll get
angry, you know, quote unquote Hashtag
activists that will attack you for days.
It's not worth it. I'm not
going to go, it's not worth it.
They'll start chanting in the middle of
your show and disrupt your performance.
They think that their sensibilities are
more important than your performance.
It's just, it's nonsense. It's not the
make them go out there and earn a living,
pay bills, get drunk, do stupid
things, get their car towed,
then come to a show,
come to a show.
And you understand reality come to
show when you understand bills and
frustrations and you know, come to a
show when you're an adult right now,
you're a baby that soften some.
I mean you're,
you're a child who's essentially gone
from your house to some sort of a holding
penitentiary till they're,
they're indoctrinating you with all
these wacky ideas and you want to yell at
people.
I Dunno. Is there anything else you want
to add before we wrap this thing up?
We did three hours. Are you serious?
Yeah. Oh my goodness. Flies by crazy.
That's how it goes. It's been fun.
Yeah. It's been great man cave here.
Some people have seen this,
this, it's getting more manly.
That's a recent addition, that mule
deer head. That's a recent one. But uh,
yeah,
it's all stuff that either people have
given me like this little biggie statue
or as Buddha, I dunno. It's just sort of
accumulates or stuff that I've put here.
Yeah. But this is where I'm, I told
you before the show started, I, I,
I have to do this because in
my house I'm a little bitch.
My House has been completely women aside.
Well that's,
I look,
I recognize things is it
my sons or husband might've
brought in and I would have
pushed aside.
I found a place for them in the attic.
I have things like this in the end.
Yeah. Mo, when I shot that elk, it's
out in the hallway. My wife was like,
what are you going to do with
this? I'm like, don't worry.
I'll bring it to the office.
Jesus Christ. Tacos. Tacos.
So listen,
thank you very much for doing this are
really appreciate you flying out here and
thank you for doing that. That video
series. I think it's excellent.
I think it's really important.
It's important for people to see that
you are a kind and thoughtful person who
is just you.
You are expressing yourself because you
feel that there is an unchecked point or
that there is a position that a lot of
people have sort of taken on feminism.
That's not necessarily in line with
how you think the, the, the, the,
the true nature of it was supposed to
be when it was originally established.
Yeah.
And if they show me I'm wrong, I'll
change my point of view. I'm open,
but don't cut off debate.
That's what's happened. So I
had to go on Youtube, I can,
you know, I'm not on the, I mean
I, I will visit the campuses,
but mainly now I'm making videos for the,
maybe the kids younger
than the millennials.
They're going to come along and rebel
against these two people in college.
I think very likely. That's possible. I
think. I think as we were saying before,
that these people that are just learning
how to navigate social media and we're
learning sort of the,
the do's and don'ts,
the etiquette that's involved and
communicating with people online.
And I think the,
the more intelligent,
rational people are realizing we should
communicate with people online the way
you should communicate with them if
they were right there in front of you.
And if we start doing that.
And I also think that this technology
that we're experiencing right now is
really the beginning of some sort of a
much more invasive interfacing between
human beings. Invasive, it
should say instead of invasive,
uh,
it'd be much more comprehensive.
I think we're going to get some sort of
a visual interaction with each other and
maybe even some sort of a sharing of
data where it's not even based on reading
things, but you're actually going to be
able to transmit thoughts to each other.
They've already figured out a way to
transmit minds and there could be merging
it. Oh my goodness, what are we
going to have? And I wish I could,
I would like to live to be 500 or a
thousand just to see what happens.
You might live to be 500 when you
look at what science is doing today,
I think I'll be, I think I'm just
going to make that darn well.
If you do miss it, I think
what you're doing, like I said,
it's very important and you think you're
opening up a lot of people's eyes and
you're also,
you're a great spokesperson for it because
you're balanced and rational and it's
easy to accept your nice person.
So what you're saying.
So coming from your point of view,
it's like, I don't know, one,
you're not grading on people.
It's, it's nice. It's beautiful.
So I want to thank you.
Thank you very much for your series
and thank you for doing this.
And if you ever have anything you need
promoted, please just let us know.
I'll be happy to, happy to get
it out there for you. Okay,
Christina Summer's ladies and
gentlemen, that's it. Show's over.
Goodnight.
Bye for the kiss.
Hmm.