Yes, we live Ben Shapiro. Hey,
how's it going dude? Very good.
How's it going with you man?
It's going well. I love you.
I love the new day cause they haven't
been here since you finished it over and I
had walked in, I thought to myself,
I've been doing my business wrong.
I mean you got what?
Three employees? Yeah.
There's not that many folks working
on this. Yeah, I mean, yeah.
So in my offices we have like 80 and
our offices are not nearly this cool.
So I'm going to go back to
my office and fire everyone.
Have your folks come in and design?
Because I mean it's either a lot of
people or I could have cars in my office.
Yeah, but you wouldn't go
down this route. You're,
you're a more of a conservative
gentleman. No, myself.
[inaudible] you're wearing a suit jacket.
You're your own boss.
Nobody tells you how to dress and
get you dressed like a grownup.
Yeah. Well, you know, I won't pretend
that nobody tells me how to dress.
We have people who tell me how to dress.
We have people who do my hair.
Do you have all that stuff you have
like fashion folks? Because I used to,
I mean if you look at the old photos
of me, I have like the Hitler hair,
I've got like the, the hair,
that's the only thing about me,
the till area and was my
old hair and I've got that,
the hair that kind of comes down over
the forehead and I still walk into the
office wearing basically an undershirt
every day because I'm incredibly lazy
when it comes to that stuff. But we
to be able to, yeah, I mean that's,
that's the prerogative of being the boss.
Maybe it'd be more relatable live you
showed up wearing like flip flops and tee
shirt. That kind of kills my brand
though. Now does it like it is your brand.
Exactly.
I thought it was being an asshole.
I think you're an asshole though. Thank
you. I appreciate it. It revert. Nice guy.
You're just conservative. That's the
dirty little secret though. Yeah.
We're not supposed to.
We're not supposed to talk about that.
But this is one of the things that
bothers me so much about you being so
misrepresented. When I read things
about you, there was a, the,
the article that we
were just talking about,
the alt right seeds without the rage,
they called you and you're not
even remotely alt right. In fact,
you were the leading target of
antisemetic abuse for all of 2016 are you?
Yeah, according to the Anti Defamation
League, which is no ally of mine. So yeah,
I mean,
I'm not only am I not outright,
I've spent the last four years like
legitimately battling the alt right,
talking about how evil,
I think their ideology is,
how evil I think white supremacy
he is. I mean, first of all,
like people at the Amika is typically
not the favorites of the alt right.
And then beyond that,
I mean,
I think their ideology is legitimately
a devastatingly awful twist on what
Western civilization is supposed to be.
It was amazing as a review of my new
book and my new book has several sections
and they're dedicated to how
terrible the outright is.
And then the interview they did with me.
It doesn't talk about
outright stuff at all,
but they just assume
I'm on the conservative.
Right and that must mean that I am all
outright and it's like no you stupid.
No problem with those labels,
disingenuous
people are labeling people in a very
simple manner to try to categorize them as
the enemy and instead of just addressing
these points like I love watching your
debates where you do Q and A's with
college students and with people in the
audience because you can see, you will
agree with you or disagree with you.
You have well formulated ideas.
This isn't just some bullshit
that you're spouting out.
You thought these things through.
I've been doing this for
legitimately more than half my life.
I'm 35 and I started when I was 17 and
I started writing a syndicated column at
that point and when you're 17 you think
a lot of dumb stuff and then sure we get
older and you educate yourself and you
spend a lot of time reading and a lot of
time studying.
Hopefully you have some cogent arguments
after 20 years of doing anything.
I mean, but it's the, the demonization
is pretty astonishing. I mean,
we had an on Andrew Yang,
he's the only Democratic candidate who
has agreed to go on the Sunday special
that I do. We did a full hour
on ubi. It was perfectly nice.
It was perfectly coherent
and, and, and conciliatory.
And yet people will suggest
that everything I do is
about destroying people on
the other side because of all the Ben
Shapiro destroys videos and all that kind
of stuff.
Yeah.
There's, there are certain groups of
people where that's their shtick there.
Like they're goons, right? They just go
after people online for attention. Yes.
This is a stick. This is not you.
And this is what bothers me so much.
And I know that you've said some things
in the past like particularly about
Arabs and like when you were
a younger man that you said,
I shouldn't have said that. Yeah, that's
exactly right. That's exactly right.
Some of those things were taken out of
context. Like that one particular tweet,
which is a bad tweet,
was a tweet that was part of a tweet
thread in which has specifically
contracting Israel and the Hamas
leadership and saying that the Israeli
government likes to build and the
Hamas leadership lid prefer that their
citizens live in sewage and bomb things.
But that was a bad tweet obviously. Yeah.
My entire history on on
Muslim relations is one,
like I supported the ability of Ilhan
Omar to wear hijab on the, on the floor.
I opposed. President Trump's
originally proposed Muslim ban, uh,
in the last three weeks I've had on
machine Nawaz I've had on a contact med I
had on yesterday,
a reformed Muslim.
Like these are conversations
that have to be had, but to take,
this is one of the things
that bugs me so much. I've,
I've tweeted I think 140,000 times
I've written millions of words.
I'm sure you can find something. I don't
even remember having written it is bad.
I have a running list, by the way.
I tried to be honest about this. I,
I'm one of the only people I know who has,
I have a running list it's called.
So here's a giant list of all the
dumbest stuff I've ever done. Right?
And I actually go through all this,
like you can look it up.
This is not me saying this now.
I mean,
you can go and look up all the
things that I think I've done wrong.
And I'll apologize for some,
and I'll say somewhere dom,
and I'll say some I'm fine with,
and you're just taking out of context.
But I mean, I hope that's when
honest people tried to do,
but does, this is the problem. You're
not dealing with honest people would,
when people try to categorize
you as outright or they're,
they're trying to put you into this
category of Internet goon there, they,
and they did quote tweet.
There's taking some little tiny phrase
that you said seven years ago and trying
to say, this is you.
This is, you know, it's,
so that's such a disingenuous thing to do.
I hate it. And I hated across
the aisle, by the way, like that.
I was a defender of James Gunn.
I thought James Gunn shouldn't have
been fired from guardians of the galaxy.
Yeah. Over the old dumb jokes. Right.
And that's exactly right. Yeah.
And even if somebody tweeted
something bad like 10 years ago,
bringing it up now is not an to
actually make the public space better.
And you're not actually offended by that
thing that person tweeted 10 years ago
that you didn't notice what it is that
you want to get rid of this person or
hurt this person.
So you're going to bring up something
from 10 years ago and then you're going to
try and club them into submission with it.
Because if you actually ask
them their opinion about it,
they might have a more nuanced
view on what they said.
Maybe they apologize and
they maybe they think,
I don't even remember saying that.
I, I felt the same way by the way.
I try to be consistent. I really
do. About about this stuff.
I said the same thing about,
for example, Ralph Northam,
the governor of Virginia who was
excoriated for having this terrible racist
photo on his yearbook page back in medical
school in 1987 and people were saying,
well, this is evidence he's
racist now. It's like, well no,
that's evidence that he was doing it
racist thing then that's not evidence that
he's racist now.
You sort of have to look over the broad
course of his career and he ended up
doing what everyone now does,
which is you just don't
apologize for anything.
You just try to pass it off as nothing.
The public space is actually getting
worse because let's say that you did
something bad in the past.
There are a few human responses to,
I did something I don't like him
past human response number one is,
you know what? I apologize.
That was wrong these days.
That gets your face step done, right? You
say, I apologize, I was wrong. It means,
well, why did you do it in the first
place because you're a bad person.
Apologies are not accepted. And then
number two is you braise in it out.
You do the Trump. You know, I
never did anything wrong, ever.
I've never perfect right and that,
and then you get your defenders to come
and surround you and then nothing ever
gets cleansed or opportunity. Number
three is you do what Barack Obama did,
which is you come out preemptively and
you try to remember all the bad stuff you
do and then you confess it in public. So
in dreams from my father, he says, right,
well you know when I was back in high
school did a little blow. Everyone's like,
oh, okay, so he did cocaine when he was
in high school. That's, that's cool.
Whereas if it comes out during the
campaign and he's known, right,
then he's got and he's got a real problem.
The problem is that right now,
even if you preemptively come out
and say, I did something wrong. Like,
for example,
Liam Neeson talking about years ago when
he had a racist thought that he didn't
act on when he had a racist thought,
this is now we're going to try and ruin
your career for something that you admit
was bad that you did 30 years ago.
We're going to try and run you over that.
If you apologize for something
that you did 30 years ago,
which you would have preferred,
just got forgotten because it
was embarrassing and stupid,
then we say you're bad.
And so all you're left with is like the
most shameless people in the world who
are in the public space,
right? The incentive structure
is to be deeply shameless,
to just say, yeah, man, I own that.
And it was great when I said it,
or I didn't say it at all. And
you're just, you're just full of it.
I never said that stuff. Oh, who are
you going to believe your eyes were me?
And it makes,
it makes for a really bad politics.
Well, it's just this, uh, the culture of,
of going after people for things and
finding any thing to categorize them as
someone who's a viable target. And this
is what I've seen. Thrust your way.
It's like there's nothing
wrong with being conservative.
There's something wrong with
wanting everyone to think
the way you think though.
This is the difference.
Like you w w what I liked that
you do is you debate your points,
you state your positions,
you have a philosophy.
And what I don't like is when people try
to pretend that that philosophy is some
somewhat somehow hateful or somehow
regressive or some like your,
that you condemn people for their
thoughts. You, you just, you don't,
this is what I,
not what I see with you.
I appreciate that and I appreciate the
accuracy because I think that's true.
I mean, I've come out against
virtually every Twitter band,
including people who have
personally targeted me.
I've come out against that have
come out against virtually every,
what would they talk about that?
Because what are you,
what are your thoughts about this
idea of d platforming and you know,
this is something that we were just
discussing before the podcast, um,
where the CEO of Youtube and
it's Kara Swisher's from code,
I think Kara Swisher.
They were talking about removing you
from Youtube and I thought it was the CEO
of Youtube. It was actually Kara
who said I would, if I could.
Yeah, she was pissed because
her son apparently listens
to, that's kind of funny.
Yeah.
If she's being funny saying, but it was,
I thought it was the CEO of [inaudible].
She was trying to much more disturbed.
She was trying to do the same thing that
they do with you or with Dave Rubin or
Jordan Peterson,
which is that anybody who
is sort of heterodox because
in that group I think I'm
the only registered Republican.
Every anybody who's Heterodox
is now being mixed portrayed.
Is it docs meaning just thinks
differently from kind of the down the line
Democratic Party platform.
You're not like down the line with
Hillary like Sam Harris who's a democrat.
Sam Harris's Heterodox because he
disagrees that Islam is by necessity a
religion of peace, for example.
Right? Or he thinks that we have to
look@actualstatisticsinordertomakeevidentiarybasepointsaboutdiscriminationanddisparityandthismakeshimanenemyofpeoplelikeezrakleinatvox.com
right.
Th th this sort of stuff,
they then say that you are a feed or
for white supremacy, right? They, they,
they can't actually get you
on what you say. Yeah. So it
turns into, well, you know,
some members of your audience do things
that, that are really bad. It's like,
well dude, I have like millions of
people who are members of my audience.
I have 5 million Facebook followers.
I have 2 million on Twitter and
you're way bigger than I am.
I assume that some of those
people are going to be crazy.
I mean, yeah, I would assume.
Yeah. The idea that your respect,
well this is what youtube tried to do.
You know about the comment thing where
the youtube was going to try to make
people responsible for the
comments and their videos, which,
what does a normal Jamie,
like a normal video that we get,
how many comments does it get?
I don't know,
like 10,000.
It's like an average one.
How the fuck
am I supposed to have some dude with
his itchy trigger fingers standing by in
front of a keyboard just waiting
for something offensive to pop up.
And this was in response to something
that happened with them where there was
pedophiles who were watching videos
of children doing things and they were
commenting stuff in the children's
gymnastics and stuff like that.
They're commenting and like communicating
with each other through the comments.
And it was sort of, um,
discovered that there was this,
this connection that they
were doing this in many,
many videos and youtube rightly
panicked and like, Holy Shit,
we have to stop this.
So the response I guess was we just have
to make people responsible for their,
someone said,
oh yeah,
good idea.
But you didn't think through it all right
that certain people that can't do that,
it's totally insane and it's insane. And
in virtually every respect. And it's,
it's funny how it's only applied kind of
by the media on one side of the aisle.
So to take an example,
the congressional baseball shooting
happens a couple of years ago.
Guy Happens to be a Bernie Fan, is
that Bernie Sanders is fault. No,
that is not Bernie Sanders
as well, in a way. Right?
Literally people stop talking about it.
And, and that was shooting of legislators,
like elected people. One nearly
died and that kind of went away.
We didn't talk about, you
know, Bernie's responsibility,
but there's a shooting in Christchurch
and it's Jordan Peterson's fall and
Jordan Peterson has no relationship with
the shooter whatsoever. It's my fault.
I have no relationship with the shooter
and denounce everything that that piece
of crap stands for. And
suddenly it's, it, it's,
it's really ugly and it's going to,
it, it will come home to roost. I mean,
here's what's going to happen is Facebook
and youtube are going to fall prey to
their own standards because if their
standard is that you're responsible for
your followers or I'm responsible for
my followers or Jordan or anybody else's
responsible for all the people
who view their stuff, okay,
then why isn't Facebook responsible for
all the people posting on its platform?
If they are right,
if Facebook becomes responsible for
all the people posting on his platform,
they'll be bankrupt and a
week they've got a problem.
They really do because they have to
decide whether they are our platform or
whether they are a do gooder publication.
I run A,
I run a a publication daily wire.
It's openly conservative.
We make no bones about that and we are
responsible for the content that appears
on our platform and if we say
something defamatory, we will be sued.
If we say something that is false,
then we will be sued.
Presumably if you post something false
on Facebook, Facebook doesn't get sued,
but now Facebook has deemed
itself the morality police,
no band people they don't like and they'll
decide what editorially ought to be
elevated and what ought
not to be elevated.
Does that sound more like
the phone company to you or
does that sound more like
my website where I decide what gets
published and what doesn't? Right.
Because Facebook's case for
exemption from these laws is,
well we're like the phone company, right
when you're on the phone with somebody,
if that person says something criminal
t and t isn't responsible for the person
saying something criminal or terrible,
it's just the phone company.
But Facebook isn't doing that.
Facebook has is jumping into the middle
of conversations and then saying,
well we don't really like
this conversation so we're
just going to kind of shut
it down. Not because of legal threat,
but because we just don't like it.
So are they actually doing that?
I'll say if you put a post up on Facebook
and they don't like the way you word
things or describe things with,
they actually shut down your post.
Where what will they do so
they've done it in the past.
To some conservative public is pretty
controversial because they're not
transparent at all.
I can tell you that the beginning of
2018 we lost about 35% of our traffic
because Facebook started cracking
down on mostly conservative sites.
They said that it was kind
of new sites generally,
but that's not what the statistics showed.
They're doing it more often with things
that we all sort of agree are bad, right?
We all agree white supremacy is bad.
White nationalism is bad.
Now they say they're going
to censor that stuff,
but here's where I'm uncomfortable.
I think that that stuff is awful and evil
and those people are, the ones are the,
they're the reason I
have personal security,
but once you get into the business of
Facebook gets to decide which speech is
good and which speeches bad.
They're an editor there, an editor.
Even if I agree with their assessment
of what stuff is good and what is bad,
I am not comfortable with them
in the driver's seat there.
And if they are going to
be in the driver's seat,
then they should be held liable for
all the stuff that's on their platform.
I mean, why isn't the Twitter,
Twitter, same thing, right?
Why is it that Louis Farrakhan is still
on that platform but Alex Jones is not
like, I don't like Alex Jones
is material or I've been very,
very critical of Alex Jones.
I didn't think you should get banned
from Twitter unless he actually violated
the law in, unless he was
responsible for a violent threat,
unless he was defamatory or something.
They're definitely going down this
road of being the moral arbitrators.
They're,
they're the ones who get to decide what
the conversations are and h and that's
an insane responsibility.
The responsibility of getting to dictate
what should and should not be discussed
and to have it to be a handful of people
and have these people almost almost
exclusively live in the Pacific and you
know in north of San Francisco that that
whole tech community,
I mean it's all tech liberals who really,
if you're around those people,
they live in this really strange Uber
wealthy bubble of super genius spectrum
people who are coders and
super capitalists and people
that are raising money
all over the place and
designing technology and they
have an ideology and it's
not necessarily a bad one just just being
honest and upfront about what it is.
It's incredibly progressive, which is
very unusual for big business, right?
For big business to be just openly,
transparently progressive and pushing
social justice. It's very unusual.
Well I think that there is a sort of
misunderstanding of when we say what big
business is,
what big businesses.
So I think that there's a wide variety
of owners of businesses and how they
think about politics obviously. Yeah.
Bill Gates is a Progressive Guy,
Warren Buffet's progressive guy.
They are now
his whole life.
And he's ruthless with Microsoft.
Well, so I think that there
are a lot of people, listen,
I think that that the vast majority,
I think mark Zuckerberg is ruthless
with Facebook and used progressive.
I think Jack Dorsey is as ruthless as
the next guy when it comes to profit.
I mean, he's still got to be answerable
to the shareholders. So I think,
I think a lot of the
progressivism is sort of a,
a way to excuse your own in your own
involvement in the capitalist market.
Facebook took off. Don't be evil.
That was their thing. Don't be evil.
They decided to remove that. Let's
Google, right? I'm sorry Google. Yeah,
when Google did that, I met Google. But
just funny when you think something,
but you're saying, um, when they did that,
it's like, why would you ever take off?
Don't be evil like cheap that,
but here's the thing.
Here's my thing. I think that if
our tech companies were honest,
they should take that stuff off.
Like stop pretending you're do Gooding.
You're not do good and you're providing
a platform and maybe the platform is the
good, right? In a capitalist economy,
the product that you provide is the good,
I don't need additional good to
come from your product, right?
If you want to provide me a
solid morning drink, right?
I don't need your politics. Along with
that, I just need the drink. Okay,
well if I want a social media company,
I don't give two craps about what
Mark Zuckerberg thinks about politics.
Dude hasn't studied it. I don't
care at all. What Jack Dorsey,
who vacations in Malaysia and gets
bitten by a million mosquitoes while
meditating. [inaudible] has to say
about the nature of life. Like what?
Why do I care about Jack Dorsey's
political view? He has provided me a good,
the good is this basic chat
room where I'm consuming news.
How about that would just be enough,
but it's not enough for a lot
of these folks. It's, it's the,
the kind of Hooli from Silicon Valley.
We're going to pretend that we're here
to do good and it's not enough just to
acknowledge that maybe the thing
that you provided is the good,
like Bill Gates has done more good with
Microsoft and then he has done with any
of his charities.
He's even a lot of money to charity,
but Microsoft has provided legitimately
hundreds of thousands of jobs and
created enormously productive lines of
business and made enormous profit for a
lot of people. A lot of people have
stock in Microsoft as a general,
as a basic factual thing.
He has done more good doing that.
Then giving tens of millions of
dollars to, to various outside causes.
So it feels like a lot of
the progressivism in in
corporate halls and in Silicon
Valley is bifurcated mentally. It's like
people have it, they're like dolphins,
just one side of the brain on at a time.
Here's my,
here's my capitalist side where
I got and make money and profit.
And then here's my other side where I
show people what a great person I am by
proclaiming that I'm for Bernie Sanders
while parking my money off shore to make
sure that they're, it's shielded
from that, from the tax man.
Yeah. Well that's a good assessment. Um,
what I'm saying is that
the don't be evil thing.
Like one of the things that I thought was
what if that was like a legal decision
was me being cynical, that
they were pulled into some
sort of an office and said,
um,
if we say don't be evil and you
take someone off the platform,
you're accusing them of evil.
That's it. I mean, then we
should slow that down. Maybe,
I mean, again, this, this,
this self assessment of you are the
moral police I find really troubling it.
It's so funny. I'm the, I'm the suppose
in more or less, right? Right. I'm,
I'm the religious guy. I'm
in the Orthodox Jew, right?
I talk about social standards and how
people should behave in their personal
life.
But when it comes to government and when
it comes to me imposing my views on you,
I am way less of a top down higher rent
than any of the people in Silicon Valley.
I am not here to tell you that you are
not allowed to be on a platform because
we disagree. It's one thing if
you're threatening violence,
which is an actual violation of law,
but this crap where people like me because
I believe in a social fabric built,
uncertain, Judeo Christian values. But
I'm not forcing you to be part of that.
And I'm not. I don't think the government
should compel you to be a part of that,
or I'm the tyrant.
But the person who sits at the top of
Twitter or Facebook who is saying that
they get to police what you see and
they're going to nudge you in the right
direction, nudge you in the right
direction without your consent,
without them even telling them what
you're doing right. They, they're just,
they're gonna push you a little bit
because they know better than you and they
can sort of massage you in a better
views if we control your channels of
information. This is the Obama
administration was very fond of,
there's a scholar in cass Sunstein as a
legal scholar and he wrote a book called
nudge. He was very famous. It was,
it was used to sort of a handbook during
the Obama administration and the idea
as well,
if we can just use a non forcible means
to sort of nudge people in a particular
direction without them even
knowing they're being nudged,
then shouldn't we do that? And I think,
no, you shouldn't. You shouldn't.
Because transparency is the only way I
can tell what kind of bullshit you're
trying to sell me.
Well, not just dot. Like you, you're,
you're closing down even conversation.
If soon as you trying to silence
this other voice, if you,
if you believe one thing
and another person belief at
different thing you should
probably talk about and the way,
the way that I know for sure there's
something wrong with your argument is if
what you're trying to do is you're
sneakily trying to silence these voices.
And again,
as long as we're not talking about threats
of violence and as long as we're not
talking about harassment or doxing, right,
we're just talking about conversation.
You're just talking about people
with differing points of view.
If you want to silence
differing points of view,
I have to wonder about your intent.
I have to wonder about whether you're
going into this conversation with good
faith.
I have to wonder whether you've really
objectively assessed whether or not you,
your argument does hold up against
scrutiny because this is also part of the
problem and when you're in an echo
chamber you often don't formulate these
arguments very well.
Like when you confront people
about certain bias beliefs
that they have and you,
you have a an opposing belief.
If they're part of a bubble,
like sometimes they might not have even
ever considered some of the things you
have to say. And I've seen
that with some of your videos.
Yeah,
I mean it does happen all the time and
with sophisticated people where I'd spent
my entire life,
literally my entire life in areas
where everyone disagrees with me. Yeah.
I grew up in La. I went to Harvard
law school for three years.
I was in Cambridge where
everyone disagreed with me
and then I came back to la.
So I have never spent more than
a week at a time in a red state.
Right.
Whoever is you have your conservative
values moved in one way or another of the,
I mean,
I should say that at all.
My personal valley's probably
haven't shifted very much,
but my political values have
shifted. Libertarian. Mm. I mean,
so I used to be a proponent
of criminalization of
marijuana. I'm no longer,
I've been in favorites for you.
A couple of things.
One was just a general sense
of the government sucks
at everything and the more
I see the government tried
to crack down on things,
the more prevalent it becomes.
I mean,
people were dealing pot
now on my sixth grade,
seventh grade playground in public school.
So obviously like mellow. Yeah, exactly.
And then it's terrible. Just a
general, a general perception.
Not only the government
sucks at everything,
but that you got to own your own actions
and also examining more of the evidence
about the impact of, of pot on
people's lives. And, and you know,
again,
there's you ruining your own life through
use of drugs and there's drugs that
legitimately ruined other
people's lives right there.
There are drugs that remove your
ability to even reason or thing.
I think there are only two reasons
to criminalize drugs in any fashion.
One is if there are
drugs like for example,
PCP that legitimately make you violent,
uh,
and then you are going out and committing
acts of violence against people,
then there's the case.
Uh,
or if you're talking about a drug
where it legitimately robs you of your
capacity to reason.
If it were a heroin,
if you were able to actually crack down
on it successfully. But even there,
I'm not sure that the proper government
solution is criminalization because
we've criminalized it and it's
still incredibly prevalent.
So it's agree with you.
I agree with her on that.
And I agree with you in terms of
drugs being extremely detrimental.
And the other part is that there's
comparable drugs that are illegal and
comparable drugs,
meaning not even really comparable
drugs that are far more devastating like
alcohol.
Like you,
you could just go to any grocery store
and buy a jug of whisky and kill yourself
with it.
It's not difficult.
And just drink the books already that
prevent externalities. If you drive high,
it's the same as driving drunk.
So I'm not sure that you need additional
laws to do that. And also, you know,
I'm not opposed to zoning laws.
Like I don't think a pot shop should open
up right next to my house right there.
Residential Zoning. That's fine. Sand
with liquor stores though, right?
I don't want to liquor store right next
to my house. This is correct. Right.
So the, so I become a libertarian
in some ways on that sort of stuff.
At the same thing is true by the way,
when it comes to the issue of same sex
marriage. So on a personal moral level,
I'm opposed to same sex marriage.
I'm an Orthodox Jew and I believe that
a man and a woman were made for each
other when it comes to
government involvement.
I don't think that's anybody's business.
I think a lot of things,
I think adults raise bad too.
I don't think the government ought
to be involved in adultery. I, I'm,
I'm so strict. I don't think premarital
sex is a good thing, right. I,
I've been very vocal about this.
I was a virgin until I was married.
My wife was a virgin until she was
married. I think that's a good thing.
So I think the government has anything
to do with any of those things. No,
I don't. I don't think it's any
of the government's business.
It's consensual activity.
There are no externalities.
So what exactly is the
government getting involved in?
And when the government gets involved
in stuff, then there are externalities.
Right? Once the government starts
to cram down its vision on people,
then you start to get unintended
externality. So for example, with the law,
with the legalization,
my view on marriage is that the government
should get completely out of the
business. I don't think the government
should be involved in straight marriage.
I don't think it should be
involved in gay marriage.
I think the government should be out.
I agree 100% and the reason that I say
that is because as a religious person,
right? Who believes in
traditional marriage, I have two,
I have to marriage certificates,
I have the one from the state
that I don't give two craps about.
It's buried somewhere in my garage.
And then I have my religion,
my religious marriage certificate,
which meant among other things that
I got to shut up my wife, right?
I mean like this was the
one that mattered to me.
And I think that's true
for most religious people.
The religious ceremony matters a lot
more than the state saying a thing.
And the state isn't incentivizing.
There's people aren't getting
married because they're like, yeah,
I need the tax break.
So that's a bunch of nonsense.
And once the government decides what
version of marriage and wants to push,
that then comes into conflict
with other values. So for example,
once the state of California decides that
same sex marriage is on legal par with
heterosexual marriage,
now I'm worried about the externality of
I have a religious day school or I have
a, my, my synagogue, my synagogue
is a religious institution.
It doesn't approve of same sex marriage.
Now is the government going to come in
and tell my synagogue how it ought to act
with regard to same sex marriage?
I don't think that's the government's.
So how about
this?
How about everybody gets to do basically
what they want associate with whom they
want and it's none of the government's
business. This seems like a pretty good,
happy medium.
I,
I'm so glad you talked about the two
things that I want to talk to you about
that I'm sure we disagree.
One of them be in marijuana and the
other one being gay people marrying each
other. Um, so let's start
with the marijuana one.
Do you think marijuana ruins
people's lives? Is it's,
is that one of your contentions?
Um,
I think that it can and I think in the
same way I ever had any experience with
marijuana, no, I'm just talking about the,
I'm just talking about the statistical
over use of marijuana among teenagers
does have detrimental brain effects
that have some long term after effects.
It's pretty proven and that's
one of the things that I really,
I'm glad you said that because I wanted
to cover that when you were in the
middle of a rant,
what we were joking around about
sixth and seventh graders selling pot.
Don't smoke pot when you're young.
You really should,
it's not good for the development of
your brain. Same thing with drinking.
You know, I didn't smoke a
lot of pot when I was a kid.
I did it a handful of times
until I was 30 years old.
But I did drink a bunch of times when
I was young and in high school and it's
terrible for brain development, especially
before you're 25 and your, your,
your funnel cortex hasn't even
fully formed. Your frontal
lobe is like this. It's,
it's,
it's a developing thing there.
There was an article recently
that I posted from BBC.
There were saying that you should
probably shouldn't be considered an adult
until you're 30.
Right?
They're saying brain development
doesn't even stop until you're 26 or 20.
This is why when, when people are saying,
let's, let's lower the voting age 16.
I'm like, what the, what the fuck
are you talking about? When I was 16,
I wish I champ. You know, I mean,
it was a champion of high school.
Now when the problem that I have with
many people's perceptions on marijuana is
that it's based on ignorance, meaning not
no personal experience with, you know,
and listen, I'll admit I have no
personal. I know. I know. You don't.
I'm not speaking. Probably we should get
high. That's what I'm trying to tell you,
man. I seen the effects on stock prices.
When people get hired in the city,
they jump up, man. He jumped
down for a little one,
a bunch of chickens jump off the boat,
then they come right back up. Um,
the marijuana thing is in my opinion,
uh,
it's another one of those
things where people have this,
this categorized box that they
like to put marijuana users in.
Like this is the category. Lazy
Stoner, stupid, delusional.
It's too widespread for that.
I mean there,
there are people I know who
are doctors who, yes, so,
well there's the Jiu Jitsu
community is a big one.
There's a giant percentage of the Jiu
Jitsu community that does Jujitsu high.
They have competition. It's
more a party. It's not man,
I'm telling you that because
it's not what people think it is.
If you've never smoked marijuana,
this is going to be a very
difficult thing to grasp.
But marijuana enhances Jujitsu because
it eliminates the rest of the world.
When you're rolling, which
rolling is like, say if, uh,
you and Jamie were going to have a
sparring match that would be rolling.
Like you'd slap hands and then you'd go
and you try to choke him and he's trying
to get you in an arm bar
and you're going after it.
When you do that on marijuana,
it's like you don't
think of anything else other than those
movements and it becomes like this very
intense meditation and violence.
Like it's not violent in terms of most
of the time you don't really even get
hurt.
He like you get to the point,
one of the beautiful things about Jujitsu
is you can grab a hold of someone and
choked him to the point where they're
going to go to sleep and you would kill
them if you kept going and they tap
around your friends again and everybody's
cool and you try to do it to me and I
tried to do it to you and you really can
do it reasonably hard
without people getting hurt.
And it happens every day,
all throughout the world.
A lot of these people are high and they're
doing this Jujitsu practice in this
all almost like a trends.
It's like it's ascension state.
If you can function when you're using
marijuana, I don't care, but you can.
This is what I'm saying.
Perceptions are off. I mean,
I would assume there's a small subset of
the population for whom that's not true.
Right, who are over using marijuana. Yes,
and that's probably the majority in fact.
Okay, so, so then you know, but it's
exactly the same way with food. I agree.
So I don't think there's
anything we disagree about
here because I'm not talking
about criminalizing marijuana use.
I think that we should honestly discuss
the evidence that for a subset of the
population, there is some evidence that
marijuana is addicting, but it's a subset.
It's not everybody who's on marijuana,
the vast majority of people on
marijuana or not addicted to marijuana.
I think in the same way the alcoholic,
that Minster of alcohol as well it is,
there's people that are going to
be addicted to almost anything.
And I think there's, there's absolutely
people that are addicted to sugar.
This for sure,
people that are addicted to nicotine and
alcohol and all of these things that we
let people have.
The material addictiveness of marijuana
is not comparable to opioids though for
it. It's not even comparable
to alcohol or nicotine.
It's seems to be very rare when people
become physically addicted to it.
Extremely rare.
And what's,
what's common though is abuse and it's
common in everything that human beings
consume. It's a fused as
common as we said with food,
certainly common with alcohol.
It's certainly common with pills.
And this is why I really believe that the
way to solve some of these problems is,
is a social fabric problem.
Like it's a parenting problem.
It's a social fabric problem.
It's a personal choice problem.
That's why virtually every solution I
suggested so funny and I'm constantly
conservatives like me who are libertarian
leaning or constantly accused of being
non-compassionate.
No,
it's just our compassionate solutions
don't involve the use of government.
It's like we're going to encourage people
to make better decisions with their
lives. And if you choose not to do that,
it's a free country. Well, you know,
coming from religious background,
you have this community that reinforces
this kind of behavior in thought.
And I think that's one of the major,
really one of the best benefits of
religion is that moral fabric and that
community, the sense of community. Even
silly ones like Mormons, you know they're,
they're the nicest folks,
right?
They believe something that
is fucking patently insane.
If you go and read the Joseph Smith
texts from 1820 when he was 14 years old,
the shit that he wrote, let me try
not to get into doctrinal insanity.
I wear a funny hat all day Syria.
Just kind of get to that.
But you know, with that said, I mean
Alexis de Tocqueville talks about this,
you know,
early on in the American republic,
the idea is that what makes
America very different is the idea.
You don't need a big government when
you do have a supportive social fabric
where people feel like they're at
least oriented toward a common goal.
It's one of the problems that I think
we have in the country right now.
I'm not sure people are oriented toward
even a common sense of, of conversation.
You don't have to agree on,
on everything in order to have a common
sense of the important values that that
unified the country are
showing. Yes. Right.
And I always use Sam
Harris is sorta my bet. No,
are here because he's obviously
a militant atheist. I'm,
I'm in equally and equally strong believer
and yet when it comes to the things
that we would like to see happen in the
country, not on government policy level,
but on a, let's have a conversation
level and discuss on evidence level,
we're on the same page.
There's certain core assumptions you
have to make in order for that to happen.
In my argument about America and the
West is that those core assumptions are
built on Judeo Christian foundations.
Sam's core argument seems to be that
they're built on evolutionary biology.
We differ a little bit there.
Mm. Um, well, I don't want to
let this marijuana thing go to.
One of the things that I wanted to bring
up too was this idea that if you're
religious person,
don't you think that there's certain
things that maybe God put here for us to
consume,
to change your perspective?
To allow you to reach new
levels of consciousness.
Don't you think it's entirely possible
that some of these things that are here,
and I know you haven't experienced,
but they might literally have been put
there by God and there's some evidence to
say that a lot of the texts from
the Bible, that in particular,
there was a,
I think it was a university of Tel
Aviv somewhere in in Jerusalem,
or these scholars were,
they were trying to decipher what it
meant when Moses encountered the burning
Bush. Right, and they believe that
it may have been the Acacia tree,
which is very rich and dimethyltryptamine,
which is a psychedelic substance that
actually that the brain produces.
It's very common in plants and they think
that this might have been when he met
God and the God was a burning Bush,
that this might have been some crew
translation of them being involved in some
sort of a psychedelic experience.
Now it sounds outlandish unless you've
had that psychedelic experience and when
you have, you very well could think that
you were in a conversation with God.
This is on earth and this is something
that may very well have been lost
information or this may very well have
been rituals that people participated in
to bring them closer together and to
reinforce that sense of community that you
do get from a church and you do get
from a group of people that share more
beliefs and values and there's,
there's real good discussion that a lot
of these experiences that became these
religious doctrines came from
psychedelic experiences. Now,
as someone who's never
experienced that before,
I know this is probably a very strange
thing to try to even wrap your head
around. It's, it is entirely
alien until you experience it,
but it might very well be religious.
I mean I've, I've heard that
from other people who've been,
who've used those kinds of drag me.
See,
I'm actually made this argument to me
too about the use of psychedelics and any
maybe mean. Dot. Again, I apples.
Well. Okay, so then this argument,
I will say I'm not super fond of the
argument that God made something and
therefor it's ours to use or be.
I mean like I keep kosher, right?
Like God made pigs, I
don't need him. Right?
So I am not a huge fan of the argument
that because something is here or because
in urges natural,
therefore we ought to imbibe or
therefore we ought to participate in a
particular activity. You know, one of the
things that I, that I'm very big on, I'm,
I'm a, I'm a rationalist
when it comes to religion,
as much as you can be a rationalist
with regard to religion,
to the extent that I think that it's up
to us to use our reasonable faculties to
determine the proper use of things. So,
which is why you shouldn't overuse drugs.
Even if you're going to use drugs,
this is prior to the problem making
things illegal. You make things illegal,
then you really don't know what it is
or how it affects the body or what's the
right dose or the wrong dose.
And then people get involved in these
terrible situations where they're taking
things.
They're just guessing.
I mean there's truth to that,
but it's also true that on a social level,
I'm not talking about legal cause
we totally agree on the legal level,
on the social level, there's a couple
of things that are true of, for example,
the Orthodox Jewish community,
low rates of addiction because
people have that social fabric.
They don't feel the necessity.
Also, you know, as you say,
substance use in moderation can
actually be quite a good thing.
So low rates of alcoholism
in the Jewish community.
And part of that is the fact that you
are getting kiddish wine from the time
you're a kid. Right? I mean you
actually are our de-stigmatize. Yeah.
It's de stigmatized. And the idea
is that in its proper context,
this could be a good thing.
Right? Uh, so I'll admit,
I don't know enough about the proper
context of marijuana to know when it would
be a quote unquote good thing.
And so can and also be a good thing.
This is what I'm trying to do. So
and also I'm, you know, I don't,
the truth is I don't enjoy drinking.
Right. I'm not, I'm not a drinker.
I don't enjoy.
I like reality.
I like living in reality
and I like experiencing it
totally sober so I've never
really felt the urge to to do any
of that stuff. I I hear the pitch,
I hear the pitch, but I've never really
felt the interior desire or need to.
Did you completely understand that?
I think that what we're dealing
with though is perceptions
that have been molded
by laws that were shaped by tyrants.
That's what I think.
I mean again that's totally
possible and plausible. Yeah, and
historically accurate.
I mean when it comes to prohibition,
prohibition with alcohol didn't work.
Plug prohibition with drugs is just
making the cartels bigger and it's causing
no problems with organized crime.
On a practical level, I agree.
Whether you liked runs
or don't like drugs,
government interventionism
is generally a giant fail.
I think our perceptions of what is good
for you and is bad for you is also based
on laws that the government
created ignorantly,
these sweeping psychedelic act of 1970,
which made virtually everything
psychedelic. They could,
they missed a few things,
slipped through the cracks, but all of
the tryptamines and or most of them, um,
the silicide been LSD.
All that stuff was made completely
illegal by people really didn't even know
what it was.
And a lot of that is why we base our
ideas of what's good or bad for you.
It's,
it's based on what is legal and what
well, I'll let other people have
done with it on, on this area,
I'll admit not only complete experiential
ignorance but complete evidentiary
ignorant.
So I haven't examined the evidence.
I really don't have strong
opinions on any of this stuff.
It's one of the bridges that we all
could use between conservative thought in
liberal thought that particularly
for people that are dying,
it's one of the things that
Johns Hopkins found. And, uh,
so there's been other studies done and
there has been therapy done on people
that are dying of terminal diseases and
they give them silicide [inaudible] and
when they give them these mushroom trips,
they have these beautiful experiences
where they completely accept death and
it's almost a universal
reaction to it that like the,
the amount of people who still experience
a positive benefit months and months
after the experience while they're dying,
that they,
they say this was an incredibly moving
and powerful moment in my life that
allowed me to accept the fact that
my time here is done. [inaudible]
I mean, listen, if, if
that's something that,
that works for people and
that's what it's designed to do,
then I don't know if it's designed well,
he didn't do it. It was designed by God.
It literally mine that that's fine.
I mean,
I think there's also the generalized
religious counter argument that there are
no shortcuts, no shortcuts
to happiness. So let's it,
let's pose a shortcut. I don't think,
well, that's the question, right?
I mean like let's say that
I could guarantee you that
tomorrow you're going to
be a happier person. All you have
to do is take this regimen of,
of drugs that you're going to take every
day and it's gonna make you a happier
person,
a more well rounded person,
but it's going to permanently
change your brain chemistry.
Is that something that you think is good
or is it something you think is bad?
Because from a religious perspective,
there is an argument to
be made that these are,
this is work you need to do on yourself
without outside aid if possible.
If there's cases where he cannot,
then you cannot. But yeah, you know,
turns an interesting thought experiment.
Terence Mckenna had a line about that. Uh,
he said that, uh, there was a joke about,
uh, there was a monk and he met Buddha
because Buddha came to town and he said,
Buddha, he wanted to impress him. He said,
I practiced the city of levitation and uh,
I have done this for 10 years and now I
can walk on water. And the Buddhist says,
put the ferries, only a nickel. It's like,
what are you fucking waste of your time?
I'll be like,
you can aid the progression
rapidly with psychedelic drugs.
And this is something that Ma,
you know,
do you know about maps and their work
with Mtma and soldiers that have had PTSD
and not too much? No, it's,
it's phenomenal by giving these
soldiers MTMA therapy, meaning they,
they give them Mtma, which is essentially
what people think of as ecstasy.
The street name, they give them pure
Mtma and then they assist them with,
they actually have a psychologist
sit with them, a therapist,
and they go over all these details of
these traumatic events and they come to
peace with everything and they've
had profound benefits for soldiers.
And four, we, uh,
some combat journalists did different
people that have been over there.
And I've experienced
the horrors of war and,
and just general PTSD maybe for people
who have experienced violence attacks.
The is shown to be one of the very best
things we've ever discovered for helping
people get past.
Here's to me,
and I'm thinking about this on the fly
because this is stuff I don't think of
that very much. Um, but it's, it's,
there's a complex moral equation to
the extent that if you're talking about
somebody who has PTSD,
somebody has a condition and the only way
to help that condition is to use these
drugs. I've never had a problem with any
of that stuff. Right? I mean I've hit,
my grandfather was, was schizophrenia and
bi, maybe bipolar, maybe schizophrenia.
The diagnosis is not exactly clear.
They prescribed him lithium
and made him a lot better.
Would he have been better off struggling
with the schizophrenia? Of course.
Not much better than he should have the
lithium and then be able to live in his
rational mind.
So when there's a problem using drugs to
get past it and work with it is a good
thing.
You do run the risk of these sort of
brave new world situation where you have a
group of people who have a certain level
of Ersatz happiness that is not driven
by a point of view,
but more by just the these
chemicals in their body.
The chemicals affect your point of view
that that is 100% true. But are you,
Yuval Harari talks about maybe
this is the future, right?
He talks about the idea that maybe the
future is we just drug ourselves until
we're happy. Basically a more
that happiness is the drugs.
Because if you're a scientific
materialist, that's what it is.
Happiness is just a bunch of
chemicals flowing through your body.
So if you can bring them
in without self change,
but I do wonder whether that robs people
of a certain level of purpose that,
that the struggle is part of being human.
I think we're changing what it is to be
human just by carrying around phones.
And it just,
I mean that's, that's true.
But I think that that's again,
one of the things that I think makes
being a human worthwhile is the idea that
you are struggling. Like I think, I think
the struggle is actually meaningful.
And I think that's why religions tend
to set prophylactic rules sometimes for
good and sometimes for ill. So for
example, I, I am addicted to my phone.
I mean there's just no question right?
It's, it's in my hand all the time. And,
but from Friday night to Saturday night,
it's off.
I can't look at it and
forbidding from looking at it.
And this breaks the cycle
at least for one day a week.
And that's a good thing.
That makes me better as a human being.
He's a limit I set for myself
and then limit that I abide by.
And if you believe in in self mastery,
what,
where's the happy medium between self
mastery and I need a little bit of aid and
I think that there, there
is a happy medium there. Um,
but I'm not sure that that,
you know,
drugs are the answer to,
I don't think you're suggesting
drugs or the county. Not
suggesting that there's also a
problem with the word drugs that the,
everything is under that blanket and
that blanket can be entirely negative or
extremely. But I know, but
that's a pro. I use it too.
I mean it's not, not accusing you
but that that term it's a problem.
It's a problem term
because what these are,
are substances that are psychoactive
and some of them can be extremely
beneficial.
And some of them have short
term experiences that last
with longterm results and
I don't think that there's
enough knowledge that I
don't think the people that
are negative against it have experienced
enough of it or have looked at it in an
objective,
rational way because I think it's
something that could be here to aid
perspective.
The give people a chance to think outside
of their normal conditioned way of
thinking that might have been established
by their community or by their church
or by their neighborhood of whatever it
is. Sometimes it a little bit of a break,
a little bit of a mental break from what
your experiencing the in the vibration
that you exist on almost every day to
separate from that and to get a look at it
from the outside.
Sometimes it allows you to have a renewed
perspective that can enhance your life
greatly as long as when people reengage
the re-engaging at a level of discipline
thing and this is what we share.
You and I have both disciplined people
and it's one of the things I really
respect about you. You're a very hard
worker. You're always on the ball,
you're very disciplined and I know that
a lot of conservative people admire that
and they might hear that and folks and
they think that people who are liberal
are not disciplined.
They think that they're lazy.
It falls into this like week Beta male
sort of category of people that are
progressive and liberal and I think
that's, I think that's a misunderstanding.
I think you guys, you and I both agreed
that the struggle is very important,
but I'd struggle physically so that
I don't have to struggle mentally.
I struggle physically so that I can have
a better way of looking at things with
less stress. So we have this shared
belief that things should be a struggle.
My Street,
I forced my struggle on myself so
that I can have a better perspective.
And this is something that
you and I differ on like I
think you exercise, right?
Yes. How often do you do it? I tried
to. Every day. Yeah. Makes a big deal.
It's a huge deal. Yeah. I mean I think we,
we both understand that struggle is a,
it's an important part of understanding
yourself. If you do not push yourself,
you, if you do not struggle, you're
not going to really get who you are,
what your boundaries are.
And if you're self indulgent,
if everyday you're stuffing things
in your face that you want to like,
it's good to have a rule like,
hey,
for this next month you can't eat this
or you can't do that or I want you to
start fasting 16 hours a day.
Is it that hard just eat for eight
hours a day and fast for 16? But no,
but that just doing something like
that and setting these guidelines for
yourself and putting yourself into a,
uh,
a discipline state could be extremely
beneficial. Like Jocko Willink,
he says discipline equals freedom.
It is a great formula
and it's real. Well, it is. And again,
it is the basis of a lot of religion.
I mean a lot of religion
is very practice based.
One of the reasons I like Judaism as
opposed to other religions say very
practice based religion.
You know,
sometimes you can take that
too far in one direction,
which is I say you need to balance reason
with with dictates, right? That are,
that are meant to make you better. But
that goes all the way back to Aristotle.
Aristotle talks about how you have
to practice to be good, right?
You have to practice to be virtuous.
What makes you a virtuous person is
acting repeatedly in accordance with with
right reason. And that is setting
rules for yourself, right?
That is not violating every rule.
And I think when,
when we talk about on
the conservative side,
you have folks on the left being lazy. I
don't mean that in terms of work. I mean,
Mark Zuckerberg is a hard worker,
I assume. I think Jack Dorsey,
when he's not getting bitten by by
mosquitoes seems like a hard worker.
But you know, most, most of the people,
most people love jobs are hard workers.
I don't think it's about
that. I think it's a, it's,
it's a certain perspective
on the necessity of rules
and the mindset that if I
don't know what a rule is for, I'm going
to remove it. So GK Chesterton has this,
this very famous,
uh,
kind of contrast that he draws between
people who tend to be right wing
political and people tend to be
left wing politically. He says,
people who tend to be left wing
politically, you're walking through a,
they're walking through the woods
and you come across a funds.
You don't know why the
fence is there and you say,
I don't know why this fence is here.
I'm removing it.
And the person who's right wing walks
through the forest and sees the fence and
says,
I have no idea why the fence is here.
I'm going to go find out why the fence
is here. And then maybe I'll remove it.
And that's the, the kind of Burkian
conservative attitude toward rules. The,
the attitude that this rule was put here
for a reason. Now maybe the wool socks,
maybe the rule has to go,
but let's try and figure out what was
at the root of the rule before we just
wipe out all the fences and then
try to rebuild from the ground up.
All these new fences.
And that's especially true
in a civilization that's
the most prosperous in free
civilization ever created. I
mean, if the system really sucked,
that would be one thing.
But I think people are kind of ungrateful
about the fact that we live in the
best possible time in the best
possible place. Yeah, that's just,
that's the reality. And everybody who's
so negative about living in America,
it's like,
okay,
in 1,901 in 10 American children died
in the first year of life in 1850 the
average life expectancy in Europe was an
under 40 so what are you talking about?
What are you talking about?
Like our biggest problems today really
for the vast majority of people is that
we are too fat or that we are,
well we don't have a job,
but we still have somebody who is
basically making sure we have food.
Like starvation is not a serious
problem in the United States.
There's a problem of poverty, but there's
not a problem of widespread starvation.
In fact, poverty tends to align
with obesity. You know, the,
the state pretty
unbelievably great society.
So maybe you ought to look back at the
roots of that society before we start
Willy Nilly tearing up all of the,
all of the moral boundaries.
I think you and I agree that this is
the greatest time ever to be alive.
I think what these other folks are
saying is that we can do better.
And I think we all agree
with that, but yeah, sure.
But to classify this time
as being a terrible time is,
I think wholly inaccurate by the
way. I hit it right and left. Right.
And then this is one of the reasons,
yeah,
the reasons why. I think there's a
certain point where the Trump, Ian,
right meets the Bernie Sanders populace
left and that is them walking around
saying how much things suck.
And it's like, no, no, that's
just, that's just wrong.
So it's an amazing time.
It's amazing time for communication too.
It's amazing time for people to kind of
understand other people's perspectives
and points of view, which is one of
the reasons why d platforming and uh,
and silencing of conservatives,
even though I'm not conservative,
bothers the shit out of me. Yeah.
I just think it's a, it's a,
it's a non harmonious action in a time
that I think could lead to people having
much more open and much
more balanced committee
occasionally.
I mean this should be the time when we
are having more conversations and more
fun with each other and, and where
we are feeling more entrepreneurial,
we have a better social
safety net than ever.
So what one of the statistics that
really bothers me is that the level of
American mobility has declined rapidly
in the United States and the number of
people who are leaving their home state
to go somewhere else to work a job,
for example, is that decades low? Why?
It's easier to get anywhere now there are
7 million unfilled jobs I keep hearing
from, you know, folks who I
personally liked, people like
Tucker Carlson, uh, that,
you know, we, you, you grew up in
this small town and the town is dying.
The industry left.
Well,
you had the government somehow owes it
to you that you get to grow up in this
town and stay in that town.
Even if all the industry left.
And I just think to
myself, by whom, who, who,
who gave you this guarantee that you get
to stay there? And I know, listen, I'm,
I'm a lucky guy.
I grew up in a two parent household.
We didn't grow up wealthy but
we were middle, middle class.
Like I grew up in a small house in
Burbank with two bedrooms and I had three
sisters.
Those,
me and my three sisters and in one
bedroom and one bathroom for six people,
that's not poor. That's
middleclass. That's a great life.
And I understand some
people don't have that life,
but one thing that is guaranteed to you
is the opportunity for adventure in this
country. So go and move. Like why,
why are we inculcating a feeling of
victim hood in a society where if you make
the right decisions,
you will do well,
I mean not you might do well if you
make basic, basic right choices,
you will finish better than you
started in American society. I mean,
we're talking like the most basic choices
like finish high school and don't have
a baby out of wedlock and get a job
like you do. Those three things,
and the Brookings Institute says that
you will not be in permanent poverty in
the United States.
Like that's amazing.
That was not true for the vast
majority of human history,
for the vast majority of human history.
You did all of those things.
There wasn't high school,
but you did all the other things,
and then you were live like a surf
on a farm until he died at age 37 of
diptheria or something. So it's just the,
the lack of optimism in a society
where it should be running rampant is,
is kind of astonishing to me.
Well, it's perspective, right? I mean,
rich kids grow up with this
perspective of constantly being rich.
And people grow up with this perspective
of how they view the United States as
this negative thing, or that they
don't know how to change their life.
They don't know how to take action because
they haven't had anyone around them
that it's done it.
And that's part of the problem with small
town mentalities is that you kind of
inherit the vibe of the
people that are around you.
And if they're ignorant or if they're,
they're shallow minded or if they're,
they're stuck in this one town and
they're never going to leave and you get
caught in that vibe,
you can one day wake up and you're
32 and you've never done anything.
I mean this is what events talks about
and Hillbilly Elegy, right? Yeah.
People flourish in these small towns and
they basically been told that they have
two choices. They can go on welfare or
they can leave. Yeah. And it's like, okay,
fine. We'll go on welfare and everybody
around me is why? Why not is it,
there's nothing morally deficient
about going on on welfare?
It is actually one of the,
the bigger problems I have with the
welfare state generally is that it just
connects the person receiving the aid
from the person giving the aid one in that
like in our religious community,
to take an example there,
there's a time a few years
back where a guy came to me,
I bought some art from him. He is an
artist and a really does good work.
He came to me and he said,
my family doesn't have enough
money to make the rent this month.
Can you offer me in advance on art that
you'll buy somewhere down the road?
And of course,
make sure.
So I sent him a check and he understood
that five years later he came back to me
and he said, you know, you still
haven't bought that piece of art.
I owe you a piece of art because he knew
who gave him the money. Right, right.
And so he was willing to understand
that that was an act of charity and he
wanted to make sure that that that was
paid back. You see this in Cinderella man,
right? With Russell Crowe, that
moment where he makes his money,
he walks back into the welfare office
and he rolls out a wad. Yeah, like that,
that feeling that the government isn't
just a giant cash machine that is exists.
You pay your money, but that money
actually comes from some worry there.
It's coming from the future because we're
going to have to pay back the debt or
it's coming from somebody whose tax money
and that we all owe something to each
other. Right. And by the same token,
the what I owe to my neighbors
is that if they're in trouble,
then it is my obligation as a good
person to try and help them out.
On a personal level. Yes. Right.
And the charity and religious
communities is extremely high. That's,
that's the social fabric that
I'm talking about. Yeah. Without,
without that sort of dutiful
sense to one another,
you can't have rights because if you
just have rights then and and no duties,
then there will be no one
to take care of each other.
It's why while I'm libertarian,
when it comes to government,
I'm very conservative when it comes to
the need to build a social fabric and
communities and,
and,
and have people with working families
and in communities of working families.
Yeah.
I really think that that's one of the
best things that comes out of religion is
when you have a tight knit community
like yours and you do have that sense of
charity where you really are a community
of people that care for each other and
look out for each other.
The problem is of course doing that large
scale and then the problem is doing it
and some sort of a
nondenominational way where people,
they don't have to have
the exact same beliefs,
but they still share these core values
of community and taking care of each
other.
I mean that's what people really benefit
from when they've done studies with
people when they show happiness and
what is happening is correlated with,
it's almost always in correlated with
friends and loved ones and family, right?
It's the most important
thing you can have.
And when it comes to diversity,
you know,
there's this slogan that
diversity is our strength. Well,
there is a Robert Putnam, a
sociologist over at harbor. Hey,
he wrote an entire book about the
social fabric called bowling alone,
who's kind of the, the pioneer
and the idea of social capital.
And what he said is that he went in with
the two writing this book with the idea
that diversity is our strength.
And then he did some research and what
he found is that ethnic diversity only
correlates with two things.
And these are his words,
increased TV watching and increased
protest marches. That's all it unless,
unless it is within the
boundaries of a common goal.
So if you walk into a church,
very diverse ethnically,
everybody's got the same general goal,
which is we're worshiping God and one
particular way and we believe in a certain
core set of values.
And now diversity is great.
Your experience has come to bury your,
you're all aiming in the same direction.
He gives the example of the army.
You see bunch of people who go in
diverse group of people, diverse races,
different backgrounds,
and when you talk to those guys while
they're serving or after they leave,
they don't give a crap about the diverse
backgrounds of the people they were
serving with. They're all aiming
their guns in the same direction.
Well in the United States, we have to be
aiming our guns in the same direction,
or we can't really have a
functioning social fabric at all.
Like I'm perfectly willing to give
charity to people who I don't know,
who still believe,
like I do,
that America is a fantastic country
rooted in immutably good principles.
But that starts to break down when I'm
being asked to give charity just on a
personal level to somebody who believes
that America is fundamentally evil.
It needs to be torn out at its roots and
replaced with something better, right?
Because now we're not aiming in the
same direction. So on a human level,
I care about you, but on
a, but on a social level,
if I have a choice between somebody
who basically agrees with me about
fundamental values and somebody
who is diametrically opposed,
I'm gonna get my money to the person
who basically agrees with me on those
fundamental values.
And again,
I don't think those fundamental
values have to be religious.
I don't think you have to be a god
believer to receive charity from me or I
don't think I should have to be, uh,
an atheist receive charity from you.
But I do think that you do have to take
into consideration a few things and now
we're on the same page,
personal responsibility.
The idea that you do live in a free
country just historically and relatively
speaking, this is a free country,
which means decision making is on you.
So man up a little bit.
They that the decisions that you make,
we should all have sympathy for people
who have had worse lives and worse
experiences. But in the
end, if you are capable,
if you are not fundamentally disabled
in some way that you need to make a plan
for your own life and
then you need to do that.
Like are you more willing to give charity
to somebody who has a plan for how to
get themselves out of the hole?
And of course, of course that,
but that relies on that person
feeling an obligation to do that.
I also think that what you're talking
about with the charity within the
community is so much more,
there's so much more connection then
charity from the government when you're
talking about welfare.
The problem is that
there's this dissolving of
responsibility because it's just
a check that comes in that you feel
like, wow, this is a rich country.
I'm owed this anyway. The, and
you know, and when I was a kid,
we were on welfare and we,
we used food stamps and I remember being
very ashamed of it and feeling really
weird that we were that poor,
that we needed help from the government,
but my parents worked their way out of it.
They were young,
they had a kid.
My guess is that I guess is that the,
the social stigma probably
has something to do with that.
Meaning that I'm sure they didn't want
to be on welfare and they don't want to
be on food stamps. Contrast your
story with Adam Carolla's, right?
Add Adam talks all the time about how
his parents were also on food stamps and
welfare and they just didn't give a shit.
And then they were just,
and he always resented that
he thought that was bad. He
said like, you could work,
why aren't you?
And that gave him the impetus to get
up and do what what Adam has done.
So you know that that kind of,
it's not pick yourself up by the
bootstrap because helping hands are good,
but it is. If I, if I were capable of
picking myself up by my bootstraps,
would I do so? Yeah. And if the answer
is yes, then we're all on the same team.
Well there's,
this is a real problem too.
And that some people just get a
horrible hand dealt to them at birth.
There was parents that really are
doing a terrible job raising them.
They're fucking him up
every step of the way.
You're around a bunch of people that
are criminals. Everybody's fucking up.
There's no examples of anybody
that's doing well. I mean,
it's one of the unique things about the
internet today is that a kid that's in
that environment can get ahold of maybe
something that you've said or something
that you know, someone else has
said and start reading books.
And start taking in information that
gives them a different perspective and
fueled that perspective
with more motivational stuff
and more information and
education. And sometimes kids, just
like you were saying with Adam Carolla,
the grow up with these parents
that are just not ambitious at all.
So they become very ambitious and they
worked very hard to not be like them.
I mean,
sometimes it's good to see that example,
but most of the time it's just fucking
hard for them to reprogram their heads.
Right.
Well
for sure it's hard to do that and it's
also hard. I really think that there's,
there's a lot of focus in the country
right now on raising awareness,
which is fine, you know, raise it,
raising awareness of our history and all
the bad things that we've done. Yeah,
good.
I mean people,
people should know about
all the good things and all
the bad things, right? It's,
its history is history,
but this,
this incessant focus on the idea that
people's lives are getting better by
suggesting that they're perennial victims
in the United States. I just don't,
I don't understand how
that's a good thing. Yeah.
Like as as a historically a member
of a historically persecuted group.
If I had grown up and my parents had
said to me, no matter what you do,
you will be put under the
thumb of the dominant society.
That's a pretty horrible message to hell
to a kid and I think that's true for
politicians, again, on both sides of
the aisle. I think you get it from,
from president Trump when it comes to
some rural areas where it's like, well,
it's the Mexicans and the Chinese coming
in to steal your jobs and you're under
the thumb of of people who are trying
to destroy you and on the other side of
the aisle, people who say, well, you're,
you're in the inner city and therefore
the cops are racist against you and want
to destroy you and everybody's out to get
you. And it's like, well, how about this?
How about like again,
the single best thing you can do for
yourself is make basic decisions that are
entirely within your control. Unless you
are, unless you are raped, God forbid,
single motherhood is a choice that
you get to make about your life.
This is a choice you get to make about
your life finishing high school unless
you are legitimately disabled in some way.
I mean,
especially in La USD where you basically
have to be able to read at third grade
level to finish high school. You
know, just just like these are,
these are decisions,
personal decision making if you want.
I've never seen somebody life get
better by complaining about reality.
I've seen a lot of people's lives get
better by acknowledging that reality is
what it is and then making personal
decisions to make their lives better.
And that's considered non-compassionate.
But it seems to me the essence
of compassion sometimes
he's saying at least make
the baseline decision. If you make the
baseline decisions and then you'll fail,
we can talk about what happened.
I don't think it's non-compassionate.
I think it's pragmatic
and I think you're right,
but I also think that there's some
people that are there in situations that
require something external to,
to assist them there,
their the way their life has been set up.
And this is what I think when people
think about compassion and people pulling
themselves up by their bootstraps.
If you have a real,
if you really have an honest and accurate
assessment of extreme poverty and
terrible neighborhoods,
it's not as simple as do something
good to better your life.
Part of it is you got to
fucking stay alive, right?
You're surrounded by people who either
have committed crimes or we'll commit
crimes.
You mean one out of every four people,
you run into my be a criminal in the
worst neighborhood in the country. Okay.
This is what it does for sure,
but I think we have to,
this is where we recognize
what government is good at.
Government is good at two things,
cutting the other people,
cutting checks from other people's money.
They're great at it and
they'll see they're,
they're right on top of those
parking tickets by the way,
to make sure that they can sign it
and they're, they're amazing at it.
So seizing your money and paying money,
they're very good at and,
and pointing a gun at people,
right?
These are the two things that government
was built to do was collect taxes and
pay out money and then point
guns at people, right? This
is what government does.
So which of those two things would you
apply in a situation where there's just a
complete lack of social capital because
cutting a check isn't going to do it
alone. Where's that check? Go to
the parents who are not doing,
not able to protect their kids.
It's one thing if you're enabling the
parents who move out of that community or
something. Right. Um, but that's
why I say you have to attach,
if you're going to do the
government welfare thing,
you got to attach it to a plan.
It can't just be here's a check.
Enjoy your life because
of what is the plan.
No, was terrible communities.
You live in an apartment complex.
I mean,
here's the reality.
I think that the plan very often when
it comes to a crime ridden area is the
other side of what the government does,
which is you need more cops in that area.
I think.
I think that the great lie that though,
that these communities
that are crime rate,
and I'm talking about White Apalasia
and I'm talking about, yes, yeah.
Black inner cities. These, these
communities do not need fewer cops.
They need more cops because at the
preconditioned to investment in those
communities and increased tax dollars
in those communities and increase social
capital in those communities is people
not getting shot every five seconds. Yeah.
I mean that's why the worst thing that
can happen to law abiding minorities is
for the cops to abandoned
areas where crime is high.
It just doesn't make any sense.
And that's not just me saying that
Jane Levy's reporter at the La Times,
very much on the left has said the same
thing while biting people want crime
rates to go down,
like conditions have to change in a
community for conditions to change in the
community.
See The wild,
uh,
well the whites who wild and wonderful
whites of West Virginia. No, it was, uh,
it was it Johnny Knoxville. Did he produce
that documentary? I think he did. Right,
dude, it's about this family that lives
in West Virginia that has just a bunch of
psychotic criminals.
There's these crazy white people,
the kids drinking mountain dew and doing
back flips on the bed and they're all
on pills. It's bananas and
it gives you this insight,
like if you are in this community,
if you were in this family,
and this is obviously very extreme family,
but there's many more of them out
there that have not been documented.
If you are in that community,
good fucking luck getting out.
Right. Good luck. The the,
the money that you get other than
Welfare's from selling pills, you know,
everybody's on these pills
so you're all whacked out.
You don't know what the fuck is going on.
Half the day you're on opiates. I mean,
it is a bananas environment and there's
a lot of people like that in this
country for sure.
And in poor Latino communities and
poor white communities in poor black
communities.
The idea that these people are just
going to pull themselves up by their
bootstraps, it's crazy. I just
think they don't have a plan.
And I think if we really
want to help them,
there's gotta be some way where you can
give these people the opportunity to
step out of that pattern,
whatever that community centers,
outreach programs, whatever
it is. I don't know what it,
I mean the truth is,
the truth is that historically speaking,
it was people actually going to church.
Yeah.
There's a good lot of good
church going person. Right.
But I absolutely recognize that there's
a lot of good involved and having that
framework
right. And, and that that's,
I'm not sure that that's,
I don't think you can create sort of a
fake social fabric with just a government
welfare system. Like it just, it, it
hasn't worked. I mean, disability exists.
I'd been increasing every
year. It's, it's not,
this is a question I asked
Andrew getting, actually, sorry.
Our episode comes out on Sunday and
obviously Andrew is a big fan of ubi,
universal basic income.
And I'm not averse to the idea of ubi in
a future where legitimately 50% of the
population can't work because they've
all been automated out of existence.
And all of this,
but there's one section in his book
where Andrew Talks about how if we cut
people a check for ubi,
then they will spend their extra time
creating art and engaging in hobbies that
they like.
And I just thought to myself,
I've been at said it to him
like people are on disability.
I don't what they're doing right.
And if you're on disability,
the people you're talking
about who are suffering,
they're not out there writing
poetry. Right? I mean the, the,
the rise of the opioid epidemic and
people who are oding on drugs and all this
stuff that's in precisely the same
demographic you're talking about.
You're just talking about a check from
one place as opposed to another place.
I don't, I don't really see
how that solves the problem.
I think we have a crisis
of purpose. Yes. Right now.
And I don't think that that crisis of
purpose is solvable on the one hand by
changing our trade rules.
And I also don't think that that
Christ is a purpose is solvable by,
by cutting a, uh, a government check.
I just don't think that
that's how people are wired.
I absolutely agree with you that
there is a crisis of purpose.
My concern is about
automation and my concern,
and obviously I haven't really studied
this other than talking to Andrew Yang
and talking to Elon Musk and a few other
people that are proponents of universal
basic income, they think that there's
going to be such a massive loss
of jobs in such a short period of time
from people that are non skilled laborers
and it's going to go away.
There's millions and millions of jobs
and these people are not going to have
anything and that it could be chaos.
So there's,
there's two problems that come up there
and this is where Andrew's book is
interesting because probably number
one is that the people will be poor.
They won't have a source of income.
Yeah, UBI solve that the other quarter,
but does it even, it gives him $1,000 a
month because he opted, right. I mean,
even if,
even if he just had a
Swedish redistribution system
and the average tax rate
went up to 60% or something,
it might let,
let's say we could solve the money
problem for a second, which, you know,
without tanking the economy,
which is questionable,
but let's say we could do that,
we could add trillions of dollars to
the budget every year and we could tell
that I'm still not sure that
that solves the deeper problem,
which is that when people lose
jobs, they lose purpose, right?
So I'm not sure that UBI solves
that problem. As I say, we have,
we have a rich social welfare network in
the United States and we're seeing this
stuff happen anyway. You
know, I'm, I'm a little bit,
I'm a little bit less
catastrophic by a little bit,
I mean a fair bit less catastrophic in
my thinking about automation then then
either Andrew Yang or Elon Musk think
that people will be able to adapt quick
enough to avoid the problems.
They'll realize the jobs aren't there
anymore and they'll just naturally
gravitate towards other
professors. Anything over
time that people will do that.
But they're not always the same people.
I,
there's all these shifts
in the economy and the,
the ideal economic model has a truck
or becoming a coder. Right. But that's,
that's not reading. It was the whole learn
to code fiasco kicked off of Twitter.
Right. And it still does it. Yeah.
Apparently if you say it to journalists,
then that's, that's very bad. If you
say, what's a coach with truck? Yeah,
that's what it was. Code to a trucker.
If you say learn to code to a trucker,
then that's just you being helpful.
If you say learn to code to a journalist,
then that is targeted
harassment on Twitter.
That's where that someone sends
it to me. Well, I meant work.
Twitter doesn't care about you. I
can say whatever I want, but it's a,
but yeah, I mean I think that, but
if you just say it to a friend, hey,
fuck face learned to code that,
I don't know,
it's your friend could report you to the
censorship board over at 20 it's such a
dumb thing to take people out for.
It's one of the best examples of like
how censorship step oversteps its
boundaries and becomes almost like satire.
Yeah. It's, it's real. It's really,
really absurd. This is the
biggest aggression ever.
Learn to code. Learn to code.
That's something,
look,
this is a stupid thing that
someone said about coal miners.
They really said that about coal miners
that maybe they could learn to code.
And so everybody,
like what the fuck?
And so learned to code became a joke
and became something that you would mock
people right there. Is there
an explanation for it was
so crazy. It was like, no.
Then learn to code got connected with
this other stuff.
That's the Hitler owned a dog document,
right? It's like dogs are bad.
Hitler owned one. Okay.
White supremacists are bad.
They used the phrase learned to code.
That means if you say learn to code,
you're a white supremacist.
We lost the frog. That fucking
frog. It feels good, man.
Frog. That's what happened to pepe the
frog. They turned the fricking fraud gay.
I mean, yeah. Oh yeah. But yeah, I
mean it's not as far as automation.
Um, you know, there's constantly
people saying this is the,
the Nicholas Nassim
tell lead view of reality,
which that the Black Swan incident
can happen any any second.
So watch out for it versus the sort
of Steven pinker view of reality,
which is the black swan incident is called
the Black Swan Internet because it's
a black swan incident, meaning
that it happens incredibly
rarely. I, you know, the,
the idea that we are on the verge of a
catastrophic drop in job numbers because
of the automation of trucking for example.
I'm not sure that I buy it.
The reason I don't buy it is because
you still are gonna need someone sitting
behind the wheel of that truck there human
drivers on the road. Uh, it's going to,
there will be a gradual transition
away from some of these jobs,
Andrew getting talks about radiologists
and how radiologists are going to be
priced out of the market by computers
that can do a better job of diagnosing
tumors first of all. Awesome.
Right? I mean, that's, that's good.
First of all that brings down cost end.
You won't get cancer as advanced.
So that'd be, that'd be a good thing.
And then second of all, what, what, uh,
a lot of technology studies
have had tended to show is
that technology just gets
integrated into different
Wagan in particular career.
So there will be jobs that
are eliminated for sure.
There'll be jobs we haven't heard
of that will be created also.
And mostly technology will, will become
more of a productivity aid to, to people.
So this is true in factories.
Jobs have been lost in factories.
It's the best example of where jobs are
lost, but it's mostly turn offices, right?
How many office jobs had been
created because you have computers?
What's more office jobs exist
because I write by hand.
Do you think that this is akin
to like a government bailout?
Like the idea of the government bailout
was like the banks are too big to fail
and some people thought,
you know what,
you got to let them fail so you figure
out why they failed and we'll never have
it happen again. If there is this
thing and the government steps in says,
wait a minute,
I know you lost all your jobs are going
to give you $1,000 you don't have to
figure it out $1,000 a month.
And some people go, okay,
I'm not going to figure it out now.
Whereas those people might have gone on
a fear filled journey to try to figure
out their purpose in life
because now they're stirred,
stuck where their job doesn't
exist anymore. So there
what did it their owner, I mean
they have to act. There is,
there is an innovation that comes from,
from a welfare check.
I mean there are people
who become dependent on
government then they're used to
being dependent on government that
that stuff is true. It does happen.
I mean and listen,
Milton Friedman made an
argument for universal basic
income as a replacement for
the welfare system.
There.
There is another problem with universal
basic income that I asked Andrew about
also. And that was, you know, one of the,
one of the big issues is that poor people,
very often people who are
permanently impoverished,
not people who are temporarily poor,
but they tend not to spend money where we
think they ought to spend money, right?
They're not taking that money and they're
not putting it into education or into
the [inaudible] Ho hos and cigarettes.
The average,
the average person who is making less
than, I think it was $16,000 a year,
spending $400 here and
lottery tickets or man,
it's legitimately just flushing your
money down the toilet, you know,
so it's so how do you, aren't you just
going to end up back in the same place?
You can go in six months where people
took that money and used it in ways that
actually didn't benefit them. And at a
certain point, the question is, are your,
do you own your decisions?
Do,
do not own your decisions and what level
of incompetence or inability do we say
you no longer your decisions.
And so we're just going to take care
of you on a permanent basis. That's,
that's really the, the,
the question here. I think,
yeah, when you're talking about welfare,
we're looking at worst case scenario,
right?
Where someone does get dependent upon
the welfare state and does use that money
frivolously and does make poor decisions.
But then there's gotta be other people
that are single moms that, you know,
maybe had a kid with some fucking asshole.
It doesn't want to pay and it is a piece
of shit and they have to hide from him
and they're just trying to feed
their kids. Yeah. For sure.
Those people exist to 100%
have a community to, to,
to help them out.
And maybe they're not a part of a church
and maybe they don't have a good group
of neighbors.
Maybe they had to move somewhere for work
and they got stuck in some place where
they don't know what study.
But it, I think part of
this is to recognize that
incentives matter on both ends.
So the idea is that you give some people
more money and they'll, they'll do well.
It's also true that if you create a
welfare system that benefit single
motherhood, you will get more
single motherhood. I mean, the,
the single motherhood rate in the black
community before welfare was 20% now
it's 70% in the white community, it was
like 5% now it's 40% you've said that
out of wedlock children and having
a kid when you're young is like,
it's a terrible idea for your life.
But what do you recommend
to have kids avoid that?
Are you one of those
people that thinks of it?
Start without that thing on
it? No. Condoms. Since we were
saying like, don't, don't,
don't, don't have unprotected sex. I
mean like this, this is not, it's not,
pardon my, my fake cursing. It's not
effing rocket science. I mean like,
like apologizing for not
curse them. Apologizing for
not cursing. Uh, yeah, it's,
it's,
it's not rocket science.
This is one the Holy Father's kids make
mistakes in. I mean, that's what happens.
And then if the government pays for
those mistakes, it becomes less.
So what should, what should happen? Should
the kids suffer? So the WHO presents,
should it be? Should it be worked out?
I mean it depends on the situation.
You know, if their parents available
to the kid, presumably the parents,
the grandparents would take
a pretty active role in the,
in the raising that kid.
Awesome. They, they're
there. Well, how about this?
How about we assume that if you
are old enough to get pregnant,
then you're old enough to, let's, let's
talk about a 17 year old or 18 year old.
Used to be shotgun marriages
thing. Uh, and uh, and really
like that's a good idea.
I think the idea of parents staying
together for the sake of a kid that they
accidentally board is absolutely
a good idea. Yes. I think that,
I think that is a better idea than
the man walking away and the kid being
without a man in the house.
So you're thinking of their childhood
and a lot of people figure a way to work
it out. Yes. And if they were both
reasonable, they could do that. Yeah.
And I think that that by the way,
a huge percentage of American births in
the forties and 50s were exactly this,
or a lot of seven month babies in the
forties and 50s something like 30 to 40%
of all kids born in the 30s and forties
and 50s we're seven months babies or
would somebody got knocked up and then
the expectation was nagging like you did
the, you did the crime,
now you do the time. Right.
And he did this dot puts
people and relationship prison.
Good then don't then don't ask, don't
die. And find somebody, find them,
find somebody to have with you.
Find somebody to have sex with who
you actually think is worthy of a
relationship right now.
Or I'm on pornography is available to you.
Like figure it out. You're okay with
that. Um, on a moral level, yeah, no,
but if I'm going to,
if I'm going to compare that to having
a baby out of wedlock, then yeah,
this is what I think about pornography.
They could stop now and
we're good forever. But yeah,
I think you guys, there's no,
there's no supply and demand problem.
And they kill like Megan it.
You guys are a bunch of freaks.
I mean there's no,
it's like a business.
It's almost like you have excess
houses that stack up to the moon.
Like there's no way everyone's
going to live in all those houses.
Why do you keep making house?
There's no way one person has ever jerked
off to every video that ever existed.
It doesn't. It's not possible. It's like,
and it's also like other forms of
media where they just stack up.
I never really thought of that until we
get the backlog of Internet pornography
and you're like, cut, I'm, you know, I'm a
month behind now. Just think about music,
right?
There's all the music that existed before
in the 50s and 60s and 70s and the 80s
and there's new shit every goddamn day.
It never ends.
It's this overwhelming library
of stuff that we have. Yeah,
Dick's bucket. It would, it would be good
if that music changed from time to time.
Yeah. At the same song recorded seven
different ways, you know? But what could,
should you listen to?
What do you think I listened to you today?
Listen to classic jazz and classical of
course. Yeah. So we just so interesting.
I was, I was a concert level violinist
until I was until I was like 17 years old
practice. Yeah. I mean,
then the only expensive object that I
own other than my house is his violin.
Oh really? Yeah. Is it a
strata of area? It is not. It
is. It is a upbeat, it's not,
that's all I know.
Yeah.
They're the two that people may know
or Stratton and like a worn area. Um,
but those, those ones are like
hundreds of thousands of dollars.
This is in the tens of
thousands of dollars.
A Stradivarius is hundreds of thousands
of, I had the guy who we knew,
my family knew hit $1 million
Stradivarius. Ooh. Yeah.
Now it was so big about it was
the big deal. Well, I mean,
aside from the historic
value of the thing, they're
not making any more of them.
Um, it does play very differently.
Very differently. Okay.
I had a crappy violin for most of my,
I like really until the last two years.
I had a violin that was handed down
from my grandfather that was worth maybe
1300 bucks. And it was a piece of
crap. I mean, it was not a good violin.
If you're good enough,
then you can tell the difference between
a really great violin to play and one
that is a piece of garbage. And I was
good enough to do that. So that's, yeah.
I mean, I was a, I was a classical guy.
I played, I played violin for years in,
my dad was, uh, growing up, my dad was a
pianist. Look at what Jamie just pulled up
the most expensive violin in the world.
Sold for an estimated $16 million
alors Yup. For a Stradivarius and never
lose value. I mean, really they don't,
and this is it. This is a
good investment. The person,
I know this guy who has offered a,
he's offered a strategy,
I think it was $250,000 maybe
10 years ago. And he's like, no,
that it's worth like $3 million.
God,
no.
What is the deal like what if you had
to explain what's the difference between
the sound that this makes?
I mean, it has to do with the
acoustics of the instrument.
Any of the wood quality.
There's,
there's slight variations
in the construction of the
instrument is certain parts
of it are thicker or
thinner. Um, and it is also,
it's easier to play a better violin. So
it, it almost covers for your mistakes.
When you play a bad violin,
it tends to scratch and screech more.
That's why when you get in the
upper register with a violin,
you had very high notes.
It can either be very screechy or it
can be very beautiful. Some of that,
a lot of,
most of that's the player.
Some of that's the violin Yasha Heifetz
who is widely considered the greatest
violinists to, to ever
live. He had a Strad,
a lady blunt,
Stradivarius cost 15 point $9 million,
and then they lend them out on, on loan
to, you know, world's great violinist. So,
but there's a button in the end. It really
is the, uh, the quality of the player.
There's a famous Yasha Heifetz story
where he was playing at Carnegie Hall and
some lady came up to him afterward and
she said, you know your violin. It's just,
it sounds so beautiful.
And he picks up the violin and puts
it to his ear and he says, Tony,
I don't hear it right now.
So do you listen to any other
kind of music? Yeah, I mean,
I like some classic rock. Yeah. I
mean, see, rocking out. Yeah. I,
I went to a Doobie brothers concert
and my parents, no, you did. Yeah,
it was really, yeah. Yeah. That's, that's
a band that was main named after a joint.
That is true. That's how ready is
accurate. I know. Did you feel like, oh,
like a center.
I was a rebel that day.
It doesn't really go into the Doobie
brothers concert with the other boomers.
So the other thing is a same sex marriage.
So that's the other thing that I
think that we disagree with. Well, I,
we agree with the marriage
thing. Governments,
government should be involved,
I think where people should be
protected is through assets.
And you know, the contract. Yes. Yeah,
I think that that all makes sense to me.
The all that stuff in terms of like a
alimony and child support and all those
things make sense to me and that, and the
idea that the community reinforces it,
which would then become the government
reinforced and all that stuff.
That all makes sense to me.
I understand it. But um,
why do you care if a two gay
guys want to get married?
Um, so from a religious point of view,
sure. Let's go from religious soap.
So you want me to do a secular
point of view first? So the,
the idea is not that I care
deeply whether two gay guys,
I want to get married to each other.
The idea is that it do I
prefer traditional marriage
to say to same sex marriage.
Okay. Well let me, let me phrase it this
way. What do you think a gay guy is?
Do you think someone's there making a
choice or do you think that this is how
they were before
the religious point of view on this?
And,
and I think this is actually just the
general conservative point of view.
Like human action generally is,
I don't know,
meaning that for the
vast majority of people,
I would assume that they have a biological
drive to engage in that behavior.
But the traditional sort of we'll point
of view is that biological drive does
not necessarily match up to the activity
you are to engage in. Right. Men,
for example, have a biological
drive to impregnate many women.
That's not something religion is
cool with either. All right, so the,
the idea is that rubber
Lou religion is cool with a man being
with one woman and impregnating her.
But you're not cool with
a man being with a man.
So I can give you the
religious explanation and I
can give you the second word
explanation.
So they,
so the religious explanation is that there
is something different about a woman.
Then there is about a man and a man is
made better through his union with a
woman and that if you pervert the sex
drive to pursue mere pleasure instead of a
lasting relationship upon which
the base of society is built,
then you are foregoing the
proper use of your sex drive.
And I just wanted to step
in and argue against that.
You would say that just because someone
can't get pregnant doesn't mean that
they don't have a loving relationship
that contributes to society. Well,
that's true,
but it is also for going the
more productive relationship
of being able to bear
and their children and also,
and also recognizing that the
sections are not different. Right.
Then recognizing also the sexes
are not the same. So it, you know,
being with a man is in a relationship
different than being with a woman,
I would assume. I mean, I assume that's
why gay guys are gay. If it weren't,
then I assume that they would be fine
with being with a woman. Right. So that's,
so that relationship from a,
from a religious perspective is more
valuable because women have different
qualities than men. You round
off each other's harsh edges.
It changes you. I mean,
you're married being very
changes a man in a different way,
that being married to a member
of the same sex would write.
But I don't want people to have to do it.
But if you're not forcing anybody,
right,
but I want them to have the option
and if you're a gay person and we
know, I mean of course because legally
we agree, right? Yeah. Illegal.
And I keep making this distinction
because whenever I talk about my moral
perspective on things,
then people immediately assume that I'm
a theocratic fascist and I just want to
keep underscoring my personal views
on Dave Rubin's marriage are of no
consequence to public policy
in any way whatsoever.
But I agree with you on that and I don't
think it should be a part of public
public policy and I think people should
absolutely be allowed to marry and
divorce and do whatever the fuck
they want to do no matter who it is.
But why do you care?
Like as a person who's a rational thinker,
it's pretty clear that people are gay
and I don't really think that this is a
decision they make in
term in terms of like,
I'm going to make a clear
choice to defy God and be gay.
I think they're just gay. Well,
again, I think that's a confession.
It's a conflation of identity.
And drive with activity,
which is something that
religion fundamentally reject.
Religion fundamentally rejects the idea
that you are driven to do something and
therefore it is your identity. Therefore,
he gets to participate in the behavior.
That's it. That's a chain of
thinking that religion, any religion,
if a man is gay in your religion,
if a man is gay and they're
in love with another man,
they should just squash those
thoughts and find a woman. Well,
ideally they would be honest with a woman
they marry and they're not like, well,
they would want to. Ideally, ideally,
you would still get married and have
children in a heterosexual relationship.
If you're not up to that,
then you wouldn't get married at
all to when you describe this to a
gay man, they will tell you, imagine
Ben Shapiro, someone said to you,
you should stop being with your beautiful
wife and you need to now marry a man
because this is what God wants you to do,
so you're going to have to stop this man
and he's going to stop you because this
is how the rules are set
up so far. It sounds pretty
terrible shirts, right? Well,
this is how it sounds to gay folks when
you're telling them they have to find a
one.
Like I like, I'm not saying you
have to find a woman. I'm saying,
I'm saying you can't do X. Right? I'm
not saying you must, but say can't.
But by whose determination? If you decide
to participate in this religion, right?
Then there is a buyin to
the precepts of the religion
and the buy in is
you can't be gay. Well, no,
the buy in is that you can have
whatever sexual orientation you pleased,
but there's certain activity
you can't participate in.
So you can be gay,
but you can't have gay sex.
Correct. That's the, and by the
way, that's what the Bible, I mean,
if we want to go direct
to the text of the Bible,
it's what the Bible actually
says, right? I mean,
even the parts of the Bible that people
really hate those parts say that a man
shall not lie with a man. It doesn't say
a man can't be attracted to another man.
That's Old Testament, right? Yeah,
that's right. That's our stuff, right?
New the new testament that it gets a
little harsher and the new testament in
some places, Romans, correct? Yeah.
But in any case, you know, uh, again,
when it comes to,
this is what I'm puzzled by is the idea
that this is a unique area of human
behavior that religion is
supposed to treat differently.
Meaning religion treats virtually
every human activity like this,
sin is a failure to abide by a
covenant, right? That's what,
that's the definition of sin, right?
When when you commit a sin in Judaism,
in era in Judaism, what you are
doing is failing to do a Mitzvah,
which is a commandment. You're
violating a commandment. Well,
there are lots of commandments that go
directly against what people are driven
to do.
Just because of the drive is stronger,
does not make it morally more morally
non culpable to violate that commandment.
So when people pick this
one out and they say, well,
this one is particularly
intolerant for example, uh,
I don't see why it's more particularly
intolerant than saying to a man that you
have to marry one woman or saying to a
Jew that you are not allowed to eat this
stuff.
Or you know like it's,
it may be harder that I don't
think there's any question.
It's harder to abide
by those commandments,
but it is well within religious tradition,
like literally every religious tradition
that there's a bunch of stuff you are
driven to do that you can't.
Now again,
you don't have to agree with my program
that I'm not trying to convert you.
It's one of the nice
things about my religion.
I don't give a crap whether
people are Jewish or not. Like we,
we actively discouraged converts.
But if you're going to proclaim that
you are abiding by traditional Judaism,
this is the buy in, right? There's lots
of buy and you have to wear a funny hat.
Sometimes you have to,
you have to go to shul on Saturdays.
You have to keep Shabbat.
Like there's,
there's a lot of buy in and as long
as I'm not bothering anybody else, I,
I frankly don't see what business it
is legitimately anybody's what I think
about personal relationships.
I'm not imposing my view on anybody else.
Well, um, I, I do acknowledge
that at all, all the religions,
Judaism probably makes it the most
obvious. They don't give a fuck what do,
go ahead. Do your thing. Like
they're not trying to ties,
you're doing your business. My uncle
converted and uh, when he get very,
it was a grind man.
He had to learn a lot of Shit
my three years of a grind. A long
time. Yeah, for sure. It's a long time.
So that was the religious
perspective and the,
and the secular perspective when it comes
to valuing traditional marriage over
over a same sex marriage,
that's a very simple calculation,
which is one type of marriage produces
traditional children produce his children
need traditional biological way and then
you have both parents in the house to
take care of the kid. Right?
That's the value of marriage.
And I fully acknowledge that when
the value of marriage shifted from,
it's about production and
rearing of children too.
It's two people who love each other.
The case for same sex marriage against
same sex marriage went completely out the
window.
Right,
so you are just sticking to your rigid
ideology in terms of like what you
believe to be a sin and not believe
to be a sin based on your religion,
based on this very strict moral
fiber that this religion is
in a religious context. It applies
to me, it applies to my family.
It doesn't apply to you.
Right.
Room for growth in that when people have
a better understanding about biology
like it, if it was proven,
if there's proven like, oh,
this is why a person develops blue eyes.
This is why a person is gay.
This is why there's nothing wrong with
it. It's just a very ocean. It's red hair,
it's freckles, it's gay, it's straight.
Tell me that that homosexual orientation
is 100% biologically driven and I will
almost completely agree with that.
I think that there are some cases
where it's not, but those are rare.
But it's particularly true by the way.
The research tends to show that there's
more sexual fluidity among females than
males. Males. It tends to be
either heterosexual or homosexual.
Research is all done by dude's want their
wife to hook up with chip. Keep going,
tell him to stop you, but hey, let me just
show you the paperwork. But it's wrong.
But again,
that it's a,
it's a question that I've always found
actually not particularly interesting
simply because it doesn't take into
account the worldview generally,
which is that a biological drive does not
equal excuse for behaving in a certain
way.
But this,
that's where it brings me back to this
like is it possible that these laws in
this religion were written when there,
what do, who do you think wrote the stuff?
Do you think people wrote the
stuff or do you think God really,
I think either way, even if it were it.
I mean, because I am a an orthodox Jew,
I believe that at the very least it's
God inspired and God written. Right?
But even if I believed out a second level
that human beings were at that stuff
too. I think that people 3000 years ago
had never seen a gay person before were
saying tenanted.
Like the very reason to have a commandment
is because certain people in your
community are behaving in a
particular way, presumably. Right?
There's no commandment not to take your
head and shove it into meat grinder.
Well,
this is also the argument against pork
is because they didn't understand trick
gnosis thinner stand.
You have to cook the meat to
145 degrees and pork parasites,
which are very dangerous for people.
I'm not, I'm not a huge fan of
naturalistic explanations for religion.
Do I think that's a good one though
for pork? I mean, I don't know.
Like I think you could
make an argument that
died in India and there's
horrific x rays of his head.
He had a parasites from pork that had
gotten into his body and they had a nested
in his brain,
started developing all these cysts
inside of his head and they couldn't do
anything about it because it was so deep
in his head that if they gave him the
antivirus antiparasitic medication,
it would cause swelling of the
brain and they will be like, it was,
it was so far gone. Tell the
story. It's actually pig shit.
Apparently the people accidentally coming
in contact with pig shit produces this
particular type of parasite. Yeah,
it's kosher. It's more rare but,
but trick Kenosis was pretty good
like a long time.
There are attempts to sort of paint back
into the Bible certain rationalistic
explanations like those where
it makes sense though, I think.
Why else would you, would it be bad?
Eat pigs, like Jesus loves pigs.
Is that what's going on?
Uh, well, I, I think that the reversal
of the kosher laws in the New Testament,
you know,
from,
from a Jewish point of view where we
don't believe in the divinity of Christ.
There you can make an argument that
the, the Gospels, which were written,
he was just taking off it
and significant, no, no, no,
we don't even believe he's a prophet.
What do you think he was?
What do you guys think? I mean, I, what I,
what do I think that he was historically,
I think he was a Jew who tried to lead
a revolt against the Romans and got
killed for his trouble.
Just like a lot of other Jews at that
time who were crucified for trying to lead
revolt against the Romans
for their trouble.
So he became legend and story and it
became a bigger and bigger deal as time
went on
for followers.
And then that gradually grew.
And then do you think that says a
wreck? No, that's not, that's not a, uh,
Jewish belief. Okay. I just want to check.
Yeah, no, or we're not into, you know,
not the marquee stories. No, that's
not to have any miracles. No, not, not,
not by Jesus. And then there
was the old testament. Yeah.
You've gotten most of splitting
of the sea and all that.
What do you think happened there?
What do I think happened there? Yeah.
Well I'll go into my mind at ease
and explanation that there was a,
I mean it says in the Bible
there was a strong east wind. Ah.
So there was a naturalistic
explanation for a physical phenomenon.
That makes sense. I mean, that's,
so that's what my mind needs is constantly
trying to do is read nature back into
the Bible.
Hmm. Yeah. That, that is the problem
with these texts, right? Is it,
you're trying to decipher
translations from original tax,
which are written in ancient
Hebrew thousands of years
ago and were told an oral
tradition for longer than that.
Right,
right. I mean this is, this is
where, you know my, my book,
which I always hesitate to pitch my own
stuff because it sounds Gauche pitch
away,
but the new book,
the right side of history and Number One
New York Times bestselling nonfiction
book
mate, you got number one and the
New York Times bestselling fee.
Yeah,
we sold enough that we knocked Michelle
Obama out of the number one slot for a
week. So that was nice. Is there a
protest? Uh, well, no protest yet,
but suffice it to say the New York
Times book review or didn't like it,
but I'm not super shocked by that.
But the basic contention that I make is
that Judeo Christian values on the one
hand and then human reason on the other
Greek reason really that that tradition
is attention and that that tension
is where western civilization lives.
That basically civilization
is a suspension bridge.
It takes certain fundamental
precepts of Judeo Christian values,
the one hand and then takes Greek reason
and they're pulling against each other.
And sometimes reason feels like
it's going to dominate religion.
And sometimes it feels like religion is
going to dominate reason and the best of
all available worlds.
You have a bridge that is,
that is capable of building upon that
where you can actually have a functional
civilization and if you lose
reason in the name of theocracy,
then you end up with tyrannical
theocracy and if you lose,
if you lose religion
in the name of reason,
you end up in some pretty dark places
because human beings don't have a very
good track record of creating their own
purpose, creating their own meaning,
creating their own systems. We tend to
get very utopian very quickly. Right,
and things get really ugly,
which is sort of the story of the,
particularly the first
half of the 20th century.
So this is the benefit of sticking to
the rigid ideology that's prescribed by
religion is that you don't allow the
human beings to keep updating it and
changing it. Because if you do, they
will eventually slide into chaos.
The yes, but there's there, which is not
to say there's not playing in the joints.
There's certainly,
religion has morphed over time of
Judaism as it was practiced originally.
Probably in many ways, does not resemble
Judaism is practiced now. Right? In fact,
the Talmud even says this,
I mean there's,
there's this kind of fascinating and
counter intuitive section of the Talmud
where Moses is, it's, it's uh,
what is called the [inaudible],
which some of these stories that
are just kind of put into the,
into the middle of the Telmate where
Moses comes back and he's watching from on
high as a bunch of rabbis in, you
know, second century Palestine, uh,
are, are talking about Judaism. And he's
like, I don't recognize any of this stuff.
Like I brought down these books from the
mountain and I do not recognize any of
this stuff. And, and God
says to him, you know,
God says to him, right? I mean, this is
how this has morphed and Moses is pleased.
In other words, he's, he's not,
Judaism has always had a common law
tradition where you're using reason to try
and develop the ideas behind
the commandments and then
try and extend them or
broadened them.
And I think that's a good thing,
but you have to be careful
not to completely undermine
fundamental routes or or
get rid of basic precepts.
In other words, you have to,
you have to acknowledge there are certain
fundamental truths that exist there
and then there's play as far
as how those are implemented.
Does Judaism have one of those?
Pray the gay away traditions?
No, that's not it. That's not a thing. I
mean it's what do they want guys to do?
Like what say, what would you
do if not not to, not to sin,
but again soon as a soon as
a thing that everybody does.
Meaning that masturbation is not,
is not okay. According to Judaism,
I assume that a vast
majority of young Jewish men,
even the Orthodox are masturbating.
So people sit in. I mean that's,
that's a recognition. It's, it's always,
again, I think I can speak on behalf of,
I will audaciously speak on behalf
of both Jews and Christians here.
I think that religious people are,
are told that when they say
that something is a sin,
this means that they are looking askance
at the people who are committing the
sin. And that is not correct. I mean,
what Judaism and Christianity say is that
we are all committing sins on a fairly
regular basis. Where we get uptight
is when people start saying,
because I have a desire for the sin,
the sin is no longer a sin. Hmm.
Yeah. The real problem is like what?
Why is it a sin a who says it's a sin?
So again,
who again,
this these rules you were assuming
or influenced by God, right?
But clearly written by people.
Well,
the,
this one you would say if you're a
fundamentalist or at least somebody who
believes in the,
the idea that the Torah was given by God
was giving literally by God. But again,
that doesn't the, the logic
behind the rules, which you know,
people like my monities
have tried to explicate. The
idea is, as I said a second,
this you can do without God, right?
This part you can without God,
the human sex drive was made to procreate
within a stable relationship in order
to pro generate and have
future generations of people
misuse of that sex drive
in any way.
Whether you're talking about from
masturbation to homosexual activity is
therefore a diminishment
of the use of that drive.
That's the natural law case against,
against homosexual activity. And again,
I will reiterate for media
matters for the 1000000th time,
I'm not in favor of any of this being
encoded into American law because freedom
is freedom.
People should be able to send how they
choose so long as they're not harming
anybody else.
Right?
No.
But what about people that have had
vasectomies and what about women that also
Judaism is not cool with this?
Ectomies not cool with it,
but neither is Catholicism from what I
understand. Right, right. Yeah. Well,
I'm not a big fan of that one,
even
though when I have more
experience with, but uh, so if,
what if a man is sterile and the woman's
sterile or they're allowed to have sex
because they both know.
So yes, because there are ancillary
benefits to married couples having sex,
like relationship building.
Right,
but that's not a generalized case
against the favored view of sex. Right.
It's sort of like arguing that intersex
people mean that there's no such thing
as two separate sexes.
There aren't two separate Texas and
also their intersex people who have a
condition. Right. And that
that's the same thing here.
The case in favor of heterosexual sexual
activity does not change based on the
fact that some people can't
actually participate in that.
What would you do if a young gay guy came
to you for advice? If someone said, hey,
Ben, a, I'm an admirer of yours.
I love the way you think and fall your
philosophies, but I've got a problem.
I'm a young Jewish man and I'm
gay and I don't know what to do.
What would you tell them to do?
I mean,
I can't tell them to do anything.
When would you advise,
would you tell?
Would you tell him to not
act out on those feelings?
I would say you do the best
you can as a human being.
And from my moral perspective,
you tried to avoid sin as best you can,
but everybody sins.
The problem does that sin though it
seems to me that it was defined by people
that didn't understand biology because
they were dealing with humans that
existed thousands of
years ago with no books.
No understanding of why people were gay.
No, I mean I again, I,
I really don't think that biblical
commandments are linked and religious
commandments generally are
linked to a view of biology.
Meaning that you don't think so?
No.
I think that sin is a recognition that
we have drives that we are supposed to
forego. Okay. That's
pretty much, I mean that's,
that's fundamental to certainly
Judaism to Christianity as well.
I would say Islam even has,
has this basic preset, right?
Right. When I think we can agree that
there's some real benefits to discipline,
there's real benefits to having structure
and it doesn't mean that you can't be
creative.
It doesn't mean that you can't be free
and do whatever you want some of the time
too. But I think we can both
agree that this is one of the,
one of the best benefits of an ideology
and what hopefully a positive ideology.
Yeah.
Right.
And one of the things that I,
the reason I keep coming
back to the governmental
regulation point is because my
view is that if your view of discipline
is not my view, discipline good on you.
Right? Like go, go do what you want to do.
Like I've never had a conversation
with Dave Ruben about,
about him being a gay guy.
Right.
But you did say that you like wouldn't
go to his marriage. Right? Well,
I said right. As a, as a religious person,
I can't say I can't actively participate
in something that I consider to be a
sin, but I would go out to dinner
with Dave and his husband anytime,
like my wife and I would do that.
Of course we'd have him over
to our house with his husband.
There's no,
you don't find any contradiction between
your religious perspective and your
personal perspective in that
regard that you would do,
you wouldn't be there
for religious reasons,
but that you would be there for
personal reasons. Like if it wasn't,
would you go to the after party? I'll
give, you wouldn't go to the wedding.
Would you go to the APP?
Bart? Anything that was a
celebration of same sex marriage now.
Wow. So anything but like
if we go to the party. No,
I mean that's it and that's
it. I mean there's a barbecue
the next day, et cetera.
You know, it's, it's,
and again, like I'm not sure
why I'm not a good party person,
so I'm not sure why anybody
would want me to write
party. Frankly. Scary. But
haven't been to a party with you.
But I went to a dinner party with
you. That's true. We had a great time.
That was a good time. That was good
times. That's a funny picture, man.
That is why I don't know what the
fuck to think about that picture.
And it's certainly true.
Eric and Jordan and
you and I. It's like what
white supremacist in one place
right now. All the, yeah,
that that is a disturbing one when they'll
just just lump you in with a bunch of
fucking psychopath just
because it's convenient for
them and it's an easy way to
diminish you that that that is a,
that is a thing that I see more from
the left then from the right and it's
really disturbing. I always thought until
this clickbait generation came along,
I always thought that especially,
well,
you know the New York Times is
obviously the higher standard,
but that you would never see that
kind of shit from progressive people.
You would never see willful distortion
of reality to define their narrative and
it's a really disingenuous way and it
happens so often now that people get
called my favorite is alright adjacent.
I know what that means.
It doesn't, they don't know what it means.
That's a new thing. It's a new thing.
People try it out to try to not,
it might go away.
It's, it's again trying to lump everybody
into group for purposes of castigating.
Their motives is really about this.
You don't have to have an argument with
somebody if you assume they're naughty.
So I guess you could call everybody a
Nazi. You don't have to have an argument.
It is goofy.
But you know,
I think when it comes to the,
the gay marriage thing,
what people really worry about is other
people trying to stop people from doing
what they want to do. You don't
have that in you. That's not you.
What you are doing is opposing it
from your, your religious beliefs.
Right?
Like if you want to join into my shoal
that she'll has religious beliefs and
that's their business by the way, there
like I can't join a church. I assume.
I don't believe the things that
people in the church believe
you probably could just donate.
You got to give the right amount of money.
Well, I don't believe in the Jesus.
So there's that. There's that,
that's not my thing. Right. I mean,
so I wouldn't expect to walk into a
mosque and expect them to change their,
their standards on religion.
I find it really audacious when people
actually expect other people to view the
world the same way that they do and then
expect that they're going to be catered
to in that way.
Like I wouldn't walk into a,
I wouldn't walk into a gay owned bakery
and expect them to bake a cake that has
versus from Leviticus on it.
Like why would I do or
weird story, you know, I'm the big cake
store cause it gets bandied about. They,
those folks went to several
Baker's until someone said
no, this is correct. They were
looking for a court case and yeah,
honestly like that's not you being a civil
rights here that you being a jackass,
seriously. Like go to the other
bakery. What do these people do to you?
They didn't have anything to do with you.
They don't owe you their cake.
And if you want to boycott,
then boycott them. Right?
You want to get all your friends to say
we're not going to go buy a cake from
these discriminatory humans. Fine. It's
a free market have at it. But this,
this notion that somebody
owes you their services,
that's that to me it's not even
a freedom of religion case.
To me that one's a freedom
of association case.
Well,
I think what the goal is is to shame a
business into submission and also to,
to put it out there in the public eye so
that people understand that this is the
discrimination that does
happen with gay folks. Will,
they will go somewhere and someone
won't bake a cake for him, you know?
And so I think they
wanted to highlight it.
So if I was being very charitable and w
I didn't think there'd be an attention
whore us, I would say maybe
that's what they're doing.
Maybe they're just trying to
highlight this very real problem.
That's fine. But they actually
like took it to the government.
Once he starts pointing government gun
to people, I get real uptight. So again,
if that's a weird one, if you were, if you
were just to walk into, right, exactly.
Yeah. Right. Talk about how much you
don't like them. Fine. You know, like I,
I may disagree with you or I may agree
with you, whatever. That's, that's fine.
But once you start going to the government
and having the government levy like
hundred thousand dollar fines
on family bakeries because they,
because you couldn't find a gay
baker in Colorado supposedly like,
um, no, I'm sorry. That's, that's
not cool. And I feel the same way.
If I walked into a bakery
and they're like, you're
Jewish, we're not serving you.
I'd be like, okay, you're,
you're in a hole. But all right.
I mean it's free country and
there's a bakery across the street.
Or maybe I'll just open a bakery next
door to you and take your business.
Well,
it's
unfortunate that anyone
would ever think like that,
but should it be a law to force someone
to think differently? You can't,
it doesn't work.
Work. This isn't it. This is my point.
Is it just a slippery to my
religious beliefs and be like, oh,
you're a theocrat and I keep
coming back to I'm not though.
Like I don't want to force
my beliefs on anybody.
Just have those books are my beliefs.
So leave me alone and those are
your beliefs, so leave you alone.
And if we can't have a system where
we acknowledge that those beliefs can
coexist and we can still
have conversations with
each other or be friends,
it's gonna be real hard to have a society.
When you told Dave Rubin that
you wouldn't go to his wedding,
did he get butthurt? No Pun
intended. No, he wasn't upset
about it now. No. Cause it,
cause Dave and I were friends.
He knows that I have no anger or upset
about him doing. I would want every month,
Fuck Ben. Come on man. I Dunno.
I'm not a friends person so I don't
have any friends. I mean I have friends,
but it's like very close
friends and then acquaintances.
I tend to keep a pretty close
social circle. That's smart.
They have so much time in this life
that that's pretty much how I feel.
Like if you're the kind of person where
it feels like a true obligation for me
to drive you to the airport. Oh, not a
thing, man. I'm not driving. Correct.
Correct. There are people who make
money off of you driving to the airport.
As it turns into that this is,
this is exactly correct that those people,
but that does,
that kind of went away for the most part.
So if you find someone who still
ask him for a ride to the airport,
that's a greedy
motherfucker at this point.
You know,
it wasn't your 30 bucks on the Uber,
like your wife or your girlfriend and she
wants to talk to you when you drop her
off at the airport. That's totally
cool. Right? Well this is a standard,
but that's what I mean by that.
I circle of friendship like somebody
where I'm in the car with them for half an
hour and it doesn't feel like an
obligation or a nice conversation,
then that's fine.
But um,
I value community and I,
I value our value.
People talking and trying to
understand each other. And I,
I've seen so much conflict that's
unnecessary because I see so much conflict
that's rooted in people not communicating.
And instead of communicating,
and I think this is one of the things
that I'm most nervous about with all this
deep platforming and censoring people
and the silencing of people on the right.
And it's not that I
agree with these people,
it's that I see how this is just going
to shore up these two sides and it's
going to make it a much more difficult,
much more difficult
atmosphere for communication,
for real understanding and coming to
agreements on things and and recognizing
the things that we all, all good
people seem to agree. You could try,
you should try to help each other.
She'd be kind to each other.
You should work hard, you should have good
morals and ethics. You shouldn't steal,
you shouldn't take from,
people shouldn't lie,
you shouldn't try to cheat the government.
You shouldn't try to cheat people.
Just be a good fucking person.
And that this,
this transcends religious ideologies.
It transcends political leanings.
It really does. And it should.
And we can have a truly diverse community,
truly diverse,
not forced diversity,
diverse
meaning some people are progressive,
some people are conservative,
some people who are libertarian.
You can joke with each other.
We can all get along together
and disagree with things.
Just not be fucking hateful towards
each other. This is possible, but it,
it becomes less possible when people feel
like they're being silenced or sensors.
Totally right.
And it's also true that when you,
when you castigate somebody
is morally on equal,
what you're really doing is you're giving
you an excuse to get into their shit.
I mean, it was like this is
what's really happening here.
Like if I had a slogan beyond the facts,
don't care about your feelings stuff.
He'll just leave me alone. Yeah.
Right. Don't get into my shit.
Like I'm not bothering you,
so why are you bothering me?
And if I have a belief system
that's different than yours,
then so the hell, what?
As long as I'm not bothering you,
what difference does it make to you?
How I feel about things?
The only thing about the
gay thing is that it's not you. You have
a belief about things that's not you.
But I have lots of beliefs about
things that are not me, right?
But there are people that aren't hurting
each other. But it's so what, I mean,
I can believe that people who
aren't hurting each other,
like I'm not a fan of prostitution.
So like,
so I am not a fan of people.
Here's some, somebody got hurt.
Prostitution's clearly more of a choice
than I think gay people are. Okay.
But I'm, I'm right. But I
know you're coming back,
coming back to the same moral distinction
which I've ever repeated a few times,
which is that I'm not a believer that a
natural desire to do something therefore
makes an activity. Okay. But that's, but
that's a view that has no extra Alli's,
my view has no externality.
So in the same way, listen,
I believe about people who eat too much
and get obese because they eat too much.
I think it's a bad thing to do.
I do think it's my business.
You want to do it your problem. Like you
want to, you want to eff up your life.
That's what freedom is called, right?
Isn't it one of the seven deadly sins.
Gluttony. Yeah. That again, a
question thing, but yeah, but,
but yes, I mean, and I have,
I've lots of beliefs about lots of
things that people do. And by the way,
so to you, things that don't affect
you, right? I, and this is, we all do,
but as long as I'm not forcing that on
you because there are no externalities,
true behavior, I don't see why it
bothers you. Like they're legitimately,
I would assume tens of millions of people
in this country who believe that when
I die I will go to hell. Right. And I
don't know. I don't believe in Jesus.
And so there are a lot of people
believe I don't believe in Jesus,
therefore I am bound for hell.
That does not bother me. One,
I Yoda cause no one's bothering
me. So what do I care? Right?
Like I don't understand why
everyone doesn't take this view.
If I'm not legitimately bothering you,
why should,
why should you care what
I think like this is,
this is what would be puzzling me if
somebody came to me and they wanted my
opinion on something because they valued
my opinion that much. I give my opinion,
but it's a f you don't have
to care about my opinion
sync when it comes to the gay thing
where people are looking for is to people
for other folks to be accepting of who
they are and I think for a lot of these
gay folks had been in the closet their
whole life. That's the big things.
They're always worried about someone
treating them differently or someone
diminishing them because they're gay.
Then when they hear someone like you say
that you think it's a sin and that you
shouldn't act on your biology,
even though you have these urges
that you should instead find a woman,
they feel the same pangs.
Rejection
that I for sure get that,
but the,
the confluence between activity
and identity is actually
kind of a dangerous one
meeting. Then the, you know, the,
the idea that if I disapprove of
an activity in which you engage,
that I disapprove of you.
Right.
I disapprove of lots of activities
in which lots of people engage,
including most members of my family,
including my children and a
lot of the time that's not me.
I just approve of them as a human being
or that I'm di I'm saying they are
lesser as a human being that like we
all interact with people this way.
Like you disapprove of my view on this.
I don't get the feeling you
disapprove of me as a human being. No,
I don't practice a religion. You obviously
think of my religion is bullshit,
but that's okay. I don't care. Like
why was, I don't think it's bullshit.
I wouldn't say,
I think it's bullshit.
You can still like God spoke to somebody
in the mountains. Bullshit. Right?
Well I don't even know if that's bullshit.
What I do know is that it's a historical
interpretation of stories that were as
much as they could or as little as they
want it to be accurately defined and
written down and then passed on from
generation to generation. For example.
You think the fact that I won't eat
pork is kinda stupid bullshit. No,
I don't think it's stupid bullshit. First
of all, I think pigs are intelligent.
I wish they weren't wild.
I have a deep affinity to pigs and
really good example here. I love them.
But I also kill them and eat
them. I mean, I kill wild pigs.
Let me be broader about this.
You're not an orthodox Jews,
so I assume there are things
about the things that I do, but I,
there are certain things of which
I believe or practice that you,
that you probably disapprove or you
don't think they're the smartest or you
think that there might
not think is the smartest.
But as I've gotten older
and hopefully wiser,
I give a fuck less about
why you do what you do,
but whether or not the benefits seem to
be worth the juice is worth the squeeze.
Right. And in your case, I think
the juice is worth the squeeze.
I think you're a very successful person.
You're very reasonable.
You're very intelligent.
You're an outstanding debater.
And I enjoy talking to him,
listening to on Youtube. Um,
I think part of that is because of
the fact that your religion, right?
Of your religious,
I think it's cross training.
I think in a lot of ways it's like
if you lift weights for Jujitsu,
it makes you stronger.
Don't make your Jujitsu better
as long as you keep training.
I think your discipline
from your religion has,
there's psychological benefits to it.
Right? Or is that totally benefits to it?
I totally get all that.
That gets to the point.
The point is that we're different people.
So there are certain activity in which
I engage that you probably think,
well that's, I wouldn't do that to
kind of dumb and that's okay. I don't,
I wouldn't though. I would,
but I wouldn't, I wouldn't,
I don't want to do it.
I don't want to wear a Yamaka. Right. I
get it. I understand why you would do it.
Hard to keep it on your head.
Just glue it.
What would it called zoots do they
put up double stick tape there?
You can not allow it to now.
You can. You totally can.
But it seems to be painful
and uncomfortable. Yeah.
Um, definitely says that.
And living in a society, we
all are constantly disapproving
of each other. Right?
Politics is just us disapproving
of each other all the time.
And so long as we're not forcing
that on anybody else. I really
don't see the problem. And I think
everybody should sort of get over it.
Like if I don't approve of your
personal behavior, welcome to the club.
I disapprove of 99% of people's personal
behavior, including my own habits.
Do you,
how,
how often do you debate people on the
merits of religion or the merits of your
beliefs?
Um, you know, not, not super frequently,
but not infrequently. I mean,
like I,
I mentioned that I've,
I've had this conversation with Sam a
couple of different times in public.
Well, he's, he's so rabid as an atheist.
He's my religion. Sam is more
religious than I am. Sam.
Sam is more of a religious
atheist than I am.
Like I'll admit questions about
my own religion. Sam is very,
very convinced of his,
of his correctness and in his viewpoint,
Sam Sam's a religious dude.
He's a fascinating guy. I
liked him a lot. And again,
and Michael Shermer,
uh,
I've had on my show to talk about
religion and skepticism and all that.
I'm not shy about talking about it.
I just, sometimes I find that it's,
it's kind of a dead end because sometimes
it just turns into I believe in God
and then the person's like,
I don't believe in God. And
it's like, well, okay, fine.
Now. Now can we talk about
the stuff we think are the,
what are the fundamental building blocks
upon which you can basis society or
basic politics? And if we agree on
those, then you know, the God stuff,
I think God is a better base for
those fundamental policies and, and,
and belief systems. I think free
speech, individualism, democracy,
these are based on a simple
verse in Genesis that human
beings are made in God's
image. I think that that's a logical
leap. This is the case I've made to it,
to see him.
I don't think that you can actually
get to human beings are of inestimable
inestimable value from
scientific materialism.
If you believe that human beings
are effectively just animals,
then I don't know why they
would be of infinite value,
nor why I should respect somebody's
belief system simply because they're human
and I don't respect animals. And if
we're just another animal, I, there's no,
there's nothing that necessitates
that logical line of the, in fact,
for most of human history, it was not
the logical line of thinking it was,
if you're a member of my tribe,
then we like you,
and if you're not a member of my tribe,
then we'd get to kill you.
A logical comparison like is isn't
there a difference between single celled
organisms and the way a primate
interacts with its environment?
I mean,
yes,
but I'm not sure why that would indicate
any sort of greater existential value.
It's not necessarily a
greater existential value,
but as we were talking about the value
of community and the value of having a
group of people that you
care about that this is,
this is a core component of being human.
This is a,
it's a core component of this
understanding mind, rational,
intelligent,
interfacing with the universe in a
way that no other animals capable.
I'm not saying you can't get to
the point where Sam agrees with me.
I'm saying that I think it's less
convincing than Sam thinks it is. Meaning,
there's an alternative line of
thought that says, okay, you're right,
social fabric is great,
you know,
or that social fabric is particularly
awesome among me and my friends.
I know where it ain't that great.
Those guys over there,
let's go kill him and take their shit.
I'm really like that.
That was pretty much how humanity
works for very, very long time. Uh,
and the simple and effective idea that
the reason that human beings are of value
is because we are more than
just our material bodies.
That there's something that is
us that is of inestimable value.
That's a religious concept and
it has a lot of weight. Now,
if Sam wants to get to the same place
and we can build a political conversation
from there,
that's fine.
My real argument was Sam is Sam and I go
down to the bottom of the iceberg about
90% of the way we have the same
fundamental values about free speech,
diversity of opinion about I think two,
two mostly an extent free markets.
Uh, you know, I think that we agree on
a lot of these fundamental principles.
He then says that he gets
those from pure reason.
I have serious questions about
whether pure reason necessitates those
conclusions.
He tends to think that those are the only
conclusions a reasonable person could
come to if you properly apply a reason.
I don't think that's right.
What do you think is happening there?
What's the mechanism?
I think that the mechanism
is that we are common.
What I said to Sam when we were debating
this in San Francisco is it's real
weird.
He's a materialist,
scientific materialist atheist who
is sitting across the stage. For me,
a religious Jew, we agree on
95% of our values. So how,
and his answer was, well, you
know, here's where I've studied.
I've studied Buddhism,
I've studied these philosophies and
I've studied science and all this.
Is that right?
I haven't studied a lot of those things,
but we have the same value.
So why it seems to me a better historical
explanation is that we have grown,
we grew up 10 miles from each other in
Los Angeles after 3000 years of common
history of Judeo Christian development,
balanced with reason in the west.
Like location has
something to do with this.
And that location was rooted in
commonality of interest in philosophy.
So I, I'm less, it's, it's,
there's a weird nexus and I don't want
to get to kind of deep in the weeds here.
There's a weird kind of
nexus on what truth is. Uh,
the where you've heard Sam and Jordan
Peterson debate us. It was insane. It was,
it's wild, right? Um, and the truth is,
I'm closer to Sam than Jordan on this,
so I'm closer to Jordan than Sam when
it comes to the value of religion.
And I'm closer to Sam than Jordan.
When it comes to objective truth,
Sam believes that there is such
a thing as objective truth.
Jordan tends to be more of a pragmatist.
He tends to believe that truth is sort of
what is useful to a certain extent. Um,
and my,
I grew with Sam,
but I'm not sure how he gets to objective
truth from a scientific materialist
worldview.
Why is their objective truth as opposed
to what you think is what you think
being evolutionarily beneficial.
How do you get from that too?
It's a universal principle that is
objective Lee. True. It's, it's,
it's a bit of a jump. Well it depends
on what the concept is, right?
Like what are you talking about
in terms of, I'm talking about,
I'm talking about anything
that Sam says is true.
What makes it true as opposed to just
evolutionarily beneficial for us to think.
So meaning what evolution does is it
creates a series of thoughts in our mind.
Presumably if you're a materialist that
are beneficial to your preservation and
promulgation of the species, right?
They're not active actually true.
So if it's beneficial,
this is the Sam's real explanation for
the prevalence of religion. For example,
he'll say religion is true,
but evolutionary biology sort of
drives people toward religions.
So you can have group bonds that
are beyond 150 people or whatever.
So why doesn't that apply to math?
Why is it the two and two?
How do you know that too?
And to actually equals four as opposed
to it is evolutionary been evolutionarily
beneficial for you to believe
that two plus two equals four.
So Sam believes there is an
objective truth somewhere out there.
The two plus two equals four I don't
know what evolution has to do with that
sort of stuff. So what do you think
is happening that he disagrees with?
So I think that what is happening is that
human beings were placed in an orderly
universe through the processes of
biology and have a unique capacity to
understand that universe because
we are made in the image of God.
This is where I think that the religious
viewpoint diversity is pretty strongly
from from Sam's usually
leave in evolution. Yes.
Believe that evolution was a process that
was created by God to formulate human
beings.
Yes. Interesting. Yeah. I
mean that's, that's the nice
thing about being religious.
You can attribute most, most
everything to goddess. It's fine.
Here's the thing,
it's not that implausible.
If there was some sort of a grand plan,
there would be no regard for like all,
but got to get a rush on this.
Making the evolutionary being,
you know, we're going to,
you know, but it was all
salaried. The process.
It's a fine tuning arguments about how
implausible it would be for just Adam's
roaming around the universe randomly to
end with with human creation. You know,
the, the alternative
explanations seemed no, no more,
no less implausible to me,
like the multiple
universes theory plausible,
but we have no way to prove it because
we can't get to those multiple universes.
So how that testable or the or the now
popular theory that we're living in an AI
simulation, not sure how
that's more testable than God.
Not sure how it's more testable
that aliens put us here.
Like how has any of this test,
why is that more testable
or more plausible than the
idea that there is a force
behind that which we see that has mine.
Well, let's, let's just
break this down slowly.
There is obviously
something that's happening.
There's obviously something that went
from the Big Bang to planet earth in 2019
with cellular communication and
satellite dishes and obviously something
happened, something pretty
radical. Why is it happening?
Is it happening because of random events
that sort of coincide with biology and
the technology and all these things
come to fruition to you and I standing
across from each other talking on this
podcast in front of millions of people
w or it
is this,
is this just how things go is things
compete constantly try to get better and
then in this gigantic ecosystem of all
these things competing and trying to get
better,
one super successful organism us rises
above and continues and continues and by
far passes all these other
creatures below it and moves.
We in our estimation,
I mean if you,
if you really believe in evolution
you can't think we're done right.
It's got to be moving towards some better
product and it keeps going until it
creates so [inaudible] Sam
is more religious than I am.
I think that there's a
plausible argument for atheism.
I just don't think that
there is a plausible argument
for Sam's moral vision of
atheism. Meaning that what, what,
what Sam tends to do, is it like,
for example,
you and I have talked a lot on this
particular podcast about the value of self
betterment and making decisions and
being responsible for those decisions.
How does that work in an area
where you don't have free? Well,
so Sam actively says we do not have free,
well, yeah, that's a weird conversation.
It is. It is a weird conversation
and sort of a self defeating one.
Sam suggests when it comes
to the scientific method
that we are using science to
find out truths about the universe
and we're using reasons him.
He's very big on reason.
I also am big on reason,
but I don't know how Sam is defining
reason as opposed to just Aiden,
evolutionarily beneficial
firing of neurons.
Meaning that that's what we are at.
We're balls Balsamiq wandering
purposeless through the universe.
And then he'll talk about making our
own meaning or seeking human human
prosperity or a flourishing
is the word he likes to use.
These are all very active
verbs, right? This is this,
is it an active vision of
man in the universe? Right.
And I'm not sure how that flows from,
we're a ball of meat that
evolve from another ball of
meat that evolve to wrench.
Really, if you go back far enough
from non balls of meat without any,
without any free will, without
any capacity to choose. I don't,
I don't know how you build
a civilization on that.
Well,
there's two different conversations here.
One is determination
or determinism rather,
whether or not you have freewill or
whether or not your life and your actions
are being dictated by the past, by your
biology, by your learned experiences,
by external pressures.
What is causing this very clear
decision that you make is this freewill?
Oh, you decided I'm going
to get my shit together,
or all the factors around you pushing
you and funneling you into this,
this direction that you, it's
unavoidable to you. Right?
And that you are not
a product of freewill.
You're just a product of a lot of
different factors, right? Or is it both?
Is it that you are the product of your
environment and your life experiences
end?
You also have free will,
right? And I'm, I'm in the latter. Yeah.
I'm in the latter group.
I think as well.
I think we also experienced great benefit
from making positive choices and then
experiencing like whenever you meet
someone who's lost a lot of weight,
one of the things they have is his fucking
tremendous feeling of accomplishment.
Yup. Yeah, I lost a hundred pounds. You're
like, holy shit man, a hundred pounds.
Right? Like they get this positive
feedback from it. There's,
there's real good and making good choices.
And when people decide to get their
shit together and make a good choice,
there were awarded.
The question is,
are you doing that because of determinism
or are you doing that because of
freewill? Or are you doing that because
of a combination of both of those things?
And can you fuel that freewill purposely
through like outwardly seeking things
that are motivational or
things that are educational,
things that allow you to kind of roadmap
the way you process reality, right?
Which can be beneficial and can aid in
you taking steps towards exercising your
freewill.
Right.
Well this, and this is why I
think that in the end it, right,
but I think it's pretty
fundamental question.
And I think that that's why in the end
I'm religious and I'm not sure why Sam
isn't because he agrees with the
same premises, right. He'll, he'll,
he'll talk about self betterment and
decisions that you can make and then he'll
write a full book about why
free will doesn't exist.
And I just don't understand how
those two things can coexist.
Yes. It's a, well, I think it's a
thought experiment, first of all,
I think the whole determinism thing is
a thought experiment because there's
really no way to determine,
right.
You have the argument though,
for sure. Right. I mean,
like there's just no way to,
to act to otherwise.
Yeah.
Um, but I, I guess I've absolutely
act as if I have free will.
Right. And we all do. And I get angry
at myself when I fucked things up.
I don't say, well, it's just
determined as a man. Right, right. No,
that doesn't get you in the,
and the button may be,
it's determinism that has put me in this
position where I'm the kind of guy that
gets upset if I fuck things
up. Right. No, I don't know,
man. I don't know, but I don't
know if you know either. That's my,
my take on all these things. When people
get really rigid with their ideologies.
Yeah. I'm like, okay, I want to hear
it out. I want to hear the whole thing.
You know, I want to hear it all. I'm
not sure if you know, I think there's a,
I think there's no,
I think there's a lot that I don't know,
but I think that there's more plausible
and less plausible. Yeah, I agree. Um,
this is where I think people
misunderstand you. You have your beliefs,
but you're not a car that
imposes them on people.
And I think we need to be way more
reasonable in terms of the way we address
people's beliefs. And, uh, I've
been guilty of this in the past.
I'm sure many people,
everyone else, everyone has.
But I think it's a core component to a
healthy community is to allow people to
have their own beliefs. And
you know, who knows, man,
maybe your beliefs on gay people will
adjust and move over time as you get older
and move into a gay neighborhood. And
I don't know. It looks good. It's not,
it's not about tolerance.
Fire.
Yeah. I mean I don't,
yeah, yeah. It's, it, it's,
it's a difference between
understanding people are as,
as whole people and then saying that I
don't like some of the things that they
do and simply saying the
making the assumption that
because I don't like some of
the things that you do,
we can't be friends or I disapprove
of you as an entire human being,
which I think is not true.
True.
It's a good belief system to have.
If you're straight and then you go look,
got it locked down. Don't need to
worry about that. I got a prop.
But if you were gay god down, there'll
be a pain. Absolutely. I mean,
it would be annoying if you just always
wanted to bang dudes and everyone's
saying no and you're like, no, no, no.
Nobody said religions. Easy, man. What's
the value in it though? If you're a,
if you're a giant homo,
all right,
and all you want to do is go to
gay discos and party your ass off.
That's what you enjoy. Some people
like golf. Okay. Some people,
some people like parasailing, some dudes
just want to fucking get it on, man.
Want to dress
up like the village people
and go have a fucking party.
That's why Santa Monica Blvd,
such a hotspot and they find each other.
Do whatever you want to do. Honestly, do
whatever you want to do. Men Don't do it.
Ask me to think that you know,
don't ask me to like put my stamp of
moral approval. I understand that.
Do what you want to do. Like
it's a free country. This,
this should be a free country,
not just, it is a free country.
It should be a free country.
It should not be my job to police
your personal behavior. Right? Right.
Like you as, I mean I have to approve
it on a personal level, right,
but I'm a jerk if I want to
impose my belief system on,
on your personal behavior
that affects no one else.
I mean that's the definition of being an,
and I'm a hypocrite if I continue
to berate you about your,
your opinion on gay folks. What do I
give a fuck what your opinion is correct.
Because you are a reasonable person
and you do, you're very polite and eve,
you're in friends with Dave Ruben.
So there you go.
This guy has got to be
something there. It's, um,
it's a strange thing though, this, uh,
this need that people have for everyone
to think the way they think and I
understand the need to
reinforce your own thoughts and,
and,
and argue them and try to figure out a
way to debate that the other person's
perspective is incorrect and
your perspective is correct.
I understand all these inclinations
that people have, but uh, I,
I think that they conflate that
with bigotry. Right. You know,
and I don't think,
I don't think you're a bigot.
I don't agree with you about gay folks,
but that's one of the,
the marijuana thing is just,
I just don't think you have any experience
center. Right. And as far as
the, as far as disagreeing,
I think that we probably
don't disagree on gay folks.
I think we disagree on identity and gay
activity and all the rest of it. I mean,
as human beings,
these are human beings that I know many
gay people who I think are significantly
better human beings than religious people.
Yeah, yeah. I'm glad you
said that. Yeah, I think
it did it in a way.
I don't have a defined religion,
but in a way I have some pretty rigid
ideas that I have in my head about
behavior and ethics and morals and
how you treat PB care about those are,
those are like,
they're pretty rigid.
And I think one of the
things that religion does is
it allows you to have this
sort of ethical framework sort of like,
um,
what is it called scaffolding?
Like when you're building it,
like it allows you to develop
a more disciplined life
and it just shows you this
is good and this is bad and it's
clear and there's this most,
for the most part it's good
for the most part. These are,
these are good patterns to follow.
And I think that I've most certainly sort
of adopted my own somewhere along the
way.
I think we all do. Yeah. I mean, honestly,
a value system effectively is
usually a form of religion. Right?
So when you're saying
that Sam has religious, he's a religious
ACA atheists, you're not. Yeah.
You're not being inaccurate.
There's a lot of folks do that.
We do develop these sort of
principles that we follow.
We're not just free willy nilly just
doing whatever we want all day long.
No one does that.
And the reason I say it
is sort of facetiously,
but I think that we all make fundamental
assumptions about the nature of human
life and we have to recognize that
those are assumptions. You can't, it's,
it's not reason all the way down.
Yeah.
That because that tends to actually
become even more inflexible than it's,
I'm the only reasonable
person in the room.
My reasons are the only ones that matter.
And so it's my reasons all the way down
the acknowledge that we're all making
some assumptions and then we can
discuss whether those assumptions are
worthwhile or not.
Yeah. The thing that when it comes with
religion in defining whether or not other
people's behaviors sinful,
but where it doesn't involve you,
that's where a lot of folks start thinking
that maybe these ideas are bigoted.
Right.
But it does involve me,
meaning that the diamond, well, I'm,
I'm enjoying every sin that I say
is a sin is a sin that enjoins me.
It's just that I may not have a
desire for that particular sin
in meaning I'm not,
I'm not holding people to a different
standard than I hold myself,
nor am I saying that I never sin.
Right.
But you know that you have different
biological desires and they do.
You can kind of acknowledge
that. All right. Of course,
that's true. Yeah, of course.
That's true.
By the same token,
I assume that a gay guy doesn't have
the desire to set up a thousand women,
which most straight guys do. Yeah. Why
do you think if, if God has a plan,
why do you think you would create gay
people? I mean, I think that God creates,
first of all, I don't think that I'm
in a position to evaluate God's plan.
I wish I work. But if you like
gods, if I, if I had to guess,
God creates people with all sorts of
different challenges and those challenges
span the spectrum.
I mean I,
I'm not so God sneaks it up on you. Hey
Man, I know this is gonna be fucked up,
but you're going to just like,
Dude's like forget about women.
You're gonna like dudes. I am not. I want
you to ignore that one of my old book.
I don't know why God gives people drives.
I don't know. I got gives kids cancer.
I don't know a lot of things about God.
Wish I did.
It would make my life a lot easier.
So you think that that is a challenge
akin to any other challenge that a human
being might face in this life that the
challenge have been a lot harder. Yeah,
but a lot more difficult and a lot more
straining and lot. Yeah, of course.
You think there's value in following that
challenge and not acting on gay urges.
I think the, I think there can be,
and you're having sex with a woman,
plug your nose,
go through and make a face cause
you discussed or did you create it?
Did you create a baby out of that?
Did that bit,
is that baby like a part of your life
now that does it that is deep and
meaningful. Mm. Maybe. What about
there are a lot of in and pass it.
There are a lot of gay guys having kids.
What about people saying
living their truth? I'm living
in my truth. Ben Shapiro.
Well I mean as a general rule, living my
truth as a bunch of crap. Like there's,
there's living your opinion,
which is fine,
like live your opinion and how you want.
Again,
that gets back to do what you want.
As long as it's not bothering me.
Living my truth is a different thing.
That's one of them.
Social media creations
like living my truth.
That's just bullshit. I'm sorry.
[inaudible] my truth is bullshit. It's,
there's no such thing.
Your truth.
There's that truth and then there
is your opinion and we do have to,
for purposes of conversation,
at the very least,
it's deeply irritating when people say
living my truth, because then it's like,
I disagree with you, and then
they're like, well, you're,
you're disavowing music.
Human being. No, I just disagree. Like
you can be you, you can do what you want.
Like you do whatever,
man. Calm, calm. Yeah.
Like I'm I, how did I become the
most loosey Goosey Libertarian,
lean back guy in the world, in
the society. How is this possible?
The most uptight person I know.
How is this a thing? Well,
you know as well as I do that the
further you go left you, you, you,
you reached the same sort of zealotry
that you do when you go all the way rice,
correct.
You,
you meet these crazy people that are just
completely connected to their idea of
being correct and they take the most
rigid stance on all these issues on the
left side or on the right side and it's
so goddamn common. It's human behavior.
It's also incredibly boring. I mean
there's just nothing to discuss with with,
yeah,
I agree and that's one of the reasons
why it's so disgusting when people miss
labeled people like so it was an article
that connected me with Richard Spencer.
Like what?
And the fuck.
Like that is such a disingenuous thing
to do and they know what they're doing.
They're the trying to get me to react to
it and talk about it and we'll get more.
It's put it's horse shit like anybody,
but if you are locked into that far
left ideology as far left as you can go,
and it's one of the problems
with ideologies that have
these extremists is that
you believe in a percentage of
the things these people say,
but then they go way too far with it.
But you're connected with them.
You're connected with them
because you're a part of that.
Even though you don't
have a similar notion.
Steven pinker got brow
beaten over suggesting that
failure to ask questions and
give plausible answers gives,
excuse me,
credence to the alt right
that that if you do a essay,
he did a whole speech where he said,
listen,
there are lots of conversations about Iq
and race and they all right loves these
conversations because then they then
they suggest wrongly the black people are
inherently unfit and white people are
more fit and all of that kind of stuff and
he says there are great ways to
explain how much of Iq is is cultural,
how much can be changed,
how much has genetic,
how much that actually matters
in terms of real life outcomes.
We can do all those things,
but when you say don't ask the question,
stop asking the question,
then you make people Google.
And the only thing that they will Google
and find our answers that are given by
people who are actually outright,
and he got ripped as
outright for this argument,
was don't allow people to push into
outright answers by failing to give them
proper responses or by throwing them out
the window. And then people are like,
well, you're all right now
because you're saying that,
that people should be able to ask
questions like, it's almost like,
it's just like,
it's the exact same version as people in
the religious community where it's like,
you know,
I used to go to Sunday school and then I
asked him any questions and they kicked
me out. Right? That's, that's
not how religion is supposed
to work. That's not how,
that's not how reason it's supposed to
work, not how any of this is supposed
to work. Right. And there's also,
when you're investigating any thing,
any measurable thing, w when you
find a number, whatever it is,
like these people, like a Asian
folks are better at mathematics. UH,
European folks are better at this and
like what is, what's the reason for that?
Like what, what's, let's find out,
is it cultural, is it biologicals?
It's something can we learn about
how human beings evolved and adapted?
Why are Nigerian so smart?
Like there's so many Nigerians that
come to this country. They thrive,
they thrive in business.
They're extremely motivated.
They're extremely disciplined. It's
like, it's like almost like Korean folks.
Why do Koreans like, why are they so
hardworking? Why are they strived?
And obviously these are big
generalizations, but what
is it about Italians? What,
what, what makes them wear gold chains
and loved mafia movies? Like what is it?
Those are my people.
We go with the what the fuck?
Why are they all talk like that?
Like what is that?
What causes any sort of ethnic group
to turn out the way they turned out?
What and why are so many European
Jews Nobel Prize winners?
What the fuck is going on over there
and also like what is the impact of the
measurable on how we live our lives? Like
Shit, how much should this stuff matter?
Is this,
is this a result of discrimination or
is this a result of something else?
Is it true that when you group
any group of people together,
racially or non racially,
there will be disparities between
those two groups of people.
This is just true statistically like,
but not asking those questions and
then saying, shut down the questions.
What that actually does is it leads
people to only get the answers to the
questions from the people who don't
know what they're talking about in many
cases and who are giving convenient,
easy,
and self laddering answers about
the nature of, of themselves.
The fear is it being used by racist
to reinforce their position? Right,
but what you find out is that those agents
are a superior race, right? They'll,
they'll do and they'll do that anyway.
One of the,
one of the funniest things about white
supremacists is they're so fucking stupid.
I mean, pardon the language. Like the,
the white supremacists are invariably
not the Nobel prize winners. It's, it's,
hey,
go to a white supremacist compound.
You're not looking at a bunch of
people who are carrying cancer.
These people piss me off and it,
and this is an now and I'll say, oh,
that won't matter to medial label me
outright tomorrow. Cause that's what I,
this goes well,
the disingenuous media that's being less
and less taken seriously taking less
than less seriously.
It seems to me that that trend,
which is a common trend that's existed
for the last few years of these click
baity bullshit articles
and mislabeling people,
it's going to go away because your,
your,
your perspective is not
going to be appreciated.
It's not going to be respected if you,
if you're obviously making disingenuous
statements like that. And I think, um,
we're in this weird position where it's
very difficult to find real journalism
and real objective takes on things
that aren't flavored by their ideology.
And everybody's trying to shape
everybody and they feel like it's their
obligation.
They feel there's many people that
write things that feel like it's their
obligation to change your perspective on
a national subjects and things that are
important to us that not their obligation
to just report what's going on,
but also their obligation to flavor things
in a way that will make one side look
favorable to the other.
Yeah. Well, I'm, I'm very much in favor
of journalists revealing their biases.
I think that the,
the greatest line media is that
objective journalism is a thing.
So I'm conservative.
You don't go to my site,
you'll get a conservative spend on the
news. That's the way it's going to work.
Right?
And guess what?
CNN is liberal and they're going to
give you the liberal spin on the news.
And that's just the way this is
going to work to do. See the video,
when the Mueller report came out and
they look, look, somebody got killed.
Oh my God. It was crazy. Shit.
Kennedy got shot. Yeah. Exit. Yeah.
Should you be happy if you guys
believed in Mueller, everybody was like,
Mueller is the fucking man. He's going to
go get Trump. This guy, he's methodical.
He's precise,
people getting booted out and everything.
Votive candles with his face on them that
they could like bird. They were pumped.
Yeah. And then he came out and it was
like, well no collusion or it was like,
well I guess that now it's a
cover up. It's like, wait, what?
Wait a minute. Yeah, maybe.
Maybe. Maybe the narrative has it,
maybe the narrative has,
has,
has trumped the actual job
you were supposed to do guys?
Well,
it's just so many people were so convinced
and there were so many people that
were making statements that
in retrospect are probably
like you could probably,
I mean,
I don't want to say I'm
not a litigious person,
but if I was a guy like Donald Trump, oh
man. Yeah. There's so many people to sue.
It was,
it was amazing.
I mean I remember I was on Bill Maher's
show and we were supposed to talk about
free speech stuff in like five
minutes before and he's like,
let's talk about Russia, his producer,
Kevin, let's talk about Russia.
And I was like, okay, fine. So we
get on to producers so that, yeah,
this is like right before they switched
the topic for your TV shows where they
just tell you what you have to talk.
The guy comes in with a clipboard. Yeah,
it was, it was a little bit,
it was a little bit strange.
And we got on stage and we, he's
talking about Trump, Russia collusion,
and I said what I've always said,
which is I'll wait for the evidence to
come out and then I will make a decision
as to whether Trump, Russia collusion
was a thing and Bill Maher's Datical.
I know. And Bill Margot's you don't,
you don't believe it was a thing.
And I was like, well I don't see any
evidence yet that it was a thing.
Like I see some evidence of attempts to
collude like John Jr I see some attempts
of people trying to get information,
but I don't see evidence of
like actual legal collusion.
And why don't we just wait like you guys
keep wanting Muller to gives her like
let's just wait on it. And Mark could
not believe that this was my perspective.
Right. It was like, it was like
shocking to him. Why should,
why should the perspective,
I'm waiting for more evidence be
shocking to anyone when it is obvious the
evidence is not out. Like why? Why is
that in any way controversial? It's,
it's bewildering to me
because people have this need to let
everyone know that they're on the right
side and they want you to know that
they do believe in the collusion.
If you disagree with
that for whatever reason,
you must either be a right wing person,
a Trump supporter or
someone who's in denial,
someone who doesn't look at the evidence
and you're a part of the problem. Yup.
But the, the real problem
was jumping to conclusions.
There obviously seem to be some attempts.
There's,
there's obviously some fuckery
with that IRA company that the,
the Internet research agency
that is responsible for
millions of interactions
with people online where they
pretended to be different
supporters. Yes. They,
they caused conflict,
like constant conflict in regards to
political opinion and that's all real.
That was coordinated effort to
try to change people's opinions,
but how much that had to do with Donald
Trump. How much did they ask for?
First of all, you've got no
evidence. Also, I was always
bewildered by this theory,
like did you watch that campaign?
Um,
that was not the most well coordinate
campaign and it was chaos. It was chaos.
I mean, I knew everybody who was
in the campaign, like it was a,
it was a shit show and the idea that
they're sitting there but there,
but when the mass comes off at night,
they call it Vladimir Putin and they put
together a point by point plan on how
they're going to swing this
particular precinct in rural,
in rural Michigan. It's like, what?
What are you, are you guys hi?
Like what are you talking
about? Like, like it,
if you could attribute
this to anything here,
here's a good rule of thumb for politics.
Attribute everything to stupidity.
Unless you can prove malice.
The real problem,
and this is something that is very similar
in what we were talking about earlier.
When you say something and you say
it over and over and over again,
and you say it with such conviction and
it becomes a giant part of your news
narrative and then that's something
turns out to be horseshit. Yup.
You just massively empowered Trump.
That's it. That's exactly right.
And a massive land for a
long time that you know,
I'm not a big fan of Trump's fake news
shtick because I think he applies it to
broadly. I think that whenever
there's a bad piece of news,
he's like fake news and it's like,
well sometimes yes and sometimes no
by now that you just blew a two year
narrative where he was
clearly in Putin's pocket,
how many people were you
thinking to listen to the
nuanced view of fake news now
and how many people do you think are
going to actually believe Trump when he
says that a bad piece of news is
legitimately a fake piece of news. Yeah.
And empowers him in a, in
a, in a spectacular manner.
They made a giant mistake.
Oh yeah. And they blew, they blew
this one in spectacular fashion.
People are still hanging in
there with all they had to do.
This is true for so many people right now.
All you have to do is not be crazy.
Just stop it.
It's all you have to do.
It was talking about the possibility
that Trump has been a Russian assets and
it's like 1987 or some shit, so
it was a, I mean Andrew Mccabe,
the former FBI director was asked whether
Trump was legitimately a Russian asset
and he's like, I don't know. It's like
you're using the power of the institution.
He used to run to spread this nonsense
and he got that from John Brennan.
He got it from James Clapper and these
are all former heads of the intelligence
agencies.
Just makes me think the intelligence
agencies need to be wildly her back.
If these were the heads of them.
I mean if like the heads of
the intelligence agencies
are using their platform
to proclaim that they have
inside information about Trump,
that turns out to be utter nonsense.
I'm not sure these people should
have that much power to like, Geez,
is that what he's saying or is he saying
he doesn't know? He didn't say, I dunno.
He was saying like I have basically I
expect that Mueller's going to indict as a
former intelligence professional. I
expect it. Yeah. There's a lot of that.
It was ugly. Adam Schiff on the, on the
Intel Committee doing the same thing.
It's crazy now because
like what do they do now?
Like how do they rebound from this? If
this is that you didn't let just say once.
This is something you said for two years
you've seen the compilation videos,
they've done them to rap
music and so they're like,
they put a beat behind it and have you
seen it? No. There's some great ones,
some great comp. There's compilations
of people saying possible collusion,
possible collusion,
possible in this music that goes with it
and they just cut to possible collusion
with the Russians. Possible
Russian collusion. Possible
Russian collusion. It's,
yeah. They blew it in a major way. Yeah.
I mean there's plenty of shit to complain
about. You didn't have to go with that.
Like the idea was that he was a train
at target rich environment when you
decided to go to, he's a Russian
trader. It's no way out or something.
And he was Kevin Costner as a last thing.
Like what?
He could have ever beaten Hillary.
Sorry.
I'm going to check my watch
to get out of here man.
I do a little bit when you
have to leave right now.
I wanted to ask you one more question.
One more question.
What did you think about this? Um,
Chelsea manning situation? Cause I,
I don't know exactly what happened other
than she's in contempt of court and so
they've got her in solitary confinement.
Now w this is about testifying
against speaking. I'll be honest,
I haven't been following it that closely.
I mean,
my understanding is that Chelsea Manning,
who,
okay, say, here's where we get color.
Bradley. No, he changed the name.
He changed his name to Chelsea. He has
a biological male can leave your eyes.
Gendering are you dead naming
as well? Don't know. No I don't.
But unless we are talking about
when he committed his crime,
do you explain he was actually
Bradley as opposed to Chelsea. Right.
So if we're talking about,
so he presented those convicted that
was a male named Bradley Manning.
Did you say they, you're talking
about the formerly known as Bradley.
And if we're talking about the human
being who is currently in jail,
that is a male who is currently
known as Chelsea. So, okay.
So my understanding is that Bradley is
that Chelsea manning is a refused to hand
over information that he was legally
bound to handover about wikileaks.
And now there were complaints
that he's being held in solitary,
but that's not true apparently.
Uh, and that he's being mistreated.
I do find it weird that the same people
who are complaining about Donald Trump
coordinating with wiki leaks are very
upset about Chelsea manning going to jail
for coordinating with wikileaks.
You're gonna need to pick one or the
other is wikileaks batteries. Wiki leaks.
Not Bad.
What is wikileaks?
It's only dependent upon whether or not
they're supporting the narrative that
you want. That's exactly right. And lackey
leaks was very good. Right, right, right.
Exactly.
It was right and left by the way,
like there are people on the right
where it's like Julian Julian Sanchez,
the worst and then 2016
happened like Julian Assange.
Now there's a person I can really
talk to. It's like, well, no,
I'm pretty sure Julian Assange is
a wiki leaks. Good information.
Suggest they are Russian front group and
take make up that what you will end of
story.
Do you think that they became a Russian
front group to try to stay operative and
stay safe because they were obviously
being attacked by the United States
government and endanger being shut
down and then they've kept, I mean,
he's been in the US.
I really don't know enough about
wikileaks to to to really get into it.
I don't want to see the historical,
but I know that he's been
trapped in that embassy for
since 2012 yeah.
I mean I hope that he's got some video
games or something in there. Fuck man.
He's been in there for like
seven years now. Right.
That's a long time to be in an end, but
it's a long time. It can't go outside.
No sunlight. Pamela Anderson visits
every now and then. He's fucked, man.
I mean it's,
it's a terrible place to be.
And I don't know if it's better than
prison because it's like the stress of him
never knowing when they're going to come
knock down the door and pull him out of
there. I was like, how, how
wild is that guys sleep? Yeah.
Seven years in that embassy.
It can be great. It can be
great. It's gotta be awful.
They took his internet in a way,
right?
Uh, I think they did. That's
fucked. Although to be fair,
Wiki leaks was releasing information on
specific American soldiers in lines of,
of combat. So yes, they didn't redact
any of the names. That was the problem.
That's why people were
pissed. Really? Yes.
Because the original dump from Chelsea
manning was that he dumped all the
information to wikileaks,
including the stuff that was unredacted
and Ricky leaks just released it.
They did. That was, that was the
plane. That was the claim. Anyway.
Um, I don't know if that's
accurate because if he,
if he vine differently than
let me know cause I'll,
I'll be happy to correct all these.
Yeah. You know, I'm sure you would.
I just don't know if it that is,
I don't know.
I don't have the information in front
of me. Do you want to check? No,
they'll take too much
time. That'll do. Folks,
you're going to have to Google this one.
Um,
but so when,
one of the things that I was thinking
when Trump got into office while this
drain, that swamp shit, I was like,
well wonder if Trump would
be a wiki leaks supporter.
I wonder if Trump would be happy. It
depends what if it helped him. Yeah, sure.
Right, right. Or even and snowed in as
well. I was wondering about that. Yeah.
It's same sort of thing.
I mean,
unfortunately politics very often has
little to do with principal and everything
to do with convenience. Yeah.
So if it's helpful, sure. If not
like him who's always anti deep state and
talking about the, the, these, I mean,
I do have extremely critical,
yes. But I'll do, I have a feeling that
once you actually sit in the big seat,
I think that tends to change.
Remember Obama was too. Yeah.
And then five minutes later
he was drawn in people.
Well listen, um, I know you've got to get
out of here, so let's just wrap this up.
Tell people about your book.
Yeah.
So you can check out my book.
The right side of history talks about a
lot of the sort of deeper issues we were
talking about Judeo Christian values
and reason and sort of the, it's,
it's a kind of short form philosophical
history of the West from Sinai through
Greece and talking about all the
major enlightenment philosophers,
some of the things we talked
about on the show or in the book.
It's number one bestseller on the
New York Times nonfiction list,
at least at the moment. Congratulations
man. That's awesome. I appreciate it.
It's really pretty
spectacular. Exciting. Exactly.
Um, your show also Ben Shapiro show, you
can get the Ben Shapiro show on iTunes.
You can get it on Youtube, your
Sunday review, which I did once. Yeah.
Sunday special. It's special enough
to have you on again. I would love to.
Thank you. Thanks for being here, and your
book's available on Amazon everywhere.
Okay. Bench Shapiro, Ladies and gentlemen,
that was great.