This is the first time he's ever had a
false darn.
He's getting tricky.
That's real.
That's real world live.
Shane.
Dorian,
how are you brother?
What's going on?
Great.
Thanks.
Thanks for doing this,
man.
I really appreciate it.
Yeah,
no problem.
I'm happy to be here.
Thanks for having me.
My pleasure.
You know,
um,
you come highly recommended by my friend
Ben O'brien,
who's an awesome dude.
And apparently you guys had a great time
in New Zealand.
Bowhunting.
Yeah,
he's very,
he's very Texas.
Yeah.
We had a really good old time down
there.
I'd never been to.
I'd never been to New Zealand for
hunting before.
I'd been there for surfing,
so it was really cool to go and see
different parts of the country and do
some hunting out there.
We did some back country stuff surfing
there.
Is it as dangerous as surfing in
Australia?
As far as like sharks a?
No,
not as dangerous.
I'd say.
You know,
there are,
there are sharks there.
It's pretty close to Australia.
It's like a one hour flight.
So yeah,
that's what I was thinking sharks here
or over there,
but I don't,
I don't know.
I don't really think of sharks as as
much.
There's no,
you have a yellow,
a total radical fear of sharks are
scary,
scary creatures.
And then I'm fucking horrified.
How close have you shouldn't be.
You shouldn't be.
Um,
very close.
Yeah.
I got bumped off my board when I was a
kid.
Oh No.
Surfing into a place.
A sort of near my house,
but the water was that the sand was
black.
So yeah,
like I can really see the is actually
clear,
but the Sam is black,
so it bumped me and I never really got
to see what it was.
But I'm pretty sure it was a shark and
A.
There's a lot of sharks in Hawaii,
a lot of sharks,
wherever the waves are good.
It seems like there's a lot of sharks,
man.
Yeah.
That's not a coincidence,
is it?
I don't know,
man.
They're just everywhere.
They're crazy.
As you know.
It's funny about sharks.
As I was
growing up,
I always thought,
you know,
the only real sharks I had to worry
about where,
you know,
great whites and you know,
I was born and raised in Hawaii,
assess where I grew up surfing and um,
you know,
I always thought like great white
sharks,
they're always in really cool places.
I don't really have to worry it around
home and they've been finding a ton of
great white sharks around where I live
now.
They're all over Hawaii now and I'm a
great white sharks are actually warm
blooded so they can actually,
they can totally adjust their,
their,
uh,
I guess I guess their body temperature
to be able to,
to totally survive and thrive in warm
water as well as cold.
So they just go wherever the hell they
want.
Every time I go to Hawaii,
whatever,
I turn on the news,
the local news.
Some dude got bit.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
How often does it happen?
They're pretty often.
There's a lot of sharks.
And you know,
what's funny is it never used to happen
when I was a kid.
It wasn't even really a thought for me.
I mean,
I was scared of sharks and all that
stuff,
but people didn't really get start
getting chomped until I was a little bit
older in the last,
in the last 10 years,
there's been tons and tons of shark
attacks in Hawaii.
A friend,
a friend of mine and Bethany Hamilton,
she's a really,
really talented surfer.
She got bit.
She had her arm chomped right off her
body for a young girl.
Yeah.
And Hawaii surfing perfect waves out
with their friend and shark came up and
just ripped her arm right now for body
gangsters.
She,
that she just gets right back on the
board and she survived.
She's bad ass.
She's super bad ass.
She,
she actually served some of the biggest
waves,
uh,
all year.
Last year she got towed into a place
called Jaws on Maui and surfing 50 foot
waves with one arm,
um,
you know,
getting pounded by giant waves and she,
she paddles into some huge ways with one
arm.
Wow.
And gets held under water with one arm
and magic magically held under from a,
a giant wave underwater,
you know,
like trying to,
just,
I mean,
I know people who are terrified of
surfing big waves with two arms and you
know,
they're under water wanting a breath and
she's under there with one arm.
Imagine having like your arm tied to
your side and having to try and swim to
the surface the way it is.
Pretty scary.
Now when you get hit by a big wave like
that and you get sucked under,
how long are you under normally for
a,
usually a pretty,
pretty short amount of time.
But it really varies.
Um,
you know,
the,
the worst thing about surfing really big
waves and the,
we've had a lot of people die surfing
big waves and it is super dangerous.
Um,
the thing that kills people is getting
held under for two waves.
So if you fall on,
it's like if you take off on a wave and
you fall and you're underwater for a
super long time.
And this has happened to me a couple of
different times.
You're underwater really far and then
you start,
you know,
the wave hold you under and it's rolling
you along the reef towards the shore and
you're underwater near the bottom or at
the bottom and then the waves just
starts to dissipate and lose a little
bit of power and he can finally start
swimming up and then the next wave is
meanwhile it's on its way and you're
swimming up,
swimming up and the waves coming at you
and you don't get a breath in.
The wave takes you straight back down
and that.
And that's how people die.
Yeah,
it's scary shit.
So how long have you been held under?
For about a minute and 10 seconds.
It's a long time.
The only reason I know that is because
a,
I had a terrible wipe out at a,
at a big wave place in northern
California called Mavericks.
It was my first trip ever there and I
was having this awesome trip.
It's like,
you know,
it's one of the best big waves in the
world.
I always wanted to go there,
but I was pretty scared of it and I
ended up going there and having a.
The first day I was there,
it was super good.
I had a,
I had a blast.
I didn't fall once.
I had to just it with like a dream
session,
cuddle these big waves.
Thought I was killing it next day,
just absolutely smashed me.
I took it off on a wave,
ate shit down the face,
got sucked over the falls,
held under forever on the reef and was
swimming towards the surface and the
next day it was like a 50 foot face
broke right on top of me,
shoved me straight back down to the
reef.
And like,
as I was swimming up to try and get a
breath,
I was doing those involuntary,
you know,
when you're going like that.
And I was like,
shit,
I got to get a breath now.
And then all of a sudden I was at,
at the bottom.
And um,
yeah,
it was really scary.
But the scariest,
scariest time of my life.
And,
and,
um,
meanwhile,
meanwhile there was a woman on a boat
and she was filming the whole ordeal.
My board was like,
they call it tomb stoning where you can
only see half your board and then
you're,
and there's a leash,
right?
And you're connected to the bottom.
And a was like this,
you know,
you can only see half the half the board
for the next wave passed me by and my
board was still like that for over a
minute and I was like a minute and 10
seconds at a way,
way too long.
Wow.
That's,
it's hard to hold your breath for a
minute.
Just doing nothing.
Yeah.
It is holding your breath for a minute
while you're struggling.
And also your adrenaline's kicking in.
You're freaking out.
Yeah.
And you're realizing that you got to get
some air soon.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
And that's when,
you know,
I mean,
that's the whole thing is,
is uh,
you know,
learning about breath,
hold the whole thing that speeds up
your,
your breath.
Hold is,
is uh,
or I should say shortening your breath.
Hold is panicking.
You know,
once you,
if you're able to stay,
stay calm and know that you're going to
be okay,
you know,
you don't use up your breath very,
very fast,
but if you start to panic it's like it's
like flooring the gas and it just speeds
up the whole thing.
And um,
so panicking is lasting that you want to
do,
but when you're really terrified,
that's what happens to everybody.
There's a big connection between Jujitsu
and surfing.
A lot of people that I know that Love
Jujitsu also love surfing and they do it
all the time.
And um,
that breath thing is something that
comes into play in both situations
because if you're in a bad position,
like if someone's choking you or
something like that,
you can relax and stay calm and kind of
barely get out of things.
Whereas if you freak out and you start,
you start hyperventilating or panicking,
you just,
you just have to tap,
you run out of gas,
you run out of air.
And then the choke sinks in deeper in.
Some people are just really good at
surfing and for some reason that like
Hicks and Gracie is a famous example,
he's really good at Yoga,
which is also really big for controlling
your breath and staying calm and
regulating your heart rate.
And then he's also obviously a master at
Jujitsu,
but he loves surfing and I think in some
way those things are kind of connected
that you have to sort of maintain some
sort of control over your physical body.
Yeah,
for sure.
And you know,
and you know,
I think um,
you know,
knowing,
knowing how long you can hold your
breath,
I'm especially under pressure,
especially with a high heart rate is the
key.
You know,
I,
I did a breath holding course.
It was like a,
it was actually a specifically tailored
to surviving big waves.
Uh,
this course I did was four days long and
the first couple of days they just,
they just kind of taught us with the
science behind breath,
hold on,
how to get your breath,
hold up.
And then they basically,
uh,
worked our way up to our highest static
hold.
And then from there we had to hold our
breath for a quarter of that time under
stress.
Hm.
So when you take a breath hold course,
like what are they teaching?
Uh,
just the science behind the how,
how some people can hold their breath
for a long time and some people can't.
And you know,
the difference,
the,
it's,
it's basically psychological.
It's all in your mind really?
Oh yeah.
It definitely is.
I mean,
if you think you can hold your breath
for like if right now you tried to hold
your breath for and you could only make
it a minute for sure.
You can hold your breath for 300
percent.
It's all in your mind.
Like if you believe that you are going
to be fine,
it just,
you know,
your body tells you that you need to
breathe.
I'm like,
Kinda for that course.
I think the first day I tried to hold my
breath,
I'm and I'm in relatively good shape and
I never ever practice holding my breath
at all.
But you know,
pretty good lung capacity because I was
training all the time,
especially at that time,
the longest I could hold my breath.
That first day was like two minutes and
15 seconds or something like that.
And then by date,
the end of the day three,
I was holding it for five minutes and 34
seconds.
Whoa,
that's crazy.
So it's just techniques and understand
the technique.
What is the world record wasn't a w,
what's the fucking magician guy?
Didn't he break the world record like 17
minutes or something like that.
But yeah,
some weird where it sucked in pure
oxygen or something.
Cheating bullshit is night and day.
Yeah.
You can't do this twice.
I,
I think it gives you like,
um,
from,
from what I,
I think that's about twice as long as,
as like a world record holder can
actually hold their breath.
I think he was packing oxygen is totally
different.
He's breathing up with pure oxygen for
like a long time.
And it totally,
uh,
you know,
it's basically like,
it like doubles your breath hold.
Yeah.
There it go.
Seventeen minutes and four point four
seconds.
Bad Ass.
It's pretty incredible.
Even with the oxygen
I.
Yeah,
I mean no matter how,
how,
how you slice it,
that's a long ass time to not breathe.
So he held the record for oxygen
assisted static apnea between holding
your breath while breathing after
breathing pure oxygen.
That would be super handy for my job.
Pure oxygen,
being able to hold your breath for 10
minutes.
Fuck yeah man.
You'd be like,
fuck these waves,
these waves and got shit on them,
but I'm just going to swim to the bottom
and kick it.
Have you seen that product that they
came up with?
It's a bullshit fake product,
but apparently people have spent like a
million dollars on this thing trying to
buy it.
It's a fake.
Like a gill machine.
They came up with this thing that allows
you to breathe.
It's total bullshit.
It's fake,
but there was like these ads saying that
allows you to breathe underwater and it
looks like like a scuba mouthpiece,
but it's just got like.
It looks like two tampons on each side
and this stupid thing doesn't work at
all.
It doesn't do anything,
but apparently it's this giant scam and
there was this article about how people
have spent like all this money on this
fake thing that doesn't even exist.
It's crazy what people are right there.
It's absolutely nuts.
What people will actually buy.
This oxygen masks allows underwater
breathing without oxygen tanks,
but it's total bullshit,
so I don't understand where the money
went or how it see if you could find an
article of like what the fuck went
wrong,
but a bunch of to be like sucking oxygen
out of the ocean.
Yeah,
like how ridiculous is that?
Like people thought that they were fish.
Oh yeah,
that's all you need is this thing.
You breathe in through those and you
pull off to that,
but it's a total scam.
It's the order.
In the next 59 seconds,
we're going to throw a second one in for
half of the price.
Yeah,
exactly.
I mean it would be cool if someone could
come up with something like that,
but that's just not how it works.
It is bizarre though that there are
things that breathe air out of the
water.
They can find a way to suck air out of
the water,
like,
yeah,
life is very bizarre if you look at it
that way.
Very bizarre.
And then you pull them onto the deck of
the boat and they're like,
yeah.
And then you put us under water.
The opposite.
We start panicking immediately.
So the shark thing,
what did they tribute it to?
Anything.
The reason why they're inviting more
people lately.
Yeah,
it's super debatable though,
you know,
like a global warming type thing.
Yeah.
There's all types of stuff like that.
There's,
you know,
there's a lot less fish than it used to
be.
And then the other thing is,
you know,
the thing I think is a,
is a huge component is,
is that going to sixties,
if someone got bit,
they would do a short call,
like they,
like people will get pissed,
you know,
some little girl get bit and then all
the fishing boats to go out and kill a
ton of sharks.
And that's what happened in Hawaii.
You know,
there was,
I think in the sixties there was,
there was some shark attacks and um,
there was a huge shark cold,
like people would just go out and kill
as many sharks they could.
And so it decimated the shark
populations in Hawaii and then,
and then they were,
and then they were protected in the
seventies and eighties.
So now there's this mega shark shark
population because they're protected,
you know,
you're not really supposed to kill
sharks.
So there's an over abundance of big
I wonder if people would be the same if
there was dragons,
would we protect dragons?
We're,
we're required.
We really are retarded for sure.
We would hundred percent like,
you're not going to wipe out the fucking
sharks folks.
Just relax.
Skill kill them all around where people
are.
Yeah,
it's,
it's crazy that they figured out like,
you know,
any technology for every single thing,
but they don't have some sort of,
you know,
I was,
I was thinking it'd be so,
you know,
with,
in this day and age,
like we can do the craziest shit with
technology.
Like why can't they put buoys around a
surf break with like some weird magnetic
thing that shoots down to the bottom of
the ocean at that,
you know what it's like 30 feet deep,
you know,
like half a mile out from the break and
then everyone can swim there.
Everyone can serve their whatever the
hell it is.
Like how come they don't have.
That seems so basic.
It does seem like something they could
figure out how to do like some sort of
an electronic fence that keeps them out.
Like they have that for your dog.
Yeah.
Can put that on your yard and the dog
can't go past it.
But it'll probably give you dick cancer.
You know,
they'll probably find out,
you know,
all these surfers and start getting Dick
Cancer.
And everybody went,
what the fuck off the fence.
The fence.
Every cat.
Yeah.
Can put up the magnetic fence because
all the sharks,
all the sharks or get cancer and then
yeah,
for Sharks get Dick Cancer.
Then Peta would get upset.
He came over to
become a huge issue.
I'm not a fan of sharks.
I don't like them.
They scare the fuck out of me and that's
what's keeping me from surfing.
Surfing looks like it's fucking awesome.
I see guys like you on those big waves.
If I don't know about the big ways that
that's beyond me.
I believe it.
Even when I was young,
I don't think I ever like this,
this kind of shit that's not.
I'm not designed for that.
It's not fun looking.
Nope,
that's not me.
We're looking at a fee for people who
are listening will look at an image.
Is that you?
Who's.
Who is that?
That's me.
Well,
Jesus,
dude,
tell me about this.
Looks like I'm falling off the building.
Falling off several buildings stacked on
top of each other.
That,
that,
that
actual number right there.
I actually felt like I was falling off a
building.
I was absolutely sure I was eating shit
right there.
So.
And you didn't.
Um,
I didn't.
Yeah,
it was a miracle.
I actually fell from the top and landed
on my board and made the wave.
And there's a big wave at a,
at a wave,
uh,
off the north coast of Maui called jaws.
Now,
how high is that wave?
Probably 50 feet on the face,
maybe,
maybe more.
Maybe 60.
So you're falling off the top of the
wave,
like it breaks and you're coming over
the lip or the,
what would you call it?
What do you call the edge of the wave?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I'm falling from the lip.
But the cool thing is you're doing it
with your hands.
You know,
like you're doing it with your bare
hands.
Like this wave comes in and you have to
read the wave.
You have to time it,
you have to position yourself so you
have to catch it in the steepest part
right before it throws over like that
because he could throw it over you eat
and shit.
So you know,
you gotta it's just,
it's so precise,
you know,
it'd be able to tighten it on a giant
wave like that.
Especially like the bigger the wave is,
the faster it moves.
So it gets really,
really technical and so you know,
a few successfully ride one of those
ways.
It's a lot of fun.
I would imagine.
It gets super addictive when you're in
that tube.
And you're slicing through it and you
see the water.
Oh yeah.
Going over the top of you.
Yeah,
it is.
It is
so much fun.
It's like,
um,
it is,
it's such a blast.
It's,
um,
it's super addicting.
I,
you know,
I've been surfing since I was,
I've been surfing on,
on a surfboard standing up since I was
five on my surfboard from my dad.
And um,
I'm still totally obsessed with it.
It's weird.
There's nothing else in my life like
that where I'm absolutely psyched.
Like when the waves are good,
I'm,
I'm like a little kid still.
What is it about it,
dude?
It's like,
it's like hunting.
It really is.
It's like I'm out in nature.
No one's bothering me.
I don't need to talk to anybody.
I can go do my own thing.
I can go down the beach no matter how
shitty of a day I had,
no matter how much stress,
whatever,
like if my kids getting a bad report
card or I had to pay my taxes or
whatever the hell it was,
I can put on my trunks,
dragged down to the beach,
grab my board and I'm good.
I'm soon as I hit the water,
I'm fine and it.
And that's how I am a bowhunting and
people who don't bowhunt,
they don't understand that.
They're like,
why the hell would you do that?
Like what do you,
what do you find,
you know,
like,
what do you find good about that?
Like being out in the forest for days at
a time.
It's the same thing.
Well obviously I've never served,
but the bowhunting thing is so difficult
and so primal and I think it hits some
weird ancient switches inside your dna
from back when people needed a bow and
Arrow to survive.
And when you were hunting an animal it.
I mean it's,
it's also,
it's so primitive.
Like there's something about rifle
hunting that's not nearly as satisfying.
Rifle hunting is.
It's all exciting and it's,
it's way more effective and you
certainly have you.
You'll have more success and there's
more range to it,
but it's not nearly the same feeling.
There's a switch that goes off that I
think is like a part of being a human
being from the thousands of years of us
shooting bows and arrows at things to
stay alive.
That,
that,
that reward is like triggered somehow or
another deep inside.
Whatever it is that makes you a person.
Yeah,
it is.
I mean it's,
you know,
it all comes down to the moment of truth
that you worked so hard for that
opportunities,
whatever it is and elk or deer or
whatever the hell it is and,
and you bust your ass and you're on your
hands and knees in the hot sun or you
know you're over there freezing your ass
off in the dark waiting for.
They get to get light and a pack your
shit from the trail head for miles and
all this hard work and all the thousands
of arrows.
You shoot your target and all of a
sudden it comes down to this this
millisecond where the elk stops in front
of you and you're sitting there full,
drawn and it's like the moment of truth,
you know,
it's super technical and really
difficult and a lot of people suck at it
and that's why it's so rad.
Yeah,
it's very technical and that is
something that I just never took into
account when I saw people shooting bows
and arrows.
Like,
oh,
he left arm straight.
You right on pulls back.
You make sure you aim,
you let it go and seems like Kinda like
a rifle,
you know,
with a rifle.
What do you do?
You sent her the radical,
you know,
you squeeze the trigger and make sure
you don't jerk it.
You're good.
Yeah.
There's so much more involved in the
anchoring of where the string hits the
corner of your mouth,
where your hand rest below your jaw,
making sure that your elbows not too
low,
not too high,
your back muscles are pulling
and remembering all that stuff in the
moment.
Yeah,
and getting to full draw.
That is the hard part.
That's the big difference,
you know,
I mean that's,
I mean that's the main difference is
once that animal's in range,
you still have to get to full draw.
Yeah.
And you're not sitting there like this
wedding without making any motion.
You actually have to go full draw and
somehow do that undetected without the
animal getting alert or freaked out or
running away.
Yeah.
It's a crazy little addiction,
isn't it?
It is very,
very crazy.
And it's also,
I was,
my wife would agree with you.
Mine went to,
um,
I was watching a video of you,
uh,
you were grilling some steaks,
some,
uh,
I think it was access deer at your
house.
And you,
when you were talking about it like
this,
like the connection that you have to
your food,
like you went and you found that animal,
you know,
that is a wild animal.
That animal was just living like they'd
been living for hundreds of thousands of
years.
Just eating grasses and staying away
from predators.
Snuck up on it and you place an hour
right
in his vitals perfectly and cut it up
and brought it home.
And now you're eating it and there's
this insane connection to your food when
you do something like that.
Yeah.
Well,
especially when you look around,
your family's eating in like my key.
I have little kids and they're sitting
there with deer on their fork eating it.
Like Dad brought this home is awesome.
I think it's cool.
You know,
like I dunno,
I,
there's just something so much more
satisfying about eating food that you
grew or killed or whatever it was.
You know what I mean?
I,
it's,
it's so cool.
When someone has an awesome garden that
their house,
they busted their ass and they'd know
exactly where that food came from.
It only touched their hands.
You know,
it's the same thing and it's even,
it's even more so when you're,
when you spend all that time in the
mountains and,
and you know,
you bring it home and you care for that
meet and make sure it's not dirty and
make sure it's not spoiled and make sure
it's taken care of perfectly.
Like you'd go in my,
in my freezer and I'm like a total.
I'm a,
I'm actually kind of a slob and a lot of
like different areas of my life,
like I don't make my bed a lot of times
or whatever it is,
but now when it comes to the meat,
it's like perfect.
Total nerd alert,
go in.
It's like everything's packaged
perfectly.
Everything's a perfect size.
Everything's,
everything's itemized,
cut date,
animal species,
you know?
Well there's a deep respect for that
animal data.
Don't tell people who just buy their
meat at a grocery store.
It's,
I don't think they could ever understand
it.
I think you can kind of intellectualize
it and you can kind of imagine what it's
like,
but I don't think you could ever really
understand it.
Well,
and I can relate to that because that
wasn't always a hunter and I,
I wasn't,
I wasn't.
I wasn't brought up a hunter.
I didn't,
I didn't come from a hunting family.
Nobody in my family ever hunted all new
to me.
I started when I was 30 and I'm 43.
So what was it that got you going?
I moved from the,
from the beach where I lived my whole
life up to the mountains and um,
I bought a piece of property and
everything I planted got dug up by wild
pigs,
so there's wild boars all over the
property and my wife started getting
pissed and,
and,
and I didn't know what to do.
I wanted to plant fruit trees and all
this stuff and everything was getting
knocked over and smashed by all the
pigs.
And so my buddy was like,
dude,
shoot him with a gun and shoot a couple
and they,
you know,
they'll beat it.
And so he gave me this shotgun or
whatever.
I shot with a shotgun and immediately
gave it back to him and I was like,
I'm not a gun guy.
I just,
I'm not into the loud noises.
And I just was over it.
So I gave it back.
I didn't know what to do.
I didn't know if I should need a fence.
My property.
I didn't want to do that,
you know,
because I didn't want to like mess up.
They're like natural pattern either.
They were there,
they were there long before I was and
um,
and my next door neighbor was a bow
hunter.
He had an extra bowl so I would go over
to his house and have a couple beers and
shoot arrows and once I get group some
arrows,
he said I was ready to go hunting and he
took me boar hunting and the first night
all these pays were there and,
and I,
and I totally blew it.
I got to full draw and my Arrow fell off
the rest and thing and all,
they all,
they all ran and made a bunch of noise.
But that was it.
The next day I went and bought it.
I used mathews bow down at the bottom
down at the boat shop and you know,
I started a building trees,
downs about my house and you know,
trying to like throw down for the pigs
to come.
I didn't know the hell I was doing.
I didn't know any bowhunters and um,
so it's cool.
So it's all like self taught.
It was,
yeah,
it,
uh,
you know,
I started with a good friend of mine at
home at the same time I didn't really
have any super close friends that were
bow hunters and.
But it's funny because soon after I
started bowhunting,
then I realized that I did know a bunch
of bowhunters and I immediately had a
really cool circle of friends that were
all experienced bowhunters and they kind
of took me in and taught me,
you know,
what to do,
what equipment to use and you know,
how to hunt.
And then,
and then I had like mentors in hunting
that really taught me how to hunt,
like to kill animals.
Well,
Hawaii is an amazing place for bow
hunting and a lot of people would never
imagined this.
It is amazing between axis deer and
mountain goats and all kinds of other
crazy shit that you guys and the pig
popular pigs were brought over there.
I'm like hundreds and hundreds of years
ago.
Right?
Yeah.
Is the captain cook thing wasn't.
So there was.
So there wasn't really no animals in
Hawaii.
Every single thing there is introduced
except for like bugs and some birds,
you know,
so um,
the deer,
the pigs,
the goats,
the sheep,
everything was all introduced.
So you go out in the mountains and
there's lots and lots of different,
you know,
a lot of different animals out there and
they're all introducing,
they're all considered pests.
Wow.
So it's a lot like New Zealand and that
sort of a way that is new.
New Zealand has an incredible amount of
wild game,
but it's all introduced and they did it
back hundreds of years ago again when
Europeans wanted it as a hunting
destination.
So they brought over stags and European
animals and access deer and all these
things and just let them loose with no
predators.
Yeah,
that's right.
So their populations just exploded.
Yeah.
I mean you came in Hawaii.
What is it?
What is it like over New Zealand?
Because when you look at the Lord of the
rings,
you know,
that's,
that's all I know about new New Zealand.
I know Kim Dotcom lives there and the
Lord of the rings and people go over
there to hunt.
It's very much like that,
uh,
um,
I hunted there this year and we hunted
in some places that like I hadn't even
done.
All I do is I take pictures and stare at
the mountains.
It was,
it was mind boggling how incredibly
beautiful it was.
We were hunting these,
these,
uh,
these mountain goats called tar from the
Himalayas there,
these hairy goats with this big giant
sable for thing and really small horns
and they live and they liked these
glaciers and he's like vertical cliffs,
maybe like a thousand foot cliff at the
top of like a 5,000 foot mountain of
granite cliff,
like a little step ledge in it that's
like six inches wide.
And that's where the tar would be
standing.
One Star.
Just be standing there looking at all
the other bad ass creatures.
They really don't look real.
Try and go kill one of those things with
a ball on public land and sent me the
picture and all the hail you forever.
They are hard to kill with a bow.
I tell you that much.
Did you get one?
I didn't.
I saw one.
I was at remy who's a friend of yours,
right?
Yeah,
yeah.
It was a Ramey warrant and we spotted
one and it's not like,
you know,
like where I come from.
You go hunt access deer.
You could see a thousand deer walk in
the morning.
Yes.
Where mark my words dude soon.
I'm online.
I hold dear in a day.
Yeah,
that's insane.
So I'm used to going out and seeing them
like tons of pigs and goats and deer and
stuff like that.
I went to,
I went to New Zealand and hunted these
tar and I'm standing there with remy,
the bottom of this valley and we're
hunting or camping in the back country
and we're,
you know,
we're glassing and don't see anything.
So we drive like half a mile glass,
you know,
and we're in totally in the background.
She went weren't driving straight up a
river like deep in a river.
We got like a,
like a,
a,
one of those like land cruisers with a
snorkel in the middle of the floor.
It's not like these animals are under
radical pressure and
all of a sudden we see one,
there's a tar and it's at the top of
this mountain.
5,000 vertical feet,
five miles straight up hill or one mile,
right.
Well,
I don't know,
whatever the hell it was was vertical.
It's vertical,
right?
Yeah.
I mean it's 5,000 vertical feet,
but you're looking at it and it looks
like it's right there,
but it's vert right.
It takes you four hours to walk there
because it's vertical.
And uh,
you know,
we saw it probably we saw it at like
three in the afternoon and it got dark
at like six.
So he's like,
dude,
we have three hours.
We need to close the gap.
We need to kill that tar today before
dark.
So we're literally like,
quote unquote running up the mountain
as fast as you possibly could.
And he's in pretty good shape.
Remy is,
he's a beast.
He's a beast.
He's,
I mean,
that's what he does.
He lives in the mountains all the time.
So He's used to that.
He's like,
they did one of those vo two Max test on
him and he's got like elite triathlon
endurance.
Yeah.
He's like half human,
half tar and uh,
so.
So we closed the gap to about 900 yards
and then it got dark time and walk back
down five hours in the dark.
Well,
it's fucking exhausting.
Is proposing you don't realize like how
hard it is to get up one of those
mountains until you try it and you go,
oh,
like you think I'm in good shape.
I work out,
I go to the gym,
I'm on the elliptical machine.
This is going to be a no problem.
I'm not one of these fat guys.
Oh yeah,
no,
no.
It's fucking hard.
It's really hard.
Like any it'll help.
Like being light helps to light and thin
where you're not carrying around a lot
of weight.
Yeah.
But guys like remy and Steven Rinella
and the guys that do that all the time,
they will embarrass you with how will
out of shape.
You are just walking up hills.
You're just,
you're just,
you're just keeping them at a,
you know,
at your rate.
It's like,
it's like you're slowing them down all
the time.
Yeah.
So it does pay to,
you know,
to train.
Especially like in the mountains like
that.
Like if you're going to go on a big hunt
it,
it really helps to train a lot and now
these animals,
how the fuck,
like I've seen goats like on the side of
cliffs where they're walking along a
vertical face and they're,
they're standing on the little,
like these little two inch outcroppings
and they're walking along on those.
Like how the fuck do they do that?
Like how were they designed?
Like what,
what kind of evolutionary advantage to
like walking along the side of a cliff
face like that has led them to be this
bizarre beast.
Like most people don't think about them
like what their capabilities are and
they can do like really strange shit.
I get as far as if they're balanced and
how they can make it up the side of a
cliff.
Like look at these fuckers.
Yeah,
look,
look at that as exactly how the tar.
Where did.
We're looking at something that just
doesn't even look real.
We're looking at these goats that are
walking along the face of this cliff and
the cliff is almost 90 degrees.
It's almost up and down and these things
are somehow or another finding
footholds,
whether their whole body,
like the side of their body is slammed
up against the side of the mountain and
they're making it up this cliff
and they're not forced to be on that
cliff.
That's the craziest thing.
Like when I,
when I was hunting those,
those,
those goats in New Zealand and star just
below where they were,
there was like these rolling hills,
like really steep still,
but it was rolling hills with grass.
They choose to be on the rocks because
they actually eat some weird stuff that
grows on those vertical cliffs.
So wild.
What are they ripping balls the whole
time.
I'd be kidding me.
The animal's not forced to be there.
He's.
He's choosing to be on that like six
Inch Wide Ledge,
a thousand feet on a vertical cliff.
Oh,
look at that fucking.
But we're looking at this picture folks.
Jamie,
what was the Google search?
If someone's listening just like
climbing goat.
This is this picture that we're looking
at now,
there's probably like eight of them
and they're on the side of this mountain
and it just doesn't even look real and
the tar does,
they don't look real as it is.
They look like some sort of a mythical
creature from some ancient Greek novel.
Yeah,
it's hard.
It's hard to.
It's really hard to appreciate how hard
core that kind of hunting is unless you
do it,
you know?
I think that like 90,
I,
I'm gonna I'm gonna Piss people off when
I say this,
but like 98 percent of the hunting that
happens in America is like park a truck,
walked to your trees,
Dan getting the trees.
Dan play play words with friends until
the deer comes underneath the trees,
down to full draw and,
and you know,
you got your tag filled and which is
great.
I'm sure it's a blast and I like dress
downs and all that stuff,
but that kind of hunting is just like a.
it's weird how hunting is at,
clumped in to like,
oh,
you're a hunter.
And as all people sort of need to know,
you know,
there's like so many different kinds of
hunting and so many different ways to do
it,
different weapons,
different approaches,
different.
You know,
it's like crazy.
Like some people are shooting animals
that had 100,
1500 yards of though with high powered
rifles,
they want to be as far as possible,
that's the goal.
And for us it's like we want to be as
close as possible
that that long range stuff is very
strange because there's a lot of ethical
questions that come up with that because
any movement whatsoever at 1500 yards,
I mean you have to be like a real
fucking expert marksman to pull
something like that off.
So there's this,
there's a lot of Dick Wagon going on
when you're killing something like 700,
800 a thousand yards.
It's weird.
It's like you don't really have to do
that.
Like you could get closer to that
animal.
I think that's the goal though.
The goal is to fight.
Anybody can get to 200 yards from any
animal.
Yeah.
I don't care what animal it is.
You can get,
if you can get to 200 yards,
you got major problems if you didn't get
to 100 yards.
I mean even from like an antelope.
Yeah.
You can belly crawl your way in
middle of nowhere to 100 yards from
antelope.
Yeah.
Especially if you have one of those
Ghillie suits.
You know remy has this show called move
super slow.
Yeah.
Have you seen remy show?
It's called Apex Predator.
Haven't seen that one though.
Really good show and it's really
interesting because remy remy is a
really good athlete and he's also just a
really smart guy and what he does is he
tries to mimic all of the behavior of
predatory animals like wolves and he'll
do like him and a bunch of his friends
were doing some sort of like a chase the
same way that a wolf would chase down an
elk and one of the things that he did
was he put on a Ghillie suit and he
crawled up to these antelope and just
slowly creeped is way up to these
antelope and as long as you're patient
and you move slow,
like he got within like seven feet of
fuckin antelope,
as long as you go slow enough.
Yeah.
That's a mistake I make all the time.
You know,
when I blow stock,
it's almost always because I went too
fast.
No matter how slow you go,
you should almost
always go slower and well.
One of the things that I've found out
recently,
you know Randy Ulmer is famous
bowhunter.
It's like probably one of the most
successful bowhunters ever.
He shoots most of his animals with no
shoes on his.
He,
yeah,
he takes his boots off and he's got just
thick wool socks and he just walks you
just correct
the
nice and slow.
And that's one of the reasons why he's
so successful.
He realized like,
okay,
you can't just be walking around with
these fucking clunky boots and snap and
twigs and shit like that.
And so he feels everything underneath
them and it's just like.
Have you ever been around a bear like
when a bear is walking through the
woods?
Uh,
no,
not really.
They don't make any noise.
It's kind of creepy.
Like this big ass fucking 300 pound bear
and it's not making a single sound as
it's walking because they have soft pads
and the predators.
So they just fucking,
I've
been,
you know,
and that's kind of like the idea of the
approach,
just just creep inch by inch.
Bears blow my mind too because you know,
I've,
you know,
I'm from Hawaii so I don't even know
anything,
nothing about bears.
So I think they're all like Yogi bear,
you know,
like they're coming in like your,
your jam and hang out and camp with you
know this,
you know,
they want a hug or something like that.
And,
and a man,
I went hunting,
I did a do it yourself over the counter
tag elk hunt with my buddy from Hawaii
and we were in Colorado and we're and we
and we hiked into area and we're all
excited and we don't,
we didn't know shit about elk hunting.
I did not call him.
I didn't know what they did.
I didn't know how they worked.
I read some articles,
I didn't know what the hell is going on.
So.
And so we dropped off our stuff.
We've got about an hour to hunt and then
we're gonna come back and set up our,
our,
our little camp there,
like a creek.
So I do a big loop.
I come back a little bit early.
I'm not going to set up my tent and
stuff and I get to one side of the creek
and my friends across the creek setting
up his tent and getting like,
like our food out like Salami and like
whatever else kind of food we had
and I was just about to like yell out to
him like,
hey did you see anything?
I was like maybe 60 yards away from him
and I looked to my left and there's a
bear,
a big bear,
big black bear standing on his hind legs
look like one of those targets.
He knows big old target to shoot one of
those things and he was just staring at
my friend.
He had no idea was there.
The bear didn't know I was there and
that my friend had no idea that the bear
was there.
He's sitting there like butt crack
hanging out,
like getting all the food out and its
barest just staring out from across the
creek.
It was radical and I just immediately
knocked in Arrow and just sat there and
then the bear saw me and then looked at
my friend,
looked at me,
looked at my friend,
and then it was this vertical mountain
right behind him.
We at the bottom of the creek and a bear
thought about it and then just turned
around and just hightail it straight up
this mountain like he was on the flat
ground was crazy and my friend saw that
story that you were telling me before
the podcast started.
Tell that fucking story.
That made me really even more scared of
bears.
Tell.
Tell that story.
Yeah,
so it was a few years ago.
I read this,
I read this story on a bowhunting
magazine and it was a story about this,
this guy and his son,
and they were hunting elk,
not sure which state,
but I'm.
The son was in the front and he was set
up and the dad was in the back probably
60 yards back and the dad was cow
calling and there was a bowl there and
he was starting to.
He was starting to come into the call
and so the kid was standing there
waiting for his shot and the dad was
sitting there,
cal calling behind them and all of a
sudden the elk runs off and they thought
the wind had waffled on him or
something,
and right behind the elk,
like 50 yards past the elc was a giant
grizzly bear standing straight up
staring at him and the kids started
getting nervous.
The bear started hightailing it straight
up the kid and the kid turned and
started running it.
The Dad and as the kid and the and the
dad went to full draw.
He had a bow.
It was.
It was archery season.
He had no gun,
so the dad grabbed his bow,
got an Erewhon,
had somehow had the clarity to get to
full draw.
As the kid passed his dad,
the dad made a perfect shot on the bear.
The bear right then catches up to the
kid,
dives on the kid and starts mauling him
and ends up dying on the kid and there
was a picture in the article is
incredible.
There's a picture in the magazine of the
kid and he's covered,
covered head to toe in blood.
The bear died on him like a heart shot.
Blood all over him for the kid like bear
blood.
Oh my God.
Just the Olympics.
What is,
um,
how do you find this,
Jamie?
If somebody wants to call Dad,
dad's zero saved son from grizzly attack
to outdoor life.
Fuck is a heavy article man.
It's no joke.
And the,
and the,
and the perspective from the dad,
you know,
it's like,
can you imagine?
I mean,
I have,
I have kids and I can't even imagine
like what kind of mental state you'd be
in if you saw a giant bear chasing after
your kid.
It does a bad motherfucker to keep it
together.
Yeah.
That gives me the nerves,
the jellies,
whatever the fuck it is.
My,
my goosebumps are popping up.
I saw a grizzly when I was in Alberta.
Black bear hunting a couple of weeks
ago.
They look at you.
So different than black bears are creepy
enough,
you know.
And uh,
Rinella was telling me a story about
this guy who first trip ever hunting
gets attacked in his tent by a 500 pound
predatory black bear.
His friend shoots the bear,
the bullet goes through the bear and
hits his friend in the wrist.
So this kid,
first,
first black bear hunt ever first camping
trip out is going in the woods.
Like this is going to regroup.
We're gonna.
Get to hang out with nature.
Bear tries to eat him.
And his friend shoots him.
They killed the bear.
They wanted to kill him.
The bear.
But black bears are scary,
but they're nothing like grizzlies.
This grizzly looked at us and they look
at you like demons.
They're there.
They have a total different look in
their eye.
Like there's nothing going on back
there.
It's just dead killed.
Machines look and feel bad when they
can.
They eat.
You feel awesome.
Gut feel super delicious right now.
He'd be screaming,
great.
W,
what?
People are so strange,
there are detachment from wildlife that
when you're actually around them,
even just around an elk,
like when you're around an elk and elk
or call and then making those crazy
sounds just like,
what the fuck is this real?
And they're fighting over the girls.
Yeah.
I just put that blows my mind like,
like hunting deer or elk in the Rut and
seeing them fight over the girls is the
best.
It's the best.
And seeing like the one that,
that loses gets his ass kicked and he
kinda like just walks off like,
oh God,
I just got my ass kicked and ended up
bowl.
Or the big dog who,
who wins?
He's on,
that's a whole Harem Harem full of girls
and he's just like,
I'm on the bad ass.
You know,
he just gets his fuck on man.
You can breed them all.
You know,
I was in California to hone ranch last
year and these two huge elk were
smashing horns.
They're both like threesixty class elk,
which is like a for people listening.
Just enormous antlers.
Six points on each side.
Thousand pound animals just running at
each other head butting each other and
stabbing each other and uh,
while we were there they found one
enormous bowl that had been killed by
another bowl,
been stabbed him in the,
in the side and punctured his lungs and
it was laying there jacked enormous bull
as the coolest.
Seeing them like act like how they're
supposed to be in nature,
how they've been doing it for hundreds
of thousands,
millions of years.
It's just nuts to just,
just to be a part of that and see it.
Yeah,
it isn't.
It's almost like we were talking about
the goats being able to walk up the side
of these cliffs,
like these animals,
they,
they've evolved to develop horns that
are swartz.
They have like spears going out of their
fucking head and they know it.
Yeah.
They're well aware of that and they were
trying to kill the other one because
it's there.
So hopped up and they were just hanging
with that guy a few weeks ago.
Yeah.
Were hanging out,
feeding out in the,
in the,
in the grass,
and they'll hang out with him again if
he survived.
Well,
yeah,
they hang out,
but then make these bachelor groups and
they get pissed.
Did you see that video of the lady in
yellowstone that was like,
no,
no.
Hello my friend.
I'm your buddy.
Oh Man.
This elk just fucking headbutts this
bitch and sends her flying.
She went flying.
Wow.
How has that Grizzly man movie?
Do you see that thing?
I've seen it about 10 times.
You don't see that you're tripping.
It's so good.
I'm trying to get Werner Herzog to uh,
he,
his people contacted me,
the director of it to be on the podcast.
I'm gonna try.
Look at this.
She's a kid.
Knew Mr. almost like a comedy.
You know what I mean?
Like when I watched that movie,
I felt like it was a comedy.
The Guys Warner please.
Oh,
oh,
oh.
He goes,
you should get that on video.
That shit's going to go find her.
Why
45 yard,
ma'am.
That's been a long time.
Thank you sir.
I'm totally used to these elk.
I'm out here every year.
It's 25 yards.
It's funny.
He's got like a number in his head that
you have to be 25 yards from them.
Yeah.
And then you're totally safe.
Yeah,
no problem.
Super Safe.
Please did they decide 50 yards to make
a mad dash you.
He's got a boner and this chick got
scared off and he decides it's you that
scare off and just go spear.
You have no problem.
Do you see the one where there's a guy
was sitting on the side of the road as a
photographer is a real recent one and
they actually had one of euthanizing the
elk because this elk fucked with this
dude for like the videos like 10 minutes
long.
They Alex.
so just like head button.
This guy and the guy sitting there
trying to cover his head as a spike and
really young bull and uh,
this,
this photographers just hanging there
and this bull starts head butting him
and the guys just decided to just play
passive.
This is it.
Yeah.
And this.
But this goes on forever,
man.
And this bull just kind of not sure what
to do because he's a really young bull.
You're looking at that bowl.
A spike is like,
what a year old.
It's funny how they get so smart so
quick.
You know,
it's like,
it's like at that age when it,
you know,
once I got like a yearling bowl,
like a little spike,
they're pretty stupid,
you know,
they'll come to any call and they're
kind of spaced out.
They don't really know what a human
looks like.
But man,
once they turn into a six by six they
are,
they are not dumb.
They get turned on.
Yeah.
But like this elk,
I think I could kill that Alco my hands.
Yeah.
I'm pretty sure I have to see you try to
get ahold of those.
Antlers are spin around.
Take his back.
Rear naked choke.
That's what I'm thinking.
Yeah.
I'm thinking I get his back and he's
fucking done,
man.
It'd be fun.
Drive for sure.
Meanwhile he would back straps and that
guy ride off with me.
He would,
he would load up the barbecue.
He would.
I would get her freezer.
Oh yeah.
Well,
those are the most delicious ones.
If you actually can,
can kill one that that's really young
like that.
They're really tender.
The same with deer.
You know,
everybody wants to shoot,
but this is the thing about elk.
They're so delicious that even the old
ones,
the old tough bull,
they taste amazing meat.
You can.
Yeah.
It's funny because I feel like super
remorseful when I get an animal on the
ground,
no matter what it is,
no matter if it's like a,
uh,
an elk or a deer or a pig or whatever.
I had this weird feeling when I walk up,
I'm like,
I don't,
I don't feel bad.
I just feel like just as like heavy
connection with that animal,
you know,
like I took his life.
That was,
that was my choice.
You know,
like I could have let it walk,
but at the same time,
like if it's like a,
a younger dear,
I'll smoke it,
you know,
because those are really good eating.
That's what I'm trying to do.
I'm out there trying to.
It's funny,
I,
I don't,
I don't have a list of animals in my
head that I need to get.
Or are you one of those guys where
you're like,
hey,
you know,
I need to kill them out and go,
I need to get a stone sheep.
I need to get a zebra.
And you find that weird man.
There's a,
there's a show that I watch you ever
seen that?
Uh,
Tom Miranda's adventure bowhunter show
television dude.
I'm like a wookie in the mountain.
You don't have a TV.
I don't have TV.
Wow.
Got like Netflix on my computer.
There's a lot of these guys that are
into the super slams,
you know,
which means all the North American game
animals and that just seems like a
fetish to me.
It gets real bizarre.
Like I think you're losing sight of what
this thing is supposed to be all about.
Yeah,
I'm totally fine with however anyone.
You know,
if someone's in a getting lions or
whatever,
that that's,
that's their trip,
you know,
I'm not going to judge them,
but I'm just,
that's not me.
I don't have a list of animals at all.
If I just hunted mule deer and elk for
the rest of my life and access,
dear,
that'd be good.
I can hunt all year long and never get
bored with those three animals.
I feel weird about bears.
Bears are the ones that weird me out the
most,
like killing a bear and eating it just
first of all,
it's really like one of the best
animals.
Like from a conservation standpoint,
it's one of the best animals to kill
because they don't have any predators
and so if you don't kill them,
they will.
The only thing that kills bears,
there's other bears,
so they like where we hunt in Alberta,
there's a giant population.
I mean it's not uncommon to see 20,
30 beers in a day.
It's really,
really overflowing with bears and public
service to get.
Yeah,
like I take a few bears.
It decimates not just the moose
population,
the deer population,
but the crazy thing is it's bad for the
bear population for there to be this
many bears because the boars eat cubs.
Daryl,
weird animal,
like elk don't eat elk,
but bears like they're predatory man.
They just go for an easy meal.
There was an article recently that I
posted today on twitter that they're
finding the grizzlies are going towards
people when they have cubs and super
fucking dangerous,
but the Mama bears are realizing that
when they're around people that the big
boars won't kill their bed,
their cubs as much to here it is.
Brown bears are using human shields to
protect their cubs,
but it's incredibly dangerous for people
because when you're around a mama bear
and she's got cubs,
she'll fuck you.
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
You don't want to get near one.
There's another one that I retweeted
yesterday,
some woman who was in a marathon.
She was running a marathon in New Mexico
and she ran past a mamma bear with her
cubs.
The Mama Bear,
just societal Fokker up.
Just beat the shit out of her.
Cut Her up,
ripped her apart,
and she just played dead.
And uh,
you know,
she's really jacked and picture of all
scarred up and you know,
the bear left her alone.
And then some other marathon runners
came over and saw her huddled up in the
fetal position off.
Fucking covered with blood as a life
changer right there.
Oh yeah.
Just the meat bear meat is really good.
It's really good.
Yeah.
There's a lot of misconceptions about
bear meat.
Well,
apparently grizzlies are nasty,
especially if you get a coastal grizzly
that's all fall bears in spring bears,
right?
Like the taste of them.
I heard,
I heard the,
I forget which one,
but I heard one is a little bit better
than false.
Supposed to be the best because the fall
bears are eating berries.
I've only killed spring bears.
Spring bears tastes really good.
Yeah.
And like I was saying like from an
ecological standpoint and from a
conservation standpoint,
it's probably one of the most important
animals to kill other than say white
tail deer because there's so 2 million
or so.
What is it?
What was the number like one point $5
million car accidents in the United
States alone.
200 people die in the United States
every year from hitting deer with their
cars.
That's the thing is people are so quick
to point the finger like,
I can't believe you'd kill a bear,
you can't believe it,
but they just can't wrap their head
around the fact that they need to be
those numbers get so out of control and
the and the world's never going back to
how it is before we lived where the
bears live,
you know?
Right.
That argument's a weird argument.
Yeah.
And their land.
Like I get it,
that's fine,
but it doesn't matter that point.
It's invalid because all the people live
there and when there's millions of bears
running around,
it's just,
it's not good for them either,
you know,
but even knowing that I still feel weird
when I kill a bear.
It just,
there.
There's so much like a dog almost.
They're looking at enormous big dog.
It's this,
it's this.
I think they're cool.
They're cool animals.
I like looking at them.
I want to.
I still want to hug them.
You still want to.
What was that?
What was that show?
When we were kids,
a grizzly Adams,
grizzly Adams,
and he had that,
like that was his best friend.
I want her to be grizzly Adams.
So bad.
That wasn't the beard and the hat or
anything.
I just want to hang out and spoon that
bear every day.
So awesome.
I had the original hipster beard.
I used to have.
That guy would get so many chicks right
now in Venice.
I know,
right?
He went to fucking owning it.
Yeah.
He would be lifting weights.
I didn't know it was [inaudible].
Sixty eight got a grizzly bear in his
chest.
Is that dude still alive?
Oh Man.
Grizzly Adams.
It says death is death.
So I would say no grizzly guy.
He was so cool.
It's funny.
I had a.
oh,
it just died.
My,
uh,
my wife and I,
Dan Haggerty,
my,
my wife and I got a,
my wife and I got a Burmese mountain dog
years ago.
Have you seen those?
It's like a big Swiss dog.
No.
Awesome.
Is A.
It's related to a St Bernard.
So it's very similar to a St Bernard,
but they,
they're not like a slobbering breed.
They don't have slobber,
so they're really awesome.
They have this really cool markings,
but mine was like 130 pounds,
so it was like a grizzly bear and I
swear I was like living my childhood
dream of being adults because I would,
I'd come home and roll around with my
big bear,
you know,
it's like he was like a big grizzly bear
who's awesome.
I wonder if that's.
What did grizzly man in like maybe saw a
grizzly grizzly adams when he was a kid
and either that or he had just a bad
batch or something ripping.
Then I laughed the whole movie.
Oh yeah.
It's a hilarious moment at the end when
he gets wasted by the barrel.
I thought it was comical sheriff,
if anybody had ever been asking for it.
It was that dude 100 percent.
Yeah.
I think it was suicide by Bayer.
I really do,
because he went back into the area where
when you're not supposed to be there
when the air,
the animals are in hibernation,
except for the really desperate ones and
he knew that they were killing cubs.
Like that was part of the,
uh,
the video.
He stumbled upon these cubs that this
bear had killed.
They were starving to death.
The rivers had no salmon there.
It all dried up.
There was no salmon run and it was
getting real sketchy.
He stuck around.
They've accepted me as one of them was
the best trip.
Oh Man.
Way to go.
When the sheriff talked about it.
Oh,
I thought he was retarded.
Yeah,
it is.
I think it's a comedy and I want to talk
to Werner Herzog because he's supposed
to.
We're,
we're apparently we're in contact with
people and we're trying to work
something out because he's got something
else that he's promoting,
but there's no other documentaries that
he does that are funny like that.
Yeah.
Like that one is fucking funny.
I'm not sure it was meant to be funny,
but it is.
I feel like human being,
you have to look and be like,
you gotta be kidding me with this dude.
There's some wild people out there
though.
For sure.
Timothy Treadwell desperately wanted to
be one with tobacco
gold.
The gold.
I'm protecting these bears.
No one's protecting these bears when he
goes into those rants because he would,
he would film himself going on like
three or four different grants and he
would only use like one of them,
but some of them he would just start
swearing and you park department and
where's the,
I want to get like the lost tapes.
They had a whole series and they really
took his,
they took his tapes and they made a
whole series about it and it was
fucking.
I mean he had like hundreds of hours of
footage and he got amazing,
amazing,
unprecedented closeup footage of bears
because no ones that fucking snow at
that crazy.
You got to be nuts.
Yeah.
And those things.
We're not like close to a town and used
to humans.
It was,
that was like in the middle of nowhere.
Middle of nowhere.
His were straight up like wild grizzly
bears doing wild.
Crazy Bro.
Shit.
Yeah.
And he was watching them go to war with
each other.
I mean he got footage from like 20,
30 yards away of these two enormous
grizzly bears.
Tell him to stop it.
Huh?
Stop fighting with that guy was 100
percent fighting the gay,
like the gay was disturbing him so much.
He decided to go camping with monsters.
He's like,
I just added Kit can accept the fact
that I'm gay and so he would fix that
problem,
didn't you?
We grow with them at the time too.
And apparently,
um,
apparently there's audio and I don't
know if they destroyed it,
but that was part of the,
uh,
the documentary.
There's,
it lasted seven minutes because fares
don't fucking tell you.
They just started eating you.
They can hold you down.
I'm not trying to kill you.
They just want,
I just want to eat you.
That's a weird thing about omnivores as
opposed to predators.
Like,
predators just kind of kill you.
But I'm divorced for the most part.
They just hold you down like chimps,
chimps to hold things down and eat them.
The whole like thing where like where we
want to dispatch an animal as quick as
possible to stop the suffering.
They don't have that part in them.
They're just like,
you want to scream?
Go ahead.
Yeah.
If you're going to get jacked by
something,
a cat is the way to get Jack [inaudible]
cats know how to kill you.
Yeah,
they're really good at it.
Mountain lions to be scary man.
Quick though.
Yeah.
Scary.
But once they get your neck,
yeah,
you tell us.
It's pretty much it.
But guys fight them off.
People fought off mountain lions because
I think animals,
they have this,
this like tipping point where they go,
okay,
could I get fucking injured here?
If I can get injured here,
I'm going to back off and go kill
something stupid.
I'm going to go fuck someone's dog up or
something.
You know,
because there's like a tipping point
where the animal realize like,
this guy is fighting for his life.
Fuck,
this is too much work.
I'm out of here.
Yeah.
You know,
and that brings me back to the shark
thing,
like the,
that that would be like just a horrific
way to go.
There's those things are enormous and
when they want to kill you,
they'll kill you.
And it's a three,
but this is a strange animal.
It's like nature's cleanup crew.
Nature's just decided,
look,
there's just too much shit in this ocean
and so we're going to develop this
insane thing that doesn't even,
it doesn't even get to sleep.
Get to see the footage of none of that.
Did you see the footage of the surf
contest that happened last year in
Africa where the guy gets attacked by
the shark?
That's a good buddy of mine.
And,
and uh,
they,
I mean that was like a 18 to 20 foot
long.
Great White Shark.
Pull it out up.
Jamie.
When I saw it,
I was on a plane and that happen and I
was landing in Honolulu and I turned my
phone on and had like all these crazy
messages from all my friends,
you know,
because it's just,
it's,
it's a really small world in the surf
world.
And that was like,
it was no accident that the giant great
white shark was within a couple of feet
of him.
You know,
look at that.
Like everyone's like,
oh,
it wasn't trying to attack them.
It wasn't,
it wasn't.
It didn't mean anything.
That's great.
White Shark is that close to a human
being?
It was having a real good look,
you know,
I think,
oh fuck yeah.
It may not have been wanting to attack
them or whatever,
but it didn't just get accidentally
stuck in his leash.
You know what I mean?
When you do that right.
There is a scare as a human being could
possibly be without getting killed right
there.
And he's looking at it.
It's behind him and he's swimming.
That's it right there.
Right.
That's it in front of them.
It was body was right there.
It in.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
He's hard as nails and,
and,
and the other Guy Julian Wilson,
that was mick fanning and the blue and
look at him.
He's just feeling when he got up on that
raft and when that was going down it
was,
it was a full on ordeal of like,
you know,
it didn't happen like real quick and he
just jumped on,
was like,
that was like a law.
A lot of seconds right there.
Happening is board got taken away from
him and he had to swim and splash you
splashing water,
you know,
panicking.
And then the other guy,
Julian Wilson in his,
he was 100 feet away and I was paddling
full speed towards him to try and help
instead of like,
that's like,
that's like when you show your true
colors,
you know,
that's when you know that Shit's going
down is when you see a friend of yours
getting what he thought was attacked by
a great white.
You probably,
it's probably just a switch that goes
off in your head.
You probably don't even.
It's probably just pure lizard thinking,
you know,
it's like the survival feeling.
Like when that thing hit his board and
you're in full on panic mode,
you realize like you have got to get the
fuck away from this town.
There's no other options.
So I watched it and you see him read it.
He doesn't like go.
What was that?
He reacts super.
He was ready to like fight.
If that thing was there,
I'm 100 percent sure he started swinging
right it right away.
If it was right there,
you know,
I have a friend,
actually I have a friend where I live.
Um,
he's actually,
he lives on the same island is me,
he's from,
from where I live in a tiger.
Shark,
came up,
grabs him,
takes him under water by the side,
grabs him with a whole mouth bite on his
ribs and his head and takes them under
water like six feet under water.
And he had a straight up punch up with
the thing underwater.
Oh my God,
he's beating the shit out of the shark.
He's a big dude.
But he was at the time he was like 16
years old.
He Oulu and he's a local Hawaiian kid
from where I live and it took them under
water and he's straight up flat.
The shark and I ended up letting him go
yet I think he had like 200 stitches or
300 stitches or something.
I mean his whole side was just cut open.
It's amazing that he's amazing.
He's okay.
I can't even imagine what that would a
little look in there.
And the thing like looking at the
eyeball,
been right there
like staring at him,
you know.
And,
and he said he was just hitting thing as
hard as he possibly could.
Luckily he's a big dude.
It's crazy that they're attributing it.
It makes sense though to overfishing
that they're just don't have enough to
eat anymore.
It makes sense.
Totally makes sense.
And the thing is,
no matter how many attacks there are,
like there's been,
there's been a shitload of attacks in
Australia,
a lot in certain pockets,
certain areas.
And there's one area in eastern
Australia like on the east coast that
is,
has a ton of attacks and last five years
and another place on the west coast.
And there's all these groups that are
just like,
nope,
you can't do anything to the sharks.
You cannot do anything of the sharks,
you know,
well,
who are these groups and what is there a
mentalist groups that just like,
no matter what,
you can't,
you can't hurt nature type of thing.
Is there a shortage of sharks?
Well,
I've mad it's,
it's,
it's hard.
But the bottom line is if they were less
sharks,
it'd be less attacks,
right?
Yeah.
So
difficult.
There's not a real,
there's not a real solution where you
can,
where are you going to make everybody
happy?
You know what,
you're never gonna make everybody happy
when you have a environmentalists or
animal rights advocates and there's a
lot of like really fucking crazy and
environmental and anti hunting an animal
rights activists that they're not using
logic or conservation,
they just love animals.
They want them protected at all costs.
What's interesting is they don't have
any problem with animals,
fucking up animals.
No.
Like they don't like people eating
animals,
but they don't have any problem with
animals.
Just ripping animals apart.
Yeah.
It's weird.
It is weird.
It's weird because it's like they accept
nature,
they love nature,
but they don't like the nature of a
human being a predator.
Like they want to move away from that.
Yeah.
People are,
are a trip these days.
Man.
I,
uh,
it's funny because the whole social
media thing for me is,
is,
is relatively new.
It's,
you know,
obviously we didn't grow up with that
and it baffles me because you know,
I can,
I can spear fish and I've,
I've posted like a photo of me.
Nobody was like of my spirit and my fit.
There's like a,
like a bloody fish in my hand.
Good job,
great going.
Awesome.
Great Fish.
No one says a word about anything that I
killed a fish.
You kill a deer.
Hollow man.
People just freak out.
See what happens.
Not Kill a bear.
Bear.
I can only imagine the more people who
hated me for that than anything I've
done.
Besides fear factor.
Yeah.
They get so mad.
I'm like,
I'm eating it.
This is what I eat.
I don't eat.
I don't buy meat.
People have such a problem with that.
Now I get these done is dumbest comments
like literally like there's plenty of
meat in the store.
Why would you have to go and do that?
Oh,
you're a terrible person.
Like I'm not a terrible person because I
go to the store and eat it.
You're a terrible person because you go
and get your food yourself.
And,
and kill it because you did the killing
with your own hands.
You're bad.
I go and buy it with your money.
You don't have to be pretty wild.
That whole,
it just blows my mind because,
you know,
I didn't grow up in a city.
Like I get all these people
from like Rio de Janeiro or Sao Paolo or
someplace in South America or a big
city.
And I hit the point I,
I'm not pointing the finger at South
Americans or anything like that.
It's like,
but it always,
it's always people who are in cities
because they have this major
disconnection from their food.
Right.
And where I live,
I live,
I live in Hawaii.
Everybody I know is a fisherman or a
hunter and they,
you know,
people have gardens.
It's like there's a way of life where
they,
where we live,
there's tons of fish everywhere.
If you throw your net,
you're going to get dinner.
That's what people do.
They know the eat the food that they get
around them.
And not always,
but that's just a,
it's very,
very typical to be a hunter or a
fisherman.
And you know like where I live,
that's viewed as the same exact thing of
fishermen and hunters the same.
I don't,
I don't see the difference.
And so that's why it's shocking to me
with the whole how people are totally
fine.
You clubbing a bunch of fish,
but the second you kill a deer,
they just lose it.
Yeah.
Well what exactly what you said.
It's just the disconnect of not,
not really understanding where their
food comes from.
Not being in any way connected to the
idea of the natural cycle of life.
And then there's also a hierarchy of
animals that you're allowed to kill.
I'm not allowed to kill Turkeys.
Nobody gives a fuck when you hold up a
dead Turkey.
No,
don't give a shit.
No.
But if you hold up a dead bear and a
dead for a period of those things.
Yeah.
Pigs,
they don't have a problem with them.
Shit about pigs.
It's weird.
Get rid of them.
Especially for takes to.
Yeah,
like most people.
Yeah.
Bacon everyday,
right?
Like,
Yep.
Get rid of those boards as that's a
disgusting filthy animal.
Kill it.
I'm going to have my bacon too.
Yeah.
Why did you shoot that deer though?
Yeah,
but they have to do that.
Yeah.
Well the bear bears are the big ones
because I think in a lot of ways people
associate bears with trophy hunting.
Trophy hunting is something that.
I mean I'm,
I get it.
I understand that there's a lot of money
involved in it for the communities where
they shoot these animals and that it
benefits them and then also they have
population issues with a lot of these
animals.
Like we were talking about it yesterday.
The thing that happened in Zimbabwe with
Cecil the lion.
Yeah.
How they have to shoot 200 lines now
they have to kill them because they're
just decimating the underland
population.
Nobody knows about that.
All those people that were pissed about
Cecil have no idea.
They got to kill the lions.
Yeah.
No idea of how it,
how it works over there,
and the only reason those lands are
alive is because of hunters and they're
losing a million dollars in revenue
because they cost them $50,000 to shoot
a lion.
So all that money would go to
conservation,
hiring all the conservation agents and
stop.
I'm
really.
Yeah,
I mean it's a,
it's a shitty system.
It's because they're dangerous.
They can't do it.
Like in America,
it's great.
It's like,
you know,
when I bought my tag for Colorado,
I buy it for 600 bucks,
like 5:50 goes straight to conservation
and that's awesome.
And that's why there's so many animals,
you know,
and that's it.
That's a really healthy system of how
to,
how to like increase populations,
how to,
how take care of habitat
at a higher more park rangers,
how to,
how to buy more land and,
and,
you know,
make bigger reservations and bigger
conservation areas.
And I don't think people know that,
but they don't.
Most people have no idea that most of
the money that goes towards wildlife
habitat,
like maintaining habitat all comes from
hunters like 90 percent.
And then on top of that there's a tax on
sporting goods that goes to that.
And you know,
people always say,
well,
hunting isn't conservation,
but you know what?
Here's the thing.
Hunters and hunting products,
whether it's a bowhunting stuff or rifle
stuff,
they did not fight that tax,
but you knew who did fight that tax.
All those other companies that make
hiking stuff and Rei and those
companies,
they didn't want attack,
so they've tried to impose another tax
and these people have fought it off and
the reason they fought it off is because
they don't have to pay it.
They don't have to pay it.
It's going to fuck with their overhead's
going to fuck with the amount of money
that they have to charge for things,
and so this,
this idea that these hunters aren't real
conservationist,
they're using it as an excuse.
The bottom line is that's where all the
money's coming from.
All of it for habitat protection,
wetland habitat protection law,
all that comes from hunters and it's all
a lot of money.
It's like if they stopped hunting,
if they made hunting illegal and they
cut off that supply revenue,
there's a lot of animals that we'd be
fucked.
There would be.
People don't like it because it's one of
those really weird kind of gray area
things or it just doesn't make you feel
comfortable thinking that the money that
has come,
first of all,
the only reason why there's elk and all
the habitats that they're at right now
is because hunters introduced them to
those areas.
They were decimated by the turn of the
19th century or the 20th century,
so in the early 19 hundreds there was
very few elk left in this country,
so the Rocky Mountain Elk Federation
spent considerable amounts of money,
resource man hours moving animals into
these areas like Kentucky,
like Kentucky has like a huge ell
population now.
There was nothing there just 30,
40 years ago.
Nothing,
zero.
So they've.
They've figured out a way to not just
maintain populations so hunters can kill
them,
but they've also reintroduced him to
areas where they didn't exist before.
Increase populations by a hundred times
in a lot of students.
I mean the elk numbers have never been
as high as they have been in the last 20
years.
Yeah,
no,
no.
There.
It's amazing what they've done and it's
all because of hunters and that's
that's.
I understand it for people that are
animal rights lovers,
but I just wish they had a more balanced
perspective and they understood what all
the pieces that are in place are.
It's,
it's an uncomfortable thing for a lot of
people to think that the people who want
to hunt and kill and eat these animals
are the ones that love them the most.
Yeah.
This crazy thinking.
Right?
Well all the people that are super
butthurt about the hunting thing aren't
doing anything about it.
Yeah,
of course.
Yeah.
They're just being angry and lashing out
with their phone,
but they're not doing anything to say
the animals,
those,
those people are
on the front lines in Africa trying to
save the lions or the elephants or
trying to.
Trying to go against poachers and do
something about it.
All those people are just are just chit
chatting,
you know,
well,
there's not enough money.
I mean,
if they really wanted to do the kind of
work that the hunters who are doing,
they'd have to have some stream revenue
and the stream of revenue that is coming
from hunting is all coming from tags.
It's all coming from the sale of hunting
gear and products and there's just no
way they can match that.
There's no way.
There's millions of hunters,
millions of hunters that are
contributing literally a billion
dollars.
It's probably more than a billion
dollars a year that goes to
conservation.
Yeah.
Especially.
So it's,
it's a weird.
It's one of those weird things.
It just doesn't.
It seems like it should be cut and dry.
Well,
and I think people have a misconception
of about hunting in general,
like in most states,
like,
like say Colorado,
that the areas that I've hunted there,
like on a do it yourself over the
counter tag costs me like 550 bucks,
600 bucks and I go there with my buddy.
It's in an area that has,
you know,
a seven percent success rate for archery
or maybe less six or seven percent.
So out of 100 hunters,
maybe six or seven people get an elk,
so all these people are really just
paying for the experience of elk
hunting.
They're not even.
It's not like they're going in there
buying an animal or nothing like that.
It's like I'm going out,
I'm going to Colorado.
This is my trip for the year.
I choose to go out and just hunt elk for
two weeks or three weeks or one week or
however long you have time and.
And that's what the hunting experience
is all about for me.
I mean I,
I love them the meat.
That's awesome.
I love the successful hunt.
That's great.
For sure.
I love eating it,
but the.
But the bottom line is if I go elk
hunting and don't get an elk,
it's not an unsuccessful hunt.
I'm so stoked.
This is like the best experience ever.
Yeah.
It's a very enjoyable,
deeply rewarding experience just to be
out there trying and attempting it and
when you are successful it makes it that
much more rewarding because you know how
difficult it is,
especially when you're doing it with a
bow and arrow.
Yeah,
I mean it is.
You have to get within,
I mean if you're really fucking good,
you could shoot something within 90
yards,
but for the most part you're trying to
get somewhere within 30,
40 yards.
Yeah,
that's right.
It's about Jim.
What is this?
Oh,
well,
I got sportsmen contribute nearly
$8,000,000 every day.
Adding two more than two point $9
billion dollars every year for
conservation hunters and target shooters
have paid seven point $1,000,000,000 in
excise taxes since the inception of the
Pittman Robertson act in 1937 sets.
Incredible.
Everybody in America knows about Cecil
the lion.
Everybody knows about Cecil.
Nobody knows that.
Nobody.
Only hunters know that,
you know?
Yeah,
I'm confused here.
How's that work?
It says I get the $8,000,000 everyday
contributing more than two point $9
million dollars every year for
conservation.
But this is what I don't understand.
It says hundreds and target shooters
have paid six,
seven point 1 billion in excise taxes
specifically that just specifically
excise taxes.
Yeah.
Okay.
It's a shitload of money.
Yeah.
So it's tags,
um,
and
then equipment and taxes.
So I guess the taxes is whereas this is
the billion,
the seven point 1 billion,
the rest of it is tags,
which is two point $9,
billion dollars a year.
It's amazing.
But again,
it's the people that live in the cities
that are disconnected and I was one of
them.
I mean if you talk to me,
if you got a hold of me,
you know,
20 years ago when I never even
considered hunting and he asked me about
like it'd be a little assholes shooting
an animal.
Animals are awesome.
Bunch of pussies with their big guns.
Go buy dog food and cat food because I
love animals and buying ground up
fucking chickens.
Yeah,
I mean that's the funniest one is like
vegans with cats want more than one
point four,
$2,
billion dollars through state hunting
and fishing license.
Wow,
that's incredible.
One point $4,000,000,000 in conservation
comes from hunting and fishing license
sales.
Six hundred,
8 million from other revenue.
Seven hundred $49 million to excise
taxes paid solely by sportsmen.
That's amazing.
Yeah.
I mean,
that's where the money comes and if that
money's not going to be replaced by
people who love animals and that's also,
there's a lot of people that think of
hunters like the characters in a movie
like an Elmer Fudd,
some asshole who hates animals,
but when you listened to like really
good hunting podcasts,
like there's this guy,
Jay Scott,
he's got a really good hunting podcast
and cody rich as a rich outdoors and
Steven Rinella has immediate or
podcasts,
which is Mike,
my favorite.
You're,
you're listening to really intelligent,
really smart,
well educated people that understand a
lot about conservation,
the environment,
the animals they're pursuing and when
they're talking about tactics and
strategies and details and all the
different,
different areas of your hunting,
all the different places where you're
putting in for tags,
you realize like this is a complex
system that they're trying to navigate
in order to be successful.
It's fucking very,
very difficult and it's primal as fuck.
The whole thing is like,
it's a wild experience and like
literally wild and many different
levels.
Yeah.
And just,
uh,
yeah.
I just,
I don't know.
I can't get enough of it.
I swear.
Like I,
I,
I feel like I,
I like,
I measure my success not so much now
because my kids are having a family guy
and,
and that's basically all I care about is
my kids these days.
But I swear like I measure my success by
how many days a year I spent in
camouflage.
That's how I know I had a super good
year is if I went hunting a lot.
I swear it's like,
and,
and like if I,
if I'm,
if I don't hunt for awhile,
like my wife will call my friend and be
like,
dude,
you gotta take Shane Hunting.
He's being a dick.
He's being a total asshole and you need
to take them honey.
So it's like you need to get your fix.
I know I just get grouchy and grumpy and
I don't even really feel it coming on.
And my wife's like,
you need to go hunting,
but what is it you think that's causing
that?
It's like the,
I don't know,
is
it,
is it something's causing hunting?
Not Hunting.
Hunting is alleviating that and some
sort of a way.
Yeah,
and surfing I,
I do,
I've,
you know,
I need to surf a lot and I need to hunt
a lot.
It's just who I am now.
It's just like I'm,
I'm 100.
It's like I'm a surfer.
It's,
it's not what I do.
That's the,
I feel like that's who I am.
So it's just being a part of the natural
world.
Like the surfing thing is you're,
even though you're on a board that's
made out of composite materials and you
know,
you've got wax on and all this jazz and
it's all created by a factor,
but there's something about your,
you're introducing your life or your,
your being into the natural world of the
ocean and you feel something like,
they say that the ocean has some sort of
an electro magnetic like feel to it like
there's something about the ocean
because it's essentially alive.
You know,
it has living things in it,
but there's oxygen in the water and
that's,
that's how these plants grow.
And when there's dead spots,
that's why these fish die like this.
It's almost like an,
it's not just like an ecosystem,
it's almost like a giant living thing
and you're swimming around in that thing
sort of absorbing its life for us
and I feel like it just keeps you young.
I think it's like,
I swear like surfing a lot,
being in the sun,
being in the ocean a lot and not like
sitting there frying yourself or
anything like that,
but just like spending a life in the
ocean and in the sun.
Is this good for you?
Yeah,
I know people who are in their fifties
and sixties and nurses healthy,
they look young.
They don't,
they don't have like tons of physical
problems and um,
I don't know.
It's just,
I think it's good for you.
I think spending time in the outdoors,
whether you're in the mountains with
your bow or whether you're in the ocean
doing,
doing whatever you're doing,
it's just good.
Well,
it's certainly good to be active now and
it's also absorbing vitamin D three or
creating Vitamin d three through the
song.
So that's a rare thing.
Yeah.
Then coming home with organic grass fed
wild meat is even better.
You know,
yeah,
no,
all those things are,
I mean you,
you're living a very natural life in a
lot of ways and that what you know,
and again it's,
there's also the satisfaction element,
just like the people who grow a garden
can Kinda,
and I have a garden I get it,
is there's a,
there's a connection,
like if I grow some tomatoes and some
Kale and I put together a salad when I'm
eating that salad,
I'm like,
I know we're not,
not only know where this came from,
I was there,
I put the seeds in,
I watered it,
I fertilized.
Yeah.
It's um,
there's something deeply satisfying
about making your own food that you grow
or that you go and get as opposed to
going to a supermarket.
It
only takes a lot more effort to.
Yeah.
So you just have like a,
you know,
like that,
that elk steak that you eat.
Like if you,
if you,
if you did a side like a side by side
comparison with someone who didn't hunt,
you know,
they may not feel the same way,
but because you packed it out,
you put all the time and on the target
you did all the hunting,
you,
you like look forward to it for six
months that hunt and it just,
that's the best tasting steak you're
ever going to have because you have the
pride of knowing that you did it all
yourself.
Yeah.
It's certainly a very,
very different feeling now living in
Hawaii and being a white guy.
What is that like?
Because people say weird things about
it.
I've never found Hawaiians to be racist
or rude or weird,
but I've heard crazy shit and I've
always wondered like if that crazy shit
is from like rude Americans that come
over there and are disrespectful or act
like they own the place or.
Well,
there's a little bit of both.
Yeah.
There's a little bit of both.
There's,
there's uh,
you know,
I mean I grew up.
I mean I was born and raised in Hawaii
so I saw a lot of this,
you know,
like in high school and elementary
school,
like if you were a white,
like everybody wanted to be a Hawaiian
when they are young.
Right?
Like everybody at my school,
like if you're white you kind of wish
you weren't really.
That's kind of the deal.
Yeah.
When you're really young,
especially back in the day,
like is it like seventies and eighties?
Right.
So like when I was a kid there was this
thing called kill holiday,
not making it up.
I don't like.
So you know what holly is like a white
dude.
So there was a thing,
it was called kill holiday and it was
always at the end of the year and it was
like,
I don't even know if they actually
practiced it when I was a kid,
but it was still,
it was a thing and it was a thing where
like Hawaiians would be like this is it,
like we're almost out of school.
It's beat up some holly's or whatever
deal was.
And that's,
I mean,
it didn't really happen when I was when
I was a kid,
but there was a thing called kill
holiday and people would talk about it
and,
but times have definitely changed.
And uh,
and,
and uh,
and the other thing is like,
there's a huge difference between a
white dude who was born in Hawaii and a
white guy who moved to Hawaii.
So if you're from Hawaii,
like born and raised in Hawaii is
totally different than,
than if you're a dude from Orange County
that moved to cal moved to Hawaii when
you're 18.
And then like next thing you know,
you're trying to talk like the Hawaiians
and stuff like that.
That's when people freak that,
that's people lose it when the,
when a dude rolls up and like with the
Hawaiian stickers on their truck and
jumps out and is trying to act like a
local dude,
that's when guys get angry.
That's not cool.
So it's like a cultural appropriation
thing.
Yeah,
they just,
it's just like,
um,
I don't know how to explain it,
but it's,
it,
it gets a little complicated.
But if you show people respect,
you know it,
if,
if you're chill,
if you paddle out in the water at a,
at a localized break and you're mellow,
you don't have a bunch of Ding dongs
with you.
If you paddle out by yourself and you
show respect and you're mellow than
everyone gives you.
Respect that.
That's what I've always found.
So the issue is disrespectful people and
a lot of ways,
right?
Yeah.
It's just a,
it's just different.
It's like its own country.
It's like I've never been to Texas,
but I hear it's like its own,
its own kind of place is definitely it's
own country.
If you get off the plane at my house and
you get like a convertible Mustang rent
a car and someone's going 45 and 55 and
a lifted truck,
you don't pass them.
You know what I mean?
If you pass them,
they'll chase you down and will really.
Oh yeah,
that's just disrespectful.
It's like you're in Hawaii and I'll slow
down,
you know,
don't,
don't go 65 and a 55 and a convertible
Mustang.
It's like they're just,
it's just a strange place.
It's like,
it's a,
I don't know,
it's just,
it's,
its own kind of place,
man.
Well,
it's,
it's occupied.
I mean,
it's sort of an occupied country
completely.
Yeah.
It's like they don't,
they're a part of the United States,
you know,
in quotes,
in air quotes,
but not really.
That's a country.
And then people sailed.
They're on sailing canoes from French
Polynesia with stars for navigation.
They got there on their own.
Anything with them?
It's,
I dunno,
uh,
it'd be 3000 miles or something like
that.
What in the fuck they did that in a
canoe.
Yes.
I don't even like driving to vegas and
like,
hey guys,
like we're out of here.
We're actually,
we're not good.
Just going on a cruise.
We're moving.
We're going to become.
Hawaiians were to bring our babies and
you have kids.
Imagine bringing your kid on a fucking
whole move to Hawaii.
They live there.
They had their awesome system of the
people in the mountains.
They trade with the people at the beach
for food and sustenance and that's how
they live.
You know,
there's a mountain people,
there's the ocean people and nobody
owned any land.
There was no concept of owning land.
People will just share it and got along
and they had their system that worked,
you know,
it was a gnarly time too.
There was,
there was a lot of gnarly stuff that was
going on.
It was like a radical time to live.
If you're,
if you did something bad,
you're,
you're executed and all kinds of crazy
shit and like back in the day.
But um,
you know,
when the white dude showed up when
Captain Cook showed up and the
missionary showed up and their boats and
they were trading a musket for like
100,000 Acre ranch,
you know,
it was like she got crazy in Hawaiian
and you and you can feel that nowadays.
I mean there's a lot of Hawaiians are
getting pushed out,
know all these people live in different
places on the mainland and make a bunch
of money.
And then they retire in Hawaii because
who wouldn't?
Right?
Everybody wants to live in Hawaii,
but they bring their money to Hawaii.
It drives the value up.
And then the Hawaiians can't live there
anymore and they get pushed out to these
areas that are less desirable,
that are,
you know,
and they can't make money in Hawaii.
So there's a lot of resentment,
you know,
there's,
there's a lot of,
there's a crazy dynamic and Hawaiian and
you feel that and I don't know that
that'll never get taken away.
How does that work?
Because the last time I was there,
I was looking at these properties that
were on the beach.
I was like,
look at the size of this fucking place
is enormous house that someone built on
this beach.
And someone was telling me,
yeah,
that's some ceos,
Jamey,
it's his house,
he's got a fucking helicopter pad and
shit.
And I was like,
okay,
how does that work?
So this guy like flies in,
stays there sometimes and how the people
around feel about that a week,
a year.
And they spent five years building their
house with like Italian.
Granted that's flown in from Italy and,
and you know,
you know,
and,
and it's like.
And I was like,
guess who's swinging the hammers,
right?
Hawaiians,
yeah.
Yeah.
And they have to drive there from like
their little zone or wherever,
you know,
wherever,
wherever they're living,
they definitely don't live in like a
private community by the beach golf
course.
Well,
and so how do people feel about those
people that do that?
They,
do they get upset at them?
Are they angry at them?
Really?
I think they understand.
I just think they,
they,
uh,
it's just a difficult situation.
You know,
it's like,
it's like a,
it's like a lot of places in America
really think about it.
It's not,
it's not that unusual situation in
Hawaii.
It just seems odd because it's,
there's so many of these multimillion
dollar vacation estates that are bought
by the beach and you're like,
that's like some crazy fuck you ceo type
money that you have to have to have one
of these things.
Like how weird is it?
These people that come to this place and
they occupy the spot,
but there's a bunch of people that have
been here and their ancestors has been
here for a thousand plus years and this
is kind of their area,
but you can buy a spot.
There were five days a week their whole
life and they can't buy a house,
you know,
and then the whole,
the whole,
the whole runway where I live is filled
with private jets.
Just sitting there waiting.
Really?
Oh yeah.
People spend 50 million on their house.
Like there's a,
there's every single one of those guys
in the fortune $500.
A CEO is all the guys from every big
giant tech company.
They all have houses where I live one
week a year and their jet.
That's so strange.
That's a good while to break in when
they're not there now they got top notch
security.
Think they wouldn't use it.
Like tech guys.
Roseanne Barr is a friend of mine.
She lives there.
Yeah.
It's a cool place to live.
I mean it's,
it's.
People understand why those people want
to live there.
The weather's great.
It's a beautiful place.
No one's,
no one's blaming them for living there.
That's not the problem.
But the problem is them being
disrespectful to the people that do live
there.
And if you're going to be there,
relax toy,
right in a big rush.
Don't overtake me.
Don't drive like you live in an asshole.
This is not la.
Yeah,
it's not.
You know,
so just when you get to Hawaii,
just relax a little bit.
Oh,
I got that text shoe this morning.
The texts that you sent me.
Fuck la traffic.
That's all it said.
It.
She realized like this place is the
exact opposite of the big island.
I mean this place is some strange sort
of magnet for Weirdos and everybody's
just getting sucked into this giant
population center.
And you try to get anywhere even in the
middle of the day.
I mean you were,
you were here at noon,
so you're driving around at 11:00 AM.
Eleven am.
Everybody's at work.
No big deal.
Yeah.
Jammed bumper to bumper.
You should go out.
Go out at four just so you want to kill
yourself.
Just go get on the four or five at four
in the afternoon.
You'd be like,
what in the fuck is this?
What is this?
If you get on the four,
oh,
five between like 11 at night and four
in the morning.
You beat rush hour traffic.
Yeah.
If you don't.
Maybe if you.
If you're.
If you.
If it's light outside,
it's rush hour.
Yeah,
straight up.
Because I drove just now from San Diego
to La.
I stopped in Orange County and get an
MRI,
but I.
It was rush hour traffic the whole way
up.
There was a stop and go and it was like
it was.
There was no accident.
There was no road construction.
There's nothing.
That's.
Well sometimes
you'll be in a bumper to bumper stop.
It's a mile long at two in the morning.
Yeah.
Fuck man.
What the fuck is this as?
I don't know.
That shit drives me crazy that a parking
in the street sweeping and then they
have these like,
like the,
like the technology,
like in places like Manhattan beach and
Hermosa Beach,
they have like these,
like the,
the parking meter dudes.
They have a thing now where if the
parking meter,
if your money runs out,
they get like a big.
Like they know where you are and that
your parking meter ran out and they can
drive over there and they just go right
to it.
It's not hyper efficient technology to
give you tickets.
Imagine like the revenue,
right?
It's like,
yeah,
but that's kind of what drives me nuts.
That's Kinda what I was getting at when
I was asking about Hawaii.
It was like,
there's different kinds of weirdness.
There's a different kind of weird just
to live in there.
And then there's a weirdness to living
here,
which is the overpopulation weirdness
and the show Biz weirdness.
Yeah.
Like what do you prefer?
Oh Man.
You know,
I don't know how I was born and raised
in Hawaii as you know,
like the pace I liked the.
I liked that no one gives a shit which
school my kids go to or what I drive.
No one judges me if I drive a shitty car
or they.
You better the opposite.
Yeah.
And,
and,
uh,
I just,
I don't know,
I dig that it's,
it's people,
people,
people judge me on who I am as a person
and what I do and how I,
I know,
I feel like it's a little bit more,
it's just a little bit more real I guess
and just,
you know,
more down to earth where I live,
but I also don't live in like the,
you know,
I live in kind of a small town,
so it's like coffee farms and ranches
and it's pretty chill where I live.
Yeah.
Yeah,
that's the weirdest thing about the big
island.
Um,
I'm a big fan of the big island.
I love visiting there,
but one of the craziest things about it
is there's so many different ecosystems
in one island or you drive through this
one area,
it's like completely dry.
It looks like a desert and then you go
into another area is constantly raining.
It's like a tropical rain forest,
like Hilo,
like up in that area.
Yeah,
it's wild.
I don't know,
I,
I should look it up.
But uh,
I have uh,
the,
the big island of Hawaii,
there's like all these,
like a climate zones and they always say
that I forgot the exact numbers,
but it's like out of the,
out of like these certain sort of
climate zones throughout the world,
like the Big island has like 11 of the
13 or something like that.
So like if you get in your car and drive
for two hours,
you'll go through like a,
like if you just like happen to like go
to sleep and wake up like 15 minutes
later everything looks different and go
to sleep,
wake up 15 minutes later,
everything looks different and it
changes so much.
You know,
it's wild,
it's like a lot of feel desert and like,
like a dry land forest and there's like
a rain forest and jungle and it was just
bizarre.
Well that's the other thing about the
big island is that there's sometimes
snow there.
Oh yeah,
go snowboarding sometimes.
What the fuck?
Where's the happened?
Like build a kicker and like launch off
it.
And
that's what we do.
And when it was snowing and I was in
high school,
we drive up there,
I try to go every year to the
observatory.
Keck observatory.
Yeah.
When it's,
when there's no moon,
so you could see the stars just to freak
myself out because I went once many
years ago and it just changed my world
and I am the one experience changed the
way it was,
like literally being on a spaceship and
changed the way I looked at the world
because um,
for people don't know,
there's all these light diffusers.
There's diffused light lamps all around
the big island so that it doesn't give
any light pollution to the keck
observatory.
Which one of the biggest telescopes in
the continental United States or in the
continental United States,
right?
It's not technically in the U,
s in the world.
I think even the clarity and,
and uh,
and no light pollution there.
It's beautiful.
You go up there and you see every star
and it just seems.
It seems like you're on a spaceship.
It's like you're on a spaceship and
you're looking through a portal.
Yeah,
that's what it looks like.
That's literally what it looks like.
Yeah.
And it,
it,
it almost hurts your brain.
It's like,
is this up there all the time?
Not to open a can of worms,
but did you follow that whole a
telescope thing last year on the Big
Island?
Oh,
about the construction.
Thirty meter telescope
that they were trying to do and they
said it was sacred lands.
We couldn't build it.
Yeah.
Well explain that.
You are up on it.
That's it.
I mean,
uh,
the,
the land,
the land where the telescopes are built
are considered sacred land by a lot of.
I mean basically like every single
Hawaiian group that there is,
but there's a designated,
there's a designated area within that
sacred land that is designated for like
astronomy and you know,
all that stuff.
So,
but they have like all these giant giant
telescopes that are owned by different
countries,
like China has theirs and the US has
theirs and Soviet Union,
whatever,
whatever.
They like.
All these big countries span all these
billions of dollars to make their
telescopes and there's some of them that
are completely obsolete and they're not
even being used anymore,
so instead of taking those four or five
down that they're not even using anymore
and building a new big one,
they just wanted to build a whole
another big one.
So there was people were up in arms
about it and it was going to be the
largest building on the big island as
well,
so people were just up in arms about it
and,
and there was all kinds of um,
you know,
people got super activated and really
started protesting the whole thing and
blocking the road and people were
getting arrested and all my friends were
involved and everybody was,
was against it and protesting.
It was pretty wild
because they just didn't want the
construction to continue and make bigger
things.
So they felt it seems inefficient.
Right.
It seems like they should be able to
take down the old ones and put up a more
modern one.
Yeah.
There was,
there was not really any Hawaiian groups
that were against the technology and
against the space exploration.
It wasn't anything about that.
It was the fact that it was,
they felt like they were being
disrespect because it was sacred land
that was not meant to,
you know,
build giant observatories there.
And,
and the fact that there was all these
ones that weren't being used is not in
the front.
Crazy is actually my truck is in the
back,
happens around here all the time.
Yeah.
It was a wild time.
And I,
and it was a weird because uh,
the,
you know,
the construction company that was
building it,
they had the permit already had the
financing already and they had the
Hawaiian government backing,
backing them.
I thought it was over.
I thought for sure there was no way to
stop the thing and it was amazing.
Like people really got activated like
through,
through social media and everybody just
got up in arms about it.
Everyone around the world knew about it
and,
and they ended up stopping it.
That's incredible.
Is incredible.
I wonder if that's a good thing or a bad
thing because I'm a big fan of space
exploration and I'm a big fan of what
they find out what these telescopes.
Yup.
But it seems like if they have
telescopes through not using anymore,
maybe it's just a financial issue or
cost a lot of money to break them down
and put a new one in the place and it's
not as financially efficient as starting
a new one.
Well,
it's always one of those things where
it's like it's,
you know,
in,
in white everything sacred.
Unless you have enough money.
It's like America in that way.
It's like if you,
if you want that beach front house,
nope.
You can't have it.
Oh,
you got enough money.
No worries.
You know,
if you're willing to pay like crazy for
it.
Yeah.
So if you want to build a observatory on
the big island,
you can't do it unless you have enough
money to put $100 million into the,
into the education system in Hawaii and
grease all the right politicians and get
it all through.
And Yeah,
a lot has to happen for one of those
things to be built and then the
contracts,
everyone's fighting over like the
building contracts because it's going to
cost two point $8 billion to build a
thing.
So there's a lot going on,
a lot of,
um,
a lot of crazy politics happening behind
the scenes to get that space exploration
happening.
So that's unfortunate.
Yeah.
And I don't think there's more than
100,000 people on the whole island,
right?
Yeah,
there's,
yeah.
There's bar now.
How many people live?
Long Island?
I think it's roughly between 150 and
200,000 now.
And when did that change?
That's just slowly going out.
A lot of people are moving there,
especially to the Kona side where I
live,
there's a lot more people moving there
permanently,
man,
it looks like lame on dope place to
live.
It's a good place to live.
I mean it's,
it's don't move there.
If you're listening to this,
you got nothing people down holly's are
you one of those so you don't count as a
holly?
No,
I'm just kidding.
Are you one of those?
Do you ever get called one of those?
Uh,
rarely,
but I am a holiday.
I have white skin,
you know,
but I don't know,
I mean I,
I feel like that's,
I'm not from anywhere else.
Right.
I'm not from,
I'm from New York City or from
Afghanistan.
But do you,
do you know how to talk pigeon?
I know how to talk to Virginia,
like if you were going to say do it or
Rogan show,
he won't do it.
It's dangerous.
It's dangerous speaking ebonics when I,
yeah,
when I,
I don't speak pigeon,
but when I'm having beers with,
with uh,
with,
you know,
when I'm at home and I'm a couple of
beers deep and yeah,
it starts slipping out every now and
then.
But yeah.
Oh,
so it's something that you did when you
were younger?
A little bit,
yeah.
Just to get along.
And it's just,
I dunno know,
it's just,
it's very typical to when people,
most local peoples speak pidgin
wireless.
Yeah.
Bj Penn was explaining it to me once.
And he was like saying like how you
would say things and that some people
turn it on and off,
but I just speak normal English.
Well,
it's a cool sound.
It sounds cool.
It's interesting.
It's very friendly.
Sort of a fun.
It is way to relaxed way.
My parents regal,
my parents were,
were uh,
would've killed me if I spoke in the
house.
Yeah,
there was not cool.
Plus it's like,
yeah,
I dunno.
I am a white guy so it's not.
I am not like a,
you know,
I didn't grow up in a Hawaiian family
where everyone spoke.
Pigeon.
So did your parents moved there?
Yeah.
My Dad was from La.
My Dad is from my dad or some this town.
He went to Hollywood high school,
Surf Malibu and he,
he raced cars and he was a stunt man.
He was a,
he was a stunt man for Elvis.
Elvis couldn't swim.
What?
I couldn't swim.
Honeymaid pulmonary on pills.
I think that he would float cookies.
All bloated.
No kidding,
right.
That was fat elvis.
He was,
he was in his prime back then.
But uh,
yeah.
So my dad did a bunch of movies with
him.
I'm like blue,
Hawaii and all that.
He had like a series of movies that were
all filmed in Hawaii and elvis couldn't
swim,
so my dad was,
the,
was a stunt double for all those movies
and they just decided to stay and he,
he just got sick of La and uh,
he hated the parking guys.
No,
I think he just,
he went to Hawaii and fell in love with
it.
He,
he ended up like moving on,
moving to a Wahoo and served and hung
out and met a bunch of local people that
he liked and he liked the lifestyle and
how people were there and ended up
moving into.
My mom went to college and she was from
Ohio and right when she graduated high
school she moved to Hawaii and went to
uhh.
Well I know a dozen.
Woody Harrelson live in Hawaii.
Yeah.
That's where the best weed is really
best.
We'd listen if there's better way than
what I have.
Keep it the fuck away from me.
Whoever's got better,
we'd stay away.
You can't get any better.
There's a lot of ways that our hands are
young people always want to say that.
Like someone said,
no,
I'm just kidding.
But we're talking about Colorado weed
isn't basically legal.
Basically illegal.
It's pretty.
It's pretty casual where I live,
I'm sure,
but it's not.
I hear if somebody wanted to fuck with
you,
they could technically.
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
See,
that's the thing about like Colorado
Colorado's wide open.
Yeah.
It's just,
there's nothing you just can't,
you know,
it's just,
it's just legal.
Yeah.
Nobody can go to jail unless the feds
come in and then you get like,
some you don't want to fuck with
Colorado people.
There's a lot of guns in Colorado.
That'd be a weird place for the feds to
kind of evade.
That.
Gives a lot of people like that.
Like woody Haroldson guys like,
I mean,
you know,
I don't know what He.
But uh,
I've,
I have friends who've known him on Maui.
They say he's just chill,
just,
he just likes to likes to Hawaii
lifestyle,
you know,
relax.
It was a very nice guy by all accounts.
I ran into this couple the other day at
the comedy store and they,
uh,
they moved from La to Hawaii.
They live in Maui now and I'm,
the girl hates it.
The dude loves it.
It was interesting talking to them
because the dude works at a resort
there.
He's like,
it is the fucking best place in the
world live.
Everybody's relaxed.
It's super cool.
The weather's amazing.
It's beautiful.
And the girl was like,
I gotta get the fuck out of here.
Yeah.
So my wife is a moved from La to Kona.
She went to Ucla and then she worked for
Warner Brothers television.
Whoa.
Yeah.
So she was on the grind.
Is that what you met her?
I met her.
I met her in San Diego years ago,
like before,
like right when she graduated high
school and started going in to like a
little college there.
And you're like,
you come in with me.
Women will go into a rock in the middle
of the ocean basically.
I'm moving into a volcano.
So she looks like a Hawaiian.
Actually she's,
she's,
she's half Japanese.
Oh,
that's beautiful and convenient.
So she looks like a local,
so everyone thinks I am the holly and
she's a local girl.
Uh,
so they think you snagged up a good one.
I did,
but they took one of their local girls.
So,
so anyway.
And,
but it's funny because when I asked her
to marry me and to move to Hawaii with
me,
it was like look like,
like this is where I live.
Like you're not from like,
you're not really.
She's not really from anywhere.
She was like born in the east coast,
like live all over the Midwest.
Um,
she moved a million different times,
you know,
her dad had for,
for his work was moving all over the
place and I went to high school and
college in California.
So when she moved to Hawaii she moved to
La and she was in the entertainment
business.
So she was,
she went from 10th gear to first gear,
was like crazy downshift.
So she's like,
yeah,
that'd be fine.
That'd be,
it'd be awesome.
Where,
you know,
I'm like,
I'll,
I'll do whatever it takes.
You're the right one.
You've got to move to Hawaii.
We're going to do this,
do this whole deal,
the family life,
the whole deal in Hawaii.
Um,
but she moved there and melted down.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
I had these terrifying moments where I
thought I was going to have to move to
la.
Whoa.
Yeah.
And I would have,
I would've done anything for her and,
and I,
and I told her,
I'm like,
Hey,
the Hawaii thing doesn't work out with
him,
you know,
I'll try and move to California.
So what was the meltdown over,
you know,
just like,
uh,
her friends,
her job,
her life was all in La,
right?
Shelly?
She left everything behind,
sacrificed everything and move to where
I live,
where my family is,
my friends and she didn't have any of
that.
So.
And then,
you know,
she had a hard time for awhile,
but as soon as she met a couple of
friends and it was all good and now
it's,
you couldn't prior away from the place.
Now she loves it where I live.
So she's a local girl now.
Wow.
That's interesting.
But it took a while until,
until she got friends there,
she was like,
the whole Hawaii thing was on thin ice.
That's how it always is though,
with people,
you know,
when you move to a new place,
it's fucking hard to be alone.
It's hard to be lonely.
It's lonely.
It's to meet people that you actually
liked to.
Oh yeah.
Especially if you're from La,
moved to Hawaii.
It's like,
you know,
she's,
she's not like a whole,
she's not like a local,
a local girl,
you know,
there's like a typical local girl.
Um,
and I don't get myself in hot water,
but she wasn't one of those.
She was,
you know,
she just had a hard time finding that
first good friend.
She was California nysed.
Yes.
Yeah.
Well I would think that like activities
like for you surfing,
obviously you wouldn't meet other
surfers.
A bowhunting,
you'd meet other bowhunters,
you find common ground,
you'd make some friends if you had to
move to a place like that.
But if you don't have like a real
obvious thing that you like to do that
other people like to do as well.
I would say that would become a real
issue.
It would.
It would because you know,
I think you feel like you lose your
identity and that's the way to live and
no you don't.
You don't want to like move somewhere or
live some life where you don't really
know what's going on or don't know why
you're doing what you're doing.
For me it would be super hard to not be
around comedians.
Yeah.
Like I'm so used to being around fucked
up people that make jokes about
everything and anything and comedians
are just so unusual in the way they
behave and you get used to them.
It becomes normal.
You know,
I'm used to being around the comedy
store and places like that and just the
sharpness and the quickness and that is
that,
that people's brains work in comedy or
even just even just in La,
just the pace of how quick people are
thinking and talking and acting and
being in living.
Then you go to a place like Hawaii.
It takes most people like three or four
or five days or a week to just chill the
hell out and relax a little bit.
Yeah,
just unwind.
Maybe just on vacation and that's why
the whole like bow hunting thing,
like how good does it feel to just
unplug your phone?
It feels good.
Good.
Turn my phone off and leave it behind
and I just.
Awesome.
Doesn't it also feel weird when you're a
place that has no signals?
There's nothing going on there.
There's no phone signal,
there's no Wifi.
It almost feels like the air feels
different.
The ultimate,
uh,
ultimate excuse though to why you can't
get back to people because I'm terrible.
I hate the phone.
I hate it with a passion text message.
Fine email.
Okay.
Fallen.
No,
don't call me.
Oh,
actual phone calls.
Way Too into constantly interacting with
all the time.
I want to communicate when I want to
communicate.
That's my text messages.
So good.
It's like you can text someone and when
they feel like they're gonna answer,
no text messages is really good in that
way.
It's.
I used to think text messages were
stupid and now I think like phone calls
are stupid for the most part,
same even email.
It's also you don't have enough time
with people constantly being on their
phone and constantly like being
connected to things.
You remember a time where there's
reflection alone time,
relaxing time,
just thinking about shit.
Yeah,
you know,
and that's,
I think for me at least that's what I
make a lot of my life decisions,
like where I want to go or what
direction
I want to go when I'm alone and I could
just think about what's going on,
what's,
what's bugging me about my life.
Like this is too busy,
this is too much bullshit,
this is too much hassle.
I need to get the fuck away from that.
And when I'm constantly on the grind,
I don't think like that.
My constantly on the grind,
I'm like,
God,
I got to juggle this and then this is
coming on and then that's coming up
next.
And that's what's appealing to me about
a place like Hawaii is like there's no
juggling man.
Yeah,
yeah.
That's great.
It's a lot for most people though,
you know,
it's,
it's definitely different.
It's definitely different.
Yeah.
Have you ever done a back country solo
bow hunting trip?
I'm not solo.
No.
You have to.
Yeah.
You have to worry about fucking breaking
my leg out in the middle of
or it's have to do it.
I have to break my leg.
No,
no,
bring a sat phone.
Oh,
okay.
Yeah.
Rent a sat phone.
Yeah,
the sat phone rental.
Boom.
You got your,
you got your sat phone.
You can call it.
You can bring an iep or bring whatever
safety stuff you want to do.
Five day back country by yourself.
Where do you go when you do those?
I do at home.
Doing home in Hawaii.
You know,
or I'll do it on Lanai or do you go?
I do it around my house where there's
vast open spaces where I live,
so I can do it.
You bring a temp in a lot of other
places.
You kinda sorta can't do it.
I'm too,
they're illegal or,
or it's not.
The areas aren't large enough to like
just really get out,
but yeah.
Do the tent to the Super Ultra light
thing.
I bring my own water,
um,
are all being.
If there's water in the area,
I'll bring upon whole deal ultra light
bag,
ultralight 10 ultra light.
The whole,
like all my sleeping gear.
A lot of times I'll do the baby thing
where you hunt all day and then you
sleep wherever it gets dark,
you know,
and that's the best.
But just the,
uh,
you know what you were saying about
like,
you know,
being alone to think finally,
it's like,
I dunno,
like even it's like we're so used to
being entertained all the time.
Yeah.
And that's something that like people
are addicted to,
like whether it's your phone or even
like if me and you went hunting a lot of
time,
I'd be your entertainment or you'd be my
entertainment,
but when no one's entertaining you and
you're by yourself and you're just out
there and you're making your own fires
and you're waking up and,
and you're doing your own hunt and
you're not relying on a guide or a
friend or,
okay,
I'm going to hunt over there.
You Hunt over here and you're just doing
your own thing and even if you're not
even a hunting,
just being silent,
you're not talking to yourself so you're
not talking to anybody.
You're not talking to your phone,
you're not communicating with anyone.
And after four or five days I did this
at home,
I did a hunt where I left my house,
had my wife,
dropped me off and I ended this long
walk over this giant mountain,
bad idea,
but it was awesomely fun and I camped
out for like four days and I ended up
hurting my leg really bad.
I like pulled a muscle behind my knee
and I was planning on going back and
having my wife picked me up again and
I'm halfway there and normally you have
no service in this area.
It's like a black zone and so I hiked to
an area where I just,
I found service and I couldn't walk
back.
I was,
I was too screwed up.
My knee was screwed up.
Anyway,
I called my friend who had access to
enroll to,
to a ranch at the very top of this
ranch.
I could walk to it.
So it was like another day's walk and a
whole day walking.
Yeah,
with a fucked up leg.
Yeah.
Slowly walking and I called him and I
said,
hey,
you know,
can you pick me up on Tuesday at the
rat?
And he's like,
yeah,
I'm going to be up there anyway,
I can come pick you up at the top.
And so he picks me up and after five
days he got out of the,
out of the car and he was talking to me
like I'm talking to you.
And it sounded like he was yelling at
me.
Oh Wow.
Yeah.
So weird as,
so used to like this silence that was,
sounded like he was yelling at me and I
was like staring at him.
I must've been looking at them really
well,
we're like,
but you gotta do you got to be
by yourself?
Totally alone with no,
like no communication for like at least
three days.
Do you know?
Just for,
just for good experience.
Do you know Adam Green Tree is from
Australia?
I do,
yeah.
I was hunting with them just maybe a
month ago.
Oh,
okay.
Cool,
well he,
he's a good buddy of mine.
We've been bear hunting before he hung
out with them and cap been great.
Great Guy.
Hung out with them in Australia when I
was there for the UFC to.
He is a killer.
It is a bad ass hunter.
He's a bad ass on.
He's,
he's just a bad ass dude.
But he was telling me that when he goes
off to these trips because he does most
of his hunt solo and that's like really,
really weird.
He detaches and you like centers
himself,
but he says he comes back after being
out there for eight or nine days and he
hasn't said a word in eight or nine
days.
He says it just feels weird to talk to
people.
Yeah,
yeah.
Just feels weird to say words.
Yeah,
it does.
And it's,
it's cool man.
It puts a lot of shit and perspective
about what you're planning on doing and
you know,
the next 10 years or what's happening in
your life or you know,
whatever it is,
you know,
not to get deep in here,
but it's,
it's a trip man.
It really is.
I did,
I did nine days by myself in Colorado
back country.
Do yourself in a tent.
It's snow for five of the days.
Where'd you go?
Um,
one time I went and,
uh,
kind of in the mountains near
Breckenridge.
And then another time I went in a
mountain range called the Santa Santa
Decristo mountains.
It's in the southern part of the state
in some steep shit,
some really gnarly stuff and hike like
eight miles back with my ultra light
stuff.
And I had hunted that area with a buddy
of mine from home the year before and we
plan on going again and then he kicked
out last second because he couldn't make
it.
So I was just like,
screw it,
I got a ticket,
I got tagged,
I'm going by myself.
So I rented a sat phone just in case and
I went there and I'm like,
the second day I walked like eight miles
back,
like as a bird flies,
right?
So it's like a really long walk and uh,
but that's where the elk were
meaning long walk for people.
Look at what was that as the bird flies,
if you go in a straight line,
it's eight
miles,
but you're going up and down,
up and down.
So it's way more than
I parked at like 8,500 feet and camped
at 10,500 feet,
which is the highest water I could
combat.
Right.
Wow.
And the elk were at like 11,500 feet.
So it was a lot of hiking,
a lot of walking and just being by
yourself.
And then,
and then the snow component for somebody
from Hawaii,
you know,
it's like it was snowing every day and I
was cooking in my tent and eating and
it's snowing and an elk were coming in
at night and screaming her guts out.
And um,
then there was like a crazy,
like lightning storm and windstorm attic
at a pack of my tent the middle of the
night,
if that was going to blow over,
I thought is going to hit me out of go
into like a dense a pine forest and
reset up my 10 mil night during a
lightning storm.
Call my wife and I in the middle of the
night and like,
you know,
let her know exactly where I was just in
case the shit hit the fan,
but that type of stuff is um,
you know,
a lot of barriers in that area and why
anzalone shit.
So,
um,
those type of experience for,
for.
I didn't never had those kinds of
experiences before I started hunting
ever.
I never saw a stat,
that kind of country.
I never,
I never put myself in those kinds of
situations.
And,
and until I found bowhunting,
that's,
that's a reason I was never like,
I'm going to go hiking,
not a hiker.
I need to have like a purpose when I'm
hiking.
Right?
So I'm basically like a hiker with a bow
these days and that's what gets me out
to these kinds of places and had the,
some of the best experiences of my life
just because I found bow hunting.
Well those,
those woods and like where you're going
these places where you're not going to
run into any other people,
there's,
there's a feeling that you get from
those,
those environments.
It's almost like a loneliness in a way,
like a or almost like a.
it's all right because it's so beautiful
and so incredible,
but it's also,
it's humbling and a bunch of different
ways.
One of the ways it's humbling because
this woods doesn't give a fuck about
you.
Have you died?
It's like,
so what?
I am.
Grizzlies keep fucking eating elk.
Keep having sex and screaming their
heads off and birds keep flying and
that's just how we've always done it.
Dude.
Sorry,
you didn't make it.
Yeah,
does.
You're right.
It doesn't care.
And you're alone,
like alone,
alone in the dark night seems darker.
You know,
the silent seems more silent.
Oh yeah.
Way More.
You know,
you get back to your tent and it's dark.
What's the big perspective enhancer?
Yeah,
it is.
I went to Prince of Wales last year.
We,
uh,
we hunted on Prince of Wales Island
outside of Alaska.
It's fucking rained everyday.
Just miserable every day.
And Moose,
uh,
we were hunting.
Deer were hunting sickle blacktail very
cool.
But I'm unsuccessful.
We didn't,
we struck out.
But when we came back hard,
it's hard.
It's real hard.
There's not,
a lot of them were we were,
uh,
we,
we fucked up.
We got to a place where they had already
moved down towards the water and we were
up high.
Were you with cameras at hunt?
No,
that was with Rinella.
That was for the mediator show.
But one of the things about it was that
feeling of like,
almost like a sadness look,
so,
and gorgeous,
like it would rain every day,
but every now and then the sun would
come up and when the sun would come up,
the sun would hit this incredible green.
It would just,
it was like an illuminating like this,
like it was lit up and um,
we can,
we got back after seven days of this or
however many days or six days and
everything in La seems so nice.
Was so warm and beautiful and I just
loved it.
I was so happy and uh,
I called Rinella up and I was like,
dude,
I don't think I've ever been happier in
my life.
I am so happy.
And it's because I was so miserable for
those days.
And that that's another perspective
enhancer to realize like,
you're so God damn lucky I have a roof
overhead and that you know,
you can listen to the radio in your car
and then you could,
you know,
you can get around and it's easy and you
could talk to be blowing your phone when
you're out in the woods.
Woods,
no cell phone service,
no nothing.
There's nothing.
We have Amazon packages come into your
house and like food delivery and
nothing.
No Pizza.
You can order pizza.
There's fucking nothing,
man.
We brought some food with us and that is
what we ate because we struck out and
the cold and the wet,
the wet
until you've been head to toe soaking
wet and your boots and your socks and
your pants and your rain gear and
everything is everything that's supposed
to keep you warm and safe from the
elements is soaked to the bone and it's
getting cold.
That's gnarly.
Well,
that's also where you appreciate really
good gear to Merino wool.
Right?
You know,
a will is a weird cloth in that like if
you have cotton on and you get wet,
you're fucked.
But if you have wool on and you get wet,
the wool actually retains the heat so
you could be wet and still warm,
which is really unusual and hard for
people to understand.
If you've never worn wool,
well that's when you know what I mean.
The the right gear,
you know as a lot of hunts that really
you don't really need the right gear for
printing,
but in that back country stuff or real
steep mountains or stuff where you have
to walk far,
if your shoes are wet and your socks are
wet,
you're going to have an earliest
blisters and you won't be able to walk
anywhere.
That's why I'm really fascinated by
companies like cool you that spend all
this time developing the most technical
gear,
like the lightest weight,
the best at absorbing wind for their
tents and,
and you know,
they'd go through great lengths to
engineer their products to make sure
that it's just mean.
It's a giant company that just makes
ultra light gear for hunting.
Yeah.
It's kind of crazy that there's a
company like that.
Yeah.
But yeah,
you can see why when you go in the back
country,
don't have the right gear,
you,
that's the last kind of hunting you're
going to do like that and how it's like
a survival thing.
How'd you figure out like what stuff to
bring and what stuff not to bring?
Did you read up or did you do trial and
error?
You know?
Uh,
I,
right when I got into bow hunting,
I got,
I got bored of,
of feeding pigs and have want to come to
my house
and,
and having them come to my trees down.
I got bored of that pretty quick.
It was Super Fun at first and I loved it
and it was a really good learning and it
was a blast.
You know,
it's building tree stands by myself,
but I what?
I super quickly got bored of that and
wanting to do something else.
I wanted to go walk in the mountains all
day long and I,
I ordered Cameron Hanes is back country
bowhunting book.
This is right when I started hunting,
I had no idea who cameron hanes was and
I was geeking out on everything.
Hunting and I,
I did some research,
found that book ordered,
it changed my life.
I got like,
and it's funny because I told Cameron
that
I,
I told them that,
uh,
that I got his book and it like fully
inspired me.
I,
uh,
I ordered like the,
the ultralight tent,
the right one to all this research on
which one to get which one is lightest,
which one's the driest,
which one is the best at cooking,
which is that the biggest vestibule.
I ordered the right,
the right stove and all the right,
you know,
ultra light plates and forks and caps,
camp cups and a sleeping bags and tout
the,
the little talent packs up tiny on the
pillow that packs of tiny in the right
backpack and all that stuff.
So it's funny because that,
that,
you know,
when you're shading ounces and it really
adds up,
you know,
it's like a difference between like 80
pound pack and a 40 pound pack when you
get,
if you get the right gear.
Jason Harrison,
the owner,
if he makes a,
uh,
a spreadsheet where he ways every single
thing he's,
he's bringing and he packs it up and he
weighs like what's in each pack and what
he needs for each and he has this like
this excel spreadsheet of all the
different stuff and then that's how
seriously people take it.
Especially like sheep hunting and things
on those lines.
I got so geeked out on the ultralight
thing that I started like looking at all
of that,
like um,
like ultra light,
ultra light hiking websites and like
getting all it
tips.
Like,
like instead of just bringing in like a
little spark,
you know,
one of those like little sport,
the ultralight sports,
you'd cut your fork in half or even like
in just one third.
So you just had the fork,
just a fork part.
So like you'd,
you'd,
you'd shave off those ounces of the rest
of the fork.
You just be the part where you just ate,
you know,
and,
and your toothbrush,
you cut it.
So it was just the part that goes on,
doesn't your
teeth.
Yeah,
that's what Adam does.
He was telling me he does that pretty
funny,
but plus I'm a manly man.
I can carry a toothbrush handle.
It's funny though because it all adds up
when you,
when you know you don't think you need
that much stuff to go in the back
country hunt,
but a lot of times you put every single
thing you're going to put in that pack
and it's a lot of stuff.
Right.
And to share those out,
this down means then you can bring like
a better 10 better sleeping bag.
Right.
You add up some more ounces on the other
side.
I,
I'm a big eater so I'll bring a lot of
food and water and you know.
Now do you weigh out your food?
Do you make sure that you have like
intense calorie dense food?
Yeah.
What kind of stuff do you bring with you
when you go on a back country hunt of.
Oh,
stuff you get bored of quick.
Like um,
I bring like nuts,
like macadamia nuts and almonds and
pecans and cheese and jerky and stuff
like that.
And if they're,
especially if there's water,
that's a game changer.
If there's water where you're going to
be,
or even anywhere near where you going to
be that are bringing stove every time
with oatmeal and freeze dried meals like
mountain house meals,
those are insane.
You have to try a dehydrated.
Yeah.
Those are the same ones.
But there's a freeze dried.
The dehydrated is apparently lighter.
That's why people are gravitating
towards dehydrated now.
Gotcha.
Doesn't own a house there.
So light.
I don't know how anyone can be lighter
than that while you're shaving the
handle of your toothbrush.
That's right.
The best space to.
Yeah.
I think that is what they're saying.
That takes up less space.
But there's certain certain things that
I can't skimp on,
like food.
But uh,
you know,
what's really good is when you like,
before I do hunt like that,
I'll make like two handfuls of Bacon and
I'll make it all up and then I'll bring
that and it's like,
that's my treat at lunch.
I'll have a couple pieces of bacon.
Doesn't it go bad?
No,
it Kinda doesn't.
It doesn't.
Once,
once you get,
once you cook it,
it depends where you hunt.
Also,
if you're hunting and in Arizona in the
summer,
then maybe a or somewhere by the beach
in Hawaii probably go bad,
but a normal hunt if you're,
if your stuff doesn't get super hot and
all was fine.
How long has cooked Bacon last?
No,
I got that idea I think from Karen and
his book because he would make peanut
butter and jelly sandwiches with Bacon
in it.
Oh yeah.
And uh,
and so I would do that.
I don't know how long it lasts,
but don't tell me if it's.
But I,
I bring it for like a five day hunt.
No worries.
And just thinking at least the first
three days,
once you start getting diarrhea then you
cut back.
Exactly.
But,
but uh,
um,
what was I going to say?
Oh,
because I don't know.
I just craved the fats.
It's like I'm eating,
I'm eating all these nuts,
bars,
nuts in bars,
nuts and bars,
not bars and all I want is fat like
Greece.
But when you're doing heavy duty
climbing and things along those lines
are going up and down mountains.
That is what you crave.
Yeah.
Like you're not in the carbohydrates,
fats your body go like we need
something.
Coward.
Dance.
Oh yeah.
And then when I,
when I leave hunting,
when I leave the mountains,
like say I go to Colorado and I hunt for
a week and I'm like I lose 10 pounds,
get super skinny and like mountain man
style,
I get out of there and I just want like
a bacon double cheeseburger,
like a big giant,
not like the kind of the fast food
place,
but like a big,
like 30 pound Burger with a ton of Bacon
on it with like blue cheese and Avocados
on it.
Yeah,
just a massive fat go giant and just
blow my,
blow my self sky high with a giant thing
of fries and
that's always what I created with the
amount of calories that you're burning
when you're climbing up and down
mountains all the time.
It's insane.
And it's thousands of calories a day.
You literally have to keep stuffing your
face just to maintain your body mass.
Yeah,
you do.
Well,
if you are a person who is doing this on
a regular basis,
I mean you would get really good at
preparing for these things,
so you must have
undergone a transformation where you
started off sort of kind of like trying
to figure it out and then as you got
better and better and better,
you got more and more streamlined in you
in your approach.
Like do you feel like you have it down
to a science now?
If you want to do something like that
with what the actual backcountry hunt or
the actual hunting,
it's all the old stuff.
You're packing your plan.
Do you ever use Google maps?
Oh yeah.
That's pretty cool that you can do a
phone these days.
Yeah,
it's amazing.
What would people do if you don't know
they,
they find an area like say if you draw a
tag for an area,
he'd get her over.
This is not for you,
for people,
isn't it?
Obviously,
but you get an overhead.
Google earth will give you.
It'll show you where the peaks and
valleys are and it's amazing.
It shows you the canyons,
it shows you water sources and you see
from a satellite image,
so you can literally see elk sometimes
on Google Earth,
which is incredible.
Yeah,
and you can really like,
you know,
you can get back to your camp much more,
much quicker.
A lot of time,
you know,
don't get lost in a dark,
you can get to your water source wave
way quicker and it's really efficient.
But then you need to bring batteries to
for your phone or.
Yeah,
know some solar panel,
but I haven't really found a super
efficient solar panel that'll charge up
your phone in here.
Stuff that fast.
Yeah.
Especially when you're in the woods,
you're not getting a lot of sunlight.
There always seems like it doesn't work
as good as you hope.
Yeah.
They're getting better at those things
they're getting.
I mean if you're in Arizona,
know when you're in this,
of course,
mule deer hunting in the desert.
You've got a great shot at charging a
patient.
Leave it.
Yeah.
One place for like a few hours just
sitting there in the sun.
Yeah,
for sure.
But as far as the hunting goes,
like you have gotten better at the
planning and the and the back country
gear,
but that's all I got.
I think you learn that pretty quick,
but you found out you find out if your
shitty hunter right away because you
come home with no meat all the time.
Right?
Yeah.
It's like it's very easy.
It's like it's like finding out if
you're good at the stock market,
you know right away you get that
feedback,
you lose a bunch of money all the time.
Right.
It's the same thing with bow hunting.
I love going hunting because I didn't
grow up in a hunting family.
I have no background in it when I was
young.
So I don't have like those,
like the instincts like that someone
would have like that.
I've really good friends that grew up
with a bow in their hand and their dad
did in.
Their GRANDPA did and they're great.
GRANDPA did actually one family in
particular,
but I'm so good at bowhunting.
I love bow hunting with those guys.
Like guys like Adam Green tree guys like
my,
my buddy justin at home.
I have my friend Jason on Lanai who
hunts axis deer.
These are like half year,
half human,
you know how to hunt,
how to kill wind to move,
how fast you can move,
how slow,
like when to slow down,
when to run.
It's just,
I love it.
I as I'm absolutely obsessed with like
trying to learn to get better at it.
Now.
Have you taken into the archery lessons?
Have you ever gone to like a,
like how did you learn how to shoot
correctly?
Um,
I didn't,
I learned how to shoot terribly and then
I had to relearn ever since I've been
trying to correct it.
So still now I now I'll shoot with guys
who are really good archers and now
they'll help me know.
Um,
so I've done a lot of work with that,
but I still like,
my effective range is still like 50
yards.
I've tried for a long time.
Thirteen years.
Yeah.
That's tried really hard.
You when you practice,
how do you feel a targeted.
I can kill a target at 70.
No worries.
But it's so different,
you know,
like guys I can say that they to shoot
60,
you should be shooting 122 to be able to
be effective at 60.
Should be shooting hundred 20 because of
the pressure of the nerves.
Yeah.
There's a difference between a target
and an animal just so totally different.
So it was also the way you shoot too,
right?
Do you use a,
a trigger or using these?
A thumb release.
So you usually use a lot of attention
and what kind of release you using?
I got target panic if you ever heard of
that.
Sure.
Yeah,
that's why I asked you socks.
You don't want to not want to get that.
But uh,
I,
I hunted for years and then recently my
friend was filming and as I would shoot
I would punch a trigger like crazy and I
didn't even realize I was doing it.
It got worse and worse to the point
where I ended up giving my releases away
and stop hunting for about four months.
And all I did was go and shoot.
I put this target right outside my front
door,
like a hanging bag target and I would,
I'd walk up to it,
draw my bow like a one foot away from it
and just practice releasing over and
over and over with your eyes closed than
my eyes closed so I wouldn't focus on
any aiming or anything.
It was like a psychology thing where you
have to break down your break it down.
We came down into like the perfect
release.
Yeah,
that's called blind bail shooting for
people don't know what it is is impact,
bracing your.
Your mind gets used to the feeling of
the bomb going off and so you brace for
it and when you do that you start to
develop these sorts of patterns where
you're anticipating the shot.
It's crazy and it can really fuck your
head up really can and I couldn't.
It got so bad to where I couldn't put my
pin on the animal and my finger on the
trigger without punching it.
I couldn't do both.
I had to put my finger,
my,
my pin off the animal,
and then my finger on the trigger and
then got extreme and then once the
trigger or what's the pin is near the
animal.
Then you just hit it early.
Nervous.
Yeah.
It was really bizarre.
And this is weird because you're such A.
I mean,
you're a bad motherfucker.
You're dealing with giant waves and
yeah,
you're,
you're fucking surfing 50 foot high
waves.
If someone told me that was going to
happen to me,
I would've just,
I would've bet my life savings against
it.
I'm totally not that guy like freaks out
and gets panicked out loud.
Stuff like that.
Especially like a pin on a boat like.
Yeah,
like break.
Yeah.
And Man,
I had to work through it for a little
while.
There's,
there's people who like give up archery
all together.
Oh yeah.
It's super common.
Yeah.
Um,
so I read a lot about it.
I'm terrified of it.
Yeah.
Don't even worry about it.
Just just do your thing and keep hunting
and what you're doing.
But I've learned how to shoot with back
tension.
So I get a surprise shot.
It's all the time.
I don't,
I don't use a trigger,
but cam diseases triggers.
But he,
he worked through it to everybody works
through it.
Yeah.
When you,
um,
when you learned
how to use a thumb trigger and use back
tension,
is something you got from youtube videos
or did you have someone show you how to
do it?
Yeah,
I had a friend show me how to do it.
I've,
I've a really good friend from Spain.
Um,
his name is Pedro.
I don't know if you know him and he's
super,
Super Pedro from Spain,
from Spain.
Okay.
So there's a,
there's a few of them in Spanish.
That's what I heard a few Pedro's down
there.
Anybody Jose's to a bad ass bowhunter
yeah.
That ass and really good archer.
So He.
So he,
he suggested,
you know,
like a back tension release.
And let me explain what works for people
who have no idea what we're talking
about.
Um,
when you're,
there's a type of release that has,
uh,
when you sort of set your stem on it,
but you don't squeeze it with your
thumb,
will,
you do,
is you need to know what I release it,
right?
It's something that connects to the
string on your bow.
It actually connects to what's called a
d loop,
which connects to the string.
There you go.
There's a bunch of.
Well those are back tension releases
where those are like real back tension
release where very few people ever use
those for hunting.
But I like what,
what kind of release you use,
what brand is?
I think it's a Carter release.
Yeah,
I do too.
I use a carter,
but it's mainly back tension.
Like I'll like,
I'll exactly like that.
Like I'll put my thumb around the
trigger and then I'll just keep pulling
until it goes off.
It goes off when you never know when
it's going off.
So because of that you're not
anticipating but in a,
in a it.
But it keeps coming back like in a,
in a situation where I'm hunting when
I'm 25 yards and I'm getting full drawn
and deer
and it's perfectly broadside.
I had this overwhelming feeling like it
wants to move and I'll then now I have
like sorta like trained myself to like
slowly squeeze,
squeeze and pull so that
it makes it go quicker.
They say you should have like a mantra
as in your head as well,
that you should have a bunch of things
that you say like line it up and release
the air like that.
You have to have like some sort of a
thing that you put in your head and you
probably wouldn't,
shouldn't say release the Arrow.
What's yours?
Execute the shot.
Yeah.
One.
Line it up and execute the shot.
That's what I say.
Lined it up.
Execute the shot.
Yeah.
You know what I do
stay calm too.
That's the other one.
I say stay calm.
Breathe.
Um,
I do that thing where I,
I spell lock.
So Loc K as I'm settling,
you know,
you get to full draw.
Get my anchor.
I,
I've,
I start settling the pin and I look at
my,
my bubble level and once my little
checklist is online and I'm on the
animal,
as soon as I feel like my,
my pin starts to relax and steady.
I spelled the word lock and squeezes the
same time.
Ooh,
I liked that.
I might steal that.
Yeah.
You know what else you're going to like.
This is my,
my friend Jeff who basically taught me
how to bow hunt.
I'm Jeff Lee.
Guys,
Legend.
He's awesome.
Uh,
he,
he told me that when he is a full draw
right before he pulls the trigger,
he says,
you're gonna die motherfucker.
Whoa,
that's deep.
Yeah.
I don't know if I liked that,
what he told me,
but he's not like that.
He's not like that.
Like you would never think
that.
He's not like,
he's totally not blood thirsty.
He's a super ethical hunter.
He just goes,
man,
it's,
it's a psychological thing.
He goes,
if you are hoping you're going to hit
that animal,
that release,
when that Arrow goes off,
if you're hoping you're not going to hit
him,
you're not going to kill him.
It's not going to be an efficient,
ethical,
ethical shot,
but he goes,
if you truly believe that you're there
to kill that animal and that animal is
going to die,
right then that's a huge piece of the
puzzle.
There's a website called iron mind
hunting.
Have you ever heard of this?
Scott?
Think I forget his name,
Joel something or another,
but he,
um,
he suffered through target panic himself
and he's a swat guy and a police officer
and developed a whole system
understanding the impact bracing and a
whole system that I haven't,
I haven't read it.
He's got a book on it and he's got,
there it is.
Um,
and he's got Joel Turner and he's got a
whole website dedicated to controlling
target,
panic and develop a whole system.
Yeah,
I have to check it out too.
And it's one of those things where,
you know,
no matter how long you been doing it,
it's possible that this shit could creep
into your brain,
which is weird,
like people have been successful hunting
for years and years and then all of a
sudden they get target panic and they're
fucked.
Almost everybody you meet who's bow
hunted for a couple of decades has had
it almost everybody.
Everybody from randy elmer to,
to everybody.
Yeah,
Randy Alma has a couple of good videos
on how to handle it too.
And he,
he says you should use a back tension
release to get used to it and a or a
hinge release.
And what that is for the people don't
understand what we're talking about.
There's another type of release.
It doesn't have a trigger at all.
And what you do is you draw back and
just by moving your hand,
you're sort of curling your pinky down
and making a fist.
It goes off,
but you never know when it's going off,
it goes off completely unanticipated.
And that helps you deal with this,
this tension issue,
this,
uh,
this fucking mind.
Fuck yeah.
But I got over the hump and I'm back.
You're back.
I had a good 2016 so far.
Yes.
Feels good,
right?
I,
it feels good.
As I was panicking about the panic for
awhile and this year started off good.
I've done it.
I've done quite a bit of hunting.
I went,
uh,
I went hunting for fallow deer with,
with,
with Remy and New Zealand,
and had a,
just an absolute ball.
Killed a great,
a great book.
I saw some pictures of the terrain.
You're using that crazy equivalent thing
too,
right?
Where it's a stabilizer.
And I tried that for awhile,
but it kept getting loose on me.
Oh really?
Yeah.
It was wiggling around too much.
I didn't have that problem writing it
down too much and it worked really good
for that hunt,
that specific hunt.
But we wanted in this awesome terrain
with this crazy rocks and cliffs.
There was not one Bush,
there was no bushes there.
There's no trees in this area.
It was just like you had to use the,
you had to use the,
you know,
the rocky,
the rocky outcroppings,
and just the basic like terrain features
to get close and we ended up sneaking
down on this bed of group of deer that
was at the base of this
cliff.
Go Get up.
Go to Ben.
Oh,
Brian's a instagram.
What is instagram?
A steep.
It was such a steep downhill shot that I
had to like,
you know,
when you're shooting down,
you got to you gotta bend at the waist,
you can just aim down miss.
And so I had to remember all that stuff
in the moment.
It was just a really technical shot and
a technical stock.
It was really a lot of fun.
Well,
Ben took a photo.
The reason why I said go to Ben's
instagram because he took a Benny Aubrey
or something like that.
Um,
he,
he has a photo of you doing it where it
looks like you're shooting from the top
of a building.
Oh yeah,
down to the first floor.
Yeah.
It's a crazy picture.
And that's the kind of,
that's the kind of,
um,
practice that you'd never do.
A lot of people don't like set their
target the bottom of a cliff and stand
at the top and it's really different or
shooting up either.
Yeah,
either one of the super different type
of shot.
So,
but that was a lot of fun and I've done
some really good hunts.
I did one to threatening in New Zealand.
I did one with Adam Green tree in
eastern Australia.
Um,
and what did you guys hunt and
Australia?
We hunted in an area that had,
um,
fallow deer mainly.
There was a couple red stags around to,
um,
but that was a ball.
We had a lot,
a lot of fun.
He's trying to get me to go hunt water
buffaloes were going.
I'm like,
fuck.
He's been trying to get me to do that to
these things are,
they're just giant fucking murderous
beasts.
Yeah,
that's not the part that to me is,
uh,
is the,
I love hunting in the mountains where
it's cold and beautiful and I'm looking
at a big valley or over the ocean in
Hawaii.
Or you can see the ocean,
the white caps and boats going by like
just beautiful,
right.
Beautiful wilderness.
And where are those bulls live?
It's like 50 million flies on you and
mosquitoes in a swamp and snake and
snakes and slugs and spiders.
FOC degrees and crocs.
Yeah.
And it's true man.
It's like I turned it a little pussy
when I come to those guys.
I can't.
I turn it a little pussy when I look at
pictures of it.
Yeah.
He's like,
you gotta come to the buffet thing,
right?
You've got to come.
And I'm like,
sure thing.
I will for sure.
Good luck with all that.
Now human campaigns,
when they brought no food and they
brought no water,
they said,
mate,
we're going to do it the right way.
So they go out there and they were
bathing in this fucking lake that they
didn't realize had crocodiles.
Yeah.
So they were in up to their neck cooling
themselves off and then later on found
out the crocodiles at slipped into this
lake.
So they easily could have gotten eaten.
Yeah.
I mean,
these are some of the biggest fucking
crocodiles in the world that live right
there.
Fuck that.
I was hunting or with another body in
Australia and we were hunting in an area
that crocodiles and everyday we had to,
we had to cross a couple of little areas
that had water and I just didn't even
think about it because I'm not like I'm
not around crocodiles.
Right.
And he just,
after the first day he didn't really
worry about it too much because he had,
after we crossed,
he goes,
hey,
if I'm not with you tomorrow and you
cross here,
make sure you throw a bunch of rocks in
the water right there to make sure
there's no crocodiles.
Because if they,
if,
if a human passes by an area where
there's crocodiles over and over and
over,
they pattern them and they will sit
there and wait for that human to cross
again and get ya.
Oh.
So they're super intelligent hunters.
So that's what they do.
They actually wait for like,
whether it's a rabbit going by everyday
or human or whatever it is,
a dog,
a cat,
and they will sit there and wait just
underwater and when you go by,
that's when they strike.
So such an efficient animal to the fact
that they could just stay under water
for hours without breathing.
They slow their heart rate down like a
beat,
a minute or something stupid.
There's A.
There's a place in northwestern
Australia where the waves are really
good and in that area there's a ton.
A ton of great whites.
Tiger sharks and ocean.
Saltwater crocodiles swim in the ocean
for miles.
They swim.
They fight the sharks.
Fuck them.
Fuck everything.
Fuck that whole.
The whole God.
That's so crazy.
Yeah.
They swim.
Imagine being in the fucking water in a
canoe and you look over and there's
something bigger than you can do and
it's a dinosaur.
Yeah.
It's swimming in the water and it wants
to kill you.
It's hungry.
Oh my on.
You'll Australia's a wild ass place,
but it really is beautiful and crazy and
wild.
Seems like New Zealand's a better spot
though.
New Zealand doesn't have any of that
stuff and I'm from a place like New
Zealand.
Right.
I'm from Hawaii.
There's no snakes.
We don't have deadly spiders or anything
like that.
And when I go to Australia
I get so freaked out about the snakes,
so freaked out and have those brown
snakes it kill you instantly.
I almost stepped on one of those.
Fuck,
I literally fuck you in green tree
trying to get me to come to your house.
My partner was.
My foot was up,
my left.
What was that?
I remember I was walking through this,
this grass called tussock and it was in,
you know,
Adam was like,
you're never going to see a snake at
this time of year.
It's like winter time.
Right.
So they're all,
they're all down,
whatever they're doing,
they're hibernating.
Right.
And so I'm walking by myself,
of course,
and I almost put my foot down and I
looked down as a coiled up brown snake
just.
And he was,
he was out sunning himself and almost
stepped right on.
I'm one of those red belly black snakes.
The thing was that thing called right
past me.
One day I was with my other buddy and he
goes,
you're never going to see any snakes.
I never seen any snakes around here.
First afternoon,
I swear to God,
first after unit ever hunted on
Australia.
This guy just told me,
you never see a snake like an hour into
our hunt,
maybe less.
He goes,
don't move.
There's a deer.
Does it dear mate.
So I just stopped.
Of course.
Right.
I didn't even say a word.
I was looking around for the deer side
side,
eyeing it,
you know,
trying not to say we're trying to be
completely still.
And he goes,
okay,
now look down.
I looked down and the giant snake had
just passed me
completely deadly.
So he said,
don't move just because he didn't want
you freaking out because I just a snake
out of flipped.
Yeah.
But he goes,
there's a deer.
And he knew.
I said,
Billy Black snake,
nothing looks awesome.
I'd like to make a belt out of one.
Those fucks.
Yeah.
There's plenty in Australia.
You can bow hunt.
Can you make a belt?
Oh yeah.
Probably make a pair of boots that go
with it.
Other than that,
no,
because she'd had a few of them.
Like you shoot all you want.
I give you permission to go straight and
shoot them all.
Well that's the thing about Australia is
like you could kinda just shoot animals
constantly.
They have special makes.
Yeah.
No one's going to be bummed out.
You shoot a snake.
God Damn.
What a beautiful looking creature.
Incredibly beautiful creatures.
They're so shiny.
I saw like a 10 foot python to hunting.
Really scary.
They have python.
I'm so freaked out about snakes.
They have giant pythons,
giant,
giant pythons.
Someone was like 10 feet long and my
buddy almost stepped right on him too.
What is the average stocking dear?
We're stocking right next to these giant
bucks and there's giant 10 foot snake
right next to how fat was it?
Like as fat as my forearm.
Jesus Christ.
Fucking big.
I was running with my dogs once in the
hills and we ran over what I thought was
a log and A.
I just ran right over it.
I ran over it and then as my foot is
passing over at Mike,
I go,
oh fuck,
that's a giant.
Rattlesnake was a huge rattlesnake.
Like literally,
I mean not quite as big as my upper
forearm but definitely as big as my
wrist and it was easily seven right here
by your house here,
right over here?
Yeah,
they're fucking.
There's a few of them up here that are
biggest shit.
It was here.
Which big ass diamond head and no big
ass triangle head.
I was like,
look at the size of this fucking thing
and I'm like defenseless,
like mentally defenseless because I
don't even know.
I don't know how to react to snakes.
I don't know what to do.
I don't know where they live.
I don't know what they hide under.
Usually I don't having snake background
so I'm not like looking.
Thank you.
Diet.
Rattlesnake killed.
Look at the size of this one.
This one is like fucking 12 feet long.
Yeah.
Where this guy killed this thing.
Mexico.
It looks like.
Oh my God,
look how fat it is.
30 yard shot.
Guaranteed.
I would definitely take it all day long
for that day.
He was 30 yards away,
smoke it with expandables.
Right.
Like a rage.
Do you use a fixed head broadhead or
these expandable.
So look at the size of that one.
Jesus Christ.
That's bigger than the one I've run
across over at least semi.
That's a big ass snake.
That's,
you know.
Thanks.
Yeah,
I use fix heads mainly.
Yeah.
I use like these little vpa heads,
a vantage point.
Archery makes these like little two
bladed,
um,
same one.
Um,
but they're all machined out of one
piece of steel.
So they're,
they're very strong.
They're very like,
uh,
there's a super reliable heads and they
fly.
Well yeah,
there's a big debate in the archery
world.
Expandable broadheads versus fixed head.
What we're talking about folks is like
expandables as they go in these blades
open up on the side,
they're like a mechanical
blade,
but sometimes they fail and they break
off when they hit ribs and stuff like
that.
And there,
there,
there's some animals that they're better
on I think.
But I've used rages a bit and I've had
really good luck with them actually.
I've had friends that were like,
Oh man,
I can't do the rage thing anymore.
But I've had super good luck with them
where they're making hybrids now to look
as he makes a hybrid and then then
those,
so,
so grave diggers where it's a fixed head
blade and then two other blades open up
behind it,
which is actually probably even better
than just a regular fixed blade.
It totally depends on what you're
hunting too.
Because like where I live on access to
your access to deer were brought from
Sri Lanka there.
They're from Sri Lanka
and India.
So there's like an Asian deer and their
main Predator in like in like Borneo and
we're.
And we're,
we're there from in a,
in all those countries there was a
bengal tiger.
So if you look up the history of access
deer,
it's mean Predator for thousands of
years of Bengal tiger.
Wow.
So they have,
they have like a vertical leap,
like a crazy vertical leap and they run
like super fast and they always jump.
You're Arielle right?
They always,
they always jumped the string.
Yeah,
so when they jumped the string to you,
aim low so they ducked down.
You catch them when they're tough thing
down,
super low,
and if they're alert most of the time
you came off their body.
So if they don't see you and they don't
see you release your Arrow,
do you still aim low?
Aim Low.
The sound.
It makes them react down.
They react like super,
super,
hyper fast.
So what?
What?
I don't.
The reason I brought it up is because
those mechanicals are really good,
especially on access to here because
even if you make a perfect shot,
like a fear,
just incredible archer,
like someone like Cameron Hanes,
you're 40 yards,
you're just rock solid,
not nervous.
You can make the perfect shot.
That animal could be completely spin
around into one 80 and you hit him in
the other side.
He hit him in,
you know you can make a gut shot even
though you made a perfect shot just
because they move.
So in those kinds of situations I think,
you know,
biggest boundable is,
is really good,
you know,
because if you hit him badly,
those,
those things cut giant holes,
you know?
Yeah.
They cut giant holes and cam shot a bear
with a,
one of those grave diggers.
It's one of those hybrid blades would,
has a large fixed blade,
but then as these two really big
expandables that go to a,
an inch and three quarters and it just
opened up a shot,
like a 300 win mag.
Yeah.
It was a huge holes.
The difference in the bear rather.
And they still get the crazy
penetration.
Yeah.
Well he's shooting 80 pounds to and you
know,
with those really thin,
a Fmj deep six injection arrows.
What uh,
what kind of boat are you shooting with?
I should have Mathews Halon six of those
are great posts.
That's what Ben has.
St Mary quiet silent.
So the six is the one with the sixth and
spray site,
which is.
So it's a little jumpy,
right?
It's like the Turbo Cam.
They have a five or six and a seven.
I believe.
So the five is like the junk,
you know,
the fastest one,
but it's probably not easy to shoot.
So like with all speed beaus I think the
shorter the brace height,
the Fascia they'd go,
but they're,
you know,
my understanding is that I'm not like
the Super Archer guidance.
Um,
but my understanding is that the longer
that brace height in general,
that the more forgiving the is to shoot.
We just got into technical geek talk and
people in their cars right now.
Fast forward to the next subject.
Yeah.
We,
I geek out on Bozeman.
I kick out on all sorts of gear.
I'm,
I'm just,
I'm a fan of all the,
like the little tiny things that make a
difference.
Yeah.
And you should avoid and make good bows.
Are Good.
Defining carbon defiant.
Eighty pounds.
So fucking flame thrower,
man.
Yeah,
no kidding.
I love it.
They fling some arrows out fast.
Yeah.
I'm just so obsessed with it.
I practice almost too much.
I really have a real issue.
We were talking about the new studio
that we're setting up or it has a 50
yard indoor range.
One of the reasons why I got it coming
back over next time I bring my belt.
Um,
so do you have anything planned that
you're really looking forward to and he.
Big Hunter.
You're planning?
Uh,
I have nothing to promote on.
The show has.
No,
no,
no.
Come on.
I have a book coming out or a movie.
If they do,
that's cool.
If they don't,
that's better.
It's not,
it's not bad one way or another yet.
The thing tonight and.
Well that's fine too,
but I just wanted to talk to you things
I do.
I do have a lot of coming up.
I have some Rad surf trips.
I served for a company called Billabong.
That's my major.
My major sponsor.
They make clothes and tee shirt on right
now.
Yeah.
So I write it.
I have written for them forever and
they're awesome.
But they have a really good amateur
team,
like their,
you know,
their,
their best youngest averages from around
the world to ride for Billabong.
They activate them and take them on a
couple trips a year.
So they're taking them to Bali.
And so I'm going to Bali to go in and
help mentor them,
surf with them,
help train them and help get them ready
for like the next step.
Right.
So I'm bringing my son,
my son is nine.
He likes to surf so I'm actually going
to go to Bali is a first time that's
ever happened and I'm going to go to
Bali for a work trip,
which I do that pretty often and go,
go on surf trips that are really a work
trip.
Um,
but now I get to bring my son because he
likes to surf,
which is really,
really cool.
Wow.
That's bad ass.
Yeah.
So he might.
My son,
now that he,
he likes to Skateboard,
he's little skater rot rat.
And I tried.
I was,
I hope that he'd be in the surfing,
you know,
because that's what I love to do and now
they'd like to surf.
I'm just so stoked.
And now I'm taking them to Bali.
So do you think he's going to try
bowhunting?
He already balanced.
Really?
He's nine bow hunts.
Has He been successful?
Yes.
Whoa.
Was He shot bars,
your nine year old kid?
And he killed a wild boar.
Now they'll text you some pictures.
You'll,
you'll be savaged.
He looks,
he got really long hair and he's in the
photo with the boys.
All this face paint on his face and he's
got his little bad ass boat right there.
His arrows all passed through y three
now.
And that's
what kind of pose you shooting.
He shoots,
he shoots 30 pounds right now because
he's tiny.
Yeah,
he's nine.
He's nine,
but he's small.
He's a small nine.
That's small.
It's a pretty fucking strong for 30
pounds is super strong.
Do you have.
I'm lifting weights.
He's ripped.
No,
he's dead serious.
He's got a six pack.
He's never stopped moving.
He's got a lot of energies onto those
kids.
He's uh,
he,
um,
he's at skate camp right now up at
Woodward West.
So I dropped him off at Woodward West
and I got some work to do in southern
California here.
So he's at skate camp hanging out or you
were saying there's something wrong with
your back?
Yeah.
What's going on?
Ah,
I dunno,
that's what I'm doing here.
I'm just,
I mean,
I had to get an Mri this morning.
I kinda just tweaked my back like,
uh,
about nine months ago and it was really
bad.
Um,
I was doing a workout and it hurt it.
What part of your back?
My lower back.
Yeah.
I've got a machine in the back.
I want to show you what's wrong.
We're done here.
It's a reverse hyper.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
That's good.
Have you heard of them before?
Yeah,
I use them a little bit.
Oh really?
Yeah,
they're the shit.
They're really good if you can,
if you have a place for them,
you should get a.
it's a fucking phenomenal piece of
machinery.
So I got really into crossfit,
so I was using,
I was using the reverse hyper a lot.
Yeah,
that's good.
So it,
was this before or after the injury?
I'm like before and after.
Yeah.
Does it help?
Reverse?
Hyper helps out.
Helps stretch me out and loosen it up.
There's also some,
we have some decompression stuff in the
back,
some different spinal decompression and
things that I could show you that will
help.
I'm kind of an expert now in healing up
a back injury.
I had a pretty severe bulging disc issue
for Jitsu that my hand's numb.
Wow.
Yeah.
But now it's gone.
It's completely.
That's crazy.
Yeah.
I don't have any bolt at all.
Had an MRI.
It's clean.
I've never had back issues.
And uh,
like nine months ago I was training the
thing with the hat.
I think the thing that happened is I was
training like really pretty seriously
for like got really into it,
got really excited about it and just
love training and it was like one of
those things I just love to do.
So I like five days a week I got really
like muscular throughout my,
my,
my hips and my quads and my core and I
just got super,
super developed,
you know,
kind of like my muscles got like cables
and um,
and then I just had like a five month
period of time where I was just
traveling out of the country for like
five months and I just couldn't do the
same kind of workout.
So I was in.
He's really mellow workouts and kind of
not working out too much and then I got
home and it had like a month to get
ready for winter and so like,
you know,
ease back into the workout thing and the
first workout I did my body just got
pissed,
just locked up a tried to go just a
little too hard too quick or trying to
go really mellow,
but I was going relatively mellow
compared to what I was doing before,
but my body just was like,
I don't know,
it just was pissed.
Do you ever fuck with yoga?
I Love Yoga.
I do.
I really like it.
I just the yoga classes around my house
or never the right time and I don't do
it by myself.
Just get a DVD or youtube man.
I need a lot
of videos on youtube and you to do that.
That's man.
That's been a saving grace for me.
It's been a big help and like,
and also there's a lot of yoga exercises
that I didn't even realize they before I
did it.
They,
they act as a spinal decompression.
They stretch you out,
you feel your back pop,
pop,
pop as you're.
You're doing some of the stretches.
I actually really love Yoga.
It's fucking awesome,
man.
I go to yoga classes.
My wife's super into yoga.
It's one of those things though,
like for a dude,
especially a manly surfer,
bowhunting type dude.
Tell people,
yeah,
I'm really into yoga.
Oh,
what are you sucking dicks over there
and that yoga class,
they're starting.
It's one of those,
it seems like a good thing or a bull.
You're a bow hunter and you surf 50 foot
waves on paper.
You're a pretty fucking macho dude
fella.
Yeah,
but if you.
If you talked to anybody who knew me,
well,
they wouldn't.
It would never describe me as macho.
Well,
I don't mean macho like a in a dumb way
to walk into a yoga class is what I'm
saying.
Of course you don't,
but saying it like saying yoga to
people.
I'm not saying obviously I don't have a
problem with it.
I do it all the time,
but I'm saying there's a sort of
preconceived notion about yoga that it's
like,
it's not a hard thing to do.
It's not like a mailing,
but it's one of the most difficult
things to do that I have ever done that
kicks your ass.
Fuck.
Yeah.
Does.
Especially hot yoga is.
It's unbelievable how difficult it is.
My wife does this stuff called Buddhi
Yoga.
Have you ever heard that?
Buddhi Yoga.
I like it.
I read a yoga,
like yoga.
She's going to kill me.
Yoga slash kind of simulate twerking,
but it's like a dance yoga.
It's like high energy but like crazy
yoga poses,
but they like gnarly cardio too.
And the girl Jen who teaches the class
is bad ass and it's the gnarliest
workout.
I'd never done it.
Okay.
Too much for that.
For Buddhi Yoga?
Yes.
See,
I knew it.
I knew I couldn't.
What is this?
This is Buddhi Yoga.
Jamie found it already.
So this girls throwing like a back kick.
Yeah,
that's.
That's definitely not what I'm talking
about.
Yeah.
Well,
I think every.
I don't think Buddhi Yoga has an
official designation,
so I think a lot of people call their
stuff Buddhi Yoga,
but the class and my wife does it will
kick your ass.
It's like really high energy.
It's really crazy.
Cardio and it's yoga too.
So.
And there's twerking is a little bit.
Are they,
do they play like little wayne and like
the gangster rap and I just,
they just go off,
you know,
they,
they get none of that.
That's probably more
my wife's much hotter than in her
booty.
Yoga with twerking plus little way
music.
Anything that keeps,
keeps stuff.
The Mrs. Oh sure.
Shay in shape and nice and tight.
I'm a giant fan of them.
Yeah,
for them all about it.
Yeah.
If girls want to do this all day,
absolutely all about it.
I'm a big fan of what she's doing here
in this video.
I don't see any downside.
Anything.
I'm agreeing with you.
One hundred percent.
Well listen man,
thank you very much for coming.
I really appreciate it.
And Shane's got a twitter but he doesn't
use it.
So uh,
she see him say hi.
Yeah,
I got an instagram that I use.
Okay,
and what is instagram?
Instagram is Shane Dorian s h a n e d o
r I a n.
well thanks for coming in man.
I really appreciate it.
I really enjoyed talking to you.
Yeah,
was fine.
All right folks,
we'll be back in a little bit with Ari
Shaffir.
Bye.
Mm.