Hey fuckers.
What'd you do?
I'm excited just talking about it.
This is the only better idea I've
heard from you is our compound.
I want that's happening
in compounds happening.
Aubrey's in Aubrey's done a better
idea ever more realistic idea.
We'd have more realistic idea.
How can you say it's more
realistic because we're not
all going to like move our
families.
Oh No,
no,
no.
This you don't understand.
This is the latest idea.
The ladies idea is we get a set up.
Why did you make condos gate?
It was at one point in time,
kind of used to be a manly word.
To me,
point of success.
Well,
I've got a condo and I've got,
I can take her back to the condo.
I leased a BMW three series and joy.
Yet you specialize that word forever.
We've got,
do you realize that if you
fall into a black hole,
you will see the entire future of the
universe unfold in front of you and a
matter of moments and you will emerge
into another space time created by the
singularity of the black
hole you just fell into.
He just broke the,
broke the Hogan and that right there.
Can you imagine giving your son to
someone to hack his balls off so he could
sing in a weird way?
People are so poor.
Back then it was like,
this is the only way out.
Oh my God.
Like opera was like white
people's basketball like that.
You have a chance to be a constraint.
If you have any marijuana
in your blood in Japan,
you're not gonna be able to fight.
So what did you get arrested for?
Marijuana.
So what,
how,
like what is it like,
is it like being caught with cocaine or
yeah,
to drugs.
That drug in Japan.
I was facing some bad time,
you know,
because uh,
I was a famous figure and they
wanted to make an example to me.
So it was then the,
the interrogation came to finding
out where I got my stuff in Japan,
if you throw everything
to a foreign person,
they'll drop.
They won't want to go
fight someone in America.
I,
I told him it was a student from Guam
and just they asked me for a name and I
said,
Tony,
I knew like three Tonys and Guam,
so
keep it real.
We had like two days of
questioning and late,
like the third day they said,
so happened caught me off guard man.
And the SP,
what's Tony's last name and
this fricken ridiculous,
the first name that
popped the males Montana
read when I said,
Oh fuck if these guys watch scarf
[inaudible]
see I'm screwed,
you know,
screwed.
Because they'll start the all over if
I get kick on an ally.
Right,
right,
right.
So he just,
I saw him write it down in Japanese in
Montana and then he just started down and
I was like,
car face.
Not that popular.
I don't think it's that popular there.
Yeah.
But how long was it was worth the trip in
you?
I hug all my friends.
Right.
This is the most awkward guy ever.
He's like,
Yo,
shell the title.
But he's like,
he,
he wasn't there.
Alright.
Jesus.
That lazy gentleman was a
gas moment in our podcast.
My belief is all of us have all of us
create what we need to work through to
create and learn what we
need to in this world.
And so I can't look at anyone as a victim.
I can't even a child.
I don't blame them.
I don't say,
this is your fault.
I say,
you made an agreement
in this place to do this and I am sending
you all my love and I believe in you
and I believe that you will.
You can be a miracle.
Okay?
I mean like who's to say how
you should live this life?
It's fucking,
I'll do it.
It's temporary.
Oreo,
right?
Oh,
you should be the ones who
are wondering totally down.
Let's just start with you over that.
We should start with you and examine,
examine your,
your behavior at the Tsa.
I say I can't do it.
Medical condition.
Okay,
go this way.
Okay.
If they say,
are you opting out?
I was like,
I don't know what that means.
When I say,
do you not want that or
do you want a pat down on?
I don't know.
I don't want to pat down,
but I'm not doing that thing.
So what am I options?
He's just trying to be Larry David.
No,
I'm just trying to not let them take
away these freedoms from me without going
down with a little bit of a fight.
But you had Kimbo in fucking side control.
You work to get it.
You got,
you were a dominant position.
He was tired and they
stood you back up bitches.
We did a,
um,
a video interview,
you know,
where everyone is on the other line.
And I've just finished training,
so I'm on the phone.
I want to,
no one was asking me
fucking any questions.
Um,
and I thought,
yeah,
I'm just the guy.
Kimbo tepee.
So Amanda,
someone asked,
go show a question.
They said,
um,
what would you do with James Thompson won?
And he said,
I'd hung myself.
And I thought,
wow.
Okay.
What's the most money you've ever gambled
the most I've ever lost in one night?
Yeah.
$8 tomorrow.
Okay.
What's the most you've ever lost someone?
1 million bucks.
Oh my.
Oh
my.
How much is it?
What's the most you've ever won?
6 million.
Okay.
Oh,
oh
Jesus.
Is it true that the reason why
we don't go back to the palms,
it's because they cut back your a,
your gambling budget because
you were killing him.
I go,
yeah.
Really?
Yeah.
That seems ridiculous.
I got into,
but that's the way Vegas says now.
I mean,
I guess the one film,
I recommend that everyone is Killa season.
All the dips said dudes are in it.
It's like the worst made [inaudible].
Oh,
you don't listen to the Dipset.
she's,
anyone here does ongoing shit.
What the dip set is?
Yo,
y'all don't know the dip set.
Y'All don't know the dip.
My grandfather's rolling over,
man.
I tell you these fucking kids today.
Wow.
Okay.
That little pink freak me out.
Gucci Mane is crazy.
Look at him.
He put an ice cream cone on his face.
It says burr.
You see it?
You see it on the cone.
Be Our,
our,
our and the taxi guy.
I was like,
okay,
call it ice.
Matt,
could you could you,
um,
I want,
I'm going to get,
have to get you to request this on
video and then I need you to get,
I need you to write this down.
Come on man.
Just tattoo it.
I ain't gonna change my mind on my face,
man.
I want a cone.
A good one.
Like a waffle type motherfucker scrape.
Craziest par lightening
bolt on my ice cream.
It looks like it under his,
I said something.
What the fuck?
Bop.
Honda's.
But yeah,
that dude is probably irrational.
Gucci Kiyoshi No,
Tom Day.
No hotel guys try.
What did you just look at?
Hartford teacher.
Got It.
What does that,
it's from gangster movies and shit.
Do you think you're talking
Ruskin?
I didn't do this to be mean.
I just did this because that's my nature.
I am the Scorpion.
You are the frog.
This is how shit goes down.
Matt.
Just tell him you love him.
Matt,
have you ever watched a Rodeo
and felt sorry for the bowls?
Nothing.
One of the stories he tells us about this,
uh,
Eskimo guy,
old guy.
And the family sort of took the keys
to the car away from him that like you
can't go anymore.
They were afraid he would go
out and die the traditional way.
When Eskimo people got old,
they were just like wander
off into the ice and die,
so as not to be a burden to the family.
And so that night he goes out,
it gets out of the house,
takes a shit in his hand,
forms the shit into a knife,
blade spits on it and the spit a is
freezing along the edge and he hones that
down.
So he gets a nice sharp
edge with his sped,
takes his shit knife,
kills a dog or a couple
of dogs and takes their,
uh,
ribs and makes us a sled out of it.
And with the sinews and whatever other
pieces of the dogs hooks up a couple
other dogs to the sled
and he takes off into the,
into the snow on his,
you know,
sled with his shit knife.
Wow.
Oh my God.
That might be the most of the
same story I've ever heard.
I had a,
I had an incident,
uh,
on a,
on the airplane going to
Indianapolis where this,
this guy,
like I just guy just started
like interrogating me.
He thought it was some
sort of flight risk.
It just sitting there and he just says,
he goes,
hey,
you were you afraid to fly?
And he goes,
how could he goes out?
Why?
Why are you going to Indianapolis Bill?
I'm like,
yeah,
I don't have to answer your questions.
He goes,
you don't answer my questions right now.
I'm going to hit that call button.
I will stop this plane and
you will be fucking arrested.
Like saying all this stuff and I'm just
sitting there and he's yapping in my
ear.
He was,
you thinks this is fucking over there
with a blindfold on laughing at him.
It was driving him fucking nuts.
It was great riding them
starting to nod off.
I just hear why he'd go
into Indianapolis spill.
I just laugh.
There's certain people that they have
music laying around just because it's
cool.
I'm tons of them.
The worst being the Tom Waits era.
Those motherfuckers are ones I want
to punch him right in the fucking face
because they're the ones you having a
good time listening to something your
Bible and they want to like
really impressed like some
fucking dumped chick with
freckles or something.
Everybody's fucked already.
Know what I'm saying?
Everybody fucked all.
You need this Tequila and a gram of blow.
She'll be sucking your
dick in a fucking bathroom.
You want to be cool and
let's the Tom Waits.
Everyone's a time.
Wait.
Um,
yeah,
I don't like it.
That's good thing.
And you want that you're fucking idiot.
But the only reason that people would
put that shit on is to try to overpower
you with that fucking star wars.
What do you call that?
The fucking thing with the mind.
The Mind Jack.
That's it.
Oh,
he's so,
oh my God.
He likes Tom.
Wait,
listen to that.
They're trying to shut you down
with a gun next to your head.
You're telling me if that's true.
That's good.
Fucking second.
That's the Beatles.
Y'All fucking shoot.
You can put a gun to your bucket at all.
Right.
Telling me that's good music.
You're fucking 20 years old.
Not at all.
Like when somebody says I
like the Dave Matthews Band,
I will pistol whip you.
He's beauty.
He just find my yard.
I swear he is to look at me.
He was my friend.
I know that sounds retarded.
But you are afraid of aliens though,
right?
Yeah.
My first a path mapped out in your house
had to get out of the aliens show up.
That's the rumor man.
That's heard.
I
heard you have a plan because I
know you like to use game plans,
so I figured he's had an alien.
I know,
I know cat ready and I know
Jujitsu all didn't show up.
I put a triangle choke
on him and I also have,
I kept that as well,
so I kept that to a Japanese get,
I'll see if they come,
I can slice them apart.
You've um,
you've kicked the green bitch.
Yes.
After a 24 year intense
relationship with the,
uh,
the green goddess or the Green Bitch,
depending on what mood she's in.
I had to stop.
Um,
and uh,
I've come in for some,
I've convinced for some,
some criticism for this and I
feel it's important to say that,
uh,
I hugely value and love cannabis.
I think it's a wonderful
herbal ally and I think that,
I don't think that I would ever have
written my books off historical mystery if
I had not encountered cannabis.
But like you mean you guys are
both in better shape than I am,
but I work out 45 minutes a month.
I do my whole body vibration
45 minutes a month.
I'm not kidding.
I do high end had a
minute less ridiculous.
That's five times more than me.
Really?
You too busy.
I have some theories
about that I was doing,
I invented bulletproof intermittent
fasting during that time,
which is when you do bulletproof
coffee during an intermittent fast,
I'm sorry,
but you could be a hilarious
Saturday night live sketch too.
You get any more famous,
you're in trouble because we didn't
do a sketch where everything,
I'm going to take a bulletproof shit.
Then I'm going to get my bullet proof
car and go to the bulletproof office.
You know,
this is my bulletproof secretary.
I'll stop bulletproofing stuff,
Joe,
but no more.
All right,
fair enough.
I got a buddy who's a billionaire,
real live billionaire.
So
years later he came into the money like
where it was his in one year he went
from fucking Zenith,
the Nadir,
like he,
he straight to Rehab.
He was,
he would call me and be like,
I'm in Vegas.
I've got the top floor of the wind rented.
I get slip and slides down the hallway.
There's,
there's strippers and hookers everywhere.
And we got midgets in a storm trooper
outfit serving a strengths and he'd be
like,
all of a private jet picking you up.
Get here.
Now how much money did he inherit?
A bout $5 billion.
Oh my goodness.
And he's not fun anymore.
It's the best clip.
All right,
we'll do this.
And you see kids running
with their elbows out,
right.
Like RTD too.
Two.
Right.
That's a test.
That's c three Po runs with his arms out.
Yeah.
What is the r two d two doesn't have arms.
I'm just letting you talk to him.
All right.
I'll try
to stay in your hair.
I'm fine.
The Opening Act upchuck uh,
the clown is trying to calm my nerves now.
There's,
there's no,
you know,
they have their,
their,
their own security.
So there's no security.
It's just,
it's just juggle a law and this huge
piece of property up trying to convince me
that it's not that scary of a Gig.
And he's driving me around on
this golf cart and he's like,
you know,
you got it.
And this huge cloud,
just,
this guy just jumps out of nowhere
and starts punching up chuck.
I'm the golf guy.
He's running along and
it ain't for no reason.
He's like,
fuck you.
Fuck you.
I'm in shock.
And he just hit a day.
Yeah.
And he's gunning it and the guy said,
we lose the game.
And he's like,
ah,
I'm here every year.
You know,
they know me,
I'm like family.
And I'm like,
okay.
So He's trying to convince me this can
affect the first kind of fake what comes
in and it just sprays all over us.
And uh,
and he's like,
he's so familiar with
getting hit with Paygo Cola.
He goes,
he goes,
uh,
it's diet.
It's not going to stay.
I swear to God.
Then one comes in and in the o nine,
he's got it on camera.
It's like the Zapruder film.
We got this can of soda.
This guy does a baseball pitch and you
see it whizzing seconds before it hits
the temple.
No.
[inaudible] it's lump sum for the wheel.
And he goes,
I'm hurt.
I'm hurt bad by the way.
He's mid sentence,
I guess,
you know,
something like that.
When the soda,
is that going to happen at a
Dave Matthews correc and slump.
So He's like,
I'm hurt.
I'm hurt bad Bob.
He's calling me Bob.
So I know he's really fucked up,
not bobcat.
We walk in and you know,
everyone's gone,
but Sam and like three other people
and they're still doing blow.
I first walked into the kitchen
and walked back to the room.
I see the doors open.
All the guitars are gone.
My bed's fucked up.
Like the door had been broken and kicked
in and Sam looks at me and goes up
pissed on your bed.
Mer,
you want to know why?
And I go,
yeah,
yeah I do.
He goes,
cause you at that fucking moron.
Sleep with my guitars.
And like,
then there's this word silence.
And I turned to bill and I said,
I told you I knew him.
Huh?
I could do John Mayer did to too.
No,
I think he's great.
I think he's very talented.
But if your wife is really into going,
you know what I'm saying?
Like she dragged you there
and just stares at him.
Right?
Boob bless you.
Notice she's not clapping because
when her hands slipped down her genes,
she's his knuckle deep.
Oh,
so sad.
It sounds like someone's stabbing of seal.
Just
she's just Fiserv herself.
She's all the way to her elbow.
Just grounded it in there.
You can see her rib cage expand as a fist.
Goes up there
fucking love you.
Okay.
Let's go.
And if you break down humor like that,
like you said,
fine tooth comb,
every single joke where
90% of the jokes you do,
unless you're talking about
balloons are bouncing a ball,
have hurt somebody.
If we get that literal with humor than
almost all jokes comics tell are going to
be up for a a careful examination.
Contributing to a fucking rape culture
is nonsense and it is to say comedian
contributes to rape culture is simply
bullshit and it's simplistic thinking.
It's a way of saying,
I don't like what you're saying
and I don't want you to say it,
but I can't come out with that.
So I have to find a higher reason which
makes it sound like you shouldn't say
it.
For this reason,
as the ban against these weapons roads,
other tyrants will have no reason to
think twice about acquiring poison gas and
using them cheeses over time
where the troops were again,
face the prospect.
Honestly,
we don't attack the area.
I'm going to get some poison gas.
It could be easier for
terrorist organizations and
the day after any military
action,
we would redouble our efforts to achieve
a political solution that strengthens
those who reject the forces
of tyranny and extremism.
Biden beat me at poker.
He used to run Raytheon.
They sell how?
Hellfire missiles.
Oh,
now he's leaving.
The same way came in.
Oh my God.
Nice and dramatic that just that alone,
all of this ready attrical
shit was orchestrated.
Folks,
I guarantee you there are some
people that are involved in this.
There's some producers,
there's some,
there's an artistic director they want.
That was a,
that was a well planned out scene.
He walks up,
he walks back.
The fact that they do it in this ancient
stupid house where he supposedly lives.
Meanwhile,
you know he's in some fucking seven mile
thick bunker down deep into the ground.
The bowels of the Earth where Dick
Cheney was hiding all throughout the Iraq
war.
I remember,
here's just a metal slide
he jumps in and look at.
It's a shoot,
like a laundry chute,
jumps in and slides through the lens and
the towels and just go some cell phone
off and surrounded by lizards
who are like excellent work.
Yeah,
it's bad.
It's about men's layer.
How much time between her putting the
Saran wrap over your butt hole and you
shooting a load,
how much time fit?
15 seconds to put the Saran wrap,
five seconds to shoot.
Gosh,
you know what I mean?
It's,
it's horrendous.
I mean you call it feminism
Marxists with pennies.
Does that socialism,
socialism,
socialism at test,
but that was a bad character
and one of my novels,
I just go on the feminism.
Socialism at Penn is that
is very true because I mean,
and then people call,
oh my God,
that's so terrible.
That's not,
I just went through all the founding
matriarchs of the feminist system that all
Marxists,
all leftist and so on and also it feminist
is so pro woman then where are they
with Margaret Thatcher?
Margaret Thatcher was like the
first leader of a Western country.
She struggled that from nothing.
I made an incredibly powerful woman,
but she was on the right.
You see,
so they hate her.
What about Iran?
I ran,
wrote,
wrote the most influential book
outside the Bible and the second most
influential book and according to The
New York Times review of books after the
Bible,
uh,
you know,
we shaped a western philosophy in
many ways and western politics and the
feminist hater.
Why?
Cause she was on the right cause he's,
that's what they think.
She was not actually on the right,
but so I mean I have these sorts of
suspicions when they're sort of the,
is it the leftist
ideology or the pro woman?
Now if it's the pro woman,
then they should be incredibly positive.
Where are the feminists when people
insult people like Ann Coulter,
where are the feminist?
When people insult Sarah Pailin,
you don't like Bill Maher,
her called her a cunt.
I mean that's really pretty vicious.
Like publicly,
openly,
right?
I mean where are the fee because they
are on the rise and culture and they're
considered to be on the right.
So they get a pass when people go,
you know,
but you then say something
bad about a woman on the left.
And so I think that he is more left
than it is pro women because when they
choose between their
politics and the agenda,
they always seem to choose the
politics of what the agenda is.
And that's why I say it's left
as rather than then problem.
Right.
People always take things at face value.
They don't tend to get to know you or,
I mean I'm sitting right
in front of you now.
Would you say that I am a woman?
No,
no.
Don't say you're a woman.
Thank you.
Have a beard.
Beard.
Yeah.
No,
you're basically a man.
Thank you.
I appreciate it.
No problem.
Be Compliment from
people.
Steal everything you see this is,
yeah,
this is awesome.
Yeah,
I saw that.
You see that on fucking unbelievable.
Joey's in a far right.
That's insane.
That would look at when we were so cute.
I got the sexy lucky seven.
Can you get it?
So it just as whole body feels is chrome
was 44 I was 44 there was local lucky
seven cause I like that.
Look at that.
Wow,
that's so crazy.
Wow.
Look at you dude.
So how old are you in this picture?
14.
14 and that's what I was noticing.
I was smoking dope then.
I was no innocent then I was smoking dope.
I was finger bang.
And people,
the hardest thing in the world is to say,
if somebody says to you,
relax,
right,
or be yourself,
it just be yourself,
Joe.
You know?
I mean,
and,
and yet I think as we
become more professional and
better at what we're doing,
when somebody says to you,
be yourself,
you can,
you know,
you're not burdened by these false
selves and these things that,
uh,
that you think you ought to
be or ought block to say,
or how you want to look
or what you ought to be.
And I think in many ways that's what
any artist does as they become a
professional at what they do.
They learned to kind of
get out of their own way.
And it's the hardest thing of all,
I think.
Do you feel a responsibility for
that or towards that as an artist?
Do you ever feel like because of the,
what you're doing,
because if you're,
you're so motivated,
you get so much done and you have
so many different projects going.
Do you,
do you realize the impact of that?
Because a lot of people
were inspired by though the,
not just the work ethic that you have,
but the,
how much quality shit you produce,
whether it's wine or music or,
I appreciate the company.
Um,
I think,
I think you can't really worry about it.
You just got to do what it is doing.
And for me,
I just have to do what I'm doing.
And there's a,
there's a,
there's a sense of,
for the art or for the,
the process.
And just for myself,
I just,
I care about what I'm doing.
Um,
if I start caring about what
you think about what I'm doing,
whether it's going to be helping you,
then I'm,
uh,
that I'm,
an assisted living,
uh,
employee when I was on the
space station the second time.
One of the other crew members,
her name is sue Holmes.
Uh,
she and I were talking,
we'd known each other
since test pilot school.
And in passing a throwaway thing,
she didn't even think she was saying.
She said,
hey,
you know,
Earth said that we're
supposed to do this next.
And in my mind,
I heard Earth said,
I heard those words come out of her mouth.
And it was like,
she has in her mind completely a split
off from the other 7 billion people.
There's her crew and earth is one
singular identifiable entity on the other
side.
And that was a real,
a bellringer to me of what it's
going to be like to go to Mars.
Those people are going to be,
uh,
a completely discrete unit of
people and there'll be Martians.
They won't be earthlinks
pretty quick in their heads.
And how do you deal with that?
How do we plan for that?
And it's still a long ways in the future,
but it's one of the many things
we need to sort out before we,
because as you say,
once you get the engines
going fast enough that you're,
you're headed for Mars,
you can't just turn around.
I think we're not talking an attorney.
Right?
Yeah.
And in Houston I was an attorney then
in Dallas I started a computer company.
I had a personal computer company that uh,
well in 1981 we outgrowth Microsoft,
you know,
I had four color picture
in Forbes magazine,
made the front page of the Wall Street
Journal and really then IBM came in and
crushed us like a bug.
Wow.
We just sort of sold ourselves out of
business and by the time we were done the
last six,
eight,
nine months,
I was financing the
thing by selling ecstasy.
What's,
and I know a guy,
my acting class and you know how
long I was an acting class years.
There was a guy,
really good guy,
normal guy.
So I thought,
and he was,
and I hired him to shoot
me to shoot this audition.
So I go to his house and he's got this
great camera and on his wall is a dream
board and on his wall is his,
no,
no.
He's put his face.
He's put his face on the cover of
vanity fair and those magazines,
he's got slogan's saying,
you're the guy,
you're the one and it's a dream board.
And it was big.
It was good.
Covered his whole wall,
man.
Yes,
you should dream big,
but you should also be
realistic with who you are.
I won't do it.
He's gonna do it.
Shit.
He could put his hand between
my legs and roll me back.
Right.
But see that way you'll get,
don't let him see you doing that.
He's going to hurt you.
What does this 10% you keep saying,
why do you keep saying 10%?
Well,
Brian keeps saying 10%.
It's a running joke based in truth.
I had some issues.
I had some situations in my life and I,
I like to put numbers on things and based
on these factors and experiences
and thought processes,
we came to the number of,
uh,
10% gay.
I'm open with it.
You know it it,
it's not,
what'd she just say it?
It's not,
I understand what you just said.
What you just said was a statement that
would really work if everybody knew what
you were saying,
but I don't know what you're saying.
So what you're saying is a 10% gay.
I'm open with it.
What does that mean?
Does that mean you're 10% gay?
Yes.
I came out on my podcast
probably like six months ago.
You came out 10% yes.
So funny.
Is there any beers in there?
Jamie?
Go get me a beer.
I need a beer on this one.
Yeah,
this is going to get rid of,
you know,
this is insane.
I just want to point something out of how
we are so weird like as a culture that
this is a part of like
normal everyday office life.
Like we've got to make
some decisions here.
Like okay look at this woman.
She's showing everything but her vagina,
I mean her knee is just strategically
blocking her Lavia her legs are wide open
and she's hot as fuck.
Now here's the thing.
If you put the Kyron right
in front of the vagina,
then everybody would know the news.
Exactly.
We'd be a very informed country and women
would get angry at you if you knew the
news.
Oh,
you were looking at her vagina
and you read the fucking news.
Huh?
This is like something that
I liked that Ron doss has,
which is like if you don't
feel like meditating,
don't meditate.
Don't force it.
Don't impose this on yourself.
Keep doing the thing you're doing
that's upsetting you so much.
Have the balls to keep doing the
fucking thing that you're doing.
Keep doing it.
If society is going to tell you,
don't be like this.
Stop being like this.
You'd have to change.
That's what your parents always say.
The idea is like no,
sink into what you are right now.
Just be that thing.
Stop resisting exactly where
you are right now is perfect.
And that's a hard truth to grasp.
I've been listening to a Dan
Carlin and barbecue my ass.
Dan Carlin was uh,
the um,
uh,
the,
our,
our guests on Monday and he has a
podcast called hardcore history.
Yeah.
And right now it's all about the Mongols.
And for the next hour home,
I listened to the history
of the Mongol Empire,
uh,
which is fascinating.
Dan Carlin's hardcore history.
Um,
I'm really into this,
I'm Dan Carlin,
a podcast recently.
He's got this podcast called
hardcore history and uh,
he does this really detailed history
of the Mongols over like five,
five episodes.
Well,
I told you I'm a fucking
in love with that.
Dan Carlin's hardcore history podcast.
You know,
that's one of the really cool things.
This Dan Carlin thing on,
um,
uh,
on the history of the Mongols.
You know,
we had Dan Carlin on
from hardcore history.
You're listening to that podcast.
I have heard about it from one of his
most bad ass podcasts is about the
Mongols.
Kingus Khan was a mother fucker.
Like he definitely killed 10 million.
God Damn,
that's unbelievable.
That's,
that's the best talking about armies
that were coming towards China where the
Mongols had been in the distance.
They thought they saw
snow covered mountains,
but when they got close they
realized they were mounds of bones.
Oh my God.
And garlic and the
garlic is just gangster,
just killing everybody.
Anybody that's anywhere,
it's like the Mongol hoards.
It's like something out of
ancient times that we have that,
you know,
Jeff,
it's like a Mongo whore.
Right,
exactly.
That's pretty preposterous.
The world has actually never been
less violent than it is today.
Look at Syria,
how 100,000 people like,
and it's a lot,
but I guess she used to be worried.
I mean the Mongols killed
a million and a half,
right?
There's a lot less murder.
Then there was like in the fucking 12
hundreds back during the Mongol days and
shit like that.
Brian blog,
go to my Twitter and uh,
there's a thing that I retweeted
earlier today from Dan Carlin,
a hardcore history guy.
He,
uh,
put up a trailer of a Gingiss Khan and
the Mongols from like the John Wayne era.
They did a movie with John
[inaudible] is con the Concord.
Everybody,
the Mongols came through
Moscow in the winter.
They came through the,
through the fucking attacked Russia in
the winter because nobody else would do
it that way.
And they didn't eat.
They didn't see it coming.
Did I tell you how they,
why they were so hard to
follow into the desert?
Who the mom calls.
You didn't have to tell me.
I know a lot about them,
but go ahead if you want to.
Well it's just what,
are you a fucking educator now?
Because did I tell you,
cause they were like,
if we get some Saturdays
to get their arms together,
I don't have,
I have I briefed you on the model.
It's my friend.
I'm going to do,
I'm glad you asked.
I think we talked last
time about how there was,
there was,
there's pictures of,
uh,
of Afghanistan with,
with Western ideal type
Western idea type cultures.
Uh,
you know,
there was a massive
culture shift in terms of,
you know,
women with education and
your state of dress and,
and things wouldn't be allowed.
Well,
there was a fantastic episode of hardcore
history and the Dan Carlin podcast
where he talked about the
Mongols invading Iraq.
Well,
this is the second time that
someone has done that to Baghdad.
It's a,
I've been listening to for
the past couple of years.
Dan Carlin's hardcore history.
When Baghdad was raided by the
Mongols and they crushed the society,
they basically started from scratch
after that kills everyone and through all
the literature away so
that they save it today,
they're just getting to the point like
culturally of where they were in 2012 and
the Mongols were throwing trees at them.
They cut all their trees down and then
they stacked them up with giant catapult
and hurled them over the gates.
Just Shroyer everything in the city and
what they would do is take the survivors
and put them in the
front lines and use them.
Oftentimes as the front.
They would push an army into the town
and people would be shooting arrows at
their own friends.
Thousands and thousands of people
just be forced through the door of a,
of,
of a,
of the gate of a,
of a city.
I listened to your Mongo podcast at least
four or five times what I called the
Joe Rogan stopped telling Joe Rogan to
talk about your mom goal podcast on his
shoe.
You talked to this poor comedic woman
about it and you said something and there
was,
we went back to her.
There's this long dead silence where she
tried to absorb what you just told her.
Who was that?
Who Do you think that would
have been a female comedian?
She said I've got a show on consumer.
Yeah,
that's most likely about it.
There's this long pause like
what do I say after that?
Yeah I can,
Amy Schumer was some fucking crazy
man.
I must be broadcasting to record.
What the fuck I am broadcasting.
He cuts.
There we go now.
Now we're on ladies and gentlemen,
we're sort of on time.
Ah
We try to get it right every week,
but every week we fucked something up
and this week I made sure that I turned
off the sound on my computer.
The one over there,
I haven't even turned off
the sound on this one yet.
So for you,
he did four years.
You got mine do mine.
He didn't do yours pass the torch.
It could've easily been me.
That just fucked up.
Which is,
that's the reason why I fucked up.
It's cause cause I'm here
cause I always fuck it up.
I fucked it up every week we'd done this
God damn thing like 22 weeks in a row.
I fuck it up every single
time for this week.
It was Brian,
you know,
uh,
I've been thinking about
this podcast a lot,
ladies and gentlemen and a,
one of the things I've been thinking
about it is I appreciate the fuck out of
everybody listening.
And uh,
we,
we do try our best to make this as
interesting as possible and as smooth and
professional as possible.
But I got admit that I've been
too stressed out about this.
I've been taking it too seriously.
I mean,
uh,
taking seriously in a good way
where as we improve the sound,
we've got a real mixer and we got to,
I mean we're sitting on couches and
shit and we're going to get it better
cameras,
but that like,
it's not like there's a part of it,
it's really fun,
but there's a part of it that wasn't
fun and I don't think that should exist.
I don't think I should ever
get too serious about this.
This is for people who are working,
who are being distracted that just
wants something because they're doing
mindless shit.
This is for people that are
driving in their cars and you know,
wants up to now listen to this
is for people on the train.
This is for people at the gym,
whatever the fuck it's for you guys.
All right.
And if,
if we take it too seriously,
you stop being yourself and it starts,
starts being like this professional
thing that you're trying real hard to do.
And uh,
I think,
uh,
I think I've fallen prey
to that a little bit.
I was thinking about it today after to
took a little bit of the head of the weed
and I was thinking
about it and I was like,
you know what man,
this thing,
like I'm,
I'm like,
Aye.
I paid too much attention to it and she'd
just be a weekly fun thing like it or
not,
you know,
for,
for anybody who's a likeminded or
anybody is interested in some sort of a
distraction from someone
who's not likeminded.
Um,
so thank you very much for tuning in.
Everybody.
Love you.
Bitches mitre
right.