Man has to be careful about what size
accoutrement he carries around with him.
Right.
Know when you get into like the man bag
category it's like,
I don't know if you could pull that off
is a note too.
So he's big.
He's held,
what we're talking about is Ian's um,
phone cover here.
It's,
it's very personalized.
It's like a change purse.
You put your cards and shit.
So it is a person
in a way it's like a wallet,
like a wallet phone.
While it's a good word.
Isn't that funny?
Like there's words you're allowed to
use.
Like,
like you could walk around all day with
a backpack and no one says anything
like,
well Ian,
unless she's just keep it.
Should I do act.
But yeah,
no,
no problem with that.
But if you have some sort of a Satchel,
yeah.
You know,
very suspect,
very suspect.
Open yourself up for a lot of verbal
attacks,
you know,
saying and it's like this style of
satchels important too because if you
got like a Satchel that's like in any
way stylish,
then you can't just be wearing like
converse all stars and a tee shirt.
You have to wear like hipster clothes,
you have to come like rolled up cuffs
and you have to have like a nice tie up
leather shoe.
You know,
like you have to go there having mcinnis
Gavin mcinnes you know,
you gotta you gotta figure out what,
what are you going to wear with it?
Yeah,
you gotta you gotta look the part.
So that's why I still take a lot of heat
for the fanny pack.
And I think it's funny cause I,
I,
you know,
where the thing all the time.
But yeah,
I feel uncomfortable when I wear it
sometimes.
Quite honestly like yeah,
wear it.
And I've realized people are looking at
it and they notice it and they're
mocking me.
I don't have the balls to wear a fanny
pack.
I got to tell you that right now.
I wear it on stage.
You wear it on stage award onstage a
bunch of times,
you're not going to pull anything out of
there because I don't want to leave my
wallet in the greenroom.
Shady people working on the comedy club.
I'd Robert him steal my wallet
and so that's how like much I'm into
like looking off looking like a man.
You know what I'm saying?
Like I'm like,
I can't do it.
You just call this a purse.
You may never see this again as I call
it a bit.
I might,
I might throw the phone away with it and
just get a new phone.
You have to have a cover though.
I found that out man.
I tried to go natural with my,
my last phone and uh,
man,
I dropped it a few times and it was
toast.
It's shattered.
Jamie's going natural.
You don't drop it.
Pretty careful with in there,
but it's still good to go.
You know what?
I don't think I dropped this one now
that I have a case.
That's what's funny.
The funny thing.
Yeah,
that happens.
Yeah.
Like you don't have a case like bad,
but I dropped back here.
Yeah.
When you go,
I've been raw like no case.
Just raw,
no condom on the phone.
You have to be careful with that shit.
Feels good that way,
doesn't it?
That way I have the natural phone in
your hand with nothing on it.
It also feels like you're a risk taker.
I'm a mother fucker and he's got no
cooper.
My phone pitch right.
Doesn't it feel kind of more modern
times?
That is a risk.
That's 2016 it is a risk to not have a
case on your fucking phone.
That's crazy.
We're rebel were rebelling.
Yeah.
This is the softest time to be alive.
It's so easy to be alive.
You know,
we're trying to eradicate all the
dangerous parts that are left.
Like there's the dead dangerous parts
are left like particularly in America.
There's so highlighted now.
It's one of the reasons why I think like
Chicago and Baltimore and Detroit and
when we find out like the murder
statistics for all these cities.
One of the things that freaks us out is
that for the most part,
most of this country is,
is easy going and soft as its ever been
ever.
So when you see some crazy violence like
in a youtube video or Worldstar hip hop
or something like that,
live leak.
I watch some live leak shit the other
day I got to stop doing that.
Man,
I got to stop traumatizing and they'll
get you.
But you realize like there are still
spots where it's dangerous as fuck,
but for the most part it's so soft.
Right now it's so soft.
Right now we're risk takers if we have
no phone cover,
that's us.
Yeah,
that's the new tattoo.
Yeah.
Like I have no phone cover.
Everybody's tattooed now.
To me that's weird.
I mean obviously I have them,
but I just,
it's odd for me to see how many more
people have tattoos today.
How long have you had your tactics?
Awhile.
While I had one on my shoulder forever,
I got one when I think I was like 23 or
four or something like that was
rebellious back then.
I was like,
Ooh,
I'm going crazy.
It was something I drew two and my
friend Tommy,
um,
my friend Tommy Jr had gone to this guy
already,
uh,
Danny Williams in Connecticut and he was
really good artists.
Man,
this guy was a really good ours,
big biker looking dude.
But uh,
it's just the trust that would your
tattoos back then it was a wicked
artists,
you know,
he was like,
it's like back then tattoos as an art
form was way more obscure.
Like now I think people know like Kat
von d,
they recognize these like celebrity
tattoo artists.
Like ed hardy came out with the line of
clothing.
Like ed hardy was like a world famous
tattoo guy.
Like way,
way back in the day.
Like his,
like there's a whole style of tattoos
that people associate with Ed Hardy,
but there was only a few other ones and
now it's like they have all these
magazines and TV shows and the guy that
did me,
Aaron Dellavedova is fucking awesome.
He's down in San Diego at Guru Tattoo
and it's,
you know,
he's like my,
he's a good friend.
Like,
I really love that store and it's like
he's a cool guy to talk to,
which is I think important.
If you want to have someone draw on you
for the rest of your life.
That's funny.
Like they have the like the hair dress
up barbershop.
It's style,
you know conversations when you're going
there to get the tats.
Yeah.
Well you do,
you get to learn about a guy,
you'll get to have like these deep
conversations.
Like Erin and I,
we talked for like 45 hours on my right
arm and like probably like 60 hours on
my left arm.
It's a lot of this talk as a lot of
talking and sometimes you don't really
talk though cause sometimes he's just
deep into it and I'm just like watch a
like like a watch I was watching.
That's my watch.
Like most of a breaking bad season one,
season two as well as shit.
That's funny.
That's like the perfect show to watch it
be getting a tattoo.
It's like that's good mood music.
You know what I'm saying?
Watching breaking bad and getting a
tattoo.
It's almost like the pain of the Tattoo
accentuates the show because the show is
so chaotic and fucked up.
It's almost like better while someone's
drilling on your elbow and the tattoo
needle.
You said elbow and needle.
I felt that he feel it.
Yeah.
That's a,
that's a rough spot.
The inside of the oboe wreck right here.
That's a really rough spot.
What's interesting is that the closer it
gets to your chest,
it's a really rough spot.
Like you're like woo.
Different spots of different level of
pain.
They experience trauma.
It's very strange.
Like your shoulder.
Nothing.
He could draw me all day on my shoulder.
I fall asleep.
Like I'm not kidding.
It's weird.
Like the shoulder just doesn't seem to
hurt.
But you get down to like some air.
The inside of the arm.
Yeah.
It's like a different feeling.
It's,
I don't know.
I guess the nerves are closer.
Like anywhere that's got more meat on it
is like protected more from the,
I don't know.
It's funny though cause it's like,
it's like you're finding out shit about
your body,
you know,
while you're getting tattooed,
you know it's like,
it's kind of like sometimes you are
having sex with a girl and I always
liked when she,
oh,
I never felt that before like that.
Nobody's ever touched that part or
explored that part and it's like you
find it anywhere you digging Ian and
everywhere.
Where am I not good?
If you love a you just,
you will try to find it.
Of course when the girl says like that,
the good percentage of me always goes,
y'all right.
Ah Shit.
Fuck.
Every time,
every time in my life a girl said
something like that.
Always be like,
okay,
because it seems like something that
girls think that guys want to hear.
Dot.
Yeah.
It's a part of faking it.
Well it's a part of getting the guy to
like you like getting a girl to like,
you guys will do all kinds of ridiculous
artificial shit.
Pretend to be a certain way per hen.
Pretend to behave a certain way,
but when it gets down to it,
you know,
you get to know them.
It takes,
takes a long time to chip away from that
stuff.
So when someone says something that's
like Cliche,
ridiculous,
or along those lines,
he got to think like,
oh,
this person just running their game and
their game,
they're running their fall in love with
me.
Game.
They're falling in love with it.
You got it.
You got to challenge those women says to
the show that they respect you and you
keep it on that level,
you know,
or don't date.
Fakers yeah.
That's hard though.
It's like my hot,
yeah.
What are you doing?
Checking tweets while the show was
trying to retweet the thing,
but I'm not getting any reception
reception.
Yeah.
I just want,
that's the only thing I want to do is
like retweet it,
but not my purse ain't allowing me to do
this.
Yeah.
You're in your rebel because you have an
android phone to both.
Both.
Fuck.
Is that the,
uh,
the note where you could draw on the
screen?
Yeah.
Those are the shit.
I love that shit.
I love it.
That's what I that no,
you had one though,
had one of those and then you switched
it back out.
Yeah.
Now I have a galaxy.
I have an iphone.
I have two different phones.
Oh,
that's good.
So you got to go to the mess.
That note that.
I just think that the ability to draw on
the show,
it was like God is going to come into
play someday.
I'm going to make some funny shit with
this.
And you're like,
have your friends and,
but it seems like those are meme
generators.
We just go and get like a little thing
and put the text into it.
That seems like that's easier.
It's easier.
But sometimes it's a pain in the ass
sometimes to move it to where you want
to move it to.
My Shit.
Like the reason,
one of the reasons I like having this is
like,
like there was like last year I wasn't,
I didn't,
I was living in a friend's,
I sold that placement of one last time
and I was living at a friend's house so
I didn't have no printer.
No,
no,
no setup where you could like if you get
a contract for a show or just with
anything but so you could print it up
yourself with this.
You just look at the thing on your
phone.
You could sign it,
you could like read the contract and
then sign it and send it in via email
back without printing anything out or
anything.
So yeah,
that's a big thing to have in that case.
But how weird is that?
We're still signing things like how much
longer is that going to,
I mean,
think about it,
a unique movement with your hand.
Really.
Like,
we all know that I used to replicate all
the kiss signatures.
Every kid knows how to do that,
right?
Michael Jordan's autograph.
Oh sure.
Well probably a bunch of people who have
fake memorabilia,
right?
Like with a guy like Michael Jordan,
like a basketball signed by Michael
Jordan is worth how much more than a
regular basketball and a fake
basketball,
not cyber.
My coach is worth still a lot of money.
Yeah.
Well how about,
yeah,
it doesn't even have to be a real
basketball.
It would be a child's toy,
Michael Jordan signs.
It's worth a lot of money.
So it,
it only makes sense that a unique hand
movement,
it can be easily replicated.
It's not like what he could do on the
basketball court.
He could do with his handwriting.
Is that hilarious?
Nobody can fuck with his hand.
Right.
You can't nobody get malaria.
Fuck slams,
gunk from center court like he did.
You know,
nobody,
you can't do it.
I can't do it.
But the motherfucker rights just like,
right.
It doesn't have some crazy writing and
nobody
can replicate.
Yeah.
He just,
he just writes his name.
So all you have to do is look at that
thing and then recreate it.
Like I was watching this,
um,
a documentary on art forgery.
Fascinating shows,
fascinating shit.
Which one I wish I could remember,
um,
because I caught it on television and I
caught it when it was already started,
you know,
just flipping through the channels.
Like what is this?
And I don't remember,
but what I do remember was that,
um,
there was an article that I had read as
well about this one guy who was a
forgery guy,
but in a weird way when he would do is
he would make a fake version,
a new piece of art,
but from that artist's style,
and this guy apparently was making
fucking millions of dollars in Europe
with this.
Like,
people would go crazy after the war,
during the war or something like that.
I wish I remembered that.
Um,
do you know it is,
yeah.
Yeah.
I'm pretty sure this is it.
It's on,
I'm pretty sure it's on Netflix or it
was,
yes.
That's the guy truckee the artist
forgeries what it is.
Yes.
Okay.
There we really,
his story's really cool how he does it.
You can probably explain it.
Yeah.
Oh No.
It's incredible.
He would study the art of each guy or
woman or whoever he was trying to
replicate,
and then he would create a new fake
piece that they did that was so good
that experts couldn't understand it.
Experts were,
they were like,
this is,
this is a picasso.
Like I know because I've seen,
because I study because this is a
picasso.
That's how good he was.
And I think what fucked him up was he
got cocky and he used a color of paint
that wasn't available back then.
And it was almost like summit speculated
that he did it like you wanted to see if
he could get caught.
Like it's almost like he wanted to take
credit for his work.
Serial killer.
Yeah,
exactly.
You know,
um,
that was,
that was how it happened.
Right?
I'm pretty sure I,
cause I was really confused as I was
watching it because he and his wife both
got,
they were both arrested in both were
serving prison sentences,
but they were allowed out during the day
to go work to draw.
But it had to be separated for some and
some part.
But yeah,
I think he was working now selling art
of his own because he was so good and
people knew how good his forgeries,
where some people actually wanted those
forgeries because they were so good.
So now he's got to name them.
Okay.
And wait for somebody forges his shit.
Well he doesn't have a style.
He's like a hack exact community.
You know what I mean?
But obviously super talented.
What a bittersweet thing though,
because you got to think that a guy that
can be that talented,
that can replicate that,
that is art,
right?
Right.
Cause he's,
he's,
he's doing new pieces,
right.
New Pieces in their style.
[inaudible] which in a way is kind of
more honorable of form of forgery.
I mean if you're going to go down the
fucker food chain,
like to recreate a piece of art is
probably more honorable or to
create your own version of this person's
arts.
Parvin more honorable than like if you
had a painting and I had made an exact
duplicate of it.
Yeah.
Well when you first started the story,
I was like fuck rich people for being so
much into art.
They deserve to get screwed by this
dude.
Then when you said he's a hack,
then I related to it on a comedy level
and I was like fuck this guy.
Cause I feel the pain of following hacks
who are ripping,
you know what I'm saying?
Or or getting accolades and the
audiences don't know that they are hack.
Oh that's the sort of story I can relate
to it on on,
on different levels.
Isn't that terrible feeling when you
walk in a room and someone's killing
with some like really bullshit material.
Like you know for sure this is just chop
chop material.
Yeah.
It makes me more angry at the audience
then the person,
cause I've already been angry at this
person.
I've already seen him before and knowing
them before,
most likely.
But then I was like I have to try to do
my shit in front of this audience that
doesn't know that this is fake.
This is a fake y'all.
Yeah.
I watched somebody still on a Freddy,
so those bits,
the other guy,
oh shit.
And I had to leave the room.
Audience was laughing.
I don't leave the room.
I was like,
Oh God,
yeah,
I can't even see this.
Yeah.
You know,
especially a guy like Freddy who was
dead,
who was awesome,
one of the best guys ever.
Just such a sweetie.
I'm trying,
I'm trying to get over stuff like that
though and not let it affect me.
Just get away from it.
You know,
we were talking about that last night.
Um,
Tony Hinchcliffe and I,
cause he was talking about,
um,
people that get to a certain point in
their career and then they want it
fucking things up.
And Tony's like super ambitious.
So Tony's,
um,
he's essentially making sure that none
of this stuff ever happens to him.
So he's like seeing things that people
are fucked up and,
and then,
you know,
dealing with people that hate on him
because he's ambitious because,
you know,
he's always getting after it,
but kids always writing,
always doing new stuff.
And some people,
they just get upset with them.
Like they think they feel like he is,
his ambition is threatening to their
examination of themselves.
Right.
You know,
and up,
we were having a conversation about it
last night and I was like,
don't dwell on it just right.
You know,
it's easier said than done,
but you see all these people out there
that are fuck it up.
Don't pay attention to them.
Just there's plenty of people around
like bird,
like you like Joey,
like Ari.
This is plenty of people that are out
there that are just killing it.
Right.
Pay attention to them.
This is the best time ever for this
shit.
You know,
like my new thing is,
you know,
and I've done it in spurts,
like just focus on the shit that I want,
not the stuff that can stop me from
getting what I want.
But I find like if you focus on the
stuff that you want or where you want to
get to and you have tunnel vision,
then you'll be fine and you'll get
there.
Like instead of creating all this
wasting time,
taking time away from your creativity,
thinking about what people are thinking
about you and all that stuff and just
focus on like,
I need to make this joke work,
this joke work.
I need to do this.
I need to do that.
Everything that gets you that step
further,
you know?
Well,
this is,
I think there's patterns of thought that
are really easy to fall into it.
Yeah,
they just seem natural and one of them
is when there is something that's in
your way and you're trying to figure out
why it's in your way,
you start concentrating on some of the
aspects of it that are out of your
control.
Right?
Like you know,
how come they don't like what I do,
but they like what she does or how come
you know this has happened and how the
fuck did this guy get this?
Instead of try to figure out how to get
so tuned into what you're doing that you
don't concentrate on what they don't
want.
You just concentrate.
God,
come on.
How many times I cleaned my fucking
brother,
I got to stop drinking this butter
coffee fucks up.
Podcasts.
It does,
right?
I'm a little too,
a little too much,
but it's hard to say.
I mean it's easy to say.
It's hard to do.
It's hard to actually like get your mind
into a place where you're concentrating
on only what you're trying to do,
especially when the,
in the beginning of your career trying
to get out there and getting booked and
nobody wants to book you write
some dude was bitching about that at the
comedy store the other night.
He was talking about how,
uh,
you know,
nobody's helping him out and all,
all these other people are doing well
and,
but you know,
it seems like it's bullshit and the
system is stacked against him.
I was like,
Jesus Christ,
like you're,
you're dead.
Well,
it's,
it's so foolish because nobody knows who
you are.
First of all,
if nobody knows who you are,
there's no,
there's,
I'm plotting against you,
but they don't know yet.
And this idea that this big grand
conspiracy,
just because it's about fear and ego,
both of those Keller,
but because these patterns and these
patterns that people go down to down
through there just,
they seem real normal.
It seems normal to concentrate on stupid
shit.
It's almost like it's a distraction from
concentrating on the really important
shit that's it's,
it's so comforting.
I'm trying not to clear my throat them.
Fuck it.
Just do it man.
But it's,
it's so comforting to go down those
stupid patterns.
That's what happens when people,
that's how people get obsessed about
things.
They get obsessive,
they start freaking out.
It's like their pattern.
Creating your own distractions.
Like,
listen man,
nobody can work harder to stop you.
Then you want to work hard enough to
make it so just,
just work hard and you'll be,
you're good.
Nobody.
Nobody's like taking that much time out
of their life to stop you like that.
Yeah.
Most of it is in your head.
Most of it's in our head.
Most of it,
and especially comics,
well I guess everybody,
but like have had a good,
has a comic.
I've been in my head,
we all have,
everybody has,
you know frank and Steve and I were
talking about this last night at the
comedy store bar.
We're talking about the difference
between when you're learning how to do
stand up and you kind of like wonder if
this is going
to work again,
this idea like,
Oh God,
is this going to work?
Can I get this to work?
How do I get this to work?
Which is still kind of do as you get
like a better at it or more experienced.
But as you get older it's,
how do I convey why I think this is
funny,
right?
Yeah.
Before I had like no jokes.
Right.
But now I have like concepts of premises
that aren't funny and it's like,
how do I make this funny?
Yeah.
What do I think is funny about this?
How do we get started on this?
We're talking about something I was
going to diverge,
but I forgot what did,
what did we go from,
we went from,
we're going to show the Tom [inaudible]
thing.
We should probably just show that.
That's why I'm so distracted.
This Thomas,
he,
let me just explain it.
This,
we give it,
let me get a little,
uh,
ended up Tom Segura,
our pal is killing it.
And he's been on the road,
he's selling out theaters is killing it
all over the place.
And one of the things that he asked to
do unfortunately is sometimes he has to
do these morning shows.
So if he's trying to sell tickets and
let everybody know that he's in town,
he does morning radio and he'll do these
morning tv shows and when you talk about
like levels of lameness for like
entertainment,
like the morning shows are the most,
it's like,
it's like people think milk is spicy,
you know,
they're just like,
how can you drink a whole milk,
half done water my milk down and put
sugar in it.
It's like the last remnants of Grandma
TV.
It is.
Here are the weirdest shows.
They don't,
they don't bear any resemblance to
anybody that I know that it's that age.
When I see them talking to these young
people,
young,
handsome,
good looking people and you go,
who the fuck are they?
Whose talks like this?
What planet are they from?
Where,
where is this taking place?
You guys are at a time capsule too in
1950s it never really existed.
It's all that media depiction of the,
the Norman Rockwell days.
It's like,
it's like they colorize some old black
and white news footage.
Yeah.
You know,
they're brutal.
They're brutal.
The dew point being,
um,
a morning radio shows usually pretty
fun.
Yeah.
Most of those guys are just trying to
have a good time.
But so tom goes on these morning tv
shows and now he has a character and his
character as a rapper and uh,
he wears,
he's got a Chinchilla scarf on and giant
fat gold rope and he's wearing his
sunglasses with his cincinnati hat on
and he plays his character now and he
just says a bunch of crazy shit.
And to him,
so much more fun than actually like
trying to have a casal.
Tom,
where did y'all start comedy and when
did you know that you were going to be a
funny man instead of that he,
you know,
he does this
announcement,
the big announcement
wanting to make a is the last year,
you know,
uh,
I,
I came out as poly and by,
and now I'm proud to say that,
uh,
I'm non binary.
Why is that interesting?
Is there any,
is there more to this because I'm
confused.
Oh yeah.
Like so most people right fall within
the male and female binary.
And then I'm nonbinary I don't fall into
either one.
You know,
so like I'm actually like fluid binaries
meaning that depending on the moment I
kind of go between different genders.
Interesting.
I like today I'm astral gender right now
I'm a gender from the outer space as to
host.
Could find a door yesterday.
Totally lost.
Listen a little,
whether you're talking giggled threw a
pretty big thing to come out as
nonbinary first we've encountered.
Really?
Yeah.
So that is a big announcement.
It's a big announce that on our show.
Yeah.
I'm happy to share it with everybody.
She actually,
they real like the,
with the chickens at least trying to get
over here.
They are going to be at the comedy zone
tonight.
So what can people expect from you all
on?
Uh,
well,
you know,
we're going to do our thing.
It's a,
it's a whole new hour.
It's,
it's different than mostly stories or
completely normal.
The last to Netflix specialist.
So it's a whole new hour.
And then,
um,
you know,
I'll,
I'll be going from,
from the stage,
like I said,
to spinning records at a local place
for,
for an after show,
maybe doing some recruiting here in the
area too,
right?
Yeah.
I mean,
yeah.
Um,
you know,
I,
I might have time to swing by a
tallahassee,
maybe on Friday,
meet some players and try to sign
somebody else.
But you are a busy guy.
Triple threat,
but in different,
different careers.
I like that.
Come on,
you can catch Tom onstage all weekend at
the Kennedy's down.
Shut up the throat.
Zella okay.
Shown up the throat.
Oh,
Shit.
His throat.
Zillow,
zillow.
No,
no.
Tom Segura is obsessed with black
twitter and uh,
so as Jamie,
so jamie could call you in a better than
anybody,
but throat Zilla is apparently a
prostitute who's famous for oral skills.
And she was in,
and some sort of a paid sexual
experience with a football player who
turned out to be a cheapskate,
didn't want to pay up.
So she blew them up.
And then everybody got to know who
throwed zillow's Zillow as a fucking
hilarious instagram page.
Well we don't need to see what football
part is like.
Let let people do some googling.
Leave the man alone.
He liked getting his ass
wrong with that.
She's got a popular snapchat too,
but she's hilarious.
She's hilarious.
She's actually been a guest on your
mom's house.
Do you ever listen to your mom's house?
I've been on it.
You haven't listened?
Well you listened to the one that you
were on cause you were in it.
You were involved.
You had to be less than right.
So one,
me too.
I've listened to a couple of their clips
though online.
Their fucking shit is hilarious.
They're so funny.
Together they've been pumping up their
youtube channels so they got all their
new podcasts just like we've been doing.
And some clips up there too.
Still killing it out.
Tom Is killing it on the road too.
He's killing it.
It's so nice.
So nice to see a guy who was that
talented.
Just get recognized,
you know.
[inaudible] he's doing dope,
man.
I'm happy for him.
Yeah,
he's a funny fucking dude,
man.
I give him just watching night.
He's just having fun.
Like,
yeah,
you can make anything fun man.
Like you don't want to get up in the
morning to do that shit.
That shit is tiring and he's just,
I,
I'm going to figure out a way to do this
shit.
Yeah,
they're brutal.
Those,
those are the most brutal.
What's also brutal because you know that
you're going to have to like figure out
a way to be awake at eight o'clock for
the show.
Like you can't be sleepy,
you know?
So you know,
you only got like two or three hours
sleep before he got up for this thing
because most of the time,
most comics don't go to bed til like one
or two get up at six,
do this radio thing bleary-eyed and most
of the time it's socks and yeah.
And then you got to kind of be phony to
sometimes,
cause you're,
you're like with a bunch of phony
people.
So it's like this is a great way to not
be phony and make fun of this phony
situation.
Yeah.
But Tom is,
he's figured it out.
I never figured it out.
Right.
I would just go and do them.
Like that guy in the blue shirt full of
shit.
Yeah.
They suppose or at least the girl was
like,
I don't get it.
And she nervously said it but she said
it.
Yeah.
And then she takes another thing she
reacted to like the correct way but
still with a nice morning TV personality
person way.
But at least she was like more honest.
The guy was like,
well that's good to know them.
What the thing that he doesn't even
understand.
Well what he's doing is what they do.
It's that way of talking that you know
that there's a bunch of different fake
ways of talking to people.
Just slide right into like a strip club
Dj.
That's one right.
Top 40 Dj.
That's one coming up next.
All right.
And you know there's a,
there's a way of talking that is exactly
the same and they all,
they all replicated.
Those are two like real big ones.
Yeah.
Newspaper Voice.
Newsman voice.
So News.
Yeah.
There's a way of talking.
What makes people think,
and there's like subtle variations that
even like today's pros use,
there's a style of communication,
lets you know they mean business,
right?
This is very serious.
Very,
very serious.
Yeah.
So these morning guys,
they're like,
they have like Ryan to crest posters up
all over their house and he's the God.
He's the God of that style that Ryan
seacrest nailed it.
He nailed it.
It life.
All he did was [inaudible] name is
talent.
All he does is talk smooth and look
great.
Keeps his hair quaffed like literally
guys made hundreds of millions of
dollars by talking smooth and looking
great.
It's it just being that guy.
Alright,
way to go Janet.
Alright.
Likes everything next to good.
Yeah.
Next two collars.
It's all you have to do.
Just never get negative.
Let it all roll off your back.
When you go home,
you scream into a pillow case.
Ah,
what is this?
Who wants to dress like Ryan's?
He crest a lot of people in New York
magazine.
What are you showing me here?
But he's,
he's got a clover popular clothing line
and then of course it does quote.
Did you hear about what happened with
all senior and or Sinead O'connor?
No.
Somebody told me on the way up I saw
like a photo of him like on a newsfeed
what she's accusing him of given Prince
Percocet,
prince dying of an overdose.
Sinead O'connor is accusing Arsenio Hall
of doing that.
Why would she do that?
Is that true?
First of all,
just because you gave someone a fucking
Percocet,
like a lot of people take percosets and
there's nothing wrong with them.
They're going to be okay,
but she called the feds and said,
I'll call the feds and you better get
your house in order because they're
coming for you.
Like she's basically blaming him for
prince's death.
That's so crazy.
First of all,
he had an addiction to pain pills.
Hall has denied the heinous accusations
and lawsuit.
Despicable fabricated lies.
That's awful.
It's awful and a whole bunch of ways
like it's awful that prince was addicted
to pills.
Right.
I didn't expect that.
I guess he was addicted to pills because
of his hips.
Apparently his hips just fucked up from
all those years of spinning around and
throwing kicks and fucking doing this
hip throw away,
you know,
and he would do those shows.
Man,
he was super active and he was always
just dropping down and do whole splits.
Like that's probably not the best way to
treat your body.
Like a lot of that stuff was super
impressive because it was like real
explosive and now he had spin around
with his guitar and dropped down and do
the splits.
It's like wwe moves
and she has like those wrestlers and
shit.
They go hook too.
When I'm Dave Chappelle had that whole
bit about prince being a really good
basketball player with Charlie Murphy.
It makes sense.
Like of course he is looking at how fast
he is,
like how well he moves when he dances on
stage.
Yeah.
But I guess that Shit just played wreck
havoc on his legs.
Yeah,
that motherfucker was electric man.
Like I was like after he died I was
watching some concert footage and it's
like you makes you feel like you're
there.
He puts on a show man.
Yeah,
he was one of the greats have stopped
one of the all time greats.
I mean when it comes to music,
I mean we were talking about this a on a
recent podcast about a,
I want to be your lover and when that
song came out I was like,
well who is this guy?
It
just,
it just had this completely new sort of
feel to it where you were hoping like I
hope that this this key,
like I remember there's a bunch of
artists that when they came out like
Terence Trent Darby was one of them.
He was one of them where he came out and
his songs were so cool and I was like,
I hope this guy figures this out.
I hope this guy keeps going because some
of these guys,
they'll,
they'll come out with some really cool
songs and a really cool thing and then
it goes away,
which is crazy,
but he's talking about guns and roses
last night because they were one of the
groups that,
all right,
this is going to be around for a long
time for sure.
They,
the next new rolling stones or whatever.
And it says like they just,
they just,
it's more,
it's more of a shock that they didn't
last and that then if they did right,
you know?
Yeah.
And terrorist training job,
he like,
yeah,
he was.
He's one of those short things back
then.
You're like,
some people you heard,
you're like,
there are a one hit wonder and like,
no,
this person is going to be,
yeah.
Sinead O'connor too.
She's one of them.
Yeah.
That bitch was so fucking in is so
fucking talented that you go,
well,
where's her body of work?
Why doesn't she have a hundred albums
out?
Why did she have a million hits?
She's so good when she's on,
you know,
like the early shit when she first came
out you like,
Whoa,
she's,
she's a storm.
Like an electric storm.
Like Jesus Christ,
she was good.
She might be like sensitive or something
happened to her probably getting turned
off from the business or something.
Well,
do you remember when she tore up that
picture of the pope?
Right.
That was a big problem.
I think she wasn't ready for that
negativity that came with that,
that opinion.
That was like 20 years ahead of time.
Yeah,
I know,
man.
She was right.
Isn't that crazy?
Yeah.
If she did that shit today,
people would support her and cheer for
her.
She's a very brave person in that
regard.
Then if she did it today,
they'd be like,
she's a hack.
Yeah.
Then she did it too soon.
It's too original.
Too soon.
There was this kid a long time ago that
had an MTV music video and people were
saying that this kid is the future of
rock and roll.
He was like 19 years old on the um,
he had a song called beat,
so lonely,
fine,
fine.
Who fucking sings that?
But this dude was like a bad ass
guitarist and he was like 19 years old
and it was one of those things where
they were hyping them up.
Yeah.
Charlie sexton.
So if we play this,
it will probably get us kicked off
youtube.
Right.
Played for the audio for people who
this.
Anyway,
this guy was really young and he was
this good looking johnny like s like a
Johnny Depp who does a lot of speed.
It was like this good looking young,
talented guitarist.
And what is it?
What year does it say down there,
Jeremy?
If you scroll down.
Yeah.
Okay.
So this is my senior year in high school
and this guy came out and there was this
crazy black and white music video.
This is the days of MTV,
you know,
so he's walking down this black and
whites treme and inbetween him walk over
this cool look and earrings and his
fucking fonzie leather jacket on.
You see the producer sliding up the
dials on the mixing board and all these
neon signs and you know,
it was so stylish and produced and so
obviously contrived,
but as a 15 what does I 17 I guess.
Yeah,
it's a 17 year old kid watching this.
I remember thinking,
Whoa,
like this guy is a,
it's not that much older than me.
And he's like smoking cigarettes,
hanging out with these rockers
with,
it's not playing in any of this song
yet.
It's just the,
but he like,
his singing is kind of interesting too,
but they put so much effort into this.
It was,
it was one of those things.
It was like,
well they're for sure going to force
feed us this guy
like
present rockstars and make videos like
this now.
Like oh shit.
Yeah,
that's true versions of this that aren't
as good.
This is a pretty good song.
People get mad at me right now.
No,
I'm telling you,
I've really liked this song,
especially when it came out when I was
17 and I thought this fucking guy was
going to be giant.
He had all the right pieces.
He didn't have tattoos back then cause
dude didn't have tattoos.
But if he,
if it was today,
he would have tattoos all over his hands
and shit.
He had some shit on written on his neck,
but he's got all the right bracelets,
his hair like his bracelet,
his hair looks perfect.
So there was,
I want him to listen to this show and
call it something.
Where is he now?
Maybe I'm wrong.
Maybe it's like a giant country star.
There's country stars that you don't
even know about that I'm like fucking
hundreds of millions of sales.
But I just saw that when you show the
image of me,
I realize how high I'm on.
Slow down,
bitch.
Shit,
I'm getting high.
You got to in this room we hotbox Ian
saying it's kind of adversity.
Anybody tells you you can't get hot box
is a fucking liar too,
by the way.
I can tell you that right now.
Somebody trying to tell me the other day
that hotboxing isn't real.
I was like,
what are you talking about?
It's 100% real
breathing in weed.
In a room with his weed.
Smoking weed.
Yeah.
I mean it's not as effective as taking a
hit,
but it's pretty close.
Have you stand there long enough and
it's,
the room is like,
like if this is a lot of weed going
around and the room is small and it's
intense and it's in the air,
that's all you're going to breathe in
all your breathing.
It might be more than taking a few hits
if when out in the street with some
friends.
Did
I ever tell you about when I was a judge
for the cannabis club?
Cannabis Cup.
Cannabis Cup?
Yeah.
I judged the Cannabis Cup one year and
they would hand you,
you know how like um,
old people that I've liked hip injuries,
they carry around a lot of pills.
They'll have like a Monday,
Tuesday,
Wednesday,
Thursday,
Friday,
Saturday when I was little seven tray
things.
This is what they gave you and it was
filled with weed and they were handing
out pipes and lighters and edibles and
it was so ridiculous.
The idea that anybody got judged,
which is so ridiculous because it was me
and a bunch of other people who are
judges like people from the local
cannabis community and I think there was
some wrappers in there as well.
But by the time your on pot number two
like who knows what's happening.
Exactly.
How do you know if three is affecting
you?
It's affecting you or five or one is
don't,
you don't have any idea.
You have to do that.
Each one for a day you do one and then
you'd come back the next day,
do the other one.
And that still might not be enough time.
I think it's 100% right.
And then you also would have to deal
with the fact that if you did it on
Monday,
Tuesday,
well if you did it everyday like that,
your body would get accustomed to
getting high.
Yeah.
So you probably get less high as the
week goes on,
but some people say that they're like
different.
You get accustomed.
Different strength.
That's Joey Diaz though.
Joey Diaz.
Listen dog.
I smoked different shit every day.
I don't want these motherfuckers getting
used to me like he used to meet,
he thinks you get used to certain kinds
of weeds and they don't fact they don't
affect you anymore.
So you got to try new shit.
He might,
he might be on to something though.
I think he's right.
Yeah,
I think he's right too in some sort of a
way.
For sure was like sativas versus in
because there's definitely a different
feeling.
Right?
So what were some of the strains here
you can get out of the story.
You've just,
you can try it.
Just smoke one for a week,
just get a different one.
You're like,
Holy Shit.
Yeah.
You can get cheaper weed instead of
smoking all the top shelf stuff.
What's,
what's fucking me up.
No Sativa or this is a sativa.
Yeah,
this is,
I'll tell you what it's called.
They labeled,
these are all from la speed.
We'd la speed weeds.
The way to go,
ladies and gentlemen,
if you're in Los Angeles,
Los Angeles is the most ridiculous thing
in the world because they're trying to
stop that and they're,
they're trying to stop it and some weird
there some sort of a zoning way.
Like what they're trying to say is
because he's delivering it like where he
selling it becomes a place of business.
So it has to be zoned in a certain way.
Like this is the argument,
which is ridiculous because how would
fast food restaurants deliver?
Like how a domino's deliver,
cause these places aren't zoned for
being restaurants.
Like if someone just shows up at your
house with a pizza,
like your house doesn't have to be zoned
for being a restaurant for him to show
up at your house with a pizza.
But if someone shows up at your house
selling weed and you live next to a
school,
right,
it becomes problematic.
It's interesting.
It's an interesting argument.
It's going to go away because it's
silly,
but um,
it's going to cost a lot of people some
money and probably Gino from lsp weed,
it's going to cost him.
So
this,
it seems like something the city makes
up to try to make some money.
Yeah,
probably,
well maybe it might be someone who is
anti weed who is at the,
at the top,
but I haven't,
I have some friends that are not pot
smokers.
Don't like pot,
don't believe in pot and they're,
you know,
older than me and they,
they'll still hang on to some of these
silly ideas about pot and they'll go,
well you are different,
you know,
to me I go,
oh,
I'm different.
Like what are you talking about that I'm
like,
90% of potheads are like me.
Like it's the ones who stand out are the
ones that are the outliers.
It's the ones with the dirty fee and the
fucking,
the macrame clothes and you know,
playing fucking,
what is that thing that you've kicked
the ball with your foot hacky sack.
Yeah.
It's funny.
It's like when you belong to a group,
there's always an annoying section of
that group that makes you not want to
belong to that group of customers.
That's where the black people or gay
people,
a certain type of gay people,
like other gay people like can't stand
because it might give gay people a bad
look and they say same thing with weed
and then then somebody who's against
that thing completely meets you.
Like I've been,
you know like when I was a teenager or
white people got,
you're different than other black guys,
which was an insult for sure.
That's like in the social justice
warrior handbook or how not to talk to
black guys.
Exactly.
It's,
it's almost as bad as saying,
Nigga,
but you're telling me I'd rather you
call me nigger at that point
because now you're telling me I'm not
black enough.
Right.
I'm saying right.
And first of all,
you don't know any other black people
were working at Burger King.
I'm the first one you met,
so you're only listing.
The only thing you know about black
people is what you see on the news.
So then you and you meet me and you
don't feel threatened.
Then you're like,
you're not like other black guys,
but I'm the only black person you know.
You live in a all white neighborhood.
I'm working in an all white neighborhood
burger king.
That's hilarious.
True.
That's why one of the reasons why New
York City is such a good place to live
because everybody integrates,
right?
Because New York City,
everybody's on the subway,
everybody's walking on the street and
everybody's around.
Everybody.
One of the weird things about la in
general is that it's a car culture and
you were in your little isolated box and
you drive to your little isolated
community and then you go back and forth
from work to wherever you hang out and
those are your spots and you don't
interact with other people like face to
face,
person to person on a daily basis.
Just the best thing about New York.
Yeah.
Cause that trey,
man,
everybody's on that track.
All kinds of people,
because even if you're rich enough to
take,
take a taxi,
it's traffic up there.
The train is still the fastest place.
Fastest way to get somewhere.
The only way it's mixed,
man.
It's good.
It's V it's super important too,
because one of the things that I think
everybody who I know who used to be
poor,
we,
Ron White and I were talking about this
the other night,
like when,
when you're,
when you haven't made it,
you always feel like it's never gonna
happen,
right?
You always feel like it's completely out
of touch.
Like,
I'm poor.
I'm always going to be poor.
This fucking struggles never gonna go
away.
But when you're around people who used
to be poor too,
but they figured out how to do it,
you go,
oh,
they're just a fucking person.
You know?
And when you see some dude and he's on
some corner office and some giant ass
building and he's a ceo of that company,
you can't imagine that at one point in
that guy's life he was fucked up.
Like at one point in his life,
he's depressed and lost and failing in
school and couldn't figure it out.
Right.
You know,
and was wondering about his future,
but almost everybody has lows.
What's everybody has almost every
successful person that I've ever met had
some crazy adversity early on.
They figured their way through that and
then they figured out how to become
successful parsley even because of that.
So when you're on like a train and
everybody's all together,
then I think it's the one of the best
sort of ways to keep that separation
that us and them separation with like
the classes especially because that's a
real fucking mindset of rich people and
a real mindset of poor people that
they're just,
there's two different groups of us,
but it's so stupid.
It's not it,
it's just a bunch of people and they're
on the same journey that you're on in a
different direction.
Just maybe a little bit further down the
road,
right.
Or maybe they didn't stop as many times
as you did.
Maybe they didn't get flat tires.
Maybe they didn't have as many potholes
in the road,
but they're all,
we're all just on this fucking same
thing.
We're all just people.
And so when you look at some dude,
you know and you're poor and you got
holes in your sneakers and some guys get
a rolex on and he's wearing this
expensive suit and he's got cuff links
and he's checking his newspaper and
Reading The Wall Street Journal and you
look at is expensive shoes like this
motherfucker's got some money,
man.
How the hell did he do that?
And I'm here a loser.
He just did it.
He's just,
he's just a person just like,
right.
You don't,
you don't know.
He never look at it as a origin story.
Yeah.
Just look straight at Batman doing doing
this shit.
Exactly.
You know,
see what he had to go through too.
You know.
It's a good point and learn all that
shit to way to put it.
And you want to,
you want to get there.
Yeah.
You want to get there,
but it seems like it's impossible.
Yeah.
Speaking of getting there,
I tried to watch soccer last night.
Oh yeah.
I was going to bring that up.
People tweeted me that you're watching
soccer.
I might invite you to a game on Sunday
at the,
I got the galaxy,
this is mother's Day.
Mother's Day.
Oh,
shit happen.
I can't do it.
But yeah.
What happened?
Why?
Well,
it was at the store and uh,
we were hanging out in the secret
comedians bar and soccer was on,
so we just started watching it.
Just started watching that shit.
Who had that on?
Ryan White was watching it.
I was watching that.
Some of the employees were watching it.
Yeah.
Um,
who else was in there with us?
Tony was watching it at one point,
but I started getting upset if these
dudes getting slapped and going down,
like that guy hit with a media.
I didn't like that.
I'm like,
I just support this kind of nonsense.
You watching a really good game.
Yeah.
You were really watching a really good
game.
Yeah,
it was amazing.
Like skill wise,
bye and Munich and the red,
they're the best German team and this is
a champion's league game so I didn't
know how to explain it.
Champions League is square,
the four best teams in each league in
each country like playing a tournament
to to be the best club team in Europe.
So Byron is is like the number one team
in Germany.
Athletical they're like number two,
number three right now.
They actually in number that number two
spot right now,
but last year they finished maybe second
or third at the end there they have less
money but their coaches are ex Argentina
player and he figured out a system where
they just hustle.
They just out hustle you,
you get the ball and there's three
motherfuckers on you and you're going to
cough it up and they're going to get it.
And they all score one or two goals game
and that's enough.
But you know,
and buying is just so really skilled
that they might be able to,
they beat most teams,
but athletics is just so disciplined
that you know,
they,
they knocked them out and they're,
they're going to the Champions League
final versus Real Madrid.
So there's two Spanish teams in the
champion's league final and both of them
are from the same city.
So it's like the Lakers versus the
clippers for like the best.
The,
the championship of w w what,
what are we in like the up North America
blip when we do it in North America,
we call it the world championships.
We call it the what the NBA is the world
championship.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Like just cause it's all the best
players in the world,
right?
Yeah.
No,
I understand.
But like when they do it in the World
Cup,
it actually is the world is the world.
Yeah.
It is the world because there's not
really any competition coming over from
Europe trying to play against the
Lakers.
Right.
It's just not really going to happen.
They're not going to have a team that
they develop overseas that can compete
with an la,
like basketball has this thing where I
think they have like all the North
American Dab a tournament where all the
like Brazil and,
and like all the,
we in North America,
all the North American teams.
So it's really asset.
Listen man,
you were born in another country just
been hot,
boxed.
I don't know what the fuck is that
just be hot.
Hotbox so,
so yeah,
like,
like all the countries play around this
area,
around this area,
play against each other.
And I guess America normally wins.
But this is,
this is,
this is a big tournament man.
Yeah.
This is the,
the actual whole world.
I know.
That's what I want.
What I was thinking like are there any
sports with the United States competes
with the whole world and does well in
soccer?
No.
In any other sport.
Yeah.
Well,
it just say the difference in this too
is what you're thinking.
I guess maybe World Cup,
his team teams for countries,
right.
This is,
uh,
teams for professional clubs.
Teams are owned and that like,
so these teams wouldn't necessarily play
the United States.
They would play like the Columbus crew
or the good la Galaxy.
They're not on the same skill level.
So it would be a really bad game when
someone says like Manchester United,
that's a club.
It's a club that's like the Yankees,
the Yankees in soccer in England.
But when you would think of,
so they would play against a bunch of
other different,
they also,
there's Real Madrid basketball team and
they wouldn't want to play against like
any NBA team cause they would get
destroyed the same way they would beat
our soccer teams.
But the United States play Spain and
like World Cup type competition.
And we also have something like that
where it's a conch,
a calf and it's like United States
versus Mexico versus some of the smaller
a Latin American country.
What I was getting at was is there a
sport where the United States is
competitive in a world stage?
Like a sport?
Whereas yeah,
like basketball we're usually like,
yeah,
but we don't,
the world doesn't play basketball.
The problem with us being competitive at
basketball.
It's like someone over here being a
cricket champion.
Nobody gives a fuck if you go to Greece
or Turkey or Spain,
they have,
they have their version of the MBA,
right?
They have their version of the NBA,
but the those teams and those plays are
not as good as ours and they come from
all different countries and then when
you,
when it's time for you to play for your
country,
you're still not as good as American and
it,
and,
and that's when in the Olympics they
have a world championship for
basketball,
for real,
I think.
And they have the Olympics,
which is like the one that everybody
pays attention to the Moose.
That's where all the countries get
together and play basketball.
But isn't it fascinating that
there's a clear winner as far as like
who is the best still when,
what is basketball really?
It's moving your feet,
which everybody knows how to do.
Throwing a ball,
which most people know how to do
dribbling and then learning how to get
super awesome at all of those skills.
Right.
That doesn't seem like,
it's not like something where someone
has to teach you some master strategist
who's like the greatest snow world has
to teach you.
Like it's almost like a form of
expression,
right?
It's like why are Americans so much
better at it?
I think,
I don't know.
It's like in soccer Brazil,
like I've been trying to ask myself the
saint cause why is Brazil so good at
soccer?
They love it.
You know,
they,
they but it's a lot of countries around
the world love it,
but they have like five world cup
championships.
Well maybe six.
Germany's good.
Yeah.
Zyl has a great history of soccer,
like with Palae of course.
But they also have a great history of
like nationalism and competitive
athletics.
Like thinking about how many Brazilian
mma champions they are.
I mean there's so many.
Brazil,
Roger,
Gracie,
just one,
one fc last night.
So there's a Brazilian champion.
Like there's so many Brazilian
champions.
He choked out some dude in one FC,
which is the Asia version of the UFC.
Right?
It's just getting bigger and bigger.
This a bunch of like really big
organizations overseas now there that
are starting to build up momentum.
But if you look at like martial arts
champions from Brazil,
Jesus Christ,
there's so many of them,
so many in the UFC,
so many former champions,
so many elite high level fighters.
Like there's a card next weekend in
Brazil and it's all like the killers of
the killer of people,
like in Brazilian champions in Vitor
Belfort versus Jocker Ray Anderson
Silva's fighting Uriah Hall.
Oh my God.
It's incredible.
There's so,
there's so much super high level talent
that came out of Brazil,
Brazil,
Uriah Faber.
Yeah,
you're right.
No,
you mean Ryan Hall.
Oh,
okay.
You're right.
Halls black.
He's from Jamaica,
I believe.
Oh,
that big monster do too.
Oh yeah.
Robot dark.
It's cold.
Fucking lightning fast.
He's one of my favorites.
That dude is,
he's such a nice guy too.
That's the thing about in the him,
he like,
he,
he made some like really heartfelt
statement once after one of his fights.
Uh,
you know about people getting along.
And I was like,
this guy is like legit.
Like this is really him.
He's such a nice guy.
That's almost been one of the things
that held him back.
Like Dana White did criticized him of it
and he said he's so talented but he's
almost too nice for fighting.
I don't think that's true.
I think he's just needs more fights and,
but he's got a big one with Anderson
Silva.
It's a big like crossroads fight.
It shows where Anderson's at.
Cause if Anderson can get past Uriah,
who's one of the best 185 pounders alive
right now.
You're right.
Is a lightening fast.
Reiker I'm picturing your riot and he
feels bigger than,
and this,
no,
he's more muscular for sure.
He's built way better.
He's,
he's probably faster,
which is crazy.
But you know,
this is,
we're talking about Anderson Silva at 40
years old versus Anderson Silva at like
34.
But uriah is,
um,
he's like got traditional martial arts
skills at a super,
super high level.
Like he does a lot of stuff like
spinning back kicks and wheel kicks and
knocks guys out with them in real high
level.
Guys like he hit gay garden was saucy.
There's Uriah,
he hit gay guy who saucy with a spinning
back kick to the face.
And it was a fight that we were calling
for fight companion.
And my thoughts on him,
I was like,
I'm telling you this guy can do things
in these explosive movements and I'm,
I'm like,
I'm so used to seeing people move.
You know what I'm so used to seeing the
way people throw kicks and the way
people throw punches when someone's
movements stand out,
like,
Ooh,
Jesus Christ.
Like they've got it honed down to uh,
a razor's edge with just lightening
precision.
It just really stands out.
And that's your riot hall.
Uriah Hall has these movements.
Occasionally we'll,
he'll just drop a right hand on
someone's channy.
You just go,
whoa.
There's like that guy was not moving
like that by the time that punch got to
him.
But he had no idea that punch was
coming.
I mean,
his,
his ability to close the distance with a
shot,
it's so fucking scary.
So it's an interesting fight in that
regard and I don't think it has,
does it have their age there?
Why are they hiring the age will be a
little girls kind of shit.
Is that show your fucking age?
Well that's great.
How,
how,
why would they have all these different
things?
I was looking for height too.
Oh,
okay.
So this is one,
this is the stats.
They have the reach and they have the
weight and then they have the height.
I was always amazed how Anderson Silva's
body does not match his record.
Well,
the Anderson Silva when he was in his
prime,
looked a little bit better than that,
but he's,
uh,
his body is a really good body for
fighting because in fighting,
like say a guy like uriah hall might be
able to punch 10 or 15% harder than
Anderson.
Like who knows?
I mean,
he hits really fucking hard,
let's say Ken,
but if Anderson hits him,
the 90% that Anderson can come up with
is just as good.
The clean shots are the most important
thing and it doesn't take like a giant
bomb to knock you out.
Right?
A giant bomb can knock you out,
but it doesn't take a giant bomb to
knock you out.
What it takes is a shot you don't see
common and a perfectly placed shot and
Anderson is the master at perfectly play
shots.
He's the master.
He's the ultimate sniper.
Out of all the guys that have ever
fought in the UFC,
he impresses me the most with his
ability to land these highlight reel
shots on people.
Highlight reel with James Irvin.
He caught James Irvin's kick and just
caved his face in with a punch.
The guy threw a kick anish and caught it
and bub boom.
You can see the dude had never been here
like that before.
He goes down and Anderson just uncorked
a couple more on them.
It opens him up.
When he fought vetoer,
he front kicked Vitorin the face.
It was like the perfect front kick knock
out and it was the first ever front kick
knock out in the,
in the history of the UFC.
Nobody had ever done it before and he
did it in a high level world
championship fight against Vitor
Belfort.
It's crazy because it's,
it's the first kick you learn in martial
arts.
It's like the first kick,
you learn how to do a front kick and
nobody,
everybody goes at that shit doesn't
work.
You got to go with the Brown house.
Anderson lands it right on his face and
this one's a free ass dude.
You think he's a,
is he back?
He's 40.
So whatever back is,
he's not going to be the same back.
Um,
but if you look at a guy like Bernard
Hopkins,
Bernard Hopkins,
who's an incredibly skillful technical
boxer,
it's still at this day.
Like there's a video of him working out
the other day.
He was hitting mitts.
He looks fucking great.
He's 50 years old.
Like Bernard Hopkins Right now at 50
years old could get in the ring and
school solid.
50% of the professional light
heavyweights in the world would look
ugly.
Gold them.
You hold the shit out of you,
hold the Shit Out of you,
Jab your fucking face off.
You know,
moving weird ways up or you know,
step on your toes,
upset your balance Mug and the corner.
Yeah.
Hit you with like short,
short,
hard punches while he's clenching you,
annoy you and getting your head get you
out of your game or a bomb you out.
Like he did Felix Trinidad,
that Philly's trend.
Dad Fight.
He put on a show with Felix Trinidad.
I was always a big Bernard Hopkins Fan.
So when he fought Trinidad and fucked
him up for me,
it was like I knew it.
I was surprised.
I thought the Felix was the truth,
you know,
while he was for a moment.
But I don't think he,
I don't want to say,
I don't think he respected Bernard.
I don't think he knew how good Bernard
really was.
I think he was doing so well and
Trinidad was such a world beater and
just such a tough dude.
I just,
I think he thought he could get through
anything.
I think,
you know,
he was one of those guys that,
I can,
I'm going to get through everybody.
Everybody,
I mean,
he's been to war before he's been
tagged.
Come about knock guys out.
But Bernard was on,
on nother level that night.
Yeah.
I've never seen anybody like Bernard
cause so it's not traditional boxing
like somebody who does that.
It doesn't get as far as him.
Right?
Like I've never seen somebody and do it
that much.
Well he's a master.
He's a real master.
If you watch his footwork and in the in
the ring it's always measured.
It's always under control.
He always knows exactly what he's doing
and what he doesn't know exactly what
he's doing.
He resets,
he's not whinging anything.
He's not taking any stupid chances.
What was that dead dude he beat for the
title at 49 years of age was his fucking
young stud.
This guy was like 32 years old,
some Russian dude,
bad motherfucker.
And he dropped him.
Bernard dropped him at 49 years of age
and people like God and then he fought
Kovalev and that was the fight that
showed.
There's a difference between the highest
of the high level right now.
And we're,
Bernard is right now with his life being
49 years old cause Coleville that was
just too much for him.
And Bernard went into a shell and just
fought real defensively and tried to
survive,
but Kovalev was opening up on him.
Kovalev it's fucking scary.
That guy's the real deal.
It's not a bad ass fucking Russians.
He's days.
I know.
It must be tougher than rush her.
Right?
It's got to be tough.
It's going to be tough on Russia.
They getting all the boxes like this is
like the sport where like a lot of
sports,
a lot of poor people come out and they
get to the top of it.
You could tell where poor,
where the poorest people are based on
who's the best boxers in the world.
Like Russia must be rough right now.
That's a real good point.
You know?
That's how it always worked in America
too.
It's like that's why Jews were a lot of
boxers in the early days of the early
part of the 12th century when Jewish
slappy Maxie Rosenbloom.
I was a dude.
You could not have that as a box name
right now.
You could be silly.
It's silly,
but nobody would take you serious.
Slappy maxims.
One of the top featherweight in the UFC.
Andre Fili,
his,
his nickname,
his Andre Touchy feely and
he's a fucking weird ass name.
He's
a fun dude though.
He's a fun,
yeah,
it's fun with it.
Yeah.
That's hilarious.
Yeah,
man,
it's,
um,
it's interesting how that APP works that
way.
It's,
and then it was the Italians.
There was a lot of Italians like rocky
Marciano,
rocky Graziano.
There's a lot of,
you know,
I'm from Irish.
Yeah,
yeah.
A lot of Irish,
a lot of immigrants.
It's immigrants that are poor.
People that need to learn how to fight
to survive.
Literally fight to survive.
You know?
That's one of the reasons why these
Russians are so fucking tough,
man.
They're coming from a harder place.
It's a harder world.
And you know,
they're just like Coleville Lev is a
straight up killer.
He's seated in his eyes when he's in the
rankings,
scared as shit.
He's just gonna fuck you up.
You know?
And then the Gennady Golovkin he's
another one.
Everybody's scared of that fucking what
the what weight class?
I haven't watched boxing.
He's won 60.
I used to be my thing,
but he's a middleweight champ.
He fucks everybody up and everybody sees
a hundred percent undefeated and he's
knocked everyone out.
I think he had one fight,
the one the distance or a couple,
maybe a couple of fights and went the
distance,
but he's on some ridiculous knockout
streak in a row.
I should know that for short.
Pull that up.
Gennady Golovkin triple g,
just a triple g record.
I'm just impressed.
You can say his name so smoothly while
he's got a second name that I can't,
if there's a triple g,
it's [inaudible] something,
something,
something Golovkin the middle one.
I don't even try with that,
but he's,
he's a fucking assassin mad.
His name sounds like when you fall
asleep on your keyboard and then you
wake up and to see a bunch of letters or
the other.
All chaos.
Okay.
Unanimous decision.
There we go.
And that's way back in 2008 he had a
unanimous decision win,
but he's got a couple of you,
man.
You know what I was decisions three
there that I say,
so he's on a streak of like how many,
how many cables in a row?
One,
two,
three,
four,
five,
six,
seven,
eight,
nine,
10 1112 there's a lot 21 kaos no.
What's funny about this chart like to
see the flags from different countries
that people he's knocked out.
Yeah.
It's funny,
right?
You know,
knocked out a lot of people from a lot
of places.
He's so next level.
He fought dominick wade and his last
fight.
Jesus Christ,
man.
Hey,
fuck that dude up.
He's so next level.
So dangerous man.
At one point in the fight he dropped his
hands and he was letting Wade Punch him.
Oh Shit.
He was just moving his head as wade was
punching him and then he uncorked bombs
on him.
He's a terrifying guy.
Can you looks like a little cutie pie?
I give it.
See what he looks like.
No,
go to go to a picture of him.
Look at him.
He's a cutie
baby.
He's a baby face assassin.
He's like the real baby faced assassin.
Like that guy looks like a straight up
qt.
It's like a handsome young man.
Innocent as a handsome young man with
fine manners.
He dresses rails well dress almost a
mine.
Just like a mime kind of French.
Meanwhile,
that dude is probably a direct
descendant of the [inaudible] goal.
That's probably what it is.
Like no bullshit.
Russians like Russia was occupied by the
Mongols for 200 years,
and a lot of these guys like Russell
Salon provide knockoff who's going to be
on the podcast soon with [inaudible]
curse on.
Yeah,
they're gonna come on together.
That should be fun.
That fucking dude grew up in like
Siberia.
He was eating raw moose.
He ate raw meat until he was like 25
years old.
He had never had cooked meat.
His family,
Raw Moose is Jesus Christ providing a
cough is a fucking,
and now he looks like he ate ramen
Moose.
Yeah,
he did.
But I mean,
this is a guy who is a another one,
probably a direct descendant of the
Mongols.
There was so many fucking super
warriors.
It came out of that DNA.
And you look at a guy like providing a
cough.
I mean,
he just screams like ancient warrior
DNA.
I mean,
to look at him,
look at his face and the way he fights.
You got to hit that dude with a fucking
crowbar to hurt him.
He engages in wars with these people.
I got to get back into boxing that Lucas
[inaudible] fight was insane.
Providing the coughing.
My Tsa just teed off on each other and
you just,
TSA is a brutal knockout puncher and
when he was hitting,
providing a cough,
you were like,
how was he absorbing these shots?
He's absorbed shots at Matisa was able
to put everybody else away with like
look at that shot.
Boom.
Matissa like it's a weird,
like you look at the guy and you say,
okay,
obviously it looks like he's in shape.
He looks athletic but he doesn't look
like a big power puncher.
Right?
Like if you look at him,
he's not like,
he's not built like Marvin Hagler,
Mike Tyson or something like that.
He's a more smooth and it's,
it's,
it just shows you that punching power is
a really weird thing.
And it's not saying that Matisa is in
any way unfit.
He's very fit,
very strong,
very good athlete.
But his punching power is almost just
like skeletal.
It like comes from his frame.
And some sort of a strange way,
and this is,
there's a bunch of guys that are like
that.
This is kidney,
UFC,
his name's Mike MacDonald and he's like
that like go to Mike McDonald.
This kid is a murderous puncher,
but if you look at him,
you,
you look,
he looks like a no,
like a regular kid,
like a regular like athlete and some
people you expect them,
when you look at them body,
you're like,
this person is probably going to hit
hard.
This kid and I don't,
he's a sweet face,
goofy face.
Ziff he'd get a picture of his whole
body just standing there.
You'd get a sense of like,
it means obviously a good athlete,
but you're like right.
There was good example.
He's obviously get out,
but his punching power is disturbing.
It's disturbing.
Lucky bloke,
he fucking cracks guys with shots and
you see the look on their face and like,
what in the fuck?
What is going on with this dude's hands?
He just hits so fucking hard and with so
much precision.
He's nasty on the ground too.
He's a real threat.
This kid and he's super young.
I think he's only like 23 yeah.
You already fought for the title.
He lost a brow and a crazy fight.
But a fight where it really got here
really got tested,
really showed what he's capable of the,
but the body thing,
it's very strange,
but it makes a person,
you never know.
Yeah.
It's weird.
Like punching power is different than
almost any other kind of athletic power.
Like you don't see it coming.
Like if you see someone who has a big
ass and fucking giant quads and they
were on the starting block,
like I bet that fucking dude can ride,
you know?
But you see a guy like Mcdonald's and
you wouldn't necessarily go,
I bet that guy can fucking punch.
Where's Uriah hall that both murderers
punches.
But you're right hall,
you see it and you let go.
Obviously that guy can punch.
Look at him.
You'd be most surprised if he couldn't.
Yeah.
And there are guys like that too,
which is weird.
There's posters you'll be able to,
you know?
Yeah.
It's like seeing a seven foot center,
you know,
like nobody like daisy sanders in the
NBA.
Like,
oh,
he's seven feet and they sucked from the
data with drafted.
But every team year after year,
we'll still put them on the team because
he's seven feet.
Maybe this is the year,
12 years in when he's going to do the
seventh
foot ship and he'd never do it.
But they make all this money because
they built like this.
They should be able to do seven foot
shit or,
or people are built like there's
supposed to be able to hit and they just
can't.
So do they get a guy like that and they
say,
well,
we're gonna,
we're gonna take him in and then we're
going to get our coaches on him.
We're going to show this guy had reached
its full potential.
And then they just don't through the
season and say,
oh,
I see why the other train teams dropped
him and we stuck putting on the bench.
You get stuck with him on the bench.
We're bringing me once in a while with
the guy that big.
Is it just difficult to move their body?
Right?
They say that,
but like Shaq did it.
Shaq was,
his movement was amazing.
Like almost small forward like,
well,
some of the shit that he used to do and
I came along Jeewan moved well and uh,
they was Robinson movie.
Well there was a lot of,
there's a lot there.
There was some,
there's some,
some,
uh,
some tea.
Like,
I don't know,
there's,
there's a lot of centers that could
move.
So when they say it's tough to move your
body,
I don't get it.
It is,
it is rare.
Like good centers are rare.
So I guess maybe it is,
but when you see the ones that do it,
it makes you wonder,
it makes you look down on the people
that can't like him.
I'm seven feet.
I'm thinking I could do some stuff,
I could be decent enough.
But there's some guys that are seven
feet and they really don't do anything
except be seven feet.
Hmm.
Now is it a benefit just having the big
guy there because they can do things and
block people and get in the way and make
it difficult for the other team to,
to use their offense?
Yeah.
It's,
it's a mentality.
It's like they always say you can't
teach height.
Okay,
that makes sense.
And then it was like the eighties and
the nineties was like the center game.
So everybody just felt more secure with
a center,
you know?
Right.
So they would plan their strategy around
the,
the tall guy,
the tall guy.
Yeah.
Because he couldn't get the ball above
people.
He has more like,
especially the way that they're throwing
the ball down at people instead of like
up and down.
Right.
He could probably do some stuff as far
as I get in the way,
get his physical body to block people,
but sometimes they're not even good
enough to do that.
And then they have to get rid of her for
real.
Like I said,
let's get this guy.
He'll do the least and then they don't
even do the least.
Do you think
that's because they're lazy?
Um,
because it was always easy for them
cause they were always so big.
And so like as throughout their career
they were,
oh,
they always had a giant height
advantage.
Being transgender.
Like you're five foot four person born
in the 74 person's body.
You know what I'm saying?
Like like you're not supposed to be
there.
He's supposed to be doing something
else.
It just got stuck with this basketball
frame.
Like some people just can't do it.
So some people they got stuck with a
basketball frame but they don't have a
basketball mind or heart or heart.
Yeah,
you have to like want to move your body
in very difficult ways.
Right.
Because I want have met like one of the
things that you notice about fighters in
particular,
like um,
you ever seen that guy a chocolate tito
fight?
No.
Self believes flyweight what way does he
champion?
I watched him fight the other day.
Awesome boxer,
amazing counter fighter,
but so light and so small like mighty
mouse in the UFC.
It's probably a better example because
mighty mouse fights at 125 pounds and
he's the best in the world.
Like no one can fuck with it.
Did Not just the best in the world at
one 25.
He's the best in the world.
Hands down.
There's no argument anymore.
After his last fight where he destroyed
Henry Hutto.
Everybody just lifts her hands up and
go.
He's the best,
he's the best,
but he's 125 pounds and he way he moves.
I always wonder my cocoon,
a 200 pound guy move like that.
Could it two 55 pound guy move like
that?
Is it even possible like can we get like
when you look at the,
the super athletes that are in the nfl
and I think we can all agree the most
explosive,
best athletes are in the NFL.
Right?
Agreed.
Pretty close.
I mean I think there's probably some
really high level guys in mma at this
point,
but I think that overall the most
explosive high level athletes are in
the,
in the NFL.
If you can get one of those nfl top
guys,
could you teach him to move like mighty
mouse if you started with him at a young
age or is it a gravity thing?
Is it that the 125 pound guy,
he can just do stuff with his joints and
his movement that the 260 pound guy just
physically his body can't keep up.
You know,
you know what the issue is.
It's like if you're little,
you know your little from your little
from you,
from your young person,
so you,
you live little,
you move little right and you act
little.
If you're big then you know you're big
and there's certain things you just
don't gravitate to doing because it
doesn't fit your size of your big.
So you see it's crazy.
You almost have to convince hypnotize a
big dude that's your little and make
them like live little move like a little
person,
like a little person like and get used
to it and then it becomes natural like
mighty mouse moves.
Like I'm little.
If I,
if I,
he fights like if he's fighting a bully
in high school,
like I can't let that guy grabbed me.
I got to keep moving like a big guys
like let this motherfucker grabbed me,
you know what I'm saying?
I want you to grab me.
So you fight,
they fight big.
It's like,
yeah,
it's just a mentality.
That's an excellent way of putting it.
That's an actual,
I think you're totally right.
I think you're totally right because we
all like do things according to just our
physical makeup,
you know?
Sure.
Yeah.
But I wonder if you could get a guy at a
young age,
like do you know the story of marvel
renovation and Todd Marinovich,
todd Marinovich,
todd Marinovich who was a famous
football player and his dad marve was a
famous strength and conditioning coach
and,
and a coach,
a football coach.
So his dad took todd from the time it
was really little.
I had a meeting only healthy food,
no sugar,
working out like crazy.
Put them through all the drills and
turned him into this like super athlete.
But he rebelled because it was just like
too much pressure and work.
They didn't want to do it.
Who's doing it for his dad?
Then he bounced.
We want to quit any went drugs and
unhealthy.
Yeah.
Drugs unhealthy became an artist or
maybe it's healthy now,
I think,
hopefully.
Right.
But it's interesting.
It's a,
it's an interesting thing.
Like this guy grabbed his young son from
the time he was a baby and had him doing
any strength drills and can coordination
drills like raised him with the idea of
turning them into this and the results
were amazing.
So you wonder,
like if someone could take a guy like a
Herschel Walker for Herschel Walker is
one of the perfect example.
Yeah,
one of the best examples because
Herschel actually fought mma Herschel,
but he felt like a big man.
He fucked dudes up to it.
He did it in his late forties.
He was legitimately a threat or good.
Um,
he was very good for the class that he
was fighting in,
but he was fairly recent to mma,
but along a lifelong martial artists
like Hershel Walker,
even back in the days when he was in the
NFL,
had some sort of a black belt in
something.
You look at him,
man.
I think in that picture he was like 47.
Jesus Christ.
Say he always looked young and gooden
and shaping.
I don't understand what's going on.
I mean,
that shit doesn't even make any sense
because he looks like he's as big as he
was when he was playing professional
football.
Who lied to bear heads.
Yeah,
I'll kill you with my bare hands and
said,
hey,
he's on top of this dude ground and
pounded them.
And on top of that he trained at a world
class gym and he went to Aka and he
trained in American kickboxing
association,
which is where that's tyron woodley,
bro.
Don't get racist.
Ami Dairy.
Just mixing up black man.
Yeah.
You're mixing black people together.
Jamie,
dare you google.
It's Google.
It's not Jamie's Google,
sorry.
Google's racists.
But Herschel Walker when he was,
um,
when he was training was training with
Cain Velasquez when Kane was the champ
or if it came,
wasn't a champion,
was one of the best and world.
I don't,
I'm pretty sure he was a champ though.
And he was training with Daniel Cormier,
I believe,
was it there at the time?
Luke rockhold.
Kyle Kingsbury.
I mean he's training with like,
John Fitch was there.
He's trained with like legit worldclass
mixed martial artists,
legit guys.
And he was just fucking doing it like a
real pro athlete would do it.
He wasn't doing it like,
Hey,
I'm a celebrity former football player.
I'm just going to kind of,
I'm going to take a fight like a Jose
can say call might.
Do you know what I mean?
Like you ever see,
I saw Jose psychos like celebrity boxing
matches and shit.
It's like,
come on.
It's like kind of,
he kind of barely did.
Not Herschel Herschel like when at it
like a real professional martial artists
and strike force had him fight a few
times.
He did that Olympic bobsled stuff for
awhile to Africans.
Right.
He just stays out too.
But he's an unbelievable athlete,
right?
Like he's,
he's a rare Bo Jackson type athletes.
An outlier.
An outlier amongst professional
outliers.
Yeah.
So if you could take a Herschel Walker
and train him,
like get him to a guy like Matt Hume who
trained mighty mouse and train him from
the time he's a young man,
like 1514 years old.
Fuck yeah,
he can do it.
He could do it.
It's him back in the day.
Yeah.
Handsome bastard.
Rocking a strong,
strong gold chains getting bitches and
bitches shown scars off Google Vogue.
I heard something like,
I forgot how much,
how many pushups he does a day or
something and saying,
yeah,
something saying that he still does it.
Yeah.
Well I guess if you just keep doing it,
you know your body stays like that.
It just requires unbelievable
discipline.
Skip days.
He's also real weird man.
He has um,
what's called trauma induced multiple
personality disorder.
Oh Shit.
Believe that's how he describes it.
But Trauma,
I'm not sure they're mean.
They mean head trauma.
I think it's more like childhood trauma,
but I'm sure head trauma doesn't help.
Yeah,
because for sure there was some head
trauma.
I mean,
he was one of the greatest football
players of all time.
Right.
I mean,
think about,
if you made a list,
and I'm not a football fan,
but if I know you and you never got
arrested and he never raped anybody,
he must be pretty fucking awesome.
You know what I mean?
Like if it wasn't some giant controversy
where you're involved in like a ray rice
type situation and the murderer or
something like that.
If it wasn't that,
and I hear about you,
he was so good that the cowboys traded
him
for a completely new football team that
won three superbowls.
That's how good he was.
That's incredible.
It's incredible.
Like it was crazy when they were going
to trade horse or walk and it's like
you're going to treat it Herschel
Walker,
but they got a brand new team and a set
of young players that ended up being
like their,
their franchise.
But he,
you know,
that's how good he was at.
Think you get all those players.
Yeah.
It's,
it's always,
to me as someone who analyzes athletics,
it's always so confusing and,
and,
and interesting when I see someone who
is just so much better than everybody
else,
right?
Like how the fuck is he so much better?
Like what is it?
Right?
This is,
this is a soccer thing.
I'm going to tell you to stop the thing.
So,
so you have the NBA,
right?
Right.
And that's the,
that the NBA is the basketball league of
America and England,
the top league,
the soccer version of Mbas called the
premise ship,
right premiership premiere ship here.
So there's this team named Lester.
Now the premiership works different than
the NBA,
all the teams stay the same every year
in soccer.
The bottom three tickets,
20 teams in the league,
and the bottom three would go down if
we'd go down to the league below at the
end of the year.
Like if you have those least amount of
points that the team three teams or at
least go down and there's a league below
where the teams that first finished
first,
second and third come up.
So that's important because lester
is a team last year that almost got
relegated to the league below.
So they almost got relegated.
It was like everybody's like this team
is going down to the lower division,
so they,
they want to maybe five or six games in
a row towards the end of the season and
stayed up.
Right.
But they're on a low budget team.
They keep the same players and they had
to fire the coach for,
cause his son did something and they got
this other guy named cloudy or rainy
area,
an old Italian coach that used to coach
and England would want at the top teams
but he never won anything.
He only came second.
So then all year he's coaching Leicester
and they're winning.
You know,
they went in but at the beginning of
every soccer season you always the lower
teams always when a little,
and then there's the,
the the championship like stages of the
season,
like the,
the second part of season,
the third and like the final forthwith
team starts slipping or less.
That doesn't slip.
They start with all the players are
players from like cast off teams and
teams play is that no team ever wanted
to buy.
And then so then they get into like the
last seven,
eight games in a season.
Everybody's like,
Hey,
they're going to start losing.
And the team behind them spurs is going
to catch them.
But these motherfuckers like,
they,
they gel together in a style that I've
never before.
Like they're very defensive.
And,
but they will,
they'll attack you really if they have
these two forwards.
Like if you kick the ball out to them,
they're fast and then they'll score and
then they'll just shut the whole shit
down.
Like you ain't going nowhere.
Don't matter who the fuck you are.
You are not going nowhere.
And on Thursday,
no,
on Monday,
this team,
5,000 to one won the premiership.
Whoa.
5,000 to one one.
The fucking killer shit is fucking
crazy.
All kinds of people had little bets that
they won like 50,000 on 10 bucks or 10
pounds or euro or whatever,
but it costs bookmakers $15 million.
Whoa.
Because like it's empowered.
It's like the most impossible sports
story.
Wow.
That's incredible.
I love hearing shit like that.
But you,
as you were talking,
I started getting discouraged because it
was like,
I dunno about the soccer project.
Soccer project seems like it's going to
cost me a lot of paying attention.
The top no,
you know what you do.
Just just pick a team.
Well,
I'm going to hit you a good team to my
mentor sort of brought you into mma.
Do a bunch of fights.
Right?
I want you to be my mentor and get me
into soccer.
All right.
Cause it seems like if I'm going to
follow some shit and you fall some shit,
the whole world follows,
right?
Like what is like everybody loves the
NFL in the United States and I'm sure
it's awesome,
but if I'm going to fall,
so I'm going to try to follow soccer.
I'm going to give it a shot right now.
Americans going crazy.
What the fuck is joe rubbing all this
goddamn bullshit black lives matter.
All of a sudden he's fucking following
soccer.
Don't worry.
There's black lives matter in soccer too
that there's too many countries are
racist as shit.
They,
they,
they monkey chants to the black players
base.
There's a lot of fascists and do when
they broadcast that shit,
they bring it up.
They'll bring it up and they all like
the ref was stopped the game.
Sometimes the players or stop the game,
they'll get those people out or they'll
ban that team and the next time they
have to play it like a real game.
Like,
imagine the Lakers playing San Antonio
Spurs in an empty stadium because they
was racist chance the last time the game
was played at the lake.
And so they just say you have a black,
you have a blackout game where none of
the fans can come was punished.
They do shit like that.
Ooh,
I liked that.
I liked that idea.
Blackout game.
Yeah.
Fuck it.
Well then,
but then people are like,
yeah,
made them black.
Hope to gain like build up monkey shit.
Everybody doesn't learn.
No.
There's a lot of people that just want
to fucking flip over the board.
Yeah.
They don't want to actually play the
game.
They want to flip over the board or get
some type of attention from it.
Liking it.
Yeah.
Well it's like we were talking about
before with people don't feel like we're
all the same.
You feel like those people over there
playing that game,
those are just people,
man,
it's their dream to do this and they
figured out how to do it.
Like you can't be angry at them.
You should be inspired.
It doesn't have anything to do with you.
You know,
like just being,
don't be a fucking asshole.
But people also get so
attached to one team versus the other.
That's another,
yeah.
That's another thing that giant problem
like sports cause it brings people
together.
But then at that point it also separates
people too much.
Oh yeah.
People have,
there's riots regularly at games,
right.
I mean if you looked at all the games
that are played between teams all over
the world,
they have respect now.
They fight in the town.
Yeah.
Outside the stadium and they throw
bottles and shit from the bars and all
that shit.
Or The town fountain.
They fight over teams.
It's stupid.
So fucking dumb.
It's dumb.
And it's,
it's hard to believe that that's like a
common occurrence with football,
with soccer,
with baseball.
Right.
There's always like fights in the
parking lots with the Lakers.
I heard some terrible stories about some
guy was wearing the wrong,
it was written wrong.
Basketball team shirt and he's with his
son and these guys at the Lakers Games
beat the fuck out of him.
Caled him knocked him out.
His head bounced off.
The concrete was in a coma for weeks is
there was this kid that happened.
I just beat the fuck out of him cause he
had the wrong shirt.
I haven't to a dude at the dodgers game
like a while ago when the mccourts he
used to own the team.
Maybe that's what I'm talking about.
Is that what I'm talking about?
Probably,
yeah.
We're raiders.
The raiders,
raiders,
Raider fans might knock you out too.
Why Raider fans?
Comments like why is that a thing?
Because everybody was worried about the
raiders came to Los Angeles that we
would have a bunch of concept.
The game there was a big issue.
It's just been their culture and
everybody just identified with it and
accepted it and said this is who we are.
Is it because of rappers started taking
on the raider hats and started wearing
raider hats in the 80s is that what it
was that what brought it around?
Nah,
they were like that from,
I dunno,
like it,
it's like there's some teams in Italy
that the fans are just bass hall
fascists and then they,
that's,
that's some of the culture.
I,
it's,
it's hard to tell,
but the rate seemed like they've been
through,
they've gone through all the routes to
have that type of fan base.
You know what I mean?
Coming up in Oakland.
So even when they moved to La and
rappers and started joining them and
then now they're back in Oakland,
it's like,
I dunno,
it's just,
it's just the had the right temperature
for four ignorance.
Well,
amongst their,
some of their friends.
I think there's something going on with
people to where we want to be united by
a common cause,
even if that common causes terrible.
Yeah.
I think that's one of the things that's
going on with trump.
Like what?
And I see some of these people that are
like trump supporters.
I'm like,
are you really?
Or are you just in a gang?
Because it seems like a lot of them are
in a cunt gang.
Like they're wearing sunglasses are
being dicks.
They're walking up there,
they're honking at these people that
have Bernie Sanders signs.
If you've seen this,
and I forget what city it was in a where
Bernie Sanders wound up winning and
trump was,
but was a big one that he won recently.
It was Indiana,
Indiana.
So he's driving by and these,
uh,
Mexican Americans are on one side of the
road and they're fucking screaming at
this guy was in a,
uh,
Donald Trump supporting truck and
they're screaming shit in hurling,
you know,
insults back and forth at each other.
And I'm watching this,
I'm going,
what,
what are we seeing in here?
Like we see in gangs form?
Cause it seems like they're not really
talking about trump's policies.
They're not talking about his
credentials,
they're not talking about his,
his ability to lead and the way he
carries himself.
It's almost like he's their guy.
Like he,
they decide this is my guy I know was
changed their mind.
Yeah.
This is the guy for Douche bags.
And then,
you know,
it's,
it's discerning to people.
It's concerning because it makes you
think like,
there's so many of us,
so many of us that when something can
unite us,
even if you're getting an ice in a bad
way,
like the fucking heaven's gate cult,
well,
they all cut their legs off and fucking
purple sneakers on.
A lot of them did.
They got castrated themselves.
Yeah.
It was part of what that guy wanted
people to do and he had,
well,
he was gay and he didn't like being gay
and he was trying to free himself from
his sexuality,
but at least one or two of his other
like big people in that group also
castrated themselves.
They couldn't just do the film,
like the Yakuza does this wrong with it.
They do a joint at a time.
Whenever you fuck up,
it's okay.
Joined at a time chunk.
Do you remember that?
Uh,
trump painting I showed you a few weeks
ago that someone paying and with like a
small Dick,
the girl who painted it got attacked by
some trump supporters and like they
punched in the face and yelled trump
2016 and random the,
that's what she's claiming.
I mean,
I don't know if it was on tape or
anything,
but yeah.
Well you don't,
oh my God.
Oh my God.
It happened in here and I'll shiners.
They found her where she lived.
It's based off of some facebook
information and found her and she came
outside.
Jesus.
That's what she's claiming though too.
I mean,
it could be,
it might not be true,
but I don't know.
I want to say,
but even it probably is,
but it's hard to tell and it's
unfortunate that you even have to say
that,
but she does have tattoos on her face,
you know?
I mean,
who knows?
Um,
I would like to believe would be more
happy if she made it up,
but ultimately you got to kind of have
to believe someone like that.
That's sad because that was a cool
painting.
They shouldn't be so angry.
Why would they be so angry if trump was
cool,
he'd buy that Shit.
You know,
like your mom and joke.
Yeah,
yeah,
exactly.
Yeah.
Did you see the recent thing that he has
on,
on his,
uh,
on his twitter?
I retweeted it yesterday.
I was like eating a Taco bowl.
I love Mexicans.
I know Hispanics,
Hispanics here.
He's out of his fucking mind.
Like this is mad.
He doesn't care.
He's flaunting it.
Yeah.
It's almost like he's reaching out and
tuning into the frequency of those,
those kind of guys like these and
they're out there.
The thing is,
I'm not opposed to someone like him
trying it out cause it happy.
Cinco de Mayo Best Taco bowls are made
in trump tower grille.
I love Hispanics.
Like what the fuck?
I love Hispanics and he's got that evil
old school.
The man look and someone pointed out,
if you click on the picture that there's
a photo of his ex wife,
Marla maples in a bikini in the lower
corner of a magazine.
He's eating his fucking lunch on.
I could wonder if he just eats like he
has the news clippings of his,
his victims,
any piles it on his desk and that's how
he eats.
Why else would you be eating on top of a
pile of papers?
Those are trophies like he's a trophy
hunter instead of it's,
it's probably all people.
He's burned in business deals and
facteau and smashed find competition.
Well,
it's like his favorite stories of
people.
He's crushed,
crushed you enemies have dumb driven
before you and hear the laminations up
to women.
That's what he's doing.
He's,
he's eating dinner on a pile of skulls.
They're just print.
What is bent films up?
What is,
I'm fucking American Lapel Pin.
American flag.
Lapel Pin.
It's kind of hilarious.
I'm so torn because as a person who
thinks that the system that we have is
so fucking absurd and it needs to
change,
this is one of the best ways to get it
to change.
This is proof that you're right about
that.
Yeah.
Well,
it just shows you like you can't have a
popularity contest to run the
government.
Right?
It should be more than that.
It shouldn't be this easy,
and it shouldn't be an electoral
college.
And delegates shouldn't be able to
decide who they're gonna vote for
despite what the state votes for.
They shouldn't be super delegates.
All this is craziness.
We have an antiquated nonsensical system
that was developed back when people
wrote with feathers.
Well,
you'd have to really fucking think about
that.
And for whatever dumb ass reason,
we continue to use the same thing and
anytime anybody talks about reforming it
or changing it or updating it or coming
out with new models,
everybody freaks the fuck out.
Right?
Like it's some sacred fucking scroll
that Jesus wrote.
We found a clay pot,
they did everything right.
Can we update this?
It's stupid as fuck.
And the only reason why it's in place at
all like this electoral college and
representative government is because you
couldn't talk directly to the leaders,
right?
You couldn't talk to record.
The government was too hard.
But we have all these new tools in place
and the idea that we're not using them,
like we're not using the internet,
we're not using social media,
we're not using our instantaneous
ability to communicate with each other
to find out what we actually want as as
a collective group B.
The fact that that's an also we should
agree with.
There should be like parameters where
things can't get past.
we're all agree.
Okay.
We cannot set aside any rules or or
create any laws that intentionally
victimize certain segments of the
population.
Right.
We all agree on that.
Yeah.
Like we make a new constitution type
thing.
We all agree on that.
Everyone agrees on that.
Right?
Right.
So when anything comes up,
when anything comes up,
whether it's about gay marriage or
whether it's about fucking whatever it
is,
you look at that and you go,
okay,
is this a law that would victimize
intentionally certain aspects of our
population?
And if so,
we can't do it.
Especially if they're not doing anything
to anybody else.
Right.
We should have like rules like
that.
Like we could update and make a real
simple new constitution that would be
way better and we'd keep most of this
shit and original most of the ideas of
freedom of speech,
but update it to,
to represent what we're dealing with
today.
Because what's free speeches today is
very different than standing on a box
and yelling into a courtyard without a
microphone.
Cause that's what people were doing,
writing something down and not being
worried about being killed for it.
We all agree on that kind of stuff,
but we should figure out like
how,
what,
what are these?
How many of these laws are good?
How many does the laws make?
Any fucking sense?
How many of those laws are just,
we just have,
cause they've been around forever and he
examines them to just have some really
smart people making some really bad laws
on purpose.
Like it,
like when you said talking about laws
that does affect a certain segment,
not making laws that affect a certain
segment of society.
Like the ones that we have now that
exist,
that does,
that does hurt segments of society was
done on purpose,
but they've just done so slickly yeah.
It's just,
it's just tough to get,
it's just some bad people in the wrong
places right now.
Yeah.
Well there's just too much money
involved in making decisions.
Right?
That's the big issue.
The big issue is there's all these
gigantic groups of people with immense
amounts of money and they can gain more
money by influence people's decision
making that are in judgment or that are
in positions of power.
And that's our real problem.
A real problem is these giant groups of
people call them whenever you want.
Calm corporations column,
you know,
whatever calm the banks,
call them,
whatever it is.
They have the ability to influence the
decision making of the people that are
in power and whether it's through fear,
intimidation,
manipulation,
or straight up bribing.
There's a system that's in place.
It's very difficult to buck.
That's why I find it intriguing.
If Donald Trump gets in,
I don't find it intriguing because I
like what he's saying and that I like is
this crazy character who's doing what I
find intriguing is it doesn't seem to
fucking matter who the president is in
any way other than socially.
Like socially,
it seems to matter.
Like,
I think one of the best things about
having Obama in office was that he was a
guy who was pretty liberal on most
things as opposed to like the eight
years that we had a deal with like scary
conservative Bush and Donald Rumsfeld
and John Ashcroft.
They were scary people.
Like John Ashcroft covered the breast of
a statue.
Um,
was it in the White House?
No,
not the White House.
Was it at the Pentagon?
No,
Wah Wah.
I forget what the statute was,
but they put a drape over the breasts of
a,
of a statue that had been exposed
forever.
Ashcroft was a guy went after Tommy
Chong and a,
because Tommy Chung's son was selling
bongs and so he went after Tommy Chong
saying that if you don't go to jail,
I'm going to put your whole in jail.
So Tommy Chong had a wine up there was
all Ashcroft daily operation.
Nice dreams is what they were doing.
It was a sting operation.
Justice Department covers partially nude
statues because of Ashcroft.
He was a scary,
scary guy.
And these are the,
this is an example of the people wrong
people in the,
in the places where they shouldn't be
because they're out of control.
Well,
it also heightened our suspicions of a
conspiracy theories and hysteria in this
country because we saw like really
dangerous people that were running the
show.
Like a guy like him,
his fucking dangerous like Rumsfeld to
push aspartame.
Like that's how it,
aspartame is legal.
It all came out of Rumsfeld.
Like he's,
he was one of those directly responsible
for making aspartame illegal and,
and avoiding all the information that
pointed to the fact that it's probably
like super fucking bad.
[inaudible] his this fucker that we
didn't do anything about it.
No,
we just like wrote it out.
Well we had to what?
We didn't know what we even could do
then.
It would be really interesting to see
what would happen if the Bush
administration was,
uh,
in office today with the current ability
to communicate about things because
that's where it's really crazy from 2000
to 2016 is a different world.
It's a different world and towards the
end of the Bush administration became
more and more preposterous or people
like what in the fuck is going on to the
point where they went out stealing
money.
Remember when they went out and gas
prices went up to like fucking five
bucks a gallon and everybody's like,
what the fuck is going on?
Right.
It just felt like they went out stealing
money.
They just like,
look,
before Obama comes into office,
we just going to suck as much money out
of this bitch as we can.
Well,
let's just go hard,
you know,
just ridiculous.
What is money?
It's a good question.
You know what?
His money and then,
and then the money that we lost during
the recession,
it wasn't burnt in a fire.
It wasn't like,
like that money went somewhere,
so where the fuck is that money that
they had to get more money to replace
that money.
Like somebody has that money and
spending that money so it's not like it
went to a vacuum.
It will never come back.
It's like so w it's just so
they never teach you in school,
so you don't know.
You don't think about it.
But where the fuck,
well,
it's Voodoo.
It's agreed upon Voodoo.
Yeah,
it's agreed upon Voodoo.
I mean that's really what it is.
We have all the same amount of stuff,
right?
We have the same amount of minerals.
We have the same amount of raw materials
or the same amount of people.
We have the same amount of land.
We have all the same stuff,
but somehow there's no money.
Right.
Whereas two months ago,
everybody was rolling in dough.
Right.
That's a sign of someone fucking,
yeah.
He's like,
man,
I don't know what happened.
We lost all the guy is crazy.
Y'all take care and we're real.
Sorry.
Worked out this way.
We gotta get going.
The recession was one of the craziest
things.
Like there's like it came on new and
said what broke all the money's gone and
everybody just started acting broke.
Everybody was just like broken laying
off people that able broke y'all and
it's like,
and then they say it's,
things are getting better.
Yeah.
I could feel it getting better.
Getting better.
I saw something that said that the
150,000 jobs were added to the economy,
but unemployment stayed the same.
The same rate,
but they added 150,000 jobs.
Like what is the rate base don?
And then someone else told me that the
rate is not based on people stop
looking.
The rate is only based on people claim
unemployment.
Like there's way more unemployment than
that.
It's just good looking.
Meanwhile,
easiest time to live our everybody
bitching about shit.
Like it's just,
you can take some dude from the
depression and put them in America today
and he'd be like,
what the fuck are you complaining about?
The no soup lines.
No one's starving it.
Look how big everybody is.
There would be like everybody in the
depression days,
they were like 110 pounds.
Dudes were tiny.
They'd be like seeing all these giant
people,
Mcdonald's fucking falling out of their
pockets,
put all the food.
These fucking people app or you got to
do is wait by a garbage can.
Yeah.
Poor people are fat today.
And I'm crazy that it's true,
right?
I mean back then you were starving.
You were terrified.
People,
people like legitimately were worried
about not having something to eat.
Right.
I read this book about this guy named
Danny Mcgroarty.
Danny mcgurty is like a,
a famous depression era pool hustler who
traveled across the country during like
the darkest days of the depression and
would hustle from town to town and
gamble with guys and make money like
barely get by,
but was an alcoholic and just wrote,
wrote a bunch of crazy stories about all
his times.
But there was times where he's begging
people for food.
Like he was starving,
he just showed up at someone's house and
was begging them for food and the guy
comes out and gives him a bowl,
sausages and shit.
And you realize like there were times in
this country and by the way back then,
no one was telling them everything's
going to be okay.
There was no oprah on TV.
There was no positive thing.
You know,
there was no mind coaches,
you know,
on late night infomercials,
I'm going to give you the tools to
achieve your greatness.
It was none of that.
They were just almost animalistic
traveling around in box cars.
And this,
uh,
this book was really intense man because
in this guy was talking like Kinda with
shame about how he had broken down a
couple of times and was just asking
people for food.
You know,
that's like,
he goes,
I didn't have any other options.
I had to beg people for food.
And you realize like,
yeah,
that's,
that's a different time than today
because people are just out there doing
that.
Well,
you know,
this is way more charity today than ever
before.
But I think also we understand that a
lot of the people that we're seeing that
around on the street corners and you
know,
begging,
they have mental problems.
Yeah.
I mean I'm sure they did back then too.
But I think back then they were probably
more people who are like legitimately
yeah.
And it didn't have the information,
didn't understand like where are all the
jobs where it's going,
what's,
what's the economy?
What does that,
you can google it you like.
So if you were a 35 year old man who was
essentially illiterate and you were a
labor your whole life and then also in
the jobs dried up,
you had no grasp of why or how to fix it
or who was going to change it.
So any politician has stood up and
started yelling things about immigrants
or about,
I mean that's essentially what happened
to Hitler.
Hitler rose to power because Germany was
in a bad economic place and this guy
came along and said,
these mother fuckers are ruining it for
us.
And everybody was like,
yeah,
they all just jumped on.
He was so charismatic too.
That's another scary thing about a guy
that's really charismatic that can unite
people for a cause,
even if it's
bad one.
You know what's crazy about,
I went to a,
what they call it,
like a opera.
What's the thing that they have the
conductor.
So opera as an opera,
music symphony,
the symphony and uh,
the thing when they have doctor
[inaudible] saying,
yeah,
I'm hot orchestra,
I'm hot box.
I don't even know if I'm saying that
right.
Hot Box and drill hotboxing is real
y'all.
It's a lot of people don't believe.
And I was watching the conductor and uh,
it was a lot of Jewish people there and
you know,
the conductor is doing this shit and if
you turn off the music is,
looks like you're watching Hitler.
Really?
Yeah.
Because the conductor has the same
motions as Hitler,
you know,
at a,
at an opera,
like the way he's directing the band.
Someone should make a split screen.
Yeah.
Hitler was really animated,
right?
Yeah.
He's really animated and moving this up.
It's been an interesting,
when you stop and think about that is
that we don't like that from a
president.
We don't like it.
And it's one of the things that sank.
Howard Dean said Howard Dean got caught
screaming,
remember that?
Well,
and it was August.
Ah,
yeah.
And it was over.
It was over.
It was like a bad thing.
Yeah.
We don't want anyone yelling.
We don't want anyone is
when you see Hitler in those speeches,
that fucking dynamic way of talking,
that scares the shit out of everybody.
That was,
that was good for back then.
You could,
you could reach people back then cause
people,
he's like expressing the anger.
Yeah,
that everybody was feeling well
in a way that's where people have a
legitimate beef without trump is
behaving because although it might be
effective in getting people to pay
attention to them,
it's very dangerous in the doors.
It opens up as far as like getting
people to unite like,
like the Shitty said.
And I was on the phone with the
president of Mexico and he said,
who you think is going to pay for that
wall?
And I said,
you're going to pay for it.
We're not going to pay for it.
Oh yes you are.
And the fence just got 10 feet taller
and the whole audience cheers.
Like that's like a f I'm paraphrasing,
it's too fucked up a speech.
But the,
the,
the idea that he would like yell that
out.
The fence just got taller.
So you're going to make a fence taller
than it needs to be.
So the,
you spite this person like is this,
is this a normal behavior pattern for a
leader of the greatest army the world
has ever known?
Right.
And seems crazy.
Yeah.
Plus in a,
in a,
especially in a world where we're
Mexicans who smuggle stuff across the
board of build tunnels.
Yeah.
Including they snubbed muggles smuggle
people through on the tunnel.
So good luck building your wall.
Your wall will never affect anything.
Yeah.
But they don't go over,
they don't go over like they have all
these secret tunnels like every,
every documentary or even Scicaro,
you know,
it's just all tunnels.
And apparently that's real too.
Yeah.
And your president is talking about
building a wall.
He,
he sounds dumb as shit you're president
to be.
How are you going to find all those
tunnels?
Yeah.
Do you know how much square right
miles you're dealing with and how deep
they go in?
Especially when you look at like the
guys got out El Chapo,
they went a mile in.
Yeah.
A mile on the ground from my thing is
underground.
Everything's on the ground.
Like the construction noise that you'll
make it to build a wall,
helps them to dig tunnels.
Yeah.
The time the San at the same time,
you're just smothering the sound.
They like the best tunnel builders ever.
Yeah.
If you really think about this tunnel
builders in the game,
who's built more secret tunnels in
Mexican drug dealers,
fucking nobody about is this El Chapo is
tunnel.
I was looking at that,
but I just typed in generic tunnel for
drug tunnels.
Yeah,
there's a ton of them,
man.
They just keep digging them,
but it's,
it's so fascinating that there's this
border,
we have this line and if you get to dig
a hole and pop out on the other side,
[inaudible] sell drugs pop out on the
other side.
It's Hilarious,
but it's so weird.
Like what a weird fucking thing that
we've done.
We've made lines on the ground of the
earth that you can't cross and there's
no difference between the people on
either side other than the fact that
they speak different languages,
but they're just people and there's a
lot of each people on the other side.
My fucking parents live in Mexico,
man.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
Oh yeah.
And then he did tell me that
Mexicans live in America.
Yeah.
You know,
a lot of my friends are from Mac.
I know a lot of people from Mexico a
lot.
Like I know I probably know 20 or 30
people who were born in Mexico.
So we integrated,
right?
Obviously there's no difference between
us other than than culture and language.
Right.
But we still have this crazy line,
like you can't come over and you guys
are fucked.
Your listen,
listen,
listen.
You were born into a worse system than
us.
We can't let you over here.
I know you want to get better,
but fuck off.
Fuck you.
No.
If you get better over on this side,
if you're born at Phoenix,
oh,
you missed it by a mile.
If you landed in Phoenix,
if you came out of your mother's Pussy
and Phoenix,
your goal,
dude,
didn't you get fucking Medicare and all
that good shit.
You in the obamacare.
But if you're born a mile the other way,
flux Ville.
Yeah.
What?
That's so crazy.
That doesn't make like logically I
understand there's a limited amount of
resources.
I understand there's gotta be some
pragmatic decisions.
Very unfortunate,
but we'll really have to do is help Max
go get back on their feet up,
up,
up.
But really what it should be is it
should be no Mexico.
There should be no United States.
It should be no Canada.
There should be the planet earth.
Right?
That's really what it should be.
If these ideas are fucking stupid,
they're like soccer clubs.
Whoa,
whoa.
We're like little soccer.
Well,
those things make sense.
No,
but I'm 1000% with you.
It's like it's all,
there's enough resources in the world.
If everybody shares him,
wait.
Right.
For everything to be fine.
All right.
Well both you and I are a direct result
of immigration,
right?
My parents were the first generation
they came from,
or they were born in America,
but their parents,
my grandparents.
Is that how it works?
What's the first?
I'm third generation.
Right?
Because my parents were second
generation because my grandparents were
first generation Americans when they
moved to America.
They weren't born in America.
How's it work?
No.
So my parents were born here is the
first,
first generation.
So I'm second generation,
so I'm second generation.
So just two generations ago,
you know,
I'm all of my family in Ireland.
All of them,
right?
Everyone,
my grandfather on my father's side came
from Ireland.
My father,
uh,
or my grandmother on my father's side
came from Italy.
My grandmother and my grandfather on my
mother's side came from Italy.
Everybody came from another country all
during the same time period.
So they were all like immigrants that
came over here.
And this is the,
this is why the United States is so
interesting because there's so many
different kinds of people here,
but there's just too many of us since
two.
Awesome.
This experiment was too bad ass
Mexico.
I don't know what happened in Mexico.
You know what went wrong?
They got cut off.
Is that what it has?
I know people don't want to share,
man.
People just want mine.
Yeah.
Oh Man.
I wonder how much of what Mexico is
right now is a direct result of the
Spanish invasions.
I wonder when something happens,
like during like the Aztec days and
there's some crazy takeover and that
Spanish language gets introduced to s to
Central America and,
and,
and even North America.
I mean,
most of Camp California will we call
California used to be Mexico.
So I wonder like what impact that had
because when you find out the atrocities
that were committed with,
with the,
uh,
the Aztecs and the,
um,
the invaders and the introduction of
horse backs,
I mean,
people riding horseback,
that was all during Cortez,
right?
And the people before him was all the
Europeans that had brought over horses.
Just think about all that chaos that
happened and they changed the language
of the country.
I mean,
the biggest maintain Mexico was
essentially native Americans.
That's why like the Mayans,
they really resemble like a lot of
native Americans.
What we,
what we think of as native Americans.
And when you look at,
there's like a bunch of different styles
of Mexican,
like their appearance.
You've got like your Canelo Alvarez,
you've got like,
who's real,
he's an outlier.
He's a rare one.
But you've got like Oscar de la Hoya.
He's that like handsome Spaniard version
of Mexico.
Right.
And then you got like real brown looking
dudes that look like native Americans
that are also Mexican that are like
really dark and you go with that guy
looks like a mirror.
I'm American Indian.
What we consider a native American
because this is like,
that's what it is.
It's,
they were introduced like the Spanish
language and all these different people
from Europe interbred with all the
people that are here and they created,
what is Mexico hilarious picture.
Cause it's like who drew that?
He didn't even look like that.
Like those,
those are hot instagram trick chicks.
Who drew this version of that?
Those supposed to,
some of them are supposed to be men.
Oh for real?
Yeah.
They're just covering their decks.
Some of them are supposed to be men.
See that one's got his a transgender.
What's going on in this photo?
Well I think these people,
like native Americans,
you stay,
keep their hair long.
I mean that's what it's depicting.
You know,
when you think of native Americans and
you think of like cowboys versus
Indians,
they all have long hair.
Right?
Well,
I think that that's what these people
were encountering back then and I mean
it was a fucking genocide man.
I mean it was essentially just a
slaughter fest.
They killed so many fucking people.
They stole gold.
They came over on horseback.
They were considered gods.
Nobody knew what it was to ride a horse.
He never imagined a guy comes over for
the first time.
They,
they land in a boat,
they get off the boat and they have
horses and swords and they start fucking
shopping everybody up.
They probably had horses,
right,
and had seen horses or maybe,
no,
no they didn't.
They didn't even have American horses
were introduced.
Horses were introduced to North American
by the European there.
What?
By the Europeans?
There was horses in North America
millions of years ago,
but they went extinct.
I'm pretty sure I'm almost positive of
this.
If there was a type of horse that lived
like in the pleistocene or something
like that and they went,
they went extinct.
But when it,
yeah,
find that out.
That's an interesting when is when we're
horses first introduced to North
America,
but horses being wild,
like wild horses is a,
a relatively recent phenomenon like over
the last few hundred years.
Gosh,
American with Columbus in 1493 there you
go.
Is second voice voyage to America,
Spanish horses representing e Taleb
Bowel.
Hmm.
Kabbalists Cabela's,
Cabela's or brought back to North
America first and the Virgin Islands.
And in 15,
19,
they were reintroduced to the con on the
continent in Monterrey,
Mexico.
Uh,
from where they radiated through the
American great plains.
Hmm.
Yeah.
See Man,
I feel bad for the horse.
He's just being on a boat that long.
Yeah,
no shit.
Right.
I wonder how many of them survived.
Yeah,
that's a long ass trip.
I wonder how they did that because that
was months and months at sea you had to
have the right amount of food.
People getting scurvy and shit.
I bet it's probably easier to bring hay
than it is to bring anything.
You know when you think about it,
hey you can stack it up nice and dense,
but horses eat a lot of fucking,
hey you have to clean up after them and
they on the over the place that makes
the boat trip even worse than I imagined
it in the first place because boss is on
board,
they're going to get off the boat and
they haven't run or walk through it all
and months.
Their legs are going to be all fucked
up.
Yeah.
I was just thinking,
I was looking for a picture but at a
representation of it,
cause they're in Columbus where I'm
from,
there's a,
they have a replica of the Santa Maria,
which is one of those boats.
It's not very big at all.
20 or 30 people could like comfortably
just be on it for a long period of time.
So I don't know where the hell you would
put animals to.
Where is it?
It's on the river.
Whoa.
Like grand right in downtown Columbus.
How big is it?
Like if you had to guess,
pretty big.
How many feet long?
60 50 60 that's it.
I,
I'm trying to guess in my head.
I don't want to yards.
It's not that big.
I'll pull a picture of it.
That's insane.
That's 20 yards.
That's crazy.
That's like what you shoot when you're
practicing with a boat.
A tune it in.
That's great for you.
Start backing up those little things.
Change the world.
Wow.
So much like if the scale of those
things to how much they changed the
world,
it's fucking crazy.
That's nothing.
I do think that is
nothing that's small as fuck.
Dude,
that's so interesting.
Ian,
what you,
the way you just explained that,
that's such a,
that's like a nuclear three of those,
three of those fucking a man.
Boy,
you just nailed it.
You just nailed it.
Those things change the world.
Three of those fucking things change.
I mean change everything,
but those three were like the seed that
planted North America.
They came over hand explosion and it
became the empire state building and the
fucking Seattle Tower.
What's that?
Tower evil.
The space needle.
The space needle brought lots of murder.
Well,
diseases,
lots of disease.
Genocide,
rape.
Yeah.
All sorts of groovy shit.
It's crazy.
It's crazy when you think about phones
and I,
well eventually eventually turns into
iphone.
Yeah.
I wonder if my phones would have existed
if we just stayed in Europe.
Probably not.
See that's what a think.
One of the things that I think is really
important about like having an asshole
as a president for a brief brief for us,
we have a chance to rethink this whole
thing is I think,
I think we have to get outraged before
things change and we have to realize
that the system is just fucking retard.
And maybe he does too.
Maybe look,
let's,
let's give him the benefit of the doubt,
right?
You're talking about a guy,
he's obviously incredibly wealthy and
obviously incredibly successful.
Maybe he is sick of it all himself.
Maybe he is one of the guys who's
actually contributed.
I mean,
look,
he,
that fucking guy paid hillary to come to
his wedding.
Okay.
Hundreds of thousands of dollars.
It's all it took and she showed up.
I mean,
this is a guy that's been deep,
deep,
deep in the system,
handed out money,
these motherfuckers.
And then finally he went,
fuck you.
He went,
I'm going to run this thing.
And they're like,
there's no way.
There's way Donald Trump,
we've looked at the numbers.
Impossible.
Everybody else dropped out.
They've all given up.
I mean,
Bernie Sanders and Hillary Clinton a
neck and neck,
right?
Except for in delicates where she is,
uh,
quite a bit above him,
but she still doesn't have enough to
win.
Like it's close enough to,
it's like,
it's weird.
It's like weirdly close where you'll
have to look at it and you need people.
Bernie doesn't stand a chance.
Uh,
mathematically he's already eliminated.
But then people say,
well,
what if Hillary gets indited for one of
the two criminal investigations?
Sir,
she's currently involved with,
what if people find out about this
fucking email thing,
but it's even worse than we thought.
What if people find out this?
What if they find out that what if
there's some dirt?
What if this isn't this?
It's,
it's fucking exhausting.
It's exhausting.
But meanwhile,
this fucking trump guy is sitting pretty
just waiting for whoever gets most beat
up by this fucking campaign on the
democratic side.
They're beating the shit out of each
other,
so they're going to come through it.
Whoever's going to come through,
it's going to be all fucked up.
It's going to have,
it's like having a,
an mma tournament.
One guy wins by a quick knockout in the
first round,
the other way.
It goes through a three round war.
Trump just ran through someone Anderson
Silva Style and so now,
so now like Hillary and fucking Bernie
Sanders,
like micky ward at Touro Goddy,
he's beating the shit out of each other
and we have to wait to see who emerges.
Why don't screen strange,
strange time.
It's crazy man.
Like,
like you said it and I've been thinking
it.
You said it last week,
I think when it was at the show about
you're more afraid of crews then.
Then he scares the shit out of me and
I'm glad he's out.
Yeah,
I'm glad he,
he,
he would have been the worst choice.
And trump,
I have a feeling if he could fool people
and do this just to win that he might
actually just be doing it just to win.
That's when you become a different
person.
That's our hope.
But if he did become a different person,
I wouldn't even be surprised cause it's,
it's Kinda almost typical him.
Right.
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
I don't know,
man.
I don't have any interaction with them.
But I do know that Jeff Ross work with
them on the roast and he said he was
very nice and very reasonable.
And one of the things that Jeff Ross
said is,
hey,
when when the camera turns to you and
you're not laughing,
it kind of looks bad.
Like you should just enjoy it.
Like don't be upset that these guys are
making funny it just laugh along.
It'd be great for you.
And he said,
trump thought about it.
He goes,
you know what?
You're right.
Like he's not an asshole all the time.
Character is definitely their character.
It's like a wrestling character.
Wwe style.
Yeah,
exactly.
Golly,
it's a wwe character.
I just,
I don't know him,
you know,
I don't buy any of this.
I don't buy Ryan seacrest's.
I don't know that guy.
I don't know Donald Trump.
I mean,
I would like to get high with Ryan
seacrest.
Find what's really going on in there.
I don't know.
Tell him to come on.
What you see what's in,
what's in his hand at cell phone.
Oh,
he's going to shave his head.
Is that what it is?
The shaver.
But Vince Mcmahon areas as if it's like
someone's gonna be like,
are they shaved?
Vince Mcmahon's head space was more
fearful than somebody's about to get
beheaded by Isis.
Is that Bobby Lashley?
That's Bobby Lashley,
right.
Bobby Lashley is,
I'm fighting MMA now.
He has to fight and like these weird
Indian casinos,
so they don't test them.
No.
Shit.
That's hilarious.
So there's a rumor going around Joe.
Uh,
I saw something the other day that a
floyd mayweather,
his team has been trademarking like
floyd 50 or something like that,
saying that like he might be coming out
of retirement.
Right.
I heard about this rumor hit today that
has potential opponent might be connor
mcgregor.
Oh my God.
Had a boxing match at t mobile arena in
Vegas.
Oh my God.
Um,
I think conor mcgregor is a very good
mma fighter.
I think if conor mcgregor and floyd
mayweather fight in mma,
conor mcgregor will fuck him up.
He will fuck him up.
Floyd.
We'll get the shit kicked out of him.
He will kick his fucking body senseless.
He will kick his legs.
Floyd will be debilitated inside of one
round,
100%.
And if connor decides to take him to the
ground,
I guarantee you floyd mayweather,
conner's no worldclass wrestler,
he's no ncaa champion.
He's an Olympic gold medalist.
Guarantee you floyd mayweather cannot
stop him from taking them to the ground.
And if connor gets him to the ground,
he's going to mount them and cave his
fucking face in or choke him or break
his arm or do whatever he wants to do.
But in a boxing match,
I can't imagine highlight world were
floyd mayweather.
It doesn't fuck him up in a boxing
match.
I think floyd mayweather is arguably the
greatest boxer of all time.
If you look at his accomplishments,
who he's been able to beat,
how he shuts everyone's offense down.
He's a more boring version of what a lot
of Bernard Hopkins does,
and he does it in a more slick,
skillful way with rapid reflexes,
and he relies on speed and movement and
just a deep,
deep,
deep understanding of boxing.
He's just so much better.
And if people don't know,
if you think you're really good and then
you get in there and you box a guy like
that,
he will fucking expose the shit out of
you.
He will expose the shit out of you.
It's just,
it's a different animal,
man.
I mean,
who knows,
man?
Look,
one of the things we know about connor
is he has a ridiculous belief in himself
and he has unbelievable power.
One of the things we know about floyd is
he's 39 I think is that old.
Yeah.
So when a guy turns 39 you never know.
I mean,
there's a,
for every guy like Bernard Hopkins,
there's a bunch of guys who the wheels
just fall off and all of a sudden they
can't take a punch anymore and they
can't fight anymore.
They don't move good anymore.
But I can't imagine a world where he's
not light years past connor with boxing
skill,
I could just,
it's there nothing.
These guys are thinking about money.
Oh yeah.
More than,
more than like a result.
The money will be giant.
They'd probably,
and they probably out a way,
we're both of them don't lose or
something like that.
I don't think they're going to do that.
I think they're going to really fight.
Hmm.
I don't,
I can't imagine that in either one of
them would be willing to negotiate with
the other one while thinking that they
might get double crossed.
You know like,
Nah,
I don't buy that because remember what
Victor Ortiz and mayweather,
when Victor Ortiz was doing some dirty
shit to mayweather and Victor Ortiz
apologized and floyd mayweather just
step to him and sucker punched him in
the face.
And Klm.
Do you remember that?
Watch this here.
Pull.
Pull that up because it's kind of
hilarious cause like there's no deals
being made and not in this world.
This is the world of competitive.
I'm only saying that because why should
the MMA guy watch this?
Victoria [inaudible] gets warned because
he kept like headbutting and like
getting really dirty and so he goes to
touch hands.
Look at this.
Boom Bang.
He goes to touch hands like Yo,
I'm sorry.
Bing Bang.
Ah,
I mean it's hilarious.
That's the real world of boxing.
Mayweather just knocked him the fuck
out.
He just,
he thought they were going to like touch
gloves and be buddies and then get back
after it and maybe where there's like
bitch pop.
He hit him with a left hook.
They never saw a common straight right
hand.
That's a wrap.
And I just think that the skill level in
straight boxing that floyd mayweather
has,
it's very difficult to understand why
you're just looking at,
look,
he's touching them here.
Look at this being bitch.
He even had a bitch lips or is looking
at the rest face like bitch even it's
like even said bitch Bam.
Yeah,
look at this bank June.
Hey,
what is he doing?
Boom,
that's a wrap.
And that was a wrap for Victoria teases
career.
Really essentially.
Is there,
is there another fight to bring floyd
out of retirement that is short
Pacquiao.
Pacquiao was the big fight,
especially since packet.
I'll just beat Timothy Bradley if
Pacquiao decided to,
you know,
really ramp it up.
I think he still can get a lot of people
excited about them.
You know,
he had a shoulder injury,
he had a shoulder repaired,
but obviously it was great.
And the Bradley fight,
he looked awesome and the Bradley fight,
he's a beast.
I think that could be a real fight,
but I also think that floyd mayweather
versus connor would generate insane
amounts of money.
Insane.
But just be fun to watch the 24 seven
they would make great tv.
Who knows?
Man,
who fucking knows.
I don't think so though.
I don't think he can.
I would imagine unless the UFC is
involved at have to let them out of
contract.
Exactly.
And I don't,
I can't imagine that they would be
willing to do that and I can't imagine
that they would let him fight.
Floyd Mayweather,
like Dana and Lorenzo and frank are
serious boxing fanatics.
They know a lot about boxing.
Could there be a cross promotion?
Oh Man.
I said I'm waiting.
Like have the fight on it.
You can get a piece could happen,
but I wouldn't throw a fighter to the
lions like that.
Like I just,
I just don't look,
I could be wrong.
I'm,
I'm no fucking
clairvoyant.
I don't really know what's going to
happen in a fight.
But I think mayweather is a ghost.
I think you go to punch where mayweather
is and it may,
well there's not there anymore and he's
popping you a jabs and slowly getting
you frustrated and setting traps.
And the next thing you know,
he's uncorking shots on you.
Who the fuck knows?
But who knows?
Maybe conor Mcgregor,
if you went to straight boxing,
would be even more successful than he
has as an MMA fighter because his best
knockouts where with punches,
I mean his left hand is a fucking
piston.
He has a nasty lefthand,
he fucks a lot of guys up.
But is he fucking guys up that are just
not at the level of boxing as say a
Timothy Bradley or uh,
my Donna or you know,
wineman male marcus,
the guys who use though and the,
and the and they're distracted by
training other types of things.
Yes.
Right,
right,
right.
For the ground game for Muay Thai,
it's,
it's like it's,
it's uh,
maybe whether it's just focus on hands.
Yes,
exactly.
And he's a master at it.
Like a straight up master.
I'm in an MMA fight.
It wouldn't even be close.
Right.
It would not even be close.
Connor would kick his body apart before
it may,
whether they even got close to him.
I think his understanding of the
distance,
there's no way maybe,
maybe they would understand the
distance.
Connor would hit him with spinning back
kick to the body,
may with a crumble.
Connor would need them in the body in
the clinch.
It would be awful.
He would kill him.
He would kill them in an MMA fight.
He's much bigger to kind of really
struggles to get done in one 45.
He's a big fuck,
you know?
So I just think in the MMA fight it
would be disastrous for me whether,
but it could be equally disastrous in a
boxing fight.
Have comical way.
Yeah.
The only thing that makes me think that
maybe connor could survive as he's a
fucking super dangerous punch or just
like my Donna was or my don is over
though.
Even though my dad is a worldclass
boxer,
my don is the guy who beat,
uh,
Adrian broner.
My Donna's a serious vicious p power
puncher and he's real aggressive and
wild makes me think like,
maybe like if,
if he,
if connor went straight into boxing,
maybe he could have been a worldclass
boxer.
Maybe could have been,
you know,
some,
some real ricky Hatton type challenger
entirely possible.
But even ricky Hatton got fucked up.
I may weatherman when Ricky Hatton was
ricky Hatton when he was in his prime.
I don't think rick and he hadn't,
should have quit after that fight.
A man.
He likes to do blow.
Yeah,
I'm wanting to get fat.
It was having a party defendant duplo
well,
he,
uh,
he did have one comeback fight and just
didn't like how he performed and I think
he actually wound up winning,
but he decided that it was over,
that he lost it.
I think I'm got to beat out of him.
It could be that,
but it also could be,
we'll pack you.
I'll really fucked him up.
Pankey out.
Hurt him bad.
We're pack out,
knocked him out and he knocked them
dead.
What?
Mayweather.
Fucked him up.
But when packout fucked him up,
it was like,
whoa.
That was a bad knock out man.
He's got those gigantic tree trunk legs
those spring.
He's got a calf.
His calf muscles are like four by four
springs.
He just,
he just jumps at you and uncorked left
hand on your chin.
And when he did that to Ricky Hatton,
he just went to sleep.
Yeah.
That's like the second I British like
hope that that happened to like cleaning
up in Europe and then they came out
here.
We have a prince knows any Mohamad
Mohamad yeah,
yeah.
I seen my Hammad got exposed by um,
the fuck is his name?
A guy who was in a series of wars with
a,
it wasn't pernell.
Whitaker was,
no,
no.
Who is it?
Mexican gentlemen.
Marcos Berrera.
Oh,
okay.
Marcos Antonio.
Berrera yeah,
yeah.
That's what it was.
And uh,
he exposed him,
he showed that fundamental boxing at the
highest level is going to beat that
crazy jumping in wild shit.
Like wild shit didn't work on the top
level guys.
And so he got kind of exposed in that
fight.
But
you know what man,
boxing is so it's so specialized and the
guys that are really good and the
really,
really good guys,
it's,
they're underrated.
How good they are.
And like as a person who's watching it
from the outside,
you don't understand how good a guy like
mayweather is.
I think unless you're there with him
while he's doing his stuff.
Like I bet if a guy's boxing him,
I bet that's when you get a real
understood
standing of how good he is.
And he's disciplined too.
He's more disciplined.
Any acts on the outside like,
like uh,
when I used to hang out with Kevin Hart
a little bit,
he used to hang out with mayweather and
said they'd be partying in the middle of
the pause.
I gotta go and it's like three in the
morning.
I've got to go to road work and they
just go run.
Yeah.
And bring the car and then run it.
And jeans.
Yeah.
Just says,
just follow me.
And he goes running.
Yeah.
Well he's in tremendous shape always.
But apparently now he's a,
he's a little heavy.
I'm,
who knows,
man.
I mean if enough money gets thrown in
the UFC is direction,
the UFC might look at it this way.
Here's a,
here's a pragmatic way of looking at it.
We can still make a lot of money with
conor Mcgregor,
right?
Still make a lot of money with conor
mcgregor in an MMA fight.
We can still make a lot of money if
connor rematches,
Nate Diaz,
which uh,
I hear they're trying to make happen as
well.
That's what the rumor been.
But is he going to beat the best guys in
the world now after Nate Diaz boxed them
up and choked him out?
Like are is that going to happen again?
And if that does happen again,
how much will that deflate his value on
the open market?
If you're playing a game of chess now
looking at as terms of a guys career as
an MMA fighter,
but looking at it as a game of financial
chess,
how do you move your piece?
You might say,
look,
the amount of money that you can make
with the main,
where their fight is off the charts,
right?
Right off the charts.
So you're talking about like a 3 million
paper view by or something crazy.
So you do that,
you move that up and you take that
chance and he gets boxed up by
mayweather.
And,
uh,
maybe survives if he survives and loses
it fucking decision.
And he goes back and he says,
uh,
all respect to mayweather,
going back to mma,
you know,
it just,
I didn't understand his hands.
Now it's a learning experience,
you know,
and he has this great conference.
If he could survive,
he's not diminished too much and they,
whether it's not like a murderous
puncher,
he's not like a Canelo Alvarez or
Gennady Golovkin Lufkin Golovkin is a
bad fight for him.
Someone like that's a bad fight for him,
a murderous puncher because most likely
they're going to take them out.
But May,
whether it's very possible he's going to
get to the decision.
39 is perfect age.
It's good angel it.
Look,
if I was in his corner,
I would say,
look,
this can be done.
This can be done.
And it feels like Mcgregor wants to get
paid because he quit threatened to quit
because he wants to get paid more money.
No,
no,
no.
He really didn't threaten to quit.
He didn't want to do as he did want to
do any of the press conferences.
So he,
he made,
he called the UFC bluff.
He said,
you're not going to remove me from the
car and I'm fucking conor Mcgregor.
I call the shots.
And the UFC is like,
oh,
okay,
well we're going to cancel your fight so
take care.
And you know,
they,
they had like a long break where they
weren't even talking back and forth to
each other and Dana was like,
nope,
I haven't talked to him.
He's not off I zone in the fight
anymore.
He wasn't the press conference.
We're just going to move on with the UFC
200 and you know,
UFC 200 is about the sport in their
eyes.
It's all about sport.
It's,
well it's also,
it's an honor to be on that card.
It's a historical car.
Just like UFC 100 was a historical card.
UFC 200 is an absolutely historical card
and at one guy can't hold it up.
It doesn't matter if you conor mcgregor
or Ronda Rousey or it doesn't matter
what kind of a superstar you are.
You can't hold up the UFC 200 cars and
you have to do the press.
So that was their position.
They took a stand.
And so now he's in this position where
he's got to figure out what the fuck is
gonna do.
He's gonna Fight Mayweather.
If that,
I don't know.
He can,
he,
I believe he would need the UFC.
His blessing.
I don't see another one.
I don't see a world.
I can't imagine a world in which he
doesn't need the UFC is blessing.
What's Rousey's playing?
What's she doing now?
You'd have to talk to her.
Um,
kind of a thing.
I think the,
the type of champion that she was as
good as she was,
as much as she dominated,
um,
I can't imagine that she's not going to
do it again.
Right.
I can't imagine that one fight.
We'll set her back that much,
but she also has massive amounts of
distractions.
She has a huge career in movies.
She's doing giant movies.
She's wanted for commercials and this
and that,
and she's got two book.
Oh,
fuck yeah,
man.
She's a superstar.
But does it haunt her that a girl that
she beat twice,
Misha tate has the belt,
but he's the champion right now and was
talking shit about her yesterday.
Um,
I think,
I think Rhonda obviously had a bad fight
with Holly Holm.
Holly Holm obviously had a great fight
with Ronda and I think Holly Holm has a
great style for Rhonda if Rhonda fights
that way.
But if Rhonda doesn't fight that way,
if she fights the way that meesha
fought,
she stays on the outside and she fights
a little more strategic and she uses
more movement and she incorporates a
bunch of different types of takedowns.
Ron does a champion,
she's an elite athlete and she's one of
the best expressions of judo we've ever
seen in all of MMA.
Her judo is spectacular if she focuses
on that aspect,
on the grappling aspect,
that judo aspect take downs more than
trying to outstand up Holly Holm,
which I,
it looked like she did in the first
place,
but in her defense she said she got
rocked by a big punch early in the first
fight.
So it's very difficult to say how much
that that had an effect on her cause she
did get car wracked by holly like early
in the fight so she could have been out
of it and not able to stick to our game
plan,
whatever it might've been.
It's entirely possible when you get
cracked like that everything goes out
the window.
You never know.
So it's normally only person knows is
the person who got hit.
You know,
cause if we see it like Aldo,
when Aldo fight mcgregor you just got
knocked out because is obvious.
We saw in front of us his body stopped
working but Rhonda could got real close
to that and we didn't even see it.
She could a blang she dropped one in on
her and Rhonda could have been just out
of it like drunk not knowing what she's
doing.
Like literally looking at life through
like a hole in a shoe box that his
entire po entirely possible.
So if they fight again and Rhonda
managers to not get hit like that,
she fights a little bit more strategic.
I could see Rhonda absolutely making a
go at the title again.
Absolutely.
Being a champion.
Again,
she's one of the best in the world,
no doubt about it,
but it's a matter of what does she want?
What does she want to do with her time?
What d one dedicate herself the way she
dedicated herself when she was tearing
up the division.
It's,
it's a very difficult thing to maintain
and especially difficult when you have
the massive amount of distractions that
she has so much Hollywood in her life,
so much Hollywood and money,
so much money,
so much.
You know,
you want to take care of your life and
you've got that.
I think she's the sets the thing too.
I also think she's taken care of man.
I mean Ron has got to be worth millions
of dollars.
Yeah.
I mean if she just lives fairly frugally
and she does,
she's good.
I mean,
she's not buying gold underwear or
anything like that,
you know what I'm saying?
If she's,
she's pretty set.
If she wants to just be set and be a
normal person.
But I got to imagine that fire probably
still burns.
I just,
I can't imagine it doesn't,
right.
I would think that the intelligent way
to do it though would be to have a warm
up fight.
That's what I would think,
you know,
and people would say,
oh she should just go right into the
title fight.
Cause what if she loses it?
Boxing is a reason why boxing has warm
up fights.
They're smart.
If they were there already figured it
out.
We're up.
Fights are good for two things.
First of all,
the name warm up.
It really does warm me up.
It gets you back to competition.
And we saw with John Jones when Jon
Jones recently fought,
um,
when he fought Osp,
we supposed to fight Daniel cormier and
he felt himself and he said it and he
just couldn't pull the trigger.
He was kind of fun,
kind of rusty in there.
It's because he had been out for a long
time,
more than a year with a guy that's
trying to get back at it.
You know,
I think it was critical for him to have
a tough fight against a guy like
[inaudible] who,
who's a world class number six ranked
light heavyweight,
get done under the belt as a warmup
fight,
then fight Daniel cormier and then we're
going to see what's up.
And I think for Rhonda,
it's probably a good idea for her to do
that.
To fight like a top 10 contender,
a tough girl like a Jessica I or someone
like that.
Give that girl a chance.
Give Jessica or Raquel Pennington,
give her a chance,
give her a chance to prove what she can
do and maybe even upset Rhonda,
give Rhonda a chance to get her feet
wet,
get back to competition,
but not be fighting for the title.
So who knows?
Who knows what she's going to decide to
do,
but she's,
again,
she's said no matter what she wants to
do,
it's a matter of what she wants to do
with their legacy.
Right.
It's not a matter of like a financial
decision.
I don't think at this point in kind of
like,
like I'm thinking,
I'm con if I'm caught,
I'm like,
I got to work on my ground game hundred
percent.
It is he doing it?
I'm sure.
Yeah.
There's pictures of him.
He has a brown belt apparently down he's
training the,
the,
the real issue is,
um,
uh,
it's a long road to develop those kinds
of skills at a high level.
You have to be in,
you might look good with a few moves,
like every blue belt,
like some,
some blue belts have like one nasty
armbar.
Like there's like these dudes that do
like a certain technique and they,
they hone that shit down to razor
sharpness.
But if you can avoid that,
how much else does he have?
So it's,
it's like having an argument with
someone.
If someone doesn't have a good
vocabulary and you have an argument with
him,
they might say one thing.
Yeah,
well you're fucking stupid.
And it might work on some people,
but you're like,
I'm stupid.
What about you dummy?
And then he started talking to that
person.
You start talking with a lot of
different words,
having a lot of good points,
saying a lot of things that you know
that they can argue against and then he
starts stunning them.
Right?
That's what a good argument is with two
people.
Well,
if an MMA fighter only has like one or
two moves,
we only have a few things.
You're not going to win an argument with
someone is verbally skilled.
Jujitsu is like that in a lot of ways.
Like someone can have a fairly good
vocabulary and a fairly good
understanding of the world,
but if you were in some sort of a debate
with like Richard Dawkins about science,
like you're going to get fucked up.
You know,
if you debate Christopher hitchens while
he's alive or Sam Harris about religion,
you're going to get fucked up.
They have more tools,
more weapons,
more understanding.
That's the same way with Jujitsu.
It's funny,
I like he said,
Richard,
what's his name?
Richard what?
Richard Dawkins.
He's on a debate team.
He turns a team.
You're about to fuck
the scientists.
They have no idea about the realm of
vocabulary.
It's about to rain on their motherfucker
tones
and they just pound them out.
It wouldn't be,
they'd be like clergy,
clergy been,
they're always debating clergymen,
rabbis,
and all these crazy people that
ancillary.
It'll leave ancient shit.
Listen man,
I gotta get the Fuck Outta here.
Ian Edwards.
Yeah,
so we're going to do some soccer games,
man.
You're going to owe you the world of
soccer.
Oh yeah.
He's going to introduce it to me.
Let me know.
It's very exciting.
It's fun.
It's funny.
Do I know what you're gonna do?
What am I going to come and then you're
going to talk shit.
Well,
I'll tell you what you,
you people,
I'm telling you right now,
you go stop falling down when people
slap you.
Nope.
Nobody likes that.
Nobody.
Nobody likes.
They shouldn't do it.
You shouldn't do it.
It's an MBA now too.
He's in the NBA now.
I don't want to hear this,
but it's just shitty.
Like I,
I've never liked it,
but people do it to get the free kick or
the penalty or to get the other person's
sent off.
It's become a part of the game.
It's unfortunate.
So let's just get that out the way
before you're coming because that's,
you're going to see that.
But besides that,
it's,
it's a,
it's a man's game.
Yeah.
I mean,
get the fuck out here.
When Raquel Pennington choked down,
Ashley,
Evan Smith and blood was pouring down
her face and she strangled or
unconscious with one second to go with a
bulldog choke in the first round.
That's a girl,
135 pound girl.
And you get smacked of running down the
field.
Like,
oh,
this is bullshit.
They hold their mouth.
They roll around like a
baby.
Yeah.
And women.
And when you watch women's soccer,
women don't do that.
Women don't do that.
Women do not take dies and get smashed.
Someone needs to start a campaign.
Maybe we can help and maybe your
podcast,
because you have a,
a suburb.
What is your podcast?
Tell them soccer,
comic rant.
Soccer.
Comic rent.
Maybe we can help.
Alright,
go home.
You fucks.
Or if you are home,
go to sleep or do what it.
Don't listen to me.
Do whatever you fucking want to do.
Much love everybody.
Uh,
Ian Edwards comic on twitter.
Ian Edwards comic on Instagram.
What else was comedian.com boom.
See?
Yeah.