Oh Shit,
I should've tweeted this.
Well you know what folks,
this is going to come out while I'm
tweeting,
tweeting at the same time as the Joe
Rogan experience podcast brought to you
by the fleshlight.
If you go to Joe Rogan.net
and click on the link for the fleshlight
Shit,
I can't do this.
I can't type one thing and think,
well I can't type,
so flashlight.
Is this thing you fuck?
It's a big rubber,
a sex toy for guys and there's a whole
bunch of different kinds.
They have different insights that feel
different compared to the girls like
Jenny Hayes feels a d really believe
Isiah Kira.
Do you really believe that 100 percent
because there's other kind of sewers out
there like wine guys who have like a
really a good palette,
like a little,
a good d,
good Dick Palette.
Like guys,
you can tell the perfect textures,
the way a guy can tell what the textures
are.
Completely different.
A good.
If you got a flashlight.com,
you can actually see what the inside of
each girl looks like.
So like there's different groups.
There's different things in different
girls like you know,
some girls look like they have huge
fucking cysts in their policies,
but it might feel good against your
Dick.
You don't know.
So about.
Yeah,
if you go there,
there's one goes,
I have like crazy bumps and like bubbles
and waves and jagged good things.
So they,
they've,
they create a bunch of different vagina
environments.
Different.
It's like,
yeah,
exactly.
And you get a discount if you go to Joe
Rogan's website,
uh,
it's a Rogan and you get 15 percent off
the number one sex toys for men.
The fleshlight dude,
you're an awesome commercial guy.
You shouldn't do commercials like
permanently.
That's all you should do all day long
because just do commercials.
So it ain't to segway.
Artists were also brought to you by
[inaudible] dot com.
It's o,
n n I t,
makers of Alpha brain,
the cognitive enhancing supplement that
I enjoy.
Uh,
and uh,
we also make shroom tech sport,
which is the quarter sepsis mushroom
supplement for endurance training.
If you're like really into,
if you do something really hard like a
crossfit class or Jujitsu or something
like that,
that's for you.
If you're,
if you're not into that kind of working
out,
you're probably not going to notice a
difference.
Brian has no use for this stuff and not
use this product,
but I'm sure it's great.
Do you do use the shroom tech immune
though?
Uh,
I use the more,
the new mood.
That's what I've been grooving on is the
new moon.
I didn't mean when I feel sick and right
now I don't feel sick.
I just feel like I need to chill out and
that's why I need the new mood because
that's more of like a,
you know,
like calm,
you down,
had some trip to me,
you know,
you like Turkey dinner and now make
that,
that makes you tired when you're,
you're done eating it well.
That kind of get,
that has tryptophan in it and it makes
you feel relaxed and it also makes you a
little bit happier every day.
I think if you take take it every day,
I don't really take it.
I take Alpha brain,
I don't take the other ones.
I changed my workout and the take Alpha
brand and I take the immune shit.
Anyway.
What all this stuff is there.
Nootropics,
and this
is my advice to you if you don't know
what we're talking about,
don't buy anything please.
Just Google nootropics.
There is a lot of really interesting
articles about the subject and it's
controversial,
but I've been,
I've been experimenting with them for
years and I enjoy them and not just the
ones that we sell have used.
Um,
there was a football player,
I think his name is Roman,
asking pretty sure he has a company
called neuro one and apparently he had
dealt with some concussions and stuff so
he created his own formula,
like a neutral but formula to enhance
the way his mind worked and it was
really interesting and I enjoy that
stuff.
I have no vested interest in whether you
buy it or don't buy it.
I if you feel like you don't want to buy
it or you feel like it's too expensive,
I encourage people to steal the
ingredients,
copy it,
and make your own like by,
by the stuff in bulk and make your own.
Yeah.
And I,
you know,
and the other thing is if you try and
you don't like it,
it's you get 100 percent money back.
So we can't make it any easier.
We can't make it any nicer.
And what's most important to me is that
nobody feels ripped off,
that nobody wants to fucking blindly
buy.
Do you?
Don't go to wikipedia.
It's blacked out,
but fucking go to yahoo or bing got in
the other search engines that are not
supporting the soap are against the Sopa
movement.
Soap movement.
Scary as fuck,
right?
Yeah.
Let's talk about that.
Hamilton Morris is here listening.
Go to [inaudible] dot com.
Oh,
N nit enter in the code named Rogan.
Get 10 percent off.
That's a bitches.
All right,
here we go.
Amanda's here.
The other one I talked to for a long
time exploring them.
Joe Rogan podcast.
Hamilton Morris comes here with a video
camera when the podcast in its most
cluttered state possible.
This room is a wreck.
I looked like I should be on hoarders in
this fucking room.
Clean this bitch out is ridiculous.
Too much traveling,
man.
Too much traveling.
You know it is Hamilton Morris.
Hello.
What's up buddy?
Thanks for.
Thanks for coming on.
Thanks for having me.
I enjoyed a lot of your stuff that I saw
online,
man.
Especially for those who don't know.
You write for a.
for Vice,
right?
For Vice Dot com.
That's right.
Vice magazine for Vice magazine.
I think the first thing I ever saw you
do.
You were tripping somewhere in the
jungle.
I don't really remember what it was,
but you,
uh,
you had taken some trip to hang out with
some indigenous people.
What did they give you?
It was the Mirena Indians and they gave
me a.
well,
they actually didn't give it to me.
It was sort of a complicated trip to
find them,
but they traditionally use the venom of
this frog cold fuel,
limited use of by color that produces a
denim that's written all of these
different psychoactive peptides and
specifically contains this
substance called der Morphin.
That's a super potent opioid,
but they kind of,
yeah,
but it doesn't have any sort of like a
classical opioid effect,
like it's not really a sedative and
people claim that it gives them
everlasting energy.
They're able to hunt for days without
sleep and to go days without eating and
all sorts of supernatural feats.
You have a great voice.
By the way.
Can we just say that you're very
mysterious voice and it's very
interesting.
You should do cool shit if you know.
Cool Shit.
And you have a voice like that dude.
Amazing plays.
Sorry.
So what is the effect this,
this,
this?
Well,
that's what I had been told that they
would go days without requiring sleep
and I'd be able to hunt all night for
animals in the jungle with these
Indians,
Jesus.
And uh,
so I was expecting more of a stimulant
type effect.
But then there's chemical warfare,
morphine,
there's no real reason you should expect
it to be a stimulant.
It's an opioid.
There used to be a theory of autism that
was based on them detecting derm orphan
in the urine of autistic children.
So they thought that there was some kind
of bacterial organism in the intestine
of these children that was naturally
producing the Dir morphin.
And so they thought autism with this
kind of opioid mediated pathology,
like,
yeah.
In the same way that you're talking
about endogenous dmt and how that can
cause a psychedelic experience without
ingesting a drug.
This was the idea is that there's an
endogenous intestinal opioid bacteria
that produces derma orphan,
but it's ever been demonstrated anyway.
So I it,
it's never been demonstrated.
So had they come to this conclusion as,
that sounds so fascinating.
It's amazing.
Yeah.
I never heard that theory before.
There's all kinds of psychoactive
substances that have been detected in
the urine of people with different sorts
of mental illnesses.
You know,
there's five mod dmt detected in the
urine of schizophrenia and Whoa.
Totally makes sense.
Yeah,
totally makes sense.
If you think about it,
because we all have bodies,
like people's bodies go haywire,
you know,
things,
things go running.
I have egos,
I have spots on my hand where my pigment
doesn't grow anymore,
so it's like weird shit happens to
bodies.
We easily could happen to your bodies,
your brain's ability to produce
psychedelic chemicals.
Could you imagine if every day was just
tripping all day long?
Like you couldn't get out of tripping
Steph,
licking frogs.
You're licking this guy and paying him
$20 just to get off.
I don't know what you're doing with your
body was producing a drug like a frog.
Oh,
and the that way.
You know,
I don't think it's that way.
Brian.
His body's now
producing a drug.
He's ingesting his body's producing a
drug internally.
You silly boy,
I,
but what if they secreted it?
Who the fuck you're secreting the guy?
No,
no.
If you were producing the drug inside
your body,
if you're urinating secretion frog,
how do they get it from?
They do they actually get five Mao from
frogs?
Can they do that?
Absolutely.
Yeah.
Yeah,
right.
That's really some toads.
Right,
and how do you do that?
Um,
there's different techniques for doing a
nice to know a guy that raised goofball
various and she lives in Boston and his
glands that I just squirted out pretty
much collected at least for two on the
neck and on the legs and he would grab
it by the scruff of its neck and then
take a cat and show it.
The cat is terrified of cats and then
that causes it to secrete the venom.
And then he would pinch all of the
glands onto a glass sheet and dry it.
That's fucking.
Tell you the secrets.
Cat Joe in life,
everything seems cat.
We've been talking about feral cats.
These cats making drugs.
Yeah.
That's incredible.
So you just scrape it up and smoke it?
Yeah,
but it's not just buy them Yo dmt.
There's also apparently some quantity of
Bufo Tinian and also a bunch of other
things.
That's why it's not really safe to eat
it.
The things people were risked to get
high.
No,
it's actually worth checking out.
Really actually used to shop where I,
I'd heard that before in the podcast.
I was doing a lot of research and buying
them in mass quantities when I lived in
Ohio I think.
Yeah,
yeah.
I mean maybe invest in a few frogs and
cultivate a relationship with them.
I mean,
is it illegal?
It may be illegal.
Five immuno DMT was recently scheduled.
So yeah,
it uh,
it used to be you could get in five mel
dmt like on the Internet,
right?
Absolutely.
Yeah.
That's incredible.
They just didn't know.
Um,
I don't think it really poses that much
of a risk in terms of a doubt.
There's very many dmt hospitalizations
compared to even things like lsd.
It's just such a rare thing and it lasts
for such a short period of time.
You can just make it like a frog kissing
booth to get around the law,
you know,
just say like,
don't say like this is to lick and error
to get the drug off of weight.
You know,
if you want this drug and you encase it,
bring you to a doctor,
I'm going to bring it to.
You're going to bring you to a doctor
and he's gonna.
He's gonna.
Find out what the fuck is wrong with
you.
You went too deep in the rabbit hole.
You know what?
When a guest like Hamilton Morris is
here,
I could see where you,
uh,
you get a little carried away.
He just wanted to.
You wanted to,
you wanted to perform on his level,
right?
No,
I,
I just want to go where he is.
Stoner is playing around too much.
You already,
you're not even a professional stoner.
You're like a professional,
a psychoactive expert.
You're like one of those dudes.
So you can say,
hey man,
what is it about that lotus flower?
And you can go,
oh,
well the ludas flower and you'll explain
it perfectly.
How do you know so much about all this
stuff?
Well,
I've studied it in school for years.
I started out studying neuroscience and
a.
where'd you go to school at the
University of Chicago.
So this was something that was just
always pulling at you,
like how the mind works and various
chemicals.
Um,
yeah,
yeah.
Not necessarily with the drug
connection,
but I was always interested in science
and neuroscience and then once you
understand that area,
then it becomes even more interesting.
And then also medicinal chemistry,
pharmacology.
It's all interrelated.
And now how did you start putting
together these videos online?
Um,
well I left Chicago and moved to New
York and a friend of a friend worked at
vice magazine and told the editor that I
had been.
I was interested both academically and
in terms of writing about all of these
psychedelic drugs and they want us to do
more informed drug related content for
the magazine.
So I'm.
So they asked me to start writing a
monthly column,
but vice used to have a totally
different attitude towards drugs in
terms of uh,
you know,
they'd give someone like an ounce of
mushrooms and put them in a hotel room
and just record everything.
They did what was happening.
They weren't really interested in the
science of it,
not that that's a bad thing.
So they used to have that attitude,
used to have that attitude and now
they're more open minded to discussing
the scientific aspects.
So do you think the scientific aspects
for the longest time where it was it
like,
I think it was like maybe a hunter s
Thompson that maybe fucked a lot of
people up because his thing was just
sort of tag on,
blast off and enjoy the ride of it,
you know,
and that you were kind of a fool to try
to quantify it and package it all
together.
Do you think that that kind of like set
that kind of mindset?
Sometimes that means that it's a fun
mindset when you talk about like eating
some mushrooms,
going to a football game.
I mean some people who like looked down
upon that,
but there's other people that you know,
that I actually enjoy doing something
like that.
It's not the spiritual thing.
It's not the full blown psychedelic
connection that you can make.
Yeah,
I certainly do.
It's fun to write
down on that.
No,
I think any way that anyone chooses to
do it is perfectly fine as long as they
benefit from it and don't hurt.
Doesn't like stab people in the process
or kill a dog or something.
If it was legal,
it would be great because then you would
know like what everything was.
That would be the best way to deal with
it.
You the the idea that you just buying
stuff from people you don't know.
It's so hard to cultivate a friendship.
You know where you're trusting someone
to sell you something they're not
supposed to be selling you
again.
You get into a tricky situation.
They don't both parties to the time.
Yeah.
Especially with something like lsd where
who knows where it actually comes from
with something like mushrooms and maybe
you're one degree of separation away
from the source.
It's producing the material and.
But with Lsd it could be 20 degrees of
separation.
You don't even know what it is.
You got to be bold as fuck to eat
mushrooms in the wild
because.
Because just to be sure it is.
I mean there's a few.
Are there few psychedelic mushrooms?
It looked like really similar to things
that are like super poisonous.
Definitely Gallery Ryan and margin Ada,
a bunch of the gala rhina mushrooms look
a lot like the slow subbies and
massively poisonous.
Do you imagine how many people have died
from that?
I don't know.
That's terrifying,
right?
Come on camera.
You're in this room.
Good.
You can just observe.
It's just too weird.
Have a seat,
man.
Have a seat.
Sit Down with us.
We got to include your camera guy.
Otherwise it doesn't feel organic or
feels stared at.
This is Matt.
Everybody mad at the camera guy.
He's here as well because I'm Hamilton
is doing something on isolation tanks
and we're going to check out the float
lab tomorrow in Venice where a crash.
My friend Craig a crash is a mad genius
putting together the baddest float tanks
in the world.
We're going to go check out his stuff
and his crazy cellular influence device.
When did you first learn about the
flotation tanks?
Is this something that you knew for
awhile or did?
Yeah,
I mean,
what?
What?
What gave you the idea to,
to,
to make do this project?
I've always found them interesting.
I think they're pretty fascinating for
anyone that's studied the history of
psychedelic drugs,
just because John Lilly use them in such
interesting ways and also at the very
beginning of psychedelic research,
there were always these attempts to try
and isolate the experience from the
environment in some way when they were
trying to quantify or qualify the
different effects of new drugs in the
sixties and because it's a class,
it's so much based on the environment
they wanted to try and figure out a way
to remove subjects from the environment
and test them in some kind of an
unbiased setting.
And the two ways they had were sensory
deprivation tanks in these Ganzfeld
devices.
No,
no.
So,
um,
you sit,
you were talking about it earlier.
You've,
you've only had one century and it was
quite awhile ago.
It sucks that it's not more readily
available,
you know,
I think,
uh,
if you could just get into it for a
little bit,
you know,
if you get into like a regular thing,
like even just once a week,
that's great man.
If you could find a place that has it
and it's like a massage.
I bet like I just recently got my first
massage and I always kind of went,
you shunted off just because it seemed
weird to me and I got my first one.
Now I get it,
you know,
it was just nice relaxation,
it's not that expensive.
It's really good for you too.
I think it's really good to have someone
that be affectionate to,
even if it's just,
you know,
someone rubbing you with their fingers,
like that's really,
really intimate.
You know,
we're pretending that it's not sexual
because it's not touching your growing.
But when some big fat,
sweaty woman who really knows how to
rubberneck when she's getting in there
with lotion and everything,
the ladies fucking giving you affection,
they're giving you affection.
The rubbing your legs when someone's
rubbing your feet.
Yeah.
They might as well be blowing you when
they're getting their heel into the
little children,
to leave the genitals out of the picture
because that's the person who's doing.
They're being affectionate to you.
You're paying them to be ultimately
affection to you because yeah,
it works the muscles.
And yet increases,
you know,
a blood flow and yeah,
it breaks up scar tissue.
It's great therapeutically,
but it's also great because it's
affection.
What if they finished it off with like,
like rocking you in a chair where they
held you for like 20 minutes at the end
and they were just like playing with
their hair at the very end,
like a baby or something.
That's how that would work.
This is like that extra $10 they'll do
that.
They said to do the whole thing.
I remember there was a place I used to
go to and they,
uh,
they arrested one of the dudes there
because he was a,
he was given dudes massages and blow
jobs.
He was like blowing a lot of the gang
guys.
And so they caught him the win.
I'm like,
look,
he's just trying to make his customers
happy.
You know?
What is customer one?
Exactly.
I mean that is what the guy wanted.
He wanted to do it too.
Who got hurt there?
They should have that for everything.
Well,
as long as it's really clear that that's
what you want,
right?
Because if you're like a straight guy
and all of a sudden he's blowing you and
you're like,
dude,
wrong signal.
Yeah,
but if you're a gay guy,
fuck.
Really?
We try to stop that.
Why we try to stop that.
Hamilton Morris in 2012.
Why math?
The camera man.
Matt the camera man.
You can talk,
brother.
You're allowed to talk.
So it's crazy seeing the internet all
blacked out today.
Like say Google and Reddit and a tedious
Hamilton.
Yeah,
I noticed it.
What did you think about the soap?
A thing?
I haven't read enough about it.
I mean,
I think it's horrifying if it is what I
think it is,
but I'd like to do a little more
research.
You can even read about wikipedia was
blacked out.
It represents a trend.
It represents an attempt in whatever it
is it's trying to control or having the
ability to control the Internet,
but reality is they can do that.
Now,
if the government wanted to step in,
like if you had some crazy al Qaeda kind
of website up,
they can shut you down and trust me,
it's not gonna do anything but create an
underground tunnel.
We're all going to use and it's going to
be really.
You're just,
you're,
you can't lose.
You're going to lose against the
Internet if you tried to do this anyway.
If you tried to start banning websites,
if you tried to like start monitoring
people,
they're.
The Internet will find a hack for it.
Just like they do every single iphone
that day before it's released.
You know,
maybe,
I don't know.
Who is they?
You know,
who's been,
who's ultimately going to be in control
of it and what you know is it,
is it really?
Is that what's going on?
I don't think there's a vague.
I think what's what's happening is
people were realizing as more people get
more access to information,
that they're not buying the bullshit
anymore and the only way to stop that is
you're going to have to limit their
access to information.
You're going to have to be able to
control them.
somehow another box them up.
You gonna have to be able somehow to.
The trend is giving information freely
through these fucking cell phones and
wireless Internet connections and
they're coordinating meetings and then
people are setting things up and they
can't stop it.
They can't control it and that's driving
them crazy,
but they can also work through the
system.
Like when you think about how many
wikipedia entries are written by the
pharmaceutical companies that are the.
You know,
how much wikipedia material is actually
advertising in one way.
Really.
I mean,
of course,
if anyone can edit it,
who wouldn't take advantage of the
incredible resource?
Yeah,
I would imagine.
Yeah.
I mean it's not all good.
It's not.
It's not perfect,
but it's the best way.
The best way is let the Internet sorted
out.
The best way is not the government
controls the Internet.
That's the worst way.
That's the worst way possible.
A bunch of people are willing to go to
war.
They get to control the Internet.
Fuck you.
No,
you don't.
That's crazy.
You fucking resource hogs.
You can control the Internet to Jesus
Christ.
You know you'd steel in minerals in
Africa and stealing oil in the Middle
East and trying to jack the Internet.
It's the same motherfuckers got.
Damn it Brian.
I blacked out my website today.
Did you really?
Yeah.
I don't know how to do it.
Yeah,
it didn't really poorly and quick.
I just changed the logo.
Made all the texts gray,
dark gray.
Do you feel like you're a part of the
movement now?
I feel a little left out.
I feel left out.
Well,
NBC would probably be pissed off at you
if he did that.
Probably if I blacked out my shit.
Yeah,
because I mean the people that are
asking Sofa is all the big media giants.
You know all that Darlin's that want to.
Google's not back.
Wikipedia is not entertainment studios
like Disney.
NBC.
Well,
yeah.
I guess they will be the ones who could
benefit from a crackdown.
You've got to think about how much money
has been lost.
Now there's my question.
A lot of people have gotten things that
they didn't deserve because they kind of
download them illegally maybe,
but how much money was lost was really
any money lost of wonder.
I wonder if like I wonder if it didn't
exist with those people have gone out
and bought it.
Is that what you're saying?
Or would you say maybe they just
downloaded it
on a whim and maybe if they like it they
might tell somebody else,
maybe somebody else.
My buyer.
Like it's possible that it's not causing
any loss,
you know?
I mean,
I don't know.
It's definitely a lot seminar.
If you look at go to a movie theater
nowadays.
It's not like it used to be.
People are downloading shit.
You think that's what's going on for
real?
Hey,
I,
I hate to admit it.
I used to do it.
I used to know I downloaded every single
movie allegedly that came out that
weekend.
Allegedly.
I mean I might be a character,
an idiot.
I'm scared to like a typical guy on the
Internet,
you know?
Okay.
Yeah.
I don't think it's.
I don't now I don't do that shit.
I don't think it's that,
I think if,
if the movie theaters are empty,
it's because of the economy a and
because of the movie is suck.
A lot of movies suck.
It's hard to find good movies and that's
the problem.
Like it's,
it's weird going to the movies nowadays
and taking a girl on a date and spending
$80,
you know,
it's like,
wait a second,
what happened to like $6 movie tickets
instead of $20 movie to cause inflation
bitch.
But that's what I know.
But that's one of the reasons.
There's a movie theater that's in
Pasadena by the ice house w that we
walked by and yet the movies were like
one or two weeks old.
They weren't first week,
maybe they weren't old yet and they were
like,
I think $3 tickets.
That place is cool.
What's the name of that place?
I can't remember.
It's off of Colorado.
I love when you find a place like that.
Yeah,
it does something cool like that place,
like just slightly old movies.
Really cheap.
Super cheap.
That's how.
Yeah,
I can wait.
I'll wait.
I'll support your cool business and it's
kind of a retro movie theater.
It's not new at all,
like it's old school,
what you remember in the eighties when
[inaudible] came out and you're like,
Ooh,
coolest movie experience Evermann we
were playing at the Houston livestock
and uh,
who is that stupid movie that they made
about,
uh,
some kids in the woods and it was like a
witch Blair way.
Blair witch project,
right?
Isn't that it?
That it was like a fake documentary
style,
which we wanted me and Chris Mcguire
watch that.
These guys came down to the show and
then afterwards one of them worked at a
movie theater and he said,
you guys want to go see the Blair witch
project?
Like right now just to us.
I was like,
Oh shit.
So it was me and him,
my buddy Chris and a couple of his
friends and we just alone in the
theater.
He turned the thing on,
like he literally had the keys and we
watched the Blair witch project alone.
Wow.
That was fucking awesome.
So the only way to watch that thing was
it was the perfect way to watch that
movie and I tried to watch it again and
it was fucking terrible.
Second thought,
it was terrible.
I tried to like,
I dunno,
recreate the moment.
Did you hear that Mcdonald's has to now
put up signs saying that their French
fries cause cancer that there.
Yeah,
it's in,
it's something that's in French fries,
potato chips,
coffee cigarettes at the chemical was
produced through the browning process.
You know,
like when they put the fries in the
Fryer,
it causes cancer.
Like that Browning Browning of what the,
I guess
the oils that are in it or whatever.
And uh,
so they have to put up signs and I guess
there's ways around it,
like they don't have to use do it the
browning process or they could do it the
baking process.
But that of course would take long.
The thing with fries,
it probably makes it super clear.
It's interesting,
there's the browning process and it kind
of makes sense because you know,
they say that if you eat meat and you
eat it like,
like,
well done.
Like the carbon,
the outside,
it's like really not good.
It's like the,
the,
the black shit that people love the
crispy outside.
It's like really bad for you.
Yeah,
that's the worst part,
right?
I think it is a fucking weird people,
men.
But they're so delicious.
That's the most taste,
best tasting cancer ever.
What did you say that's the best tasting
cancer.
Oh,
by the way,
a lot of people got mad at us because of
this last podcast.
I had a fucking bunch of annoyed people
with me on twitter.
Why?
Oh,
I don't know man.
There was a couple of people that are
annoyed that we're vegans and one guy
might have overreacted to because I just
get tired of people in their Hashtag.
I'm Vegan,
like they say something and then go
vegan.
And he was a saint because we were
talking about um,
uh,
animals getting killed in processing
plants.
It does happen,
you know,
groundhogs,
all kinds of animals die know it's not
when you buy plants from a store.
I mean,
unless you're a grow your own organic
setup and you're doing it all yourself,
chances are in the harvesting of the
plants,
some animals are going to die,
unfortunately even more.
What's that?
Maybe even,
I don't know if it's different.
It's like mice,
these,
uh,
you know,
the area is going to be devastated
unless you have some like,
really good setup or it's like,
you know,
great composting.
I mean,
unless you're doing it all yourself for
your own food,
if you're doing it all yourself for your
own food,
that's one thing.
But if you're buying some shit from
whole foods or from wherever it's coming
from a farm somewhere,
even if it's organically grown,
you don't think some animals are getting
jacked.
Oh yeah.
There was an article about doe in
Australia at least it's a,
a greater total loss of life,
but it's a different type of life if
you're a vegetarian than if you're an
omnivore because,
uh,
because of all the mice that are killed
in the process of harvesting Greens.
But I dunno,
it doesn't totally make sense.
But again,
I don't,
I don't think this is where they're not
ridiculous.
They're sensitive people and I can
understand that.
Excuse me,
I can understand that,
appreciate it.
But it's,
um,
it's just,
it gets annoying that I'm Vegan.
It's like it's this self self righteous
air to it and there's a weird thing that
it's okay to live,
to eat some living things.
It's okay to kill trees.
It's okay to kill plants.
It's okay to kill fruit and vegetables.
Okay.
To kill that.
You can kill it.
You could chop that fucking let us read
out of the ground and it's debt and then
you eat it.
That's okay.
But it's not okay to kill an animal
like,
well,
when do you,
when do you draw a line?
Is there any distinction that would.
If the animal was just meet,
it was just meet with a heartbeat and he
couldn't think and it just sat there.
If it didn't,
if you didn't need it,
somebody else would.
Is that okay?
At what point is it okay to eat an
animal and other life form?
Is it only stuff that can't move
already?
So we're sensitive people.
What you should be asking for the like
even responding to that because who
cares what other people eat and what
their views on.
You know,
I think there's certain cruelty
associated with factory farming and I,
I agree with this gross.
It's horrific.
You know,
I try to avoid.
I try to avoid cheeseburgers except in
and out,
in and out.
It's pretty fucking spectacular.
Five guys burgers.
I hope those cows were treated well.
If I had known they were treated well,
I feel much better about it.
But the reality of you by Kentucky Fried
Chicken,
are you by any sort of meat product,
from any fast food,
anything you're buying something that
did not live a happy life,
you know it's going to be the cheapest
meat they can possibly get you.
Right?
I mean,
isn't it right?
Africans fiberglass,
right?
Like,
look at Taco Bell's meat.
I don't want,
you know,
I don't think vegans are silly.
I just don't agree with it.
I don't agree with it.
And I don't think we should be.
I don't think we should be treating
animals the way we treat people.
I think we should be kind to everything
we can be kind to.
I definitely think factory farming.
It's fucked,
but I think regular farming,
it's pretty goddamn natural.
I mean,
it's what people have been doing
forever.
Yeah.
As long as you're not abusing the
animals,
it's,
it's what people have been doing for
forever and those animals.
I mean,
who's to say that you're not supposed to
take out cows?
That's silly to me.
Someone's going to take them out.
Is it a Jaguar?
The Jaguar is and take them out.
Can people take the cow out?
We can't.
You're talking about extremeness though,
unlike most people don't believe that
even even most like normal anti cruelty
animal companies or whatever they're
called charities,
uh,
even them,
they still believe in,
you know,
humane killing of animals.
But the,
the,
what you're talking about is people that
are just like nothing.
No,
you can't.
Well,
there's definitely grades,
right?
Yeah.
And that's only a small amount of the
people at Joe's,
like you're talking about like the three
twitter,
twitter followers or whatever is.
But it's,
you know,
it's a significant chunk of the
population.
I think there's a lot of people that are
like really upset at any idea of any
cruel to whatsoever the animals and you
know what man is because they love their
animals.
I totally get that.
I did love their animals and I totally
get loving wildlife,
but you know,
the idea that they're going to live
forever if you don't eat them.
Like,
what the fuck's happening here?
No,
don't eat animals ever.
Okay?
Who's going to eat them?
Then block them.
The fuck's gonna happen.
You're gonna,
you're gonna.
Go around and gelding them.
You gotta to make sure that these elk
don't fuck because otherwise they're
going to be everywhere you ever go to.
There's a town in Colorado called
Evergreen,
beautiful,
beautiful place.
It's amazing.
It's up in the mountains and it's,
um,
you,
uh,
there's a certain part of town where you
can't go anywhere,
uh,
at a,
during certain migrations because the
elks,
we'll just walk down the main street.
It's fucking amazing.
There's like a hundred elk.
There's a photo of them and there's like
a herd of them and they're walking down
the middle of the street.
It's like,
wow,
what a crazy place where you live,
man.
A herd of elk,
just Walkman.
You know?
If,
if it wasn't for people shooting,
those elk herd would be 200.
The next year it'd be 300.
There's not enough predators.
Like unless you want more mountain
lions,
unless you want to start bringing in
mountain lions in your daily equation,
you've got to do something to get rid of
those elk.
Look,
they have to shoot those fucking things.
We want to live there.
You're going to have to shoot a deer or
fucking terrifying.
If you've ever been in a place where
deer are like super plentiful and you
can't drive safe now Ohio,
it's ridiculous.
There's deer flying all over the place
and there's.
You wake up.
Normally I would wake up at my,
at my dad's house when I lived at my
dad's house and see a deer,
like,
like every week I would see a couple in
my backyard.
Yeah,
and if you're driving home at night,
that's the main streets are right next
to my dad's neighborhood.
So I mean obviously that's dangerous.
Yeah.
Somebody is going to eat them.
You got to eat more of those.
Yeah.
I've never actually had deer.
I've never had any of that craziness.
You've never now I sending you're
vegetarian or anything?
Oh yeah.
How long have you been a vegetarian?
Since 2009.
But occasionally.
Is it a um,
health choice or is it a,
um,
I think it's just generally encourages
me to be more conscious of what I'm
eating because otherwise I'm more
inclined to eat,
just gross fast food and things like
that.
And I think my diet,
it's improved enormously since I became
a vegetarian.
Yeah.
The more plant matter you can get in,
it seems like you just feel better,
feel healthier.
But goddamn need is delicious.
I eat what ash occasionally do.
No red meat or anything along those
lines.
I have my theory that the,
uh,
said it before,
that the stuff that's the quickest is
the best for you.
Like deer,
deer is really good for you because
they're hard to get those motherfuckers
they run because they got like really
good meat cows.
It's pretty good mate.
What's tastes like?
I don't know because it has to be the
best.
Get a Cheetah Burger.
Oh Damn.
People will be like,
no,
don't eat a cat.
Yeah.
Isn't that funny?
I bet you,
but nobody wants you to eat a cat.
You can't go hunting tigers and eat the
tiger.
Tiger meat was fucking delicious.
People will like you dick.
But meanwhile that tiger would hunt you
dummy.
I'm not saying tiger should be extinct.
I'm saying if I lived in India I would
think tiger should be extinct.
Not necessarily,
but definitely if I lived in the.
I say they've canceled alone.
What about big ones?
Man?
Man.
Leave him alone.
Fucked up bro.
You ever see a real one?
You just have like a cat thing that you
would have to do at tiger about to
attack.
You just throw.
It was like a piece of paper the other
direction and run,
you know,
or something like that.
That will work.
It probably does.
There's probably like,
like in,
in their instinct that they will do
that.
Yeah.
I wonder if there's like any people that
has ever tried that.
Dude,
I can't even believe you're asking that
question.
It might be DNA stuff.
It might be.
You got to high before the show,
just a red ball when clients come in and
see what happened at Hamilton Morris.
This is a ridiculous show I brought you
onto.
I apologize.
But then again,
I don't.
It's fun.
I'm just kidding.
Um,
so you,
you've been doing this a vice.com
thing for how long now?
Since about 2000.
Seven.
Two thousand eight.
Is that full time your thing?
No,
I worked for other magazines as well,
like writing stuff,
writing for Harper's as well.
But vice is the main.
What was it like when you sat down with
that a shogun character?
What is that guy's name?
Alexander Shogun.
Yeah.
And he's like some crazy super chemist.
He's really brilliant.
He's,
yeah.
That was an amazing interview and that
was really different,
you know,
people kept writing me saying,
Oh,
you're so lucky.
You're so lucky.
But it was incredibly difficult to get
that interview with them and it took.
So it wasn't like a luck thing.
Like I just like,
hey,
we found a Kooky guy for you to
interview.
Go visit him.
I had to,
had actually been to his house a couple
times beforehand and I had to be vetted
by his family and all of these things
because a lot of people don't understand
what he does and uh,
and he's harassed by people.
There's this ridiculous idea that
inventors are somehow responsible for
what is done with their creations.
So people think that if somebody dies of
an MDM,
a overdose,
that he is somehow responsible for it,
which is of course totally ridiculous.
Wow.
But you know that mentality.
Yeah.
There is that mentality which is pretty
silly.
The legalization of any of this stuff
would require people to go over dosages
and be scientific about it.
And if,
if,
if any of this stuff was legal,
it was legal.
If you could just be prescribed for
being prescribed,
if you could have a doctor that would
say,
you know,
you're pretty sane.
I think you could handle ecstasy.
So he prescribes you a little ecstasy.
Go have a party this weekend.
You know,
I don't know about that.
But I think using it as an adjunct to
psychotherapy is not that far away.
Well,
you think so you really think they're
gonna accept that there are certainly
trying to.
The organization maps,
that's pretty much what they do.
Yeah,
I'd read that.
They've made great strides with people
as well with posttraumatic stress
disorder,
which is not surprising.
I mean I think a lot of this stuff that
maps does,
it's just proving these things that most
people understand intuitively,
but it has to be demonstrated in a
rigorous scientific fashion before and
the regulatory authorities will accept.
That would really help a lot.
No doubt about it.
They would restructure society if,
if people would allow.
We're allowed free use of psychedelics.
Everyone looks at it as such a frivolous
issue,
like so silly,
you know,
like why,
why,
why and concentrate on such things.
What a tiny do.
Trying to get high.
You know,
if you talk to most people about
psychedelics,
you feel like you're stuck in the 19
fifties movie.
What are you trying to do with your
life,
kid?
What do you want to do?
Mess with those mushrooms.
Put that stuff down,
get yourself square,
get on the straight and narrow,
but the mushrooms down boy,
isn't it?
I mean,
doesn't that seem like that?
It's a.
it's not a subject that's easy to be
approached.
Seriously with adults.
There's not a lot of them that will
engage you in it.
In the regular world.
You want to talk seriously about
psychedelics and seriously about
positive effects of them and mushrooms
and know who wants to talk
to you about that stuff.
Yeah,
I mean now most of it has to be shrouded
in scientific research.
What if you were working for an
insurance
and you were like one of their top sales
guys,
but you're running around the office
telling everybody that got to do acid.
You know,
I guess I don't even really know what
public perceptions.
I mean I have an idea,
but it's so hard for me to go into like
to really understand what it would be
like in middle America or something if
you worked at an insurance office.
Well,
I think it's different now everywhere
because of the Internet.
I don't think there is necessarily a
middle America that's the same middle
America there,
there,
there were some innocent parts of the
country or countries where things were a
little quieter or slower.
But I think because the access to
information that people have today,
I don't.
Kids can learn a lot of shit online.
Even if their environments socks,
they can develop and be engulfed and
whole communities online and they can
evolve so much quicker.
So this is like groups of people that
evolved like in small towns now that
would have,
they wouldn't have existed to three
decades before.
You know,
I think that's,
that's one of the big differences
between now and you know,
I try to think about what it must have
been like to be my parents to grow up.
You know,
the Internet doesn't come along until
you like
way too old,
barely getting into it.
You just go on CNN.com
and check things and whether the big
thing.
I remember going to the library all the
fucking time.
Like that was like the cool thing to do.
Random movie.
Go get a book.
Libraries must be fucking hurting right
now.
They're not doing as well as they've
been doing before and why libraries are
doing great.
I think so really?
I would just think that it's easier to
get information without going to the
library and now my mom doesn't even go
to a library morning.
She would go like multiple times.
Most people have access to a computer.
Then there's all these subscription
services that are too expensive for
people
that are individuals to use.
So it's like if you want to use factiva
or scifinder or lexus nexus or any of
these databases,
scientific databases,
you have to go to a library or awakened
me.
Right,
right.
Of course.
So if they're always going to exist in
some form,
it would be too expensive.
There's reading books is a different
experience than reading a kindle.
I don't know why I'm mad.
I don't know why.
Oh yeah.
It's kind of better.
I don't know why though.
I don't know why I like turning pages,
you know?
I don't know why.
I feel like I've actually thought it
with me.
I think it's softer.
I think once the technology gets up,
which is already here,
but went to get the technology because
we can kind of feel like a cottony feel
or I use a kindle,
I use a kindle,
right?
I mean I do have one of those things,
but if I had to choose between that,
like if I had the book and it was on the
kindle,
I would take the book with me.
Do you smell your books before you read
them?
No.
You'd never seen,
never smell your book before.
Do you ever smell your book?
I have no books before.
I like that little muskie.
I shouldn't say I've never smelled like
smell when I'm reading.
We have.
It's cool until kindle has that ability
to like holding your hand in it.
It's its own thing.
Like that book was great and it smells a
little weird until it has that kind of
real feeling to it because right now
it's just like you're looking at a piece
of glass,
like a words on,
on a screen.
It's,
it's you disconnect from that.
The last used book that I bought was a,
the sacred mushroom and the cross is the
only way to buy it.
You was used until young Ervin just
rereleased it and data.
Did you.
You've read that right?
I
familiar with it.
I've read part of it and read it cover
to cover and I've read part of the
second book as well was at the end of
the road or something like that.
It was a sacred mushroom in the cross
and then there was the other one was
goddammit.
Turn back time.
Something in the Sea Scrolls and the
Christian myth.
Something along road.
Yeah.
I do home care before a sacred mushroom
and the cross.
Is it just A.
Yeah,
it's Bible scholar.
that's a,
that's the idea.
And then he,
uh,
he was the only one who believed that it
was all about mushrooms that the entire,
the Christian religion,
like a big part of it was about
fertility.
Rituals and mushrooms.
Yeah.
But even that you,
I don't know if you're familiar with the
book,
shroom by Andy Lead her or letting her
know.
What's that?
Oh,
it's good.
You should definitely check it out.
It's really a pretty impressive piece of
research,
but he in the book and then he goes
through all of these different mushroom
myths,
but he talks about a sacred mushroom in
the cross and claims it allegro never
even believed that,
that that he was just so.
He hated Christianity so much at that
point in his career that he just was
looking for some way to disprove it or
dismiss it or make it look ridiculous in
the public eye.
Whoa.
That's awesome.
If that's true.
Holy Shit.
Damn for it.
Part of me doesn't want it to be true
because it's such a great story.
I really.
You could say,
look dude,
the Bible was about Dude's tripping on
mushrooms and I really wish it could say
that and that's what Rick Strassman is
trying to do now with,
at least with the Old Testament in dmt.
We're really.
What is he saying in psalms speak
relatively recently,
and he said that he has a new career
goal,
is to go through all of the old
testament looking for instances of
altered states of consciousness that
might be indicative of some kind of a
dmt type experience.
Well,
yeah.
Yeah.
There were some recently.
There was some guy.
I'm a scholar from Jerusalem that was
proposing that about Moses and he was a.
The Moses,
his encounter with the burning Bush
might've been some reference to the
Acacia Bush,
which is very high dmt content.
Absolutely.
Yeah.
No,
that's how he saw God.
Yeah.
I've already got a legit scholar.
I forget the gentleman's name,
but he was a legit scholar who is
bringing up this connection to possibly
know psychedelic experiences.
And then I've also heard a theory that
the ark of the covenant was a Meth Lab.
That's awesome.
That's a fucking great quote.
That's a kind of quote you here and you
go,
damn,
I wish I wrote that.
Your architect covenants a meth lab.
Do you ever hear those people that
believe the Ark,
the Ark of the covenant actually exists
and it's in,
um,
what part of Africa is it?
I don't know.
I only know about it through Indiana
Jones.
I've seen the photo.
That template.
Is it?
Ethiopia,
Ethiopia.
Good.
Graham Hancock was one of the guys who,
uh,
that's what got him interested in,
these,
uh,
alternative views of history.
Zeros,
I believe it was Ethiopia.
And they have this area that's guarded
and these,
these,
these monks,
it's guard that they have like a 20 year
lifespan.
So powerful.
It's so sexy.
It's really.
Shit was true.
Uh,
you know,
I really,
I don't know if it's true,
but I don't want to anybody to disprove
it.
I think it's been investigated.
I think the discovery channel or someone
did a special.
I really haven't.
I wanted to do it thing.
What Hancock had said was that no one
was ever allowed to get anywhere,
even close.
Maybe it's politics.
That's what he said.
But here's the map of it on Indiana
Jones to,
during one of the cutaway scenes where
it's just like that,
that plane,
a dotted line,
just find it through there.
I don't think it works that way.
Could you just completely interrupted my
train of thought?
I don't know where I'm going now.
You know.
Let me,
have you ever heard of [inaudible] Lane?
What is he?
And it's that America's oldest brewery
and it's in Pennsylvania and it's used
to be this beer that living in Ohio.
People I know would go to and stock up
with truck folds just so they could have
it for like a year.
Why?
Uh,
because it's,
you know,
it's really good.
It really is.
It's older than Budweiser.
Budweiser came out,
supposedly stole their Eagle Logo.
Is this a new sponsor?
Worked in doors.
You can't even buy it here in
California.
So they stole the Eagle and Budweiser
stole the Eagle and used it in their
logo.
And now you decided to come to Ohio.
Uh,
the first week sold out the entire,
like,
like ipod style,
like they had to build a whole new thing
on their factory just for Ohio now
because I had an everywhere you went
beyond that,
that's all everyone served.
Everyone else was drinking that.
It was like the craziest thing seeing in
Ohio when he went back home,
everybody was drinking this beer and
it's fucking pretty good for just like a
Shitty,
cheap light beer.
But everybody was drinking.
That's how bad Ohio sucks.
They get excited about some shit.
Beer Budweiser's heard get so fired up
and they band together to support some
shit.
Beer Budweiser's hurting from it.
How bad is that?
Beer?
It's a really good.
Come on.
I wish I could give you so many.
You could probably get in Chicago.
No,
you probably can't get.
I like Sam Adams.
Is it like that?
Uh,
they,
yeah,
they have different kinds.
They have like lights,
they have lawyers.
They have.
I mean it's,
it's really good to work for them.
Place the oldest brewery.
It has to be the best.
They're going to fucking like the first
one.
I don't know what's going on here.
I think he's.
I think he's broken into an impromptu
commercial note.
You'd like it trial if you ever get the
chance.
Alright.
Pennsylvania for finals is a impromptu
commercials.
Not only do I swear to God,
Dude.
Get the fuck out of here.
Don't play anything from.
Okay.
I believe it.
How dare you never heard of it.
I know either did I don't give a fuck.
Beard.
That's crazy though.
But the budweiser story was really
interesting.
I thought like how they took the logo or
the mascot.
Eagle.
Dude.
Everybody wants an American Eagle.
What about goodyear tires?
Will they have an American Eagle too?
It was not an American Eagle in there
somewhere.
What about the same as.
Wow.
It's pretty close.
It's crazy.
I mean,
there's a slight difference.
Budweiser is the led Zeppelin a beer.
So that's what you're trying to say.
Maybe they stole it from Budweiser,
you know.
No,
no.
They've had it longest subtle who?
There wasn't even a company when it came
out.
Settle down.
Son Hamilton.
Morris.
I apologize for everything.
Everything you've experienced so far
today.
And this,
uh,
strange ride.
Um,
so,
um,
do you want to do this,
thing about isolation tanks?
What's your,
uh,
your goal when you try and get out of
this?
I'd like to use one of the tanks myself.
I want to try specifically those tanks
that you were talking about earlier that
have some kind of an auditory and visual
component.
Yeah.
He's got that all set up,
man.
He's got it set up where he's got videos
of it.
Were they using the sound and they're
playing like music and you could see the
waves in the water because the speakers
were actually like floating in the water
and they're,
they're like set up right by your head.
And the waves are like making the water
splash and jump and wiggle.
It's pretty fucking tripping,
man.
Yeah.
It's pretty trippy thing that's going to
be also affecting your body while you're
in there.
You know,
you're going to feel sound on your skin.
Yeah.
Fuck yeah.
You will get it.
Yeah.
You're going to hear it in your,
in your ears and you're going to feel it
on your skin because it's like moving.
That's moving through the all the water
though.
The whole thing is rippling while
they're doing this.
It's really pretty one.
Wait until you hear it because your ears
are under the water.
Here's the under the water and it's not
distorted by the water.
I don't know.
Could be on big notes as possible.
Things like really splash around.
Well,
what does that feel like?
That's to feel nutty.
I'm curious.
Yeah.
His idea,
Scott crashes,
idea is that he's going to develop,
um,
like how to tutorials for sports and for
all sorts of different things.
Music,
language.
They'll be able to teach people language
is much quicker and that in the sensory
deprivation environment with the lack of
external stimuli,
your brain will be more focused.
So it sounds like it does sound like the
lawnmower man.
You're right.
It does.
Does he do these nootropic injections
beforehand or something like that?
That's what he should do,
right?
We've got to give them some fucking
nuclear shit.
It's like an x men type situation.
Yeah.
The,
um,
the idea behind it is fascinating.
You know,
the idea that you can program the mind
better inside the sensory deprivation
state.
It really makes a lot of sense and it
seems like it would work that way if you
really get someone really knew what they
were doing to design some cool programs,
you know,
we think that would be like the best way
to learn ever.
Especially if you learned something
cool,
but it'll be a would be distracting your
concentration and the campaign.
That's what I would think if you got
comfortable with it.
See the thing about the tank is once you
do it for a long time,
you know you do it a couple times,
like four or five times.
Once you,
once you do it,
he know what it is.
You can just settle right in and once
you settle right in,
then stock it distracting at all.
It's going to be wild as fuck floating
there,
watching some just image appear right in
front of you because you can't really
see that the light is so dim that all
that comes through is the actual image.
You can't see the outline of the box.
Have you ever been to one of those group
massages where there's a shitload of
people in one room and then they're
playing like,
like a movie that's on loop,
like on the wall of like a house,
you know,
in Asia somewhere like a bird's flying.
See,
I find that annoying and distracting.
If it was pitch dark,
I think I would be better for sure.
And I think that's how like when you're
relaxing and one of these isolation
takes any kind of,
you know,
sound or anything like that,
that seems like it'd be distracting.
You're absolutely right.
It would be.
And I have never gotten into the video
or audio thing that's scarred crashes
thing.
I like to go in and just chill on my
own.
But I think it's fascinating.
I mean I'm not opposed to trying it.
It sounds really nuts.
And if he could ever figure out how to
really hook it up and do it right,
I mean what a great way to like learn a
language or something.
And what a great way to like,
you know,
could you imagine if you took,
like if you found out that you could
develop a course specifically for use
inside the isolation tank,
like the optimum way to learn things and
memorize things and put them to use and
you show that you could make people
learn Spanish 10 times quicker,
something fucking nutty like that.
So you wolves on loop at night,
like walking slowly just to go against
your fears and stuff like that.
Yeah,
if you could really get it to the point
where it becomes a Hologram,
that would be the ultimate entertainment
experience.
Dude.
You're living in a hologram.
You get in the isolation tank and they
put whatever Hologram you want on.
Yeah.
Okay.
Let's do the Amazon jungle.
Boom.
That would be wild.
Wouldn't be wild.
And you get to watch like a movie.
Get to watch a life take place in front
of you,
sister,
act to someone to about you.
Don't even paying attention.
That's what reality is going to be.
Eventually it's going to be,
you know,
opera.
You know you're going to have options to
be able to choose where you want to do
today.
Give me an eventually.
It's got to get to a point where we can
construct reality.
I mean,
I know that they've,
they've devised artificial realities for
video games.
They looked pretty fucking spiffy.
You know,
when you're watching a good video game,
like,
like what is it like metal of honor,
one of those games that were there,
that's the name of it.
It's one of them called call of duty in
comedy.
You watch those,
those video games like that's the
graphics are fucking absolutely
incredible out.
How long is it before they can project
that into your head?
How long is it before?
Instead of looking at that amazing
thing,
someone figures out how to projected
into your head that's going to happen
and when that happens,
that's going to be an alternate reality.
They're going to be able to program it
alternate reality,
and if you,
if your consciousness,
if they can figure out a way to lock
your consciousness onto that alternate
reality,
it's almost like putting you in another
world.
It's almost like putting you in another
dimension.
Yeah.
Is that possible?
I think it is.
Yeah.
That seems like what's gonna Happen,
right?
Primitive forms of it are already
possible and things like that.
Those implants for blind people that
allow them to see what the camera and
the go.
Oh yeah,
I've heard about that.
Into their brain.
Jesus,
you can input visual stimuli instead
still probably far away to everyone can
do it like xbox seven,
$7,200.
Right.
It's like how we look at like the old
cowboy style photographer dude who had
to throw that thing over his head,
remember and he had the big torch on his
hand and it would go off.
Do you remember that?
Like when like all the wild west movies,
the guy would like have to get under a
tarp and shit to take a picture.
Do you remember all that?
And think about what that was.
There was like,
there was no fucking movies like shut
up.
They could barely get an image.
Everybody at a stand still,
you know,
you had to like really wait,
like how long did it take to take that
picture?
Yeah,
took a little time,
right?
Yeah.
You couldn't just move around and wasn't
like instant.
Think about that was only 200 years ago.
Right.
That's amazing.
That's fucking incredible.
That is 200 years ago and now we're
complaining.
I wonder if all the shenanigans that
happen,
like having to sit there with your
family and then like one of the kids
would fart and you know,
there was probably all these little
things that always happened during those
photos.
You know,
still there was probably some humor
that,
that was lost and that we went after to
that anymore to hold their face.
Right.
I liked a lot of blurry pictures from
the.
Oh yeah.
Usually the kids.
That's why the kids are always the
malaria post photos is that his people
would walk in and out of the frame and
you made nothing.
Drives me crazier than fucking ghost TV
shows.
When I watched those ghosts TV shows and
I just go,
you're not gonna find anything while you
fucking with me.
Never find anything,
there's never been a bigger cock tease.
Then the ghost reality genre and they're
on like season three or something like
this.
Like,
look,
can you see this?
ECTOPLASMIC enters the room.
It's like a speck on the screen.
It was like this.
This is where the ectoplasm enters the
room.
This is where the.
What the fuck did you say?
Like you asshole,
you know they have a fucking ghost ghost
hunting.
You're not fighting shit.
Shut up.
Every fucking shows.
The same thing.
There's some people in a dark room
watching something through night vision
and someone goes,
what was that noise?
And then they go to commercial and then
they come back and it's nothing.
It's ridiculous.
My mom,
I just got back from Ohio.
My,
my home,
my mom's house is supposedly haunted,
like,
like my sister used to always talk about
it and then my mom is now talking about
it and my Stepdad,
he's like,
he owned the architect firm and he's a
really smart guy,
you know,
huge corporation this guy had.
And then he retired and he's a farmer,
you know,
he's just a very intelligent guy.
And he said he saw it the other day and
then so it's just like,
all right,
you guys,
stupid fucking gas leak or a mining leak
somewhere that's giving you likely he's
fucking your mom.
Right?
That's what if you came to me.
Okay,
what if there was like a sour well near
my mom's house farm?
What's going on here man?
I said,
well,
she's probably a little wacky.
I think there must be something,
some kind of feelings going along with
her.
Radon gone bad.
The might be man.
You know you grew up at a desktop radon
radon test in your basement.
Do you remember?
How about the shit that was on apple's.
Oh yeah.
What was that?
That was that,
that chemical.
They use the spray that fertilizer on.
Is that what you're talking about?
Remember,
there was a something
that was on apples that were saying was
dangerous for it.
Do you remember that?
No.
Fuck Shit.
What was it?
And I was.
I don't remember what the fucking
chemical was.
I'm sure twitter will let me know on
twitter.
Somebody please tell me what's the
fucking chemical was something or
another.
Oh,
all something you remember,
something like that.
I know exactly what you're talking
about.
Wherever
my dad actually has a patent to get
radon out of your basement that he used
to build these machines for rich guys
that like only you these so like maybe
50 of them is totally legit.
No,
it is.
It is legit.
Yeah,
it's definitely an element.
I'm sorry.
It's hidden in people's homes.
Is it a health issue
really,
really have to worry about.
I don't think so.
I don't know.
I've never heard of anyone I knew dying
of radon poisoning,
but how did they get brought up?
Do you know?
How did it become an issue?
I guess some people died somewhere.
Well at some point they must have and it
does exist.
It is a element that leaks out of the
earth and news that you've radioactive
gas that's nasty.
So it's just a natural part of.
Yeah,
no,
it's not a result of nuclear testing or
anything like that.
It's a totally natural way.
So do you think that people died because
there's just some areas where it would
just come through and heavy doses and no
one anticipated it?
Is that what it was?
I think it's heavier than oxygen,
if I remember correctly in sort of
settles on in basements and your floors
and people sleep impulse of it and just.
And you can get radon poisoning,
but you know,
it starts in your respiratory system and
then you just start like wheezing and
coughing a lot and shit like that.
It's actually pretty crazy that it was
so popular,
but then it just died off like they were
still probably getting this.
They did.
Did they find something new?
Like oh by the way,
right.
I'm poisoning is actually just now.
It's all about outside.
Yeah.
All it takes is like one death somewhere
and then all of a sudden everybody
starts chasing after him and he could
have been one extreme example that was
very,
very rare and then everybody started
chasing it and it's sensational stories.
If you have one good story about someone
dying from some invisible chemical or
even a drug or there you go.
He's going to drug
I won Pennsylvania to highest lauren's.
That's where their beer.
So good,
isn't it?
He's men.
When you,
when you stop and think about that.
So many of the different things that
you've talked about are not illegal,
you know,
different psychoactive substances.
Like when you were talking to a Shogun
guy,
like all the different things that he
was talking about,
the different tryptamines and how many
of them are illegal.
A lot of them are
illegal.
Five mud,
apt DMT.
Lot of them are maybe 11 or 12 of them,
maybe more.
Probably about a dozen.
Tryptamines are illegal schedule one.
Uh,
yeah.
No,
it's ridiculous.
And a lot of them never had any real
popularity in the first place.
Drugs like doe tea or something,
or tma two were never particularly
popular substances.
Could you imagine if something like five
Meo dmt killed as many people year
cigarettes does?
Wouldn't that be amazing?
Could you imagine how people would
react?
What a crisis they would be.
We've got to get this off the streets.
Did you imagine with me one on one
cigarettes,
do it.
It's like,
well,
you shouldn't have been.
Yeah,
whoops.
Whoops.
Yeah.
I mean,
I wonder if nicotine would be legal if
it were a recently discovered substance.
Probably the nicotine is not as much of
an issue.
I think there's.
I think a lot of is all the other shit
they put in them to make it even more
addictive.
They say that if you smoke cigars,
you know people that smoke cigars,
first of all,
you're not inhaling it,
but you're getting like a real pure type
of tobacco.
It doesn't have chemicals on it and it's
supposed to be not nearly as bad for
you.
It's not great for you.
It's not the best thing for your sucking
on a crazy fucking plant that gives you
nicotine all day,
but what it is is a better,
healthier version of that tobacco and
that the 599 different additives that
the food and drug administration allows
cigarette companies to pump in a
cigarettes to just to make a mostly make
them more addictive.
I think.
Believe that movie with.
What's his name?
What's homeboy's name?
Fucking gladiator.
Dude was so crowded,
so grow.
Remember that movie played a dude who
was like the scientist who knew too much
about cigarettes,
used in a real story that was terrifying
if any of that stuff,
and I moved,
I can't even remember the movie,
the movie's name or the actor's name,
but they don't even need to.
I mean nicotine is incredibly addictive
without any kind of mysterious
additives,
but then there's also the Beta car
booleans in tobacco that may give it an
additional addictive component because
they may improve mood.
When that movie he was talking about,
and again,
I don't know how much that movie's
dramatically.
I think it's based on a real story
though,
isn't it?
I'm going to him.
I remember I remember it being based on
it or something like that.
It was terrifying to think that a
company would be so evil that they would
go out of their way to try to use
chemists to make their shit more
addictive and you're like,
wow.
Like that's a.
that's a really nutty choice.
Five hundred and 99 is a lot.
When you find out they have 599
different chemicals they add to
cigarettes.
We're at one of the editors don't really
even make sense.
I've looked through the list that don't
really stand wind eight shoes like what
dean or.
Yeah,
purity and would be an example
disappeared.
Then it's an aromatic six membered ring
with the nitrogen in it that that is
just smells really bad and you wouldn't
think that it would have any maybe to
counterbalance just tons of stuff.
It's like all these different.
Just bad.
That's all it does as far as I know.
And the quantities that they would be
using it.
I can't.
I mean maybe it's like a in a really,
you know,
in the same way that like Indole and
very,
very small quantities.
Smells like jasmine,
but then in large quantity smells like
shit.
So some of these things that smelled
bad,
it's probably used for smell to,
to sell a cigarette.
Smoker doesn't smoke and they smell a
cigarette.
You want a cigarette?
Bad.
Really?
One hundred percent.
It's like having an apple pie.
When Apple Pie comes out of the oven and
you smell apple pie,
you're like,
fuck,
I want that Apple Pie.
Same reason.
They're probably making a smell,
well,
I don't know if they're making it so
attractive to people,
but they'd probably making it more
attractive to the people that are
smoking it.
It's weird that it'd be a stinky thing.
You say a stinky thing.
It's probably a mixture of different of
stinky things that
make the semester.
Some of them were just smells and so who
the fuck knows know?
Like I said,
according to the Russell Crowe movie
that I can't even remember the title.
Right.
They like done some deep research on
hooking people and deeper and deeper
with all these different 599 chemicals.
It's just ridiculous.
That's too many.
That's a lot.
It's very complicated.
It's ridiculous.
Even when you're looking at the
interaction of two chemicals and once it
becomes incredibly complicated,
think they constructed that lead me
your.
You understand that field.
How did they do that?
I mean,
I'd have to look through the list of all
the additives,
but I don't know.
I mean,
it could just be,
you know,
even things like any candy that any
child eats probably has an equivalent
number of different chemicals in it.
Um,
you know,
people that the word chemical always
sounds bad,
but it was 599 chemicals,
but there's a guarantee,
599 chemicals in this,
in everything,
in everything.
So it depends on how you want to phrase
it.
I don't know.
I'm sure the majority of those chemicals
are benign,
but maybe 11 of them do have some level
of function.
The are based on some tobacco industry
plan to addict people,
but I really do think that nicotine in
and of itself would be enough.
I think those are the people that smoke
those natural cigarettes,
those like in what do they,
do they experience less addiction?
Uh,
no,
actually I,
I think that's where he hit me harder.
Like I wake up spitting up like buckets
at boobs,
you know,
like just like having roommates hooks
them.
And is it just a major film producer?
Maybe it's like a,
maybe some chemicals that cigarettes
make,
make it so that Burns easier.
Oh yeah,
definitely.
I mean like,
like what most people smoke I would say
is Marlboro lights or camera lights or a
light cigarette and it's more like
having a diet coke.
It's just like,
you know,
you just want a little taste of the
chemical and a little smoke,
but you're not.
But then you get these guys that are
like smoking.
Marlboro reds were.
It's like having a little cigars,
you know,
it's harsh.
It's.
Have you ever seen the wonderful whites
of West Virginia?
No.
You've never seen it?
What is it?
It's a crazy documentary that uh,
they did all these people that live in
West Virginia that have been notorious
family of outlaws and wild people.
And there was a woman and her name was
sue Bob and I swear to God that was her
voice has always been a sex.
He wanted a family and just go and you
just stop and think about that.
So lifted cigarettes do to her man.
What did cigarettes do to her?
Nobody sounds like that when they were a
woman without cigarettes.
Like it's only cigarettes that they give
you that.
I mean,
maybe some crazy exotic disease,
but that's what she sounds like.
It's amazing.
If you've never seen it,
man,
if you just want something silly to
watch,
it's so well made.
It's a beautiful documentary.
Johnny Knoxville's production company
put it together.
It's really awesome.
It's about this family.
They're just awesome characters,
man.
They just live in West Virginia and they
sell pills and they're just always
getting arrested.
It's just wild,
man.
It's so crazy
to watch.
It's really,
really fun.
But cigarettes.
Fuck that chick's voice up.
You did.
We didn't talk about that.
That guy that.
Uh,
what's his mic?
Fannie Mae,
Fannie,
whatever that guy's name is that's
running for president in the marijuana.
A Mitt Romney,
Mitt Romney man.
Alright.
Yeah.
That about him in the marijuana patient.
We remember we were going to talk about
that.
Yeah.
That's crazy.
I talked to you about it before we even
did the show.
It was so.
It was so sad to watch someone.
It could be so callous about his ideas
like that when some,
if you haven't seen it,
Mitt Romney,
guys running for president.
Very,
very wealthy man standing in front of
this dude in a wheelchair.
Guys like 80 pounds,
man,
I think he said he had muscular
dystrophy.
I apologize if I'm wrong about that,
but you know,
he said to Mitt Romney that he needs
medical marijuana and that medical
marijuana is the only thing that that
helps him.
And Mitt Romney said,
have you tried the synthetic form?
And he said it,
it makes me vomit and marijuana is the
only thing that helps me.
Would you put me in jail if you became
president?
Sure.
Let's play it.
Let's see if it sounds good.
All right,
let's see if it sounds good.
It's really depressed and old video that
just really just became popular.
Really.
Okay.
It's so good.
I have all my life,
my doctor saying that I want to that
medical marijuana for everyone and you
have synthetic marijuana that's
available and other that I have tried it
and it makes me throw up.
I have tried all the makeup and all the
forms that come in after high
stimulator.
The steroids.
I have muscular dystrophy that's
completely against my DNA.
I'm sorry to hear.
My question for you is will you arrest
me and my doctor's medical marijuana?
I'm not in favor of medical marijuana.
How are you?
She just turned away from the
politician.
Smile.
Hi,
how are you?
He asked if you were going to arrest
patients like him.
Governor,
you're going to just ignore a person in
a wheelchair.
I spoke to them,
but he didn't answer his question.
All right,
well this is good.
So disturbing.
This is what we're doing.
Hamilton Morris,
I think you got a good voice and you
should run for president.
Yeah,
I'm pretty sure you could pull this off.
Why not?
All right to it.
I don't think he's enthusiastic.
Not Patronized.
It's shocking though,
isn't it?
That a person like that could be like
even close,
remotely close to being able to run
things the bit that you would be so
cold hearted.
Just walk away from that dude like that.
That's like a serious issue,
man.
You got to address that issue.
This guy's telling you there's something
that helps him and he's obviously in
terrible,
terrible straights.
The guys fucked up,
man.
He can't move,
his body is in a God damn wheelchair and
he's telling you this.
Something happened against this,
against his will.
This is,
this is something that he's saying helps
them make them feel happy against his
pain,
and he even said,
I'm not for legalizing it for anybody.
He goes,
not for everybody,
but for people that you can use it for
medical purposes.
It works.
It's you just walk away from God like
that,
you know?
It's just disturbing that anybody would
be so flippant with the idea that it's,
it's so.
It's so preposterous.
It's so gross to them for some fucking
reason.
I don't know what it is,
but the idea of altering your
consciousness anyway,
other than the sanctioned ways that
we've prescribed to for the last several
decades,
anything that steps outside of that
becomes a danger.
I don't know why,
man,
why you told me,
I dunno.
I mean it's not a majority view.
I don't think.
I think it had to do with a few people
who,
you know,
when you think about it only takes a few
people to make these enormous changes in
drug policy and like,
I don't know all that much about the
history of marijuana specifically,
but it was like that one guy primarily.
And then with the psychedelics,
it's the same kind of deal.
It takes one person to die at the wrong
time and you know,
one person dies after smoking.
Salvia,
the guy,
Brett cit,
esther,
and then it's illegal over 10 states.
Dude died,
smoke itself,
you know,
he didn't even die.
I mean,
there's,
there was a teenager named Brett cit,
esther who wrote in his diary,
I love Salvia it,
uh,
but I also understand that life has no
meaning now or something like that.
And then a few days later he killed
himself and his mother looked in his
diary and said,
oh,
it was the Salvia than even suicidal and
went on this crusade to have it band in
every state that she could and was
successful in something like a dozen
states.
It's called Brett's law.
Wow.
But that's the way it always is.
It's always one person that there's like
the that act based on the person that
bought morphine on the Internet and
overdosed.
It just takes one promising.
All the mushrooms and the Netherlands
are now illegal because of care off the
girl that jumped off the bridge.
Just one promising person whose photo
looks good on the news dies.
And that's the end.
But what did she do?
She got mushroomed up and jumped off the
bridge.
It's unclear.
I mean that was the,
the official idea that was written in
the news.
But then when I was in Holland recently
working on this new project for VBS,
we were at this place called magic
truffles,
which is the largest mushroom,
or was largest mushroom farm in Holland.
They make metric tons of mushrooms in
this factory.
And,
but then mushrooms became illegal so
they converted their entire operation to
producing psychedelics.
Clarissa.
But they say the whole thing is a scam.
They think that,
uh,
that she wasn't even on mushrooms at the
entire thing is based on a friend seeing
her with a box of mushrooms in her hand.
But on the day of the death and then
they put two and two together and
decided that she must have been on
mushrooms,
which he died.
Oh God.
So she could have just been depressed.
Yeah.
I don't think there are any toxicology
reports that confirmed she was under the
influence of any psilocybin at the time.
I can get not wanting to give it to
everybody.
I just think there should be places
where you can get at where someone could
walk you through it and you should be
able to make an educated choice.
There's just so many people shouldn't be
denied the experience because I think
the experience makes people more aware
and more sensitive and that.
I only think that that's good.
I think the world can use a lot more
aware and more sensitive.
So why aren't there centers set up?
Why is it still illegal?
That's where it gets completely,
totally ridiculous.
It gets to the point where you're.
You're keeping something that might be
beneficial to a lot of people because
some people might fuck it up because
some people might fuck with it.
Do something crazy.
It also has to do with fashion in
science and medicine,
you know,
it became very unfashionable in the
eighties to do psychedelic psychotherapy
and uh,
and there were only a number even in
places like there certain parts of
Germany where any,
any psychiatrists that wanted to could,
and they chose not to just because most
people weren't interested in it for
awhile.
They thought it had limited potential
and now I think the potential is,
you know,
there's the renewal evolved,
the psychedelic research,
but in the eighties people didn't think
it was even people that were pro
psychedelic drugs,
they just didn't have,
a lot of them didn't necessarily think
that it was a viable road to producing
important neuroscientific research or in
terms of psychotherapeutic drugs.
Yeah.
I recall hearing a Mckenna interview
where he was talking about that,
about how scientists were often like
discouraged from going down those paths
because people would say like,
you know,
there's not really nothing there for
you.
Well,
yeah,
it's hard.
It's hard to.
It's difficult to quantify the benefits
of psychedelic drugs like a lot.
There's a lot of anecdotal evidence that
they have lasting effects on people's
lives and that they have relief from
depression or alcoholism or things like
that,
but when it comes down to really,
really putting it down on paper,
it's been difficult and an often it's
things like the Johns Hopkins study
where silicide been occasions long
lasting mystical experiences.
That famous paper,
a really recent one.
Yeah.
The reason why it's getting a huge
amount of press,
but it's amazing.
Yeah,
because they said that it improved their
personalities.
Yeah.
But even that is kind of slippery when
it's a mystical experience.
All these terms are slippery and if you,
you know,
when you look at a nootropic that was
very defined studies of how something
does it aid road into navigating amaze,
does it allow them to,
does it allow a human,
does it prevent the formation of certain
types?
Disease or proteins in the brain are
things that that are indicative of
neurodegenerative diseases,
but there isn't anything like that for
psychedelics.
There's no single benefit that can be
quantified.
And uh,
and I think that's one reason that it's
difficult for researchers is.
And then there's ways around it with now
a lot of people try to emphasize the
positive effects that are not
necessarily psychoactive,
so maybe they have some kind of an
immunosuppressant effect that would be
useful for our,
uh,
for arthritis or some kind of
inflammatory disease or something like
that.
That's one of the,
you said that because there was
something I was reading just a couple of
days ago about people juicing cannabis
and that doesn't have any psychoactive
effects,
but there's a lot of great health
benefits.
Absolutely.
Using it in cbd,
the non psychoactive Terpene,
one of thc and cbd are the two main
chemicals in.
So would you juice it like a smoothie,
like blended up?
Oh,
I don't know about.
I don't know about this specific
technique,
but cbd is not psychoactive and has all
kinds of a medicinal effects.
Like it's currently undergoing clinical
trials as a treatment for schizophrenia.
So I mean,
in addition to the psychedelic effect,
there may be all kinds of things we can,
you know,
maybe neuro regenerative,
maybe synaptic Magenic,
maybe all sorts of different things.
The marijuana one is the biggest trip
because it's got so many excellent
properties yet it's illegal.
It makes the best paper.
It makes the best clothes,
like the fibers.
Excellent.
You can make like wall board out of it.
There's like four times stronger than
plywood.
It's like a really incredible plan
because it's super strong like have you
ever picked up a hemp stalk?
It's really weird,
man.
It's like from another planet because
it's really fucking strong,
but it's light.
It's shit.
Like you pick it up and it's like this
is a weird kind of wood.
If it seems strange and it has so much
fucking potential as far as like you
could like you can grow like a massive
forest full of it,
chop it all down and then have another
massive forest like six months later,
a year later when it's renewable,
you could do it over and over again and
all the health benefits,
all that.
It's like it's from another planet.
It's really crazy drug.
When you think about all the good things
it does,
it's great and it had.
The seeds are awesome source of protein.
It has all the essential amino acids.
It's actually good for you if you juice
it,
if you smoke it,
you get high,
you feel amazing.
It's like it couldn't do any more for
you.
Come on man.
You can make paper out of me.
You want to make clothes out of me dude,
you can eat my oil.
My oil is really good for you.
It can power cars too.
It's like I'm renewable every six
months.
I mean it's like it couldn't be any
nicer to you.
It couldn't be any more of a productive
plant.
Know as far as like society just uses as
you know,
as a quantity,
as you know,
uses as a something that you could sell.
Absolutely.
And it's the same thing with mushrooms
as well and if so many benefits beyond
just being
vessels for carrying these psychoactive
drugs.
You know,
I think Paul stamets did a lot of
experiments with the Defense Department
using either a p scion essence or as
their essence and using them to d
phosphorolate,
seren to break breakdown nerve gases
because in the same way that all of
these enzymes in the mycelium that are
able to break down the cellular
components of the substrate,
whether it's wood or grass or some kind
of seed,
it's able to break it down and extract
all of these amino acids and then bios
synthesize chemicals out of it,
but uh,
but it can also break down all other
kinds of substrates,
like there's all this bio remediation
where they use mushrooms to clean up oil
spills because the mushroom mycelium is
able to break down the aromatic
hydrocarbons in the oil and to totally
detoxify.
You can even eat the mushrooms
afterwards.
Wow.
I,
I'd heard of it
about something like that,
that they use things like that in
Alaska.
Is that what they experienced?
That,
where that was the before the Gulf
incident.
That was like the last big,
right?
Yeah.
They tried to.
They wanted to do it in Japan as well
too,
to clean up radioactive waste because
you realized the mushrooms to
bioaccumulate radioactive fallout and
then pick the mushrooms and slowly
decontaminate and area.
I mean it's an extremely slow way to do
it,
but it also effective.
Wow.
It would take hundreds of years.
Well,
what other options are there?
I mean that's the thing.
Imagine that's the best way to do it,
but then once you get the mushrooms to
eat it and then you have to pick up the
mushrooms.
The mushrooms are still radioactive,
right?
That's right.
For how long until the decay of the
radioactive atoms.
Hundreds of thousands of years.
Yeah.
So it's essentially just moving the
problem to another area.
Yeah,
but at least you're concentrating it.
It's better to have like a 20 drums of
radioactive mushrooms in a concrete
vault somewhere than to have it covering
100 miles of land
eventually.
Panting is so terrifying to me because I
have no understanding whatsoever how
nuclear power works.
I just always took it for granted.
You never even thought about it.
I never.
And then I just recently found out that
it's about making steam.
It's about like somehow or another loop,
the nuclear thing.
It's like the power comes from Steve
Powers things,
steam turbines,
steam turbines.
I'm like,
wow.
That seems like so old school,
you know,
it's just,
they're using this super powerful fire
to boil water.
You know what I mean?
It sounds ridiculous.
I mean,
my,
my simplification of it sounds
ridiculous,
but when you find out that their spots
now where there's just no one's ever
going to be able to go there.
And then when you can't go there,
you can't go there.
That's fucked for forever for.
We probably won't even be people anymore
because you know,
100,000
years ago we weren't even this,
right?
We were like barely this as a,
as an organism where we're essentially a
little bit more of a monkey than we are
now.
By the time that shit's done,
what are people going to be like?
By the time that's not radioactive
anymore,
we're not even going to be people
anymore.
We'll probably be some new shit.
We all have autism
and it will probably be just like the
grays dude,
just crazy.
Something like that to the graded trip.
He's going to happen.
We're going to be assimilated with the
machine.
Yeah,
that's my conclusion.
Yeah.
Assimilated with the machine.
What do you think's going to happen?
Something's going on.
I don't know.
I mean,
Think about it.
I do think about it.
I just don't.
It's difficult if anything seems
possible.
It's just like with any.
Any issue where it seems as if it could
go one way.
I certainly am a pessimist ultimately,
and I'd like to be an optimist.
Are you a pessimist as far as the
potential that the human race can reach
or as you put about the possible
outcomes?
Are you a pessimist about people in
general?
I mean,
I got into an argument with a Daniel
Pinchbeck recently about,
about,
about aliens,
and he has this very optimistic idea
that if aliens.
He told me he goes,
definitely exists.
He,
he believes a lot of things that I
definitely said he's very open.
Well,
I enjoyed talking about before we say
anything further.
Oh yeah,
no,
I enjoyed talking to him.
Yeah,
just playing.
But uh,
so,
so what happened,
aliens.
We were talking about Stephen Hawking
and Stephen Hawking has this idea that
if we ever do make contact with aliens,
the best move would be to ignore them
because if,
if they ever come to our planet,
the chances are they're not only going
to exploit us but destroy us.
I mean,
you didn't say exactly those words
would.
He generally has a,
a pessimistic view.
And I think that that's a well informed
intelligent view.
There's no reason to have an optimistic
view about that,
but Daniel Pinchbeck seems to have this
idea that,
uh,
that,
you know,
touristic Gilliam friends and we'll
drink sweet.
So sweet.
Um,
I don't think so.
Look at,
if you look at every single organism
that we can observe on this earth,
it takes advantage of the week or
organisms,
including the most intelligent.
We take advantage of dolphins.
We put them.
Absolutely.
That's exactly what I was saying.
As we look into killer whales,
we don't give a fuck.
We put,
we locked them up in tanks and we know
they're intelligent.
We just can't understand them,
and so we forced him into slavery that's
not mentioned humans to humans,
the keys to the doors and we we,
but with animals that we don't
understand,
intelligent animals,
we understand.
We regularly enslave them for people's
enjoyment to watch on television,
and then we believe somehow or another
that some super intelligent organism is
going to show different behavior than
what every single organism on this
earth,
including the highest us,
the most aware us.
We do it worse than any of them.
We do it worse than dolphins.
We do it worse than killer whales.
We have chimps.
We locked chimps up.
We don't give a fuck.
You make humane people.
People that love to still keep them in
or people that love champs,
keep them in cages.
People's love.
Dolphins keep them in tanks not
literally kept himself into the tank,
so even if they were trying to be nice
to us,
who's to say that it wouldn't be some
nightmarish.
It's fucking hell for that dolphin,
man.
It's got to be hell.
They're.
They're intelligent.
They're just.
They just can't change their
environment.
We know they have dialects and they have
crazy Alexis societal and you
know dolphins have.
There's this,
they have a huge attachment to their
family and their loved ones to just
snatch one up and stick it in a fish
tank.
It's fucked up,
but we do it.
Why would we think that aliens wouldn't
do that to us?
We are crazy.
Could you imagine if you came down here
and you watch all these little pink
monkeys with their fucking bank stigs
and nuclear weapons.
You found out that people had nuclear
weapons.
You know,
you see him at home,
slack,
jawed watching the Kardashians.
We have nuclear weapons,
the same animal.
You know the same animal and it's all
going on right now.
Imitate aliens who is probably cute.
Want to shut this whole fucking show
down?
You'd be like,
you're going to ruin this whole planet.
You stupid fucks.
You would want to come as we would for
sure.
Shut this planet down.
If we came into an area and there was a
budget champs and the chimps had machine
guns and tanks and we would shut that
fucking place down.
There's no way we're going to let some
chimps start running shit.
We would take all their weapons.
We'd go Jesus Christ who gave chimps
these fucking tanks,
what chimps do and flying around in
jets.
We would totally steal their shit.
Who would never allow that image of
chimps started coming into our towns and
stealing our cars and shit.
There'll be a real issue.
We wouldn't allow that.
We would take our shit take from those
dumb monkeys and that's what they would
do.
They would come down,
they would steal our cars or iphone.
Excuse me.
That.
How'd you figure this out?
You fucking dummy.
They would take your iphone.
Oh,
check you out.
Look what you did.
Did you figure this out?
Think about the average person.
How stupid there.
And they have an iphone in their pocket.
Boom.
And they don't know how to use it.
Yeah,
so pinchbeck thinks so they would all go
IOWASCA style.
Yeah.
They would have a song prepared.
Hello humans,
we want to.
We prepared this for you.
We will eat at the buffet is the day the
Earth stood still the other day?
Have you ever seen that?
I have been since I was a child.
Wow.
It was amazing.
It was like I was watching a movie.
It was Kinda cool.
You know,
it's kind of cool because you know,
you put yourself back in that sort of
like old school comic books,
style of storytelling.
They did in the fifties and the innocent
days when they made that movie.
But the other thing was like,
oh,
how naive like the portrait of like an
alien,
what it would be and you know,
just how naive the situation was in the
military and every obvious bad guys and
good guys,
like how naive but yet,
how do you know who even now there's
really no impressive concept of aliens.
That's what.
I don't know if you're familiar with
this science fiction writers Stanislaw
Lem,
but he wrote Solaris and his master's
voice and all these books in.
His main idea is that humans can't
conceive of anything that is truly
alien.
We're only looking for ourselves in the
universe in anything that was truly
unlike us.
We couldn't even imagine.
Right.
So even like the movie alien still isn't
thing.
Not even like it could be a living ocean
or living planet,
write a plan,
and with consciousness,
that's always been a fascinating idea
that everything has some sort of
consciousness,
you know,
whether or not a expresses pain or even
feels it or can't communicate that
everything has some sort of a,
a type of consciousness will definitely.
Our idea of life is generally very
narrow,
like a budding field of astrobiology,
which is just a speculative science,
but even in astrobiology textbooks from
a couple of years ago,
there would be no mention of the
possibility that,
uh,
that arsenic could replace phosphorous
in bio molecules.
It didn't even seem like a possibility.
And now we know that that can happen.
How does that work?
What,
what happens?
There was like a,
a lake,
I think it's in Nevada that had
extremely,
extremely high levels of arsenic in the
water.
And this researcher is last name is
felice.
I think a collected bacteria from the
lake and found that they were producing
dna and amino acids where the
phosphorous atom that's present in a lot
of these molecules was replaced by
arsenic.
Whoa.
Yeah.
I had arsenic poisoning from eating
sardines.
I told you that,
right?
Yeah.
I ate too many sardines.
I was eating learn Qantas or deans a day
or so.
Funny.
Who does that?
No one.
The only person that likes sardines.
Are they a good source of arsenic?
Why?
Apparently,
or at least sardines there they feed on
heavy metal or will they don't feed on
heavy metal,
but they feed at the bottom of the ocean
and that's where a lot of pollution as a
lot of the heavy metal pollution and
they,
they get a concentration of arsenic not
enough to really to make you sick but
enough that shows up on tests.
So you get your blood checked and he
said,
who should have some arsenic in there?
What the fuck is going on?
Like someone's trying to kill me slowly.
Or is it sardines?
Turns out it was hard Ns.
Hmm.
What if you could get turquoise point,
like poisoning,
like if you like constantly ate a little
bit of turquoise everyday.
Like if is turquoise toxic.
I don't know.
It's in stone.
Yeah.
But if you like,
shaved it down into a powder and put it
in some proteins and stuff.
I don't know.
I don't know what the chemical
composition of voices,
but you just don't study show that
doesn't get you fucked up.
No,
I do.
How do you know what?
It's the best thing ever.
It's a pretty.
Maybe that's.
That's a terrible question,
but it leads to a half decent one.
How do you think they've discovered all
the psychedelic substances on earth?
Or do you think?
No,
not even close.
When I first saw Alexander Seligman's
work and saw call,
I was discouraged by it because I
thought that it had all been done that
every single possible psychoactive
tryptamine and ethylamine had already
been sent in from people who don't know.
Picasso is Phil.
What is it that I had known then that
means I've known and loved and
tryptamines I've known and loved in
there.
These two enormous thousand plus page
books written by a chemist in California
named Alexander Silgan and they contain,
knew least about 100 drugs that he's
synthesized and these two chemical
classes in each volume and it looks
pretty comprehensive.
It looks as if he's evaluated every
imaginable psychedelic,
but that's only a fraction of what's
possible.
I love that interview that you had with
a man because I had never seen a guy
like that in the wild.
I'd never seen some super chemists.
Dude is created like God knows how many
common auditory.
So how many times has he created
something,
some new cool thing or discovered some
new cool things.
It's hundreds.
Yeah.
How many has he documented?
It's amazing,
right?
Enormous,
enormous.
Don't incredible.
And that he's sitting there just
rattling all this information off to you
and you were like a fucking kid in a
candy store that you could tell.
You were like,
wow.
Like you couldn't believe you were
hanging out with him.
I'm so cool that the enthusiasm,
like it really came through like the
your honest enthusiasm to be hanging
around with this guy.
It really.
You had an educated sense of reverence
about what he's done.
So it's like when you addressed all
these things,
like you could tell that you had this
great joy in getting this opportunity to
talk to that guy.
Oh yeah.
It was really cool.
I love him with a passion.
He is one of the most amazing
scientists.
Talk a little watch that.
What is,
how can I find that?
What is it?
If you type Hamilton's Pharmacopia,
that's the name of my show on vbs.
Uh,
you can find it on vice.com
through the video section if you just
look for Hamilton's Pharmacopia.
Uh,
but yeah,
I mean he's in it and I seen him quite a
few times since then and it really is a
privilege because his entire methodology
is one that's not followed anymore.
It's like it seems very antiquated to
most young people and even
pharmaceutical researchers,
the idea that,
that,
uh,
anyone would take a drug that they
synthesize is ridiculous,
but that totally,
totally normal.
They used to be the way drugs are
developed.
The chemistry invented Ritalin,
took it after he synthesized it and
tried it and didn't really get much from
it.
Then he gave it to his wife Rita,
and she loved it and said that it
improved her tennis game and so he named
it after her Rita Lynn.
Oh Wow.
But that kind of thing was calm and
improved her tennis game because it's
essentially like speed,
right?
Yeah.
It's like cocaine or how does that work
with kids where it makes them,
you know,
kids who were really rowdy at calms and
down.
How the fuck does that work?
I mean,
there's a bunch of different proposed
mechanisms that are kind of complicated.
But um,
I don't really know how it works.
That's always been.
I've,
I've met a couple kids that are on
Ritalin and it's always been a very dark
sort of a moment when you realized that
these people are drugging their kid,
you know?
Uh,
I don't know if some people need it,
but I know some people don't need it.
I've seen some kids that are just a
little bit rowdy and they need attention
and not getting it.
Then all of a sudden they're pilled up.
That's a disturbing thing to watch.
Yeah.
I think it's with.
Especially with very young children
around high school,
College Age,
and especially when the mom crushed to
the down.
They snort it like in the wonderful
whites of West Virginia.
The wild and wonderful wives.
They were snorting pills as after friend
after she gave birth,
she gave birth.
She was in the hospital.
Remember that?
Didn't have seen some of this.
Actually.
It's fucking fabulous.
It's like watching.
If you,
you turned
monkeys loose and let them live amongst
people.
How they live.
They would live like these people.
These people are wild.
They're fucking
why y'all?
They're a different breed of human being
here.
You're in here rattling off all this
scientific knowledge,
neurochemistry and Pharmacopia and
there's people that could breed with you
and they're there.
My name is access one in the family.
It's amazing.
It's all going on right now at the same
time.
Oh Man.
We had a guy on a that was talking to us
about,
uh,
about hunting.
His name's Steven Rinella.
Who was on the last podcast and he was
telling us about,
he was in Africa and in Africa.
He was hanging out with these people
that have to hunt for their food every
single day and he was out to go with
them,
but they have an internet connection.
They don't really have electricity.
They have a generator they can turn on
for like an hour or two at night,
but I can't.
I can't keep it on the can't afford it.
It's hard to get gas out there.
They have arrows and bows and shit
they've made themselves and yet they
check their email and you can friend
them on facebook.
That's all going on right now.
At the same time.
It's amazing.
Yeah.
Do we get you to high before the show?
Be honest because I think I got too
high.
I was high for a while.
Grandma was.
Well,
it's also I'm,
I'm so fucked up because I just got back
from Brazil.
Most of my,
my brain is on total auto hotel.
I am one of my babies was throwing up
last night.
That sucks.
It's sad.
So sad.
I,
I fucked up.
I flew southwest,
which you say I love southwest,
but they have that whole number thing,
like if you check into late you,
you're either a,
b,
c or d or whatever.
How many people get on the plane first
they put the a's on then the bees and I
did one of those things where you sat.
I sat was Columbus to la?
Well,
Vegas Still La,
but I sat between two of the fattest
people ever and I'm sorry,
but um,
they both took up 90 percent of my,
my seat.
So the whole time I'm like,
they were in the middle and the other
side,
so it's like a movie.
It was,
but I was holding myself like this and
you know,
my,
my elbow pain that been in,
I am so jacked from that flight.
That was the closest thing to torture
I've ever been and I couldn't do
anything about it.
You can't do well.
Didn't they kick Kevin Smith off?
Yeah.
How big were these people?
Pretty big.
Kevin Smith,
the,
the guy was bigger than the girl.
But the problem was the guy,
he had so much room to lean on the
window,
but he decided to lean on my side and so
the whole time he's like,
oh,
he's on my lap on the east.
And the woman was trying to be a little
bit nicer about it,
but she was still pretty big.
So she was on my space like our C,
that's a human rights issue.
It's fucking seats for two goddamn slow.
I need like a rape whistle would slip
right in.
You can just go sideways and those
families couldn't even touch you.
You'd be like a sheet of paper between
pure red rocks.
Yeah.
I have no problem.
There should be a whistle for them.
We have an issue with people are getting
too fucking fat,
you know,
and it's been going on for a long time.
There's a,
there was an image once that I saw
online from the early 19 hundreds and it
was one of those carnivals and it was
the Batman and the carnival,
like there wouldn't be the guy that was
the fat man and he was barely fat.
I mean,
in comparison to what we consider fat
today,
like some of these people that you see
that have to get moved out of their
house,
they have to cut a hole out and they're
attached to the couch because they
haven't gotten up.
They'd been shooting where they sit in
their fiber,
their skin has like melted into the
fucking chair.
This is not just one person.
This is many,
many,
many people have done this.
It's been a bunch of people that they
had to cut their fucking house open so
they could pull them out attached to
their couch.
You know,
and this was just,
you know,
1,919.
Oh three or something show fat man.
And he was like barely fat.
It was like barely.
Who was a guy who should go on a diet,
you know,
who was like not,
Joey Diaz when he was not even at his
heaviest,
like halfway there,
halfway between joy.
So it's like that's just a shorter
amount of time ago where it was really
rare to get that fat.
It's amazing.
It's amazing how far society,
his sled or how far humanity has slayed
when it comes to that or our bodies are
exploding.
Like it's so common to see people just
overflowing out of their clothes,
you know,
fast food.
It's corn,
it's a lot of it.
Corn Syrup,
right?
Isn't there a documentary on the corn is
really terrible for your body and
difficult for it to break down.
That's why they feed it to cows and shit
and get them fattened up before you
before you slaughter and makes them more
delicious.
Yeah.
I don't know.
You should be diet drugs from easier to
obtain as well.
Oh really?
Yeah,
definitely.
So you think when.
Well,
I know one girl I saw,
I saw one girl lose a shitload of
weight.
She lost like 50,
60 pounds.
She went from being kind of Chubby to
like really hot and it was like whoa.
And it happened so quickly and she was
on something called Phen Phen you
remember that?
Yeah.
That stuff Jachter though.
It just totally short circuited.
Are cardiotoxic dangerous.
It's crazy.
Yeah.
So she went right back to her normal
weight again.
It was like she was a hot chick for like
a year,
that phen phen kept it rock and for like
but it was just too,
too nutty,
you know,
the store with them was to every
stimulant they've used as a diet drug.
These teas,
methamphetamine used instead of me and
they used 10 metres,
the views,
anything you can imagine,
any stimulant and just anything that
they could sell you to make.
We're going to loose the stimulants,
do work and fen phen worked,
I'm sure.
And do those things that you see like,
you know,
ripped fuel and all that shit or they
are,
those are those diet pills or those
things affect it?
I don't know what's in them.
I mean if there are,
some of them have weird derivatives of
finesse,
Colombian,
you know?
Yeah.
What does all that stuff?
This was just amino acids.
Is that what it is?
No,
they're just probably really weak
stimulant.
Like thin ethylamine is a close
derivative of amphetamine,
just missing one carbon atom and uh,
and it's illegal.
So you can just put tons of it into
dietary supplements and it produces a
short lasting stimulant effect.
It's amazing that that's one of the
number one concerns that people have
getting rid of fat.
So it's it.
It's a very strange statement when you
think about how society becomes so
successful that even when people are
down in the dumps,
they're still fat.
There's still fucking.
It's like normal.
It's normal to have excess energy stored
away onto your skin.
It's normally to be prepared for,
for your fucking stocked up,
you know,
in,
in the,
the wild days.
So rare to,
to become a fat person,
you know,
so fucking terrible conversation.
You guys checked out a long time ago.
I smelled it.
All this talk about fat.
You know when you have friends that are
overweight and you worry,
you know,
after patrice died,
especially our friend Patrice O'Neal's,
a standup comedian just recently.
You know,
you have friends that are overweight and
it's just,
it's like a bomb and you know it's going
to go off eventually.
You don't know what you can do.
You've got to try to diffuse it.
You try to lead them in the right
direction or enjoy them until they blow
up.
Patrice o'neal think that is fatness
aided his comedy as well.
I've never had that conversation with
them so I could never speak of it,
but he's.
He was really analytical about his
comedy.
I just think he was also a guy who
wanted to do whatever the fuck you want
her to do right then and there.
Some of the best comedians are also very
impulsive people and you know,
it can be good and bad.
I know comedians will become impulsive
gamblers and they get addicted to drugs,
so like a lot of them have really kind
of wild and impulsive instincts and
that's what makes him funny.
That be the first person to say,
bitch,
shut the fuck up.
And that was patrice o'neil.
He was the first guy that would say he
call you on your bullshit.
The first guy to say,
shut the fuck up and to be that person
that doesn't really like worry about how
this is going to come out and just fly
with it.
It's like it's a very specific type of
personality.
Not that many people do it and they,
that personality is prone to doing a lot
of other crazy shit to that,
that personality,
personalities prone to just eat until
they're fucking pass out.
A personality is prone to do 15 shots
and you know on a dare.
That's a wild personality.
That's a personality.
It's going to go with you to Mexico.
You know,
it's like that.
That's the reason why they're funny.
So it becomes a.
you're sad.
Like you see your friend who's really
big and you see them eating themselves
to death and you're like,
oh shit,
what the fuck?
And I said,
you can't say anything.
There's nothing you can do anymore than
you've already done.
You're an asshole.
You tell them you love them.
Give them a pat on the back.
If you need help,
come to the gym.
I work out with you.
But other than that,
what the fuck else can you do?
It's a weird world.
We live in people eating themselves to
death.
Hamilton Morris.
You don't have to worry about that shit.
You stay slender with the vegetarian
lifestyle on your bare basic alanines,
whatever various substances you choose.
Do you,
do you.
Are you a multivitamin guy?
You seem like you know so much about the
body.
Do you,
do you take supplements?
I take,
I take lists that you do.
I knew you motherfucker.
You're concerned about your liver.
It depends on what supplement.
Not all of them have hepatic toxicity
issues,
but some of them do you handle taxes?
This is just about not like,
it's inherently bad for your liver to
take vitamins,
but uh,
it's part of food,
right?
I mean that's essentially what I mean.
Everything has to go through your liver
so they don't,
that's not a huge worry unless it's
something or some in super high doses of
toxic.
Like what are the ones who was the
lawyer?
Soluble ones are,
are like vitamin e potentially vitamin A
as well.
I don't know.
It's not something I've done a huge
amount of research on,
but now when you say fat soluble,
if somebody said that once for someone
who got caught taking a performance
enhancing drug and one of the the people
that was in his camp said one of the
things that fucked him up was that he's
too fat and so he can't get it out of
his system as quick short.
Is that really true?
Like it stays in your fat,
like if you are a lean person,
you would get it out of your system.
Whereas if you were a person that had a
high percentage of body weight,
it would remain for longer.
It's possible.
Yeah.
I mean that's one of the main physical
properties of any molecule is that it
has different abilities and different
chemicals and some things are lipid
soluble and and if it's something like
thc and you have a huge amount of fat
tissue on your body that the thc can
stay in so you just fucking high all
day.
Certain people,
you're not getting high off of it.
It's just just in hearing and yourself.
It's not doing anything unless it's in
the central nervous,
just giving you a very mild high,
just in my mildest,
just cooks in Lindsay's point where it
the claim that there's like some
reservoir in your spinal fluid or
something and if you crack your back the
right way,
that all really blast of cannabinoids or
Lsd or something really.
Wow.
People would say that.
I don't think it's true.
Well,
there's people that say that Kundalini
Yoga practice can lead to psychedelic
experiences.
Sure.
Yeah.
Have you ever experienced that?
I studied Kundalini Yoga for a while
during the trip.
No,
no try.
I mean that was one of the ways they
tried to sell.
I had to take it as part of my sport's
requirement in high school and Sports.
That's awesome.
That is awesome.
Holy Shit.
That's amazing.
Yeah,
that's great.
Yeah.
And they tried to sell it by equating it
with a drug experience of some kind and
that's why it was so popular in the
sixties for that same reason,
but I don't really.
I never achieved any
profound state of altered consciousness.
One friend who,
uh,
had a,
a girl that he knew that was a friend of
his,
that he actually went on a trip with
her.
They were actually just platonic
friends,
but they would,
uh,
traveled together occasionally and she
was into like serious Kundalini Yoga
where she would get up every morning at
a very specific time and she would have
to face a very specific angle.
I don't remember what it was,
was towards the Sun or away from the sun
and I don't know what she was doing,
but she would do these very intense
Kundalini exercises for like an hour,
an hour and 15 minutes,
an hour and 20 minutes.
And she did it every day and she claimed
that when she did it for long periods of
time,
because she did it so much,
she could get into like an astral
traveling sort of dimension,
a traveling state of consciousness where
she would have psychedelic experiences.
Yeah.
Actually,
now that I think of it,
I did have some.
You just forget that they weren't
exactly the same.
I wouldn't.
You've had,
you've had so many psychedelic
experiences for you to have one in Yogi,
like,
oh yeah,
I have one in that too,
but it wasn't really,
it was like a,
you know,
they,
they didn't use breathing techniques,
breath of fire,
and for a normal person having an
experience like that would be something
they would never forget.
Oh my God,
did yoga and I had this most incredible
transcendent experience.
I left my body,
I became one with the universe for you.
You're like,
Oh yeah,
I did that during yoga too.
So how did it happen?
How did that go down?
You know,
you have to follow these different
breathing techniques and then hold
yourself in some kind of a weird stress
position that's extremely exhausting.
And then your,
all of your muscles start to vibrate.
Like I was on that machine of the turbo
sonic.
Yeah,
like the Turbo Sonic.
So it's like a turbo sonic type effect.
I would say.
I would compare it more to the turbo
sonic then to Lsd.
Wow,
that's interesting.
Yeah.
What's the number one thing that if you
had to do it again,
you would approach with more caution?
Is there any.
Is there any one psychedelic experience
for a loop?
I mean,
yeah,
many have,
but I think drugs like there certainly
are drugs that are more friendly than
others and I think five immuno dmt would
be an example of something that has the
capacity to be extremely unpleasant if
you take it under the wrong
circumstances.
I had a friend completely flip out
taking it because he had.
He had eaten and so he had to throw up
and he got up to throw up and he got to
the sink just in time to throw up,
but then he was just going crazy.
You're talking about rape,
talking about all kinds of crazy shit.
Took his shirt off.
Yeah.
I had a friend lose consciousness and
started vomiting and look as if they had
died.
I've seen.
I had a friend read them.
My friend Doug Stanhope comedian.
I thought we'd lost him.
It was going like this and little
bubbles were coming out of the corner of
his mouth and I'm like,
Shit.
And I'm hanging out with Doug and I'm
just thinking of all the chemicals that
doug throws into his body,
cigarettes and beer
and fucking mean.
Doug's shits on multivitamins.
He's not taking a multivitamin fuck out
of here.
So I'm like,
we might have red lined his body with
this shit.
I was like,
he just took a big hit and he's.
He might,
he might be a goner,
but he came through it,
but it was terrifying for a couple of
minutes.
You did map them out then?
Yeah,
almost done,
man.
I'm,
I'm okay.
What were you saying about that?
Just that you were asking me if there's
one that I would approach with caution
again in the mail you think would be the
scariest one probably.
I mean there's also just isolated
experiences that you can't necessarily
connect with the substance p called
there's like an shogun takes this
oxygen,
less masculine derivative called
isocracy and goes into a fugue state
where she has a prevailing sense of
unreality that lasts for months or
something.
It just totally feels like she's in a
dream.
But then I've had friends who also have
used unusual substances that have been
tested very much and have weird
reactions,
but every,
even if you ingest the same substance
over and over and over again,
you really don't know exactly what's
going to happen with the psychedelics.
You taking the exact same quantity of
synthetic suicide and over and over and
over again a year apart.
Every year will feel completely
different every time.
So I'm always skeptical of people that
deals if they really know the effects of
any substance because you always
completely different.
Well,
dmt always seemed like there's so much
coming at you and there was coming at
you from like 15 minutes.
Like it was almost impossible to bring
back anything.
It was almost impossible to record any
of it.
Yeah.
You know,
I mean to say that you know,
that experience,
my God,
you'd have to do that experience so many
times just to get a general sense of
just looking around and just relaxing
and trying to absorb it all.
Trying to like figure out what the fuck
is this?
Can I move this around myself?
Like what is this?
Is this,
is this an organism?
is this the universe?
Is this the wiring of love?
What the fuck is going on here?
It takes so long like you do it and
every time you do it you come back and
then you go,
what the fuck was that?
And then you go back in again and it's
still the same thing for 15 minutes.
It's just like it's too alien and too
crazy.
There's no way you can have a really
truly get a grip on it.
It's not like you can go on a vacation
to dmt land,
you know,
if you could take a trip,
you know you could go somewhere for two
weeks and in that two week time you
would see the entire time you will be
going through a dmt trip.
Right.
Then maybe you would kind of get a grip
on the IOWASCA is some intermediate
between smoking dmt and a non
intermediate.
It's just the longest that you can have
that experience and even then you don't
really.
It's not it lengthening the experience.
It gives you some greater understanding
of what it is necessarily.
I don't think it's really any less or
more confusing than smoking it.
It's just a longer duration.
And even then you have people like
Gordon,
todd skinner,
who are opening themselves up
to ivy bags filled with dmt.
No,
this is the guy that you wrote about in
the what,
what is it called?
Crystal.
What?
What is this?
They'll call,
but your.
Your article was called high on crystal.
Crystal is what?
A fucking crazy story.
If you haven't read that.
This is a must read the other one.
The other thing we were,
you were interviewing shogun was amazing
as well,
but you have to see this.
This girl was a stripper and she meets
this dude who's like this big time lsd
manufacturer who has a fucking house in
a silo and millions of dollars,
right?
He's rich as fuck and he's like the
number one lsd guy in the country
or so.
I mean it's also unclear is another
example of a story where a lot of people
talk about it with an enormous amount of
confidence is if they have no
understanding of what happened and say,
oh,
it's all crystal Coles folder.
It's all x's falter wise,
but if I've learned anything from
researching it over the course of years,
it said absolutely nothing is certain
about the story.
It's incredibly complicated and there's
so much conflicting information for
absolutely every element of the story
that you have to be very careful about
talking about what happened with
certainty.
But there was this lab and uh,
and they did crystal coal into it and
she did become a part of it.
She took down the dude.
Yes.
That's amazing what everyone was crazy
girl.
Shamana Kalanick.
Woo.
It's just hundred that she did it.
Yeah.
It's way harder than she did.
I and stuck it up his ass.
I don't even care about that.
Why did it,
how to amazing story though,
man.
This,
this,
uh,
this girl escaped,
right?
And then the dude came after and
kidnapped her and some other dude,
they escaped together to get away from
this fucking crazy guy and it turns out
the guy was working with the FBI or the
Dea.
So there's number one,
lsd dealers working with the dea and had
been for quite some time.
Yeah.
You know,
that reminds me of a story.
Do you know who Whitey Bulger is?
Yes.
You know that store then from acid?
Right.
You're from Massachusetts.
What an amazing story.
For people that don't know,
Whitey bulger was the head of the Irish
mob and he was also working for the FBI,
so if you turned Whitey bulger in Whitey
bulger would know from the FBI,
first of all,
they wouldn't arrest him and then he
would kill you and that's really how it
ran.
I mean,
they really did run it like that and you
find that out and you go,
that is amazing.
This is essentially along the same lines
and things like
it's been happening for a long time,
both in the US and internationally.
You know,
there's the Iran Contra is with this
whole scandal about them pumping cocaine
into ghettos in America to create the
crack problem.
I don't know that it's necessarily true,
but it's a theory that a lot of people
have and the same thing happened in
South Africa with with methaqualone,
with quaaludes.
There was this whole project called
project coast where they were
synthesizing massive quantities of Mgma
and quail ludes in order to weaponize
them for crowd control.
Supposedly they were pumping them all
into the streets and now the ultimate
MTMA weapons is a crowd control.
Oh my God.
So you would blast the crowd with
ecstasy.
Yeah,
it's called project coast.
What a brilliant idea.
Where do I sign up?
That's my bit about how to calm down the
Middle East.
I had a bit.
I did about sending crop duster planes
just fucking cover the Middle East with
chronic smoke for just weeks.
And then they did that as well.
Actually weaponized thc.
They did at at that.
That's the craziest James Gyms.
There's a crazy sentence ever.
Weaponized Tac.
They called it like red oil or
something.
That was like the code name for it.
What does it do?
You spray it on people and they become
high.
Yeah,
exactly.
That's hilarious.
Edgewood arsenal,
that's the name of it.
Uh,
yeah,
it probably,
I mean that was the,
it was not a visit improvement because
it's a nonlethal incapacitating agent
and you know,
if you have a choice between shooting
someone and dusting them with Thc,
dad's amazing.
I can't believe that was a real product.
Absolutely.
Yeah.
What else can they trust you with MDM
TAC and they try LSD as well.
I mean the problem is also that the
physical properties of these different
drugs that limit their,
their ability to travel through the air
to maintain their potency when they're
laid on surfaces around the soil.
LSD is pretty,
it's not a stable molecule.
So when they were trying to weaponize
it,
one of the problems,
it's just,
it didn't aerosolized well it didn't
last on service as well.
And then they settled on bz because they
thought it was a better chemical weapon.
Bz what is bz?
It's a anticholinergic drug like Jacob's
ladder.
The movie Jacob's ladder is really?
Yeah.
So they really were trying to make lsd
and use it as a weapon.
Absolutely.
What was the idea that,
well,
what was it going to do to the troops?
Just to make them disoriented and you
just take them.
Well,
yeah.
I mean,
can you imagine if you discovered,
if you didn't know anything about
psychedelics at all and discovered LSD
and they.
They tried absolutely everything they
could with it.
They tried to see if they could use it
as a truth serum.
too.
They tried to both good and bad uses.
There were scientists using it to
increase their intelligence and then
there were people trying to get use it
as to make people insane,
to reprogram people's brains.
That was the large part of the MK Ultra
was about,
you know,
manipulating people's minds using
psychedelics and sensory deprivation and
things like that.
And it was just crazy trial and error by
murderers.
That's how they did it.
Trial and error by Nixon's people.
They should make it into a steam ship.
Imagine man,
trial and error with Lsd by Nixon's
people and supposedly the word trip
comes from.
That's like FBI lingo from when they
were doing the experiments.
Wow.
The scariest thing that I've ever heard
connected to any psychedelic
experiences.
That was that Timothy leary was
connected or not Timothy,
I'm
the unit Barbara.
Ted Kaczynski was connected to a some
studies at Harvard and he had done like
some classified lsd studies and they,
you know,
they,
they tweaked a lot of people's fucking
hands.
Then he went back to Berkeley.
I taught math for a few years till he
got enough money to buy that cabin,
take on the technology they might have
fried that dude's brain.
Oh No.
They were love automizing people and
they were doing just unbelievable.
And if you're familiar with the book
acid dreams we had,
they did every imaginable thing.
Hookup people to ids with stimulant,
like amphetamine in one wrist,
and you're the second person in a week
that's direct recommended acid dreams.
I'd have to go get that now.
Let's read the first half of it.
So it's all about mk ultra different
experiences that they tried to important
people with lsd and it's about.
Yeah,
all,
all of these attempts to weaponize LSD
and to use it as a truth.
Sarah and mk ultra buying it right now.
You know,
it's an old book.
It's been around since the eighties.
You've heard of,
uh,
there was,
it's supposedly an urban myth,
but a French town that they dosed.
Absolutely true.
It is true.
So they do.
That's true.
And that's more recent research that
came up in the last maybe in the last
five years I had read it and then I had
read a counterpoint that said it was
bullshit because you can't even get acid
to work in bread like that,
that they wouldn't maintain itself.
Is that true?
Yeah,
it wouldn't,
it would not survive the heating,
but they could've added it afterwards
and they supposedly they,
I mean,
you know.
Sure.
So when they have to be,
I mean,
how would you go about getting that acid
into the bread?
You'd have to get a CIA guy who works
there and just just fucks with
everybody's bread and squirts it out.
Go ahead eat that.
I guess so.
I mean,
you could spray Brad with LSD.
Yeah.
It was just,
it was an interesting argument when I,
when I heard,
because I had to assume that it was true
and I was like saying like,
wow,
look what they found,
and then I saw this counter point to it
and I was like,
oh,
okay.
Is it possible that they have,
could have created a more stable form of
LSD or could it be some other
psychedelic that would have similar
effects that would be stable?
Sure.
Yeah,
absolutely.
I mean there's,
there's plenty of psychedelics that they
were testing at that time that are more
stable than LSD.
LSD is unusually in stable,
but uh,
but yeah,
I think the,
I think that they recovered some
communication between two operatives and
I said like,
did you finish the mission with the
diastal I it or something.
You didn't specifically say Lsd,
but they used some abbreviated form.
So it's not conclusive,
but I think that there's strong evidence
that that happened.
You would think that if they knew of
that it would have monstrous effects.
They would have to know whether or not
there's something that they can
monetarily.
Well,
I think they did that.
They want it,
they wanted,
they wanted to happen,
but it seems like such a powerful thing
to have.
You're going to find out what it's
capable of.
Kind of just let it go.
You're going to have to like try to
crack the code and apparently they were
like spraying it into the New York
subway system.
That's crazy.
No,
it's.
Oh,
they had an entire CIA or house where
they were taking.
Yeah.
That's operation midnight.
Climax in San Francisco and New York.
The two different whorehouses.
That's an amazing story.
I love that story.
You gotTa Google that folks because it's
amazing.
They ran brothels where they dosed
dudes.
Poor guy.
Just killing in there for some sexual
relief just to just take.
I'll take his mind off.
It's horrible day.
Hey,
would you like to drink honey?
He's like,
yeah,
I just said Jack and coke or do me great
jack and coke with acid.
Oh No,
what the fuck man.
They really didn't know them.
I mean,
they probably had an idea,
but there was the anthropological
reports of what Indians do when they
take pod,
but they had no idea how.
Just some businessman.
Well apparently they started doing it
once.
They stopped getting people that are
willing to sign up for their,
for the voluntary tests that too many
people were getting fucked up by the
tests and so this is what I had read was
that they switched to a dosing people
when they ran out of volunteers.
Huh?
I would imagine they would have had
volunteers especially later on in these
programs and they were becoming publicly
known substances,
but yet a lot of the early research,
there's a book called drugs and fantasy
where it's just people being dosed with
PCP and I think the France one was like
51 or something like that,
wasn't it?
It was just something.
Yeah.
It's really terrifying to think they
actually did do that.
You believe it.
The downs,
the whole town.
Let's see what happens.
You know nuts.
You've seen,
you've seen the videos of them dousing
soldiers.
Right?
If she ended up,
because I believe it was the English
army know they just wandering around.
It's amazing and people died in that
French town.
It was,
didn't he commit suicide?
People jumped off bridges.
I mean,
I guess it's the same kind of stuff that
happens today with psychedelics for
certain people respond badly and want to
jump off of things.
Do you support the theory that that was
the cause of the Salem witch trials and
all that stuff that it was an Erg got
infection.
You know that story.
Do you know that story?
I know that they claim that which brooms
or an implement for vaginally
administering scopolamine and atrophying
and all of these fronts.
Delirium,
Christ vaginally,
distributing with a pole that seems so
crude and uncreative.
That's one idea,
but I don't know about or God in
witches.
No.
Wow.
What is it?
Um,
it's,
um,
a fungus apparently.
Oh yeah.
I know about it.
And apparently it has some psychoactive
effects and they didn't get like a
poisoning from it and then give you some
sort of a psychoactive effect.
And they thought it was responsible for
a graph.
Yeah.
They thought it could have been
responsible for people that thought they
were experiencing magic and they were
hallucinating.
They were,
you know,
getting fucked up and,
and they could've started blaming it on
women,
which is,
which do,
you can't get laid.
So you're all fucked up on this crazy
bread is Erg.
Got,
you know,
apparently if you've
never heard of or got being psychotic.
Oh,
absolutely.
Yeah.
No,
it is.
Yeah.
And that's really what is the effect,
like what is the effect of or got like,
um,
well it contains just a variety of these
different ergo line substances.
But there's lysergic acid,
amides and um,
and,
and they were used medicinally for,
for a very long time.
That was the reason that lsd was
discovered is because they were using
these isolating different alkaloids from
or got Sclerosia and trying to see if
they had some use in,
in preventing postpartum bleeding in
pregnant women.
And yeah,
so it wasn't,
they weren't investigating psychoactive
drugs that had some interest in using
them as potential analytics,
like drugs to reduce fatigue.
And that was this one,
nootropic hydro gene was produced by
Albert Hoffman in the course of that
study,
but they certainly weren't looking for
anything like LSD,
wasn't lsd.
There was.
There were some,
some people that they were looking for
something to make women more fertile or
something along those lines.
What the fuck that I read to something
that would encourage women to ovulate?
Is that true?
Did I read nonsense?
I don't know.
I mean it happens all the time.
It's out of my head.
I hate that.
I hate when I have a thought that I
can't wrap my head around.
There's too much goddamn information
online.
Yeah.
But that happens all the time.
And in medical,
they'll be trying to create for one
thing and wow,
that's the story of Viagra probably
drove to keep them,
to stop them.
Bitchin I mean.
Yeah,
Brian,
that's what it is.
Let me ask you this,
because you're a rational guy that does
the stuff.
You're obviously very well read.
You know what you're talking about.
Clearly when you have an intense I could
delegate experience and when you
experience what seems to be something
that is not you,
something that you're interacting with
that does not appear to be the
imagination.
It could be,
I don't know,
but a lot of people,
a lot of people have interesting
opinions.
A lot of people that have seen real
intense psychedelic visions have very
interesting opinions and you,
you might be the most psychedelically
traveled person I've ever met in my
life,
so it's a perfect combination for you to
be the guy that answers that question.
What the fuck is going on?
When you have an intense psychedelic
experience,
is it just chemicals perturbing your
natural brain state?
What?
I think it's.
I think it is,
but st just chemical chemicals is
already kind of problematic because
chemical,
everything's just chemicals.
Chemicals is absolutely everything you
ever experienced and remember
remembering I've ever lived,
so everything is a chemical phenomenon.
Consciousness as a chemical phenomenon.
The fact they were able to perceive any
of this.
We'll have this conversation right now.
It's all an amazing chemical
interactions,
so I don't see the need to bring in any
kind of supernatural interpretation of
the phenomenon because it just is not
necessarily the same reason that I don't
see the need to bring in a supernatural
interpretation of the universe or or of
anything else or even ghosts.
You know,
you can look at,
if you look at a ghost haunting,
you can look at it two ways.
You can say,
oh,
this was a weird supernatural
experience.
Or You could say this was a really weird
moment of psychopathology and what
psychological mechanism may this person
so afraid that they hallucinated and
thought they heard something or thought
they saw another being,
which is equally fascinating,
if not more fascinating,
or there's a dude who didn't get enough
attention from his parents or pretends
to see God is in the basement and watch
a show with night vision.
That could be the case too.
I mean,
I almost feel like that's the.
Like the lesser interpretation.
It's the easy way.
It's much easier to say,
oh,
they're aliens.
That's very simple.
Whereas if you actually wonder what is
the true biochemical basis of this
phenomenon,
it's an incredibly complicated question
and it won't have a simple answer,
but that's why it's a worthwhile
question.
Do you believe that it's possible that
taking something along the lines of Bmt
or any really intense psychedelic
actually opens up some sort of a door to
another dimension,
another place,
another exist in something that you can
experience another frequency and other
station on the dial?
I think other dimensions of yourself,
certainly I don't know that there's
another physical dimension that you are
accessing.
I wouldn't.
I don't see any reason to believe that.
I think there's enough inside of all of
us to account for that.
So you think that when you have this
incredible,
like massive visual experience,
it's all an imagined Tory thing.
It's not like your consciousness travels
to a place more tunes into a frequency.
No,
I don't think that.
So you think it's just a chemical
reaction but in incredibly fascinating,
accomplished or chemical and I'm
absolutely not arguing with you.
I'm not sold on what the hell it is and
I've.
I've had that argument with people that
are really almost like they almost
proselytize about the experience to the
point where they're,
you know,
they're talking about like as if it's a
religious,
a religious,
definite,
you know,
this is what happens,
this is what happens.
And I've always said,
you know,
maybe it's possible,
but it's also possible.
It's just crazy chemicals.
It doesn't mean it's not spiritual
spiritual benefits.
That's fine.
It doesn't mean that they don't have,
they can't have a religious experience
or they can't interpret it however they
want,
but I sure the interaction is beautiful.
If the interaction is beautiful,
it doesn't have to be other worldly for
it to be defined.
You know,
the interaction is beautiful.
It could set you off on another
direction.
Rewire your board.
I mean,
how many people have you ever talked to
that have had a big psychedelic
experience and totally stopped doing
pills,
are totally stopped smoking cigarettes
or just completely rewired their life
because of one like emphatic psychedelic
rewiring.
Yeah,
absolutely.
Absolutely.
And uh,
but yeah,
I just think that you think.
I'm sorry,
go ahead.
Well anyway,
just the,
just the chemical thing,
it's just something to be careful with
and when interpreting things,
no,
you're fine.
It's just a chemical.
Everything is just,
I sound too dumb to be talking about the
first place.
I'm just trying to skate by with my
limited knowledge I have,
but I want to pick your brain so when
you experience like really profound
wisdom in um,
in psychedelic states or you have like,
you know,
this almost feeling of being analyzed
and like seeing through and shown all
your flaws and all your craziness and
then you have this sort of like a reset
thing.
We kind of get a new fresh perspective
of your place in the world and how
you're,
what kind of an energy,
what kind of vibe you're putting out.
You think that that's all maybe
internal,
that's all.
Maybe imagination or is it,
is there the potential that there is
some sort of,
uh,
another intelligence out there?
There's some sort of a thing that you
can tune into some sort of a way that
we're connected to but we don't have
access on a regular basis.
Is that possible or is it silly?
I don't think that it's,
there's no reason to believe that that
is possible,
but I think that there's all kinds of
things within us that we don't currently
acknowledged and understand.
I mean Shogun Shogun and Timothy leary
talked about this idea,
you know,
this is all this noncoding DNA that's
sometimes called junk DNA or in Toronto
Dna and uh,
and although it doesn't,
they were probably wrong about that.
So it doesn't contain any kind of like
instinctual evolutionary knowledge,
but,
but there was,
they were using it as an example,
like what if all this noncoding DNA
contains instinctual ancient knowledge,
they're able to access will or on
psychedelics,
um,
but maybe not with specifically with the
noncoding DNA,
but with parts of the brain,
with who knows what sorts of things are
stored within us that we don't know how
to access.
I think that it is actually a
scientologist idea,
but I think that there's some truth to
the idea that we remember absolutely
everything that we experienced,
that it's all in there somewhere.
You just need the right catalyst to
remove that piece of information.
Wow,
that's amazing.
Well,
sometimes someone will bring something
up and then all of sudden the file will
open up in your head and you're like,
yeah,
that guy.
Where is he?
What has he been doing?
Like boom,
all of a sudden some person who you
have,
I could have come up to you,
do you know of,
of Bruce Blah Blah,
blah,
and you'd be like,
no,
I have no idea who that is.
But then somebody shows you a picture
and says,
you remember this guy,
second grade,
remember?
And you're like,
Whoa,
yeah,
click,
click.
All of a sudden the file's open and
you'll remember several experiences.
You might've had that person.
It's almost like we don't have enough
room for all the shit we're saying.
We just put stuff in shitty hard drives
and stuff in the closet and then every
now and then it comes out,
right?
I mean,
it's like an indexing problem.
That information is there,
but we don't always know how to access
it.
You remember that show taxing?
Um,
I'm familiar.
Marilu Henner,
remember the very attractive redhead
woman that was on that show?
No,
she's got some crazy memory thing.
She was on stern show.
She can remember everything.
She has an insane memory.
Like she can tell you,
like you can tell her,
you know,
June 13th,
19,
76.
What were you wearing?
She was like,
I was wearing a blue dress and because I
was on my way to this and that it was.
And she'll,
she can tell you what the temperature
was outside.
She can tell you everything.
She remembers everything.
Yeah,
no,
it is possible.
It's very much in the size of a normal
head.
Those things are possible.
We don't need giant brains and the size
of a normal head and she's not even a
nut.
Like she's like a normal person.
Like you talked to her.
She sounds normal.
It doesn't sound like some maladjusted
person with some incredible gift.
She's not like a rain man,
just like a normal human being,
you know,
there's.
And there's lots of these new modernists
that are capable of those sorts of the
mind feeds.
But uh,
and one interesting thing about the new
monitors,
they all seem to have synesthesia.
At least ones that I've read about and
uh,
so when they remember something,
it's a visual memory and an auditory
memory and all,
and all their memories are cross linked
over multiple sensory modalities.
So it's like,
uh,
and then,
and then there was a lot of research in
the seventies about potentially using
psychedelics as cognitive enhancers and
I think that's one way that they could
function is by encouraging this type of
synesthetic thinking where you're
experiencing everything through multiple
senses,
an indexing information through multiple
senses simultaneously.
What do you think about the
controversial,
stoned ape theory?
Oh,
well,
I don't think there's any evidence for
it,
but that's like a lot of parents,
we kind of stuff.
I like it.
I think it's interesting and worthwhile
and funny and sexy.
Yeah,
it's good.
I'm glad that he said everything that he
said.
I don't agree with it.
A lot of it,
but uh,
some of it's a little wonky.
Yeah.
A lot of it is,
but that's not much fun.
Yeah,
it's good.
It's all good.
Yeah.
And even the stuff that's Wonky,
I'm always willing to give him the
benefit of the doubt that I just don't
see that he seen it.
And that's,
you know,
that's most science anyway.
It's just people coming up with theories
and models and trying to improve the
model.
So he came up with a model or theory
that was wrong.
There's nothing bad about that.
He was just stoned ape theory.
Is it wrong as far as like the time
frame of,
of history and development?
Like because that's what I've.
I think I read that.
I read that he got his,
his errors wrong or something.
Um,
I don't think there was any evidence
that primates eat mushrooms.
Maybe I'm wrong about that.
I don't know that.
I don't think that.
I think the evidence that he was relying
on for that theory that uh,
either it was LSD or psilocybin
increases visual acuity.
I don't think that that's been
definitively proven science that we've
noticed published in a prestigious
journal at the time.
I'm not sure that all of that research
was methodologically sound.
You know,
what the,
how the study works,
you don't think they only had like two
sticks that were,
weren't parallel lines,
and then they would have someone turning
one stick on the other side of extremely
slowly to the point where they would no
longer be parallel.
And it was who could recognize that the
first and the stone people recognized it
more than the nonstop people on.
So his,
his joke was that maybe being stoned,
you see the world better than it really
is or better than you can when you're
sober.
Other.
Yeah.
I mean it hasn't really been studied
very extensive.
So even though it was published,
it could've been horseshit.
Like you would have to be replicated a
few times.
Yeah,
I think
it would be.
Yeah.
Um,
I,
that seemed like a weird one too because
like,
who's going to take a little dose?
You know,
if you're going to have mushrooms you're
going to blast off.
I just don't see it being to the point
where you're going to take like a little
tiny doses of it so you can see better.
You know,
if you have the blast off thing,
you're not going to be saying like,
well,
what if I just don't blast off?
What if I just nibble,
nibble,
nibble so I can barely feel it?
Who's going to do that to go hunting?
That's ridiculous.
Or maybe they didn't even know that you
could play for awhile.
Thinking Salvia people don't realize
until the nineties until they started
extracting it and making those extracts
publicly available.
People didn't really know their,
you know,
their chewing and say,
oh yeah,
it is active,
but they couldn't really characterize
the effect until he had concentrated the
Salvinorin a,
it is a trip that they look like dinner
plates to trip that they just grow out
of the ground.
They look like,
Hey,
look at me.
Did you know when mushrooms grow mean?
Like there's a green field and it's
green grass and this white thing just
like,
here I am,
and it's like asking you to eat it.
I mean,
if there's anything that's ever asked
me,
it's a polite and subtle color.
I'm white,
I'm so bland,
don't even worry.
Just come home and take a bite.
I mean,
and the idea that,
that they might have actually not even
from this planet and they might've come
here and asteroidal impacts.
Sure.
You know,
that's my favorite one.
That's the,
my favorite sexy theory.
You know,
that there's another mechanic theory,
right?
Whereas he or he,
he supported the idea that,
uh,
he said you would know this.
He said that,
um,
silicide Ben.
There was no other plant that was our,
that had the four and the [inaudible]
position or no other,
no other life form fungus that had that.
It was the only one except for
hydroxylation is unusual and there's a
lot of five in the plant kingdom for the
four is unusual.
Is there other other ones besides.
I'm not that I can think of off the top
of.
So his theory in mushrooms,
there's sites didn't,
things like that.
His theory was that that had come from
a,
an asteroid impact that sports could
survive in a vacuum when we know the
building blocks of life and amino acids
possibly came here from outer space.
Maybe mushrooms that,
that was them.
They're communicating with you my plans
to.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
He would buy the guy totally.
He meaning,
that's what made him write the timewave
zero novelty theory.
He,
he,
you know,
they told him that he had to do it,
could you imagine how annoying would be
every time you went on a trip,
you know,
you got some fucking alien mushroom
people telling you,
you gotta write a theory.
You've got to write some biological
theory.
Brian,
you could not look anymore board who's
listening from now on foreheads and
that's it.
Cut you off before you went to five and
you can't handle five.
You think you can.
Um,
so we got over the stoned ape theory.
What else?
I want to ask you a
alien life,
yes or no.
Again,
I mean,
all these things,
there just isn't enough evidence either
way.
And I know that it's like a boring
answer.
And in some ways,
but I just,
you know,
people will say like,
it's always huge news when they find an
extra solar planet that might be able to
support earth like life,
but so far they've never found anywhere
in the known universe,
a single planet that we could live on
without a suit for a minute.
So that's not really that encouraging.
Ultimately.
I like.
But then when you also factor in the
enormity of the universe,
then of course,
I think it's possible.
Absolutely.
I just don't see at this specific moment
in history any reason to think that in
the part of the universe that we've
observed,
there's any life.
What do you think of the theory that
life does not come here in a physical
sense,
but comes here through your mind in that
what psychedelics are is real like
gateways to communicate with other life
forms and that we were hung up on the
idea that something has to actually be
right there to talk to you.
Um,
wait something.
The theory,
the theory is.
And psychedelics opened up some sort of
a gateway that allows you to communicate
with aliens.
That's the only aliens have.
There are the aliens only exist in this
is when you take a psychedelic,
you can communicate with it.
You can enter into some sort of a
frequency that the alien is on.
That's the only way they get here.
They don't get here through metal ships.
That's all just craziness.
Uh,
alien contact only comes through
psychedelics.
It's an interesting idea
to what end are very dismissive.
But I believe,
I forget who was.
Yeah,
whose
idea that was.
But there was a.
God Damn it when the aliens or whatever
they watch when they're in our bodies.
I don't know.
It might've been when Kennedy's idea as
well.
Yeah.
He had a lot of nutty ones abroad about
mushrooms.
I'm pretty sure it was him,
but his idea was that it was an alien
life form.
And then that's how you would,
you would communicate with it.
He didn't think it was going to come
here and metal shifts.
He thinks it was going to come here
through the frequency that you would
achieve heavy duty psychedelic state
that he believes he believes he was
really encountering something else.
You don't believe that you don't know.
You believe that it's just just the
deepest facets of your imagination or is
there a kashic records like do you
believe in any of that?
What is that?
The ACACIA,
Acacia,
Greg Kaushik.
The idea that there's knowledge and
information out there and you just tune
into it and that there's a record of
information and like literally exists
that you can just tune into and this is
where creativity comes from.
The other in creativity.
When you teach eve the zen state of
being completely in the moment,
these ideas would just come to you.
The idea is that these ideas are not
just the firing of your synapses and the
accumulation of your life experiences,
but in fact you are pulling from a well
of information that's out there that you
can't quite recognized a regular basis
and that there's.
There's knowledge inherent to to the
world and I think it's called the a cash
occur.
Acacia records is the idea behind.
It's almost like taking account to
there.
It's almost like a crude way of
explaining why we don't understand
creativity.
While you know,
we don't understand the state of mind to
achieve the proper creativity is like
this zen excepting sorta like when I'm
in the zone.
When you're writing something,
you know you have great writing,
I read a bunch of Shit.
You,
you write some really beautiful lines,
but you know how sometimes they just.
Sometimes you're banging them out,
but sometimes they're just flowing.
It's almost like they're coming out of
you,
like you go into this zen state and
like,
oh,
that just came to me like,
here's this thing.
Some people believe that the.
What you're doing is by being really
creative,
you're tuning in to intelligence,
you're tuning into ideas and that the
human body and it's managing as
consciousness is really just managing a
radio,
right?
I mean,
yeah,
there's a lot of that.
I find all those ideas kind of Hokey,
well just ultimately disempowering
because the de emphasize the agency that
human beings have in creating,
oh,
we can create.
Our brains are not sufficient to create,
we need to tune into some kind of a
record of that creates for us.
Um,
it's sort of a religious idea as well
that,
that there's like a god that gives us
some kind of power.
I think that's a pattern and a lot of
these ideas is that they try to remove
power from the individual and place it
in some kind of intangible realm that we
can access through being pious or
through following some set of rules.
But ultimately I don't want to buy into
any of those ideas.
I,
I find that I completely agree with you
and that I think that a big part of it
is when people do better with creative
endeavors when they're humble and so
it's sort of a way of not taking credit
for what they're doing and just tuning
into the right creative frequency.
And sometimes that creative frequency,
the best way to do is just give it up to
like a higher power.
Sure.
And that's not to say that it doesn't
help people in the same way that
religion,
even if it's wrong,
helps an enormous number of people.
Well,
I've always said that it's a great
operating system for a lot of people and
it really does enhance their life.
There's a lot of people that,
for whatever reason,
I don't know whether it's they're
uninspired or whether they have brains
that don't function at the right Rpms or
whatever it is.
But if you give them a some sort of an
ideology,
they can live a happy life.
But if you left them alone in the sea of
doubt and in the unknown,
they could go down any path they could.
They could wind up a mess.
They could wind up depressed.
I got mine up fucked up.
They can wind up in a cult.
You give them a happy religion to just
live 70,
happy years,
die,
be happy that they know they're going to
go to heaven and everything's cool.
It's almost like it's a,
it's an effective operating system.
And at the end we were really not
exactly sure how much of this fucking
thing we're controlling with our mind.
We're really not.
There's a lot of doubt on that.
There's a lot of doubt as to how much of
life is truly random and how much of it
is really created by the energy you put
out your imagination,
your,
your actions and your deeds.
What the fuck is really going on?
Is it 100 percent physical or is there
some.
Is there some manifestation that the
imagination takes part in?
We don't really necessarily know.
There's people that are always good.
Things are constantly happening to them
and they're always in great moods and
they seem to perpetrate that same energy
forward and you look at people like that
and you wonder like how much of that is
them?
How much of that is they just figured
out how to roll this thing and figured
out how to create reality if they
figured out how to just ride this thing
correctly.
Is it possible?
Yes,
it is,
right?
Absolutely.
Yeah.
You're one of the most experienced guys
I think I've ever come across and as far
as altered states of consciousness and
you're not an old guy.
How old are you?
Thirty four.
Twenty four.
Jesus Christ son.
I was going to say you're 30.
You're a hard 24 kids.
I've seen them on the apple commercial.
You were really young and that one,
somebody just sent me that.
That's crazy.
Dude.
You're way too smart to be 24.
That's scary.
It is.
That's fascinating,
man.
When I was 24,
I spoke in grunts for the most part.
That's amazing,
man.
Wow.
You um,
you.
Yeah.
You,
you must be the most experienced person
I've ever met.
Right?
Many,
many more experienced in this case.
I actually don't know that.
All this stuff he's really done.
What do you take out of it,
man?
Do you,
are you happy that you had all these
experiences that changed you who you
are?
Absolutely.
Yeah.
It's good.
I think just experimentation in general
is important.
Can everybody handle it?
Probably not.
Probably not,
right?
but I'd be a fix that.
That's a very,
very complicated question.
So good one though,
because you got a problem.
Some guys are good worker.
I think it requires.
She was good with the landscape in
business.
So that fucking Hamilton Morris,
cardamom acid.
Sure.
Yeah.
No,
I've had close friends that dropped out
of society for whatever reason because
they started to find a pointless.
And it's difficult to argue with that if
someone really genuinely feels that way.
But um,
I think there's just a,
it's sort of an infantilizing gen
generally disempowering idea in
psychiatry and throughout society that
we are not in control of ourselves.
We probably see a doctor.
The doctor is the expert on our mind and
our body and they tell us what's wrong.
They know us better than we know
ourselves even after only talking to us
for five minutes.
And so if you go to a psychiatrist and
you say,
I'm having trouble working,
may maybe depressed and they have adhd,
what do you think I should do?
I think that adderall would help me.
It's immediately suspicious because you
think you already know too much about
what you need.
They want you to go in as an infant
that.
So they can tell you what you need,
I believe that you have,
there's some emphasis or some,
there's some impact at the imagination
and your thinking and your energy
has on life.
But I also believe there's a lot of
random shit too.
I don't think it's an either or.
I think it's a combination of you
interacting with all these other people
that are also creating their own
realities at the same time and that you
can have a,
you,
you can all tune into a,
a good frequency and perhaps you know,
create a good community.
And I think that's what people try to do
it in tribes and shit like that.
But at the end of the day,
you're still dealing with random shit.
Like the idea that you blame people for
fucking diseases or for being attacked
by barbarians,
you know?
Is that,
was that in the secret,
you know,
the secret work back 10.
Did they manifest these barbarians to
come over the hills and,
and,
and chop people up.
But swords back into Kona and days.
No,
right.
You can't say it's completely.
Nobody would ask for that.
Nobody would create that in their own
imagination for there for themselves,
so it's not,
it's not that you are completely in
control of your destiny,
but it seems like you have at least some
sort of influence with energy and with
your imagination and with,
you know,
the things that you create and the
environment that you set up.
I think that's one of the most important
things that I've ever learned from
psychedelics.
Absolutely.
Yeah.
And just being in a mindset to try new
things,
whatever,
whether they're chemical or experiential
or whatever.
I think cautiously try to consciously.
You're,
I mean obviously you didn't find out all
this information about it after you've
tried all these things,
you knew that going in.
What's the one thing that you ever did?
We were like,
Oh boy,
here we go.
In what way?
This might be a slippery one.
Ugh,
God.
Slippery one.
I mean,
I've had a few slippery ones in my day,
but uh,
I think a lot of the really potent
psychedelics have,
have the ability to induce terror if
you're too high of a dose.
I've had that happen with both dmt and
suicide than,
um,
so just so many,
so many different occasions,
but suddenly I've never had anything
where I will actually have.
Yes,
I have,
I've had a few kind of close to what I
would consider overdose of psychedelics,
where the dose is just so high that I
think there might be some physical
toxicity,
but,
but with those sorts of cases,
it's very difficult to differentiate
between what is motivated by fear.
You know,
a lot of people,
even when they're sober,
they'll,
they'll panic or be uncomfortable and
think they're having a heart attack,
but it's just a panic attack or it's not
even a panic attack.
Um,
you know,
the mind is so informed by the body that
especially in a psychedelic state,
that it's very difficult to say,
what if you're drinking IOWASCA and
suddenly your heart starts beating fast.
Is your heart beating fast because
you're scared?
Are you scared because your heart is
beating fast?
And which do you concentrate on the
heart or the fear first in order to calm
yourself down?
Yeah.
And you might be throwing a puzzle that
you can't wrestle with.
It just runs you over.
It's just too much.
And you're just there in utter fear and
until it
slowly leaves your system.
Yeah.
I overdosed when I ate that one bad
shroom trip,
you know,
like six months ago.
I mean,
I couldn't walk.
My legs would not work.
I,
they would.
They were failing.
Well,
yeah.
That's how he,
he got over seven grounds.
It was a lot too much.
And that's just a guest that was over
seven.
It could be way more than that.
You know,
you,
you're silly.
You went to hearts on not,
it's not unnecessary.
Yeah.
Did you come back?
Well,
what'd you come back?
Fucked up.
Took me a while.
Like a day.
A good 24 hours after two.
I felt 100 percent.
But didn't you learn something from the
experience?
Uh,
yeah.
My wall was like,
or my bathroom was like,
Tron,
the original tron.
If you two had a conversation,
I'd say,
well,
which one of these is 24?
Which one is almost,
it's almost scary.
How old are you now?
Thirty seven.
Thirty seven,
37,
he's 37 and you're 24 and see that.
And he votes too.
I took molly the other day and it,
molly,
Molly said the MTMA and it was a very,
I've noticed something recently doing
shrooms and it happened for some reason
with molly this last time.
So it makes me wonder how much of it was
really Mali.
But uh,
I could see so much better when I'm on a
psychedelic.
Like,
like it seems like my eyes were up
because her pupils are bigger.
So you probably don't have that vision.
No,
I mean like brighter.
I mean everything's a lot brighter
though.
Like I can almost see in the garden
tools and it makes me.
And I had this thing I was thinking of
like it would be weird if like all the
shit that you see when you're
showrooming is there all the time,
but your eyes adjust to the certain
lightness or there's certain level of
being open that you see it more when
you're on shrooms.
So like,
like when you're seeing like you're
looking at your hand,
you're seeing like this crazy shit all
rounded like these,
like,
like minds that are growing over.
What if that Shit's there all the time,
but you're just focusing in on that
layer of a brightness or if it was more
as we throw to you possible surveys,
one here qualified to answer that.
Uh,
I would say if I had an answer for you
poppy cock,
it was just one of the things I thought,
wow,
I'm molly because I was looking like
Jesus.
I can see in the dark right now.
Let's make a bet.
Let's make a bet because I say,
he says it's bullshit.
What do you say?
Oh,
it's just a theory.
It's a.
What if no one knows.
I would probably say,
well,
it's your brain just shutting down.
Going crazy.
If I had to support your own thing.
No,
no.
I'm just saying it's a.
What if I don't?
I'm not just saying.
What do you think he would think?
Oh,
I would say is even right.
I would say he would be exactly what he
says on everything you know,
like he's takes the safe route,
which is what I do,
and it's like I'm not going to fuck.
He takes the scientific,
the scientific route,
way more angels and Unicorns.
I'm looking for bigfoot,
Bro.
I'm always looking for bigfoot,
but I know I'm looking for bigfoot.
I know I really want big foot to have
this,
but I don't think he does.
Right.
But I really want them.
You know what I mean?
Right.
I mean,
you don't see any.
Nothing exists in the first place.
None of this is colored or has any.
Nothing actually looks the way we
perceive it as a sensory phenomenon.
And so to say what things are actually
like is already problematic because it's
a sensory experience.
So how you.
Yeah.
That is fascinating,
isn't it?
It's almost impossible for people to
really wrap their heads up that your
mind puts that red in that picture.
Your mind puts the dark and someone's
hair,
your,
your interpretation of the world.
I will,
you know,
and then that's the total stolen talk.
Wonder Man.
It's like the color blue,
like what does it look like to you,
man?
When you see this guy,
what does it look like?
You do?
You really don't know.
We do know that it is different for some
people really different.
Well,
I mean there's this colorblindness is
like linguistic relativity and color
naming.
There's been a lot of scholarly research
into the issue where certain primitive
societies have fewer names for colors
and so they'll,
they'll only have black and white and
that will encompass black one.
Companies like red and blue and white,
so it's not cross culturally defined in
any way to.
It must suck to get your car painted
there.
Can you car painted in the jungle?
Like I asked for blue.
This is red.
You fuck that.
Like same shit.
The end of the podcast.
We just all lost.
Complete total news.
Yeah.
Asm.
I don't even know how we got onto the
subject of the color.
Where did that come from?
He was saying that he saw vines crawling
all over the interpretation of things
around us.
I love molly though and I think it's one
in this beautiful drugs ever.
Is it illegal?
Totally illegal by Joe.
Have you?
Have you done it?
No,
I've only done Mtma and I only did it
work.
You take your wife to Hawaii,
you sit on the beach and you do two each
and you just sit there and you will
fucking have the most beautiful time in
the whole entire road and you're going
to have a reset.
You're going to be so you and your wife
are going to connect in a way that
you've never had since you've started
dating.
And it's,
it's,
it's gonna be amazing.
Well,
it's,
I highly recommend it more than
anything.
Why?
I love it.
It's like a little love bug.
Get Molly.
You will have the time of your life.
How much maurice,
you're a a young fellow.
Um,
how do you find a mate that can deal
with any of this?
Talking in conversation?
How do you,
how you at 24 years old guy or girl,
I don't know if you're gay or straight,
but how do you find anybody to hang out
with that?
You would,
you know that you're ready?
Start off looking in trees or chicks?
Well,
I'll tell you right now,
it's gonna be a tough conversation at
dinner.
Well,
many people that are interested in the
scientific element of a few close
friends who are scientists who I talk
with about this kind of stuff.
So when you date,
how do you,
you know,
what did you do at work today?
And you started talking about feminine
allylamines and all these different
crazy shit.
Do you have girls?
Do their eyes glaze over or do they,
did they look to you for God?
I mean it depends on what their academic
background is,
but yeah,
I would say most people are not
interested in that sort of thing unless
you.
I'm trying to phrase this as high as
possible without actually saying it,
but you must get mad amounts of stoner
pussy thrown at you.
At least.
Come on man.
You're like a.
you're an online stoner hero type.
Do they must just chicks boss launched
at you?
You don't use the twitter enough.
I don't.
Maybe today's the day that I started
Hamilton Morris one when that letter.
One name no space.
Yeah,
he's got one tweet.
But if you're going to have one tweet,
this is the fucking tweet to have.
What was.
What was your tweet?
You have one amazing tweet.
What is your one tweet?
Do you remember?
None at the top of my head.
It's a pastor
second.
Trying to find it now,
right?
I want you to talk one profile.
Please vote for me on the shorter shorty
where it's got a desk dot TV and at the
top of it click on phone for me and I'm
getting beat by a wwe wrestler that has
half a million hits.
I won't win,
but it just makes me feel happy that I'm
in second place.
At least Hamilton.
Mars only has one tweet and this is it.
In the realm of scientific observation,
luck is granted only to those who are
prepared.
That's romantic.
You can have one quote by the way.
I think that quotes kind of hacky.
There's A.
There's a couple of versions that are
out there.
You know,
somebody,
somebody fucking gangsters,
quote.
Luck is only granted those prepared.
You know,
success is when luck meets preparation.
It's like an old.
That's the oldest quotation ever.
They just,
Dr that shit up.
It made it fancy.
They made it sound a little profound.
Little more profound,
but really basically they dug,
they dot an old saying a Fox,
but if you're going to have one quote,
that's it dude.
And I like,
I didn't even use quote marks or didn't
use it.
Period though.
You used the period maybe should be
attributed to someone,
but it's easy enough.
Yeah,
they should figure it out.
Right?
You didn't write that yourself.
Did you fade away like Def Leppard?
I don't know.
Did he say that?
Hamilton Morris.
This has been our worst podcast we've
ever had,
but it's only because of us.
Really.
You were amazing.
Every time we called upon you,
your questions were great.
We just got Brian a little two.
It's two stones and it threw us off a
little.
But uh,
it was fascinating,
man.
You,
uh,
you don't have to turn the music.
Let him pump up his shit right now.
It's going to put.
Um,
so if,
if people want to watch any of your
stuff,
um,
it's Hamilton's Pharmacopia.
That's right.
Yeah.
That's what it is.
And Vice magazine and then vice
magazine.
Copia on VBS.
Was there any one site that's the best
place to access all your stuff?
A vice is the main place.
I usually post new things on my blog.
Also Harper's magazine,
so they should google it.
Right.
But not today because Google's down
bitches is.
Wikipedia is down
the protesting Sopa they're trying to
take it folks.
They know.
They know the end is near for them.
They know you're good for hillbrow
people for big corporations like Google
and that in a wikipedia for standing up
for this shit.
Well,
I heard it's dead.
I heard the bill is dead as it stands,
but they're going to try to rework it.
I don't know.
It's terrifying.
This is.
It must terrify you mean you.
You're on the Internet constantly and
you're doing illegal shit.
Yeah,
I mean it could have some employee.
The idea that they can just come in and
take down your site at their discretion,
and this was right after the Nda,
a a national defense authorization act
passed,
which is another terrifying thing to.
Could just arrest you.
They don't have to have a warrant.
Just we were wearing weird times,
man.
They're coming after your dual cassette
recorders guys.
They're coming after your flashlight,
so by another one.
Go to [inaudible] dot net and click on
the link for the flashlight,
codenamed Brogan,
and you'll get 15 percent off the number
one sex toy for men,
Hamilton.
Morris,
if you want,
I can have some shipped to you.
You don't have to say anything on air.
Just wink twice.
You're good.
Okay.
Shipment on the way.
No worries.
So the effect of masturbation product.
Ladies and gentlemen,
it's a weird subject.
It's much like psychedelics.
It's really underappreciated.
It's physical maintenance,
I think.
I think it's good.
The body needs to be able to breathe as
often as possible.
And uh,
that's too distracting.
You don't want to involve all these
different people in your life and have
sex with them.
Get yourself a flashlight.
Kids.
It's not that expensive.
They last a long time.
As long as you don't do what Brian does
them and fixed them,
turn them inside out shows going on
anyway.
Go to [inaudible] dot net and click on
the link for the flashlight and enter in
the code name Brogan and you're good for
furniture for number one.
First store from thank you to onnit.com
o n n I t,
makers of Alpha brain,
new mood,
shroom,
tech,
sport,
shroom,
tech,
immune,
all that good shit.
If you go to Joe Rogan.net,
click on the Alpha Brain logo entering
the code named Rogan.
You'd get 10 percent off.
Thank you.
Hamilton Morris for coming down and
please start using twitter.
You're too fucking cool to not be on
twitter.
We want to pump you up.
Please follow Hamilton Morris h a m I l
t o n m o R R I s on twitter and make
this motherfucker tweet.
You need to contribute bro.
You're a part of the hive.
You're a valued member.
If people want to watch his stuff,
any of that stuff,
just Google Hamilton Morris.
That's the simplest way because vice,
they do awesome shit,
but it's crazy trying to go to that site
and navigate it and try to find
anything.
If anybody wants to come to Chicago,
tickets are almost sold out.
That is a the 27th and it's with me Joey
Diaz and Duncan trussell.
That's the Chicago theater.
Friday,
January 27.
That's going to be fun.
It's fun because then the next night
it's UFC on Fox Hamilton.
Thank you very much for being on one of
our most awkward podcast ever,
but you were a delight to talk to.
You're a wealth of information and a
cool motherfucker.
Thanks a lot buddy.
Thanks for having me.
All right folks,
we will see you next week.
That's it for this week to get some
sleep.
Oh yeah.
And the Ice House.
Um,
I've had no sleep for days.
I'm so.
I'm,
so.
I've never been more out of it doing a
podcast ever.
Um,
my,
my little girl's been throwing up and no
sleep at night.
And coming from Brazil,
I'm a mess.
So if I sound half retarded today,
I will bounce back.
I promise you,
next week I'll be strong.
I'm going to take some Alpha brain and
some fresh squeezed juice and want to
get the party started.
So see you guys next week.
Um,
I think Greg Fitzsimmons is doing this
sweet and uh,
I think Brian Cowen was due as well and
we,
Brian,
we're going to do Brian's the new
podcasting Friday.
Brian counts new podcast.
Pilot starts at 7:00
PM Pacific and then right after that
we're,
we have an ice house chronical.
We put the tickets on sale for sale
right now@icehousecomedy.com
and it would just have her chrysler and
it might have Duncan trussell and it's
going to be a big surprise,
but it definitely has Bryan County.
It's whoever's in town were.
All of our friends are in town.
We um,
we just decided to do this show
yesterday.
So if the tickets are not on sale they
will be soon.
So that's a Friday night.
Ten PM,
10 PM,
10:00
PM.
Podcast starts at nine.
All right.
And then the podcast,
icehouse chronicles,
you could watch it here on ustream slash
Joe Rogan ustream dot TV slash Joe
Rogan.
Or you can get it on itunes but only on
the death squad label.
So you have to subscribe.
Death Squad get that.
And there's a lot of the cool podcasts
on that.
Sam Tripoli's a show,
the naughty show.
I'm one of the funniest shows I've ever
had last night with that penthouse pet.
Two thousand 12.
Oh,
in Brad Williams.
Yeah.
We're going to get.
Williams was fantastic.
Them on.
We'll get them on if he can get
permission.
All right,
thanks everybody.
We'll see you soon.
Bye.
What's it?
Smile.
Smile for the picture.
Okay.