Thanks for doing this man.
My pleasure.
My right.
Here we go.
Experience Joe Rogan podcast.
There's only been two people ever.
The dentist Mckenna's record recommended
for this podcast.
You and josh worker him,
so that puts you in very lofty company.
Dahmer.
That's the way Daimler.
Dame French.
It's dumb air.
But is that how your family pronounces
it the correct way?
Damers the best.
But do your friends call you a dumb air
buddy?
Like give you full respect in the French
heritage?
No.
That's a thousand years ago.
They gave it up after awhile.
They gave it up after they invaded
Britain.
Ten 66.
That's clever.
That's a good move.
You've got a very unusual background,
man.
I mean,
Dennis would not stop raving about you
and then when I started doing research
on you,
I was like,
you were.
This is the craziest story of all time.
Not not the craziest,
but it's pretty crazy.
You were in burning man during Katrina
with you are partying and Bernie Mann
with people who work in the Pentagon.
Yes.
When Katrina went down camp ply a gun.
That is the most ridiculous thing that
gives me great discomfort to know.
The people who work in the Pentagon are
partying at burning man rocking.
We called for Blackhawks,
but we got the order tonight,
but that's a whole other.
That's a whole story.
Well,
that's.
We'll.
When Katrina was happening,
you guys were amongst the people that
were in burning man,
the very few that had a connection to
the outside world.
If we had a,
you know,
we're.
Our camp was doing the Wifi and the
Internet for burning man,
for the public and emergency networks,
the private network.
And so we had a dish and we could
takeover satellites.
So one of our guys took over recon
satellite.
Is it a Pentagon move?
Is it depending on.
Woo.
So he took this thing offline and I'd
actually been at a,
a is NRO national reconnaissance office.
I had been at an nro launch just the
year before.
And then I look over and I see the logo
on the laptop and I say,
what are you doing,
you know,
to this man who remain nameless.
He said,
shut up and turned his laptop away.
And he pounded in a code and he took
this thing off line and so our iridium
phone rang,
you know,
this Pentagon wireless satellite phone
that's like the,
the,
the general on the other side is saying
what's going on and basically the,
he instructed the guy not to answer.
So we then had control of this thing and
we could watch Katrina come in because
the government wasn't doing with all
this national resource assets to,
to help people.
And this was the frustration that he
had.
He wanted to be evacuated to be taken
out off Playa with Black Hawks and heavy
duty helicopters because he had just
come back from the Asian tsunami,
you know,
the event.
And then he went straight to,
to Afghanistan and then he went to
Baghdad.
And then he came to burning man.
I looked at this man's face.
It was like lying deeply,
you know,
just unbelievable stress.
Can you imagine this was his job.
He works under title 10 money,
doing extreme comms,
extreme emergency relief efforts.
And he's invented all this shit,
like cell phones that come down on
parachutes that'll run for a month.
And people pick up these cell phones and
push a button and there's somebody who
speaks tagalog the right on right there
to say,
what do you need?
What are your.
What's your position in that?
Cool.
That's amazing.
Cell phones run for a month.
They're like in rubberized cases,
this guy has invented all this
technology.
So this rubber Rebecca
case just has a massive battery in it.
Sentence
recharged.
Yup.
So this guy is really thinking.
So here,
here we have a natural disaster
happening in our own country.
You know,
barreling in.
Nobody at burning man knows about it
because there's no cell phone service
fan back in 2007.
It's barreling in and 2005 rather.
And we watch it coming in.
Now the,
the amazing thing is we,
we saw you could watch a video for more,
but on this screen,
on this guy screen,
and you could watch people walking down
like we saw levy breach the first levy
breach in the ninth ward or something.
We saw that on the screen from,
from our camp at burning man.
So when you say you took over
satellites,
satellites that are broadcasting,
what is it?
Broadcasting media like news,
Fresno,
high risk reconnaissance imagery.
Okay.
So it's a satellite that is like one of
those spying on bad guy satellites.
Exactly.
Whoa.
Yeah.
Couldn't eat.
We couldn't read.
I can talk about this.
Go ahead.
If someone finds out about that,
is that like,
is this an issue?
I don't think so.
I mean it's something that would be
really frowned upon.
Well the,
the phone,
the iridium phone kept ringing.
Yeah.
It's like your dad's call and you're
having a party.
The neighbors are calling your dad
going,
hey man,
I don't know what your son's doing,
but uh,
the lights are on,
there's a million people on your front
lawn and the phone just keeps ringing
and you're like,
ah,
but these guys knew who they're dealing
with.
This is this innovative genius type guy
that is totally respected and
organization.
So the general that initiated the
inquiry was covering for him.
Oh,
I see.
So the general could then contact space
command and say,
I can't get any of.
Oh,
okay.
Okay.
I see.
He had put the satellite in some kind of
a failsafe fallback mode,
so they would spend the several days
trying to get back into it.
Whoa.
He was just like,
we kept passing it and keeping them out
and burn hydrazine and locate,
you know,
stuff on,
on the Playa.
Wow.
So tell me all the details,
but he's basically,
don't you know,
I'm doing this right.
What,
what kind of satellite Internet
connection was available in 2005.
It was a very small,
slow upward,
a little bit quicker download,
but still pretty whack.
Right.
By that time you have the next year I
think they got the big tower on the
plier which had the dish.
They went right to gurlack with
[inaudible] three connection.
But what does,
what does that mean?
What'd you just sick of?
Really fast.
A sort of,
almost like a radar less.
What is girl girl?
Oh,
you haven't been out there?
Ah No.
You know,
I love hippies in small doses.
Hippies to me,
like pizza.
We just can't.
I can't eat pizza every day for like a
month I was with.
But you can hang around ply a gun
Pentagon people and yes,
I could probably hang around your camp.
Went out there with and they're dirty
people with Sherpas,
Sherpas,
you know,
they're,
they're white people,
White Sherpas,
servers for the billionaires and they're
billionaire camps,
but that's too much.
And they have walls of motor homes or I
want to hang out with 100,000
air camp.
I don't want to hang out with ability of
Eric.
You want to hang out with people who
live in rvs and like,
everybody's clean.
But I don't need Sherpas will come.
You know what I.
here's a secret that I'll tell you on
here.
Oh well it won't be a secret.
A secret.
My of my mit.
So Dennis hasn't been to burning man.
Dads,
mechanic,
good.
Me and him.
Same page.
So I've two old guys don't want to party
with young kids.
So I told him that.
Dan,
to tell you that Dennis would only go to
burning man if you went.
Oh,
did you do it the opposite way?
That's against each other.
There you go.
Yeah.
That doesn't work with me,
but thanks.
That's sweet.
So I would go anywhere with him though,
anywhere with Dennis.
I really would go with him just to talk
to them for days.
Yeah.
He's,
he's amazing.
The world's most amazing teddy bear.
Yeah.
He's uh,
he's.
He explained the stoned ape theory in a
way that I've never heard anybody
explain before with science and the way
that psilocybin interacts with the human
mind in a way was like,
oh yeah,
oh,
that had to be a part of it.
You know,
I'm sure there's many factors that led
to the increase in human brain size,
but when he describes it,
he was like,
oh,
that's fucking mushrooms has to be.
And you know,
we were at a meeting,
an event yesterday where all the
silicide when research was being
presented by the Johns Hopkins teams and
Ucla and Madison thinks these people are
doing silicide funded research to for
smoking cessation,
end of life,
reduction of anxiety and ptsd.
And this one young researcher,
Matt,
that we talked to,
he basically said this amazing thing
which was,
we're not
plugging up neurotransmitter portals to
deal with addiction here.
We seem to be hitting higher order brain
functions much higher rather than
plugging up your desire for nicotine.
We're when we watched the FMRS,
when we put people under the magnet,
which means put them in an Fmri try
realtime brain scanning.
We watched this,
the parts of the brain talking to each
other like the default mode network
seems to be changed
and is this while you're under while
they're on mushrooms.
See,
I would have to think that suicide
suicide,
that was the thing that would radically
affect your experience because it an Mri
and Fmri.
Similar because I've been an MRI before.
It was like bang,
Bang,
Bang.
If I was on mushrooms and I was in an
Mri,
I would freak the fuck out.
Yeah.
I've never been in a functional Mri.
I've never been in Mr and Oh,
I was in one less than a year ago.
I had a,
an issue with my back and I had a
bulging disc in my back,
so I had to get an examined by an MRI
and you lie down on a plank,
like a little skinny little gurney thing
and they roll you into this tube machine
that's a giant magnet and all I could
think of some story that I had heard
about some kid who died because they
left a fire extinguisher in the room and
then turned on the Mri and it sucked the
fire extinguisher into the bag and
killed one freak incident out of a
billion usage.
It was like a torpedo that killed
somebody.
Um,
but it's a very claustrophobic and
strange experience.
You roll into this thing and just lay
there,
you can't move and you can't bang,
Bang,
kick around your head.
It's all just echoing around you.
I mean,
you get earplugs put ear plugs on and
you close your eyes and just deal with
it.
But I would imagine that tripping on
that would be incredibly strange.
So I would think if for MRI is very
similar to its functional Mri,
if it's the same machine,
that would mean the old adage is,
you know,
five grams and silent darkness.
Right.
That's what terence always described her
as kind of prescribed or buddy this is
like the opposite of five grams and
silent dark desks
like a.
well maybe they've got it down to a
baseball cap now.
You know,
I don't think they do.
I've had two Mris actually in the past
year and a half,
so I'm pretty sure
maybe by the 2015 will all be like this
is a theory that I have of where it all
this is going.
Then I can
revealed to you later.
Oh,
excellent.
I'm absolutely interested.
But what all I was thinking was that the
whole experience of siliciden depends
very much so on where you're at while
you're experiencing it.
If you're in a beautiful,
peaceful place,
like
the colors are brighter and you see like
all sorts of cool visions and you have
this connection to nature where you feel
like you're grounded and.
But if you were in like some horrible
place and you were on suicide and you
would be very sensitive to that horrible
place,
I couldn't imagine like doing psilocybin
and going to like a war zone and
experiencing war,
you know,
or,
or anything else horrible like the gym.
What was the movie that depicted the
Vietnam fats?
You know,
what?
Was that a Jacob's ladder?
No,
the ones where they got high in Vietnam
on all said.
Oh,
what movie?
One movie A.
Not Apocalypse now.
Apocalypse now weren't an acid.
Oh,
that's right.
Martin Sheen was on acid when he punched
him when he did karate and his hotel
room and punch the mayor.
I know there's another,
there's a video of British soldiers on
acid and the fifties.
You remember that.
And they're all thing and they can't be
made to fear the enemy or put fear into
the enemy or be a part of any
organization,
which is what the British army was about
to become.
Anyway.
Yeah.
That's a beautiful video.
I love that video.
That was peace and love before the
Beatles even got rolling and 59,
right?
Yeah.
Well,
it shows you also what a incredible like
transformative drug that isn't really
for the most part,
all psychedelics have that capacity,
so incredibly transformative capacity
because you're here,
you're dealing with people whose job is
to kill folks.
That's what their job is and what are
they doing?
They're giggling and they're falling
down and they're not thinking about war.
They're,
they're like,
they think everything's preposterous.
You know?
And it's just amazing when you look at
the transformation in our culture from
the 1950 [inaudible] to 1970 when
everything was clamped down on.
I mean,
what a radical couple of decades of
change.
I mean,
people don't realize.
I mean I trying to explain to people
that if you like,
I'm a technology historian,
you know,
I have the Dog Barn Computer Museum,
I've got like 30 tons of vintage
computer hardware in the barn and I've
interviewed a thousand people on how did
this all happen?
How did the Arpanet get made?
How to apple found and all that sort of
stuff.
And that the years between 1945 and
1970,
oh my God.
The,
the change that happened.
Unbelievable.
And really if you drive into a
neighborhood like even around here,
San Fernando valley houses built in like
1962.
The only difference in technology is
that there's ether net,
like there's an internet,
there's a network and there's computers.
Otherwise House of 1970,
he had microwave ovens and a cable TV in
the beginning and all that sort of
stuff.
Not a lot of difference.
Just the digital tech.
That's the only really big thing that's
come in and that model has now spread to
the whole planet.
So China did it in shorter time,
you know,
and I lived in Czechoslovakia and they
did the whole transition in like eight
years.
This incredible South Africans at the
transition,
like 15,
just boom to our model shopping center,
you know,
off ramp,
wired into the Matrix,
you know,
consumer culture,
Boone,
the whole world just went bang,
Bang,
adopting that.
It's a very strange time,
isn't it?
Yeah.
And everyone's rushing to that model.
I mean,
there's no,
no stopping it.
Well,
it's,
everything's tied into it now too,
which is really spooky.
You know,
I'm absolutely fascinated by ancient
cultures,
by the idea that there were great
civilizations that fell apart and like
what caused it wasn't natural disaster
was at this,
was that.
And when you look at grain ham,
Graham Hancock on last month,
I've had grandma a few times.
He's awesome.
And I've also had Randall Carlson on
who's also really enlightening when it
comes to that subject because he's a
true expert in cataclysmic disasters.
Particularly the comment,
the putative comment impairment that
created all that flooding.
Yeah,
one of his.
I mean he's,
he's an expert on pretty much every
significant traceable impact and it's
really crazy.
He can drive his suv and read land.
Right.
You can sort of read the teaching him
about what happened.
Well,
he'll show you some things on satellite
images that if you looked at it,
you would go,
oh,
that's just some hills and heal.
But the way he described it,
he'll draw it out for,
you know,
here's where the crater is and this is
where the craters in the middle of this
ocean and this,
this part of the ocean.
And if you follow that crater out,
you realize these are where the waves
hit toward the landscape apart like
you're looking at a gigantic version of
what you see when you see the ocean
leave marks on the sand when high tide
comes in,
but you're seeing this unbelievably
extreme version of it that probably
happened instantaneously.
You remember Jerry personnel and Larry
Nibins Scifi classic Lucifer's Hammer.
No,
it's fantastic.
It was about a comment impact on the
Pacific and the scene.
These are master Saifai writers.
They both live in here in the San
Fernando Valley.
And this wave was a 1200 feet tall and
he did.
They describe it coming across the
southland.
And there's this surfer now,
the surfers out on Santa Monica,
right?
Decides to take this wave.
Now what's happening before the wave
arrives,
as the ocean is roaring at hundred miles
an hour out toward the sea.
So this guy has been carried out,
you know,
40 miles out to sea because it's wave is
sucking down the coastline,
but he knows what is going on because he
saw the fireball because I'm going to
die anyway.
I'm going to try to take this wave and
this is a great scifi novel and he does
it.
And what happens is the wave comes
across,
he looks down
and he can,
he's on the face of this wave is coming
across Los Angeles and,
and he's looking down at the city,
you know,
like 800 feet below as this wave is
because he has on the face of it and
he's managing his board and then he
just,
and he looks up and the,
the,
the language is great.
It's like in the first interstate
building,
hit like a flyswatter,
you know,
that's a crazy way to die in the wave
crashed.
It went inland to like a palm springs
kind of indio.
That's where.
And it created sort of Lucifer's hammer
worth getting worth getting.
And here's the reading.
Uh,
Larry Niven and Jerry poor now are the
two great hardcore Saifai writers.
And Larry told me about 15 years ago,
he said,
let me tell you something,
uh,
I was in my office when there was this
earthquake,
like you've been in the south line long
enough,
right?
There's this earthquakes every x amount
of time and they do a certain amount of
damage,
like northridge was big,
but before northridge,
Larry sit in his office at like eight in
the morning and an earthquake hits,
I think it's the whittier quake or
something.
And the last thing he remembers this a
bookshelf coming right at him.
Right.
And he comes to and he is blacked out.
I mean,
he's blacked out for a couple of hours.
Right.
And he has this vision comes to,
he sees a spine of books and one of them
says Lucifer's hammer hardcover edition.
And he realizes I was almost killed by
my life's work.
Yes.
And Lucifer.
Samara knocked him out.
Wow.
So he bolted the shelf to the wall for
the next one.
That's a good move.
Bolting shelves.
Always good move here.
We started this off talking about,
um,
being fascinated with ancient
civilizations and the fact that we don't
really like,
we know quite a bit about ancient Egypt
in,
in sort of,
if you look at it,
the fact that it's 2,500
plus BC and we know quite a bit.
That's a long time ago and we have some
pretty incredible structures are still
remained from them,
which is pretty amazing.
But no writing.
I mean just hieroglyphs we don't have
books for the library of Alexandria was
burned to the ground and who knows what
was in that,
you know,
there's so much lost when it comes to
ancient civilizations and one of the
things that I worry about is that we're
moving everything digital and
everything,
even more than just digital.
People are storing things in the cloud
like crazy and that when we get a
Lucifer's hammer,
it's all gone.
Right.
That's the thing is if we left behind
some flash drives and some hard drives
in some old computers and stuff and then
everybody else died except for like a
few thousand people that live like
nomads,
how long would that stuff even make it?
How long would it take?
We'd all be absorbed by the earth.
Right.
You remember wally trying to get all the
trash compacted and everything and he's
choosing things that he would know the
volley
of the robot from the movie,
the Pixar movie and he's like,
oh,
keep that.
You know,
because he's,
he's making a library apart,
so he hit himself going skins of going
for 50,000
years this way and the shit he's
throwing away,
like he does keep an ipod because it
plays his favorite movie,
you know,
and he's able to rig it up.
He's a robot,
right?
He's a little macintosh robot,
right.
But uh,
it's interesting to see the pixars
depiction of what is going to trash and
when the earth is so toxic and is
covered with trash and the people have a
VAT evacuating our living aboard a ship
because the earth detoxified.
But we're sort of banking on the fact
that nothing happens when we have like
the Georgia guidestones which are
dubious.
It's very weird.
So key population to $500,000,
$500,
million worldwide or something like
that,
you know,
it's like very interesting rules to live
by,
but it doesn't tell you anything about
how to set up solar power,
you know,
what is the Internet,
how is it,
how does it connect China to the UK,
you know,
there's none of that.
So here's an interesting thing for you.
Britton,
southern Britain,
when Rome fell right and the Romans
left,
no one was there to maintain lead pipes.
So the Romans invented fantastic bath
systems with lead pipes that that could
run cold water,
hot wire,
that valves and everything.
It's all this stuff went to potty and
the roads went bluey and the Roman roads
were straight and they had these
mountains on either side that you could
have watchers and stuff like that.
And it was super high tech,
right?
And then Roman went away and all this
stuff just fell into ruin.
And the British forgot how to make
bricks.
So there are no brick buildings,
you know,
they had to go back to knocking out
stone to build the first Christian
churches in England were made out of
because they did not have brick
technology gone.
What was the classic example of like,
what's going on right now is we have so
many things that we need.
Like I had a joke that I was doing about
how uh,
what I thought happened with Egypt was
that the dumb people just out fuck the
smart people and left behind a bunch of
shit that didn't understand and that if
I left you alone in the woods right now
with a hatchet,
how long before you could send me an
email,
right?
Like,
we have so much that we rely on on a
daily basis.
Me,
you might not understand it,
but I don't understand it.
Most people that use it don't understand
it.
One of the most terrifying TV shows I've
ever seen about this as James Burke's
connections,
which came around 1980.
And in the first episode,
what you see is this British guy,
you know,
he's a master presenter,
right?
And he's walking up to a screen door on
a farm and he's saying the electricity
has been off for a week,
two weeks,
four weeks.
The people are starving.
People are trying to leave the city.
You escape the city.
You managed to get to this farm.
The farm is abandoned,
right?
You know,
it's one of the places you could
survive.
You are coming up to the door.
The people are not there.
What do you do?
You Go,
you see this a milking machine,
you can't use it.
It's no electricity.
You see everything that you can't use to
farm even though you maybe you
understand farming,
but modern farming.
Then you go up into the attic of the
barn and you find a discarded plow from
like the 19 tense.
That is your tool.
You have to know how to use that and how
to put that onto animals,
onto pulling draft animals to break the
soil.
You're now in the 11th century.
If you can't master that plow,
if you can find that plow and know
everything there is to do about that
technology,
you're Outta luck.
Everything else is just trashed at that
point and that would go away in a
thousand years if that was still left
around 10,000
years from now,
there'll be nothing.
No plows and knowing.
So how much do you think happened like
that with like ancient Egypt?
I mean,
how much of that stuff,
just whatever they built or whatever
they designed,
I mean we were essentially,
we have fossil remanence of their
civilization.
We have what,
what survived and pottery form and stone
form the papers all gone either burned
or destroyed or thrown in rivers or
whatever.
There's very little.
That's,
I mean,
how much of what we have today would be
around in just like a thousand years.
All the computers would be gone.
Cars would be gone.
You know,
there's that great tv.
Was it on discovery or history or they
showed the earth after people are center
people and man,
you knew watch Manhattan,
you watch the at 500 years.
Uh,
the Brooklyn Bridge finally comes down
because it's so well built.
You know,
the,
the case ons are all incredibly strongly
that the cable ties and everything.
They figured it would take about 500
years for those cables to rush through
in the finally the decking,
whatever's left of it to come down.
Nothing has nothing.
But that would be the last piece in New
York as this.
Their skeletal framework,
the blackberry bushes would come back,
the streams would come back in their
normal of Manhattan island,
right?
It would just come back.
Deer would come back in and when the
last things would be this,
this Brooklyn Bridge coming down.
That is so crazy,
but that totally makes sense.
I mean nothing.
None of that stuff lasts.
It's not going to lie.
We don't build mean the pyramids.
Did you know that?
The pyramids.
I didn't know this when we had this
wonderful lecture by an Egyptologist
who've worked on the Giza plateau for
like 20 years and he said,
we've discovered so many things about
the city of artisans and craftsmen teams
that built the pyramids by excavating
this massive area now that they've done.
He said,
one of the things we discovered as the
pyramids were classed clad with polished
limestone and they used it all to make
Cairo that chipped it all away.
It and you find this in vases in China
that this stuff was taken off the
cladding.
Is it?
The pyramids
used to be shine.
These to be like a prism,
say blind you if you're coming at a
certain angle in the desert,
in the sun.
They were just this incredible shining
pyramid.
Can you imagine the power on the average
nomads?
Seeing that with a gold cap too.
There was a golden cap.
So like our money,
you know,
with the little icon on the top.
Yeah,
but.
And so people will rip the stuff off and
they took it and it's all over the world
and various holes.
Assholes ruin everything.
But this,
this guy,
he showed us this initially,
he went to the Giza plateau in the
seventies.
He was part of some kind of a cult that
believes the parents were built by
extraterrestrials and he was literally
in this cult and he went to see it.
He was sort of like sent there by the
cult,
got so interested in excavation and the
reality of trying to really solve it.
He sort of left the cult,
went back,
got a phd and he's been working there
for 20 years and he gave us.
Oh yeah.
It was amazing.
Wow.
And he showed us,
like he said,
all the Hollywood mythology of slaves
building the pyramids and was all
complete.
You know who we are.
Here's,
here's the plan of the city of the
artisans and the construction teams and
the contractors that built a pyramid,
central avenue,
big hospital complex,
the best one in the ancient world,
huge bakery.
This bakery would make conical bread
loaves that the guys could put a rope
around,
throw over their backs and then go up to
the job site and they ate the bread.
And then he said,
we kept cutting down through sand
through these clay layers that didn't
see that they shouldn't be there.
There's,
you know,
20 feet down and there's a layer of
clay.
They figured out the clay was from a
quarry up up the Amazon App,
denial rather no wrong,
bring going in the wrong place.
And then he said,
well,
what on earth is going on?
And so they started excavating
horizontally and they found that these
were clay tracks.
And they said,
well,
what on earth is this?
And then they started seeing these.
These clay tracks matter a lot there,
not just leftover layers in the desert
and then they map them out and there was
a whole network of them and what they
were were low friction slipways and so
they said they put the blocks on some
kind of a canvas on some kind of a
thing.
They had mastered low friction.
They'd figured out that clay and an a
layer,
like a micro layer of water on it
creates a hydraulic system that you can
move massive tonnage on.
And so they built one of them using the
same clay from the same quarry up the
Nile they made when they brought all
these Cairo University engineering
students out or probably mechanical
engineering and they put like a
multivitamin block on canvas on this
track and these guys pulled and they
were able to get it up to some speed of
10 kilometers an hours.
Wow.
So this is how they move the volume of
the blocks.
Wow.
And it was probably started out,
you know,
they've been building pyramids for a
thousand years before that.
And so there's the famous bending
pyramid that's like not collapsed,
but about two because they didn't
understand foundation because you can't
build a foundation for a pyramid.
It's on sand.
Most of them were.
And by the time of Giza,
they mastered it.
You fill the area with water like you,
you,
you basically packs and down huge area,
acres and acres,
fill it with water.
And then the teams would go on,
they would pack the sand up to the level
of the water,
water's flat.
And then when they started laying down
their sort of first case ons that would
evenly compressed the sands is the key
thing is,
is massive compressive strength evenly
over the area so that the thing will not
abandon fall down.
Wow.
And they had to do it so accurately that
over 2 million,
500,000
blocks or could be like such little
deviation to line up at the top.
And that's so incredible.
They learned that these guys had
mastered a whole field,
which we lost,
which we didn't even know exist.
It's sand hydraulics.
So these guys were literally using
hydraulic sand is a flowing things like
water,
right?
You have an hour glass,
it looks like water flowing down,
but it's sand and so to,
to set keystones,
they would have a column,
a sand get the keystone to the top and
they would pull plugs out and the sand
would come down and it would.
The keystone would come down absolutely
perfectly in the right place.
San Hydraulics sound foundations,
clay for slipways smart dudes.
Isn't it amazing when you say what you
said a thousand years like they had been
making pyramids for a thousand years.
We can barely comprehend what a thousand
years.
A thousand years to us is like if you
want to go back to 1014,
can we even like Genghis Khan Times for
him?
And of course theater cathedrals took a
thousand years to master.
Right?
So think about the fact that they were
doing that,
making these things for a thousand
years.
And even though as far as we know,
they didn't have electronics,
they didn't have computers,
they didn't have any of these things.
They still have the human mind,
the human mind,
without electricity,
without engine,
the contemplate of time,
and they had a culture that supported it
well.
They also had this incredible connection
with the cosmos because of the fact that
they weren't dealing with light
pollution like we are.
We've done a really weird thing in our
arrogance.
I mean,
it's not arrogant that we did it.
We did it out of innovation that have
this burning desire to continually
create new and better things.
But our cities,
which is the giant population centers
we've ascended essentially cut off our
view of the cosmos almost entirely is
incredible.
Dan didn't,
and
they were entirely invested in not just
the cosmos,
but there are positions in the cosmos,
the,
the uh,
the astrological charts and where things
lined up and where the,
the shafts in the great pyramid that
would lead to various constellation and
then the lay lines of Europe.
And then incredible Denison.
I in August for rent running around
Macha Picchu and he said,
we've got to find the observatory.
We've got to find the observatory.
And he knows this place pretty well.
I had a wonderful tour of it from him
and we found it and it has this rock
that has all these angled pieces in and
it's a star map or a big,
big rock multi-tone rock,
but it's carved.
So if you look this way,
you're gonna you're gonna position on
this star and position on that star and
and the and it had a sort of a portal at
the top and this is what's remaining of
much peaches observatory.
So it's like all these people have this
knowledge gap as long as people stay
alive and they keep innovating,
they,
they do it differently than we're
currently experiencing it right now,
but they figured out a way to do it and
some really intense,
very sophisticated way.
And if you compare,
what does that Jamie the observatory,
is that it?
Probably.
Yeah,
that looks like and the thousands of
years ago,
right?
This is like at least a thousand years
ago that much.
Fifteen hundred.
1,400.
Okay.
So less.
Less.
Yeah.
In fact,
the Inca complexes,
Dennis and I and our group are running
around a lot of income complexes,
including peace sack and the other
places,
and they,
those dudes knew how to cut rock so
perfectly.
I mean,
when you know how they did that,
you know,
it's not known.
They could have used ropes.
Have you ever watched ancient aliens?
I,
you know,
I've never seen.
I've never seen that it was alien.
Everything's dealings I've ever seen
that show.
I'm a born skeptic.
I'm a Canadian,
so a more skeptical.
Oh,
much more.
Less religious.
So where it is,
we have a basically armchair views of
America.
I grew up watching all Canadians who
have watch America with exhilaration and
horror and admiration of your porch from
our porch.
Well,
you know,
they say there's a joke about North
America,
which is,
there's a three story apartment block in
the middle apartment is this out of
control fricking party and beer bottles
and crapping thrown.
That's America.
In the bottom is Mexico and all the beer
bottles in the crap are falling on that
apartment.
And up above is Canada and Canadians are
leaning over the balcony scene.
Can You keep it down a.
So that's problem was Toronto has rob
Ford.
Oh,
Toronto.
And Arab for.
So that's changing.
You're getting more American.
He'll soon be exported.
Thinks so.
And we should have him on the show.
I would have them on the show.
Absolutely.
I'd them high get an absolute crack
cocaine.
I would smoke crack with them just to
get them to do it right here on the
show.
Like one drug to get you in trouble.
You helped Graham break is fast.
Well he wanted to.
He,
he kept talking about it and I'm like,
you want to try it?
He kept looking over your way.
Come on.
He was great though.
He took a little baby,
hit another little baby hit and then he
was off to the races.
You can see it like the cannabinoids
receptors firing and all the words
flowing hours in his eyes.
And yeah,
he was.
He became like Terrence Well oiled.
Yes.
Yeah.
Well it's back to subject this.
It is amazing when you think of the fact
that these people did have these
incredibly sophisticated societies,
we just don't recognize them as
incredibly sophisticated because they
didn't have electricity because they
didn't have the combustion engine.
Those are are our benchmarks if you
don't have that,
you guys are dopes,
but meanwhile the reality is they had
some stuff that we still are perplexed
by some structures that have taken
decades upon decades of some of the
greatest archeologists,
geologists,
and engineers to try to even get a
theory as to how they put these things
together and that's all we've got.
Right?
I mean,
we've got some pretty good information
on a lot of things like you're talking
about the sand hydraulics,
but as far as like the ability to go out
and build one right now,
good fucking luck,
but like it at one of these ruins so
soon as the Spanish arrived in England
lands right?
What they did was have the inca knocked
down their own temples.
Oh God.
And then those stones were carried down
fucking white piano to build a Catholic
cathedrals.
Then the next earthquake happened.
The Catholic cathedral is were flattened
and ink and complex.
We're fine,
you know,
because there's 12 to 14 degree angles
on all the windows.
It's built to survive earthquakes for a
thousand years.
It's incredible.
And the water channels that has been no
maintenance for 500 years,
they're still pumping out billions of
gallons of water for all of these
firearms.
Amazing,
amazing and and I stood there in awe of
a 30 ton block.
You could see this.
This was above Cusco and this block was
carved like doop,
doop,
doop and does that mean tube,
tube,
angles,
angles but flat faces and then there was
a block next to those was perfectly
matched,
I mean no gaps.
And then the one down below I set the
stone.
Mason stood and studied a pile of rocks
and in his head,
because he was such a deep,
profound present engineer expert,
he saw the pattern of these rocks and
how they could fit together with the
least amount of cutting and with
perfection.
These guys had this in their heads and
they could like bone.
I know cut that.
Take that one.
That's going on the center and then they
had to lift them and they had to cut
them first and then lift them into
place.
They had to be perfect.
So this guy had three dimensional mental
acuity that blows our minds.
I mean any kind of world of warcraft
player couldn't navigate that space.
The three dimensional acuity of these
people.
Yet it really is incredible when you
think of what has all been accomplished
long before people invented the Internet
long before people were going to the
library to get their books on all this
stuff.
Or maybe they were,
you know,
library of Alexandria,
of course right now,
but it's,
it's thought of as primitive,
you know,
we still think of them as primitive and
when you compare the,
the work of John Anthony West and Graham
Hancock and Robert Schoch and all these
geologists and people that are pointing
to all these erosion,
mark's going,
you know,
we might be dealing with some really
ancient civilization mixed in with some
other civilizations that are like,
well everyone wants to date Egypt around
the same time,
but there's a growing movement of people
that are saying you're dealing with some
pretty significantly different
structures.
I know Graham cat covered in your show
him your last show.
It was just fascinating.
Thousands of years of rainfall erosion
in the last time there was rain fall in
the Nile Valley was 9,000
BC.
And did you know that?
When I was visiting the Sphinx about 20
years ago,
our guide said,
did you know that this thing has been
for 10,000
years?
But in the last 15 it has been so
damaged by Cairo city sanitation
department raising the water table.
So every he said,
every toilet flushes in the city of
Cairo is taking a chunk out of the
interior of the Sphinx.
So we are pumping in paraffin wax to
keep from coming apart.
So I mean,
look at the destructive power of our
civilization,
just haphazard and,
and the archeologists that gave us this
tour of the Giza plateau,
excavation,
they,
he said,
look,
here's modern Cairo coming up over top
of our excavation site.
We can excavate under that notice the
Warren of chaotic streets and bad
planning and pad everything.
And on top of this beautifully thought
out,
you know,
fully functional city of artisans and
construction people.
How have we evolved?
Tell us the acef fascinating that this
really wacky city is over one of the
greatest ancient cities ever.
Like Kairos is another example.
Yeah.
So how are we evolving exactly while
we're doing something?
Because the Mexico City during the
Aztecs,
if they knew what we know now or the
incose,
they would have known the Cortez was an
asshole and they were shot him and they
would have never thought he was a
warrior.
That was part God on a horse.
You know,
they would have not had any
misconceptions about him because they
would have known what a horse is.
They would have had the internet.
No one horseshit is horseshit,
but yeah,
literally and figuratively.
Right.
So here I want to propose you a theory.
Okay.
That's kind of captivated me and it's
partly woo and it's partly science,
but it'll really is my favorite stuff.
It's fear.
Favorite stuff.
I like half,
so half of woo.
So yeah,
you got a t shirt that has the blue on
the front wheel on the backs of you turn
around your woo.
But.
So that the Eleusinian mysteries,
you know about the La one and mysteries.
Yes.
So they ran for 1700,
1800 years.
They ran,
they started out before Greece.
The Greek civilization explain people
what it means,
what it,
what it was.
It was a kind of like a burning man or
more serious than I'm burning man was an
initiation ceremony that happened at
elusive in Greece and it was run by
women,
sort of high class women.
They were kind of a monopoly.
And when they finally got this thing
cranked up,
because we don't know much about the
earlier history,
but you can go to the temple of a to
date was destroyed in the fourth century
by characters that I want to bring up
later.
This is why we might be still in the
culture of the people destroyed
ellipsis.
So they built this thing.
So the fully powered appaloosas theme
park transformational experience was a
thousand person buried temple could,
could house a thousand initiates buried
under the ground so the people couldn't
see out.
So they were totally in an internal
process.
The initiates came from all over the
Mediterranean.
They included Roman emperors,
philosophers,
etc.
And you had to go to a loose once in
your life because the thought was you
then became a human being.
So they cAme off their boats,
they landed,
they wore the sink garb.
They had a fasting diet.
Sound familiar?
They say I had a fast ramadan.
It sounds like a.
What I would say today,
it sounds like people who are doing
initiatory practice iowasca for example,
people are going to mecca to see people
wearing the same clothes.
Exactly,
bring them down and so the initiates
would walk through villages and the
villages would come out and their job
was to cat call to to swear and bring
the people down.
Say,
oh,
you've got a big nose.
So,
so if it's a noble person who was a lot
of wealth,
they're getting screamed at by villagers
and they get knocked back to la,
knock them there,
their ego out and and to dissolve them.
Basically a boundary disillusion
exercise.
They were walking next to fields which
had wheat which had tiny mushroom like
purple.
It's a purple.
I'm a brain is shot today,
but it was basically a rust that would
grow on the wheat that was used to make
the chi keon drink that would be given
to the initiates after nine days or
eight or eight or nine days.
So this was like some ergot based forgot
basis in there.
Gotta mean sort of an earth based.
How do we know this?
Because I thought that was like a giant
mystery as to what they were taking.
Like some folks thought that it was
suicide and some people felt it was an
erg.
Got beer,
there was some sort of an origami beer,
I mean,
hoffman's book,
he talks about it apparently being in
ercot beer of some sort,
but there was definitely an inefficient
potion that was extremely powerful.
But what makes you think that it was
what you're saying?
Um,
because you can find this in the area of
alyssa's today.
You can find,
and I'm no expert.
I mean you should have an expert on
this,
on the show.
I've read a number of books about this,
but,
but when I pieced this together,
so there's a fantastic book called
psychedelia by patrick lundberg that
came out last year.
He paSsed away.
Unfortunately the author is quite a
young man,
but in the first chapter he details this
and what he says is the initiatives
would come in,
they would go into the temple.
They were on this fasting diet,
the temple of the people who are running
the temple.
It was sound and music.
It was all factory smoke color and they
were driven to this intense state.
And then they were given the kike ian.
And I think they,
you know,
a philosophy,
greek philosophers and others have
written about their experience it
appaloosas and they would emerge a
really an incredible,
maybe they got incredibly high,
maybe their boundaries or dissolve,
but they emerged with visionary,
uh,
coming back with vision of what to do,
what to do in their world.
and when they,
when they went home,
they boarded their ships and whatnot and
they went home.
And what did we see happening in that
period?
Greek theatre,
mathematics.
The academy road construction had
hydraulics,
uh,
the idea of a city organizational
structure,
the republic,
the idea of polity,
the idea of representation.
And the indian mystery school was just
one of many that were going on.
But ellis was a big deal,
right?
Looses was,
was destroyed partly in some periods and
then a roman emperor would,
would reboot it.
And,
and finally,
and I think it was the end of the fourth
century coming in from the north were
sort of the savage germanic tribes that
were basically taken out the whole
western roman empire.
And guess who was coming in from The
east black robed christians were
described as,
you know,
cranky fellows with a real sort of
obsessive perfectionist,
reductionist kind of negative.
They were described as really nasty
characters.
They formed this compact and together
they destroyed the temple.
That elusive.
So my woo woo theory is,
are we living in an inferior culture
that has no initiation,
replacing initiation,
powerful initiation with what you know,
all these other structures of,
of abuse and usury,
church structures,
corporate structures,
commercial structures.
Are we juvenile in?
Are we were we made juvenile?
But the fact that we didn't have a
powerful initiatory experience at
dissolved our boundaries that that
opened us to vision that that made us
human beings certainly think that's very
arguable.
It makeS a lot of sense.
I mean,
if you,
if you compare our resources to their
resources,
what we've accomplished and what we've
managed to fuck up in comparison to what
they managed to create with no
combustion engine with no hydraulics
with them,
of course they had slave cultures and
there were a lot of,
here's,
here's the other thing and you should
ask graham when he's next on that.
I'd love to,
to hear his response to this.
What did you have before the rise of
civilization?
Especial in The mediterranean,
you have the upper paleolithic,
you had village cultures.
Tribal cultures had quite a bit of
conflict but quite a bit of advancement,
but that was thousands and thousands of
years and then suddenly and for sure
they had some kInd of initiatory
experience for their youth,
especially for young man because as we
know,
you know in,
in,
excuse me,
in cultures of indigenous cultures that
still have an initiatory practice.
I think that's a very important part of
life.
Having some very clear graduation
pRocess and we have it throughout
schools.
We have it in grade school,
we have it in martial arts,
martial arts,
jujitsu and martial arts is where we're
bringing it back,
right?
Strong initiation because you know,
you probably see this because the people
that haven't had that,
they think cruz a loss and they know the
ones that have been very apparent,
you know,
pampered and helicopter parenting.
We all talk about thIs and they now
talking about the hoop jumping circus
train circus pig.
Kids that upper middle class parents
say,
jump through this hoop,
you know,
there are three or four years old and
they're jumping through these hoops
because why?
Because they're being prepped to get
into top level university.
And so they jumped through all these
hoops and there's a,
a professor at harvard written the book
about all this and he said he's watched
and his incoming classes of these kids
that are really good at achieving the
goals,
but they can't deal with ambiguity.
They can't deal With irony.
They can deal with creatIvity,
creativity.
They just living outside of the box.
Right?
So they're gonna jump to,
you know,
the investment bank or.
But they're not very functional,
so because they've not had a practice of
initiation and if not have a leveling
practice of boundary dissolving
practice.
They've been in this programmatic
evolution and it's dangerous.
I think that there should be some sort
of graduation process for various stages
in your life that sort of establish the
fact that you've learned from your
mistakes you've grown,
you've achieved in,
you've gotten through some.
You've overcome some adversity in your
higher.
I got it through scouting and Canada
because we had a total wilderness
situations where we have a bunch of us
almost died a couple times.
You know,
we are out in 45 bulleit below a
cracking cold january and we were in a
snowshoe can hike with a 60 pounds of
birch bark vog logs in our backpacks to
tough on ourselves.
It was just during no adults and we were
climbing over a mountain range and we
this,
the cold snap came in and I remember,
like I said,
we're this close to hypothermic.
Somebody dying in this group of like six
or eight of us or 14 years old,
whatever.
Because I went out to take a leak one
night and you can imagine you're wearing
jeans.
I mean this is the seventies,
you know,
we don't have proper clothes even.
And I took,
I sat down on this rock and I took a
leak and then I came back,
pass him the next day.
I mean my,
my piss was freezing on the way out and
I realize it's a dead stallion is
frozen,
solid wildhorse frozen solid,
you know,
dead.
And it was a rock.
I thought it was there.
I sat on it and we saw wolves and they
were really skinny,
you know,
in the distance.
And we realIze we are really close to
this is,
you know,
if somebody goes into hypothermic shock
in that environment,
you're done,
you're done.
And another time we were hiking on the
west coast trail and vancouver island.
We made a wrong turn and the whole
group,
we found ourselves in this,
you know,
this rock outcropping with a tide coming
in and storm surge and we had to cling
onto this thing all night and we
couldn't set up any kind of camp.
And it was like those were important
experiences,
rights of passage,
overcome adversity,
all those different things.
I think they should probably be
engineered into our cultures and our
communities.
I have a theory that goes along with
your theory.
I think your theory is probably
absolutely correct that we are a in some
ways less sophisticated or less advanced
society,
at least less what will we will most
certainly more materialistic,
right?
Most certainly more dependent upon the
internet and most certainly more
dependent upon computers.
Technology.
I have a theory about people,
and this is a very,
very shaky,
but here's my theory.
My theory is I think that everything is
natural and I think that all behavior
like wolves chasing out the beta and the
alpha taking over,
I think like,
you know,
birds of prey,
feasting on other birds and bears eating
salMon and all these complex ecosystems
that we see all over the world.
We just accept them as being natural
because they're a part of the world that
we didn't alter.
But ourselves,
we don't look as natural because we've
altered ourselves.
But I think we are entirely natural and
I think our society and our civilization
and our as fucked up as it is,
it's also natural and I think the
purpose that it serves is we live to
give birth to technology.
Marshall mcluhan said that human beings
are the sex organs and the machine will
hold.
And I think that what we're doing right
now by our obsession with the newest
greatest iphone,
elon musk just released a tesla that
goes zero to 60 in two seconds.
Oh my god.
It's amazing.
I have to have it.
And by continuing to be obsessed with
acquiring the latest and greatest
gadgets,
we push that innovation further and
further.
We fuel it with money and that
eventually it's going to give birth to
an artificial life form.
It's inEvitable.
I think it will give birth to the next
thing.
and I think we are like a caterpillar
that is becoming a butterfly and we have
no idea what we're doing.
We're just in the middle of doing it and
we're just like,
oh,
so much better.
Back in the old days when we chopped
wood.
And the reason why we think that is
because we know inevitably that we are,
we're not going to last.
We know that it's just a matter of x
amount of time before we're were
outdated.
Here's something not get to.
And I,
I believe you're right.
And here's a nugget to add for you.
That goes back to our deepest history.
This goes to my practice.
I do what I call indogenous visioning.
Sometimes in science is called thought
experiments or get duncan experiments.
But I can close my eyes mostly closed
eyes and I could go into worlds and
that's what I've been using to design
the spacecraft for nasa and origin of
life.
I work in the origin of life field and I
sort of visualize molecular storms and
flows and all that stuff because I have
this practice of just doing it and I'm
not taking anything just doing it.
And what happened about two years ago,
I was reading an article in science that
all.
It was an article.
It was about as like we found a femur
bone that was this small,
just a few send parsh portion of a
centimeter,
a female meters.
It's like quarter of an inch long or
half an inch long and that it's a femur
bone from our ancestors.
The ancestors of all monkeys,
primates,
lemurs,
all of them,
all of us students.
It's our common ancestor is $55,
million years old and then they had an
artist's conception of this thing that
would've been about two inches long and
they said,
well,
our ancestor lived in the forest canopy
and ate insects.
We are insectivores.
So I closed my eyes and I said,
okay,
I want to go back there.
I want to do an endogenous thought
experiment in science and see what comes
in from the ether.
What was our life like fan because
that's a big clue of who we are and
where we're going.
And I had this go into a kind of a dream
state serve meditation and breath work
and when I go into the dream state and I
see this branch at dawn and this a ball,
a ball of us all clumped together
because insectivores,
they protect each other by going close
warmth and all that stuff.
And I watched as this young proto
primate polar herself away from the
ball.
So story always comes to me to do this
kind of shit.
And she's creeping out on the limb at
dawn.
Why?
Because she sees a glistening globule of
something.
and why is this important?
Because that's sugar.
That's tree sap that comes out at night
and the diet of these insectivores are
uh,
leaves and flowers and stuff and
catching like a dragon fly,
which is a major kill for protein and
sucking down tree sap.
So it's like fries,
a burger and a shake diet.
Let's our diet and an incentive or diet.
And she's creeping out on the limb and
she's sucking down this glob.
You'll have sweet.
And one eye is looking back to see if
the somebody in the community notices
her because she'll get busted,
sound familiar the other eyes looking
forward on the limb and it sees this
very trippy scale pattern,
this trippy pattern of color.
She doesn't know what it is,
but what it is,
it's a tree snake.
And the tree snake was this sole giant
predator that survived the impact in
Mexico that killed the dinosaurs.
And then we rose after that.
Although he may have been earlier,
the tree snake is on the branch waiting
for her,
waiting for her and she.
So she's getting high on all this sugar
because we still get high on sugar.
Here we are drinking our coffees right
with our sugar.
And she's watching that and that trees,
that pattern of scales is evolve to
mesmerize her.
It's totally there to captivate her.
Why?
Because of the head is under the branch.
The head is about to come up.
If she doesn't snap out of and leap
back,
it will snap her ass down.
So this happened for tens of millions of
years.
This is coevolution.
What I believe from that.
That vision that I had was I said,
Oh my god,
this is why we're mesmerized by screens.
We're the only animal that is mesmerized
by this screening of a phone or you
know,
texture patterns,
movies,
moving images.
It's totally hardwired into us.
We're also terrified of snakes.
I mean,
we have a hardwired circuit in our brain
that if you see something that looks
like a snake,
you just jumped in voluntarily,
right?
That's in there too.
I thought that serpent on that limb,
that coa evolved our brain to vision.
That gave us color vision.
That gave us a three d high acuity,
a vision that we were talking about the
ancient peoples because we could see
incredible pattern.
Why?
BecauSe we evolved for for $30 million
years with those guys.
We had to solve that problem and the
evolution for 30 million years.
That's a lot of time.
It's a lot of programming,
so a lot of brain development because
the ones that got snapped down weren't
as good and so good old fashioned
darwinian evolution and I sometimes have
these conversations with what did I call
them,
andre,
so I know mother nature or the guy in
planetary plant bolus and I said to her
at one point,
I said,
you co,
you use this technique to evolve us to
evolve our vision so we could drive cars
and we could create media and all this
sort of stuff,
but it is now coiled around the planet,
technologies,
coil around the planet,
squeezing out the lifeblood of the
planet.
And I asked her,
does this bother you?
And she said,
no,
as long as you do the prerogative of my
prerogative of life's prerogative,
find me a new home.
I must make a copy.
So what life does this,
this,
this planet is a womb and it's a two k.
This is all just a crazy vision.
You crazy vision.
It's a womb and attune to home.
You're talking about space travel,
interplanetary space travel.
Yeah.
And what we've done as a species in it.
So I do a lot of this work for nasa of
designing strange space,
craft and art.
Exactly.
Is your educational background when it
comes to that stuff?
That stuff?
It was,
you know,
it was started out as good old usc
trojan,
you know,
graduating in electrical engineering and
the eighties.
But of course there was hardly any
software out at that time and I was
trying to do artificial life in 1987.
Can you imagine this on computers at usc
connected to the arpanet and it was too
soon.
So I restarted at 22 years later and I
made a project called the evil grid but
it was too fricking soon.
So I.
So you're kind of like the,
like the virtual reality.
People were also too soon.
They were.
And in 1993,
94 we all read snow crash and we read
near romancer and all those sorts of
things and we watched a,
you know,
a minority report and all that sort of
stuff.
But I actually started organizations to
kickstart virtual worlds on the internet
in 94 95.
And we have the first conference that I
wrote,
a book called avatars and help to
network together and get all these
people in the same room that we're
filming avatar,
cyberspace and three dimensional,
you know,
move through and you see objects,
fish and people and whatever and they
talk to you and et cetera,
et cetera.
And that's how I got connected with
terrence.
Terrence mckenna,
this terrance was fascinated by that.
And I was the go to guy.
So he came,
he came to the farm and sat at our
little table and I put them into these
virtual worlds,
but it was an amazingly powerful medium.
And then we spun that medium into all
this work for nasa for 12 years.
Using virtual worlds to model the
surface of mars,
for example,
and a rover and how it would work.
The rigid body dynamics of wheels
driving in bulldozers on the moon and
stuff like that.
And how do we build moon basis.
But we could use three d graphics,
you know the serpent.
Again,
our ability to create these worlds to
figure out how a vehicle would work on
another planet before we built.
We built banta any metal,
but it turns out,
coming back to the life propagation
thing,
if you go to the curiosity rover or the
two rovers on mars and you take you a
screw gun,
if you were there,
you know,
hopefully the vehicles are dead so
you're not caught on camera,
but you.
You drop the belly pan off of them
inside.
There's a dozen species of bacteria that
are just there for the ride.
They're inside the vehicles.
They can't be knocked out any clean room
and they're dry,
but there are life,
so there's life on mars is.
This happens to be in the bodies of our
space craft,
so there's no way avoid to avoid that
really no way.
There's no way to.
And there's certain species of bacteria
that will always be present and in fact
the jpl vacuum chamber and where they do
the final prep for some of these
missions.
They found that because they had created
the vacuum chamber and the clean rooms,
certain types of bacteria evolved to be
good at living in those.
So they already good at hitching a ride.
So of course they're inside the vehicle
on there on mars now outside of the
vehicle,
there's radiation and stuff that make it
impossible for them to really spread and
get into soils and stuff where there was
a
fascinating podcasts from radio lab
about the galapagos islands and about
how many invasive species have found the
way to the galapagos,
even from just the heels of people's
feet having seeds ground into their
pattern of their shoes and that
sometimes the seeds will get into these
grounds and then these invasive species
will start growing and
and jeff goldbloom and jurassic park,
he says,
life will find a way out or something
like that.
What they were trying to say is
there really is no clean.
Like this idea that you're not going to.
That a human being entering into some
particular environment is going to not
leave a footprint like it's not.
It's not happening.
You know that just by virtue of you
being there,
your bacteria or disease and we're
carrying around in a single celled
organisms,
bacteria to help us digest food and
stuff and that the body load of that
stuff out.
Numbers of the number of humans that
have ever lived,
we're just in some sense,
here's a joke for you.
So we come,
we rise,
we don't do the deed,
we don't create life off the pilot.
We just sort of go away.
Planet goes on,
runs down 5 billion years from now,
the sun is a is a red giant and it's
expanding and and we come,
the earth comes and it scrapes the outer
corona and it starts breaking apart
because that's probably what happened
and the crust comes apart.
Now of course we know that bacteria can
survive and all these crustal rocks on
maybe traveled to other source systems,
but my prediction,
the surface bacteria will say,
hey guys,
and the ones that are five kilometers
down or three miles down said,
hey guys,
listen around a billion years ago or 600
million years ago,
there was all this surface gigantic
plants and labels and dinosaurs and
stuff,
and there was one species that did
technology and they even took it out a
little bit and then they just blew it
and went away in the five kilometer
deep.
A Bacteria will say,
you're kidding.
That was going on.
No one told us,
you know,
that was happening on the surface.
We're,
we're used to just being bacteria on
planets that never go any further than
just the bacteria phase.
Well,
the primary idea about how life gets
moved around about the galaxy is
asteroidal impacts,
right?
Like the idea of panspermia like that,
much of what is life sustaining exists
on asteroids can be no acids and water.
It was,
it was a theory put forth,
I think in the seventies versus
initially sort of panned,
but month now we're discovering media
rights that have come from mars and
landed on ice caps on earth and go in
and realize,
no,
it's quite possible that things hitched
a ride and that mars would have cooled
sooner,
had a liquid ocean,
sort of more stable environment sooner
than earth would have.
So if life arose on mars and got some
impacts and blew off some crustal
material than we could be all martians.
Yeah.
That was the idea.
Right?
Well,
if that's the case mean isn't the rover,
uh,
just a very microscopic farmer that.
I mean,
it's not an asteroid,
but it is or something that came from
one body and is now occupying another
body and it has life on it.
So here's the other part of the story.
So perhaps,
and this is all woo woo,
but the bacteria in the mars rovers are
communicating with the maras bacteria
and saying,
listen,
you know,
we got life started on the earth.
We went up to a certain point where we
had trial of bites and we had deep
swimming things and they weren't really
evolving.
So we ordered an airstrike,
knocked him back and then we got things
on land that crawled,
but they just basically all he did was
eat and shit,
you know,
and they got big and whatever,
but they weren't going anywhere.
So we ordered another air strike,
kill off the dinosaurs,
and now we've got this new thing,
these primate things.
But we don't know if they're really
gonna go anywhere.
So we just might order one more air
strike.
And to start with arachnids,
let's,
let's do spiders.
The next time we gotta we gotta find one
that's going to do the job of getting
life spread.
You know,
so you think that that's where our
primary objective is to get off this
planet and the spread life throughout
the galaxy.
See,
I Think that life life is so powerful.
I mean life it,
it pushes into new environments from
early thermal springs on volcanic
islands and it figured out this is the
work I'm doing with my colleagues at uc
santa and nasa and elsewhere.
So to try to figure out a model of how
life started in those volcanic springs
in those early on,
we've come up with a model.
We were just actually submitted our
paper this week on that model,
but life pushes its way in life.
Had to learn in that model to survive in
the oceans and then it could spread.
And these little bubbles that are like
pre early life,
really fragile and don't have much of a
genome,
but they can persist long enough.
They can get to the next island.
You know,
life will find a way like jeff goldbloom
said,
but look at where life has gone and
missing.
Incredible as you say,
if we are spreading wings of the living
system,
we are a magnificent creation of that.
I mean we're,
we have the potential to spread life
everywhere.
And one of the other projects I'm
working on asteroid capture and
retrieval.
No,
if you're wanting to hear about that.
Yeah,
sure.
That's a mechanism to actually spread
life in the large scale.
You know,
even though it's indirect,
so you know,
nobody's going to fund a project to
spread life into the solar system or not
so visionary,
you know,
we're pretty pedestrian than we do
things for business reasons or whatever.
So there's this whole new space movement
that's come up,
you know,
space x and elon musk,
all these private entrepreneurs.
They're proposing how to get to mars and
stuff,
right?
nasa still in the game,
even though they can't launch people,
you know,
they're going to be using space x and a
few years.
So nasa has put out this call for,
well,
let's see,
what can we do with the human crew?
Well,
we can,
uh,
back in 2007 when they were going to
shut down the shuttle program and that
was on the books.
I worked with a team that worked with
headquarters to design what's possibly
the very first,
you know,
we can even bring up that video,
how to get people to an asteroid,
how to land a human crew using the
hardware that nasa wanted to build,
which is called constellation at the
time.
And it turns out it's a tricky thing,
you know,
who is it?
The movie,
the deep impact movie?
Uh,
you mentioned Bruce Willis.
He had one and the other one was morgan
freeman.
There was,
there was two,
there was a deep Impact and there was
harm again.
So what we said is,
you know,
that's all well and good,
but how do you really do it?
And it turns out that an asteroid even
that's a half a mile long,
has almost no gravity.
So you're not,
you're not actually going to as your
video that this is it.
Jamie's put it up here.
Jamie has put it up.
So there's almost no gravity.
So it's very difficult to land on,
so that's a really big object,
but then it's going what,
like 45,000
miles an hour or something.
Then It's rotating and it's,
you know,
so it's spinning and it's moving,
it's moving.
So here's our craft.
So it's like a football because I was
like a space potato.
So here we are coming down and we're
using our radar to trying to find a spot
that might not be so crumbling because
these often rubble piles and this is
going to be people are going to land.
This is a human mission.
So let's see the ring of airbags that
allows a soft contact,
the vehicles under thrust and it's watch
this.
Here comes a penetrator.
Amateurs coming out,
there's a pen of trauma.
It's like a boom penetrates on the edge
of edge of a rope in the penetrate
amateurs or to try to grapple the
surface.
You get tension.
If you've got tension on three or four
year lines like a rock climber,
you can.
You've got stability.
So it actually digs into the surface and
the surface.
I can anchor and here are the guys
coming out?
No sir.
They're floating.
They're coming out on handrails.
They got nice earth flag.
They're saluting.
This is our design from 2007,
which was done for a nasa headquarters
study for the administrator actually.
And uh,
anyway,
so that was done.
Uh,
I unimed barcode it so it was so
controversial at the time because the
whole bush agenda was to go back to the
moon and this was like another target
and I thought,
you know,
we need to go somewhere else if,
if human beings are going to ever go to
mars,
why don't we go to an asteroid?
No,
this is,
this was running around the community.
There's sort of an asteroid underground
and you know,
our center director was one of those
dudes and I was sitting in his office
and he's a two star general.
He said,
well you can,
you can go public with it because you
can't get fired.
You're know,
you're not a civil servant.
So I did.
So I lined up space.com
and seen it and you know,
popular science was on the cover of
popular science and we put that out and
we said,
here's our study,
here's how we grapple,
you know,
we'd talk with an asteroid and we get a
human crew,
et cetera,
et cetera.
And that kind of goes into a black hole
because,
you know,
nasa sort of got that kind of
institutional thing where they do a lot
of studies,
but we had done it in public and it
actually shaped it,
pushed the space industry as I forgot
about is 2007.
I said,
ah,
you know,
it's out there.
If you google humans on an asteroid,
it'll come up.
But turns out people were watching that.
I'm looking at that.
We just put it out there.
And a guy at,
I think it was jpl,
saw that baCk in the day and then he
designed the next mission.
You sort of an outsider,
the student at the time.
And he said,
wow,
this is really cool.
We should be doing it as an agency.
And he came up with,
couldn't we bring an asteroid closer to
the earth so the crew doesn't have to go
so far with what?
LiKe pull it closer to closer to it
sounds like a disaster waiting to
happen.
Small one,
small disaster or a small asteroid,
all asteroid,
but you can land on it.
You could,
you could go and sample it like a
geologist with your hammers,
how big you're talking about when you
say small,
literally pretty small between like 12
feet and 30 feet long and you could land
on something 30 feet long.
You couldn't land on that.
You can do what we just saw,
but the human crew could park next to it
called proximity ops.
Yet it could park way downstream.
Turnoff.
It's hydrazine jets and send astronauts
over to to sample it.
But how do you.
How do you move something like that
saved to the orbit of the moon,
which would be a safer place.
Put a moon around the moon.
So nasa had initiated that challenge
based on this work which bounced off
this.
This guy who said we need to bring an
asteroid in the moon.
And they now they have that as a
direction.
So a colleague and a me designed a whole
system to do that.
A system to put an asteroid in orbit
around the moon.
And here's the neat thing about it.
We figured out,
here's,
here's the problem.
You got to one of these asteroids,
it's a rubble pile.
Most.
Most of the ones that we're really
interested in for science,
right?
For sampling there 5 billion years old,
there are 4 billion years old.
They're collected rubble piles of pieces
of the early solar system.
So they're,
they're fragile.
And why do we know this?
The asteroid that came in over Russia,
the asteroid that came in over africa
last year,
broke up at a certain altitude so we
know what pressure took to break it up
so we know how much you got to push it
to break up the thing up because the
atmosphere did that and then it comes in
and pieces and rains down.
But isn't the concern that you can't
predict what happens when you break them
up and then you might deal with a bunch
of giant rocks hurling towards earth.
Yeah.
And that'S why it's really hard to do
asteroid deflection by some kind of
explosive and you're ready to to that.
They want to just be able to push it or
put some kind of a webbing on a graph.
Changes the.
If you put a rag right,
if you put a webbing on it,
they made us come apart.
You,
you can use something called gravity
tractoring,
which is developed by rusty schweickart
and ed loo at the un,
a separate separate work that we were
doing with them.
They have this idea of flying a
spacecraft alongside something and
gradually the gravity will change the
orbit.
What is the purpose of going to an
asteroid though,
or especially a human mission,
like what would be the benefit of having
people go as opposed to having some
remote vehicle?
Because it seems like as we get better
and better with remote technology,
you would be like a lot more efficient.
It would save lives and
well,
here's,
here's the we.
We were asking that same question.
So initially nasa said we want to do
science.
We want to take samples off of something
that says old as the earth are older
because then for origin of life
research,
which I'm involved in,
I get,
I could get a few pounds of this
material out from under this space crust
that's on it,
that has protected it for 5 billion
years or 4 billion years.
That is precious because it was what was
raininG down in the skies of The early
earth that was coming down to the little
ponds where life may have started.
It's like spinning a refrigerator all
this time so it's really precious for
science and figuring out how the solar
system came together.
So our design was to go out to the,
to the asteroid,
up to a thousand tons.
They're all rotating.
They spend one time,
I'm in something like that and half a
rotation a minute,
put a balloon around it.
Just extend this airbeam enough.
You've ever done any helium balloon like
high altitude flight?
There's no.
Oh,
they're incredible.
I mean,
julian not lives out in santa barbara is
perHaps the greatest designer of these
kinds of balloons and he's honored our
team for this proposal and he said,
look,
what you do is you,
you extend these air beams,
you know,
like the,
the balloons you have at circus as the
guy just like blows up along balloon and
makes a dog out of it for your kid or
air beams.
They're the rigid parts.
So you literally go out to the asteroid
using xenon gas.
You fill these arab beams and they pull
your fabric out,
you know,
and there's a,
there's a folder of a bunch of images of
the assistant called shepherd I got and
it will capture the asteroid here.
It's kind of come out.
There we go.
You can see that it's hard to.
So,
so this is a balloon.
This is literally a balloon captures the
asteroid.
So the astra is now inside it and it's
tumbling is rotating and there's the air
beams.
Those blue things is how the capture
works.
And here's the air flow.
We may leave it on that one and we'll we
can explain what we're doing.
It turns out that if you inject gas into
this balloon,
you will gradually slow the tumbling the
asteroid to stop it.
Now it's stopped.
They've solved.
One of the big problems of capturing
asteroids is to get rid of the spin and
tumbling because if you can't,
there's all these powerful forces.
If you try to put a net around that
would just come apart or terrorists.
Spacecraft pieces.
Okay,
so you put a bubble on it.
You capture an asteroid.
Now what?
Now?
What is.
You'll notice in our little drawing
there,
we start shooting waves,
the xenon gas at the Back end of it,
which puts a force on it,
not not a forced to break it up and
enough force to shove It,
and then we use the same xenon gas and
our motor to keep up with it as it moves
and we can use like sale power.
This is like a sailing ship.
We can use sale power moving gas to
change its orbit and to retrieve it and
bring it to move it into some other.
Part of the solar system is this
potential technology to avoid gigantic
asteroidal impacts on earth or is it
just too small?
This is too small,
so this is only for examining old rocks
for an examining on rocks blood.
It turns out that when we were
investigating this further,
we thought,
wait a minute,
what if we had a piece of a comment?
You know,
comments are coming in the pleiades
meteor shower and the land.
It's that come in and they give you this
nice light show in the summer.
That's all valid voluble volatiles.
That's water,
that's methane.
All this wonderful stuff.
What if you had a chunk of a comment
that had all this,
these gases coming off,
you know the rosetta mission the
europeans are doing right now,
they're orbiting one of these gigantic
comments that has these geysers coming
out that's thrust doesn't like a rocket
thrust.
What if you could capture a small
comment from further out,
put your balloon around it,
capture,
stop at rotating,
capture all the stuff coming off and use
it for your engine.
You could then create a moving chunk of
the early solar system who came outside
of,
what if we did this and what if we did
that and you know,
being able to do it would be cool and
everything like that.
Will it be the benefit of getting some 5
billion year old rock at a space?
Oh,
here's.
And again,
why would you want to do it with people?
Why wouldn't you want to do it remotely
with machines?
Well,
here's where the people come in.
So if you can move a basically a wet
space rock,
capture all the gases coming out of it.
Concentrate the gases in your tanks.
A human crew can dock with it saying,
you move it to mars,
to mars orbit,
move it to the Lunar orbit.
Now you've got a gas station in orbit.
You've got a gas station somewhere in
the solar system full of exactly the
material.
You need to get a human crew.
They dock with it.
When they get there,
they refill their tanks.
They now have their return fuel to go
back to earth and then they fuel their
lander and they go down with.
They don't have to carry that stuff.
You have gas stations,
you have a sustainable space flight
system.
That sounds beautiful,
but if you
don't send people out there,
you don't need that.
So you're saying we would do this
because when the people were out there
that way we didn't have power,
but if you don't need people out there,
you don't need this power.
And what would be the benefit of having
these people out there other than the
fact that
do it?
I think because we're exploring species
that are eventually going to want to do
it.
Right,
but what are we exploring remotely with
the rover?
Aren't we exploring remotely with
voyager?
We're still exploring.
We're exploring.
the proposition of going to mars is so
unbelievably unattractive to me.
Like when I hear that 100,000
people signed up for mars and I'm like,
well there's 100,000
people that would just drink draino.
Those are 100,000
people that would dive into a volcano.
if you can put a camera on them,
what the fuck are they doing?
Why do they want to go to mars?
It's the shittiest neighborhood ever on
earth.
Imagine going to some unbelievably
unhappy,
an unpopulated inhospitable environment
on earth.
Would you go there?
Would you go to someplace where you're
like sleeping on the edge of a volcano,
breathing cosmic gases through a fucking
giant mask because you can't breathe the
air.
You have to have this some air tanks and
you have all this gear.
Just keep you alive.
You'd be like,
fuck no.
why would I do that when I could live in
Hawaii?
Why would I do that when I can be in san
diEgo?
You wouldn't.
Why would you go to fucking mars?
Except that there are some people.
There are some crazy.
People really want to see this new shit.
The people that pay the $20,000,000
to build the space station,
there's gonna to be hitting 50 million
at some point to go around the moon.
I mean if you talk to the people who
went to the cost per person,
50 million.
I heard it thrown around,
but only rich assholes are Going to Be
able to afford going around the moon
then.
Well,
it's like in the days of great
exploration.
I mean rich assholes funded darwin's.
Is it going to be like cell phones where
it starts off with rich assholes like
Michael Douglas in wall street with the
big brick.
Huge on that.
Eventually on the miracle mile show.
Yeah.
You go to third world countries and
everybody has a cell phone.
It's going to be like that.
Is that true though?
Because it's very disturbing to me that
people aren't more up in arms about the
loss of the space shuttle and.
But the loss,
lack of funding.
That was crazy.
it's so crazy,
but it's so confusing because every
movie from when I was a kid or even
television shows.
You remember space 1999,
1999.
We were living in space.
Nineteen 99.
What happened?
What was it?
Two thousand 14 and we don't have an
have an active space program.
We don't.
And because there's fundamental problems
with the economics,
but even space x,
so space x,
what they dId.
What elon did down in el segundo here,
he said,
okay,
well we're going to do is make a low
cost launcher,
gonna up tHe same engines on the second
stage as we have in the first eight,
not to fricking types of engines with
lockheed martin and boeing launchers
like they're so complicated.
Why?
because they're government contractors.
They're going to have to bill a lot more
money.
They're going to overbuild the
government for being.
That's what it was.
Oh,
it's incredible.
So it stifled innovation.
The fact that we're getting money from
the government.
Yeah,
because it's government contractors.
So what the government did in the 19
twenties when aviation was just starting
out,
they gave these contracts with these
little fabric error companies to run
postal mail.
They invented air mail.
So they said,
well,
we'll create a new kind of male called
air mail for the post office.
It doesn't go by horse and buggy or
train or whatever,
and these little companies got enough
finance from that that they started
running air mail around and they became
continental airlines and united airlines
and all of them came out of that thing
by moving it to private enterprise.
So it nasa did and it's great wisdom.
Sometimes it has great wisdom and
created a program in the two thousands
and the arts to do this.
So you've got space x now and you've got
orbital sciences at least,
but what?
They're not inventing much in the way of
new tech.
They're inventing a reliable low cost
launch or just like the soviets head in
the sixties and still have proton,
you know,
low cost made an assembly line.
You look at the air and erica mush
factory in Russia that makes the soviet
boosters and,
and how they make this,
the soyuz craft.
It's like henry ford's assembly line,
low cost,
high reliability,
you know.
So we had lost that culture and now it's
coming back with space x.
But the economics are still really
rotten.
So it's coming back because of private
funding and the private sector,
private sector because of competition,
because of competition and innovation
coming from silicon valley and other
brains than people who work for large
aerospace.
So it's kind of another example of
bureaucracy and government sort of
getting in thE way
progress.
Well,
in this case they got out of the way of
progress and they said,
well,
we're losing the shuttle anyway.
We'll create this small program
relatively small where we'll fund the
winners of the competition.
So somebody.
It was kind of like the x prize,
right?
This idea of challenges and prizes in
the darpa prize and that's created a
huge amount of innovation that's really
worked.
That's been a government thing that
worked because they said,
well,
a cure to new astronaut glove or self
driving robot that can track the.
So the highway.
But so much military technology came out
of the apollo missions means so,
so much of from the space race between
us versus the soviets.
So much innovation came out of it and so
much of it was was very valuable as far
as military.
why don't I just don't understand why
that didn't continue.
It seems like that would be a no
brainer,
like there will be a very important part
of what the military would want and who
gets more money than the military.
The military against an ungodly sums
cash.
They're really,
really inefficient at delivering
programs.
they have a high cancel rate and when
they cancel a program,
it's $100,000,000,000
of loss,
but they seem like they've just stopped
and what the military has done with the
dod has done the same thing.
Nasa is doing the public sector chip
manufacturers,
everything from laptops to whatever are
so much more advanced than what the
pentagon or nasa can make that they just
use off the shelf.
It's called cots commercial off the
shelf and so they're not innovating.
They're just using laptops,
you know,
and they're using standard stuff they're
getting from industry because the
industry is so far ahead.
Back in the fifties they were ahead in
the sixties.
Now industries are so freaking far ahead
like tesla's batteries.
I mean,
who can.
Nobody's going to create something is
superior.
Is that right?
Or not?
Anytime in the near future.
Yeah,
there everyone's goes by those
standards.
Do you think that there is a way that we
can kind of get back on track because of
the private sector being involved in
space travel and we can really start
saying man,
space travel to like we really can make
up for that hiccup where we thought we
would be with the shuttle down to the
and then with only cost 50 million
original movie alien.
What year was that Based in [inaudible]?
80 two.
No,
79.
Yeah,
it was 79.
80 nine based on.
It was based on not that far in the
future based on 2020 or something goofy
like that.
But it wasn't a fee.
And you know,
blade runner,
2019.
Los angeles raining and sidebars and
stuff.
yeah.
Yeah.
No,
we're.
Well isn't that still possible?
And then what we were talking about
before about the creation of artificial
life and the exponential growth of
technology,
if you factor in those little things,
it might not 2019,
but it might be 2000,
29.
I mean,
they very well may have artificial life
that's indistinguishable from you are on
in another two or three decades.
So that's very possible,
right?
No,
no,
it's not.
It's really not.
I've spent at least 10 years trying to
figure out why technology and biology
are counter pose systems.
Why one doesn't do the other very well.
So for example,
um,
I do a talk now and then at the
singularity university,
I haven't been there for a couple of
years,
but my talk is why the idea of a
singularity is really not possible and I
can show up possible not possible with
technology we have now.
Yeah.
But what does that mean?
I mean,
when you say not possible,
if things continue to go along the same
exponential rate of progress,
right?
If it continues to go,
it's sort of,
I mean has to reach some sort of an end
point,
right?
I mean it has to continue to innovate,
continue to grow as long as we have the
physical materials.
Parents thought that parents read a lot
of science articles and popular science
journals and I remember sitting with him
in his house in Hawaii,
you know,
up half the night trying to to explain
to parents why this idea was not
feasible.
Why is that?
Well terrence,
yoU know,
you see we just done a whole virtual
world thing.
I said,
terrence,
the virtual world that we just were in,
it's just,
it's a.
It's a a cardboard cutout.
There's nothing in it.
It's just polygons rendered in a scene
by a serial processor that's getting
bits from a server and it's all
extremely fragile.
It looks realistic to us,
but it's a complete cardboard cutout and
on the other hand,
here's if you look down from terrence's
house down,
a captain cook and you looked at the
pacific ocean,
I said,
you take a glass full of water from that
ocean of what heck is going on in that
class full of water and computational
terms is just mind blowing.
It's a computational superpower and in
fact that glass of water could not be
simulated accurately by all the
computers we've ever built all running
at once.
Not today,
but couldn't it be a thousand years now.
It's not possible to continue to stay
alive and innovation continues to push
the boundaries of whAt's possible as far
as computing mean.
you can only imagine what's capable.
We're capable of 100 years from now,
but the thing is we're building what
we're building.
say for instance,
the steam engine,
right?
The steam engine was large bore diameter
pistons,
right?
Starting to 18 twenties and whatnot.
They got smaller and smaller and better
and better.
So we got motors,
we've got low commoditY and we got
gasoline.
Right?
But the the piston and camshaft model is
still what drives your tesla?
Well,
maybe not because it doesn't that
pistons,
and I know that's an electric motor,
so it for thing,
right?
Yeah.
It's a beautiful thing.
It got miniaturize,
it got better and better,
but it was stuck in a rigid framework of
what Its limitations work.
Computers are also stuck in that
framework.
So for example,
john von neumann,
when he designed the von neumann machine
and at in princeton in 1948,
49,
and they built this first really
reliable,
no patch cord,
lots of registers and memory and vacuum
tubes and drums and shit.
They got all working by 1952 and then
they gave the plans away.
Well,
von neumann,
the creator of this wrote,
this is a contingency architecture.
This is just to get something to
actually work and not break down in 20
minutes and do something,
but it is no way a strong architecture,
especially when it comes to dealing with
natural systems.
But.
But how haven't they overcome a lot of
that,
at least in theory with quantum
computing.
That's,
that's all I'm.
I'm not sold on that at all.
I think that those are extremely
specialized,
very,
very small processes that we don't
really even understand what's going on.
But doesn't It open up the potential.
And if you go back to the invention of
the steam engine,
you compare it with a tesla and you look
at the x amount of hundreds of years,
put a plus of innovation that led to
this incredible leap in technology.
When you just extrapolate and say like
what we have today,
you can't possibly say that like flash
drives and three gigabyte processes as
the end all be all.
If we can't do it it with that,
we're never going to be.
Isn't it true that perhaps in the year
2050 there will be a computer with a
serial processor?
Maybe lots of like might have a thousand
cpas or more,
but it's still doing the same thing.
Why?
Because
tied to legacy,
it doesn't have to be.
It has to be,
well why does it have to be doing the
same thing that it's doing now?
If quantum computing really does turn
out to pan out,
he has a has to run microsoft word.
Why does it have to run microsoft word?
Because as the forces that are driving
the evolution,
it's sort of.
But I mean like microsoft word today has
almost no relation to microsoft word of
windows 95.
I mean,
it's barely connectable.
It's actually slower.
Well,
it does a lot more though,
right?
It does more.
I mean,
where
bloatware in.
I've got a 19,
91st three,
86 computer running windows.
three point one.
Mcguire had one of those.
He kept that shit deep into the
nineties,
man that I had it in like 97,
98.
He kept at.
oh my god.
Windows three point one.
I booted this up the other day.
It comes up.
Bam.
It's so fast.
I'm running
word,
I'm running.
I'm doing email in aol like so quick and
then I go.
Then I go to my modern machines is
10,000
times
powerful.
It's like,
oh my god.
Another processor glitch has happened in
the wheel.
Have of laconic processes happening in
windows or painting slowly because this
bloke layer
upon layer upon layer of crabs,
you really have that much of a heart.
What?
What do you run?
Windows or unix or what are you run
through?
Ridiculous.
I mean,
I'm,
I'm running vms,
like I run machines run like windows on
top of a mack plan for him and I have
tweaked and I go into all these forums
and it's like,
oh,
you know,
windows seven not on a vm has all these
incredible problems with a search
indexer with.
You got to stop this because it'll
totally choked the operating system.
You got to stop that.
You got to do this,
so you have to.
It's like an automobile in 1910.
We get to be a mechanic to keep it
working efficiently.
The stuff is so bad,
but you're running some really
complicated stuff though.
If you're running virtual machines,
well I'm running.
You're essentially running a heart.
You,
you're running an operating system,
then you're running another operating
system on your operating system that's
operating simultaneously and that's a
lot of rich source,
but it's using the same hardware.
But what it exposes is the incredibly
how incredibly poor we are as a species.
That writing software that's good and it
stays stable.
So this is just super duper complex.
I mean,
I don't have a problem with things
crashing.
I mean,
if you compare it to like with windows
95,
used to be like windows 95,
you see the blue screen of death all the
time.
My favorite story is if we're halfway
between earth and the stars unite,
we're halfway to alpha centauri and the
3000 crew are and their deep sleep and
suddenly they're all woken up.
They're getting out of their vessels and
they go and they,
they look at the screens on the bridge
and they're all blue and it says press
control,
alt delete.
You will lose all data.
And we realized we were running dos
underneath all of this technology layer
upon layer,
you know,
they'll be doomed.
You know,
I'm really confused about your,
your idea because you,
you,
you seem to think the things we're
better off when they were lIke really
clunky and they couldn't run as much
software and the software wasn't as
complex.
For example,
windows xp,
like when they discontinued support of
xp.
Oh my god.
You found out there were millions and
millions and accompanies that were just
totally depend on it.
Saying this is so robust.
This is so such good software and since
xp,
that course they went to vista,
which was a disaster and the windows
seven was sort of recovery and then
windows eight was sort of a disaster and
now of course the evolution of mac ios
is maybe a little different.
It's fantastic.
The macro s is so much better than it
ever was.
Back in the day.
The days,
the pre intel days,
the before rhapsody and before mark and
unix.
Yeah,
it was.
It was just a kluge.
The macro s didn't have preemptive
multitasking,
no memory protection,
all that stuff.
I stayed away from max until the unix
got onto the 10.
One 10 came along with him a lot.
But if you look at how can we be so bad
and we're
spending the maximum amount of cash and
only one or two companies and one or two
ever efforts make something that's good.
We're not really good at software
actually.
You're talking crazy.
This is your.
You're like extreme pessimistic attitude
towards innovation.
Yes.
Growing up in the software business and
well,
you know,
seeing how things actually get done and
then you meet a futurist or popularizer
who comes up with this wild thing and
you say,
no one's working on the project for one.
No,
there's no investment going into say
putting consciousness and computers and
does that.
I always ask the question,
putting consciousness into computers.
We're talking about a completely
different thing now.
Talking about software develoPment first
and you cited will soft software
writing,
creating.
You cited one excellent operating
system.
Mac ios,
which exists right now.
I mean we are.
We are.
We need to say no one is writing it,
but it's there.
I'm on it right now.
It's fantastic,
but it's doing stuff that has been done
for 35 years in different operating
systems,
different ways,
but that's one of the big things that
happened when the transfer to osx came,
is that there was this big.
You had to get rid of all the old
software because all the legacy software
was no longer useful.
He couldn't use it because it was
running on a completely different
platform.
So that right there sort of contradicts
your idea,
doesn't it?
The thing is if you talk to somebody say
in 1990,
right?
Uh,
well,
uh,
you know,
where will software evolution be in
2015?
They Probably would just like your
disappoint with the space program,
right?
It's disappointing in the software
business is the software business is
grinding away.
This is what jaron lanier talks about.
He,
he wrote this thing caLled half a
manifesto about 10 years ago,
which is like we are so burdened by
legacy and for poor practices that we
just add.
We're building like a tower of babel.
Sometimes works well sometimes doesn't,
but we add layer upon layer upon layer
without thinking.
So we're not building great pyramids at
giza were building some kind of tower of
babel of technology that's really
patchwork together.
maybe you just know more about it than I
do because when I look at it objective
as someone who's not involved in the
industry,
all I'm seeing is continual innovation.
All I'm seeing is things getting better,
crisper move better,
boot up faster when he went last.
I agree
witH you on that.
When we went to say the ipad and mobile
devices,
they could throw away all that legacy to
say throw it no more compact discs,
throw it in the trash,
no more file systems and layer and that
will build a brand new operating system
running on flash memory and get rid of
the crap and we'll even have new ways to
do applications.
So when that happened,
it was like a hUge breath of fresh air.
I was like,
oh,
there isn't 500,000
features to my mail program.
It just does mail.
And we dumbed it down.
We made it super simple to get away from
our natural tendency to.
So the space station are going example,
like space stations.
So complicated,
right?
It has its 15 nations are 13 nations.
There's a hundred and 50 kinds of
connectors on it,
right?
It is designed to be remotely run
without any crew.
That was one of the initial design
criteria that we should be able to
completely remotely run in the space
station.
So it has laptops and ancient computers
and huge millions of lines of code to
run the space station.
So it's a huge cost,
it's a huge burden to keep that thing
running.
Go back to skylab,
you know,
you're old enough to probably remember
skylab was a tin can,
does an upper stage of the saturn five,
the beautiful saturn five most reliable
booster in history thrown away.
So one of the last ones,
they launched the upper stage as a tin
cans,
space station,
solar panels up super simple,
huge interior space.
Guys could run around it,
remember how they could run and you
know,
a beautiful model of a space station
that didn't require more than a 30
percent of crew time to sort of keep
maintenance going on the international
space station.
The crew or are overwhelmed with
maintenance chores.
It's so complicated.
So we built something and I asked a
friend at nasa,
I said,
what if you put boosters on the space
station and senate,
tried to send it to mars to carry a
crew,
said they'd be dead in a month because
we're constantly having to send up parts
and repair shit that's breaking is not a
sustainable platform currently without a
huge amount of maintenance and resupply
and constant management.
Right.
But I'm like an operating system.
Your,
your pessimism though,
because it seems to me that if you
really want to like nitpick and focus on
this blip in time is one blip in time
where they may be peaks and valleys in
innovation.
Ultimately it seems to be sort of
inexorably moving towards progress or
moving towards complexity.
Right?
When did you agree with that?
But the progress say toward having
something as good as biology.
How biology operates.
Operating and technology is a big
challenge.
Technology is this,
I mean the biology of the cell and how a
cell metabolizes products,
how it manages its energy,
it has its feedback.
You know,
a cell is like a huge cityscape working.
It works.
90 nine point nine,
nine,
nine percent of the time,
otherwise you'd be just mush flowing on
the ground,
but,
but isn't,
are we talking about biological
processes like processing proteins and
things along those lines and yeah,
exactly.
That won't necessarily be necessary if
you have something artificial silicon
based,
something that's running on electricity
and technology and lithium ion batteries
here,
problem.
it's based on two week of a model of
physics.
So here's,
here's the,
here's the metaphor that I use and this
is why computer people hate this idea
life.
What idea?
The idea that life based on
probabilistic events.
So here's,
here's how you digest sugar.
Say you take a nice big bolus of sugar
into your body.
Um,
you know,
the,
the sugar molecule will come into
yourself at some point somewhere.
It will hit this molecular storm of shit
going on.
Mostly water molecule.
It will ricochet around the cell hitting
just about every other molecule that it
can in the cell for a second,
second,
half to seconds until it hits.
It hits exactly the right place on a
molecule that has a pocket of the sugar
fits in perfectly.
And that thing will cause it to band and
go click,
click and make it into a polysaccharide,
which is an important valuable thing,
but it's all done through this.
What is going on as a probabilistic
stochastic process.
It's completely nuts,
but that's how nature is.
And so when you compare that process to
the way a computer would work,
so a computer designer would say,
well that's dumb.
That's a whole lot of wasted steps and
computation.
I'll just build a assembly line.
we'll take that sugar in and along the
similar line and we'll hit my thing out.
Digested immediately.
Well,
it turns out if you do things like that,
they're so rigid that they break almost
immediately and in real world and
nature.
But this isn't this if you're imitating
biological synthesis or biological life.
And why would you do that?
If you're creating something artificial,
all you need to do to create an
artificial person as have it behave.
Think compute,
react like a person.
It doesn't need to process proteins.
I mean these are all.
that's legacy.
Isn't that like being tied to legacy?
What do you throw away from what a
person is?
How do you define,
say consciousness or I don't think you
would call it a person at all.
Why would you call it a person?
I mean,
we're not throwing it away.
What I'm talking about is creating
something completely unique and wouldn't
have to be a duplicate of a person I
would have to do is look like one.
Right?
But then we're building cardboard
simulacra again,
that really aren't the real thing.
If you sent that person or the New York
subway system,
that robot robotic entity,
it will be soon overwhelmed with
stimulus and programs
unless she conditions before it,
unless you,
unless you built human being one point.
Oh,
and you found the flaws and then built
two point zero and found the flaws and
keep going the same way we've described
already with operating systems from
1995.
A mere blip in time to 2014 and the
massive amount of progress has been made
since then.
If you did that with computer generated
or,
uh,
electronically generated,
whatever you want to call artificial
life forms that we've created.
I mean,
it just stands to reason given enough
time.
No asteroids,
supervolcanoes,
no ebola,
right?
Humans are going to get there.
I think it's a harder problem than we
can suppose.
Like nancy,
it's really hard because we don't
understand how basic really functions
when we don't understand,
for example,
well,
here's another example,
the neuron,
you know,
with 10,000
connections and the body and the sodium
channel and there's all these things
that come out and you know,
the neurotransmitters are generated into
this pole and they carry the signal and
everything.
The neuron Is so frickin big.
I do something called molecular dynamics
simulation.
Our team has done that where you just
simulating a molecules wiggling
movement,
right?
and they're doing this now for protein
folding where they get 10,000
atoms all arranged in the right place in
the simulation and the computer so that
it behaves like a real protein would do,
which is fold and do all this weird
geometry.
So they have to simulate the protein
being slammed by water all the time.
It's this crazy process.
It might take those guys a month of
computation on a computer.
A 10,000
processors to simulate a couple of
nanoseconds of that action because
otherwise the simulated protein just
doesn't behave like it really does in
nature.
It's that hard.
Right?
So I think we're in agreement that
replicating absolute biological
processes would be insanely difficult.
Saying may take forever,
but my question is why is that necessary
to create something new that can think
for itself?
Because here's the problem.
If you created something very small,
for example,
not a human walking around the New York
subway system,
it's something we're.
What world does it live in?
You know,
he lives in a.
If it's a robot,
say it's a little insectoid robot.
What world does it have to live in?
Just living in this world?
What do you mean?
Well,
if it lives,
say on a factory floor,
a good example,
factory floor robots are really getting
good.
Like they can carry shit around,
they can track spots on the floor and
they can do all kinds of shit,
but if they ever go out in the parking,
if you put them out in the parking lot,
you know where they're out of.
They're very controlled theory in a
virtual world when they're in a factor
in there,
they see tape and marks and fire codes
and all kinds of things that create the
mental model inside the robot,
but if it goes into nature and the chaos
of the natural world and vehicles moving
around and stuff like that,
you know,
the darpa grand challenge,
which has all these great teams making
robots are self driving.
They found out reAl fast that we're,
you know,
this is hard,
super hard
currently hard but,
but,
but isn't the new tesla d you could
phone home with this thing and it will
literally drive to you.
And I heard a rumor by the way,
and this is maybe a,
a google car in a self driving google
car that on the eight 80 there was a,
a google self driving car scene that had
an irish setter sitting.
You're done and we'll hear a dog on her,
right?
It was sitting in the passenger seat.
There was no one else in it.
And the cops were told about this.
People are calling this,
this,
this car.
There's this irish setter is driving
this car and the cops come up and
there's an irish setter sitting in the
seat and there's no one else and they
follow it and it goes to a
veterinarian's office and the door opens
and the dog laid it,
goes into the veterinarian office and
this is the rumor that I heard was
somebody just didn't have time.
They put the car,
the dog in the car and they send it to
the vet's office,
you Know,
which is totally in violation of any
kind of.
Doesn't that story Itself disprove this
notion that it's too difficult to do
something like this when you're dealing
with the real world and all the
variables and all the moving parts and
you just talked about a driving the
fucking car.
I meAn that's kind of It right now.
And this is only 2014,
but you know,
in footprint tall in Germany,
in the 19th century they were doing a
remote control trains.
They were doing trains that would go
onto the track track to an electrical
signal.
Stop,
pick people up.
I mean this stuff is actually pretty
easy.
okay.
And but that's not,
we're talking about a road though.
It's not a track,
but there the difference between that
and a living system is those are fixed
function algorithms that are doing edge
tracing on the edge of a highway saying
where's the right line and where's the
yellow line?
And they're getting a gps signal and if
you look at the code,
it's not very big.
You know,
if it was a very big and complicated,
it probably wouldn't work.
So these google engineers have made
something pretty elegant that has fuzzy
logic and everything.
They've got it to work.
This has been tried since the 19
thirties with the radio control cars
that had radios on the front and back
control of distance and they've got it
to work.
But is this anything close to what life
can do?
The adaptability,
but like,
no,
but,
but neither was the initial combustion
engine even close to what the saturn
five rocket was like neither was the
original model t in comparison to a
tesla.
And I mean doesn't that just stands to
reason that constant innovation?
I agree with you except that when I see
really saifai things come in that are
just because I'm an engineer,
fundamentally when I see stuff that's
like,
oh my God,
I can't even imagine how to get there
because they're not even defining were
what their term,
right?
They're not defining their terms and no
one's working on the project.
So I'll give you one example of how hard
this stuff is.
So terrence and I would have these
conversations about what he called
novelty.
You remember he used to say can
crescents into novelty.
So you know,
terence left us in the year 2000.
I saw the millennium.
If you define it as the year 2000,
but people say it really started in
2001.
But I'm.
Terrence was talking about all this
stuff and I would say that's pretty
obvious to myself.
If things get novel,
how do they get novel?
And for years and years I worked on this
project called the evolution grid.
What we did was try to say let's
simulate actual chemistry inside the
computer and see if we can see novelty
accreting and how does it do it.
And in 2011,
after running a year of simulations,
partly at uc san diego and up in my
barn,
we believe that the whole surf all wired
together,
we found this staircasing formula that
was a way that nature form structures in
this case bonds form between these
virtual molecules and doesn't break
them.
They don't just all go back to mush.
And it was this staircasing thing.
I said,
oh my god,
you know,
this took eight months of computation of
find this method by which perhaps the
universe accretes novelty and holds onto
it.
So I sort of did a virtual call,
the parents and I said,
we found the formula,
I call it the cosmic wiggle,
and he calls this stuff like the cosmic
giggle.
And if you remember from some talks,
I said,
we found the cosmic wiggle.
But in the process of doing that,
what I learned was holy shit,
the basis for life,
which is this massive,
huge engine of stochastic probabilistic
storm that's going on that literally
ratchets and rocks.
Everything from jujitsu matches to the
jet.
Air.
Airplane is a powerful system.
It's not at the basis of computing
computing is this delicate little thing
will take a number and we'll do a thing
with it and we'll spread it out here,
but nature's this massive machine.
So perhaps the future,
and this is where we would come together
is a merger between computing and
natural systems.
So this is a project that I'm calling
the genesis engine project and it's
having a computer control,
trillions of chemical experiments all
going at once and looking at them and
selecting them and saying these are more
powerful experiments and it can just
search through molecular space.
I just talked to a guy from google about
this and he was like,
oh,
molecular search.
We're interested in that.
We're not just limited our searches to
you know,
the best bread recipes.
No,
we would like to search and molecule
space and I talked to our neighbor and
we have a place in New Jersey and he's
like a head researcher at glaxo and he
said this is incredibly valuable if you
can,
if you can actually use molecules to do
the walking.
run a trillion experiments at once and
pick the best ones.
And then run the trillion more
experiments and walked through chemical
space.
We can figure out how to make a
pharmaceutical in the least amount of
steps you can simulate you create new
materials and we'll have a hybrid
digital and natural analog computer for
the first time in this 21st century.
But now you're really confusing me
because now you've,
you seem to think
that innovation is going to reach some
new plateau if we do that.
If we're able to hybridize,
I think we're going to make the leaps
that you are talking about.
Joe,
if we can do this hybrid,
if we can harness pessimism line,
what do you,
uh,
I'm an engineer so I know what it takes
to build these things.
And so I don't want to really oversell
that by a certain date.
We're going to have a singularity of
some sort that certain dates.
Stuff is always a goof it.
Ray kurzweil wants to do it now with 20,
45 and the 20 slash 25 slash 45.
They're being silly by doing that.
And I think it's,
it's,
it,
it does the whole idea of an exponential
increase in technology.
It does that whole idea disservice by
like pretending than anybody.
First of all,
nobody's ever fucking predicted
anything.
Right?
Right.
Nobody's ever nailed it.
I mean,
there's been some fascinating hg wells
predictions that sorta came true,
but no one said like on November 19th,
1972,
there's going to be a telephone that
does this.
And instead what happened like that?
December 21st 2012 drove me fucking
crazy.
It drove me fucking crazy because first
of all it was intoxicating and then it
was maddening and then it became
ridiculous.
And as the day rolled around it,
I did an end of the world show you
december 20,
first 2012.
But doug stan hope and joey diaz and my
friends,
honey,
this band.
And we did the show.
We did it live at the wiltern.
It's not,
it doesn't exist anywhere.
It was just a,
just a live show comedy show.
Yeah.
We just thought the asteroid was going
to hit her.
The mayans were to come back or the
aliens are going to land or whatever the
fuck was going to happen.
Nothing happened.
Of course,
down underneath grand central station in
New York city with a friend of mine
who's a.
He's a kind of a psychedelic comic and
he does.
What's his name?
What's his name again?
What kind of a friend is this brain is
fried.
He's a wonderful guy,
but we just.
We laughed and then no one's gonna find
them.
7 billion people in the building.
People.
we laughed our way through the day like
you guys are doing it,
the wheelchair and tell jokes and we
said we gotta get less serious.
This idea of picking a day so goofy.
Like I had daniel pinchbeck on the
podcast once and he was saying that it's
definitely going to change the world to
san diego.
Do you know that?
December 20,
first 2012.
Something's definitely not easy.
It's absolutely,
definitely gonna change where I was
like,
what are you talking about now?
What are you fucking.
How can you say that?
You can't say that.
You can never say that.
You can never say that date,
but here's the show.
Here's a real cool and for you,
I have some of the last terence mckenna
papers,
you know,
is archivist fire in 2007.
What happened there?
That was his lips in a rain forest.
How the fuck did a fire destroyed after
he died?
The papers went to excellent.
Were you just were on the big sur coast
and they stored them in town office in
berlin and a quiznos shop.
Sub shop.
I kid you not at some kind of electrical
issue.
Burned
a whole city block down and the eslan
office and terrence papers
go,
but didn't,
didn't his place in Hawaii burn too?
No.
It's still there.
Oh,
who owns that?
You know,
I don't know.
I think it was sold recently.
Jesus christ who bought that fucking
thing.
God damn.
I would love to have that place.
But in.
so those are kinds of her lost.
And as soon as that happened,
I heard somebody called me and I called
lorenzo.
Lorenzo haggerty or dear friend.
I love that dude.
And I said,
lorenzo,
the ells have removed the incriminating
evidence.
Again.
That's hilarious.
we have to rebuild terence mckenna from
extent materials,
so it's like a grateful dead show thing.
Send in your cassette.
Well,
his,
one of his most problematic theories was
that novelty theory that the idea that
december 20,
first 2012 there was going to be some
point of infant novelty and he thought
it was going to be a time machine
perhaps
based on the each and so I got a packet
of papers in the mail that I came
through,
another archivist because I'm also
handling timothy leary's,
the remnants of timothy leary's library
right now that are,
you know,
we're trying to scan the news archive
and whatever,
but this packet of material,
15 years of letters and there was a
timewave zero edition,
you know,
in a little binder or whatever with
terrence has a little writing on it.
And there was a post it note that we're
terrence's scribbled something.
And then at the bottom he says December
21st.
Yes,
yes,
yes.
On the bottom of this post it note 1989.
And so I scan that sucker in and put it
online in december of $20.
here is the nefarious posted note where
terrance finally settled on this date,
at least for terrence,
you know,
are they a wireless,
uh,
associate eric had been involved in this
too in the course.
But it says,
it comes down to this posted note in.
I wanted to put that up to sort of.
So the absurdity of this is a guy that
doesn't really know terrorists,
wasn't a technologist and you know,
he was a visionary thinker.
We love him.
I mean,
he was an amazing dude.
We love to listen to him,
but I think you're right.
I think he was off the rails on friday
too much into that one thing.
And not only that,
didn't he move the goalposts like at one
point in time,
it wasn't december 20.
First it was like november or something
and they changed it.
He changed it and he was trying to fit
the data to the curve,
but he wasn't really an expert in trends
and history.
And how can you match trends in history
to anything.
Anyway,
I would listen to him talk about that.
This is the one thing that I had to shut
off.
I've listened to pretty much everything
that he's ever done,
all of the lorenzo archives,
all the stuff that yana and put up way
back in the day to
podcasts.
Three 16 in the salon because that one
we kind of take this thing apart and
I've met with ralph abraham.
We meet once A year kind of thing and
then 2011 I was setting up to do a
program called terrence 2012 about the
life of terence mckenna.
And I met with ralph and I said,
tell me ralph,
what was going on in the late nineties
because you know,
they're the trial or ralph rupert who
was on your show,
ralph abraham.
And,
and ralph said,
we kind of were getting fed up because
terrence was just spinning these stories
and we didn't think they had any,
any basis.
And so at the 1998 trial logs,
you know,
the trials were,
were they all met?
And they talked to you there at uc santa
cruz.
He said,
if you listen to that rupert,
nice,
set a trap for terrence.
We trapped him over and over again and
we basically for an hour he was
squirming and he was pretty up.
Pretty uncomfortable slide.
Pull out our cassette tape of that and
we have digitized it and sure and
behold,
and you'll hear this within podcast 3:16
and what rupert says,
it's terrence is talking about,
you know,
the internet will come to consciousness
in 20 minutes or less,
you know,
it will be an ai that will no longer
need us.
And so rupert was ready for that and
said,
terrence,
uh,
I've heard reports of voice.
You had him here and I've heard 10
versions of this story.
And then the last version,
it was an ai coming out of a time
portal.
No,
because they're not going to let them
get away with this.
And terrence is such a good irish.
Right?
He's such Good on,
you know,
storytelling,
and he's good with.
And he says,
and that to 10.
But at the end of that,
it's very,
very heartfelt and kind of terrence
realizes his friends have kind of drawn
a line in the sand.
And the last thing he says in that trial
august,
well we want profits but we don't want
false prophets.
So,
you know,
I think the story was the thing at that
time.
So do you think that he just got carried
away with it?
Like is it mean obviously he liked you
and I like everyone we know is flawed as
a person and he also,
part of the reason why he was as
visionary,
sort of out of the box thinker,
this guy who had this really incredible
way of describing potential
possibilities was that his mind was
prone to going on these little weird
journeys and took a lot of chances and
maybe might have been married to a few
of these chances that maybe shouldn't
have
you have dennis.
Dennis was in The introduction,
I think,
to the second version of invisible
landscape.
dennis is writing,
you know,
this is what we went through and we were
in our twenties and we've learned
something since then.
We don't really know,
I don't believe this anymore,
and,
and you know,
I think it's almost like in this could
happen to any of us.
We get attached to a story.
That's our shtick.
It's our comedy act.
It's our thing.
We do our conspiracy theory.
It's the thing that brings people into
the seats,
fills the theaters,
and if it's paying your bills and it
gives you self worth and whatnot,
you can get really attached to that
story.
it's very unfortunate,
you know,
because
the rest of terrence's ideas were so
fascinating.
Compelling and listen to them talk about
the positive benefits of psychedelics,
what he thinks the potential of
psychedelics hold and what he thinks
about psychedelic culture.
and there's so much fascinating.
Absolutely fast.
I love the amount of him.
He was terrence for me.
I can tell you,
and I only knew him the last couple of
years.
We didn't know he was on his way out.
Frankly.
You know,
we did this whole fantastic thing with.
We brought virtual worlds,
sos house in Hawaii office,
satellite dish,
and he was placed into a world and he
became his own ghost.
The avatar was fantastic and I was
looking forward to a long association
with him and we were planning to an
excellent workshop where he and I could
do pieces of the same puzzle like I
could do like the deep tech and weird
ideas and stuff,
but it was based on science and tech and
some visionary thing and he would come
in from his history side and elusive and
all that stuff and we were going to go
on the road and then he had a grand mal
seizure two months later and it was
horrific and we saw him last in
september,
[inaudible] 99 and it was like a good
event that was held.
If he was around today,
is there sufficient medical advances
that would have helped him?
You know,
a glioblastoma multiforme is,
they're so rare and they have a really
bad prognosis.
I mean he had gamma knife surgery and I
think it was november.
I mean Eric Davis has last interview.
The interview.
Eric davis is wonderful from Hawaii
right from,
from,
actually it might've been on the
mainland.
You hear a lot of dishes in the
background.
That wouldn't be the model for.
He might've been an occidental during
that one,
after the surgery,
but he's so beautifully cogent and
coherent that mean he says he's a
master.
He's.
He's so in his heart.
He's so brilliant and you know,
he's on all these antiseizure drugs and
everything.
One of the things he does say,
which was this,
he said,
you need to rethink this thing because
I'm an altered spaces because I'm on
massive medications because I have a
brain disease because,
and there are people walking around that
are certifiably in altered states and we
shouldn't just privilege psychedelics.
There are so many avenues into alternate
realities is allowed us to see the world
and I'm just experienced them and that's
part of what my mission in the world is
to say don't privilege these substances
because then they become crutches.
You can.
Terrence used to say,
you can't do this on the couch,
you know,
but I've since met a lot of people that
are going to profound spaces through
other means.
Yeah.
I think he was a bit.
I think he was a little hasty in his,
his proclamation that this isn't
capable,
this is impossible under natural
conditions because I have a friend who
has had psychedelic experiences.
He's not averse to it.
He's a regular marijuana user.
He's also
a kundalini expert and he's become a
kundalini expert since I've known him.
So over the lAst 10 years has been
practicing.
I've known him for about 10 years,
has been practicing clue a very,
very intensely over the past four or
five and since then he says,
he goes,
I have deep dmt experiences doing
kundalini and I have no reason to doubt
him.
I have another friend who does a
different type of medication,
some,
some sort of a.
It's not kundalini,
but some sort of meditation and he also
says that he's like,
I have legit,
full blown psychedelic experiences and I
think I'm,
I'm starting to research this and I'm
actually going to be working on a book
on this thing because I keep running
into these people and I call it.
And you know,
we taught indogenous,
so I'm using the term endo endo beings
or endo voyaging or whatever.
Using your own endogenous ability,
because I do it,
I think it's just unbelievably difficult
to do and I think some people are just
lazy.
I think that's really a part of it.
It's also physical effort.
There's a lot of people that are
investing a tremendous amount of time
and thinking calculation postulating,
but the physical effort of meditation is
beyond them and that's one of the things
that mckenna talked about.
Terrance talked about all the time how
boring meditation was,
so incredibly.
Blood had a flash insight.
Joe were to come back to the original
theme that we're talking about.
Why did the ancients could do this
amazing stuff that we're now
discovering?
It's like currently high tech because
they weren't distracted.
What could they do?
It's true.
No internet,
no twitter.
You can check their faceBook every 10
minutEs.
They could.
A guy could look at a pile of rocks and
see the full structure of the pyramid
and it's in his head or her head with
water flowers and they perhaps because
they're not so distracted in a stimulus
response,
cortisol being shot in and interrupts
and to do lists and whatnot,
just massively distracted.
Those guys were using full power of this
endogenous power and maybe a loose.
this was unlocking net.
It's also possible that they didn't have
the predetermined limitations that we
have when we consider like what normal
states of consciousness exists.
We have this idea of list exists and
then if you want more than that,
you got to take acid.
If you want more than that,
you've got to get on prozac.
If you bought more than this,
you know you have to be drunk.
You have to be this,
you have to be that.
So we have these preconceived notions
about altered states of consciousness,
brilliant insight and,
and,
and we're so channeled and managed in a
technologically are driving like driving
here.
I mean,
we drove down the back of California
from santa cruz ceremony,
some of those beautiful landscaping.
Amazing.
Kayla and I are looking at this glowing
light coming off the ocean,
like what you saw at big sur.
Those dudes,
I mean we get a little snatch of it,
but we don't have the full experience.
We're not standing on the shore smelling
the plants in a full body
of health being impacted by those
photons coming,
giving us an enlightened states because
we're driving past it and we're watching
our time and our gas levels and whatnot
and we're out of tune.
We're not present.
I've talked about this many times on the
podcast.
I had a really life changing experience.
It had nothing to do with drugs and it
was.
I went to the big island.
I went to the keck observatory.
Wow.
It just went because I was on vacation
with my family there and we went to the.
There's two levels to the observatories
is the main observatory and then there's
the visitors area and the visitors are
just have a bunch of telescopes set out.
It's pretty cool,
but it's so high that it's above the
clouds clouded area.
Was it clear?
Was it totaLly close,
cloudy below us or was just fascinating.
We were bummed out.
We were like,
oh man,
we're going to hit clouds.
we're not gonna see anything,
but we actually drove through the clouds
and because they have the diffused
lighting all over the big island to
protect the observatory from light
pollution.
Man,
the view was stunning.
The milky way was so bright and clear
and there's so many stars in the sky and
it was a perfect night.
I went back recently and I made a
mistake and went back when it was a full
moon and it was.
It was actually a super moon.
It was awful.
I think august,
august was the moon.
It was still beautiful and amazing and
still like,
wow,
that's a planet floating above us,
but nothing like the first trip and that
trip,
being there and seeing those stars,
you've got to think that is what early
man saw every day.
They were just awash in the mystery.
That is the sky and they paid attention
so much.
They knew its shape,
changes,
wobble of the eaRth.
They knew about the procession of the
equinoxes.
They had it mapped out,
I mean there's so much that they had
figured out that the equinox procession
is,
look what,
26,000
years somehow or another.
These people had figured a lot of that
out a long time ago
and it may have been just total presence
and that they built the model in their
head with their own dmt,
if you'd call it that are endogenously
or who knows.
I'm sure they took drugs to.
Here's a show that was a part of it as
it was that as well.
Here's another good one.
Her friend andrew was commissioned.
He's an incredible painter and he was
commissioned to paint the caves of last
scope,
a co.
Andrew johnstone,
a complete reconstruction of an on like
a surface.
It was the same rock face,
but it was for like a restaurant or
something.
Oh wow.
And so he got all these,
you know,
different.
You can't go in there.
I guess it's people's breath will
destroy it,
but he started to paint this,
this,
you're going to really tune into this.
He stArted to paint this inside this
restaurant with the rock face and he was
painting the copy of it and he would go
out at night because he had to paint at
night because the restaurant was in
business and he would just know his
break and whatever,
and he started to study the sky and then
we'd go back and paint more of the
bowls,
horns and the running,
missing that,
and he would go back and after all this
time he started,
wait a minute,
I'm seeing lusko in the sky,
but it's a little different.
And he would go back and look at,
he was reconstructIng also go from the
lowest detail and he said,
this is a fricking star map.
This is a star map.
And he actually submitted a publication
to an archeological journal,
I don't know,
was reviewed.
Uh,
you know,
I don't know what happened.
I think he wasn't reviewed well because
I don't think that it's in the
literature and I'm not seeing it now,
chris,
the stars are in a slightly different
position,
right?
Let's constellations work,
but you know,
it doesn't,
it's fucking powerful,
but isn't it one of those things we can
kind of see patterns if you want to like
go,
oh,
I see a bowl.
I mean we have,
there's some patterns like the big
dipper,
like,
oh,
it's big dipper,
right?
But when you see all the stars behind
the changes,
make up your own fucking patterns.
You know,
the big dipper represents to me is like
an established pattern that you know
exists.
So you can call it the big dipper and
say it's a dipper,
but what it,
what it is,
is just,
oh,
that's that,
that there they are there.
If you know.
Oh,
I see a bull.
Well,
you're already fucking painting a bowl,
dude.
You know,
of course you're seeing a bowl in the
sky,
right?
Could be good.
Plus you fucking stiff and pain all day.
You're out of your head going outside,
you're delusional.
You're tired right now.
Be a lot of things going on there.
It wasn't reviewed very well.
maybe not a blue wig and started writing
a paper on it and everybody's okay.
How much paint do you paint?
Are you using?
Right?
How close are you to this pain?
Then we get.
We run into the mind of science.
Yes,
of course.
It's and it's born to critique has to,
right?
It has to so much fuckery.
You have to.
Because it's one of the only human
enterprise.
It is making progress.
Well,
think about your friend that you were
talking about that was in a fucking
cult.
The thought that aliens made the
pyramids that led him to actual science.
The science actually set him free from
the cult.
It did.
Indeed.
Doesn't mean that's the whole reason why
it has to question everything.
It has to go.
Okay,
what did you see up there in the sky
while you're sniffinG paint pal.
That's right.
You know,
the cults can waste a lot of minds and a
lot of lives then that's charismatic.
Leaders are very dangerous,
especially when they want to lead.
And also I think that the intoxicating
nature of being that leader.
What do you think of,
you know the talk about sociopathy and
psychopathy and that that's a certain
percentage of the population is lacking
a brain region that just doesn't have
it.
when they put the system together,
that's there's no empathic part of the
brain.
Do you think,
I'm asking you on on the air here,
I mean this sounds like a eugenics kind
of a thing,
but do you think a future society or
future earth ought to screen people when
they're young kids when they're young to
find out if their potential psychopaths
and sociopaths and give them different
trainings and not allow them say to run
armies and countries and stuff like that
because they're just not going to have
the empathic response.
Like if you had poor vision,
you shouldn't pilot an airliner,
for example.
It's a physiological thing that makes
you kind of not suited for certain kinds
of jobs.
Can be proven that this is like there's
an undeniable correlation between this
particular area of the brain and lacking
empathy in that you cannot be a good
leader.
You cannot be a good.
There's so many factors like saying to
someone can't be,
if they lack empathy,
they can't be a good leader,
but what if those same factors that led
them to lack empathy also lead them to
lack a certain amount of ego that would
kind of fuck up being a leadeR or law
they laid,
lacked a certain amount of need to be
charismatic,
right desire to have all these people
follow you,
like certain high functioning autistic
folks have incredible skills in a lot of
areas that maybe people that have
extreme connections to emotions or to
social interaction might not develop.
So I don't necessArily know that we
understand.
You just don't know all the potential
possibilities when it comes to human
interaction and messing with that.
There's just a,
there's this weird range of what is a
person,
right?
And to say that,
but there's also people that have taken
those psychopath tests and you know,
they will technically I'm supposed to be
a psychopath.
meanwhile,
I'm a functioning rational,
normal member of my community.
I'm a loving father and husband and,
and um,
everything's great.
So what the fuck,
like why does this test say I'm a
psycho,
right?
I don't know.
I don't know if we haven't nailed yet.
The problem comes when we get
psychopaths doing really terrible shit
like dictators and stuff like that and
we can't get rid of them.
Then the damage isn't being done and we
can't do any.
And what makes them a psychopath in the
first place.
Like a perfect example is saddam
hussein's children who were notoriously
evil,
uday and qusay,
where names were two of the most
horrific human beings that we've ever
seen come out of the,
the,
you know,
the brute of a diCtator.
I mean he,
he developed some unbelievably evil
children.
Now,
why is it that they were evil?
Is it the environment?
Is a nurture?
Is it nature?
Is it genetics?
Is it epigenetics?
Like what is it that.
Is it just being unbelievably spoiled?
Because you have ultimate power from the
time you were a child and you're
essentially royalty.
What is it?
What causes that?
It's possible that our survival as a
species is going to come down to how
well we unhealthily we manager our
children.
I mean ultimately if we're.
If we're not doing that,
then like if for instance you were
building a mars colony,
was going to have 250 people in it and
they're going to have children or
whatever.
You
would know that if you get one kind of
crazy revolutionary leader that does the
whole charismatic thing and whatever,
and then there's a shooting thing is
going to shoot a hole so the dome and
everyone's going to die.
So you can't ever afford that.
So you have this careful management of
human psychology within that call on you
to make sure it's healthy and watch
those processes and it.
To some extent the scandinavians did
this a thousand years ago.
The scandinavians have the vikings.
when they had their war parties,
the leader of the war party,
they would go and invade east anglia or
all the way to greenland,
labrador and what they called these guys
the preserve or kinks,
and these guys were put in charge and
then they would go and they will do
terrible shit.
I mean they would terrorize and murder
and whatnot,
but when they settled east anglia,
when they built york,
york,
right,
they excavated it.
Well,
the vikings are now settled,
so they took the.
The worker king.
Thank you very much.
You've done your job.
You get the nice little grass hut at the
edge of town and you're off duty because
we can't afford that.
Now we have to build a community.
So what will they do with him?
You did retire them off.
Retired to mob and how you keep them
from killing people.
I'm going nutty.
He just.
Nobody would follow him as the rules.
It was the.
It was the way that they did it.
So when you look at how sane scandinavia
is today,
maybe they got all that out.
That's a funny.
That's a very funny thought.
That who knows,
who knows,
who knows.
I think it's also there is a potential
for technology to play a part in all
this.
I think that one of the things that's
coming out with technology is access to
information and access to information.
Not just current information,
but I'll maybe even future like the
ability to read minds,
to read thoughts to read,
look,
fff,
mri,
[inaudible],
although it's been widely criticized,
has been used to convict people of
crimes in India.
There's a woman who was convicted of
murder because she had what they
describe as functional knowledge of a
crime scene and this has been widely
discredited and it's very controversial.
I don't know.
I don't know the whole story,
but it was for a television show that I
was doing for saifai.
We interviewed a neurologist or a
neuroscientist and she was describing
how this in in our country will never
work,
but in these other countries where the
maybe they don't have as much of as much
of an understanding or they were able to
manipulate their courts into thinking
that this was far more definitive and
conclusive than it really is.
But the point being that this is just
the tip of the iceberg,
right?
And if they continue to get better at
this,
and if this human technological
symbiotic relationship takes place to
the point where we essentially are our
memories,
especially there pretty piss poor,
but if we can turn our memories into
some digital archive that you can
access,
it will.
Then we're going to know I've got an I'm
going to look into your head and I'm
going to know what's going on and to be
able to tap into it and we will.
We'll be connected the same way we were
connected with wifi the same way our
cell phones are connected through the
cellular network.
They'll be some sort of a network of
information exchange between all people.
And if that's the case,
deception will be almost impossible.
Motivations would be crystal clear and
you're going to know who's full of shit.
That's going to be a fucking bad day for
a lot of idiots out there because a lot
of assholes out there that have been
leading along idiots and the they,
they believe in these people.
You know,
whether these cult members or whatever
you remember in kubrick's film,
2001 in the beginning when there's the
pre,
the monkeys,
the monkeys model and they're sitting at
dawn and they're sitting in this kind of
cliff area and they're looking at each
other,
right?
They're looking at each other.
I never forgot that scene because it's
the scene before they get attacked by
that other group that comes in,
but they're looking at each other and
their nonverbal.
RighT.
They're not communicating.
They don't have to do lists and emails
and shit going on.
They're just there.
And to me like kubrick was trying to
show that they are in a group
intelligence that just by eye gaze they
could tell what the state is and then
the share that state.
Because if somebody in such an intense
environment,
I mean if you have nefarious purposes or
you know you're going to look away and
you're going to have that whole thing.
so maybe that's the way we were before
we came into mind.
Before all this stuff came in
civilization mind to do lists,
hierarchies and whatnot.
We were.
There was no way for us like we're way
we're looking now at each other.
We're really connected.
Maybe the valleys of perceptions may be
the pre communicative apes where they
didn't have verbal communication or
language or anything.
Maybe they had this sort of intuitive
sense of each other and then that was
all lost with email and twitter and
ended up coming back with some new
technology that takes it to a far deeper
level.
And
what I think,
and this is my theory,
is that a louis.
Yeah,
we were warning,
you know,
it looses by packing those thousand
initiates and two that buried temple and
subjecting them to sound and music and
you know,
some kind of sounds like a rave.
It was like intense,
but these people were fashioned.
they were fat.
They were fashioned into new beings from
in that experience wasn't,
couldn't it have been a group mind fast
and couldn't have been,
you know,
returning that.
And when we siT in medicine circles
today,
when we do jujitsu,
when we do a group yoga,
intense things are intense ordeal.
Things that people are seeking out now
for deep connection to remove isolation
from other people.
Meditation's all these practices are
this yearning to get back to where we
were,
you know,
you didn't feel isolated from others and
that we had her in a group mind and that
that's the future of evolution of our
communities and we may need the shaman
to come around,
you know,
in the upper paleolithic,
those communities were pretty helpful.
That waS a pretty functional world.
I mean,
you know,
coming into,
the karnak and the stone hands and the
lay lines and be incredible world of
even celtic europe was incredibly
together.
There was killed at europe is like the
european union now.
Celtic europe had medical practices and
common laws and the druids could come in
if there was a battle about to occur
between celtic people's.
The druids had the power to walk down
that line and decide whether the battle
should happen or not because there was
an authority.
There was.
So this whole idea of the civilization
of the european union after 2000 years
of roman interest to seen war,
barbarian warfare,
christian religious and whatnot,
as they've returned to the celtic model,
they've returned in sense the upper
paleolithic model of civilization of of
civil societies and not beating each
other in and in doing and of common
currency,
common exchange,
common health comm.
So maybe that is coming back that is
returning and we're,
we're shutting off the culture that came
and destroyed illusion looses.
Well,
I think there's definitely a feeling
amongst a lot of folks that the standard
model,
the cubicle life retirement at 65 is not
just unappealing,
not just unrewarding,
it's surf,
surf model slavery.
It's a form of slavery that's voluntary
mean you,
you're,
you're connecting to a machine.
You're giving your body literally.
You're giving your health,
you're giving your spinal fluid,
ears,
soul.
Your creative creativity are very.
Your body literally is like giving into
your chair and your back is being
compressed and your discs are bulging.
Your feet are going numb,
and I mean your,
your body is being sucked down into
this.
Your mind is turned into a stimulus
response pieces of jello and I think
that's what a lot of this yoga,
this,
this renaissance of meditation that a
lot of people are experiencing,
especially yoga.
Yoga was never this popular when I was
right.
it's incredibly popular now and as the
rise of technological connection,
electronic connections with each other
has also facilitated the rise of like
and you know,
fit these people wanting to do things
that are physical,
physical.
I.
On friday I did a pretty long float and
we go.
By the way they've offered you a free
float if you come up to the santa cruz
mountains are friends.
that sounds like a long trip for a
float.
I got one in my basement.
This is a beautiful flotation.
It's the name of the company.
Cloud nine.
Oh,
okay.
I've heard of them.
Yeah,
because jim shaunti and they was
fascinating
property and I went there for a float
and I tell you,
you know,
it's,
it's incredible because it's,
it's like doing,
you know,
a psychedelic in that or doing deep
meditation or doing.
But the flotation tank is I think better
because I process all my brain shit,
like for the first hour or something in
this probably happens to you.
It just grind through and it's like I'm
having these repeated thoughts of my
mind or my ego is grinding through and
through and finally it quiets fine when
it's quiet and I don't have stimulus on
my body because I'm in a flotation tank
and I maybe have my head held up or
whatever and I start not knowing my body
where it is and I'm free,
I'm liberated,
and then the I can do the deep work at
my god.
I mean the next day,
this is why I was able to finish this to
scientific papers because I floated and
I lost all that 2000 years of refer me.
It was months and months of being in my
head.
I mean,
I,
I.
It's such a powerful,
powerful
tool.
It's an amazing tool and it's really
bizarre to me that this was something
that was kind of forgotten for a long
time.
I didn't understand when I first
discovered the tank when I first saw it
in altered states when I was in high
school.
That,
uh,
amazing movie with William Murray where
he turns into drink.
Iowasca became some freak animal.
Crazy movie really does not hold up.
Don't watch it again.
We'll try to watch in 2004.
It's a piece of shit.
Oh,
it's so bad.
It's so bad.
Like people have watched.
It laughed at me like,
you fucking like this movie.
My brow is 14.
Okay.
So long time ago.
but point is I didn't experience it
until 2002.
And when I first did it,
others plays in burbank called soothing
solutions.
I was placed.
Where did it.
The first time I did I wanted to do it
forever and I found a place that had it
and I was like,
how is this not popular?
And then when I started talking about
it,
everybody's like,
wow,
you're always talking about this thing.
Like you're the guy who talks about the
tank.
I'm like,
how are you hearing about this from a
goddamn comedian?
Like,
how is this not the.
How's the president not on television
and saying we need to create a more
introspective commerce society and one
of the things we're going to do is we're
going to wheel out isolation tanks all
over the nation.
There will be a beautiful thing to bring
them up to some high schools,
community centers,
universities.
This will accelerate thinking.
It's one of the best tools for personal
evolution I've ever experienced for
actually the exact same thing as you
said.
For me it's the first x amount of
minutes is all just going over my own
bullshit,
but slowly but surely because I do it so
often I've gotten quicker with that and
it's gotten down to like 20 minutes,
but it's just I get in there and I go,
here we go.
I've got to go through all this stupid
shit.
Clean all this out.
But perspective enhancing like,
you know,
like no matter how hectic and weird my
life is when I get into that thing and
then I get out,
I'm like,
that's all right.
Yeah.
You're like,
I'm the best hippie of the 66.
It's beautiful.
It's so important for me because I'm
always juggling like five different
jobs.
Yeah,
a million things to.
And you know,
my back,
I put my fricking back out so I go into
float and it's like the first hour it's
just so painful.
It's like slowly like separates and it's
like I barely do this and then barely
put my.
Put my hands down and then then I say,
wait a minute,
my body can take any position so I let
my body tickets own position.
It moves itself around until I'm not in
pain anymore.
And then by the time I got out the pain
was down like 80 percent.
Yeah.
it's,
it is an unbelievable tool and it's just
weird to me how uncommon it is as
terrence's.
How do they keep the lid on this stuff?
Don't.
The other thing that terrence says,
the man,
sometimes people do the man's work for
like no one's putting,
keeping the lid on isolation tanks.
It's just no one tAlked about it for
whatever reason.
It's just life is tough.
People have mortgages,
they have student loans.
There's a lot of work that has to be
done.
The lawn has to be mowed.
Got to raise your kids a lot of shit
going on.
It's hard to servitude jail.
We were talking before the podcast about
chairs.
It's weird chair that I have this saddle
chair.
Do you use an ergonomic chair when you,
uh,
when you do your writing,
you know,
I,
my neighbor and I made this chair.
We took this body built chair from.
There's a plug for you from Texas that's
used by surgeons,
by brain surgeons.
It tilts forward.
It has incredible support and we made an
extension arm that holds the keyboard of
my lap and the mouse exactly in the
right place just right where your arms
hang,
and then I can roll back from the
screens.
I'm much farther from the screen so I
don't get that myopic kind of early
visit and vision loss.
That's me.
I got that chair.
Yeah.
So I've been using that chair for 20
years,
but now what I'm finding unfortunately,
just even reaching for the mouse as
creating repetitive strain injury for
me,
even going to get one of them helmets or
move around your eyes.
Unfortunately I'm back on a laptop where
I don't have to do any motion until my
friend told me.
He said,
you're an idiot.
You know,
I have a friends of the hassle.
right away you're an idiot.
I'm an idiot.
He's an asshole.
But I have my own podcast called the
levity zone.
And I do lots of editing.
You know,
I know that you could just go straight
out,
but I'm like a craftsman.
I,
we have different musicians in each
episode for the levity,
sound liberties on.org.
Um,
say that again.
Levity zone.org.
[inaudible] dot org.
It's the world needs more.
We have plenty of novelty.
We need more at t l e v I t y zone.
So you're in the zone when you're
listening to these shows at [inaudible]
dot org.
And so I do tons of editing and he said,
you fool,
you need to get a kensington track ball
so you're just moving your thumb,
not your arm.
All editors are using track balls for
buttons.
And I finally got religion and I'm
finally not using a mouse.
Mac has a,
uh,
they have like a key,
like this track pad.
Yeah.
It's a larger version of it.
That's what I use.
It's amazing.
I used to move the tracks back and
forward and then I use the other hand on
the kensington to go cut,
paste,
cut,
paste.
Okay.
You're doing great.
Yeah,
totally.
Great.
Yeah.
Well you also have probably have
keystrokes preprogrammed on that thing
and the buttons.
Yeah.
That helps cut.
Copy paste.
Mark's like no collected.
I love the track pad.
Once I switched to it on a,
um,
on a home computer or on an imac,
I would never go back to the house
except for gaming.
But I can't it either way.
The digi barn museum,
we got a new artifact.
Doug angle parts mouse,
you know doug engelbart,
he and building that.
She created the mouse and the first
online system in the mid sixties and
they dug,
had something called the mother of all
demos which happened on December 9th,
19,
68 and it totally revolutionized what
computing was going to be.
He was like in this hall in san
francisco using a mouse and the cursor
was going on the screen is opening
windows and clicking the first graphic
user interface with 68 house and I don't
have that one,
but I've got a.
If you look up mother of all demos,
you'll see the one that came into the
dog barn looks exactly like the one that
doug is using the demo now.
There were several of them made so we
don't know,
but this has the round buttons as a
great big case on it and a key set.
So the see he had.
He didn't have to go to the keyboard.
He had this,
this court keyboard.
I'll that.
Yeah,
there,
there are three buttons mean well,
apple had one button actually that deep
into the two thousands probably from my
collection,
but that's an alto mouse from the
seventies.
If look at sandy's,
yeah,
do tug to mother of all demos and you'll
probably find the,
uh,
the video of it.
Is it true that xerox created the user
interface in the apple copied xerox and
then ultimately microsoft copies apple?
It wAs,
it was kind of passed from one to the
other.
So for example,
uh,
a say sri stanford research institute
did this,
doug engelbart nls,
fantastic demo and everybody watched it
and go,
oh my god,
this totally changed computing into a
human thing rather than data processing
and batch.
And you know,
it became no,
it's visual.
We're visual.
This is a tool for our minds.
It's a tool for this.
This is it.
An hour and a half long though.
So yeah,
scroll around and you can see doug,
you can see doug other areas.
wow.
You see that thing on the right?
See that in 68,
68.
So look at that.
That looks exactly like the mouse.
It's at the barn right now.
That's remarkably similar to what a lot
of people use.
Then look at the keyboard and I think
steelcase or somebody did that thing and
the key set allows you to court key
movements like accelerated things and
then on screen he has clickable text.
He's got a video window that a guy
appears from sri transmitted live video.
Look at this.
That's him.
Yeah.
That's one of the engineers at sri.
So he's got live video on a screen.
Yeah,
this is 68 and 68.
He is live video.
Yeah,
and this is beamed in a big auditorium
in san francisco at a conference and
everybody in the audience is going,
oh my god,
this is computing.
This is,
this is interacting with people and so
he's clicking see the cursor.
You can just sort of barely see it.
He's moving around,
he's clicking on things,
they're pulling up data,
they're doing searches and that's a
recipe lists and so everybody looked at
this and said,
oh my god.
And so xerox palo alto research center
kind of had a bunch of people from
doug's group and then they built the
first network,
personal computer or the ether net and
all that stuff.
In the seventies,
and you're right,
you know,
in walks steve jobs and in the croup and
they kind of went,
oh my god,
that's the future of computing,
and they created the lisa and the
macintosh and bill gates and the company
looked at the xerox star and altona and
gerald pneumonia who was at park,
came to microsoft and created microsoft
word based on him creating the first
word processor at park and then made a
billion dollars.
Right.
And everything.
But no,
I mean xerox really did invent the
future under bob taylor's leadership in
the seventies.
They just created the future.
Right.
How did they drop the ball and go to
copy machines?
Well,
you know,
it was such a company full of copier
heads and understand what they were
looking at it and walked out the door,
But dolby came out of that and everybody
in ibm in the 19,
whatever it was,
when they said no one's gonna want a
computer in their house.
Yeah,
the fuck up.
It was like the biggest bad call ever.
Right?
I mean,
there were all these predictions that
completely ridiculous.
Ridiculous.
In retrospect,
in retrospect,
how could anybody.
No,
that's.
Isn't that always the point?
Is that like,
like we were talking about,
you can't predict a 2012 or 20,
45,
you're just not going to not going.
No one's gonna see it.
I am going to have some ideas,
but the ultimately the thing itself,
like no one ever thought the internet
was going to be facebook or message
boards or you know,
twitter,
social media interaction.
The way we we experienced today.
It's so unbelievably bizarre.
this connection that we have to each
other.
It's so intense and,
and,
and no one saw it coming.
Like for instance,
just yesterday morning I got up into
holy shit,
I'm going to be on joe rogan.
I'm going to just at least post your
beautiful red face logo,
my facebook page and put it on a bunch
of groups because available on a mug.
So I just put this up.
I put this up just on facebook.
I only got three or 4,000
followers,
but this thing just went bing,
bing,
bang.
And people,
you know,
there's probably a ton of listeners that
there wouldn't have been just because of
one little thing.
Yeah,
I'm sure.
Well,
it's one of those things too that I love
the fact that someone could listen to
this and go,
hey,
you know,
bruce damer is on this podcast.
you got to check this out,
here's a link.
And then boom,
boom,
boom.
And then someone retweets it and it gets
retweeted a thousand times and sent to
facebook and someone sends in an email
and
it's like,
we're back.
We're back in that little group of 2000,
one eight,
looking at each other.
But what we're looking,
we're spending for sending the whole of
our culture and technology in each gaze.
It's amazing.
I mean,
if you could be some kind of super being
unwatched the mind of humanity from
orbit and study it as a thing that's
coming alive and it's moving.
It's getting connected,
uh,
maynard to be better than any trip
experience.
I mean,
just in truth,
you know,
I look up at the night sky or doing the
work in origin of life.
I'm looking at molecular streams and
looking through microscopes on liquid
chemistry and I was like this most
amazing universe of just lipids moving
around on a slide and then look at the
internet.
This is the greatest time in the history
of and,
and you know,
the people talk about rare earths,
you know,
how rare is,
are we,
you know,
the drake equation,
which shows solar systems that have
planets in the planet that have been the
right habitable zone and the develop
intelligent life.
And we had just the right end asteroid
impacts to come in and spin the disk and
say,
start again.
Do it again.
And,
and we rose.
I mean,
what's the chance of us snus being out
there?
How many of them are there?
Well,
isn't the ultimate mind fuck the concept
of infinity?
Because the way I've heard it described
that if infinity exists and they believe
it does,
that means the universe is so huge that
everything that's ever happened on earth
in the exact same order,
it's happened in infant number of times
somewhere else.
Well,
I had,
I once had a kind of a conversation with
the universe and I asked it,
so I went through a thought experiment
where I went through the origin of life,
you know,
I just loaded my mind with everything I
could do and I went through and saw it.
I was like super charged on all this
stuff of my meditation and my thought
experiments and I came out screaming,
you know,
I came into the division of the first
proto cell and while it was happening,
I looked around and I saw all this crazy
molecular stuff going on,
which gave me the vision to work
backwards to create the model that we're
just publishing now.
But I felt,
and this is kind of heretical,
but I,
I couldn't see that it was all
mechanical,
you know,
it seemed like there was something doing
it.
I mean,
it was so complex.
So in this thought experiment,
I,
I sat up straight and I said,
I want to ask one more question if this,
if there's something before life.
There were,
if there was intelligence in the,
did this,
can I see it?
you know,
this is,
I think when you asked the ineffable
these questions ineffable,
just get pissed off with questions
sometimes and the inevitable,
what it did in my consciousness as I was
looking out into the night sky into the
darkness and it resolved and to
starfield and they'll start fill the
rural salt into gas clouds and galaxies,
and then the whole thing came rushing
into,
slammed into my consciousness sensor and
knocked me down and what the answer was
you silly monkey.
The universe is big enough to have
agency.
It grew big enough from the big bang.
It grew along the probability streams so
that this happened.
That's the answer.
There's one concept that I.
I can kinda understand infinity.
I can kind of understand a lot of the
concepts of the cosmos,
but the big bang,
which is I hear it,
it goes in one ear and it goes out the
other and it's just some words.
It's just some shit that's typed out.
It's just an idea that someone has that
I can't conceptualize.
It doesn't.
my brain is too fucking dumb.
It just doesn't process it.
I,
I got a vision of it because it's,
it's hard for me to,
I mean the vision that I got,
I was sitting there in bed asking the
question of what can I see pack,
so I wanted to see back and what came in
my head were three buckets and inside
the three buckets were three blobs and
eat.
one of the blobs is super low
probability of ever happening.
The probability buckets and the others
are kind of like ordinary rowboats.
And then there's a thIrd bucket.
Second bucket has a super low probably
blob,
and then the third bucket has the low
probably blog and the,
the intelligence that was communicating
to me to teach me said,
watch me bing,
bing,
bing.
So when you say this though,
I'm sorry to interrupt you.
So the,
the,
what the intelligence showed me because
I was asking the question and getting a
thought experiment back was saying I can
trigger the lowest probability of hanse
one after the other after the other.
And I said,
whoa,
okay.
And said,
watch me.
I will rotate them towards you.
So the buckets are all lined up and you
say you see the path through the low
probability events.
I say,
yes I do.
He says watch this.
And the path went all the way back to
cosmo.
Genesys and I went,
oh my god,
you know,
this energy was pouring through super
low probability and then the entity said
watch this.
And I was pulled back and I saw
trillions of these tracers coming from,
from the singularity,
from the big bang.
And the answer was that is the power,
the power to trigger the lowest
probability events in all directions.
And that is the power,
you know,
away from mundane it please.
So you're saying that you know,
you're communicating with an entity and
you're saying,
you know,
this thing that's communicating with
you,
this is more likely your imagination.
No.
Well sometimes it is imagination on
steroids sometimes to stuff comes in.
It's like your friend you were talking
about stuff comes in.
I don't know where from,
you know einstein for example,
used to do this.
Einstein will be having his coffee and
his swiss cafe pondering about can can
light go faster,
you know,
is there a constant and the speed of
light and one night he just sort of sat
down,
closed his eyes and suddenly he was in
this endogenous world and you can read
about this.
He called it good duncan experiments,
thought experiments.
He would say,
I'm going to try to understand this,
but he would open himself to anything
and what came into einstein's mind was
he became like a train.
He was like mounted onto a train and
there was another train coming down the
track and they each had so it was at
night and the light was streaming out
and he said,
but how can I be the photon going toward
that?
Other photon in the photons are going
twice the speed of light relative to
each other and then he had this credible
insights about,
no,
it's possible if you have different
frames of reference,
it's possible.
His face change in all the whole special
on general theory of relativity came out
from these thought experiments that he
did that he didn't quite know where they
came from.
They just sort of poured into him.
Then he had to interpret and into
mathematics and into testable theories.
Well,
when we're.
do any ideas come from though really?
when,
where,
why?
Why consider the possibility that coming
from entities?
why don't why?
I just think this is your mind,
your imagination.
Just contemplating possibilities and,
and here's where I think,
oh,
this is a really big woo model because
this wound,
wu on the front of the stove,
the t shirt here.
I think that somehow our minds when
we're open and we're,
we're in a state of not distraction or
boundaries or dissolved and we're in a
clear state that our minds are big
enough computational engines to resonate
with a whole lot of shit non locally.
So for example,
you believe nonlocal intelligence.
You think that like perhaps there's some
sort of a universal intelligence out
there that you can tune into.
I think that in some way,
like for example,
if you trace all of the neuronal
pathways down,
all the synapses and across all the
caps,
backwards and forwards in your mind,
and you can look this up online,
the number of those tracers,
those unique strings is larger,
you know,
or an equivalent or larger than the
number of subatomic particles in the
universe.
Now,
all accountable objects in the universe.
It's this huge.
The common materials are huge because
the brain says this network and as soon
as it ramps up,
so your brain,
if you.
It's like an informational system,
a coding system that,
uh,
if you could activate this pathway and
that little variation of that pathway
and that will,
is actually bigger than the universe.
And of course it's in the universe to,
it's not bigger than itself.
But then you have the idea of non
locality where everything talks to
everything non locally,
you know,
and instantly was this bell's theorem
and all this sorts of things.
And so could it be that there's some,
and this is a total who hand wavy thing.
It could it be that your mind really
fully activated,
really fully present through your
filters,
through your training,
whether you're a roman catholic or
you're a skeptical,
whatever you stuff can come in that's
resonating from some field,
another intelligence objects,
patterns,
stuff in time and history beyond what
our little reductionist kind of
mechanical thinking gives us that could
we be resonating with real shit that's
out there,
that's beyond what our training is,
but it will be filtered throughout
training.
You're sort of tapping into some
incredible,
ultimate potential,
some potential for accessing information
and,
and possibilities for,
for possibilities as far as connections
possibilities,
as far as like putting things together
in your head and proposing the various
scenarios that maybe wouldn't be
available.
If you impose limitations on where they
came from,
you try to figure out with your training
in your to do list and your algorithms,
you'd never get there.
So you're literally have to blow your
mind completely open.
You know,
uh,
graham hancock gave a fantastic example
on your show within the last month,
which was a telescope.
Remember that needs to shape change the
shape of the lands in order for you to
resolve and see stars and galaxies.
Right?
So those people who never use telescopes
say,
well,
you shouldn't have to perturb the mind
to see what's out there.
Well,
they've never looked through a
telescope,
right?
So we should,
as a species,
we realize we need to perturb our.
Mine's always have a huge problem with
people that say you shouldn't perturb
the mind because I don't see the
negative impact of perturbing the mind
and I see a massive amount of positive
and then I see these people saying you
shouldn't perturb the mind and they
haven't perturbed them on something
like,
well,
what are you talking about?
Like anyone who says that like
psychedelic experiences are not valuable
and hasn't had psychedelic experiences.
I'm like,
okay,
we're just going around in circles here.
We're talking crazy.
Like you don't know whether they're
valued and you're just totally.
They've never floated or they've never
done meditation.
But the what I think the beauty of
psychedelic experience,
the actual taking of a psychedelic is,
is that it's undeniable mushrooms work
on everybody.
Dmt works well.
Some people,
some weird freak people apparently don't
have dmt experiences.
I don't know.
The problem is it's so illegal and it's
so.
It's so difficult to to.
I don't think strassman had any people
that didn't find a an impact for the
intravenous dmt studies that he did at
university of New Mexico,
but I think that people that say it's
not valuable and haven't experienced it,
you're discounting it just thousands,
millions,
perhaps people who have had incredibly
valuable experiences doing it and you're
saying you don't need it.
Like you know,
you're scared.
You're scared.
All these tribal cultures and that
needed that use that to initiate people
into humanity,
to human being.
I think from then then your idea of
endogenous access becomes becomes very
attractive and it also becomes more
plausible because people know that these
states are reachable because I think
without knowing,
like I remember the first time I had any
psychedelic experience,
the first really big one was a five men.
Oh,
I had a small mushroom experience,
but the five meo dmt experience.
Like after that I can remember really
clearly thinkinG,
well,
now that I know that this is a
possibility,
I have to kind of rethink,
rethink my spectrum,
everything,
and so then one could see reaching these
incredible states through some sort of
indogenous method that maybe perhaps he
would have never even given it the
chance before and I think you know,
you're looking african communities that
used ibogaine as an initiatory
experience on ordeal or initiate or
experience.
they're trying to take those uninformed
youths that think they know everything
right,
and they're and they're exposing them to
something so massive that forces them to
challenge their own internal state and
and come to terms with fears or other
things and broaden themselves out there.
We even there weft as a human beIng.
When they come out of that,
they're a member of the community and
they're trustable and they look each
other in the eye and they had the taps.
They're not children name or not
juvenile anymore,
and this is perhaps it was stolen from
us when we lost our initiatory rights
and was taken away by priests.
It was taken away by corporations or,
or maybe it's just a blip.
I mean maybe it's not taken away.
Maybe it's just in our context of our
lives.
We'd look at a thousand years being so
long,
but in the universe said nothing.
Nothing.
And if this state,
this the look to the life of the earth,
it's enough and then nothing.
so we're like,
it's been taken away from us.
Like now we're talking about it.
It's not going anywhere.
We're.
Yeah,
we're,
we're celebrating its return.
Listen,
we're out of time,
but this is an amazing conversation.
We could have 100 of these.
I think we really could.
We could,
we could go.
We could take the what if train to the
end of mars and back and I would like to
come back and bring you a bunch of
artifacts like that original miles that
you can,
you can play with on the show here.
I would love that.
And where can people find out more about
you?
Calm.com.
D a,
m e r.com.
And facebook.
Facebook.
I'm bruce damer a twitter.
I'm be damer.
I'm on youtube,
bruce digi,
but it's all there and levity zoned dot
ord.
We rebuilt the site just for you,
joe,
last week.
It's all new word press theme.
Oh,
I'm worried about the impact yet.
We've been on new servers,
crashed into that website right now.
Let's crash it and love it and if
anybody wants to reach me,
it's easy.
Bruce,
at [inaudible] dot com.
You just made a huge mistake.
So that's a tremendous mistake.
Prepare for a tsunami of dick's coming
your way and who knows what kind of
photographs could be a disaster.
It could be done that filter those out.
You might to add slides.
I should have stopped you anyway.
Um,
so the,
the podcast though is available on
itunes.
It's on itunes,
everything,
everything on soundcloud.
And one more time,
the name of the podcast on [inaudible]
dot org or.com
or whatever it is.
Bruce damer,
ladies and gentleman,
excellent podcast,
dennis mckenna.
So right about you.
That was awesome.
Thank you very much.
Really appreciate it.
Joe.
A lot of podcasts this week,
folks.
Paul stanley on wednesday,
uh,
from kiss.
We're going to have a lot of fun and,
uh,
and more and more csun.