Four three, two, one
and
we're live, this is a bummer of a fight
week, but also an awesome fight week.
I'm very excited. Did you see the, the
latest count down? What does it, uh,
all access? What do they call
it? No embedded. Embedded. Yeah.
Most try to call it with the
name of those. It's really
sad. They're all the same,
but yeah, all access embedded 24
seven. That is very good. I should,
I should remember the name. It's very
good. They're all, yeah, they're on this.
This new one is really good cause it's
got Max Holloway running on a treadmill,
two treadmills over from Nigga Madoff
who's also running on a treadmill and
they're fucking very cool to each other.
It's very interesting.
It could be thanked him for taking
the fight when she should. She should.
Thanks for taking the fight. And then
they have the same weight coach. Yeah.
That's crazy. Lockhart.
Right? It's the card is d.
This is Lockhart working with
number of command on both of them.
So Lockhart was like,
Lockhart is legit.
Like he goes over calculations
of how much you weigh,
how much water you're going to take,
and he's weighing things out.
It took them an hour and a half to do
the calculations. It wasn't like, hey,
we're going to wing this. It's like,
no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
We're going to do this
weight cut correctly, and
he's got it down to the day,
you know, like it's six days to lose. He
think he was one 71 is that, is that the,
I was wondering what it,
what did he start at?
Is it one 71 so I think
he's got to lose 16 pounds.
What's crazy is when Max was on my show,
I was talking to him a little bit off it
and this is on record, on that spilled.
Anything that he didn't say,
but he just goes with the injury.
Jesus credit embedded I think is
better than that. UFC, not UFC,
the HBO ones. I think it's been
24 seven yeah. How dare you?
I think it's better than one four seven
when there's a big fight. Yeah. You know,
Washington generals or
blah. I think, well,
I think in general they're better
because they do more of it.
But a 24 seven they're like, they're
good. They're fucking good. Very good.
Liev Shriver. Oh, I'd love that
Bro. Watch her work on that guy.
But I like these better. Remember
I only cat leaves driver. Yeah.
Was like night here with angle, but
it was nowhere near as it say. Yeah.
It was horrible because there's
almost no narration, right?
Yeah. It's almost just, it tells a story.
Footage. I want to see the footage.
I would have liked the video of
when they called Max with the fight,
cause from what I heard, he goes, it
could be that stuff's got in the world.
Fuck yeah, let's go. What?
Just insane. I was like,
why don't they have a video of that? But
no one knew. I don't think they knew,
you know, to, to turn the video on.
I don't think Max knew
whether they were calling him.
Amazing video of him
isn't actually if he wins.
This is my thing with
Max is I think could be,
is the toughest fight in
the world on six days.
Notice I'd rather fight anybody else
in the world and could be one six days
because this style, just his tenacity.
But with, for Max win, lose or draw,
whatever happened Saturday night,
if you don't respect.
And like him even more after this,
you're a moron, you're a physician.
Champions on a bra and like
Max Holloway's on that would be willing
to take this fight on six days notice.
And also I should say coming
off of a broken foot. Correct.
So he had a pull out of a fight with
a broken foot with Frankie Edgar.
What's just happened? So I mean, how
healed dizzy. And like it said on my show,
he was saying, you know, I've, I've been
doing some Jujitsu in the swing of things.
For me it's good because I haven't
been balls deep into training.
I've been just been a little
just to get a light workout,
but it gives me time with my
family. And he goes, which NGOs,
you know this in camp, you're present but
you're not, which is true. And he goes,
you know, so I'm going through it.
I'm, I'm with my son in the family.
But I'm thinking about something else.
He goes,
so this has been good for me to really
focus on my family. That was what,
two weeks ago? Three weeks ago. Wow.
So then pay him you're fighting.
Could be even the reason why he wants
to fight Khabib is cause he thinks could
be the best pound for pound
fighter in the world. Yeah.
And which is nuts because you know
when you look at, it could be resume.
It's good. It's, it's, it's,
it doesn't blow your hair back.
He's 25 and Oh for God's sake it's good.
But it's not like all this crazy,
you know, big names on his rag. Right.
But you talked, I was just in San Jose.
John Fitch goes, dude, and this is John
Fitch. Yeah. It could be, you know,
welterweight goat. He's fucking not
cope. He's got damn good. He goes,
I've never seen anyone my
lifetime like could be. He goes,
I fought GSP in his prime. He would
beat him. That's how good he is.
DC said he's the pound for pound.
Greatest fighters ever seen DC
said that he had fights with them.
Like dcs was the heavyweight Strikeforce
champion. He said, he goes, dude,
we go to war.
We go to war war.
Like imagine that [inaudible] Gar Willa,
he's jacked.
I mean DC's got some body fat on him.
He's strong as a fucking ox.
You see soak at downtown.
So fun. It's fun to watch.
When DC throws Josh Barnett through
the air, when they fought Strikeforce,
she just go,
Jesus [inaudible] fight was offensive.
That goddamn American,
it was offensive.
He ragdolled Hendo and couldn't be a
cooler guy like the nicest guy ever.
You see might be the
nicest fighter of all time.
One of my favorite people here in Max,
they're up there.
I love him for nicest fires. I don't know
Max as well as I would know. Do you see,
because I've done so many shows with them,
but for DC as good as he is to
say that him and Khabib go to war.
I'm like, that's crazy to Josh
Thompson is the cap ne Kay said,
you know Ed Ruth Penn state and
three time national champion freak.
Just start doing MMA main belt
door, complete freak wrestling. He,
I was in San Jose and he, yeah,
I did a show with him and I go,
what were you doing? He goes,
I just came from practice.
Could be second class practice and
go, what was he doing? He goes, oh,
just straight wrestling. I said, who is
your son? He was Ed Ruth. I go, oh my God,
the Penn state like legend. He goes, yeah
man, how's that go down? And he's like,
the only one of them's gone down
and it could be like, what Ruth?
And he goes, oh, he goes, bro it,
I've never seen anything like it.
So there's just this legend of five.
They skipped when they tell me that,
it scares me like Jesus.
Well, what do we get to see it in
action? When you saw the Barboza fight,
he's walking towards him like a Zombie
gets a hold of them. And just rag dolls.
I'm just rag dolls.
But this is what's great about this
fight and that's what makes our sport so
specialists. Yeah, I'm super bummed.
I've been in deep depression
because Ferguson fell out,
and we've talked about this off here,
but our sports so special because
what Max Holloway has the chance to do
Saturday night, if he can beat him,
if he can somehow pull that out.
There's nothing like in professional
sports, there's nothing like it.
If Lebron goes out, the team still goes
on. It's whatever. If Tom Brady gets hurt,
it sucked. But they still
play here. You know man,
Max has a huge chance now are the
odds stacked against him? Good God.
Are they ever there couldn't be
a worst matchup for him, but it,
what's the one Achilles heel
if there is one for Khabib,
a guy who can strike going backwards.
Max Salaries Pretty fucking good
at going backwards. Yeah, it's,
it's a fascinating fight.
If there was no controversy,
if it wasn't like six day
time period for and all,
it's kind of cool. Do you don't
have to fight. It's been like,
that was a Nate when Nate
took on Connor and the first,
here's the difference though.
Nate's the bigger guy, right?
Nate and the bigger guy, the more seasoned
guy there. So for Nate, it's like, yeah,
it was short notice, but that's a
rough matchup for Connor. Connor.
It should be an underdog in that fight.
They wouldn't find the same weight class.
So that makes a little more sense.
But wait a minute. They do Nate.
Nate fights in 55 uh, before
that though, he's fighting
that 70, right? Oh No, no, no.
He only fought three times at seven.
But he saw that seventies the point he
fired a college never fought at 70. Right.
But if con when Carter fought him
at 70, that was Saturday. Yeah.
[inaudible] 70 pounder.
Right. But I mean, Nate,
when he fought 70 it didn't go
well. I mean, who did he fight?
He fought Rory Macdonald. 70
tough. Who else did he fight?
We will see if I had 70 his fights
at 70 I think wasn't great at, no,
he didn't lose all of them. Wasn't great
one. Yeah, it wasn't great at 70 house.
But the thing is, he's the bigger
man. He's a, he's a much bigger guy.
But if they agreed to fight at one 55
and he would make the one 55 weight,
100% yes.
It's like there was all this talk about
him being so much bigger than Conor. Oh,
he's bigger for sure. It's taller.
He's taller, he's a pizza maker.
He's a bigger guy.
It's around heavier when he gets heavier,
but when they fight at
55 he makes that weight.
And Connor makes that weight tough too.
They both struggled to make one 55 it's
a much easier cut for counter at 55 it's
not the hardest cut.
But when you look at the difference
between how he looks physically when he
fought Nate at one 70 and how he looks
when he's, you know, one 45 he was awful.
I was going to say he's on down one week
one 45 Nate could nav. I mean there's,
there's no show me could've made it
intimate fighter when he was killed a leg
off.
You don't have to like real list.
He's not making five very thin
during the ultimate fighter days.
Remember we fight fighter,
right?
So you have to make weight
basically three times in a row. Why?
Just think he filled in too.
I mean he was really young back then.
100% but you have to
maintain a lower weight.
That's the closest fight to it though.
I agree that fight,
the same kind of balls that nade
has is like what? What it, but Max,
the difference is that like Max has
taken on a guy that everybody's avoiding.
No one's been able to
solve the riddle of Khabib.
No one's even ever even put them in
jeopardy like he's like a Johnson hit him.
But that really wasn't
what was going a bit.
We were talking about that the other day.
Who knows what was going on in that fight
because that was a fight where he had
the same issue cutting weight that
he did when he had to pull out of the
Ferguson fight where his body shut down.
So who knows?
He had that same issue with the Michael j.
He might've been severely compromised in
that fight even though he beat the fuck
out of. Agree. The difference between
Mcgregor and Diaz is the both.
Keeping on the feet really, right? Yeah.
He has a phenomenal boxer comes
phenomenal striker, Max Holloway.
Phenomenal striker could be
phenomenal grappler. So it's a,
it's even more of a task because could
is not going to sit there and strike with
him. That's your one way to win. Cool.
I'm the best grappler on earth. Yeah.
He'll entertain it for a little bit,
but if you, if you want you down,
there's literally no
one in the world from,
I'll say one 55 to one 70 he's not
going to take them. I want to see,
I really want to see him in some
straight grappling competition to,
you're hearing this, hearing that about
how amazing he is in the training room.
I'll take it from a guy
like DC. I know, and and,
and Fitch and you're talking about in
the hall, pioneers of the sport animals.
I want to see him against Woodley 70 I
think 70 is his natural way. Plus, yeah,
I think he'd probably be a lot healthier.
Imagine that.
Imagine being stronger and healthcare.
It Woodley and Khabib. Jesus. What?
But Woodley's at different thing, man.
You, you miss. You, you fuck up and you,
you leave yourself in a position to get
hit with one of those nuclear bombs.
Oh knock you out.
Woodley could put people to sleep and
he can grab was acid rap his ass off,
hard to take down and puts
people to sleep with one shot.
I don't think woody gets his due and I
think the best evidence is the two fights
that people point to where they say that
like Woodley should have done better.
Those are the Thompson fights.
The end of my fight, my fight.
But Maya never got hurt like he,
he hit my a bunch of times but it
was uneventful cause he was hurt.
Woodley was her early in the
first round with the shoulder.
He fucked his shoulder up.
Mile the, we should fight my,
if you don't want to go to the ground
100% but my point is in those two fights
with Thompson Woodley was
the one who hurt Thompson.
He hurt him that bad in both fights.
Almost stopped him in both fights. Yeah.
I don't see them ever fight again.
But I hear you. Great flood. Yeah,
I'll pass hard pass. It was a
crazy UFC 200 card that was on it.
I wouldn't be mad. I mean he's one of
the dough as a main event. I get it.
I get it. I like when people
twice. Wow, cool. Yeah. No,
that's a super calm kid.
Upset, upset though.
They're just not good dance part and
the same thing. If they just said no,
this time it's going to be different.
I'm going to war. I'm going to call her,
fuck you.
And then two rounds and you like
bastard is circling each other.
That's like Dana on Ferguson and Khabib.
He's like, that fights never happened.
A fifth time not happening. I'm
like, I get it. I get it man.
It's such a bummer though.
Let's talk business like,
I don't know how many paper
views this was going to do,
but for the hardcore fans,
this was a big one.
This was a big one because this is the
first time Khabib is finding a guy that's
super versatile that can fight. Standing
up, can knock you out with one shot.
Tough is fuck has incredible endurance
and can grab off his back and the most
dangerous guy could be will ever face.
Yeah.
Tony Ferguson has the perfect style to
test what was so we could really find out
where it could be exact cause we know
we're Tony's at we and we kind of know
where could bebes at,
do we? We kind of do.
We said the Barboza fight in my opinion
was the best example of it. Dos Anjos.
Dot. Los Angeles was great. It's
old school dos Anjos, that's a dose.
Angeles also compromise to
make one 55 right dose Angeles.
They want 70 different animal.
That's a different fucking animal.
That's a totally different piece.
And I think dos Anjos is one of those
guys where you point to a perfect example
of a guy whose body just was not allowing
him to compete at one 55 he's an,
he's a fucking animal in his mind. I mean
he, no one works harder than that guy.
You've seen that guy trained, but
yes, I have you seen in person, right?
This monster.
However,
how about he's fighting Colby Covington
in Brazil and Brazil. Troy that Colby,
good luck. Call me. Good God.
Security security to
super hard to take down.
Real hard to take down and pour rootle
leg kicks and I don't know. He said,
well I fucking what? 90 minute but
video he's been doing every day,
but his legs are gigantic.
Grumpy,
romp that Brazilian shit
or on of his chest. He,
I don't know what squats,
front squats, dude,
I don't know what kind
of crazy shit he's doing.
I know he did some training
in the past a lot with nick.
Curse on at a speed of sport. Nick
helped him quite a bit. Nicks,
you know that Marvin Marinovich a disciple
and he does all that crazy shit that
Marv had. Bj doing. He was doing, he's
got a ton of videos online though.
Is he working with Perello? Jason
Parillo? Yeah. I don't know.
Is they still Sanchez and PR?
I got to think Ese. I remember,
I remember seeing him at the Ruca.
Jason Parillo the greatest coach of all.
Like he's like, you're having
problems with your career, come here.
And just being cyborg. I mean just
these monsters and you know what?
Good Dude,
great gun and doesn't want the spotlight.
You doesn't want to be out on camera.
Doesn't want anything done.
When I was telling him, I think he's
doing a great job, dude. Shakes your hand.
Looks you in the eye. Like he's right
there. He's right there. Thank you.
He's like write to anyone won't
work with just tenure either,
which is what I like.
I like what he did with Bisping help
Bisbing a lot became world champion. Yeah.
I mean he's, he's a fucking great code.
Back to Khabib. You know who I think,
and I'm not just saying this
because he's my boy of known for it,
but you knew who I think
could be his Achilles heel.
Who matches up better with them than
anyone who everyone's overlooking.
Brian Ortega. Ooh, that's a good point.
Brian would take is a big dude at 55 easy
weight cut for him and let him on the
ground on the ground. He's
the most dangerous guy in
the world right now. Yeah,
I think so too. I think the way he locks
up submissions, it's very different.
It's like if everybody else is hitting
it at a seven or an eight or take is
hitting a 10 where you watch and you go,
oh,
that's different and you haven't seen it.
So for could be who he's,
how long he's grappled fricking
grizzly bears since he was four.
He and he's seen Sabo, he seen black
belt Jujitsu, he's seen all this stuff.
You're not going to catch
them with Ortega take,
it's a little different and he actually
encourages you to go with the ground and
he's, he's dangerous on his feet,
but on the grounds where he thrives,
isn't it funny how that thing about going
to the ground, what does a bride says?
Tag wrote for the record.
Dana called me yesterday to see if I
had stepping against Khabib since Max
hadn't responded yet.
I said yes.
Eventually Max Supply and
Gay Dana gave him the fight.
If all goes according to plan, I'll get
my turn at both of them. Whoo. To Phnom,
no fight, fire. But just
stylistically I own it. And if
I'm could be, could be goes,
why would I fight our taste?
Phenomenal fighter.
But he didn't have a belt in a big name
and it's the most dangerous site form I
think. And it's, it's also mean or tag,
it became a much bigger star
with the Frankie Edgar knockout,
much bigger star but is a ways to go.
Yeah.
Max Holloway is one of the
best fighters on the planet.
That's a really interesting fight.
Tor or take has got,
there's something about his Jujitsu man.
It's like it's on,
it just ramped up and
sharpened down to like such a,
just a razor's edge man.
When he grabs a hold of stuff you like,
you have very little room to get out,
you know,
and he sets it up from the clinch and
it's a very unconventional and the head
snap switch or like Tony Ferguson and
the dark jokes where he scene, you know,
snap city. However, why I wanted
to see him. This Ferguson,
Khabib fight with the snap city is
like Josh Thomson Fitch or like, oh no,
we've never seen could be because his
neck snapped down ever that it's for him.
It's a pride thing. Grown up where he
grew up there. No one snaps his neck down.
He'd known snapping them down.
It doesn't work.
Well that's Tony Steam.
They go watch, watch.
No one's ever snap at his neck down.
Avar wow. Yeah. That's so crazy.
I've never seen him lose around like why?
What are we doing?
These goddamn legends is people like
this and I'm drinking the Koolaid.
I'm drinking it too. I'm so
into this coalition. Well,
wear that hat Saturday night. So
yeah. Damn. I'm, I'm fascinated.
I'm fascinated by this fight.
I'm always fascinated when could be fights
because you're always wondering like,
what's the first guy that's going to be
able to give him something different?
See, I look at it different.
I look at like, all right,
I hear all this crazy talk about could
be, let's see it. Like, I wanna see,
I wanna see that pound for
pound greatness out of them.
Let me get it when you don't, you think
you saw it in the Barboza fighting? No.
I think Barboza is one dimensional.
I think, uh, I think we did see,
and I think people are taken for granted
how good could be both a grappler is,
cause you talked to Frankie
talked to Eddie Alvarez. I go,
how hard is it take down Barboza they go,
oh,
it's damn near impossible and training.
Like we don't get them down very easily
and they're bad asses. Right? So you'll,
what could be did we didn't
think he was gonna be able to do.
And if you look at that third
round with Barboza is like,
he gets taken down and he's like kind
of cage crawl and you look at his face,
he looks like,
get me the fuck out of here.
Like there's sheer panic and that's the
difference during could beam and the
rest of these fighters.
That's why it's the worst of fight them
on short notice because it's not going
to be fast. You know, it's not going
to be fun for you. It's a smashing it.
I feel like the brightening, we've seen
the pound for pound greatness in him,
like the potential for it, but we need to
see him against pound for pound greats.
Well that's how you get get there.
But show up Connor Aldo. Right,
right. That quick knockout
or DC Gustin Jon Jones, DC,
like there are certain times in your
career where you have the signature wins.
He doesn't have a
signature win. Right. Well,
I think the Barboza is
as close as you can get,
but Barbara was his lost to
a few guys. He lost it. Tony.
He got dark choked and
plus cowboy. Yup. Yup.
But he's also very one dimensional.
Yeah. Phenomenal on the ground.
He's a good anti wrestler. His striking
is phenomenal, but overall package.
Yeah. And that, that is
the difference, right.
Is the really good guys always
threatened takedowns always threatened
submissions.
He just doesn't do that.
He stands up and he's a
specialist standup, but I mean,
standup is wicked and he's got some of
the best stand up in the world for sure.
Uh, in MMA. I mean Barboza
so fast to such a wonder boy.
Barboza the write up there during until,
yeah,
Darren till in Wonderboy is
going to be a mother fucker.
How about wonder boy?
I saw a quote coming in here we goes,
who's been not that impressive?
Dare until who is he? I'm like,
did you learn nothing from the cowboy
fight? Even I learned from that.
I talked to you. I was like,
man, why would cowboy take this?
I don't really know who Darren till is.
And then my inbox just flooded with shit
and even did until went off on me and I
look at my like, oh my God, this
guy's a monster. He's an animal,
doesn't have a gorilla
tattoo or something. Does he?
He's got gorillas all over is like uses
it and his screen name and Twitter. Well,
he's a gorilla. He's a girl ever pool
group. Gorilla is a bad motherfucker.
Wonderboy who's rehabbing is thumps and
it's just like, alright, if you want this,
and then what happens if one,
let's say Wonderboy were to win,
which I don't think he is unfortunately.
Let's say I don't you think I'm on the
sales till you get them? I just, yeah,
I think there's this kind of Darren till
decried a little bit right now. Ron,
hard Dick Riding on Khabib till there's
a few guys DC always Conroy's always
Brian or Tayga. I did ride
mighty mouse for sure. Yeah,
you do dick ride that guy.
I think he's been that way forever.
I think he's the best. I mean, that's
fair. He needs a guy is a challenge him.
Is He fighting? So Hutto again. Who I
love so who don't, but it's like that.
Do you guys hate fucking money?
That shit's ridiculous. I mean,
so who knows a beast? No doubt about
it. And I love what, so who did, uh,
against uh, Wilson Hayes. I was like,
Holy Shit. There's like a different,
so who does it looks like a karate
champion. Yeah, I get all that.
Did you see what mighty mouse did? He
went right through him. Oh, you, oh,
you're black belt. Cool. Jewish on bar and
bar. And what he did to, so who does, oh,
you like to clinch. Check these out to
take all the Olympics. That's very cool.
Check this knee. Ouncer needs the
body as fat. I grabbed him once.
Just joking around. Plan. He hit me
in the body with a niece so fast.
He was confusing. It was a confused.
Where'd that come from? Like I go, I go,
I got ya. He turns out, hey man,
that's not supposed to go that quick
like this supposed to be. I see you move.
I get to think that this might come my
way. Here it is. No, it was already there.
I realized he was doing it.
He's so fucking fast. Why did,
do we know why the TJ fights aren't
going down? Dude? I don't know,
but that one bums me
out. That one. That is a,
that's a fucking gigantic super fight.
Like why wouldn't he take that fight?
Well, first of all, mighty mouse right
now is rehabbing a shoulder surgery,
so it's going to be a while. He was
doing those, you know that both thing.
They do that flexy thing.
He was doing some of those exercises
the other day on Instagram.
I'm looking at him like, okay,
that's a guy that's got like,
he's got some scar tissue to work out.
Like that's not, that's not healed up.
Did he get surgery or no?
Yeah,
he got surgery so he's out for a little
bit and Tj probably doesn't want to wait.
I don't know if that's what the case is.
I don't know what the case is.
You know I mean shoulder surgery, six
months. I mean, so you wait three months,
then you have a three month camp,
you know?
I mean if they wouldn't announce it yet,
right. No, I mean I don't even know.
You can't even say that
because teachers have to go on,
you might not be able to go if you,
Matt Hume and mighty mouse are about
as smart as it gets when it comes to
preparation.
So there's no way they would take that
fight of his shoulder wasn't 100% or any
fight and risk his legacy because he
loses that fight and was like told Ya and
they wouldn't go hard early to test it.
They would let it.
We'll look at Willie's been out a little
bit because of his shoulder. Yeah,
he was in here like right after he got it.
He said he's going to heal up quick.
Yeah. And he might PRP all that.
Yeah. He's going to do all the PRP. A,
you know this as much different therapies.
Cryo I'm sure it was probably still
takes a while even with all our advanced
stem cell, but not now.
He's forced to fight and I,
I see what the UFC is doing
where they do interim belt.
Tween Colbian dos Anjos
where the interim belt.
So now Woodley, you literally
have to fight the winner of this.
Do you have to fight them?
It's a very sneaky may have a belt.
What are you gonna do you want a
super fight? Nope. This guy's a belt.
I get both sides here.
If it stills Angeles,
Los Angeles Beats Colby dos Santos,
lightweight champion,
now welterweight champion.
But to me it takes me right.
Dos Anjos sitting there with
two belts on shoulders. I mean,
and then what do you do with Dan until
let's say he, for whatever reason,
walks through Wonderboy, which
is, you know, tough to do,
but to say walks through it, which would
lead, you know, struggled a little bit,
walks through them and one of boys,
the number one guy not there until jumps
up to number one or his dose central
work that way because the
ratings are fucking screwy, man.
Sometimes I see a guy who,
a guy and then the guy who he
beat is still ranked ahead of him.
They're a nightmare. All they
are, all the ratings do now.
It almost hurts if you're a guy like
Sean Shelby or Dana trying to make these
matchups cause guy who's at
fourth year, hey, wanting to
fight seven. He's like, no,
he's seven. I have nothing to gain
from that. Where before it was like,
he wants you to fight this guy. He's a
name, he's on some fight, win streak.
We don't know what ranking is,
but we know he's damn good. Right.
So you guys were more willing to
take it now they, nope, he's seven.
What I want a number one. Exactly right.
I need three, four, you know? Yeah,
that's weird. It hurts us. That's
also weird. Like the UFC could just,
did they just decide who's fighting?
I mean, it's the whole thing.
The business is so interesting because
it's like they decide who's fighting.
They decide who's champion. They decide,
Tony, you're not champion anymore.
I'm going to strip yet.
It's like put it, I fell.
I don't want this to happen. Fox
Studios, I just do, I twist my knee.
But he was working for the UFC when
he fell. I mean, he's doing his,
his obligations,
his press obligated.
It's very strange to strip them
of a belt when he never lost it.
And he the longest winning
streak and then and mean.
But also you has no belt can
because there's no belt can be,
was going to take the belt.
They're gonna make up a belt.
And then Connor has the belt at 55
so what do you do with that belt?
Well what they're planning on doing,
I believe,
and now they've kind of let the cat out
of the bag because they said it's going
to be for the world lightweight title.
They were going to strip Connor the
moment something happened like the moment
the fight started. That's when they
were going to trip Connor. Yeah,
because if they'd stripped him beforehand,
then what happens if Tony doesn't
make weight or something totally mix.
They with cope out of
Khabib doesn't make weight.
Then what the fuck do you check concern?
They didn't have nothing.
I mean you already stripped him.
We're going to give it back to him.
I'm going to give it back to him now.
If he wants to fight again now,
he's not the champ anymore.
The fuck kind of Shit is strange.
So they waited and the idea was to wait,
but now they're in a desperado situation.
Strange Desperado
that'll yet fucking April fool's.
April fool's day, it happens.
I didn't believe a God damn word of it.
Jimmy Smith's starts texting me. I'm like,
fuck that dude. I'm not falling
for it. Jamie texted me. I'm like,
I'm not falling for it. You texted me, you
go, Bro, it's April fools. I'm like, no.
But Dana, I sent dated, released
a video and he's listening.
I'm sure he likes a
good April fool's joke,
but what he likes more his money and
pay per view buys. You can't honey dick.
The fans are like psych. It's back
on. People are going to be pissed.
And that's a good point. I
didn't buy it. I still was like,
maybe it's just an elaborate PR scam.
I didn't even tweet about it
until the next day. I know.
I was tweeting about other shed.
People were like, what the fuck, Bro?
This is go down. You're not even tweeting
them out. And I'm like, I'm not, I'm not,
I'm not gonna do it. I'm, I check it. I
checked with you. And then I checked with,
uh, Josh Thompson who works closely
with, uh, could be, and then I,
so boom, there's my two main guys.
And I went, all right, Ariel,
that's all aerial tweet. I'm like,
God, he's like journalist. I'm a,
I'm an ass clown. He's a legit
journalist. Like he has the credibility.
So I went, Bro, is this really
goes, I would never joke
around like that. Brennan.
I'm like, he's right. Well, I went
straight to his Jujitsu coach.
I called Eddie, talked to
him on the phone. Yeah.
So an Eddie gave me the full
rundown of what happened with Tony.
It's like he saw somebody and
he turned to say hi to somebody,
didn't see some wires on the ground,
tripped over some wires
and just blew his shit out.
And Eddie was on the podcast yesterday
and Eddie was saying that Tony wanted to
fight or day before yesterday. Tony wanted
to fight. They wouldn't let him fight.
Yeah. His, his ligament is torn
LCL around the bone, which is rare,
which is hard to do. I don't want, where's
that one? Lateral, lateral, whatever.
Collateral Ligament, some shit.
Anyways. But do you think,
uh, it would, uh, if, if,
if it went tripping off that,
is that a freak accident or do you think
it would have went during the fight?
It's hard to say. Oh, I bet it was a
freak accident, right. To associate LCL.
I mean the way they said it, but first
of all with Dana said was very savage.
What'd he say? Dana said,
uh, he wears her sunglasses,
indoors doors that should happen to
everybody that wears sunglasses indoors.
That's the Larry David, the
light of your glory, David quote.
Cause there's only two types of
people that wear sunglasses indoors.
Blind people and assholes.
It's true. It's so true.
It's so weird thing man.
Especially at night,
like what are you doing so hard to see?
What does this, what are you doing?
I've seen a guy in a club
when I used to go to clubs,
he does his glasses on and
then people walk, laid,
lift them up to look around and put
it back down and you can't see shit.
The biggest tools where glass assist to
fights and wear sunglasses and they sit
there with her fucking sunglasses. Not
like, especially celebrities that do that.
It's like flurries do it. It's like
get it, get a grip however we meet.
That's like when you know you fucked up,
you got two famous,
you have to wear sunglasses at a
fight that sit in the front row.
It's Sunglass and your boys are
just like, no, I like it man. Yeah,
we're those indoors.
That makes complete sense.
It same if you were like a peacock coat
and your boys like, that's all good.
I'm gonna Start Doing podcasts.
Like that stresses me out for now.
That stresses me out. Sam. We did
a podcast like this. Did you say,
what did you say something to him like
what are we doing? And I put mine on,
I put mine on and we, we've done it before
with the sunglasses with NASA outfits.
That's hilarious. Deleted. Did our put,
did the fight and the kid with sunglasses.
I don't. I go, Bro, you got to
take the sunglasses off. He goes,
my future's too bright.
Oh fuck mine too.
And the calendars. Shit. I'll have my
sunglasses. Yeah. It's a weird thing.
Sunglasses. That's a hilarious quote by
Dana though. Yeah. Hilarious. Hilarious.
And especially considering how much money
he's losing on this. Can you imagine?
Can you imagine getting a call
that close and be like, what?
What keeps happening? It keeps
happening. It keeps happening.
Does it tap into this Mac
temps typing a bunch of times?
Just one limb and may God to like you
morons. I'm trying to do you a favor.
Who was the most recent
one where that happened?
Where cyborg stepped in last minute.
This close. Yeah, so the last one,
Cyborg stepped in. Who? Oh, that was Max
Holloway. Max Holloway. Frankie acres.
But then there was the Ferguson one with
Khabib where Khabib's liver shutdown.
They had to take him to the
fucking hospital. It was a bummer.
That was a bummer because this
happened a ton of times though.
It was the worst one.
Jon Jones do UFC 200 DC where the
right literally the day before.
You're like,
what?
But I would if that's better for
the UFC shitty business either way,
but is it better for the UFC because
people we've waste seen the hype or a
bought in and then like the next day like
what the f where's John like, oh yeah,
you didn't hear that.
Like,
does that help them more or does this
week at least app can promote a little bit
with Max Holloway,
you could promote a little bit with Max
Holloway and it's an interesting fight.
It's a very interesting fight.
Yeah.
There's a lot of those men that
happened to you. Like what?
Which one was the Jon Jones DC one.
UFC 200 and that,
what was the thing that John did? Which
one was that? Remember that the coq one B,
I think there was a coke when coke
was, he goes, this was dick pills.
You remember these? He was
like, Hey, we got strip up.
We had to pull them from the card
and then DC fight dash and Silva.
That's right on like [inaudible] Anderson
and then DC didn't winning fans that
cause he just kind of, yeah. Yeah. He just
waits. Fight. He just wrestled him in his,
whatever. It's still one the
front kicked him in the gut too.
And I think you heard him.
He has messed up. Yeah.
But it happens in sports. This, this is
what I think makes fighting so great.
So great.
Max has an opportunity that no one
else in the world in sports can have.
And then, you know, then look at Canelo
triple g. It's in, in combat sports.
This is what we deal with. Yeah. Canela
it's a biggest fight of the year.
Biggest fight ever wants to see the
rematch of the year and then tainted meat.
Do you buy the tainted
meat? Absolutely not, sir.
I've had many Tacos in Mexico
and I am not swell. Yeah,
but you're not getting tested for trace
amounts of Clenbuterol. You don't know.
Maybe I have to go and Snitch,
come to my house just for the fuck of it.
And just dripping. I'm still
in the testing protocol.
Interesting. No, I, yeah, maybe.
I don't know. But I would see some sort
of change. But even triple g's camp goes,
uh, last fight. He was on it. What
else is new now? Why didn't your book,
why do you think they said that?
He, I don't know. I'm sure. Listen,
I'm sure Gonad has been in there with
what? Over 500 people now. 400 people.
And you just said in his experience he
can tell who's on pds and who's not.
And he thought Canelo was,
do you buy that?
I do cause that a fighter as a fighter.
This guys I fought who I assumed were
okay, but what about Woodley Woodley?
He has tremendous genetic. He's always
been like that. Always been like that.
But so it was Kanella no you, you look
at it, he's gotten pretty swollen now.
He's getting older though.
So it could be that too.
He's just as you get older you but I'm
more size. Well the big one was Manny.
Manny was the one that everybody was
always accusing and man he was the first,
I mean Manny went up eight weight classes
and kept his knockout piece fighting
as a little boy and then just was like
crazy. I mean and kept the knockout power.
True. And most people thought
that man he was on ped. Correct.
And then they thought that that man had
got off p ds when he fought Juan Manuel
Marquez and he got starched. But there's
two, there's two side of the story there.
He got off PDS and also
found Jesus Christ.
So he stopped going to the Strip clubs.
He stopped hanging out with girls,
but he stopped having fun and then got
serious about Jesus and got knocked the
fuck out. Yeah, Jeannie saw Jesus
and that Jesus is like, listen,
if you want to be a savage, you got
to live like a savage. He's like,
I'm not even advising this man.
Do your thing.
Can I go take them steroids? It's
like, listen, I made steroids. Okay,
I'm Cara run God. That wheat grass
ain't going to help your son.
That's good for you, but you
need good, but you need this too.
It depends on what you are. I mean, if
you want to be 147 pound knockout artist,
but Marquez is no stranger to the,
uh, not just getting supplements. No,
no, no, no, no, no, no,
no, no, no. Well, his,
they had the same strength and
conditioning coach when Manny found Jesus,
his old strength and conditioning
coach went over to the doctor,
wet mat warm and Mel Marcus, he's always
on the dark state on the dark side.
That dude was always in the dark.
What was he going now? He blinks Alex.
Alex. Oh, Riza. Yes. Good call
brother. Yeah, he knows his shit, man.
He knows his shit and I don't know
whether or not he'd got anybody on ped,
so they're just blaming him.
He knows his shit is a strength and
conditioning coach. That guy's very,
very good. I would have worked
with them if I was sweating.
I saw the stuff that he was doing
with wine. My Mom Marquez, I was like,
this guy's,
he's super legit.
And he brings those guys up to
like modern levels are correct.
Not The old school shit. It's some
of the old school shit to this day.
I think chopping wood, that's all
legit man. Sledge hammers on tires.
I think it was good. And I agree.
I think it's good to add in.
I think dead lifts all that stuff.
But I think you mix that with the new wave
of technology. Now you got some, well,
what, what I was saying about nick curse
on and that Marvin Marinovich method,
it's all, it's playas man. Everything's
like junk box jumps and movement. Yeah,
left right. Left, right, left,
right. You know, curse on sits on.
Very interesting to me when I said like,
what do you think fighters are missing?
Most like strength condition wants to
that foot strength. That makes sense.
Totally makes sense.
You know who's,
who's been on that ball since God
since I've known him as Lauren Landau,
who I worked with in Denver and
now he just got the Gig as the,
he's the head condition coach
of the Denver Broncos. Wow.
But he was making us work out barefoot
for Avar even as football players.
Steve Maxwell was always on that too.
I was kettle bell workouts,
those guys who it's like,
oh, this is all new.
And then you talked to like a
Lauren or that Max will gather. Uh,
we've been doing this for like 20 years.
You guys are just now finding out about
it. Well, so many people, you know,
you see so many people working out with
like high thick ass running shoes that
are all spongy on the bottom. Yeah. It'd
be one of them. Yeah. A lot of people do.
But you're not training for a fight
right now? No. No. But if you were,
you tried to optimize
everything wouldn't you? Yeah,
I used to wear those five finger
to, I'd wear those to run, I'd
wear those on the track had,
were those during most of my stuff.
So now you just wear regular running
shoes for comfort, regular running shoes.
And then w I had a knee prompt,
I was putting so many miles on
it and now I'm on a bike. I got,
I got one of Pelotons so those are dope.
But it's, it's been good. Those uh,
it's good because it's, you could play
along and go along with the class. Yeah,
it's cool. I don't know if it's the answer
do every day, but I like you, I need,
I need to mix it up man. I'm getting,
I'm just bored as fuck with working out.
So Deco bike, those are dope. I want
to get one of those in the crib.
Got Our callbacks,
but I like to waking up cause my
Mondays and Tuesdays are a nightmare.
I have to be on set at 7:00 AM so I'm
waking up at like five just doing that
Pelton for an hour if that I'm
off. Oh, that's good. Yeah,
we're before I'd have to try and go
to the gym. I was missing my workouts.
It drives me nuts,
dude.
He helped to start the day with
a sweat and then I get going.
You know what kicked him on the
versaclimber. Those are a nightmare.
I went to the gym the other
day and I did 150 meter sprint.
At the end of the workout,
the trainer had me do 150 meter
sprint on their first climb.
I feel like passing out. Holy Shit. It's
hard. Holy Shit. When you get off man,
like you're barely older on before.
Yeah, but I haven't been doing it now.
I'm getting one in here now.
I May.
It might be the toughest thing as far
as cardio wise. Again, Loren Landow,
you still have even as football
players all the time, and I was like,
what the fuck are we doing
man? This is awful. Is by far.
He'd have these circuits and it always
end on that. I remember everyone,
if he's like, here's your
circuit, then you ended on versa.
Some of the best athletes in the
world, just like, oh my God, man,
what are we doing? Yeah, but
that's what they do with this.
This gym that I've been working at, he
likes you to do a circuit in the circuit.
You get on the versa climber
and you sprint and it's,
you know how much time
to get to 150 meters.
I've been doing a rose with my trainer.
Oh yeah, I do that too. I do wrote,
we get a thousand meter row and I'm like,
what's a good time?
So we looked up the top times.
I'm like,
I think I'm top 300 in the
world right now. A bit. You
know, I got to do some work.
There's a big,
yeah,
there's big difference between top 300
and then the top hundred. Yeah, but dude,
you're top 300 in the world with a
row. With a row. Yeah, look it up.
That's pretty fucking sweet.
It's all right. I mean,
it's a row machine and the top
85 million. I mean, the hold up,
you're the, hold on, hold on. Let's just,
I would that, that was the humble brag,
but let's just be serious here.
You're the,
you're the hardest kicker ever on
that Goddamn UFC machine. Well,
I call it the Francis Machine. Well, I,
there's a video of me doing 152 right.
Right now you only see the one that me
kicking it and with my jeans on and that
what got to one 35 stretchy jeans.
Yeah, barbell jeans. Basically. PDS.
PDS. Yeah. He's like sweatpants,
man. So I'm dude burned me,
burned me from the audience and he goes,
hey man,
how long did it take you to
paint on those genes? And I went,
oh my goodness sir,
you just scorched me.
Theo bunk did me dirty, brought weird
clown on each other. We'd call each other.
I said, you look like an extra
from the waterboy setting. He goes,
he goes, no, fuck. I'm like,
he goes, Bro, you like you,
you look like you work at Nordstrom's
rack and you're a mechanic. Like fuck.
He talking about. He's so good. He's
one thing, but that fucking pants man,
these pants are the shit.
These are different.
These right now I have on there similar,
they're called Mott and bow is a no,
those are good company. Yeah,
those are like legit jeans.
They'd like more feel like jeans where
the barbell jeans are like they look like
jeans to touch them and I go, hey,
what's going on here? Like sweat,
sweat pants on Sun. No, those are,
that's it. A good company to Jacob.
Just so bind you up a little bit more.
If you were trying to kick
somebody a little bit more.
So what did you do though?
Record setting. Kickup barbell jeans.
This is the, I did the record on.
This is the record one. That dos
Anjos rump. Let's see. You saw my,
he'll run in man.
My ass is way bigger.
A lot of people have been
complimenting me on it.
Nothing wrong with a night off like that.
Fat Belly though. I'm so fat right now.
You are not fat for me.
One 52
and what's the hardest?
Definitely fatter than I usually am.
I been cheating on my died way too much.
I hear you man sheet and wait. You my,
well, it's also, I can't,
there's certain things I can't do in
the gym right now and I got this man,
this dildo that I got here.
Yeah. This is for, uh, you know,
I've Golfer's elbow. I have this
tendonitis on Heather. Fuck Dude.
I've never had tendinitis before.
Have you ever had it? Yeah. Not Fun.
It takes forever. Forever.
Like way more than a muscle.
I got PRP, I got Regena
keen, I got stem cells.
I had a bunch of shots.
This, this Dildo I'm holding.
This helped me more than any of them.
I only did two weeks in two weeks.
Is things helping dry needling? It did
seem like it should have fixed everything.
What did the dry needling?
Oh yeah.
I had dry needling where
they used electricity and
these zapped it and they get
pollster to do nothing for me. It
didn't help. This helped. This is cheap.
You buy it on Amazon. It's called the
theraband. And what do you do with it?
And my friend Brian told me about this.
Callan, no, no, no. Brian from, um,
I'll give you his last name. He's
Vinny shoreman, his buddy from Fontana,
California. I think.
What does this his thing,
double Deuce Moitai tie is that his,
uh, his place here? Hold on. Sorry.
It's a great shirt by the
way. Jamie, Brian Doppler. Um,
and Brian is a great Moitai coach himself.
So when he do,
he had, he had a issue and he told
me this is the thing that fixed him.
You take it, you hold it out like
this right in front of you, right.
Then you twist, this is the arm that's
injured, the bottom arm. So you hold out,
you twist it,
what the other one,
and then you hold it straight and then
you let it untwist with this arm slowly.
And I've been doing this shit
all the time. I do it in my car,
I take it with me at home,
but I'm twisting the shit out of it and
then slowly untwisting it with my right
side to helping out too.
And it makes a big impact.
It makes a big impact because it's
strengthening it, strengthening this,
this little particular area,
but it's also getting a ton of blow.
You hold it like that,
like palm palm out and then twist
it right and now straightened out.
Now unwind it with this hand
with the injured hand. There
you go. Just like, yeah,
and you just do that slow and
I'll do that for like five,
10 minutes at time and then I'll
leave it alone. Game Combat,
game changer dude.
A lot better.
I mean obviously I've had a
lot of other shit done to it.
Like the Regena keen was like uh,
might help a month or so ago.
I'm sure it helped,
but that's good.
This once I started doing it almost
immediately within a few days.
Sorry, feeling better basics
then. Yeah, but I can't,
there's a lot of shit I can't do.
Like I can't do chin ups right now.
Have been able to do chin ups.
I could do rows,
but I can't go have you
then like 50 pounds.
Like everything has to be all about
preserving this little ligament and your
trainer knows that. Yeah. As
a new trainer? Yeah. Yeah.
As long as they're a good trade, as they
usually know how to adapt. But even here,
like when I'm training here,
he can't do it with so much shit I can do
and can't do anything on the rings. No,
no. I can throw straight punches. Yup.
No, no hooks, uppercuts. But it's getting,
it's getting much better just in two
weeks of using this fucking thing,
thinking about resting it maybe
just not doing Amy thing sir. Hmm.
That's how I got fat. Well you could,
you could still get up. You're crazy.
You're crazy. For me to put together
a diet, so I have to add to uh,
have a meal specialist, like delivering
my meals on that guy right now.
I'm usually really good at it,
but,
but one thing this has done
is ramped up my hill running.
So I've been doing just go, oh, are
you the type of dude though? Well,
we see you late night. You're always
posting. You know, you get that Fedex.
I would see when Ph vet,
I see when a at night when you
come home from the comedy store,
you always posting like
protein and veggies.
Are you really eating
that or are you like,
there's that and then you
have a Mcdonald's on the
side? I'm not saying Donald,
if I cheat, it's pasta have
to be lasting a whole pizza.
The other day I can give it up
Buller from, it was at a restaurant.
I worked with the, with the misses and
we ordered some other stuff and I said,
let's just get a pizza too. Right?
That's how it's done. She's like,
I'm not really into this. I'm like,
good for power. That's me, man.
I walked the whole pizza down eight,
that whole fucking,
I'm so disappointed in myself. I had
these, I had these meals. Man, I've,
I've been strict on it. When I'm
on the road it's the fucking tough.
Or when if I might get in the sleep.
My buddy crave sugar and carbs,
but I always say, and
I'm like, I just want,
and then one I just can't stop myself.
It's hard. And then last night my, my,
my son this pasta and of course I have
to try it and I'm gonna make sure it's
not poisoned.
I tried,
I'm like that's fucking way better than
my meal that they eat so I just fired up
some Tortellini.
It's hard.
It's also hard when you work hard
because I wore, I do a lot of things.
I'm always busy and it's like sometimes
it just want to go off with food.
Like that's my indulgence. That's the
one thing that I can get loose on men,
but most of the time I'm
very strict most of the time.
But it's been hard with this injury it
just because I thought it was going to be
healed by now so it's been frustrating.
The shit out of me.
There's certain things I want to do,
like I was on this heavy chin up kick
and heavy cleans and presses kick and
that's probably where I want to do it
because I felt some twinges instead of
just working on it and
like letting it heal up,
push through it for months.
That's the athlete in you.
That's the idiot in me for months. I
pushed it. But that's how it works.
When you're an athlete. I'm sure when
you're doing taekwondo or Jujitsu,
you get hurt. It's not like, oh, let
me take months off to make this bad.
It's none of that. Yeah, that,
and that's what Eddie said about Tony is
it like Tony when he gets hurt and he's
like, whatever I'm hurt, just
works around it. Whatever it is.
He doesn't stop working out
ever, ever. Yeah. But this is a,
an eyeopener for me. This, this theraband
thing is like always keep searching.
There's,
Oh,
and another thing I have is this other
thing that I put my fingers in this
rubber thing and I expand my fingers.
Right?
Because it's very difficult to expand.
You know, it's easy to contract,
you're always doing that.
But how much strength do you
have this way? Very little.
It's kind of shine. Do you ever
do it? Never. Never. Never.
But this rubber thing is
really good and I think I read,
I think it was Jim still panty,
who's a bodybuilder guy online.
He's got a bunch of supplements and
shit. And, uh, he's uh, he's also super,
super smart,
educated guy and he was recommending
that for people with tendonitis.
There's a lot of different things you
could do with bands. And this one,
this is the strongest ones they have
to shaking like a Dick Rubber Dick.
Do you think if you would've
went to a physio therapy,
they would have shown me all this stuff
before he injected yourself with all
these needles and stuff? I feel like that
a lot of it's physical maybe. Yeah. No,
you live, you learn. Most of them
were just saying ice it and rest.
It was like damn. Well the rest,
yes, but the rest of they want,
it's just not what I want to do.
Yeah.
Well it's also when your body is so used
to going hard and then going hard and
then your body like, okay, let's find
some problem to kill us. It's still,
it's like one, I'm lazy and that
respect, they feel like a bitch.
I know, but like I said, it's increased
my Ba donk. Donk. Yeah. That's funny.
Oh Man. Dude, the missus likes it
or she wants you to turn it down.
She's happy with it. No one likes the
flat ass. No one likes vanilla guy. Yeah,
no one.
That might be the worst thing.
You feel flat and I want to grow a small
deck girl wants a flat ass cause she
knows the guy is not going
anywhere. Correct. Yeah. Look,
look at him when it's flat.
Right.
Flat Ass fucking Shitty gene
loafers on Gucci Loafer.
Gucci loafers.
No socks gets tired.
Walking upstairs to imagine if all of
a sudden you had someone's flat ass and
then you had to like walk around
and you gotta to realize, Oh my God,
it's so hard to walk up hills.
How to get around,
get around flat out carrying up the
grocery bags up the stairs. That's out.
How about when you you,
I've seen it where it might one
of the easiest muscles to build.
Like there's some girls with flat asses.
Then you see them on Instagram.
These Instagram models who do like dead
lifts or something and then just over
time,
boom that ash grows like a tomato.
If they really are motivated, you can
get your ass to grow. Little Winnie,
little fucking little of that for sure.
There's a lot of that going on
with girls, man. When straws,
what we're talking about folks who
don't know what [inaudible] I wasn't
referring to Winnie the Pooh. I'm
talking about when Straw. Yeah.
A lot of those fitness girls are doing
steroids. They just do a little bit,
just a little bit, just a little
bit changes in Moran Bit. The jaw.
You look at the shoulders,
they get manly anytime to anytime counts.
He's a rip curl, use steroids and
literally everything. Steroids. My God.
Damn Bro. They keep that
shit though. They keep it.
That's what's weird to keep the manly
parts like the like they don't just keep
the muscles when they get off the shit.
If their face, it's still hard. Yeah.
They're structured like their face
structure's a little different.
As a lady who lives in my neighborhood,
she used to be a big Ole Miss Olympia and
see her walking around and it's weird.
She's, she's, she's looks like a man.
Not just in her face, but in her, her,
the way she carries herself
everything. Right. So like, you know,
I mean that sounds weird to say,
but there's a certain masculine
quality that the, the people,
the women that take massive
amounts of steroids, they develop.
They just develop the, they look
different. They will, they're wider. Yeah.
They don't look like they're gonna take
care of you. You know what I'm saying?
I don't, I'm not attracted to that. I
don't know. Listen to each is sweet.
Then I can be the best moms. What
I'm saying, it's like, it's not,
that's a, that's a, that's even
bad. But it's, but if you want that,
I'll suck those career women will be
mad at you. Like if you want a soft,
if you want a soft, sweet,
caring woman who likes to cut on,
it's going to be a good mom and it's
just sweet to be around kind of.
You mean the opposite of us? Yeah. Yeah.
But a lot of career women will
get mad at you. I know that goes,
that's what you want. You want a woman
to just can't take care of her salary.
You don't want it to be equal. No
badge. I Day Brian Callahan. I'm good.
I talked to a week, I'm Brian if I
wanted that. Well that equal stuff.
It's like equal. How? How's how? Oh,
you just can't date your equal. You Go,
you go date some cartoon like all right,
okay.
But they want to be a woman
in some respect. Right?
They don't want to be an equal,
they're not claiming they're
like is strong as you or
as funny as you or is know
as much about pussy.
Good. Where are you equal?
You're not an equal, you're a woman.
You're just, you're just an aggressive,
successful, powerful woman. But
cause you, but you're not a man.
Like if you were an equal,
I'd bigay correct.
We'd be two dudes like high five
and in Buttfuck it together. Yeah,
that's fine. That's cool. But like this
whole one, an equal like why do we have,
why are we playing math games?
Yeah. Why can't we just be chill?
Can we just like each other? Why don't
we have to be equal? What is that?
I don't know.
It's weird when I have run from it.
He so successful. Who? Who? Who Was it?
Who said there can only be one headshot
and household and we heard that.
That's good though. You can only
have one head shot in the household.
It's not going to work out if you
both want to be famous. You know,
George Harrison once said,
he said, um, he said,
all I need from a woman
is to be attracted to her.
Everything else I get from
a man, it's like, wow,
we're going to get shit for that. Well,
what did you say that I didn't say? No,
I would never say that. I would
not either. I would. I knew with,
I knew all that cool, equal,
equal, right. Equal pay,
the rent a bitch and I need someone who
calls me on my shit and yells at me all
the time and throws things
out and even makes fun of me.
Oh yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
That's what I want. That's exactly what
just comes home with a sick back then.
Rips a huge fart.
Like this female bodybuilder,
Candace Armstrong steroid habit made
her grow a penis and facial hair. Whoa,
that's she's a dude.
Well, sure. That's real.
She's on that Gold's gym.
Dial. What? See the Dick?
Come on. Whoa. Oh Wow. Yeah. See
she turned into a man. Oh Wow.
And the heavy Whitehead. That's
a giant white. So white must've.
They must've put makeup on her too.
How are they letting that Whitehead go?
That staff, why wouldn't they cover
that up to she's so jack later hands.
Oh my God. Look at her arms to she
should [inaudible]. That's a dude.
That's a dude. Come on. Is this a joke?
It was, might be a judge like criss angel.
She doesn't even look like Jack.
Yeah,
but w the sides of her hands
looks proportionate to like,
she doesn't look like a girl. Shit.
There's nothing feminine about that woman.
Look at her back. Holy Shit. Look
at those back picks. Same Person.
Oh sure. Oh my God. That's photo shoot.
That's a dude with a nice set of here.
Well,
some girls can be jacked and muscular,
but still look like a
woman like Felice Herrick.
Do you see Felice Herricks
she's fighting this bodied,
but you see the picture her do
a double biceps from the back.
Some pictures she did it.
The UFC press thing,
you're like Cha tractive young lady.
There's a few who are jacked.
He would attract. She's jacked,
but she's Jack like a woman. She Jack
like a woman who lifts weights. Yeah.
It doesn't look artificial. No.
This lady that we just saw. Yeah,
that's a good picture. But that's
just her looking fit. There's a,
there's a picture of her just Google,
like her image double bicep or
something like that. [inaudible]
they see it,
but she shreds city.
That's a shredded fit woman.
But there's,
that looks like a woman
like look at her arms.
It looks like a powerful
woman's arm who's in shape.
His balls as shit in shape is fuck.
But that other lady that didn't,
I didn't mean to shaping the county.
I understand. We get shit online.
She's a tank fire shop.
He said balls. Yeah,
we can't fire for your own thing. If they
fire you from showtime, it'll be like,
they use the force against themselves.
They'll just make you stronger.
I do see a lot of crazy shit though.
He could do that show on your own.
You can do all or anything like
that you could do on your own. Yeah.
I think it's great that you're on
showtime. It's a fun show too. Yeah.
What I like about it is you're
being you on that show. Yes,
I see you on that show. I'm like,
oh, they let him be himself.
Like you say about your silly
shit laughing. There's a
lot of cracking ops. Yeah,
I have fun. They let me do my
thing. The first one, it was like,
there's a lot of teleprompter and I was
like, God, that's really not my thing yet.
Let me go. And they listen to me.
That's the great thing about showtime.
They listened to me,
but the fans like, man,
this isn't why we listened to Brendan
to be another fricking sports show.
Like you gotta let them go. And then
literally they all were like, all right,
here you go, man. Here's your point. Do
what you want to do. I'm like, really?
But then they edit it so I don't
get in trouble like, oh my God,
which is why they're showtime and um,
what I do,
well that means this were we we talked
about the other day with Eve Edwards.
He was in here. That was,
that's one of those things like,
and I was saying when you talk as much
as we talk, we both, I talked too much.
You talk too much. We
talked too much. Yes.
When you talk too much shit
comes out of your mouth.
You guys step in some shit and then you're
scrambling and trying to like make it
make sense.
Joe and I can't,
I didn't listen to the podcast with these.
I like these,
we don't know each other that well.
The thing that bothers me about this is
I couldn't even tell you the point I was
trying to make as soon
as I give us $1 million.
Tell us the point you're
trying to make money. I forget.
I remember I'd Kevin Leon and then I
remember before that I was 20 minutes deep
into explain why,
think DC's the greatest of all time
as beside you as a commentator.
Why is the future of the sport?
And then before that show,
me and Brian were talking about
something with race and men and women and
somehow that entered my brain and I
have no animosity toward it this way.
It doesn't make sense.
I have no animosity towards UFC tonight.
Two of my favorite shows. I've worked
with Karen Bryant for over 10 years.
She's a good friend, Woodley
DC, Kenny Florence, get friend.
Brisbane's a good buddy. Uh, I don't know,
ease. I work with the team on UFC light.
I love those guys. I just had Jimmy Smith
in and on my show who works, you know,
there it does,
it makes zero sense.
And then I was in Saint Louis and I
started to get texts from so involved in
that show. I won't say their
name and he goes, hey man, uh,
some people are upset here about what
he said. And I'm like, what? I see,
I can even tell you what I said. And he
tells me like what? And then Chin goes,
hey man, I'm seeing online about some of
the stuff. He goes, should I edit it out?
No, we never do that again.
Don't edit. Let me deal with
it. Let me see what I say.
Cause that makes me look even worse.
If you cut it out,
it looks like I was saying something
that I wasn't meant to say. And uh,
then you know, ease was upset and then
me and Eve's texts back and forth again.
I don't know him.
Brian works with them a little bit
uncertain stuff for help or something like
that for shows where we've tried to do,
which is great.
Everyone should talk to Brian, you know,
if you're friends with them. And then, um,
I sent eva tech says number from a Brian
and I thought it was over squashed.
And then,
uh,
I was doing PR for my pull the belt show
in New York and someone brought it up.
I'm like, oh man. Again, I
went and I meant, no offense,
I come up with about 10 hours of content
a week. I can tell you what I say,
and I messed up. Um, whoever
had, uh, problems with it.
If it's Eve Edwards, um,
that's his own insecurities,
which is so stupid because I couldn't
tell you what he should be insecure about
it. That makes sense. And then as
soon as I get done that I interview,
I get texted, my brother is
this, he goes, you're an idiot.
You resurface that story.
I'm like, oh my God.
And so I texted him again and
then come down here, right.
And then I haven't listened
to it. And then, uh, you know,
I texted, he's like, dude,
I don't want to keep going through this.
I meant zero fence.
I've texted Karen Bryant, DC Woodley,
literally anyone that you'll see tonight,
I this business, especially in
entertainment, you notice better anyone.
It's impossible to be successful in
this business. It's a fucking monster.
I'm, I'm willing to help them out. I want
to help. You know what I'm saying? I,
I don't want to criticize people.
That's not what I do.
That's not what I signed up for this.
I just got caught on a path when
you started talking about, yeah,
and then one of the things that we do,
the best part about it is there's
no script. The best and the worst.
It's the worst because I could deal with
this. Sometimes he goes haywire. Yeah,
but it ain't go haywire.
My biggest issue is,
is whenever someone was hurt by my
words or are upset by something I said,
then I'm like, I again, I don't know Eve's
that well at all, but I lost sleep over.
I'm like, oh my God, what am I
doing? I have respect for him.
He's a pioneer at one 55 again,
I love all the people you've seen
tonight and I've watched the show all the
Goddamn time there.
My makes zero sense doc and you,
you tried to just make sense
of your words. It makes no
sense. I Apologize Steve.
It's, it's all good. I told him,
open door policy ones come on the
show we can talk about on there,
but I put my foot in my mouth and I hate
to tell you three and a half. And again,
I wish I could say it's not,
it's probably happening.
It's part of what makes it fun is that
you are really working without a filter.
Working without a net. You're just,
you're trying to have fun. So yeah,
I mean that's,
sometimes you just take some swings and
you miss things that I came to ball,
I was trying to hit. I came to tell you
I was taking swings at balls. I was,
even though it was hitting. So sometimes
that shit happens, but it happens.
Yeah. It's just one of
those things. I mean,
I've done it a hundred times
on this podcast, said some
shit and I'm, I was like,
what the fuck?
Can I even say that for?
I don't even know what
was going on in my mind.
And sometimes like when you're
trying to form a sentence,
like right now I'm trying to
form a sentence, right? Like,
sometimes while you're thinking about it,
you're like, this isn't going so good.
I know. Let me try to make
it sound better. All right,
let me try to see if I could rescue this
for the people that are listening and
make some sense.
And then it just makes it more clout
and more fun and it's hard for people to
fall. And you just like, God, I speak for
a living. Have you ever been on stage?
He was going through my set and I was,
I've been doing it so much lately.
I'll be in the middle of it and in my
mind on fast forward to already the next
bit. And I'm thinking about
that bit while I'm doing this.
One of you had done that or am I curious
about that? I know cause I'm not,
I'm not present. Don't do that. You
know what happened is I missed, I,
I skipped over a part that was new and
I thought it was gonna be a home run.
I skipped over it. Yeah. And I went back
and cause I record it. Right. And, um,
and I didn't realize I was doing the
moment. And I listen, I go, oh my God.
And I remember in my head
going, dude, you're here on
third. You're on first base.
You're looking at third already. You
Miss Second Pace. You're not even,
you're not even the moment.
That's hard because there's like a,
you never know how you should
think when you're on stage.
You're doing the bit and you're just
trying to perform the bit, right?
And if it's going well, then you start
thinking, okay, this is going well.
What am I going to lead into next?
But while you're still talking about
the original, you can't do that. I know.
Have you done that before though?
Yeah, no, I've definitely done it. You,
he was so disappointed in myself,
man. The big thing about comedy,
one of the big things is the audience has
to know that you are honestly thinking
about that subject.
Like even if you've talked about it a
hundred times when you're talking about it
that day in front of those
people they want, they,
they're hearing it for the first time.
They want you to be tuned into that
subject 100% and present. Yeah,
if you're not, they can sense it.
I know. I was so disappointed.
I've never done it before. And it
was, it was very strange too because,
and this is what hurts me about the eve
Edward situation is the guys I looked up
to yourself, Gary Shandling, like
they always help people, man.
You don't put anyone down.
They always help people.
And I don't have the same
platform you guys have,
but I like to think one day I will.
And I want to help people,
like you guys help people like the 60
degrees of separation and you look at all
the lives you've touched and
Garry Shandling and it's insane.
That's so inspirational to me. And I was
watching the Garry Shandling doc. I went,
man, that's so cool. And that's why
this Edwards situations fucking me up.
Cause I'm like, damn man, it's
not, I don't want to hurt anyone.
But with back to the comedy, I was so
excited because the Garry Shandling stuff,
when they, whenever they be channeling,
whenever they show comedy store stuff,
it's just,
I'm so into it man.
And he was talking about the comedy
store and I got super inspired and I was
like, let's do this. I'm never
been more pumped to hit the stage.
And then that happened. I
was so disappointed. You're,
you're still getting it.
I mean, think about like how
long you've been doing standup.
You'd been doing it less than two years.
Yeah.
This is a thing that's going to come up
and it's like, you know, it's like, uh,
like when you're, you know, you're
doing a certain move and you'll,
you'll leave yourself open for
an arm bar, you know, like,
how the fuck am I still doing that?
It's just,
you just have to submit it into your
head. It's a craft, you know what I mean?
You're, you're, you got a great work
ethic and you're a funny dude and you're,
you're very good at going off
the cuff and you're impulsive.
Like those are all great
qualities for comedy.
And you also doing the work and to
involved like you're listening to tapes,
you going over notes, you're doing
things. A lot of comics don't do,
cause a lot of comics are fucking lazy.
Like I've had conversations
with dudes and I'm like, Hey,
you did a fucking special last August
or last October and you're already
recording another one. And I'm like,
yeah I work. I fucking work that stuff.
Like I really work like I
get home from a comedy store,
I'll get home, it's 1230 at night. I'll
just sit in front of the fucking TV.
I'll put something on just for background
and I pull out the laptop and I start
writing when he come back from the
semester. Right. I started writing.
This time I go over, I go
over subjects, I'll put a,
I mean I sometimes I just have something
in the background just for a visual.
I just like to be stimulated
by something back.
Or sometimes I'll just sit by
myself at my desk, just nothing,
just nothing but that
fucking screen staring at it.
And when I do that every two or three
days I'll come up with a great line. Yup.
Every two or three days,
which is nuts. This is nuts,
which is a lot of work. Yeah.
And cause usually I'll come home,
you know, it's late at night,
I'll just take one little hit
to sit down and go over.
The idea is give those ideas their time.
You're the stuff you already have. Yeah.
Give those ideas their time.
And then maybe I have a new idea,
maybe of a new idea.
I'll flesh that out too.
And then I'll come back and look
at that again tomorrow night.
And then I have a whole list. I started
using this program called scrivener.
You've ever heard of scrivener on
the IPAD? Well you can use it on Mac.
Um, it'll work on an iPad or you
could use it on a windows too. Um,
I've been writing on windows. I write,
I liked that. I like actual paper,
uh, papers. Good. But I can't write
with my hands as fast as I can type
the phone version. Oh, they got a phone
version two. Is that for Android as well?
It says features for Ios. So what
exactly do you do with this Joe? Well,
this one is, this is different show the
cork board thing, the corkboard things.
Interesting. Um, what,
what they do is just see if you could
yeah, right there. Pull that up.
So they have it like this. This is like,
you could do it in different colors,
so you've got to have different,
each one of those things,
those little windows can be like a box.
So that's cool that you know that
that doesn't look like a cork board.
But sometimes you can,
you can change the background and shit
and it make it actually look like a cork
board.
But what it is is basically a board,
a bulletin board where you've taken an
index card and you put it up there and
the index card has the subject. That's
sweet. So I'll do that in real life too.
I have a real cork board and I put index
cards on the Cork Board. Like if, uh,
I'm doing like Vegan cat, I'll do
that bit, I'll put it up right there.
I can't wait for that line and I put
all these different things on the cork
board and then I'll look at them and
I'll pick one and then I'll do it.
It really, all these different
things, it's just about
making the time, making the,
putting the focus.
That's what you do and that's why you're
getting better so quick and all these
are the guys like what the fuck?
He's where we're doing an hour.
What the fuck is touring the road? He
works, he listens to those recordings.
Nobody listens to the recordings,
man.
They record them and they never
listened to them. I listen.
You gotta listen half too. It sucks to
hear your voice, right? It's not good.
They're the worst. That's what it
looks like. Oh, that's sweet man. Yeah,
so it's set up like that I like,
we're literally looks like,
so I have that on my laptop
and so I come home, I'll,
I'll pause to open a card and I'll pick
a subject and I'll start going and if
something else comes to
mind while I'm on that,
I'll just start talking about
that and just keep going.
It's all just about opening up the flood
gates. But really I just about giving,
giving everything more time, giving
everything more, more attention.
You're more focused, you know, and not
just skimming through it and over done.
What's good is a moment like this where
you fucked up and you were thinking
about one bit while you're
thinking about another,
now you know that that can happen.
Yeah. So that's like a lesson.
So just look at it as a good thing.
Like now you're set,
we'll be stronger because of that.
Yeah. Whenever I have a bad set,
the one good thing that it
says to me, it's like, okay,
I know how bad that feels.
I know where I went wrong.
I know it meets live comedy.
Man Live is crazy. It's just,
there's so many factors. It's so,
it's so loose and wild. It's just,
it's a crazy way to perform. You know?
And sometimes it doesn't go right, but
purest way to perform. Yeah. Yeah. I mean,
but it everyone I know like as far as
who's just the tip of the spear as French
comedy, like you bur deleah
there's one thing in common.
All you guys work, man. Gotta
work relentless. Constantly.
Got to be doing sets all the time.
You know, I'll do sets three,
four nights a week, um, at the, at
the least a good week. I'll do five,
like wrapping up from my special do
five and your specialty paper. Yeah.
Yeah. It, uh, Wilbur Boston. Yeah. Hell
yeah. 20th and 21st can't wait man.
Great. Is that room the
best? That room is crazy,
right for me that I highlight that one.
Like as far as lifetime achievements,
the Wilbur for a guy like me to sell it,
the Wilbert Wyatt and then you open and
we kept it a secret. I'm a chatty Cathy.
I was so proud of myself. That was
great. That was great. Good Beth man.
Well also that places like three
comedy clubs. Yes. It's like there.
Everyone's so close to you, even though
it's like 1100 people, 1200 people,
whatever it is.
They're stacked up so close to you.
It's like 500 on the bottom and then,
yeah.
You know it's like that in the fight world
is the poems. Yeah. When I thought Roy,
I was like, God, get off of me man.
Get out of town. I didn't like it.
The palms was great. Yeah, pumps is great.
They're not doing it anymore, right? No,
I think doesn't Lorenzo on the palms
now? Didn't they buy the palms? Yeah,
they did. Yeah. Hashtag
Bolan taken over. Yeah,
because the 27 casinos just isn't enough.
Like now let's keep it going. Yeah.
They own all those station casinos.
Those fuckers are everywhere
ever stayed at Olin, don't
I stayed at, they made me stay at that
Palestinian casino when I was getting,
before I went on the ultimate fighter,
the worst whole diversity
of my life. Really the
worst. The worst. Hands down.
I've never stayed in the worst hotel.
Now at the time is under construction,
is off the strip and of
course there's a hooker.
Been smacked around the other room.
I've told this story when I thought
I was going to be a captain.
Save a hoe and they get pulled out a gun.
I ran my underwear,
almost got kicked off the
ultimate fighter. I've told
this story on here, I think,
but that's power station casino
guy pulled a gun on you. Well, uh,
it was the night before, uh,
the ultimate fighter, right?
Sorry if you've already heard this.
It was the night for the ultimate fighter.
And they,
they put all the fighters in there and
they tell you the production staff goes,
do not leave this room.
If you leave this room,
you will be kicked off the
show before even begins.
You're not allowed to leave this room.
We're taking your phone.
Everything all you have is what you bring
in the house. Do not leave this room.
We'll bring you food, any
food you want, call down.
So I called had myself Nice Caesar Salad
Cause I was worried about my figure on
the ultimate fighter.
And the next day and uh,
I finally fall asleep and I hear this
arguing next door and the walls are paper
thin.
It's pallet station for God's sakes.
And I hear this guy in this girl arguing
on mine. It's waking me up. I'm like,
what the fuck?
And then she's just going off them and
I hear him slap the piss out of her.
Oh my card. And then there in, then I
hear, keep going and him hit her again.
I'm like, Aye man. So I'm like fuck this.
So I get up in my and under Roos to like
stop this because I just thought it was
a regular dude hitting a girl. I'm not
flying. I'm not cool with that man.
I get up and salt. I'd get on my door and
I hear another do go, Nah man, Nah man,
fuck this bitch. I'm going to shoot
her and I hear a gun clock, Amal. Uh,
definitely not going in there now.
Fuck that noise. And I'm like, God,
it's so quiet. I'm like, I
don't want him to hear me.
So I'm army calling my undies till the
door cause I'm afraid fucking gunfire.
It's going to go off. I get to my
door and I hear him go, hold up dog.
Hold up someone's next door. I'm
like, Oh shit. So you'll see that,
I'm sure there's video
of this power station.
Me just booking down the hallway
and I run to the casino and the,
the staff was like game when something,
they see me go run by and went to go get
security or underwear in my underwear
and I went to go get security. But all
the production staff saw me. They're like,
what the fuck is shop doing?
So I told her, I'm the k,
some girls are about to get shot next
door. I don't know what's going on.
But she was hip before. There's two dudes
in there and there's a lady in my room,
two 13 and like, all right, so you'll
show us. So I go up there, I'm watts,
it's there and then they just,
they go, go to your room.
But I'm in my room like look
and see what's going on.
And like a whole crew
of them go in fucking,
the girl starts defending
the dude attacks. Security.
They have to taste the dude,
the other guy who was going to shoot her,
they put in handcuffs and it's too large,
you know, black dudes. And I'm like,
I'm like fuck this.
So they bring me down the hallway
cause just in case he's going down,
they're bringing down the hallway,
but I'm like this with the
crew and I hear the guy go,
I see you white boy fucking snitch.
We'll be back and we'll ah, so that,
and I was like, can I get another room
that I like? No, there's no more rooms.
I'm like,
well they know where I'm staying,
man. I'm supposed to start a show
tomorrow. Like what this is. I mean,
what do you want us to do?
And like anything else.
And I had to stay and I got
zero zero winks of sleep.
Literally Zero Shiro Mesh.
I was so scared.
And that's more than when they knocked
as a gas. Yes, I'm here. I'm here.
Put me in the ultimate fighter house.
Yeah,
that guy got out of jail like quick
or guarantee. Oh for flapping up.
And she was a prostitute. I did not
know that, but still eat the pimp.
It was a pimp and a prostitute. And then
some John is in that. She's a woman.
She's a woman. She's my equal.
She's your equal. She's my equal.
I like how you thank you. Think
you're a feminist. Ah Man.
I swear I can turn this
into that as a joke.
That's just showing
your belly. I know, man.
This whole me too movement and it's,
I dunno.
It's a tricky situation. It is.
You think is going to bounce back.
I think the game's changed for forever.
I do. I think if you're a creep,
you can get sought out and found out.
However,
I think men in power and position and if
there's an attractive young lady in the
office or the studio,
there's,
this is always going to be the
dynamic because I think there's,
I think there's some attractive
young ladies out there who are like,
I don't have a problem with it. They did?
Yeah. Okay. Yeah. He's an attractive dude.
Just happens to have some power
and get me a movies whenever,
but actually liked him. You know, I'm not
being forced to do this. Well, there's,
there's a new option now. It's almost
like a new element is in the game.
Like if you're playing a game and then
all of a sudden someone found like a new
magic power,
you can end careers now.
If you are like a woman who was sexually
abused by a guy like Harvey Weinstein
used to just have to take it. Now you
have a new power, which is all about.
However,
some will take advantage of that power
and pull that card when it's not real and
dude's are losing their jobs. Like, whoa.
Yeah. There's people that are crazy, like,
look, that video that we were
watching before the podcast today,
or that lady was shot up youtube.
We're watching her, her online videos,
one of the worst youtube
videos I've ever seen.
She's fucking nuts and there's going to
be people like that and there's going to
be people like that that take advantage
of the me too movement. It's just,
it's just going to be,
I mean,
there's no way you can deny that there's
just a part of human nature that's with
anything though, right? Yeah.
But it's extremely ultimately where
it's going to shift as people have to be
nicer to each other and they can't
get away with shit like that.
And that's what Weinstein was
doing was nothing but crime.
It's just crime. He's a bad dude. He's a
bad dude and I'm glad that happened. Yeah,
I really am. I'm glad he got sought out
and he's scrutiny should be screwed.
You imagine being a chicken,
you have to suck that fat guy's Dick
nor to getting a movie. Hey Harvey,
he's there Amy way. You could just
look a little more attractive now.
Do you have to be so hideous?
There's nothing he can do at this point.
They would have to cut chunks of his
face and pull it back to kids. The money.
He's got this blah, blah. What about the
Diet? It's part of the whole thing, right?
It's like he's a glutton.
Would girls complain if you
look like Brad Pitt though?
Tony Hinchcliffe
has a bit. Oh, it doesn't want
to. I meant to tell you that my,
that I wasn't trying to screw us bit.
He doesn't use that as an example,
but it's a great bit.
You have to see it.
I don't want to even paraphrase you give
it away. No, no, no, no, you didn't.
It's a great bit. It actually involves
a Louis C. K it's a great, I love it.
It's really fucking funny.
Tony's brilliant.
I don't want to tell you where it
goes because it goes even crazier off.
Are you gonna see him tonight?
Yeah, he's at the store.
I'm at the store to him or heard or I
took them in the row with me this past
week. He's a killer and murderer and he
murdered them in Nashville. Murdered,
murdered them in Charlotte. A
lot of rednecks. Ackland Woo.
Tony had to go to war because
Gluck heckling Tony. I mean,
he's a writer for the roast for guts.
He's so witty. I fucked up one time.
It had let my shield down.
It's tell them I almost started crying
and comedy central and I just feel as
neck gets stiff and go
and ride when I'm like,
oh Harry coms.
And then he was like,
you almost cried and comedy central and
just roasted me for basically the rest
of the show. Why would you, why did
you almost cry on comedy central?
Just cause it's full circle for Gallic
Miyubi on county central doing stand up.
You know, it was just a special
night for me and I, and during this,
the story that I tell,
I talked about how I realize
that's never become UFC champ.
But being on comedy central and a Judd
Apatow is one of the books I've read when
a super,
you know,
concern and comedy and that day at App
Towel on my show that night did comedy
central,
I don't know,
it just hit me in that moment was on
stage at a strip club where they shoot it
and I don't know, I got
emotional. I was like,
do you need to get your shit together man?
You gotta get your shit together,
you're happy. I was happy.
I was emotional man.
And then he said that on the
pockets, feel close, Nico,
Nico, and I was like, oh fuck. He's like,
this isn't comedy central in 2010 and
just went nuts man. Well, Hey Ange,
because I've always had a thing with
comedy central. Whatever reason. Yeah.
For whatever it's going to
burn his side about them.
Like they didn't appreciate him.
He's a very underrated guy man.
Like right now he's still to this day,
he's right now, he's underrated. I agree.
And I think with your show and we
were, he was close I think. Got, yeah,
I mean he's a monster in our show.
Uh, the most underrated guy who I,
who should be selling out
theaters just feel Vaughn,
well we were talking about that
before. He has got, he hit a stride,
like within the last year,
he had a stride where he just like,
sometimes you'll see dudes,
they,
they're doing really well and then for
whatever reason they figure something out
and they take it to the next breakthrough.
And that's where Theo is right now.
He's just, he's a, and he's a unique
guy. Like his comedy is so unique.
Like it wouldn't work with anybody.
You don't see it anywhere else.
Sometimes I'll watch other
comedians and I'll go,
I can see how they came up with that
idea and I watched the, I'm like,
what the fuck? What the fuck you
smoking? Yeah. Where are you coming up?
Where were you raised?
How old?
How was that race?
By a fucking pack of
crocodiles in New Orleans.
Did you come up with this? Yeah, he's,
but even just hanging around with him
like offstage. He's just a weird dude.
Oh Bro. He pulled up oh, fun.
All of this dude yesterday.
And you just got a new car. I
don't, I won't say car. Nice
car. We'd like it. And uh,
he, I go, dude, you're killing
it man. That your car is. Yeah.
And he has some homosexual. Bumped
into the back. Can Be there.
Why is he a homosexual? He's like,
cause he was, I'm like, all right.
It just happened. Yeah, it's,
yeah. He's like just having a beat.
He's just so hilarious, man. Yeah,
there's a lot of good guys right now.
I was talking about,
uh,
watching that Garry Shandling stuff and
doing all the stuff Judd's document.
That's Judd Aptos documentary.
It's brilliant on his
process and stuff like that.
I got emotional on that as well.
I don't know if guys know this,
obviously I'm a complete bitch.
Uh,
but guess Shannon talks about how his
goal through going through everything was
to get on the tonight show and then he
does it and he walks backstage and kills
it. Right. But that was his goal and he
starts crying. He falls in a Bob Sag.
It's arms starts crying.
Right? Cause that was his goal.
But he's talking about the comedy store
and like he's talking about all the big
names there. And I was thinking, God,
that must've been cool to be involved
in that back then around all this big
names. I was talking to Brian, Brian
Goes, man, right now the comedy store,
some would argue it's better and we
think about it. I'm like, God, it is.
When you think about all the
fucking just legends, man,
you [inaudible] you got married and
got delete. I mean just, he keeps,
the list goes on and on and on.
I'm like, oh my God, it's bad, man.
It's a crazy time.
It's certainly the best time at the
store in terms of like the amount of time
that I've been there and I started
going there in [inaudible] 94.
It's a long time. It's a long ass time.
So in 24 years that I've been going there,
it's better now than ever before.
But when you think about it,
I mean obviously there's the seller in
New York, but as far as like on a Gig,
you go there on a Tuesday
night and Wednesday night.
I mean it's fricking, yeah,
they're very similar. They're
very similar in a way. Um, but,
and they're also very similar in that
they become big tourist traps to like
comedy store.
People take vacations for comedy,
they do comedy vacations
and they fly from Australia,
getting a lot of people from Australia.
But because you know, if you show up, uh,
you're going to see bill
burr, Rogan, Mark Marin,
and delete in the same
night almost every week.
One of us is there sounds at least unless
someone's on tour so it's off. Yeah.
Yeah. I ended a lot of
times you are on tour. Um,
but shit on any given Tuesday, Dave
Chappelle might stop it. Correct.
And then Chris Rock's rock,
maybe Louis don't make us come back there.
I hope he does.
I'm going to lose people like come on,
come on. You like people watching me beat
off. I mean this is worth shit. Come on.
Yeah. Just need someone to come up.
Someone has to do some much more horrible,
you know, calen shooting his
special I think in July. No,
he is through uh, some, I
forget who's who's shooting it,
but definitely not as buddy
works for ESPN this time.
So they're doing it right there.
He's doing it right time. But I,
they're going to go out there and try
and sell it, but he's ready to go.
I just hope it works out for count as
far as Netflix or showtime or somewhere.
You got to land somewhere. So is he going
to sell it and then bring it somewhere?
Is that the move? I think so. I don't
want to misquote Brian, but I'm,
I'm most positive,
but he has someone who I think he shot
girls and a bunch of other guys stuff
like it's someone who knows
what the hell they're doing.
Where's he going to do it? Uh, I think
Chicago. Ooh, Chicago was in July. Yeah.
That's a good spot. I'm
there for the UFC. June.
I'm doing the Chicago theater. June
7th or some shit. I love Chicago.
Ooh, what theater? That sounds. I did
Chicago theater. Chicago. Yeah. Yeah.
It's great. It's beautiful. Beautiful
place to, yeah. Chicago's awesome man.
Doesn't get enough love to weird place,
right? It does it not get enough love.
I feel like everyone
fucking loves Chicago there.
Pizza people won't shut up about
not really pizza. It's casserole.
It's the casserole. Correct. Yeah.
It's like a wrap calling that a Pete and
that's not a pizza. If you took large,
thick square, that would be a
casserole. Where I come from.
Have you ever hamburger and
you roll it up in a Tortilla?
Is that still a hamburger?
No. That's the Tortilla wrap.
That's a Burrito out proteins.
That's lettuce.
We call that out. Let us cargo. That's
a lettuce wrap. Chinese food place,
chicken, chicken wrapped.
See the differences the way
you make it. It's rolled up.
Look, you could take a piece of pizza
and flatten it out and fold it over,
over and over again,
and then it'll become folded pizza.
But if it starts out folded, what are you
selling me? It's a cal zone. You sell?
Yeah, he saw me a Goddamn cal zone. I love
the cows. I'm a fan. I'm a fan of cows.
And we had to get thick piece of pizza
from a basic casserole from Chicago
though. Yeah. Oh yes. You've
ever had though is very good.
The best you've ever had.
What did, where's the place we
go to? So what is it called?
Might've been, you know, who
makes a nice square piece?
Is King's in New York or have
you ever heard of a Ah, fuck.
Can we get the artichoke
pizza in New York?
Artichoke P it's called artichoke pizza
of Dev ripped pants to get in there.
No Sir. No Sir. People
kept telling me go there.
When I was in New York working
with showtime, I tried one slice,
you know Postmates, Postmates what
makes me fat now? Because I was posting,
I was at the, we'll get food
drops it off to your hotel room.
So I get done after a long day of
PR. I'm like, pizza would be great.
So I get two slices. I'm like, next time
like fuck, that was delicious. I see. No,
my God,
I fucking love handles and a chin.
Isn't it weird how like when you're tired,
you want carbs,
you want sugar and carbs. I wonder why.
I think it's like my willpower is weak.
Yeah.
Like I want like I never fuck with egg
mcmuffins or McGriddles mouse water.
But if I'm at the airport and
I'm on a fucking 7:00 AM flight,
you and I together. I never eat that shit.
You and I did together. It was so good.
For the brief moment. It was in my mouth.
Dude. You know what I was thinking?
I'm like, I'd love and be Grillo, but
I don't wanna be judged right now.
I'm going to wait to see if he goes to
that fucking weird place on the breakfast
spot on the right or is he getting going
to Mcdonald's when we started leaning
over there, I went and I want to be,
I wouldn't be mad at egg mcmuffin.
And you've looked at yes. Fuck
this. Let's do this. Yes. That's I.
Before I saw you guys, I thought
you would skip it. Oh, that's fine.
You want to be the guy who
pulls the trigger. You don't
wanna be judged, man. Yeah.
Most of the time I'm going to
not pull the trigger, but it's,
I feel like that's part of the thing.
It's like pulling that trigger every
now and then for the fuck of it.
I have some fun. Get chicken
and Waffles, go to Roscoe's,
go to Roscoe's in and her that mother
fucker with maple syrup and butter.
You just can't do it every day.
You can't do it every day,
but you do it one day a week. I agree.
Rock his, his Instagram, like those,
the pictures of him eating stacks
of cheat meal. Stacks of pancakes.
Definitely a photo shoot. Yeah, I
hear you. You Ain't you and all that.
So you think so? No, that's definitely
says a giant, you know one thing.
He eats all that shit. Yeah. He's
not a jerk. I mean he, he, he's,
he's on different supplements than I am.
We're about very similar size,
different supplements, different
supplements, supplements, Supplement pays,
and they come from south of the border.
I'm sure he's eating the same top case.
You ain't the same tacos
and you see, he came out to,
he has depression. I think
he's, it's football thing,
man. I think. Um, and then also
pro wrestling, all that slamming.
I like getting slammed around. This is
my take on this, I think. I mean you,
I'm sure you've dealt with depression,
right? You have bummer days,
Jamie Haft bummer days,
right? Shit happens.
I think there's a difference between
having a depression period in your life or
events in your life. And then, you know,
you're normally a happy dude and there's
people with severe depression who has
to be medicated. There's a scale.
Yeah. And he's not on that scale.
Now he's on that scale. Makes news cause
he goes, Hey, I've been sad to before.
Like yes,
rockets sat two different sad.
We're not talking all you should fear
depressed here. You know what I'm saying?
Right. He was talking about his mom was
Ari Shaffir depressed out. Mike Royko,
his mom walked into traffic and I'm,
and I'm not throwing shade at Ari.
We've talked about already having
depression before and he takes medication.
That's why I said that he doesn't anymore.
He's off medication better and he's
hilarious magically. Oh, weird. Yeah.
He's a phenomenal comic and successful
and he's not depressed. Also,
he got off Propecia cal calls portion.
I council taking Propecia like their
skittles and he's the happiest man I know.
Yeah.
But it's not necessarily like universal,
like some people can take penicillin
and then all of a problem.
Other people are allergic to it.
Yeah.
But I think it's a rare case where he'd
take Propecia and get depressed. Oh,
things are rare. If you look at the
studies and this come from countless,
I mean look, this is bro. Science
count just wants that hair,
wants to keep that hair so bad.
I'll do anything. You know what?
I think you should wear wig.
Oh, good fat one red one. Yes.
Just go crazy so I can yank it off
and I want to wear a wig so bad.
Like one of those, uh, those mesh
net ones, just like the little bronze
sprayed on looks almost looks
like a Pittsburgh Steeler helmet.
Ron Still doing that? Yeah,
kind of. Yeah, definitely.
You just got to let it go.
Question on this stuff.
Wouldn't you take from Kesha because
you're a little depressed because your
hair's falling out and if it didn't work,
you're going to stay correct.
A little depressed still fucks
with your Dick game? Yeah, maybe,
but I think what they're saying is
like suicidal depression that there's
something about the DHT inhibitor
dihydrotestosterone which is derivative of
testosterone is what causes
you to have your hair fallout.
The DHT inhibiting factors
in Propecia with some people,
it adds to it. It's a low percentage
though. I'm pretty sure might be
the study of this comes from,
which I just,
I googled it might've been more than
one study was in 2012 and it was only 61
men. Oh the only did 16 one
minute. How many got depressed,
said a 61 man who formerly use Propecia
who experienced more than three months
of sexual side effects and
had no history of depression.
Sexual problems of any sort.
Yeah. I don't know, Dude. If I'm losing
my hair and my Dick won't get up,
I'd be depressed too.
Yeah.
And then also you've got to figure like
what's happening in your love life.
If you're depressed and your Dick doesn't
work correct. But also philosophy,
if you had a nine to five job you hate
and that pay the bills and then you got
family drama,
11% of those, I guess 11% of the 61
which would be what? Six of them,
five or six had mild symptoms,
symptoms of depression.
28 had moderate and 36 had severe.
Whoa.
36 had severe.
Uh, I mean, so that's also then when
you're asking them, so it's like,
what does the study,
what was the study on the
second you say 61 people,
36% had severe depression.
Yes.
I found that 44% of the men had
experienced thoughts of suicide.
Hold on. I'm already hold
on. Jesus Christ be 4%
right. But that's what I'm also
going in. Like what were they,
did they just ask them like, have
you ever thought of it? Because
well, did they call, it's
the scientific study.
I'm sure there's some sort of
protocol they have to follow.
Let me understand this though.
66 people were randomly out of Iran.
How many people took it,
right? It says that the Journal of
Clinical Psych, psychiatric psychiatry,
I'm sorry, study included
61 men. That's what it,
so what does that like 28 dudes wanted
to kill themselves. That's fucking crazy.
Lay off that property show. Fuck that.
I'll just, I'll just don't ball Jude.
Ari said it like it was like almost
instant and he never put the two of them
together. Never put the
dough in depression with the,
with the suicidal thoughts like it,
all of it came like white when he got out.
I'm like,
you know,
he had had some issues in the past
with being depressed after breakups.
Normal shit, like everybody has,
but it wasn't, that's not the case.
I know want to kill me. Didn't, he
didn't, Ari's kind of a stoic dude.
He's very proud and he doesn't
talk a lot about stuff.
And so it took like me and him hanging
where he like wasn't talking and I was
like, okay, what's the matter? And
he's like, dude, it's just hard.
It's hard to just not kill myself. He
said that to you? And I went, what? Yeah,
so we were playing pool at my house and
I was like, what? I go, what's going on?
So he starts telling me,
um,
they put him on medication
and the medication didn't
work and then they put him
on another medication and then that
didn't work. And you know, he's with Sag,
it's sag after insurance, not the
best insurance. And he's like,
I don't know what to do.
Um, and I'm like, okay,
this is one of my best friends
and he's reaching out. I'm like,
[inaudible] and I don't have any
experience with that. I mean,
I've had some bomber moments in my life,
but I would never say that I
was depressed. I'm, I'm pretty,
pretty happy person depressed though, if
that bad moments. But I'm not a, I'm not,
I've never gone through depression.
I've never been down for like six months.
Couldn't get out of bed or
thought about suicide. No,
this is a scale of that shit.
He was,
he was on the dark end of the scale
and that's what he was thinking about
killing himself and trying to,
trying to not do it. So, um,
I just started making some
phone calls and I found, um,
my business manager found the
best psychiatrist, like you said,
like this guy is a wizard. He's dealt
with a bunch of my clients before. He's,
he's helped out a lot.
It was very expensive.
So I just paid for it. Not to say just
to life. I just told Paul, no, I mean,
I'm thinking about it that way. I mean
for Ari, he couldn't afford it at all.
So I always like, yeah, I'm sure a great
option. I can't afford this. You know,
he was getting by,
I'm winning poker tournaments and getting
the occasional commercial goes this
quite a few years ago. I want
to say like 2000, I dunno,
it was quite a few years ago,
2004 some shit like that. I Dunno,
I don't remember when it was,
but it was far enough back
where [inaudible] was really
struggling as a comedian.
I mean I used talked about this publicly,
the otherwise I wouldn't talk.
That's why I brought it up that
he's talked about it publicly.
I'm not airing dirty laundry out there.
I love art.
I mean,
I don't know what caused it.
If it was that I can't stop
coughing today. Like my,
my kids are sick as fuck my youngest
one and everyone gets it. Yeah.
Um, he just, his career wasn't
going well cause he was, you know,
it was just getting the ballroom really.
But I really think it was the show.
He don't you think he was the
perfect storm Propecia career?
Who knows what's going on with his girl
and then it's just this fucking perfect
storm. The Propecia is making you
even more depressed. Like, dude,
I'll think about killing myself. What the
fuck is going on right now? But anyway,
so he pulled out of it, got
off the prepuce show, um,
and then his career took the fuck
off. Right. He got on good medication,
whatever the medication,
his new psychiatrist got him on,
worked like a charm and like he
was better. And like couple months,
a couple months, he was like back
to Ari fucking around laughing.
Then oddly enough,
when it started working really well for
him, then his career started taking off.
Right. Of course. That's how it works. I'm
a standup started taking off his career,
started taking off,
he became happier,
got off the Propecia and then
weaned himself off the drugs.
And now he's good. Now he's good.
Yeah. That was great to see.
But he smokes a lot of weed
and I always wonder like,
how much of that is self
medicating? Yep. But it's okay,
but you smoke a ton of weed. It's not
a self medicating though, right? No,
I like it. I just like doing it then.
You're not a doctor. It makes you,
it makes you vulnerable. It makes you
think about shit. It makes you nervous,
like see,
like makes you pause and you don't just
take things for granted when you get
high, you start thinking about, my
problem is I smoked the other night.
I couldn't sleep in US
thinking about a lot of things.
And then I got this thought in my head,
cause some weird shit man.
Let's talk to uh, a thing I was
telling calendars that hate when my,
when I think like this,
but I was in San Jose and I saw this mom
with two homeless kids and the it and
um, I was at the store and I was going
to buy an expensive sweater and I felt so
guilty.
So when he got cash and gave this mom
bunch of cash and she started crying and
I'm like,
fuck man.
And there's like this weird guy around
the kids and the kid was about my son's
age, about two sitting there, this
little girl. And I thought, I thought,
I don't know why I had this random thought
once he grabbed her by the lake and
spiked on the ground. I don't
know why. I know, I know.
And then I didn't and I gave her the cash
felt better cause there's more people
around. I'm like, no one's
gonna let that happen to a kid.
And so that whole night fucked up at
it and its own reached out to him like,
dude, that's her side hustle. She does
that all the time. She's actually not,
we've seen her like raise
those kids on the street.
She gets picked up by her husband. It's
a shitty deal. So I'm like, all right,
that's fine. Then I smoked
weed. Right. And I'm,
I'm laying in bed and then I had this
visual so don't do that to my son.
I got to sleep. I felt sick to my
stomach. Yeah, I know. It's weird.
Like sometimes we'd,
I can think if I think about a bid,
I think that some are
good on this cool road.
But then if that creeps in there and
then it's like it get, it kept coming.
And it was so visual and I was like
sick to my stomach. I mean it's,
my son woke up at five and I fucking
beelined to his room and just like squeeze
the fuck em for the rest of the morning.
It's hard man.
Nobody knows how much you love a person,
how much you can love a person until you
have a kid. Correct. Once one says that,
everyone says that and I'm
like, okay, okay everyone.
I know you told me that Brian
till everyone told me this,
but then once you have a kid it's like,
I don't know man.
It's just a different animal where
now like when I see the shootings,
when I see, you know, the,
the, the nuclear war talk
with North Korea and Russia,
I think God and I see that a
lot of negativity on social
media, stuff like that.
I'm like,
the world is such a kind of a fucked
up place if you want to look into that
stuff. And when I have a kid, I
think about him like, God, man,
what's it going to be like when he's
like 16 or 18 like what kind of world is
going to be when he's 18 of
I think too hard about it.
That's when I'll get depressed. Well,
I think the world's going to be okay.
I mean for sure. I don't mean to bring
this spot just down a bummer. No,
but horrible things are going to
happen no matter what. Correct.
But you know it changes who you are.
When you have a kid, it really does.
You're or you're a piece of shit
or you're sociopath and he's such.
Just if you're around the kid enough,
it changes who you are and
if you're not around the kid,
it changes who you are because then you
realize you're not around the kid that's
going to take a piece out of who you think
you are. But you know what? If, if you,
if, and we have friends who aren't great
dads or whatever and you could see it in
their kids. I can I, and I'm,
I'm not slowing up psychologists
or I'm some expert in parenting,
but if I go to a person's house and I see
the way the kids treat the pants, I go,
you're not around enough
man. I can, I promise you.
I can tell my son doesn't act
like that. Yeah, cause one thing,
I bet you can call me whenever you want,
whenever you want.
One thing I am is a beast of a dad. I
know that. I don't know if I'm get comic.
I don't know if I was a good fighter.
I don't want from good podcasts
are that's all up for debate.
One thing I know is I'm a fucking good
dad man. Good for you man. That's a,
it's a very, very, very, very
important quality and that quality.
When your kid becomes an adult,
that's going to be just a major factor
in how you get along. Know I give you,
I mean,
even parents,
I know friends had had bad relationships
with their parents when they live with
them and then once they got out,
their parents were nice to them,
but the parents were shitty
to them when they were kids.
And they always hold it
against a whole week.
They always have that shit in
the back of their head. Like,
why were you a dick when I was 12?
You know that that shit
is always in their head.
It's like that Avatar horse
when you're young, you,
you mixed together and if you don't mix
together when you're young it, yeah.
And I was talking to someone,
a, a therapist. They're saying,
I think it's from like two,
they're three.
If you don't make that
connection when you're like,
oh, when they're for like, oh,
I'll do it now. It's almost
too late because they already
developed these, this,
these brain pathways were like,
Nope,
my dad's an ass and there's really
nothing I can do to fix it. Yeah, man.
I went to the movies yesterday
with my kid, my movie. Uh,
we went to see the GNOMEO and Juliet.
Oh yeah. What is it? A Sherlock gnomes.
Yeah. That's you're like, no, I'm so
cute. Little movie. Yeah, but you know,
we went to that synopsis place
where you know, you lean back,
you know those things. Seats, lean
back, good food, and you take the uh,
the seat rest down. And she just, my
seven year old just snuggles with Macbeth.
They're snuggling watching a movie.
I'm like, I couldn't be happier.
I don't want to see the stupid fucking
movie. No, but I don't care. She wants to,
so I'm, I couldn't be happier.
I sat there and watched us.
Silly knows shit movie. Yeah.
She just a little snuggle bunny.
I've watched her last baby nine
times by time. Not a bad mood.
And like a week though, that's pretty
funny movie then. I'm boss. Baby's great.
Alcohol is the voice I watched like
nine times, but my son, whenever watch,
he snuggled up when usually
this is why I want a daughter.
That's why I'm jealous you have daughters
because daughters loved their dads.
My son. I'm like, you
little traitor mommy, mommy.
Like, dude, it's me
every morning. Your car
for your mom.
Crozer like that too.
And a lot of ways it's just you got to
accept the fact that the mom is not just
the soft sweet woman in the house,
but she's also the person who made
them in her body and there's chemical
connection of her body. Man. There's
no like I had to deal with my wife.
Like I'm not naming any kids.
I go, I got veto power. I go,
but you do way more work. Like it's
way harder to make the person I go.
As long as you tried to call the kid
applesauce or something fucking stupid.
Yeah.
You know,
I just don't feel like
it's not even proposition.
Oh I did this fucker,
we're going to do anyways.
But now we all deal with the
seed. You know, you got a bonus,
a bonus overtime for you.
It is kinda crazy though,
that sex is how you make people I know
and everybody wants just wants to fuck
all the time and you want
to fuck a bunch of people.
A lot of people don't want
kids. No. Hell No. You know,
who opened my eyes like in a big way,
uh,
in a podcast recently that's really
been making me think a lot about this is
Bret Weinstein. He's the, the professor
that gotten that. Do you know the, the,
you know, he is controversy with the
Evergreen universities and all that,
and they were taking the day,
it wasn't a pronoun thing.
It was the day of absence. They wanted
all the white people to stay home.
And he's like, that's racist.
Yeah. Anyway, he was on,
you said there's two different
things that men are attracted to.
They're attracted to a woman that they
think would be a great companion and a
great mother.
And like someone who,
he said there's a difference
between hot and beautiful. Correct.
Like some women are beautiful and like
they're loving you want to be around them.
I goes,
but then there's other women who are
just hot and in males that very receptive
woman who doesn't require any commitment,
was an opportunity for men to spread
their seed with someone who they didn't
have to be around for. Wow. Yeah.
So there's literally like a
programming in a man's mind.
So you see a girl with big giant tits
and a little waist and a fat ass hanging
out of her shorts and she's got sloppy
makeup on and she looks at you and you're
like, oh, okay, let's do
this. But that's what that is.
It's not like I live with her.
Right. You let, you're not saying,
I would like to start a relationship
with you. It's like, no,
I want to shoot my load into you and then
you raise my kid when I'm nowhere near
you because it's an opportunity
for my DNA to propagate. Wow. Mike.
So much sense.
It makes so much sense.
I literally never considered it until
he brought it up on the podcast. I went,
oh Duh. Me Neither. I just
thought she's hot. She's just hot,
dirty in a dirty way. Attracted to that.
Why is she so dirty? I told my girl,
Joe, I told my girl, Joe,
probably four weeks into it,
five weeks we were getting serious and
she got this job offer to go to Miami and
she was talking about career
and stuff like that. And I
went, no, that's all cool.
It's all I know one's career first
more than me. However, uh, you know,
you're put on the search to be a mom,
right?
Like you're going to be such a
beast of a mom. I guarantee you,
because I saw interact with Callan's
kids. I want, I can guarantee you,
you might be the greatest
host in the world,
but you're going to be the best mom I've
ever seen. And then she's like, really?
I'm like, I guarantee you fucking Bam
Bam. Well that's just those qualities.
They can see it's something. And when
someone's not, when someone's a bad mom,
it's such a depressed man.
Nothing worse.
So depressing to be around women was like
really short with her kids and shitty
with them and like,
oh well even as a kid,
if I had friends who like talk back to
their parents are mean to their pants and
like, Oh God, what's wrong with you?
If I was dating a girl she'd
like bad mouth their mom.
Like what's wrong with you girl
on the hard thing is that pattern.
It's hard to break.
Those kids may very well have that same
kind of behavior towards their heads.
Like when they become adults,
it's a hard pattern to break.
Sometimes you need the
right person in your life.
It's like a good person in
your life that you, you know,
a wife or husband or whoever it is.
You know when you,
you match up with that person,
I, it changes who you are too.
That's what I always say that one of
the most important things about um,
community, like your community of friends.
Yeah. It's when you have good friends,
those people change you.
Like you react.
Like everyone is your tribe.
You react like everyone's your friends.
So you want good for them. You
love them, you care about them.
They change who you are. They change
if they inspire you or they like it,
whether they inspire you with being
smart or their kindness or what their
ambition, whatever it is that
we're, we're not individuals.
We're a piece of a community
always and that community,
even if it's a small community
that you call a family,
that piece is dependent upon
who you do that piece with. A,
you might be an amazing dad with the
right woman, but with the wrong woman,
you might be so frustrated with the
relationship that you're not as good a dad
is right now. There might be
chaos going on all the time.
You might be situations you put the kid
in when you're yelling and screaming at
each other the kitchen and see all these
different factors that are dependent
upon your relationship with this other
person and they changed you and you
change them like you might
be the wrong person for them.
They might be super cool
and calm with someone else,
but with you it's just not a mish.
It doesn't hit buttons for the reason.
A woman saying to you, uh, you know,
you don't want an equal like, well,
I don't want this. I don't want this. No,
I don't want this. You might be right,
but I know for sure I don't want that.
You're threatened.
You threatened by a strong woman. No,
I'm threatened by you. You're just,
you're aggressive for no reason.
Who the fuck has ever said
that you threatened by strong
man run by a strong man.
Like shut up. Was he calling yourself
a strong man? Get the fuck Outta here.
Any guy who calls himself a strong man
like that shop most likely's up pitch.
Most likely.
It's just trying to prop himself.
And I feel the same way about women who
say that women who were like, you know,
you're scared of a strong
woman. Like, okay, am I really
or are you a cocked? Yup.
Oh, are you a call? Just a
raging cause this can talk.
This sounds like this guy can't talk
around. Again, super uncomfortable.
I don't know what got us to this,
but whatever I did
please, I'll apologize. But
I also feel like in, in,
in this community of friends that were
talking about if you are a shit father,
it would show elsewhere in your life
around us or if we're at the comedy store
where a restaurant or in your,
in your social media,
it's going to come out one way or another,
you know, tough to be in that group.
You know the expression, how you do one
thing is how you do everything. Yes. Yeah,
yeah.
I think there's something to that.
I mean obviously there's people that
are really good at one thing and suck at
other things. So it's not a, it's
not always a hundred percent correct.
But you know, if you're a
shitty dad, you're going to
be a shitty friend. I agree.
And if you're a shitty friend, you're
probably going to be shitty. Dad and I,
and I say this too,
with like with due to our shitty
debt dads, it's like right.
If you're willing to do that to your,
literally your connect to this person,
chemically, they're, they're made of your
DNA. If you're on a treat him like that.
When the going gets rough for me, where
the fuck are you going to be? Right.
There's no way I want you to my
foxhole. Yeah, that's big man.
And then people that don't,
they don't understand that.
They don't understand what they're doing
wrong. That's rough too. The bummer.
The people that can't see it and he tried
to explain it to them and they can't
see it. The one thing people will put up
with those, and I would never do this,
but if you give someone parenting
advice, just doesn't, there's just,
there's certain things you can't
talk about. Usually politics,
religion and parenting.
The only way I think parenting advice
works ever is if you talk about one great
thing that you found that you do with
your kid without criticizing another pass,
you can,
you could give them advice but not give
them advice by like you can relay your
personal positive experiences and
either they take it or they don't.
But as soon as you start saying,
hey man,
I see how you talk to your
son and you're like, what?
What the fuck did you say people
get? Your son is uh, you know,
he's an individual man. You treat
her like an object. Like fuck,
I don't fucking treat my son
like all the time came over.
He's not even listening. What
you said you're all ramping. I A,
my son was one and a half at the
time and I was taken to this,
this play area and he,
you know,
he did not express himself and everyone
was older and you hit kids and he's a
big kid. He's a 99% tile
for size and all that stuff.
And he would hit kids and the,
the place where I was taking him in
Brentwood knew I was a former fighter.
One of the guys who works
front desk as a fan.
I've talked MMA with them and they
took me to the side and said, you know,
we got a bit of a problem because tiger
is a hitting kids and we think it's in
direct correlation of you let
them watch fights. And from,
I just started laughing, you
guys are silly as fuck. Hey,
I'm never bring them back. B. He's
one to a half. Anyone else in there?
Three. I mean, yeah,
he cold cocked that kid with a
left hook and I'm proud of them.
I could took his toy. However, it's
just, this is what kids do. They hit man.
It's nothing that we, and I tell him,
no, I'm stay on top of my helicopter.
The parent the fuck get him
when he's in there, but these,
these one and a half there were
some are older and have, trust me.
He's not watching UFC.
It's not has nothing to the side.
This lady was like that. You have fc or
whatever you're getting into. I was like,
oh my God,
this is some Brentwood shit lady.
There's a lot of shit right now. All
right, yellow, yellow, meet dirt.
If they hit each other,
they hate each other.
We're concerned that you
constantly reaffirming his
gender without him choosing
were concerned.
I was reading something about some lady
on a three year old trans kid. I'm like,
oh my God.
How about are you sure?
Are you positive and not
just a kid? You're three. Oh,
you mean the how he's into cars this week.
Next week he's me and trolls and he went
chop his dick off while they were like,
this article was like really
super positive about it. Ah, ah.
Bringing the kid to therapy and
shit and aiding his transition.
My keys fucking three in this. I just
read this like two days ago. I was like,
this is so nuts. There's so much
that it's going on right now. Yeah.
And I want to be a transformed when
us three you don't see my dad punched
fucking mechanicals arms on me.
Imagine if I was three arms mean
I'm 19 like what the Fuck Dad?
Why am I a robot now? Well, when you're
three told us you wanted to be a robot,
it's the same shit. It's the same shit.
It's crazy. It's insane. It's so weird.
It's so weird that people are just
openly jumping into this and it's these
weirdo super,
you know,
ideological progressive people that just,
they're locked into this idea that it's
amazing to have a trans kid and you know,
the kid shows any sign whatsoever of being
inclining to be female or inclined to
be mailed. They're pushing
it. I'm like, Oh God, I feel
like this actually bad. Well,
it's also very dangerous because they
start wanting to fuck with the kids
hormones. Like you got to let the child
develop. There's no real science and,
and what the fuck happens when
you put hormone blockers new,
a three year old and try to
transition them into a girl,
but also the real doctors,
you know what the hell they're doing.
They're not going to inject that kid
with hormones. So we can say, listen,
if you want to do this when you're
1819 even then it's a little too early.
But when you're 21 which is
again, it's too early. The,
and I've seen this on some of the
bullshit reality TV shows that much,
but these legit doctorial then
I'm willing to help you out.
But before then get out of here.
No, get out. Let's see where yet.
When you're 16th there's a market for it,
which is a cruel thing to say
in a weird way to describe it,
but here's the problem, John. We
were, we were talking about, you know,
on the spectrum,
for some of those kids,
they do feel like they're trapped
in a woman's body, you know?
And I feel for them that must suck to
go through high school and all that.
But isn't that the exception?
You know what I'm saying?
Like is that kit the
exception that feels like,
and they should have access to it. How
could you do that with a three year old?
I know. I mean, how do you know? I mean,
you just don't, and anybody says he do.
Your crazy people change. You change
when hormones get entered into your body.
And maybe you won't be the most
masculine man in the world.
And maybe you will turn
into a woman someday maybe,
but give yourself a goddamn
chance to just exist.
Do you see the high school wrestler?
Yes.
The girl just beaten up right in that
and then she waved to test booze like gay
motherfucker.
I know it's not fair.
She should be able to out to a Russell
Ball or he should be allowed to wrestle
boys, you know? But you know,
whatever, man. It's crazy. You're,
you're taking a high school girl and
you're filling her up with testosterone,
with injections,
what?
It's nuts and then you're allowing
her to wrestle girls that aren't on
testosterone. It's fucking cheating. Okay.
If she was just a girl and she wasn't
like trying to transition into a man and
they found out that she was winning the
state championship as a woman or as a
girl, rather by taking steroids,
they would take it away from it.
She would say she's cheating. Sued.
They'd be, there'd be an uproar,
but some shit not let her
wrestle. Yes. Not let her wrestle.
Wrestle at all levels.
If they go,
we can't wrestle with the boys
and just can't rest that all,
we'll get to wrestle. The boys don't
wrestle. I would say she, that's what she,
he wants he, what's the
rest of the boys? They
zero reserves. Um, yeah.
I, I think it, hey, if you,
if you're going to choose to go that
path of this transitioning to a female,
then you give up your right to wrestle
because we don't have a division for that
vet and get,
and we don't have enough wrestling.
She's transitioning to he and
it's just, it's not fair. It was,
if it was the other way,
it would be more fair because like if
you're a man and you're transitioning to
be a woman and they make you wrestle
men while you're going to be at a
disadvantage because you are
taking hormone blockers or
you're getting castrated,
you're losing your test to goals,
your whatever, whatever it is,
you are at a disadvantage in that aspect.
Yeah.
He's at a disadvantage
now transitioning to,
I mean he's at an a massive advantage
right now. Transitioning to a man there.
He's on steroids.
You going up the kids on steroids?
100% and probably a lot of them probably
a lot of it because they're trying to
turn him into a man.
Correct. It's all nuts.
But I know like where
was this 30 years ago?
It was it just like a silent epidemic.
There's everyone just under cover.
It was like, God, I feel like a woman,
you know, there was a few of those.
There was like that one guy,
Renee Richards that uh,
the tennis player that
wound up transitioning.
He was a terrible male tennis player,
transitioned to a female tennis player
and start dominating that Joanna man,
that's the plot of Joanna man
tennis addition. Now that movie, No,
it was do you want them to want a man?
Was the guy who couldn't,
he get suspended from like the Lakers, the
fake Lakers in the movie. So he's like,
God, I want to play basketball. So
like you could make the women's team,
he just wore a wig and put TVs on
us. Started dunking on bitches. Well,
that does happen today. There was a guy
who was ready for this 50 years old.
He was six foot four or five,
played women's college basketball
because he played as a man.
But now he's not a man anymore. Now this
fool is a fucking woman. He's a fool.
And you went back and you're 50 years
old and you're pretending to be a college
girl and be like, I'm in a
fantasy. Where is my fantasy?
And she's a giant and she's swatting
basketballs out of people's hands.
There's Joanna man.
Yeah.
See if you could find guy who played it
was 50 type in 50 year old transsexual
man,
transsexual plays,
women's college bath in America, right?
Yeah. In America. Well, here's the thing.
Imagine if your kid is on a team with
that person and that person takes your
kids scholarship, takes your
kids. Look at that right there.
Aw,
seriously.
Gi Yak jacked and got 50 year old knows
on them and became a college basketball
player at fucking might get the
fuck out of here. 52 excuse me,
Gabriel Ludwig [inaudible] 52.
Okay.
Two years old than me goes
to college and she ball. Uh,
I think she played as a man.
Look at that size difference.
Now imagine your kid is competing
against her and it can't get a shot off.
Can't get a Shaquille O'Neal
and it's just bullshit.
It's like if Shaquille O'Neal
was playing on that other team,
if Shaquille O'Neal transition to be a
woman and decided to go back to college,
this college would let her play as
a woman. That's Shaquille O'Neal.
I was a woman. What colleges? That
douche bag university. I Dunno.
I don't wanna I don't want to give
him any press. Press makes me sick.
I mean that's a giant man with tits.
It's straight nonsense.
This is where she good ball play.
This is where progressiveness
goes down the rabbit hole.
What does it mission college.
That's probably a juco. Huh?
I don't know what it is but it gets,
it could suck it.
It can suck a nonexisting ticket.
Well interesting thing.
She played college basketball for
30 years ago as a man. I said,
how does she still have eligibility? Cause
she's a woman now. That's what I said.
But she'll transition. They let
her, they let her transition.
And when you're transitioning,
you go back. Now you're a woman.
You don't have a history
of playing as a woman.
So now you're allowed to play it again
for five more years of college. Yep, Yep.
Too. I feel like a lot more
ask you got to do this.
There's a few that would do
it. Oh, hundred percent. Oh,
Dana White was joking around about
that. Like, I know a few guys,
if it could be a world champion, they'd
cut the dick off. There's a few gaps.
There are some guys who by all means
this too, it's crazy to even suggest,
but so is walking into youtube,
shooting a bunch of people
and then shooting yourself
in the chest. That's crazy.
Suggest too, that he fucking mind. That
bitch was definitely out of her mind.
And also if you saw U two video, no one
or you can made no fucking money lead.
Those videos were terrible. Well, there's
something wrong with that ladies brain.
How about her dad goes, uh, warned the
police. I can guess need to check her out.
She didn't do something bad to youtube.
There's some, some issues here,
but if you're a cop and they did find
her the night before at 2:00 AM cause she
went missing. They found
her and they're like, yeah,
she doesn't seem like she's gonna
hurt herself or anyone else.
I don't know where you want us to do.
Like we found her, she sits, she's good.
She's sleeping in her car
until someone does something.
It's so hard to do anything about it.
Like they um,
they sent that one college kid, they're
sending him back. They found, uh,
his roommates. I was, we were
talking about it yesterday.
His roommates were talking about and
there were seriously worried about him.
He had bleached his hair,
blonde start stockpiling ammunition,
bought an assault,
gone and then the cops came to
visit him and after the cops left,
he went out and bought another ar and
they're like, okay, okay. That's it.
And they are, we got it. We
got to do something about this.
His roommates are freaking out.
Like people are freaking
out being around the guy.
And they sent him back on a technicality
because he wasn't going to school cause
he stopped going to class.
So what can you do a student visa?
What the fuck can you do? They deported
them. Oh really? Yeah. Oh perfect. Yeah.
And they said, we think we prevented
the tragedy. I love that. Yeah,
that's exactly what they should
do. But however, would this lady,
let's say they stopped
at two in the morning,
she's in a car and the PA and the
Dad, the dad who, you know, uh,
she came from, his seat goes, listen,
she, she, she's going to do something bad.
We think we've seen signs.
We've known her since she was a day old.
You guys should do something about it.
I don't think you should go out.
We talked to her, it seems
all right. Maybe take her
in for the night. Do though.
Talk to the therapist.
But if she doesn't do anything and
then she does like people are so
unpredictable and get those eyebrows and
class or in jail for that video of her
doing those squats and the jumps,
the workout video to hairball of
those eyes crazy that she's not there.
She was a different plant horror movie
and then, but then, and then she's mad.
She's not getting fricking revenue
from the Youtube and youtube like ah,
your videos suck lady.
We have nothing to do with it.
You didn't come up in the open mic circuit
so you don't have a phd in Psychos.
Like he,
Tony Hinchcliffe,
all these dudes that have been
in the grind like I remember
a long time ago,
but they're fucking crazy people.
There's a certain amount of open Microsoft
think that they're really funny and
they can't get work and they're angry
about it and they're really fucking crazy.
Get on killed Tony, when I've
been in like two, three times.
Perfect example till Tony is a primary
example. You go there and you're like,
what in the fuck am I watching?
And if someone tries to tell that person
like maybe you should connect more with
the crop. I connect, we get mad. This
is my best bit. He's pitcher. Good bits.
And the people were like, what in the Tony
told one guy like, dude, you're bombing.
He goes, they were
laughing. They're laughing.
They laughing at you until you those,
they're laughing cause you're fucking
terrible and we're making faces behind.
He goes, that's laughing. You don't know
what the fuck you're talking about, Tony.
He's like, get off the stage. He's like,
make me. It's like, oh my God, boy.
Yeah, but you see, you see
that too on American idol,
there'll be some crazy dude like,
my mom thinks I'm the best,
you know the best things,
Lionel Richie and they get up and it just
completely bomb and they cock shit to
the experts. You guys just
don't know what you want. Well,
you have to look at people as a whole.
Right now,
if you look at people as a
whole, like physically, right?
There's people that have built like you
and there's people that have built like
Vern Troyer. That's just a fact. It's,
it's tough. It's tough. It's tough.
It's also brilliant mind.
But my point is it's come on seven.
It's a roll of the dice.
That's the same thing with everything.
It's the same thing with your mind as
well. It just is. The mine varies widely.
It varies racially. It varies
interracially it varies. Uh,
age wise.
Like you can have a 50 year old black
guy that's a smart guy you ever met in
your life and you're going to have a
50 year old white guy who is a fucking
moron and you're going to have a 50
year old woman who is out of our fucking
mind and you're going to have a 50 year
old woman who's a brilliant physicist
and you're gonna have everything.
You have, every combination,
every combination of smart and stupid and,
and the tall and thin people vary.
But they also vary with how crazy
they are. But also that's a variable.
I think some people are crazy and then
they find a passion. They run with it.
Maybe it's music,
comedy,
but then some of those crazy people who
are different than the others in high
school get made fun of,
get bullied and then that craziness turns
into darkness and then they get ahold
of Ak 47 then that's when you
get the mass shootings. Oh yeah.
Cause there's experiences with those
crazy people and maybe they turned the
right direction and they do
something great. Write great songs,
come up with a great bid or come up
with a great TV show or that person gets
bullied so bad, the direction
they go. It's dark. It's fun.
Hundred percent crazy mind does crazy
stuff. Yeah. So 100% physical abuse,
sexual abuse along with that medications.
Sure.
Medications can do it and it's all,
I mean every single mass
shooters on medications.
But when you look at the combination
of all the different factors,
it's like when you see that lady crying
in her car to clock in the morning,
you're a cop, you don't know
what to do. What do you,
what do you think you
think she's going to like?
I knew when I looked at her that she
was going to go on to youtube and shoot
that place up. Now there's no way,
you know, there's no way. Nope.
How close cruise kids,
same thing.
They came to see him two years before
they decided he wasn't a threat.
And the people like the
FBI's and competent know 24
months later, first of all,
he probably got fucking crazier,
crazy, right? In 24 months.
His mom wound up dying like
six months before that.
So that probably fucked him up too.
There's probably a whole host of factors.
Right.
But he never did it before.
How the fuck can you predict
these random shooters? It's how,
I don't know what you're going to do.
The only thing with the Youtube
thing is if the dad goes, listen, my,
you can do something crazy and
they find her near the Youtube, uh,
northern California offices, we should
at least take her in for the night,
talk to her. And that's the leash.
You're not gonna lose anything.
Taxpayers be happy to pay for a night in
there, you know, it's all, it's all good.
Yeah. I mean, I don't know if
that would do it though. You know?
It's like that lady just seemed fucking
nuts, man. Someone saw and said, uh,
someone posted it and said,
be ready to never sleep again.
That'd be didn't scare me that much. Yeah.
50 I went, oh, she's bat shit crazy. Yeah.
Like super duper batshit crazy.
Youtube was out for,
cause she was,
her views were lowering one video though.
She had 45 views. It's like, come
on man. It's fucking bananas, man.
I'm sure they pull her youtube
pages by now, Jamie. Yeah.
And how if you're going to go out,
right? Most people do it to the head.
She shot herself
in the chest.
That's dot savage. That's dark.
That's a dark way to go. Okay.
The people have done that.
I guess people that knew they were brain
was going to get junior say I did that
show himself in the chest because he goes,
I want you to stay in my
brain because it's not good.
Fuck yeah.
I can't feel good. No, I feel like
the brain bee was, yeah, we went dark.
We can we talk. We got to bring
it back. We've gotten dark,
this punk to bring it back.
Let's bring it home.
It's bring him home on a positive thing,
but you don't stop roles, Doug Rau.
That's a fight. No one's talking
about you, Ana rose. Hey Jamie.
Tell 'em homeboys got to watch the
Monitor. All right. Yeah. Um, yeah.
Talk rose. It's being overshadowed.
Yeah, it has been overshadowed.
It's a crazy one,
right?
It's because nobody expected it to go
down the way it did in the first one,
you know, not at all. And the rematch
you on is on weight. She's way lighter.
She was one 22 last week, you know,
so she's just a few pounds away.
Here's my problem with this
fight and uh, I hit, I might,
I might stop making pigs.
I sat on a podcast yesterday.
It doesn't make me feel good
when I pick gets people,
it doesn't make me feel good.
I feel like I have to do it.
A lot of people don't do pigs
and they come to me for pigs.
What do you think's gonna Happen?
Uh, for a long time I thought,
oof. Rose Rose, she's a monster
and I know rose right from Denver.
She landed that left Hook
and Trevor teaches that and
Pat Barry teaches that and
that's exactly one to do. Amazing
fight. I bet they fight, you know,
three or four times,
but if they do a rematch,
which they should give you
on the immediate rematch, me,
a little bit of trouble cause
you on is a fucking machine.
Here's the caveat to that. When I see
you on a do interviews and she goes,
it was my nutritionist. It was this
person, it was this, it was this.
She never once has she owned it
and taking credibility. I go,
that's not the way a world champion
speaks. That's not the way it all.
Someone talks and when I see
a bunch of excuse go, Oh shit,
you have a hole in your boat and your cow,
you're masking it with duct tape and
you're trying to get back to this point.
You're just math.
You're not solving that.
Actually patching that up and so
you're susceptible again and now you,
you're talking like that never
happened. It was a fluke. Yeah.
Rose is pretty fucking good. And
if you don't respect her, again,
you think it's your nutritionist
is why he left that fight,
you're probably gonna lose again. You
might be right. He might be right.
It's only thing that bothers me,
I think you on is one of the greatest
games of all time when the greatest
fighters. But it's just when I see them
like, oh you're, you're just going,
you're going about the wrong
way. And she goes, you know,
I even talked to Rhonda and you know,
she said she had to wait, come like,
no one's dealt with loss is worse than
Rhonda. You don't want to preface that.
You don't want to reference that at all.
Right.
I don't want to see that out of you, Ana.
She has so much more work to do. Yeah,
well it's also,
you want to had a long career in Moy Tai,
a long career. You know,
like a lot of fights, tons,
lot of a kickboxing sparring,
a lot of MMA sparring.
Sometimes your changes goes, I
mean, this is a, this is a real,
sometimes you change,
just go. You didn't get the Chin thing?
I don't know. Yeah, I don't know. I see.
I think it's too early to call for that.
Especially at that weight class.
I think for her it's more,
she just wasn't being respectful of rose
[inaudible] she's gonna walk through
and all the shit talking and she was
doing and roses a different animals. She,
she reminds me of Brian Ortega a little
bit where, where she's very dangerous on,
on conventional and the certain
spots you can't train for.
So she's that type of animal with
similar Brian Ortega. But with Yolanda,
a gun to my head, I'd say you
ana winds by decision. But again,
I hate bacon. Pigs makes me feel
badly. Yeah, making picks is tough man.
Because you know you're going to piss
people off and you know, they, oh,
we're fucking route niggers.
That's no,
you have to look at the
analysis of it before the fight.
I thought rose was in
trouble. I'm like, you want,
it's very hard to take down to her.
Stanhope is world class and I think she's,
she could very well pick
rows apart and you know, and,
and crack or she's coming in.
But when she hit her with that left and
she hit her before that and hurt her,
but when she hit her with that left
hook, I was like, Gee, explosive too.
She looks good man.
And rose like a on the embedded rose was
a pat Barry takes a giant box of tennis
balls and throws tennis balls at her and
she's popping tennis balls in the air
and she, she looks fucking solid and rose
to her ceilings. We're just seeing it.
It's just so much room for growth to
show young pat just Trev around her.
And now forever people are like,
you're going to be world champion.
And when everyone tells,
coaches tell fives all the time,
but what actually happens? You Go,
Oh shit, they're not bullshitting.
They're not just saying this.
And I think when she actually believes it,
now you're dealing with
different thug rose.
You're dealing with different Yolanda,
you,
Ana doesn't think she's the
greatest gift to the MMA world.
So that kind of combination.
It's such a fascinating and no
one's talking about it. Yeah,
well everyone was so caught up in this
cancellation and the Ferguson could be
fight was so huge for
the hardcores for sure.
But it's also one of those things where
with rose coming into this fight now and
you want to make an excuses
for the last fight, you know,
I'm really interested to see what
happens when they square off.
I can't wait for that fight.
Each other is yawn again and do the same
talk and again and roads 10 reciting
the Bible. I don't think
she can. I don't think,
I don't think you'll want to can
do the same talk and you don't.
You don't think she goes, this was a
fluke. I'm doing the exact same thing. No,
I think rose going to stare right through
her fucking soul again. I'd be like,
I'm the champion.
When you talk a gang of shit at someone
and they just stare right through you
and then they merch
you in the first round.
It's very tough to talk all
that shit the second time.
It's going to be interesting.
I think that's a sign if you want.
It isn't respecting rose again. If she
gets up there and start talking that shit.
I would put a ton of money on rose.
Yeah. If I see her doing the same things,
I'm like, Oh shit. You learn
nothing. Go there. Nothing.
Well it's whether or not
rose can clipper again.
If rose charges in eclipse or again it's
also the thing about a striker always
worried being taken
down is more likely to get hit with a
shot like Kevin randomly when he knocked
out Mirko Cro contract.
Same thing like Kevin was
the threat as a wrestler.
Leaps in with a left hook and
catches him right on the chin.
Knocked him the fuck out. I think there's
a, there's a real correlation there.
I wouldn't be surprised if you on a so
focused on improving her stand up and you
know it's like kind of
got caught this time.
Just get overwhelming or to stand up.
She gets submitted.
She overlooked the submission
game of rose, which is
actually Rose's best weapon.
That's what I was thinking.
I was thinking, Bro,
we might see rose throw a flying arm.
Correct.
We might see rose wild shit doesn't
care about being on her back. Oh No.
And she's fast. She, she
goes for shit. She like,
she's a wild explosive person,
you know,
and she's a really interesting thinker
too. You know. She had a tough life man.
Yup.
Tough life growing up and develop this
very strong mind because controlled chaos
is what I taught and she's brilliant at.
Yeah.
I think what else about fascinating
about this? Not that fight, definitely.
I'm more, almost more excited
for that fight. Anything now.
But what's fascinating to me is everyone
talks about Conor Mcgregor, right?
Especially when you're talking about
one 55 and with Connor and Max Holloway,
Connor's never looked back.
Went af fight that guy back there.
Even though I'm better than the thing
that gets caught her out of bed,
I think is the challenge
and making history.
And I think if Khabib or Max where to win,
that would be a new challenge.
And he'd been the underdog.
It's could be even when Max Holloway,
the you have a history at 55
especially if could be where to win.
I think we see connotate that fight now
cause he goes, that's about frown. Great.
Well I'm the best at moving
backwards hitting dudes.
I bet you I can beat that guy.
And we see him.
I think we see him take that fight
and I've never said that before. I've,
I've always, I know Dana said, oh they're
going to fight in Russia. I'm like, God,
why would kind of fighting him
and then I think we're like,
when you think of all the challenges and
college career and what gets him going,
it's not people behind him.
It's always when people go,
that is the best of you was cool. Give me
that guy. Very similar. Max Holloway. Mm.
Yeah.
If Max wins for sure they have a rematch.
100% a hundred percent the thing about
Khabib is you always got a wonder who
avoiding him. There's a difference
there. It did see the differences.
Max is one of the best fighters on the
planet. No doubt. He's one of my top,
one of my top guys. Maybe you just
ever top featherweight of all time,
but people aren't avoiding him.
No. It's like I said, can be,
it's a different animal.
Like aerifying referenced this I said,
I said if you gave me a choice to make
the walk against Francis or could be,
I'm cherry picking Francis Cause it's
a quick death and not the head in the
third row, but it's quick. It could be,
but it's like an isis videos can be long
drawn out and to be a fucking nightmare
that you're not going to forget. Yeah,
he's going to beat your body into a pulp.
But the worst is he breaks you where
it's like, oh you are good at this.
And people thought you were
mentally strong. Watch this.
Now your entire family and friends going
to see how much of a pussy you are as a
bash. Your brains in round after
round, after round after round. You see
him break guys too though.
You see like there's something
happens to them when they just,
they give in to the inevitability of
getting ragdoll. He's just better. Yeah.
Oh, the only person that's going
to beat him. It's not a person.
It's a fucking grizzly bear. You know?
It's like, fuck this man, and you see,
you can't see it in their eyes where
it just changes were just like, no,
not happening. Now, how many
rounds for four more rounds
of this? This is terrible.
If he wins and he beats Holloway,
I guarantee you he's calling out McGregor.
He wants the GSP fight.
Khabib wants GSP.
Holy Shit. That's what I hear. Whoa.
That's the one 70 whoa.
What a great fight, right?
It's a perfect time to do it right
now. Right? GSP wins by rear naked,
choke against Bisping at one 85
says he doesn't want to fight it.
A five again here, take
your belt, suck it cs it.
Just go suck it. Take you. No,
I told you I'd fight their soc.
Do whatever you want to do with that belt.
I'm going to just get to do
whatever the fuck I want.
I made a couple million bucks.
I'm gonna kick back for Awhile
and now you get party who? Oh,
you fancy yourself a grappler.
GSP. Me Too. Let's party.
That's a really interesting, if I can
make a super fight. If I was like Dana,
scrooge McDuck, there's sit on top, all
these gold coins. I call it Ben African.
I'm like, Yo, any interest in
fighting Khabib at one 70 fuck yes.
Fuck. What's up bro? That's
what I'm talking about. Yes.
That's the call your boy.
Oh my boy. I'm going to tell you
blocked by calls. We call your boy.
He block your call.
I don't call him but I'm sure he
collected into him this weekend.
I want to talk to him this weekend.
Dad would be the fight,
but you know what have
been asked for and wins.
He starts talking Shit Calling Dana.
Perfect. Perfect egg head. It works.
It sells papers. It's the bottom
line. Yeah, but then you ruin.
Could be if Ben asking.
It could be,
I think you give Ben ass grin a
guy who's a good fighter. GSP.
Well you haven't seen it.
Most people don't know who Ben Askern is.
The problem is he fought in Bellator for
so long and then even when bell tours
gotten bigger on Spike TV,
he was off in one FC,
which you have no one are huge Ben
asking fans now, but we are hardcore,
like the casual fan has no idea.
Like who is this guy with the curly
hair they're sending to his death,
but we can sell it because he speaks well.
He's a beast on the mind and then you pin
if it gets hit an Olympian, he's never,
who's undefeated never been
hit against Khabib. Yeah,
and we call it the Cold War. I
think in the UFC, particularly me.
Well I'm a big Ben,
her Dick Rider and Jimmy Smith who's
also a big Ben Aspirin Dick, right?
I think we're all Dick Writers.
We could sell the shit out of it.
I can hype the shit out to be
100% honest in the process.
I think he's something special I
think is grappling is very unusual,
very difficult to prepare for.
And if you're going to deal with Khabib
against a guy who can neutralize his
stuff and then we see like, what did we
see Khabib on his back? Ben Asked Grin.
Fucking
would a knee across the belly punching
Khabib and the face. We like, no.
What about Beneski right? We could be
just doing the ground and pound, right.
There's these trait crazy scrambles and
the grappling communities can be like,
it would be amazed is terrible.
Striking good blocks on that Uncle Dana.
Uncle don't think somebody for,
for, for, for, for fuck you.
He's going to slam that phone
down. Fuck you. He would
have to have, he's like, sir,
I'm trying to finalize cm punk Floyd here.
You're talking about Penn
aspirin could be, how dare you.
He would have to have a good relationship
with Ben asked her and they would have,
no, he does not. He's I disagree or
he doesn't know. He can go, all right,
I'm gonna make money off this
kid I have for $50 million.
They make money off this kid.
Let me do this.
Don't you think you'd have to put Ben
asked her in in a UFC fight though,
against some money to show everybody
what he's capable of. Nope.
He has all those belts. Undefeated
Olympian. We're just promo the shit.
He's on embedded. He's on Uca night.
He's on below the bellies on jre.
We go on this campaign,
he's dressed in oak flag and he's like,
watch me beat the shit out the
pound for pound grain Russian.
Who else don't like
Russia all? Yeah, Maca.
Maca. Great. Ooh, I like it.
It's never happening. Probably
that's never happening.
Know what you sold me.
Thank [inaudible].
Just get Daniel or listened
to this video. Dana, Uncle d,
if you just have him fight
someone who's really good,
like Neil Magni or Carlos condit,
have him up like fucking Kobiashi talk
squash that introduction fight and who
knows? Nope, this is a one shot. Hell
Mary. We're selling the fuck out of it.
I'm interested because then what happens
to be fighting to a mega CROs Kinda and
just like rape some humps on for three
rounds people. If that's sucked, man.
I know, but he probably won't
be able to do like Khabib.
So you've gotta watch that one.
We missed the boat style is so much
more suited to one fc because they allow
those knees to the head on the ground.
True soccer kicks in,
but they still are soccer
kicks in when I've see it.
Did they stop it after Brandon bear?
Like almost an excuse to dude,
I thought or maybe I think they still do
it. How about the Roger worked at one.
Oh my God.
I've got head kicked by the time about
Roger Work does fight and Ben Henderson
this weekend that's flying under the
radar. It is fine under the way. Well,
it's like,
you know,
worked out was the first ever MMA fighter
on the cover of sports illustrated.
People forget that.
People forgot that back in the day was,
this is like 2000 twoish threeish
he was coming up right before that.
I forget who we beat. Then you're
supposed to fight Kenny Florian.
If you remember, he was like the front
cover. What year was that? 2004 two,
nine five no two.
Then six.
Dot. Six six was to say, Oh
yeah, here's the head kick.
So the dude uh, is, is already beaten him.
He rag dolls hortus down and look at this.
This is horrible.
Oh, I mean, that was one of the
worst head kicks you'll ever see.
That was horrible. Let's see. I don't
want to see that. I don't want that in my,
that's horrible.
That one's horrible.
Like that guy was,
he was already hurt and
out of it before that. Um,
well the average casual
adult soccer player can kick
a ball with a thousand foot
pound force.
The average professional soccer player
can kick it about 1,200 foot pound force.
My educated guesses,
elite highly trained martial arts
perform very similar to the professional
segment.
I'll tell you what,
if you put somebody down in their hands
and knees and I kicked him in the head
like that can be a lot more than that.
They're fucked. He broke and killed a guy.
You know, you don't want
to see them. You could,
you could kill somebody doing that.
You literally could snap their
neck is no doubt about it.
When was that sports
illustrated cover though Jamie.
Okay.
Cause you met Roger where he worked
at sports illustrated illustrated.
I want to and it says is Emma,
is the UFC the next emerging sport or
is it just a fad or something like that?
I want to say 2006 two I'm thinking six.
I think it's post.
Um, it's post tough. Yeah,
it's post Stephan Bonner.
Forrest Griffin. Agree. And that
was 2005 maybe seven, maybe seven.
Yeah.
Um,
but remember Roger work to,
he got all that notoriety and then he
tried big Dick in the UFC when now I want
this, this and this though. It cool.
We're going to sit ya and then give
you the worst matchup possible.
Here's gray Maynard. Yeah. May
28th, 2006. Oh there it goes.
Ah, mother. So we're in the neighborhood.
They were closed.
So this was a,
you know Roger where it was like
the poster board, Handsome Hispanic,
Latino, bad motherfucker. I remember
watching her work to beat that dude up.
That punched a chick in the face like a
guy named [inaudible] in Austin, Texas.
He's a big football player, black
player, sucker punch to grow in the face,
in front of everybody dropped her and
then Roger where to takes his shirt off
and fuck this dude up.
There's a scramble.
You see the dude squaring off
Roger's way smaller than him.
Cut to a few seconds later.
See Roger Soccer kicking him.
Here it is.
Okay.
So Roger is standing back here
and this guy steps into this girl,
TMZ son. Did you show the
first beginning of it? Yeah,
but the beginning of his, when he steps
in and punches the girl in the face,
all right there, we'll drop the
girls go to right to the beginning.
Knocked the girl out
right to the beginning.
Okay.
It doesn't play the whole thing. So the
guy, the the guy in the orange shirt,
big ass dude drops a girl, female
girl face look work to look at them.
Yeah.
Good luck.
Colon back does talking shit.
He's saying that's a girl man. He's so
much smaller. This guy is like, fuck you.
I'll fuck you up to.
We're always had good fashioned
to just want the other there.
There's another video this week. Hear more
volume when I'm talking to each other.
This might be the only one I've
ever seen. Oh, there it goes.
Work to take your shirt off.
And he's pissed guy who had girl Roger
where I took their shirt off. Okay.
They got some titties with a sub.
Roger chases him down.
Well Roger was fast as
fuck too that Oh yeah,
no idea what he's doing before he knew
animal that before he knew what that
dude's getting punched in the face and
at the end you see Roger's got the dude
in the ground sock kicking them. No,
it's like, it's like jumping into the,
into the water and there's a
crocodile in there before you know it,
look, get Roger, boom, he's out cold.
You're not. And that's justice, isn't it?
It needs to be JC. He's
basically a Mexican Batman
there. If he kept kicking him,
it had been justice. I mean it was
justice for sure, but fuck that guy.
I know some guy's cock sucker
punching your daughter. Big giant,
250 pound football player.
Sucker punches her daughter face.
It'd be hard not to kill. Very hard. Not
Super. Not to very lucky he's alive. Yeah.
Very lucky.
He's alive and he probably shouldn't
be if he doesn't feel remorse for that
sucker.
Punching a girl in the face like that.
It's a special kind of piece of shit.
Big Dude too. It's a giant. Yeah.
I mean who knows what the fuck was
going on in his head, but then again,
who knows what the fuck is going on
with a lot of football players that have
suffered a lot of head trauma.
True. Or he could just be a bad guy.
That could be a bad guy. Maybe he was
raised around that, thinks it's okay.
Maybe who knows what the
girl did? Either way. Never.
Okay to hit a girl fuck like that too.
It's, that's a hard thing to watch.
It's a horrible thing to watch is gets
off that guy punching a guy like you is
horrible but punching a girl in the face.
Horrible man.
There's a lot of fucking shit
of humans out there, man.
A real unfortunate part about us,
but keep going. Dark dots hard,
tough not to when you watch something like
that. But the Roger, Roger, Sarah Day,
he did man superhero style.
I bet that guy s but his friends,
I remember that time yet.
Burke by Roger worked up and really it's
tiny thought 155 pounds and your giant
ass is all juiced up in the God damn
weight room every day and you still got
knocked out for hitting a girl.
Remember that asshole every day.
Ever lived that down? Nope. Even now, I'm
sure people will find them on Instagram.
Be like,
hey Rogen shove,
we're talking mad shit about you man Mir
that we'll never get to live it down if
he never went to jail for that.
That's the punishment. Correct.
He never went to jail for that. You're
supposed to go to jail for that. Yeah.
That's supposed to put you in jail for a
long time and hopefully he doesn't have
kids.
Stark.
We won't talk again.
Wait, go dark sometimes.
What else is on this car
this weekend yet? Uh, Pedis.
That's a fun one.
Everybody's dad slept on that fight.
It's another one that's gone under
the radar. She has both pet dies.
Very interesting man. Jessa man, he
fucking submitted by Neil Dariusz.
He gets your back, your Foxville. Remember
he got submitted by Kevin Lee? He did,
but he didn't. He didn't. He didn't get
submitted. The referee stopped it. I know,
but he was saying he was good. He look,
he was tightening up his neck. Yeah.
It wasn't me that you got to let the
guy go out. I'll come on brother.
100% he was done. Felder,
outlier Quinta. Whoo.
Woo
catered. Did you see he's a monster.
Calvin cater and a Meu Cano.
That's a good fight to at the undercard.
You got bored. You got Joe
Lozan got caught run on quarter.
Calvin cater and not to a more economy.
That's a great fans fight.
Fight of the night. Written
all over it. All over it. God,
there's fucking five excellent
fights in that main card.
Like your boy fleets hit or look
at your girl fleets hearing. Yeah,
ver versus Carolina. Yes. Lena.
Kickball Kovich and then I'm not even
mad at the fight. Pass, fight the uh,
your boy Bruce Leroy Leboeuf
low Bob who's off the team.
Connor and then team could saw
each other and they got into it.
They think the other team,
Connor and then the team could bebes got
brilliant to it cause Kimmy obviously
as for Connor, when Tony fell out and date
and was like, come on, let's get real.
Yeah,
you can't put that better shot
a video supposedly have a low voc calling
him a coward and he was calling them
out to say it to his face.
Oh Wow. Those guys from uh,
Pakistan. This is Dagestan, right? Yeah.
You know how many people he must've seen
get killed shit. Now Margaret Madoff,
like mentally,
he's in a completely different space.
Goddamn Mike can be in color as to why.
Why don't they have Mike Rodriguez?
It's Mike and Black and white. White.
Is He in Dad's ashes? This bullshit.
What is this bullshit? They didn't
even, it didn't even allow them to flex.
God Damn my car hit the fucking regular
Russell shorts on that you get in gym
class. Fuck Mike. Oh Man. Oh
Joe Lowe's ons on the car too.
Mike slow. Mike Rudd. Re that's not
a great nickname. Uh, slow Mike.
That's not good. That's
a trek as fast. So fast.
It couldn't get them a color picture.
Um, light heavyweight. Look at that one,
two Oh five and one 92. What
is that? What's that shit?
This is not real weight.
Is it always in one night to one of
them is two oh five ones. One 92.
That doesn't even make any sense.
Like unless they're fighting an 85
and they caught them before the wake.
That makes zero sense. That
makes zero sense. One guys,
13 pounds heavier weight class. They
finding it. I mean no, I know that's,
that's light heavyweight.
But what Mike?
Mike Rodriguez with Shane's
name for black black dye.
Last name Mike or Rodriguez Cuban
maybe. Um, his name's Mike though.
Slowmo Mike. But um, if he just
fortunate he had a picture,
cause usually this throw up a shadow
if they don't have it right this time
though. You know what? You're
not going to shout out.
We're going to black and white for him.
We're going to let people know that you
haven't really fought in the UFC before,
but we're still getting pictures. What
do you think about [inaudible] and Pedis?
Ah, man Pedis, right? It's just
bad streak. He's on a rough streak.
He won his last one, right? But then
him find a 45 whoever told him, dude,
that's insane. So it's tell Holloway
got his belt. But I'm a Kevin Lee Fan,
but I say he did not submit Michael. Yes,
you're out. They should have let him.
They should have let them go
out and he would have won,
but they didn't and he didn't. Okay.
Zuora, we're in the same boat. However,
if it would have kept going on, he had
been choked unconscious. Not, maybe not.
I've been doing Jujitsu maybe too long.
Not to know.
The PS is like Hicks and Gracie.
Hixon Gracie,
let's black belts take his back with
full rear naked choke. And it's like,
go ahead. I know. Crazy. Right to
chocolates. That's, that's you know,
you know what Gracie, we're talking
that takes and for Gosh Sakes,
I love Chia Aza.
That's a far cry from Hicks and Gracie.
But also he went to go tap. Have you
look at the video, look at the video. He,
he panics a little bit and now he's a,
he's a,
he's a black belt I think he said
he knows what the fuck he's doing.
He was going to and trading on his neck.
If you hear him talk about
it that he tightened,
he put all his focus on his neck and
he let his hands go and it's just
tightening it.
Oh yeah.
You have Kevin Lee who's a fucking
anaconda around your neck and has previous
winds of rear naked choke. I
don't buy it. I agree with you.
They should have let it go on.
I think we'd been choked
unconscious to let it go on.
You have to you to let it go on.
The only worse rest I've seen was the
ref in the, uh, Joseph Parker fight.
I didn't see the judge. The Ref would
not fucking let these guys fight.
Anytime they even got close, he jumped
in their own, push them away. Hmm.
Who Do you think that favored?
They,
I think they thought it was going
to favor Anthony. Joshua for sure.
They want him to win but
actually favored. Um, yeah,
they, yeah. Well you agree with the
decision. Yes. Parker definitely lost.
But I can only agree
where people are like,
oh Auntie Joshua look batty an off
night. No, no, you morons. The,
and Polly mentioned this, the distance
they fall in such a high level,
no one got hit. And Parker is such a
good boxer. His Jab is so goddamn good.
It was just a battle
of straight skill man.
And I thought it was so impressive
and people walk away from gun man,
Anthony Joshua is not that good on it,
man.
He's better than I
thought he can box waiver.
And I thought well it's cause you
understand the people that say what?
It's not that good cause he didn't win
by spectacular knockouts like Deontay
wilder. Correct. Wilder.
That's uh, that's interesting.
The wilder fight is very interesting
because while their talks a ton of shit,
he's exciting. He's brash, he's
got serious knockout power. Crazy.
He, he's fun to watch, man.
And he's like a brash American,
you know, that's a great,
it's a great fight. What are they
going to do that it was wilder.
I have to fight somebody first.
It sounds like Josh was going to fight
someone else and Wilders gun fight song.
Why are they doing that? That's so
stupid. So stupid. Not boxed in this.
It's so stupid.
Well,
they build it up to make this big giant
event and when it comes off like, look,
it comes off. It comes off like
Pacquiao versus Mayweather was giant.
It's the number one problem with boxing.
Give us the matchups.
Everyone wants to see.
That's why the UFC gain so much
ground because usually Dane,
besides the aspirin can be usually
when there's a fight, Danny goes, boom,
there you go. Super. You want
see steep ADC. Boom. There
you go. Yup. Colorado. Boom.
There you go. So we get all
the Connor. There you go.
So we had these super fights
in boxing like, no, no, listen,
we want to do this and
this guy's a mandatory.
I managed this guy and this
guy's PBC bucks and sky showtime.
So saw this red tape. It'd be a phenomenal
fight. It'd be a phenomenal fight.
Phenomenal fight. It's going
to happen. I think it happens.
I don't know if happens under this year,
but I just can't believe triple g and
Canelo are not going to fight that such a
both. I feel like it's not even, I
mean what is today date is April 5th.
It's a month away and they haven't even,
they haven't even put the, uh, the,
the hearing together, the hearing is
like what the 18th there's some CML.
It backed out. Why did he
back out? I just don't the,
I think he knew the odds were against
him and backed out and then, you know,
triple g still planning
on finding May 5th wow.
Still going to fight and I was
hoping he cause he gonna fight.
I'd love it if he fought
Billy Joe Saunders.
But Joe Saunders can't fight till
June. So why Triptan uh, cause he has,
he's coming off a hand injury
but he's like, I'm ready in June,
let's do it in June. If I'm
cooking, if I'm tripleG ,
I'm not finding May 5th you're going to
sell 30 paper views when Canelo drops
out, whoever the replace with,
it's not going to be a huge name.
I'm sure it's gonna be a tough guy. It's
going be a worthy opponent to be tough.
You know it's not gonna make you bank.
You make bank up your paper view.
Just fight and fight and fight fucking
Billy Joe Saunders in June for us. Yeah,
but the problem is they don't have the
date in June when you look at a venue
like the tee ball mill arena in Vegas,
that motherfucker is booked
up for UAA and advanced. Yeah.
Except for the Mayweather. Mcgregor
fight. The Mayweather Mcgregor fight.
They found an opening.
I said,
let's do it because now you're dealing
with the box and commission. Yeah.
Didn't have to pay.
They have to pay ice cubes.
Basketball league had a
books that it had paid,
like he's keeps basketball league.
How much do we have a league?
I heard 6 million. 6 million to w and
then they didn't like the parking lot,
but it's three on three basketball for
so ice cube, get the fuck out the way.
I'll watch three on three at the rack.
I'm not trying to see these old basketball
players play three on three get the
fuck out so we can watch
Conor versus Floyd. Don't give
us any hassle. Basketball.
This is three and three league.
It is.
It have a bunch of old like college
players and some old NBA players and they
play a three on three
half court game put on TV.
It was like done every week and a
different city and like a table,
a four point shot.
It's like if there is a master's leak
and you could only use your left jab,
that's what it's like in the
sons of bitches. Karate is back.
New World, full contact.
Karate Combat League kicks off.
Is this with the Bas Rutten just
announced today? Yeah. Yeah.
Bas Rutten is the a commentator.
Commentator. He's coming on.
He might have something to
do with the organization.
Two bosses coming on next week to
talk about it. El Guapo in the house.
Love boss too. They play in a pit
or they fight rather in a pit.
It's a shape like Sam. Pick at
it. Look at it, see it. Oh Bro.
Chuck Norris did this shit and
it's the way to go, man. Oh yeah.
Worked out great for chuck.
Look at what did work out great.
He had a lot of successful shows
and have a fight booked. April 20th
Wonderboy flat fight with
karate pants onto it looks like.
So they're fighting with little gloves on,
but they're wearing karate pants.
It's going to be in the Olympics,
not this
exact thing, but cries and Olympics for
the next Friday's in the Olympics. Yeah.
I'll tell you right now, all
these fives better. Pray to God.
Wonderboy doesn't get a feather up.
His ass decide to join this league or
Raymond Daniels. Yes. Worldclass guys. Oh,
you're shooting now.
Can you kick to the legs on it?
You better be able to kick the
legs. You can fuck it for sure.
Find a sandpit though.
They should fight in a basketball court.
Oh God Nah. Stop that. We can't,
I can't say fight in a
basketball court period.
Don't let him get too close to the fans.
Don't want him to do go three rounds
of three minutes, three minutes.
Offensive techniques scored more
highly than counter strikes.
This is karate is back.
Approximately 50 million Americans have
participate in crowded some point in
their lives and then I, and then I grew
the hall. You got to stop with that.
I grew the fuck up. Then I realized, oh,
I'm not learning shit that John Claude
did in the movies and this isn't fun
anymore.
Yeah.
When someone says that karate
approximately 50 million
Americans and participate
in karate at some point they're like,
yeah,
little kids taking fucking karate classes.
My seven year old's awesome man.
Correct? Yeah. That's great. I
was a yellow duck out of here.
The problem with karate is we already
know about MMA and we already know about
Muy Thai,
but ng Jitsu would I do like is if they're
allowed leg kicks and they have the
small gloves on, it's basically like
it's MMA fight, but I'll stand there.
It's all standing, but also
then I can allow low kicks. God,
it got a lot leg kicks.
That's a huge fuck up.
If they know a lot like cake boss
just to calm Taylor, he's in on it.
I know it was promoter. I don't know how
I'm going to want to find out next week,
but I would,
I would hope that they allow leg kicks.
I don't even like the glory doesn't
allow elbows. I feel like I agree.
I think that's the sport. The sport
is, if you're going to stand up,
it should be more time. I mean that, that
to me is the sport. The rules of Morita.
You could throw a wheel kicks in Muay
Thai, you get through a flying side kicks,
you do whatever the fuck you want,
but you also can do Moitai like
needs the body, elbows to the face,
all those super effective close range
techniques that glory doesn't allow,
but I think they're worried about what
the elbows guys aren't going to be able
to fight, you know, close together because
they almost cause the cuts. However,
I'd rather deal with that
then not allow it. Oh,
well I don't like the guys
fighting close together.
I think that's super dangerous,
but when you have guys fight
more than one time and at night,
I think that is fucking crazy.
When you have guys fight two,
three times a night like Joe Schilling
did in the La last man standing event
that is bananas like you are,
you're taking a giant chance.
You're hoping that someone doesn't get
severely concussed even in a win and
their first fight and then come back
and fight in the Senate and make it fun
though. Like that's kind
of the nature of the game.
Like what about wrestling against the
double A's? Those guys, Russell filtering,
head kicked,
they're cutting massive way.
They are cutting massive weight but
they're not getting head kicked,
getting getting head kicked in the first
round and getting up at the count of
seven later and fighting and then
getting head kicked again an hour later.
It's nuts. It's crazy. I just
don't like it. It's just to,
and also you don't get the best guy
versus the best guy in an even right.
Like
if one guy wins by first round knock out,
the other guy has a four round
war like Joe Schilling doing.
He fought Simon Marcus,
right? Crazy fight. They go
to three rounds. It's a draw.
They go to the third and Joe had been
knocked down I think in that first.
And then Joe's arched him in the fourth.
Isn't that crazy? If you know the sport,
you're like, Damn, look how
these guys just get through this.
They've dealt with this and
now it's kind of cool but,
but we know the repercussions.
Most people don't write well then the UFC
should bring back a tournament to then.
I'm not mad at that. The pride
tournaments, it's so old school it's in.
People are probably gonna
die cause guys so good now.
But it's what you sign up for with the
problem as if one guy goes through three
rounds of hell and the other guy just
lands like a Connor straight left hand
they did on Aldo and wins in 13 seconds.
It's just not fair. I know and you know,
but,
but however that guy pulled off that 13
second knock out another guy had a war.
It's true. It's true. It's
true. It's true. I mean,
Gloria is the only organization right
now that's mainstream where you could
watch guys fight more than once in the
night. I do it all the time. Here's the,
here's the point. Why do
UFC is never going to do it
and most sports won't do it.
It's hard to a, it's, it's a long show. B,
it's hard to market that it
shouldn't be sanctioned. No,
I mean there's a reason why it's not your,
you're in the right here.
There's a reminder tonight,
I play devil's advocate,
but the reason why it's not is because
the math is they're like, well,
Attison it were just saw,
get kicked in the face fighting again.
They sanctioned it for kickboxing,
but they don't sanction that for MMA.
Isn't that weird?
Because like last man standing was in la.
We saw that at the fucking forum.
That was, uh, that was right here.
The whole,
the whole rules are where the judge,
and we've talked about this before and
that's why I was so intrigued about the,
uh, Tony First and fight, and this is
why I, I did a standup at, uh, this,
uh, San Jose Improv and in the front
row and I didn't know that there can be,
there was all of teammate Kay,
John Fitch Thompson and stuff
like that and a after the show.
So in front of them asked me this before
first and dropped them at Ferguson
could be who's going to win? And
I, I, it was a toss up for me,
but because I thought Tony was gonna do
work off his back when he was going to
land crazy amount of elbows
and fucked up could be face,
but because it could be was on top,
he'd get the wind via decision and I said,
the losers are going to be the judges
because they won't know how to judge that
fight and say that in front
of the AK team was awkward.
Depends upon how it plays out, but if it
plays out the way you described it, yeah.
If, if Tony is landing big shots from
the bottom, submission threats, elbows,
his face getting bloody,
but Khabib's doing work on top,
but Tony's still threatened
elbows, elbows, this fucking
them up. It's possible.
But if could be malls, him,
which should be real clear.
We don't judge them when we got it.
I see that now. And that is a sin.
That's a sin against humanity. They says
we won't. That says we will never see it.
He said, he said crazy shit like John
Jones never be in a main event again.
He said a lot of crazy shit true.
He says this pushing gets a title
shot and then someone else does.
I think he's emotional. He's
upset. I'd be pissed too.
But also thinking about money, he's
missed out on it. That'd be it.
If they tried it again and be the
fifth time trying to promote this,
is that also really,
this is the fourth they've dropped out
or if they've tried to make this fight,
that's in Sean Shelby and
Josiah was trying to make
this fight before he retired.
The one five you want to make never
happen. So if you're Dana, you're like,
hold up, how much money have we
put in marketing to these fox?
And it just doesn't happen for us.
We're down in. That does happen.
You gotta do it.
You know,
you said that you didn't believe it was
going to happen until you saw the door
bolt and they're standing next to each
other and here we are. Yeah, you're right.
It's such a shame.
You're the first person I texted when I
saw it cause we were talking about how
sad we'd be.
It's a jet bomber,
but this is the next best thing.
No, the next best thing is Connor.
This is the next best. Next, the next.
This the next best thing on
a six days' notice. Yeah.
You would never get Connor on six days.
No, it is. No, but if Connor would have,
Connor was scheduled to fight. See the
thing about a Connor at this stages,
there's no tuneup fights.
It's, there's never, it's never
going to happen again. No.
Like every fight is just giant.
Only fight where where it'd be a level
playing field would be Nate Diaz cause
he's been out just as long.
So you're both going to be,
have a little bit of ring rust.
You're both can be out for a long time.
You're both going through the same thing.
You find a guy like Khabib.
Do you think they offered it to Nate?
Who Do think they offered it?
So we know they offered
it to the Ortega Ortega.
Eddie Alvarez and Alvaris had no,
right? Yeah. Why did he say no?
I'm not sure right now. Oh yeah,
he's one 90 he's been doing it too
long. He said he's like, one night,
I'm not making that son. He said,
I'm all of one night. I love Alvarez.
Imagine losing 35 fucking pounds.
How much? And if you know,
please say it for everyone,
how much you think they paid Max Holloway
to take this site? Six Day notice.
And they go, Bro, we know you're a champ
at one 45 here's the offer. Oh wait,
we're just giving you this much.
All I know is what Eddie told
me on the podcast about Tony,
you said he was going to make millions.
So if that's what we know,
we've got,
assume there's a big paycheck and it
for Max Holloway, I told Brian Goes,
how much you think he's in
pain? I said, if I'm Max,
I don't take that fight for
under 4 million. I know they're,
they're in a tough position and they
need a big name and then trying to recoup
the paper views.
So I got them backed in a corner.
I'm on the longest winning streak.
I'm saying 4 million or bust. Ooh,
you're a bold man.
I'd say two till after taxes.
That's not worth it. That's fucked
that out when you're fighting Khabib.
Now why? Ah, I need a
million for every day.
So six days. So he said,
you know, you know,
Max can submit people, but
we don't anticipate him.
Surbiton could be. It just,
it seems like cubbies grapplings
on a higher level than Max.
It seems like the way Max can win this
fight is by pacing because Max is,
even if Max is not in shape, he's in
phenomenal shape. I mean he's just,
he's got an incredible cardio
and he really knows how
to pace himself very well.
Pacing if it's more of a style of fight
and if it's at his temple to beep goes
watch a tempo and just throws
in a blender. Yeah, he's so,
and it's a six day notice and it's
a Max who was taking time off,
spend time with his family. So all the
chips are stacked against Max, all of it.
And it's a weight class
above his weight class.
It's a Khabib who's a huge one 55 it's
arguably the best grappler in the UFC.
And the other promise,
he really doesn't attain the standup game.
So your chance of the one,
the home run shot,
it's even dropped even lower.
That's what I'm saying for mill.
Did you hear what he said about it?
He said thank you too for taking fights.
I don't think you'll ever be the
same again. Oh, I said I have foss.
I don't think of that'd be the
same again and pry not aligned.
That's a dark thing to say to not just,
Oh my God,
I'll never be the same again.
Ah, it breaks my heart.
Did we might say hope he's wrong
and you know, you know I do.
If I was in Max's corner and if,
and if it's like halfway through
the second round and I'm like, damn,
Maxx looks exhausted. He's not in shape.
He's just taken a beaten. He's so tough.
He's probably last five rounds.
I've thrown that towel.
I'm going to take all the shit for the,
from the fans because I don't want Max
dealing with this because this isn't,
this isn't his fight to be honest.
This isn't his fight. This isn't,
his path was going to make
4 million round hopefully.
And he's gonna be set for life financial
if he's smart with his money. However,
this isn't his path. We did this
to help out the UFC. He made bank.
There's a towel. Fuck you. I know
you're, you're in hate me Max.
We'll talk in Hawaii over bull of
a Ahi tuna. That's not a bad idea.
Well if we know we,
I think with a could fight,
one of the things is after the first round
you kind of know how it's going to go.
Well No,
and split the thing too from act suit.
If he had 12 weeks and he's in phenomenal
shape and he gets taken down all a
kind of Chad Mendez, Conor McGregor
when cargo tank. Now we're like,
it's just matter of time where Mount
Mount of time you're going to catch him.
But with this could be in better shape.
He's had more time.
He's been preparing for a guy
who's insane cardio shape.
So it's just the odds are so
fucked for Max. Crazy, crazy,
really quite stressed.
So stressed as I was unexplained
myself, I'm stressed out. Wow.
It's going to be interesting to me.
Interesting man.
That's going to be a good one.
So we were talking before it,
lets wrap this up but before
talking about for this,
we want to do a fight companion,
but there's no fights that were all
around for a fight companion. So let's,
let's do a fight companion.
Get all the boys in here and put on
some fights during the random night or
something like that. Ran like a
fucking Tuesday or some shit. And My,
maybe you were a compete us.
Yeah.
I'm hearing pizza right now and then
we'll wait. We'll save for a cheat meal.
How about neither one of his cheat until
that night. Okay. Deal. It's a deal deal.
I'll get the pizzas.
Let's wrap this bitch up.
Brendan Schaub a big brown breakdown.
No below the Pelicans. No worries.
No worries. Well not the podcast is
renamed below the belt. Oh really? Yeah.
Oh, it's still on my show. You know what
I'm saying? So Michelle below the belt.
Yeah. The name of your podcast,
just so it's all in. Go.
Yeah. Okay. I like it. Yeah,
like it.
Next episodes,
a number four episode next Wednesday
night and then she sat k.com find the kid
and then a Friday night Bakersfield.
There's 30 tickets left this Friday night.
Tomberlin brewering and some is, is that
I gets a good spot. I love Bakersfield.
That was exciting and fun,
man.
I had a great time and biggest fear and
there this Friday night and then, uh,
April 20th, 21st Calgary Yuk,
yuks boom. Beautiful Houston June.
Okay, love you. Bye everybody.