Hey everybody,
we're doing a podcast again.
Can you believe it?
Can you believe we even still alive
after that Shane Smith podcast,
the podcast for everyone who thought
it was the best podcast ever.
Thank you for everyone
who tweeted me and said,
it sucked.
I'm sorry.
Who are these people
that think that sucked?
That was fucking fun.
Everybody has the right
to their own opinion,
sir.
Okay.
And I'm my apologies to,
to anybody who did,
we didn't mean to get that fucked up.
That's just what happens when you
drink with Shane Smith of vice.com.
I think that was the second time.
The second most drunk I've ever seen you.
Yeah,
it was pretty,
pretty hammered this episode of the Joe.
Some guy sent me a message like that.
He went to the comedy show and
he was mad at me because I,
uh,
I made a cancer joke.
I'm like,
I don't have a cancer joke in my act,
man.
I don't if I said,
I don't know where it came from.
I Dunno.
He said the cancer joke was not cool.
It was like,
I don't think I have one man.
Maybe it was a drunken joke.
I can't see where I would,
I'm pretty sure at the end of that show
that I know when I'm trying new stuff
out or when I'm venturing
off into strange territory.
I don't think there was any of that.
This episode of the Joe Rogan experience,
Bud Kist is brought to
you by Ting Ting is uh,
first of all they are,
I'm a supporter of this podcast because
we believe in companies that are not
trying to rip people off that are given
you a good service at a reasonable price
and have reasonable rules.
I don't like contracts
with cell phone companies.
I think it's gross.
I understand it.
When you buy a phone,
say if you buy a phone from
Verizon and you'd get it for,
you know,
x amount of dollars.
If you sign up for three year service,
when he tried to cancel,
they hit you with a big fee.
The reason why they hit you with that
big fee is because you didn't really pay
for the whole price of that cell phone.
They sort of factor it in over the course
of three years and then when you want
to cancel,
they want that money back.
Okay.
I think that's silly.
It's just like it's,
it's not necessary.
Okay.
And it's also not necessary to,
to have it set up where you like,
you can't have two
people in the same plan.
Um,
ting has that.
They have it set up so that you can,
first of all,
no contracts you can buy.
They have high level android phones,
the best android phones available,
including the Samsung Galaxy s three
soon to be as far I think it's coming out
really soon.
And the uh,
Samsung Galaxy note to
really cool cell phones.
So you,
you don't have to deal with crappy phones.
You're also dealing
with the sprint network.
So it's not like they
have their own network.
They have a major network.
It's excellent service.
I've got nothing but people saying
good things about it on Twitter.
Ever since we started
having them as a sponsor,
including people saying how
much they've been saving.
Now,
one of the things that I really love
about Ting is credits on unused service.
I just think this is such a great idea.
There's plans,
but if you use less than
you thought you would,
tink drops you down to the
level that you hit and you,
they credit you the
difference on your next bill.
You can't ask for anything more than that.
It's good service.
It's a good company and
it's all reasonable.
And if you go to rogan.ting.com
and you can save yourself 25 bucks,
either off service or off one
of their groovy cell phones.
And by the way that they have
used ones also as you know,
and they're just refurbished ones and I
haven't bought refurbished ones through
tank,
but I bought refurbished phones before
and then there are a lot cheaper.
So if you're looking for
a phone on the cheap,
you could even get,
you know,
get like the Samsung Galaxy
s two epic four g touch,
you know,
and that's like a lot cheaper than,
buying it new.
So if you even need a cheaper phone,
you can.
You have to use marketplace also at tig.
Yeah,
and the reality is,
unless you're like some crazy power user,
you know,
if you're on a budget,
you can get by with a phone that was
really cool a couple of years ago and you
want to get him to notice it
barely makes a difference.
It does pretty much the same shit.
I love that Samsung Galaxy s
three and I love the screen.
It's amazing.
Once you go to that screen for
looking at web pages or the note,
which was even more,
more insane,
you'll love it.
All right,
so go there.
Rogan dot [inaudible] dot
com save yourself some cash.
We're also brought to you by
Squarespace and Squarespace.
If you never use them before.
It's really cool new service that is an
all in one website development service
where you can do it all yourself.
You go to squarespace.com forward
slash Joe and you can try it out.
If you go to squarespace.com forward
slash Joe you don't even have to enter in
your credit card.
Just try it out.
Start building your website.
They also have online commerce.
It's super easy to set up.
You can create your online store
ridiculously fast and easy.
You can choose from over 20 bad
ass designs for cell phones.
Really cool stuff if you've
never tried it before.
I know nothing about coding.
Brian's actually coded websites on
notepad with html and all that jazz.
But for a person like me that I am
not going to learn how to do this,
it's not happening.
But I've gone to Squarespace.
I've checked out there.
It's very intuitive the way
they have it set up and I,
I'm very confident that I
could set up my own website.
So they have it there where,
um,
you,
you also,
um,
you can even eat,
it gets 24 seven support.
You get a free domain name
if you sign up for a year.
So go to squarespace.com
forward slash Joe to try it out.
You don't have to pay anything,
but if you decide to purchase it,
use the offer code Joe Three,
that's Joe and a number three,
three because of March,
and you'll get 10% off your
first purchase on new accounts,
including monthly and annual plans.
Okay,
so that's squarespace.com forward slash
Joe and use the offer code Joe Three.
If you want to try it out
and save yourself some cash
and it's really cheap,
like their highest price plan for like
unlimited bandwidth and storage and
everything is $24.
That's their most expensive plan.
Yeah,
that's awesome.
We live in strange times,
folks.
Yeah,
it's cool.
It's cool that you can do that.
It's cool that you can build
your own websites really.
And I'm not exaggerating at all.
Wait,
wait til you go and try it out.
It's excellent.
It's,
it's a really cool service.
We're also brought to you by on.com
a lot of new stuff in it on it.
If you've never seen any of the
fitness equipment that we have now,
um,
we have,
uh,
pull up bars,
jump ropes,
steel maces,
steel clubs,
kettle bells,
battle ropes,
all kinds of stuff for functional fitness.
I can only do this commercial so many
times before it becomes ridiculously
redundant.
So if you've heard this
podcast a few times,
you'll probably fucking hate me already.
Uh,
cool stuff.
As far as a supplements,
including health supplements,
like Himalayan salt and
killer bee honey and MCT oil,
uh,
we,
we even sell Blendtec blenders.
We sell basically things
that can aid you in your,
your,
your physical performance,
your mental performance.
You're just supplements and fitness
equipment to make you better at life.
Bitch.
All right.
You use a code name,
Rogan,
and you will save 10% off
any and all supplements.
And as I said,
we have a plethora of them.
I remember in the old days
when we first started out,
I'd be able to named you.
I just,
a couple of them might say,
Hey,
go,
I'll try some Alpha brain.
Try some shrimp tech.
Now it's just ridiculous.
I'm not even gonna try,
but go check it out.
Enjoy on it.com code named Brogan.
Save 10% off any and all supplements.
All right,
folks.
Jacob Ward is here from
Popular Science magazine.
We're going to get freaky.
We're going to learn some shit.
We're going to educate the masses.
They're up his Twitter account,
the Joe Rogan experience.
Try it by day.
Joe Rogan podcast by night.
Powerful Jacob Ward.
But you prefer Jake,
right?
I do.
Yeah.
Call me Jake.
Jacob is very biblical dude.
I gotta tell you I'm sold
on all of your sponsors.
Really?
I don't know if you are what?
I see a lot of pitches during my day.
You know,
I spend my professional daylight.
Look at,
people are pitching me all the time.
Stuff's cool.
And you actually made the sound of the,
of the,
the name of the galaxy,
uh,
sound cool,
which is impossible as the worst.
This the longest name performance.
A great piece of technology
with a terrible name.
Yeah.
Galaxy x three galaxy note four.
It's just too long.
I know they cut a lot of phones,
but I was just thinking
that the other day.
Why don't they just call it like,
there's a lot of names in this world.
I'm here to tell you.
Yeah.
The,
there's no need for that.
Right?
Why does everything have to be
note this and three and four,
right.
I don't know.
But the tech,
I mean,
the stuff itself is amazing
and you're absolutely right.
They're like a couple of years old phone.
He's a great deal.
Like those,
they change so fast.
Yeah.
Especially the Samsung phones.
Apple,
you have to wait a couple of years for
a new iPhone because each one has to
knock it out of the park.
You gotta go all the way with apple.
Yeah,
but I'm not,
I don't have the confidence in them
without Steve jobs at the helm.
I need a crazy person.
Completely obsessed with success.
Totally regular Tim Cook Fella.
He's terms like a regular dude.
Yeah.
I,
I don't know enough about him.
He's supposedly a very orderly person,
which you would need.
Like,
at the very least,
you got to run the hell out of that place.
I think when he gets home,
he probably relaxes and I don't need that.
I need that in my seat.
Yeah.
You need a guy driving around,
pissed off at coders because
they got something wrong.
And Google maps with Tacoma,
you know?
That's right.
It's fucking Tacoma,
Washington at the wrong
place or whatever it is,
whatever it is it Steve
jobs go bananas for.
Right.
How long have you been the
editor of Popular Science?
So I had a,
I had a crazy experience.
I was the second in command at
puppet science for five years.
I was like the doer and a,
and then my boss decided to leave and I
got promoted about seven months ago and
suddenly like I'm,
I'm running 140 year old magazine.
I'll tell you right now,
it's a big responsibility.
And I am,
I feel free and you know,
I freak out each morning for five minutes.
I'm like,
I can't believe I'm about to go
make these decisions and then boom,
I go off and do it.
It's a great thing that an honor.
Um,
the,
the popular science episode that I a or
a issue that I quote to people all the
time is the one way
back in the 1930s camps.
A new billion dollar crop.
Totally.
We were way out in advance of that.
That's what's cool about popular science.
It's like we are,
we're at least five or 10 years ahead of,
you know,
we put our flag into each issue.
If you look through history,
I can't take credit for that personally,
but it's really cool that it happened.
You know,
that was on the cover of popular,
oh,
it was actually popular mechanics.
That's cool.
I hear,
I'll clear up the confusion.
For a lot of people,
people were like,
why are,
why is there popular mechanics,
popular science on this stuff and why
aren't we the same magazine were actually
competitors,
which is a weird thing,
but it's because we date from the era
when everything had the word popular with
the front of it,
popular portraiture,
popular,
you know,
whatever it was the name.
It was basically saying like,
hey normal person,
come read this thing.
You don't have to be an expert.
Unfortunately I was incorrect.
Um,
popular science actually
demonized Marilyn.
That's probably true.
We probably did way back in 1936 it was
when the government had gotten their
greedy little pause.
Let's be fair.
You know,
that's the depths of the depression.
Everyone's freaking out,
you know,
that is not you.
And that is not the
popular science of today.
And blaming popular science for that
would be like blaming me for killing
Indians and to be truthful like
there's worst stuff in that.
And the history of pumping science.
We have tea,
we have a cover in the middle of World
War Two that has a this like cartoonish
caricature of a Japanese.
Yeah.
And the,
and his,
if you look at the Google a archive that
we have and bracket it on either side
of that man's face is you know how we're
going to drop missiles from you know,
tanks,
fighter jets,
you know,
like there was everything is military
hardware and I decided to look at the
archives of pumps and I
said is to look at a uh,
like an art project that is the history
of America and what we were thinking
about at the time,
but written in these really cool covers.
So it's pretty sick.
Back in the day there was so
much more responsibility to,
to deliver this kind of
information with all respect.
You would not be on the air in 1936.
Like the,
the access to technology,
right.
The fact that you and I get
to have this conversation,
people are listening,
right?
We're just such an amazing
and wonderful thing.
He's so new.
I wouldn't have been on the
air in 96 have no real options.
That's interesting in this game.
Long enough to know,
right?
Yeah,
that's right.
That's right.
It's a,
yeah.
It's a whole new world.
And,
and,
uh,
back then,
you know,
the pre Walter Cronkite man to get on air.
Holy cow is that heart you,
you know,
the amount of work,
the amount of letter writing
on letters to negotiate,
you know,
whether that guy is going
to be a guest on Cronkite,
you know,
oh my God.
And the ability to control the public's
perceptions of things back then was so
complete.
Like what Harry Anslinger and William
Randolph Hearst did controlling the,
the public's perception on that.
You had to be so,
you know,
brilliant and kind of scary to
rise to the top of the money.
And you know,
especially in the end to have enough of
a fortunate that you lasted through the
30s.
Like you gotta be carnivorous human being.
You know,
you're a scary dude.
And then if you put something in your
magazine or in your newspaper back then,
that was doctrine.
Well,
yeah,
but here's the thing where I would say,
I see where you're going with it.
And I with you halfway there,
I think the William Randolph
Hearst to the world,
you know,
we're very crazy and very rich
and it was powerful stuff.
But the people that you hire in
to run your editorial product,
you know,
or you the person you hire in to
be your publicity guy back then.
I mean you think,
think about the generation
that generated Apollo,
right?
And all that stuff.
Like those,
those guys were raised in the values of
you do the best possible job you can.
You repay hard work with hard work.
And you know,
it was,
it was an earnest group.
And so,
you know,
I'm looking like my dad,
uh,
is a writer.
My uncle's a writer,
everybody in my family comes out of this
sort of New York magazine world in some
way.
And it's a real meritocracy.
People who are really
trying now that said,
there was a lot of other stuff.
Everybody's white,
everybody's man.
Like there's a lot of other
limitations to the good old days,
the good old,
I mean,
it's what it was.
That's what it was,
you know?
But now,
you know,
it's a,
but the,
the to now be able to be on the air,
you know,
with you like this,
it's just cool.
It's fun and more people can,
can listen to it than ever before.
Everybody can listen to this.
It's all so cool.
I've heard people say
that they believe that,
uh,
in today's era the Watergate would have
never happened and that that's sort of a
sting operations against some hasn't.
Oh my God.
Not only would it not have happened,
it would be on 5,000 galaxy s three,
five,
whatever the name of the phones are.
Maybe.
So everybody would have filmed it.
Yeah.
You're not going to able to get
away with anything in the future.
People I'd like everyone to know that's
an important message from Popular
Science magazine.
Behave yourself.
Uh,
law enforcement's about to get serious.
They're going to know
exactly what's going on.
Here's a crazy thing that I did a
story a little while ago about this.
Um,
there's a thing called IARPA,
which is a,
and I have to choose my words carefully
cause this is a sort of a complicated
thing but like,
or you know,
sensitive thing.
But anyway,
IARPA is a,
is the,
it's an advanced research projects
agency for the intelligence community,
right?
There's Darpa which does it
for the Defense Department.
I are but does it for a coalition,
each of like the,
you know,
the NSF,
CIA,
whoever will kick in doe and everybody
funds little incubator projects of
research to see,
you know,
can you do stuff and you
basically the way you,
what'd you do is you issue a challenge
to the public and you say anybody who
can,
who can do this get to $1 million,
you know,
or whatever the prize is.
And that's how robot
cars first started out.
You know,
those guys,
the Darpa urban challenges,
how these Google's self
driving cars are coming about.
But this one,
there were these two projects
that I bumped into and the,
and mind you,
I'm,
I can't tell you for sure that these,
that the implications of this
are what I think they are.
But here's what the
programs themselves do.
The challenge is,
uh,
the challenges.
Uh,
can you identify a visual information
in video basically such that,
uh,
if I,
um,
am looking for,
well,
so here's the,
here's the first challenge.
The first challenge is from the
visual information in the photograph,
right?
You're looking at it for a computer,
looks at a photograph,
and from the visual
information inside of it,
it knows exactly where
the photo was taken.
Whoa.
Does that make sense?
Right.
Triangulate from the visual
location information and you know,
right.
You got to be a hardcore New Yorker
to be able to spot a photograph of any
corner in New York City and
know exactly where you are.
Right.
That's a hard thing,
right?
Imagine a computer designed
just to do that thing,
you know,
a piece of software that
can do exactly that thing.
Would it be able to triangulate in
anywhere in the world based on where the
light sources coming?
You don't know?
Yeah.
I don't know.
I don't know if it would
know like time of year.
Right.
It might be able to someday.
That's,
that'll be possible.
Then I think someone was
busted recently with something,
I don't remember the specifics of,
uh,
what it was with someone.
Someone was claiming to be somewhere
when they took a photo and then some
analysts looked at the photo and said,
that's not possible because this
photo was taken and this Hematoma,
Taylor and the light source from here.
So it had to be taken in the afternoons.
Totally.
It's all data,
right?
That data is out there.
It's just can you parse that data
fast enough and in this case,
these computer programs or are saying,
okay,
can you triangulate?
Everybody has.
Then the other,
another one they're working on
is can you feed a query into the,
into the,
the data,
the database and have it return,
uh,
information not based on,
you know,
how,
like on Youtube you'll see,
uh,
you know,
the tags at the bottom,
right?
I mean,
I'm sure on under our pocket pad tags,
Joe Rogan,
whatever,
those keywords help everyone's
search and organize it themselves.
Right?
But this is a program that can go in
and look at the visual information of
what's being shown in front of it.
And be able to come back with a correct,
you know,
a set of photographs or videos that,
that you know,
correspond to those search terms.
Google image search.
Nowadays you can upload a photo and it
will show you pretty much every similar
photo and show you where that
floaters in both Facebook and Google.
You've got the ones that were the,
it says,
who's this,
right?
I,
I put pictures of my daughter
up on the end of that,
you know,
to show my,
her grandparents and uh,
you know,
uh,
it will say,
who is this,
you know,
or whatever.
There's little question
mark over her face like,
who is this little cutie?
And I'm like,
I'm not telling you a Google.
Yeah,
don't want him to,
I don't want
you to know that.
On the other hand,
Google,
you know those,
there were some good hearted engineers
there who probably have a really good,
useful thing for us for being able to
find pictures of your daughter wherever
they are.
I mean,
that might be useful.
It would definitely be useful.
But it seems like we're resisting
the inevitable with a lot of this.
A retaining privacy rights and things.
Interesting.
I had fight should go on maybes.
I think it should.
I think it shouldn't,
first of all,
because one of the real issues is
that along the way on this fight,
the,
the issue is being decided by people.
People are deciding whether or
not they can read your email.
People in the government
of deciding whether or not
they can listen to your cell
phone and how are they qualified and how
are they moral and how were they better
than you?
Or how were they as good as you,
we don't know anything about them,
but yet they can look at your Dick Pics.
Yeah,
you're totally right.
You know what I'm saying?
I mean,
if that's wrong.
And,
and how did they get government person,
right?
I mean,
are they really ambitious and are they
really ethical or are they someone who
really seeks to change the world?
Or are they just some Schlub who,
you know,
backhand that is way up to the top
and now he's reading your email?
I like to believe that the people I,
you know,
I believe in civic institutions.
I believe they really can function,
especially when they come
out of the generation.
It's,
you know,
two generations ago,
there's some nice stuff.
Just there's some good dutiful
people still in this world,
you know,
and I'm,
I'm very cynical about that stuff too,
but I,
I,
I'm surprised how often,
like I was just a thing the other day,
uh,
at the U S Air Force Academy in Colorado.
It was a,
uh,
one of these challenge programs
and he's very students,
you know,
young like undergraduate
age air force cadets,
you know,
marines where they were.
We're coming forward with their like
cool science fair project basically.
And this little panel of generals
were saying this one or that one,
it was very cool.
But,
uh,
um,
at the beginning of it,
the guy who is running the show,
the MC or whatever,
you know,
military solid and ordered Mc is,
but,
uh,
stands up and says,
hello,
you know,
describes the attorney.
I said,
but before I begin,
I'd like everyone in the room to take a
look at the emergency exits over to your
left.
And then there's one in the back
and then there's one over here.
And as he pointed at each place,
everyone in the room,
military cadets,
look to the one on the right and the
one behind them and the one on the left,
you know,
they're,
they're totally,
uh,
and it turns out like when
you go with the program,
sometimes good things result.
It's cool.
Like to be in a place where
when things catch fire,
everyone runs for the exit in
the way that you're supposed to.
You know,
like these,
like a rap concert.
Sure.
Right.
But,
you know,
it's just cool.
I find some of that order,
you know,
if you meet like a test pilot,
those guys are just money.
That's the world's most reliable person.
You know,
I definitely believe in destiny,
not with a bottle of whiskey and,
but yeah,
I believe in the order and
I believe in discipline,
but I don't believe in other
people controlling people.
Well,
that's right.
That's the real issue.
That's exactly right.
Imposing you,
imposing your values on me.
It's not okay.
Right.
And,
and posing the ability to control
people by having their inflammation,
right.
It's just,
it gets into weird areas when you don't
know the motives of the people looking
for the search or who's,
it's just so gray as
to who's allowed that.
And now that the,
this government,
this administration has made it so that
there's all sorts of Wa warrantless
wiretapping,
uh,
more,
um,
arrests and the ability to detain
citizens without any due process.
You have to have a lawyer anymore.
You don't all the checks and
balances that were in place.
So like someone's people,
a lot of people unfairly think that
if you criticize the way things are,
it's like,
oh,
he's an anarchist.
Oh,
he absolutely not.
I,
I believe there should be a
system of checks and balances,
but I also believe there should be cops.
I believe they should be lawyers.
There should be judges.
This should be jails.
Cause people,
human nature is that,
you know,
in the real world,
people fuck up.
Totally.
I mean we're,
I'm quite excited about the amount of,
like you were saying,
Watergate could never have happened.
Right.
We'd get been caught so quickly,
right.
The amount of,
of sort of,
um,
you know,
just the number of eyes on us right now
mean that people are going to behave
with some more and more,
but only if there is the threat of
punishment for messing around with that.
And,
and so I think that as,
as much as I want,
you know,
these incredible,
services,
the kinds of things that you,
you know,
cheap software,
a chief cheap website hosting,
it's a great idea,
you know,
the cheapening of democratizing
of stuff like your,
your sponsors or you know,
uh,
represent that kind of thing.
Um,
but in order for that to happen,
you have to have the threat of law.
You have to have that or
the threat of anonymous.
I think,
you know,
one of the things that I love about the
Internet is the rise of citizen activism
and people who have looked the morality
of the anonymous Internet is pretty
outstanding.
If you stop and think about the people
that that anonymous have gone after,
you know,
they've gone after some really fucked up
people and they've kind of decided as a
group,
you sort of just through the Internet
without even meeting in person,
yeah,
this is fucked up.
Let's expose this,
let's go after this.
And I think that's really encouraging
because people are anonymous and they're,
you know,
they just have the choice to do whatever
they want online and yet they decided
to try to right wrongs.
It's the most evolved form of democracy,
right?
It is so granular.
Yeah.
Like,
you know,
you've got a reliable way of measuring
public approval or disapproval on almost
any subject you can think of by
virtue of comments and the forums,
you know,
the participation that
we're all suddenly having.
I mean,
it turns out when you take away the
worry about being shamed in public,
people really,
you know,
do bold things.
They go out there and they
write manifestos and yeah,
you know,
there's so many.
I'm supposed to go off and do this,
uh,
speech to,
my college,
a writers conference.
And I was asked in advance,
you know,
what's the,
what's it like to be a writer now?
Is this a,
you know,
what is the state of
writing now or whatever.
And my feeling is it's like,
it's so nice to be,
it's such a good time.
I didn't say this,
somebody else originated this,
but um,
to be,
it's so much of a better time to be a
reader now than it ever has been before.
You know,
so much cool stuff to
read because everyone
can write,
everyone can get into print.
I read this the other day that 90% of the
world's data was generated in the last
two years.
Sure.
It's unbelievable how much data there is.
Right.
And we can't,
and it's a fire hose.
We don't really know how to Parse it.
Yeah.
Twitter is so primitive compared to
what we're going to have in 10 years.
You know what is going to be the next one?
That's a,
I never saw Twitter coming.
I never thought,
even when it came out I was like,
okay,
what the fuck is that?
I know 140 character text messaging to
anonymous people like that doesn't make
any sense.
Right.
And the the Guy Jack Dorsey who founded
Twitter has this brilliant thing where
basically he was geeking out on uh,
the patterns of cities.
He was way into um,
uh,
police scanners and stuff
and was tracking the,
the signals that I'm like Limo
Services Ping back and forth.
He was just interested in the like the
the flow of information that is generated
by cities and he saw that ambulances and
limo services and delivery trucks have
a system for saying where are you?
And then the truck could says back,
here I am,
you know,
there,
there needs to be a system
like that everywhere.
And his thing was let's give it to people.
People don't have a system for reporting
in their location and their status.
That's where status updates came from.
It's interesting cause that's what it
used to be but it's not really that
anymore.
What it's evolved to now,
at least on my Twitter,
my Twitter is all fascinating articles
that people send me that I retweet or
your neighborhood at Twitter
is different than mine.
It's really interesting.
I've already acquainted
with your father's not mine.
Oh Damn.
Like you know,
you get slaughtered up in here.
If you do something wrong,
it's,
yeah,
there's the light popular science.
Reduce this,
this,
these are freaks.
These are people out there on the fringes
with shotguns in the wrong aware when
the zombies attack.
I want your guys,
that's why guys can't help me.
That's right.
They know how to read our candidates,
how to hunt.
My guys would actually devise something,
some piece of software that lets you
control the Gatling gun and we'd all be
saved.
Well,
your guys would devise a new method
of power that didn't rely on oil.
Get together.
Zombies will be burning wood.
We'll have zombies like
walking on treadmills forever.
Generating power.
Yeah,
put a Zombie in a dog collar
and we can go to work for you.
Like a durable popular
science was the only magazine.
My Dad's and to you as a kid
growing up like since the 70s,
what was your dad?
What'd your dad do for a living?
It was an engineer.
Oh,
cool.
Yeah.
What kind of engineer?
Uh,
he builds huge batteries and backups
and stuff like that and huge dragons for
huge companies.
Like that's great.
Yeah.
He's tried to retire several times.
He's like,
I'm the master electrical engineer.
Yeah,
I bet he's in part of the old breed.
That's right.
He knows what he's,
what he's doing.
Yeah.
That's so cool.
Now you guys have
transferred onto the IPAD.
Yeah.
Now have you noticed the
subscription that paper based,
uh,
is,
is dying for shirts or is it,
here's what's so great about being,
about working with probably the science,
and this is why I'm so lucky to this
magazine I've inherited because there's a
lot of magazines,
a lot of problems of science is just like,
it's a universally beloved brand.
Like even people who don't
read it actively know or
have never even read no one.
It's,
you know,
like,
and so it's such a cool universal thing
to just walk in anywhere and be like
Papa Science.
And it was like,
oh my,
you stood by,
you know,
my dad reads that,
whatever it is.
And there's a cool sort of a
hipster subset of like guys like me.
I think that's what I imagine,
uh,
you know,
who,
who are starting to pick
it up in their twenties,
you know,
dig it as like just a thing
to sort of geek out on.
But it's got a really loyal
following in every medium.
Basically.
There's this,
you know,
there's a,
the veracious Internet hoards,
you know,
uh,
seizing massive of Internet guys
come to our site and are really,
you know,
brutal.
If we get it wrong,
they're great.
I mean,
exactly the kind of
engaged on as you want.
And in print we have people who,
you know,
that we pour a lot of effort
into the print magazine.
We really try and uphold,
you know,
you're paying money for it.
So man,
I'm working to make it as good as I can.
I'm glad it's still exist.
It's in print form.
It's great to take on an airplane.
You know,
it's great to,
it's a,
it's beautiful visually,
you know,
and you can find out so much about it.
Various things.
Now this episode that you're
a or issue or that you're a,
you're promoting is the brain issues,
brain issues.
So,
uh,
you know,
it's,
it's an amazing,
what's so cool about working about besides
that we get to touch on everything,
right?
We can do robots.
We got,
I mean literally I can,
I would come here anytime you want
to cause when we could talk forever.
Dog.
Sure.
Really Fun.
Call me dog.
Uh,
so,
uh,
the,
you know,
the brain is one of many
subjects we covered this one is,
um,
uh,
you know,
what's amazing about it is how little we
actually know when we are just starting
to noodle around.
Uh,
you know,
just around the sort of the
basic functions of the brain.
We don't really have any idea
how personality is built.
You know,
I mean we have some idea,
you know,
but like the subtleties,
like why we get along,
whatever,
all that stuff is totally unknown
in terms of how the brain functions,
but already just by literally poking
at the brain with Zapping it and stuff,
we can do amazing things already,
you know,
like ease the symptoms of terrible
diseases and do all kinds of crazy stuff.
But Hey,
before we get into the details of that,
cause I,
I,
here's the like,
can we talk about,
uh,
something I actually
wanted to ask you about,
which is,
um,
sort of fear in general,
the psychology,
like,
just thinking about like the subtleties
of personality and the brain in general.
I'm really interested by the,
like how different a person I am from
the people that can handle fear in any
real way.
And you,
I know,
have you had to watch people be really,
really good for living,
you know,
uh,
and still do really,
even more.
And even more so now,
I was kissing.
Now as a matter of now that you're,
you're really doing,
you know,
absorbed,
excuse me,
observing a sport that you love.
Uh,
you see like how the people for me who
can train themselves to be unafraid or
can channel their fear in the face of
getting pummeled by an by a big person,
but big dude like is an
amazing thing to me.
And how that trait is expressed
physically in the brain versus how,
you know,
a guy like me who's like,
fuck dude,
I'll give you any money I've got.
Don't beat me up.
You know,
like I'm not a fighter.
Uh,
the difference between our brains,
like who knows what that is?
That's definitely so subtle,
but you don't need to be a,
you don't need to have the ability
to perform under pressure like that.
We don't think.
No.
But if you did,
you would,
you know,
if your life depended on it and if you
were in some sort of a walking dead
situation and you had to deal with fear,
you would deal with it.
Think there's two kinds of people.
Basically,
there's two kinds of,
I'm sorry.
Right.
No,
I'm saying to come through,
right?
You're thinking just
one kind of person and,
and it's just the choices you make.
Yeah.
There's survivors or people who die.
I mean,
literally there's no,
during most exchanges
in civilized society,
there's no need to be
afraid of other people.
There's no need to be afraid
of violent altercations.
It's very rare.
Unless you're in terrible environments,
unless you're in war,
unless you're in really,
really bad neighborhoods,
most likely you're going to
be safe in San Francisco.
Just go into your job and
interacting with human beings.
Yeah.
But when you,
you're forced to in a day to day basis,
overcome stress and fear,
and it becomes a part of your reality.
And once it becomes part of your
reality in terms of performance,
it,
it also becomes,
uh,
something that you kind
of have to be inoculated.
Right?
Right,
right,
right.
You start off slowly and
like even stand up comedy.
The first time I tried to stand up tall,
terrified.
Terrified.
Now I know I'm not scared at all.
Now it's fun.
And that is like part of you.
You,
you've got to be competent,
you gotta have your bases covered.
And I remember competing
as a martial artist,
there was a big difference between how I
felt when I was really prepared and how
I felt if I was injured or if I was sick
or if there was something wrong or if I
didn't train hard enough.
When when you have doubts,
that's when you're in a really bad place.
I would say though that the
raw materials are distinctive.
I mean we can agree right that the were
all physical materials of people are,
are you know,
distinct from one another.
Like my,
my wife is an Olympic who
was an Olympic hopeful,
she was uh,
uh,
a track and field runner and uh,
you know,
her body and its strength.
I mean she had a 30 inch vertical,
she's five,
eight,
five,
nine,
you know,
could hang from the rim,
like has hang time,
all this stuff.
I used to play ultimate
Frisbee in college,
you know,
whatever.
I took her out a few times to,
to play it with us and like we'd
never had a real athlete play before.
Like she was out running all the dudes,
you know,
all that stuff.
There's just,
there's distinctions
between people that I think,
uh,
you know,
are just part of the thing.
And I think there is an expression of
that in the brain that the brain is built
differently for different things,
which is not to say that that
is not to say that you're wrong.
No,
no,
no.
But the question is,
does that have those physical distinctions
from her gifts from the womb or is it
from constant focus on,
it's a little about athletic
activity I think is a little bit,
I mean,
you know,
fast,
which is slow twitch muscles.
I mean,
we know,
we know that the difference between that,
like,
you know,
a long cabs versus the ones that
are high and tight and you know,
there's,
there's jumping ability,
there's sprinting ability versus
being able to run long distances.
There's this,
there's just distinctions
between people physically.
It doesn't mean anything other
than just jeans are out there.
That's what's amazing.
So with the brain,
with the,
the,
the way that it,
uh,
is distinct,
you know,
it can do amazing things.
Like we're literally putting
pins into brains now,
delivering a little
signal and turning off,
you know,
seizures and turning off stuff.
Like it is triggering memories,
right?
Yeah.
Triggering memories.
We,
there's a,
so,
uh,
there's basically a new category of a
thing called a biomechanical engineering
where they've taken,
you know,
guys like your dad,
uh,
who,
might have,
you know,
who liked to tinker and are good at that.
Right.
And turn that into a,
combined them with,
you know,
a little bit of medical training or maybe
pair them up with a medical student.
There's programs that do that.
And being a biomechanical engineer,
they're literally creating little
devices that will do stuff.
And so in one case,
um,
the,
uh,
in the case of of dementia,
it's basically putting a pin,
essentially you imagine
a pin into the brain and,
and delivering a little jolt.
But first you have to
pick out the pattern.
Um,
so in this case it was,
it was monkeys,
uh,
that had,
been taught a cartoon game,
basically like a turnover and
match the cards kind of game.
And uh,
when they got it right,
that signal,
the computer picked that up,
right.
Software recorded that pattern.
Then later when,
I don't know if it was the same
monkeys are new Monkees and forgive me,
but um,
when they played again,
uh,
they would use the signal to incur it
to stimulate the part of the brain that
had lit up when they,
when the monkey got it right last time.
And they found that they could increase
the accuracy of the monkey 10 by 10% on
a consistent basis by jolting them
right before they were about to make a
decision,
like hitting them with whatever
the signal was at that time.
And then this is the
other crazy part of it.
They then hit those
monkeys with each with a,
a hit of cocaine and watched their,
you know,
they fell off by 20%,
basically from their normal
abilities and that game.
Then they started doing this zapping
again and could restore them to normal,
uh,
ability again.
Right.
So the trouble in this case though,
I mean,
are the reason that this is still a decade
or more from being possible in humans
is we don't know.
You know,
life is not like a game of flashcards.
You don't know what the signals are that
you're going to want to prompt ahead of
time or whatever,
but they think that there's
some memory stuff that might be,
you know,
that we could in,
in future sort of improve our memory,
right?
You have a little signal processor and a
thing that would zap the right spots of
the brain or whatever,
you know,
could someday.
It really is such a fascinating time,
um,
in regards to what we're saying
earlier about a data and information,
but also in the fact that we still have
so much to learn when it comes to the,
the human bind and the ability to it,
which is something
that scientists are really
actively focusing on right now.
I found a,
a,
an article in your magazine that I
thought it was really amazing where
scientists had created a tiny artificial
brain that exhibits 12 seconds of short
term memory.
How nuts is that?
You know,
how long before one of
those is in your pocket?
I know,
I know.
You know,
and it has all the information
of the entire universe.
W I was just hanging out with it.
This one of these total boy genius kids,
this guy,
a brilliant gunman,
aser Raskin very smart dude.
And he was pointing out a
thing to me about Google,
uh,
where evidently one of the chief sort of,
you know,
math officer's essentially of,
of Google,
uh,
basically released this paper in 2000,
2001 that said,
uh,
that it doesn't matter
how good the software is,
data,
the more data you give,
you're always going to outperform soft,
even the best software.
So basically like really good software
given a small Dataset is not as good as
mediocre software given a huge Dataset,
right?
And so data is what is what gives
you your correct answers every time.
So you don't in fact need the
little brain what you needed,
a little device that connects
to the whole big brain,
right.
To the,
like the world of,
of data around.
That's sort of analogous
to an educated person.
Right.
You know,
I mean,
uh,
if a person is a,
a clever street smart person or if person
has just of average intelligence but
very well educated,
you would much rather go to that
person to train intellectually curious.
Right?
The guy who likes,
wants to find out the answer
or has access or has access.
Yeah.
I mean if you either,
there's a lot of really smart people
that probably live in Siberia and they're
forced to work a trap line
catching minks and Shit,
you know?
I mean,
if you don't have data and you
don't have access to more data,
that's,
that's who you are and that's what you do,
right?
You will excel in your field,
but you're,
you know,
your ability to actually do things will
be completely limited by the data that
you have access to.
Right,
right,
right.
It's cool
to see how,
uh,
how,
you know,
people are being given so much
more data than they used to.
Right.
It's really hard to be sort of an
ignorant person these days just because
there's so much information coming at us.
Yeah.
It's also hard to pay
attention to everything.
Like there's not enough,
I've literally find myself,
sometimes I come home and uh,
it'll be,
my kids were all asleep and I'd just get
on the Internet at 10 and before I know
it,
it's three 30 and I'm still reading
things and watching videos and I'm like,
shut,
shut this fucking thing.
But Jesus,
it's like shut up high of mine.
Yeah.
But I can't help it.
And I really find myself struggling
with disconnecting from Twitter and I
have not mastered it,
but I know a guy who turns it off for he,
he goes to places without
Internet connection.
He takes his laptop to places that
don't have Internet connection.
Maybe that'll be a new like hip thing,
right?
It would be like places that
don't have wifi.
Uh,
you know,
but you can go there with a
computer and sit without Wifi.
And he just,
and that's where he does
writing or whatever,
you know,
any actual thinking he
has to because yeah,
I'm like you man,
I get distracted.
Addictive.
I do my writing that way
where I don't go online.
I have this,
uh,
this program called right room.
And uh,
what it does is it allows you to see only
the text on the screen by screen goes
black and it's green text on the screen.
And I just,
this is the most limited word processor
is it shows you where you're spelling
things wrong and that's it.
Perfect.
And then when I want to go back and like
Google is certain things I'll have like
little highlights in certain areas and
I'll go back to those and then I can get
online and do the rest of my research.
But I find it's too easy to look at porn.
It's too easy.
It's just way too easy.
This is perfectly designed
to get your attention.
Oh,
it's so quick.
And by the way,
with like Google chrome,
all you have to do is press
y and it goes to your ages.
You know what I mean?
You don't even have to
do much more than that.
That's because you go to youtube.
I know when,
when,
if I'm like looking at a,
um,
something,
I want to show my wife something.
I gotta press y o u t so fast.
I got to go through while you can't,
because she's a clever one.
She,
she's over my shoulder
and she sees me hit that.
Why
I'm thinking about just putting it in
the fucking bookmark bar right there.
A little youtube link.
Just click the price.
Just click the private
browsing thing on a safari,
which makes it so,
yeah,
it has no cookies or anything.
Sorry.
I find so far to be
whack it in chrome too,
I think.
Is that,
yeah.
I really enjoy chrome.
I love the fact that in
chrome I can go to the uh,
the uh,
html to the address bar rather,
and just type a question
and it'll take me to,
you know,
a Google search.
That's beautiful.
Yeah,
I mean that is just,
it's,
we live in awesome times.
It really is awesome.
But still,
um,
I've described this as this,
this time we live in now as the roaring
twenties of the digital era where you
could still go like this and they
know we don't have to have license,
we don't have to,
you know,
talk to government official and get a
license and it's still rare enough that
were popular.
This is,
this makes us,
you know,
we're,
we're in that we're like,
you know,
7.5% more famous than other people,
or whatever it someday.
Right.
That,
that,
that percentage is going to drop down
because everyone's going to have access.
Sure.
And there's also a lot of people online
that were never famous before and got
famous because they're online content,
which is really amazing.
Amazing Medians.
I know Comedians,
like our friend Russell,
Russell Peters,
Russell Peters became
famous because of Youtube.
Is that right?
Yeah.
People found his clips on Youtube and now
he sells out the o two arena in London
two nights in a row.
Wow.
That's like 18,000 people.
The whole generation of those like,
you know,
out of nowhere,
literally out of nowhere,
uh,
success stories.
Yeah.
So cool.
And it's so modern.
That's totally what we like this era.
I made that possible.
Yeah.
I love the ability
to distribute content,
the ability to distribute artwork and
podcasts and in comedy shows on Youtube or
what have you.
I think it's just is the most
amazing time ever for self promotion,
self publishing.
We live in really cool time.
Like you say.
I mean,
like we were saying earlier,
it's a great time to be a reader.
You can,
anybody can kind of write those people,
you know,
tapping out a whole
novels on their phones.
There's all your stuff out there,
you know,
didn't Steven Wright like
write a whole novel on Twitter?
Oh,
who is that true.
Yeah.
I wrote a whole novel,
guys.
Crazy.
Yeah.
Fascinating.
Um,
is there anything in this episode
or this issue that deals with a very
controversial issue of
antidepressants and they're affecting?
Tell him,
I saw people asking about,
uh,
about that.
So,
you know,
anti psychotics,
here's one thing that I'll say about,
uh,
or ssrs or not anti psychotics.
Sorry,
not an Ssri.
I don't have,
I don't have a good informed
opinion on antidepressant.
I don't need a depressed,
I just don't know enough about it.
I wouldn't,
I wouldn't know how to
comment on that intelligently.
I will say that,
you know,
anti psychotics,
which are a sort of,
you know,
an extreme thing,
right?
There's all kinds of,
of uh,
you know,
incredible research being done,
but we're still very,
it's still very early days
in our understanding of
what drugs do to the brain
and what happens here and there.
And so,
you know,
anti psychotics,
there was,
there was a statistically
significant group of people.
I think,
God,
I'm going to misrepresent this button.
I'm busy.
I was talking to a university professor
who had done this study about,
um,
she was a clinical psychologist who had
done a study about people taking it and
I psychotics and a certain number of,
of,
uh,
the patients were so transformed by this
new generation of anti psychotics that
they,
that they voluntarily went off them to
go back to the hallucinations that they'd
had before.
Wow.
It's not a lot of people.
I don't want to miss her
represent the number,
but it was a statistically
significant group of people,
which means that there are people
whose re who's for whatever reason,
their reaction is,
I would rather,
so in one of the cases
that you described was a,
uh,
a man,
a homeless man who believed that he
was being pursued by the Russians,
you know,
and was living in stark terror in
this kind of Cold War nightmare,
uh,
every waking moment.
And he was homeless and so with you,
but just ruined guy.
He goes and he gets,
begins to get this anti
psychotic medication and these,
and it turns off not
just your hallucinations,
but it also maintains your
ability to reason and function.
You know,
it can be very helpful sometimes if it,
if it works.
And I'd like to point out
that's not always true.
Um,
but he was so destabilized by
discovering that nobody wanted him.
The Russians didn't want him,
nobody wanted him.
He says to the homeless guys right now,
he's just a bum dude.
And he was like,
he was bummed out because
he wasn't special anymore.
He was the star of his own
action movie for so long,
you know,
and,
and more guy.
And He,
and he voluntarily went back to,
to being,
to living that life.
You know,
why he took the blue pill and then,
or whatever it was and
then wished you hadn't,
well I would like to see what he saw
before I made any sort of a judgment on
them.
Cause who knows,
he might have been living in an awesome
world like a Winnie the Pooh ride at
Disney land.
Totally.
You know,
just neon colors everywhere and fucking
Russian agents hiding behind two
dimensional trees driving
a Camaro convertible.
Yeah.
I mean who knows what he
actually saw antipsychotics,
although a fascinating subject
is quite different from the Ssri.
Yeah,
absolutely.
Um,
which I,
I think the SSRI is subject is a really,
really interesting one.
Yeah.
What's your feeling about it?
I mean,
do you do,
I don't need them,
so I feel like it would be really silly
of me to make a judgment in one way or
another.
Um,
I don't have any personal
experience with them,
but I do have friends who
have had personal experience
with them and including,
and people that I really respect that
they changed their life for the better.
That's right.
So I definitely think there's a,
there's certainly a benefit to them.
And there's,
I mean,
I don't know.
The other thing is,
which one?
You know,
I have a friend and,
uh,
he got on some antidepressants and they
started him off on one and it's socks.
And then they switched that
and got them to another one.
How do you feel on this?
You know,
and then they doubled his dose.
And I'm like,
what the fuck are they doing it?
Like they don't have like dental do a
blood test and give you a very specific,
this one,
what you way back to the thing.
I don't know how it works in the brain,
right?
The,
the blood brain barrier is,
uh,
this,
you know,
basically the body's system for keeping
things only the tiniest molecules from
passing into your brain because
it's such an important organ.
Like no one gets in VIP.
We Boone's let's get right in.
They do good write it and
they get in front of the line.
So,
uh,
you know,
the,
the ability of,
you know,
medications coming through that barrier
to change your mood or your outlook on
life,
it's such a difficult thing to predict.
Wow.
Um,
yeah.
And not only that,
it's so variable between
human beings that it's,
it's one person would describe you.
You'd almost think you're dealing
with a completely different substance,
one person's reaction to another.
Sure.
For some folks it's mild.
For other folks,
they have horrible side effects.
Yeah.
And they can't tell
until they put you on it.
Right.
It's,
it seems like there's so many variables
when it comes to any sort of a
medication that affects the mind because
you're dealing with who knows how many
thousands of generations of genetics,
where your origin was like,
it's pretty well known
that certain people,
a certain nationalities have a difficult
time with alcohol because they don't
have a cultural history of it.
They don't have a genetic history of it.
Well,
the truth is,
human beings don't have
a history of alcohol.
We're not,
we're not evolutionarily,
you know,
supposed to be drinking booze and
stuff is poison in terms of just the
toxicology of it.
But,
but we evolved literally.
I mean there's,
there's,
there's a whole field of
evolutionary biology that's studies,
uh,
the moment that we began to
drink alcohol and it was,
you know,
I don't even,
I couldn't even guess when,
you know,
it's probably,
fifth century BC or something,
something,
you know,
way long time ago.
Um,
but the,
the idea was that there one theory is
that you would drink it in order to
survive eating rotten meat
traveler's poisoning,
they would call it,
oh,
is that traveler seginus yeah.
They would drink wine with all of their
food because the alcohol and the wine
they thought would kill rotten meat.
Totally.
They haven't really figured out how
to refrigerate things to Joe Rogan.
You want a job?
No.
Thanks.
Um,
I also read a fascinating
thing about the origins of,
um,
alcohol being that it was with honey,
Huh?
That they had figured out a long time
ago that honey was a preferred method of
storing things in because it
prevented a deterioration,
prevented a things boiling.
And one of the things that happens with
honey is that it ferments and becomes
need and millages.
Yeah.
This was one of the theories of Terence
Mckenna on the changing of the culture
is from earlier psychedelic based,
uh,
mushroom cultures.
Two cultures that were more alcohol
based was that they started storing their
mushrooms in honey and uh,
that,
uh,
a very,
that's true.
That's so fun.
I don't think there's,
I think any history older than
6,000 BC is like good luck.
Good luck trying to figure that out.
But they know that,
uh,
many,
many cultures where a preserving
mushrooms in various ways,
some of them were drawing
them out over the fireplace.
They were doing all these different things
with mushrooms and they know for sure
they started storing them in honey.
And they also know that there
was climatological changes
where mushrooms weren't
growing in areas anymore and they had
a switch to different and toxicants and
then the raping and pillage.
And started,
shit got crazy
according to Mckenna,
at least I hadn't heard that.
But mead,
that's a lot of people don't know that
alcohol made with honey is a w an early
intoxicated.
I have to tell you though,
I once went to a wedding
where the only drink it was,
it was announced to us when we
arrived would be honey mead.
That the,
like the grooms brother or something
had made and everybody had only made and
uh,
you know,
it's not like I hold it against people,
but you know,
I would have happily paid cash
for a cock for a whiskey cocktail,
you know,
like,
oh my God.
And it does,
it tastes like it's a,
it was like,
Oh man,
I don't know.
It's like week.
It's like a cross between
wine and beer almost,
but,
but sort of a sour sweet,
you know what I mean?
It's a weird drink.
I didn't like it.
I didn't like anybody.
Like,
no.
I would say like the whole wedding was
people dumping this stuff into beef
plants,
plants and over and over again.
Someone who it would be
like and raise your meats.
Fucking Dork.
They dungeons and dragons player.
Probably.
Probably people are so silly.
Careful.
This is my people only.
Probably my people too.
They're still fucking silly.
Not that it's bad to be silly.
I'm pretty sure it's a big D and d guy.
That was probably,
that was my thing.
Yeah.
That was to roll the dice.
I should've been playing basketball,
but I was inside like casting spells,
Rolling d 20 years.
The world draws you are the universe
draws you to where it would be safest.
Yeah.
Maybe.
Maybe you're safer.
Rolling dice and tricking me.
It's a weird choice.
The guide,
dry,
dry makes it himself.
Was that what it is he was making
himself was I've never heard of that.
I've heard of people making wine.
I've never heard anybody
making their own need.
Yeah.
I don't know.
It was definitely a,
uh,
where I went to college.
There was a house of a renaissance guys.
Uh,
and,
and one point they,
uh,
they would practice in
the courtyard of the dorm.
And when,
uh,
one of my friends figured
out that if you yelled,
hold,
it was the super secret signal for them
to all that somebody had been hurt.
You know,
somebody's been like,
you know,
poked in the eye with a nerf
sword or whatever and uh,
they would all go down on one knee.
Uh,
and it was like their practice
thing for like taking a time out.
And I was like,
stop hurting each other.
And uh,
and so for like,
you know,
for about a week,
you could trick them every time.
You could just yell,
hold across the courtyard
and make all of the meal.
But it only lasted for a second.
So those are my people,
man.
I love,
I love it.
The best kind.
Have there ever been any studies
on figuring out what it is,
what the process is with the people that
can't handle alcohol versus the people
who have a,
I'm sure street.
I'm sure.
I don't know what it is,
but yeah,
I mean,
you know,
it makes sense,
right?
It's just,
it would be like,
how long did people have the
gene that allows them to,
you know,
turn the liquor into sugar,
or whatever.
Like,
I dunno what the,
what the,
um,
what the distinction is or
if they've discovered that or
someone's studying for blackout drunk,
right.
What is that?
This tolerance.
Your brain just says
enough when you're young.
One beer got you drunk getting the more
he drank it now like I could drink a
million beers,
get blacked out.
But it's not true.
You can't even drink one without slurring.
The fuck is different than blacked out.
It's true.
I might drink jack if I,
if I drink jack,
I'll black out if I drink.
I mean,
literally if I get best five or six beers,
I start to be on the verge.
Right.
Yeah.
I'm a,
I'm a mess.
Thing is fascinating to
me because some folks,
I've seen people who are
quote unquote addicts and uh,
they can't do anything.
They can't drink,
they can't smoke,
they can't do anything.
They'll drink coffee.
You know,
coffee apparently is okay.
Um,
but if they have one drink,
they're gone.
They're off to the races and they're
doing heroin and sucking dicks for cash,
money to get home,
whatever.
They just,
they,
they don't know what happened.
They don't know what it is.
But for me,
I can get fucked up and I still remember
a pieces and chunks and I get home and
I don't really black out.
Huh.
So I have a good friend
that fucking blacks,
I mean completely
box.
So you give them two drinks.
Our friend Joey Diaz says is the Indian
in him because he's Mexican and Mexicans
were part Indian Spaniards,
um,
that the Indian and I'm
kicks in and he's gone.
He just vanishes.
It's no longer there.
You look in his eyes,
looks like a durable,
durable eyes and those drugs,
you know,
you look at it durable,
then motherfucker doesn't
know what's going on.
I don't what is,
I mean,
do you know what that mechanism?
I don't know.
No,
I don't know enough about it.
I mean,
you know,
like I said though,
the stuff is poison.
Eventually your brain,
your body is going to say,
okay enough,
good night.
You know it's going to paralyze your arms.
So they can't lift anymore of
it to your mouth or whatever.
There's,
um,
a lot of new research being done on,
substances that act as
a vaccine for addicts.
You aware of anything?
Yeah,
sure.
I mean,
some of the,
one of the pieces that we,
uh,
are looking at here is a
thing about exactly that.
Basically,
it's a,
it's a piece of technology
that allows you to head off,
um,
uh,
seizures,
um,
and lets you basically,
uh,
not only deliver an electrical
signal into the brain,
but also a pro very precisely
timed a jolt of medication.
So you're,
you know,
your,
uh,
ability to,
to not just,
you know,
it does,
it affects not just your,
um,
uh,
the function of the brain at the time,
but can also like guide
it a little bit basically.
So the way it's designed
is like this tiny little,
uh,
you basically end up with a film,
a molecule thick,
basically film of,
um,
uh,
basically film on top of this electrode.
And when you hit it
with a negative charge,
the film releases and medication
deep inside your brain.
And it'll turn off seizures
and they think that they,
it can also do stuff with,
uh,
that it might be able to help ward
off the effects of Parkinson's.
Basically,
seizures happen,
you know,
everybody,
every,
so many kinds of ailments
can cause seizures.
Right.
It's super useful.
So,
and they also think they could use it to
turn off some of the addictive impulse
that could detect,
you know,
I,
I dunno how they would do this,
but somehow they would detect the
signal in your brain ahead of time that
signals,
or maybe it's,
you know,
the environmental thing of like,
he's alone.
He's been alone for the past two days.
Who knows how it could be
triggered and then boom,
it hits you with this thing that,
that,
you know,
jolts you up a little bit,
wakes,
you know,
it gets you up again.
Do we know the difference between the,
um,
uh,
a physical addiction in the mind and
the strange addictions like gambling?
Sure.
I mean,
you know,
it's the reward mechanism in your brain.
Your brain is,
is a,
um,
basically is,
is rewarding you at all times
for whatever it is you're doing.
You know,
with a nice feeling.
You get a little jolt of,
of Serotonin,
uh,
for having done the right thing.
You know,
a lot of the time,
but some sort of a guiding
principle of your body basically.
And so you get a little thrill from
things like Twitter checking Twitter,
right?
Or,
you know,
there's a whole body of,
of,
uh,
writing that's been done about this,
like the,
the addictive nature of picking up
new information all the time and how,
that's why we can't get
away from the Internet.
Uh,
sometimes there's no
reward and you still do it.
Yeah.
Well,
it's right.
It's compulsion.
That's the thing.
It becomes a tick,
right?
It's a compulsion.
Your brain forms,
pathways,
it,
it'd be,
it literally,
you physically re architect your,
you know,
rearrange the architecture of your brain,
uh,
to reward yourself deeper,
more and more deeply for
that addiction over time.
Um,
so gambling is exactly that kind of thing.
It's,
you know,
what will I get,
what's the little reward?
I'll get,
you know,
and there's the,
the expectation of it,
the temptation of it,
all of those things.
Plus then it does pay off sometimes.
You know,
it's a crazy,
uh,
it's just your brain is an elastic thing.
It's if it's changing and adapting
to keep you alive and you know,
doing,
you're doing the best you can,
uh,
no matter the circumstances.
So,
you know,
if you expose,
if you're exposed to an
addictive thing enough,
it's just going to adapt to that thing.
Are you aware of the correlation that
studies have done about correlation
between brain damage
and addictive behaviors?
Gambling?
No.
Yeah,
we had a friend in here
used to be a boxer,
uh,
the president of UFC,
Dana White,
who,
uh,
has been hitting the head a bunch and uh,
he gambles like ridiculous.
Like he's,
he's lost $1 million in a night and one,
one 6 billion in a night as he ever has.
He ever saw in a professional
opinion as to why that is.
Sure.
He's rich.
Just keeps gambling cool,
keeps rolling and go,
you know.
But,
um,
he also has had a brain scan because he
was going to enter into a boxing match
about six years ago.
And when that happened,
they found spots on his brain.
They're like,
yeah,
you've been,
you've been hit a lot,
dude.
Huh,
Huh.
Yeah.
And the fact that he's
a addicted to gambling,
crazy,
fascinating.
Now that the correlation
between the two of them,
it's like there's damage.
So your brain's just like constantly
urging and the impulse to seek those
rewards.
We,
so,
you know,
selfish,
let's do this to my magazine,
but,
uh,
in this issue of the magazine,
we have a,
a,
a thing about,
um,
uh,
basically,
you know,
savant,
right?
The idea of being a savant right here,
this,
uh,
for anyone it doesn't know,
you know,
it's the,
it's the idea that you're just this,
this perfect,
uh,
incredibly skillful,
just master of a thing,
whatever that thing is.
And,
um,
there's a B,
basically the,
it's the story of the,
of the sky.
Derrick Amato,
who was a,
uh,
he was,
you know,
pushing 40,
uh,
you know,
we're,
normal guy,
uh,
playing football in a pool with
his friends and Sioux City,
South Dakota where he's from.
And somebody throws a pass
to him from the Jacuzzi.
He leaps into the pool for it and he wacks
his head really hard on the bottom of
the pool and you know,
comes up and thinks that he's like broken.
His skull is clutching his head,
you know,
really in agony.
It goes to the hospitals,
got very serious concussion and they put,
they send him home,
you know,
there's nothing really to be done.
Uh,
and so they sent him home and
he sleeps for like four days.
Basically.
He wakes up,
he goes over to his friend's house,
one of the friends that was with him
when he was playing football and,
uh,
sits down with the guys piano
or keyboard or whatever,
and just begins to play the piano and
has never really played the piano before.
Um,
and begins,
there's just,
you know,
can do the trials and you know,
he's doing all the fancy stuff.
And,
uh,
the,
he then immediately of course goes on
the Internet and it's like Jesus Christ,
what's going on?
And he said it was like an
itch that he needed a scratch.
It was satisfying to play
in a way that he couldn't,
you know,
had never experienced before.
So he looks online and discovers that
there was a whole field of study called a
co into what's called
acquired savant syndrome,
where you pick up a miraculous skill
like this from some sort of debilitating,
you know,
brain damage or whatever the
thing ends up being and that,
and so he was led to a researcher who
diagnosed him as having this thing.
There's like fewer than 30
documented cases in the world.
Uh,
but it happens.
And I'll just tell your
listeners right now,
don't go whack in your
head on stuff like that.
It really doesn't work out most
of the time that from memory,
well this is what they're
trying to figure out.
And so there's two things.
There's two competing theories about it.
One is,
and neither of the,
it may be that one of them is wrong.
So let's all keep that in mind.
But uh,
one of the theories is that when
you damage a part of the brain,
the,
the you,
you can sometimes damage a part of the
brain that had been inhibiting the other
half of your brain.
Basically the right brain,
you know,
it was inhibiting the left side
and by damaging the right side,
you're,
the left brain becomes disinhibited.
And so one of the things that they,
one of the examples they use is,
you know,
as we get used to stuff over
the course of our lives,
we begin to develop a
shorthand for it in our brain.
Right?
You don't pick out the details anymore,
you're picking out the,
the very general landscape.
I was just thinking about
this on the drive here,
right?
We're driving through Burbank and,
and you know,
I was looking at a truck
and thinking to myself,
how would I see that truck if I was
seeing it for the very first time with,
you know,
with that side of my brain disinhibited.
Every rivet,
right?
Every little reflector and the,
and the panels inside the reflector,
like just tripping on the details and
instead my brain can go truck and,
and boom,
I'm onto the next thing.
And so that kind of shorthand
they think gets maybe scrambled,
this disrupted in some way when the,
when you damage a part of the brain and
suddenly you're seeing everything fresh
again.
And so there's a whole world of guys who
can do amazing new things and there's a
whole new world of people who do artistry,
uh,
dementia.
People who are old and have dementia,
uh,
develop an artistic flair
all of a sudden with the,
um,
the savant syndrome is there
like a loss correlation?
Like they lost this.
And so now all of a sudden that it
almost always comes at a terrible cost.
Yes.
You know,
reasoning,
you know,
something will come out of,
and you'll have people who are severely,
uh,
you know,
some of the,
some of the most amazing savant stories
or people who are very developmentally
disabled in other ways.
You know,
somebody have an Iq of
50 for a verbal Iq of 54.
This one kid,
uh,
could listen to a piano on TV
once and play it perfectly,
whatever it was,
Tchaikovsky and a movie,
and he'd sit down at the piano and play.
Uh,
and so he,
but he's severely
developmentally disabled.
This is somebody else who's,
who's,
that's not an acquired savant,
that doesn't make a famous savant case.
So in some of these cases,
yeah,
it comes at these terrible
things he's paying,
you know,
and this guy has pain,
has all kinds of terrible,
debilitating things from his head
injury but can suddenly play this,
this stuff,
you know.
And so,
uh,
the other theory about it is,
is maybe in the dying
of a part of the brain,
there's weird electrical activity that,
you know,
supercharges either the area
in some way or you know,
this again,
they don't know enough about the
brain to really have any idea.
We barely understand concussions,
you know,
I mean,
actually we have a pretty
good grasp on concussions,
but we have no experience
protecting people from them,
you know,
and all of this because the brain,
just our understanding of it is so new.
What is the thought on people that
have autism and can do amazing things.
Like,
have you seen the young man that can
look out a window from a plane and draw a
picture of juggling?
He's unbelievable,
right?
Unbelievable.
If you've never ever seen the video folks,
just Google,
I believe his name,
someone on the board
posted Steven Wilshire,
Dj crack pies.
Thanks for putting that up there buddy.
Um,
yeah,
that's,
that's his name.
Um,
the,
uh,
ability to do things that a normal person
would literally never be able to do
ever.
And this guy can do it every single time.
Right,
right,
right.
It's the thought that the mind is still
evolving and advancing and one day we're
all going to possess
those sort of abilities.
I haven't,
I haven't seen anybody do any
research that would suggest that,
but I do think that there's a lot of just,
I just have to say that as the
editor of the science makes it,
I can't,
you know,
I dunno.
Just speculate it.
Yeah,
sure.
I like that though.
It sounds cool,
but I don't know that
that's the case anyway.
Uh,
the,
the feeling though is that,
um,
uh,
you know,
autism,
autism is a vast spectrum of symptoms.
Uh,
you know,
it's not at all common for someone who's
autistic to also have these savant like
abilities.
Those are really unusual things.
Um,
what's crazy about the,
you know,
the,
uh,
the thing that I find so interesting
is these people who are aging and
developing,
uh,
you know,
pain,
being able to paint,
being able to do all this stuff.
Um,
there's an amazing,
uh,
since I,
I like the theory of just from a,
like,
because it's kind of Nice
to think about that there's,
you know,
as people minds are decaying certain
artistic abilities or whatever suddenly
begin to flourish.
Like it's pretty cool.
I don't know.
I find that story pretty neat.
Um,
but uh,
like Louis Wayne,
you knew who he is.
He's that famous artists that you said,
I think draw for the New York
Times or something like that.
And then he started getting schizophrenia
or started going crazy on his older
age and like just his
normal drawings of cats.
Like,
here's a example.
It's normal drunks and cat,
which were like,
really,
you know,
normal.
I started to getting more
and more psychedelic,
almost looking until
near the end of his life.
It was straight up like
a grateful dead tattoo.
I've never seen that.
That's really cool.
Right there is so complicated.
Yeah.
Is that looks like psychedelics.
That looks like something you would
see if you're on mushrooms or on DMT.
It looks like something that's right.
That's right.
It's very fractal fractal.
That's right in which is what you see
when you take hardcore psychedelics.
So who knows his mind,
like just slowly flooding itself.
The other one is Henry Darger.
Do you know about him?
He's fascinating.
Same kind of guy like look like,
um,
uh,
and his art,
he did so much art that uh,
he from the history of how it was stacked
up in his apartment when he had died
and his landlord found all this work,
nobody knew that he was doing this stuff.
And it's incredible.
Uh,
he illustrates whole novels,
uh,
of,
of this stuff and it's all fantastical.
It's quite creepy too,
I'll tell you right now.
I mean,
you know,
lots of stuff about
little girls and stuff.
Yeah.
He's just absolutely
obsessed a little girls.
But it also,
he,
he the,
the body of work got more and more
intense and more and more prolific at a
certain stage in his life.
And then at the end of his life had a
tapered off and he wasn't doing any it
anymore.
And there was,
they think that it,
like his schizophrenia had sort
of flamed out at a certain wow.
Yeah.
Schizophrenia wears off.
Well they don't know.
But you know,
over the course of,
of as you get old the brain
changes and who knows,
you know,
somehow it,
it,
it changes.
So yeah,
it's crazy too because if you get,
yeah,
some of this stuff is very disturbing.
Uh,
and when you get in there,
uh,
the,
the note there in the bottom,
I'm sure,
like he has all this mythology.
He wrote all this stuff,
you know,
he had two,
two races.
The,
the tattle lingo,
Ian's versus the such and such,
I can't remember what it is,
but they,
it's,
you know,
two,
two armies going again
going up against each other.
Wow.
Yeah.
Crazy stuff.
It's so fascinating how someone can
lose their mind and in their artwork you
could sort of see the,
the,
the window into their craziness,
right.
Through their,
their,
their offerings to their total activity.
It's manifest that the human mind is such
a strange thing in that we're the only
animal that we know of that's truly
aware of what the fuck is going on.
Um,
and that there is also a truly aware
of its origins and development.
We have some sort of sketchy information
about dolphin intelligence and we,
we,
there's a lot of speculation when it
comes to what they can and can't do,
but the reality of what humans can do
as opposed to like what they used to be
able to do,
you know,
a 50,000,
hundred thousand a million years ago.
I mean we,
when we go to Australia,
pithy kiss and we see the little pieces
of stone that they used to chip into a,
a slight edge to cut meat.
And then you look at
a cell phone right now.
That's right.
I'll tell you right now,
there's a,
there's an app we made where you
can take a photo of yourself as an
Australopithecus or as near the end Athol,
uh,
and see what you would've looked like.
It literally maps the faces
of the details of your face.
If anyone wants to check it out.
Uh,
it's uh,
uh,
evolver is the name of it.
Check it out if you want to.
But the,
the,
and what's amazing about it is,
um,
absolutely would you say like so
much stronger neanderthal man,
you know,
so much stronger than we are right now
with totally tear apart the greatest UFC
fighter just because they're just so much
heavier and there's a really short for
battle.
The short feet tall,
200 pounds,
but completely different.
But we're getting there and like stab
a rhino in the heart with a spear,
a sleeping rhino.
That's how they would hunt.
You do that and then
run is like their job.
And so they would find,
uh,
this is one of the theories
about why they would find,
uh,
the vertebrae of buried neanderthals
would be all messed up because from
terrible falls,
you know,
and being trampled and
rolled by some rhino,
they just stabbed,
you know,
the bravest people like you know what,
just dumb as fuck and really strong,
but they're why we're here.
Right.
I mean like they hate entity.
Totally separate from us.
Neanderthal.
I mean we,
we carry around some of their genetics,
but there's a lot of speculation as to
whether or not we interbred with them or
whether or not we just
have similar origins.
They think that because they,
you know,
were around at the same time,
it may have happened at some point
that they had larger minds too,
which is even crazier.
They had larger brains and people,
which probably means or I don't know,
probably is not the right word,
but,
but may mean that,
you know,
they had different senses.
Right.
Different,
other capabilities like larger eyes to,
yeah.
Right.
Like,
let me be time slows down.
Right.
For like Anderson Silva time is,
you know,
certain slowness when the
punch is coming or whatever.
Right.
And these guys,
right,
probably could see it from a mile away.
They can see that rhino
tusks coming around.
You know,
he probably,
yeah,
he probably had to,
I mean just the,
just be,
we know by their bone structure and their
w w what we know about their tendonous
structure.
They were ridiculously physically strong.
Two,
three times stronger than a normal human.
Oh yeah.
Like we literally turned,
you know,
could tear your arms off if
it got a good purchase on you.
You know,
like,
like really strong people.
Are you seeing this
thing recently where the,
these Harvard scientists are trying to
talk a woman and to giving birth to an
atoll?
Oh my God,
no,
I haven't heard of that.
I mean,
I've heard of it,
but I don't know anything
directly about it.
Yeah,
I've heard of it.
Yeah.
They're trying to find a,
a brave woman.
I thought you meant that they had found
one and we're trying to talk her into
it.
I'd heard about the thing,
but,
well,
they're trying to find one.
They're willing to implant the embryo of,
of a neanderthal.
I was managing the actual negotiations
with the specific woman and felt myself.
That'd be a tough,
tough day.
It would be tough because there's
plenty of crazy people out there.
I'm sure that we'd do it
just to become famous.
Sure.
They thought that could be the next
Kim Carr Dasha if you throw the reality
show,
I'll do show of that.
Like going around to the she she mall
or whatever with a neanderthal babies.
Well,
they're really trying to do this.
It would be amazing.
It'd be amazing.
I don't know that it's,
I think it's a great idea
to actually bring one back.
Terrible idea.
But,
uh,
that's amazing science.
I'm sure.
I mean,
what if we find out that,
you know,
that we had that fucking killed them
off because they were killing people,
you know,
and then they were our mortal
enemy and that they were trying,
can we split the proceeds on this
movie that you're writing right here?
It's already been rented.
Sounds good.
All right.
See that?
Well,
I mean,
we really are entering into
very unexplored territory.
Right.
There's,
um,
a new frog that has been extinct for over
30 years that they'd just have created
in a lab.
The one that births,
it's young through its mouth.
It,
that was it's trait I guess,
wow.
Through its mouth is where it gives
birth crazy and they've created the first
embryo of this now extent frog the de
extinction movement as a whole thing.
I'm not down with that.
Yeah.
You know,
some of it though is,
is,
I mean,
I'm with you.
Yeah.
I don't want them like,
you know,
letting loose herds of 25 foot sheet,
just because that's a better meat source.
You don't want the,
uh,
you know,
you want a little government
regulation on this one,
I think.
But,
uh,
I'm not sure if the government's
wise enough regulation of some sort.
Yeah.
Whatever.
I'm scientific and somebody
to hold that back somehow.
But anyway.
Um,
but yeah,
it's a,
you know,
there are some things where you could,
where we could learn all kinds of,
you know,
it'd be amazing to know exactly what
we had in common with Xyz person.
I mean,
you know,
the amount of mileage that
people get out of even the most,
you know,
loose stories about like,
we may have inherited
this trait for aggression.
This is like,
uh,
people love reading about that stuff.
You know,
that's a really interesting
trope for a lot of people.
But,
uh,
to know like this
neanderthal was this way,
you know,
comparison.
I'm just kidding here.
But like,
you know,
it'd be like the,
the way that,
you know,
an animal correlates to
its modern day incarnation,
right?
And what that,
that connection is what
they have in common,
what they don't would be
incredibly valuable science.
But I'm not qualified to speak to
whether or not that's a really good idea.
I think it probably is.
I really don't think that anybody can
extrapolate what happens when you start
making a neighborhood of neanderthals.
You know,
no one knows,
no one knows in the entrance.
And no one knows.
And I think there's,
there's this issue with,
um,
we're,
we're always going to be curious and
we're always going to want to come up with
the newest,
latest,
greatest thing and figure out the newest,
greatest thing.
But like,
like the creation of the atomic bomb.
It's almost like once
you start that process,
kind of have to see it.
You got to have to see,
can we make this,
we do this.
There was,
the famous thing from,
from the Manhattan project
is evidently Atlas Allah,
most when the explosion was happening,
you know,
when the cumulus clouds going up is when,
um,
uh,
pull the cat.
Wow.
I can't believe I'm going blank.
His name Robert,
somebody helped me.
Yes.
Thank you.
Oppenheimer.
Uh,
my God,
Robert Oppenheimer's,
you know,
famous phrase,
uh,
I have become death just for
a worlds and racked by guilt
and the Bhagavad Gita.
The BHAGAVAD Gita.
Yep.
Richard Fineman,
who's like 22 or something at the time,
uh,
is up in an airplane watching
for both taking notes.
And he remembers,
and he wrote this in the book.
Uh,
he remembers that.
He thought it was,
oh,
that's how clouds are made.
Like he was already onto the next thing.
Like you know,
he,
he wasn't thinking at all about the,
the moral implications of
what had happened below him.
He was like,
that's how a clown's made.
That's so cool.
He's a scientist,
he's a nerd.
You know,
he's thinking that these,
the best kind of Geek and you need
those guys who just want to find out how
stuff works.
You know,
that our Oppenheimer quote
is the creepiest thing ever.
Also because the translation is so odd,
I am become death.
I am become death destroyer of worlds.
Yeah.
I know.
The just not knowing,
not having any idea how
this is going to be used,
seeing it explode and going,
oh fuck.
Oh,
what have we done?
Yeah.
The ceiling.
Well,
can you imagine the feeling
of the shockwave going by
when they're all in that
bunker?
And you know,
one of the clearest examples of us really
not knowing the implications of these
things is watching those early government
tapes where they would send the
military towards the blast.
Right?
Right.
Everyone get under your desks or no,
when they would,
when they would blow the atomic bombs
up and then they have the military run
towards the blast.
Man,
those guys are dead as fuck.
All those guys that did that,
right?
They died horrible deaths
and they didn't know.
They just like,
what's he see?
What happens when make the
soldiers run towards the blast?
Yeah.
I mean,
the videos are really,
really creepy.
These,
these poor guys,
they're in the,
they're in a ditch.
They blow up the bomb.
Shit's flying overhead.
I mean,
the,
the whiplash from that fucking
explosion must have been insane.
I mean,
the,
you know,
the electromagnetic pulse
that goes through all of this,
this,
the concussive force of that is
so unbelievable and all kinds of,
you know,
that you were talking about,
your friend had had
white spots on his brain.
You know,
there's so much of that kind of brain
damage or out there in the world and
especially people who've had their
bell rung by a big concussion.
Like that is a terrible injury.
Yeah.
That's a lot of things that,
or one of the,
one of the things that people are
finding out about folks that are
recovering from traumatic brain injury
in the military now is that they could
save many more people than ever before.
But you're getting many more people
that have these brain injuries just from
Casa.
Any other physical signs of injury.
That's the other crazy thing.
They're not,
you know,
they're,
they,
they walked away,
you know,
and,
and are lucky to have done so,
you know,
that's the sort of the medical
evaluation or it used to be,
and now they know that
there's an invisible,
uh,
effect in the brain.
There's a shearing force that
passes through the brain that,
that,
you know,
can mess things up.
And that's,
you know,
a lot of the,
uh,
both football,
concussions and these kinds of things.
Like there's just a,
you know,
the brain is,
is fragile.
We're learning and,
and that kind of concussive blast,
you know,
an IED going off by the
roadside is really a terrible,
you know,
can can ring your bell and
really damage your brain.
Yeah.
We're just not that fucking durable.
It seems like we're not really,
does that look at these guys watching
this blast to staring at it and then they
climb out of this ditch and
they run towards the explosion.
Jesus.
Wow.
I've never seen that footage.
Oh,
it's so,
so gross.
I wonder,
I wonder what the purpose was of taking,
I guess just seeing what happens.
Wow.
That's what it is.
I mean they just look at that,
oops,
I got hit in the face with nuclear waste.
Boom.
I mean look at the,
I mean these guys are a couple of miles.
Yeah,
that's the thing is it's probably
hitting them just after the,
yeah.
And then they jump up and they look,
let's run towards the blasts.
Like we're going to go get the red.
I wonder.
Yeah.
I wonder if it was at a time when they
actually thought they would follow up the
blast with,
you know,
invading right.
Yes.
That's exactly what it was.
These guys are walking towards
a Goddamn mushroom cloud.
I haven't gotten mine high,
Huh?
Yeah.
It's insane.
It's completely insane.
And this was just a couple of decades ago.
One of the things that I've brought up
on this podcast before that is one of the
wildest statistics is that from the
invention of the airplane to the time
someone dropped an atomic
bomb from an airplane,
it was less than 50 years.
Wow,
that's crazy.
I,
you know,
there's a,
there's this long history of,
uh,
you know,
when,
uh,
the military funds,
technology and goes after it,
you know,
they master it quickly,
there,
they bring a lot of resources
to it and they get it done.
You have unlimited budgets.
Yeah.
Unlimited budgets.
That's right.
Especially when it's classified.
It's like you can have
line items that are,
you know,
$600 million,
Belmont,
it'll,
it'll say,
just like,
you know,
project roundup,
and you're like,
what?
You know,
and then that's $600 million.
It would just line item
whatever they are spending.
And,
and you know,
I did a TV show for discovery
of the logo that was about this.
And like they've got,
uh,
you know,
these whole hangers set up for private
contractors out in near Edwards Air Force
base at area plan 42.
Um,
and,
uh,
they just build,
you know,
sometimes you'll have two private
contracts like Boeing and Lockheed both
building the same thing,
not knowing that the other is also
building it and it's the military funding,
two competing prototypes and
then melding them or whatever,
see who makes the best product,
the best product.
And they both will throw
all the money out of it.
That kind of stuff.
It's crazy.
So the,
the,
but when the military,
you know,
throws money at a problem,
they tend to solve it.
You know,
I've seen this stealth fighter a
fly overhead while you were in,
um,
uh,
it's Palmdale hour is near the Edwards
air force base and we were out there
filming fear factor several times.
These things fly over a,
especially because when we
first started fear factor,
it was right after September 11th.
Fear factor was a,
it went on air,
I think 2002.
So we would watch these
things fly overhead.
It would be like,
Whoa,
yeah,
that's a God damn spaceship.
Yeah,
totally.
Totally.
With all the,
all the angles on it,
it only has like two or three
angles built into the whole thing.
How does that work?
Do you know literally
that like if you have a,
if a,
if radar hits a thing,
um,
you know,
it needs a certain number,
a certain amount of the radar has
to bounce back basically and the,
and the more that you can make the
angles of the body of the plane match,
right.
So that's why you get those
sort of like Batman kind of,
you know,
crack ular kind of,
uh,
what am I trying to say?
Serrated edges.
It's to make those angles line up
and it's because that's a lower radar
signature.
It's,
there's less for the,
for radar to pick up a
disturbance basically.
Our sucks.
Yeah.
Well it's not really good.
It's awesome for 1945 when you had some,
that's a subject.
I don't know enough about it.
You're making me realize like that's
totally a thing I'd need to look into.
Where,
what does the state of radar right now?
Is there an a new upgrade?
I don't know enough about that.
That's really upsetting.
Gigantic spaceship with what happens?
Well I,
it makes me wonder,
right?
Yeah.
And you don't even see it common for like,
or you know enough cameras
with enough cameras.
Do you even need radar?
Right.
It's like a,
I dunno all those,
a radar signatures of Ufo sightings.
Like that's one of the things
I always point to for evidence.
You know that he's a Rino,
they showed up on radar.
You're telling me that we can make a ship
that doesn't show up on radar and the
fucking aliens haven't
figured that out yet.
That seems so preposterous.
That doesn't make any sense at all.
Right.
It's like the same as they are,
but tests.
Cause last time you went to a doctor and
he stuck something up your ass and it's
pretty rare you have
to have an ass problem.
But almost every alien abduction,
it leads to it and an anal test.
Right,
right,
right.
Yeah.
Did you know radar from Mash?
Lost all his fingers on
his left side of his hand.
I don't think that's related,
but no,
I did not know that.
How did he do that?
Or actually they were just Sporn smaller.
Half,
half small.
Huh.
Oh,
so he didn't lose them now.
I'm sorry.
Thanks.
Internet powerful Internet.
Um,
the,
yeah.
So,
so just to get away from
that sort of technology,
the,
the state of,
um,
uh,
understanding on the,
on the of the human mind today,
what,
what is like one of the most bizarre
things that they've discovered recently
about human beings,
about human mind?
Well,
I mean,
to me,
the,
um,
the money that is about to be proposed
or the rumor is right that Obama is going
to,
um,
uh,
President Obama is going to put up a
$3 billion a proposal for a brain map
project,
a federally funded brain map project.
It's like going to Mars,
right?
It's a great national ambition.
And you know,
I am as frugal as the next person and
I understand that we're at a time of
austerity.
But I also think that these kinds of
projects can really pay off and that you
can get incredible of research done
at a great value of these days.
And so,
and it would be really nice to
understand the brain better than we do.
Well,
it's ridiculous to think
that a few billion dollars
is a lot when you can sit in
the military budget and seem to be a
lot of people complaining about that.
Totally.
Some folks are,
but it's not like no one's saying,
listen,
we have to stop spending
money on the military.
Right.
If you also,
if you look at those social and economic
payoff of a lot of the military funded
or government funded research projects,
you know,
the Internet has,
I think we can all agree
has paid off pretty well.
You know,
that's,
that's that,
that technology is working pretty good.
I'd say right now,
uh,
lcds were created under
a government program.
You know,
there,
there's all kinds of,
of things that make,
uh,
you know,
our lives possible that get off the
ground that way and the brain is such an
unknown.
You need that bridge of money
to get from here to then the,
when the private sector will take
over when we know some stuff,
there's going to be a lot of economic
activity that comes out of this.
Um,
so to me,
I,
you know,
I would love to know better the,
basically what they want to do is we
don't know right now what neurons in the
brain correspond to,
what behavior in the body.
We don't know what the thing is.
You know,
what the connection is yet.
And they want to try to map that out.
I mean,
as best they can.
But what's the general consensus as
far as what created the doubling of the
human brain size?
Uh,
one of the things that I read about,
uh,
the,
the human brain's
development was that the,
the one of the biggest mysteries in the
entire fossil record is that doubling of
the human brain for a
period of 2 million years,
right?
Yep.
So the,
the sense that I have of it and I don't,
that's,
I don't know that area too well,
but I,
but the,
the eating of meat set off the explosion
of the brain's supposedly like eating
animal protein and suddenly,
boom,
we were able to,
to grow our huge brains bigger.
You know,
um,
the process is so slow evolution,
right.
Moves so slowly that like,
and you know,
that that process of that time,
you know,
for it to show up in the fossil record is,
means it happens so quickly
in evolutionary terms.
Meat makes sense.
If cougars are super smart,
you know,
why,
why do people get really smart?
And unless I guess they had to
figure out how to get that meat.
And since we're sort of kind of physically
weak scavenging and trying to stay
alive.
That's right.
Well,
it's all we had.
I mean,
it was so important,
right?
That that we're one of the few
mammals that has babies that are born
defenseless,
utterly defenseless.
And it's because the brain is
so large that the body has to,
uh,
give birth to the baby before the baby
is truly qualified to be outside of the
body.
Well,
it's just ridiculous that people have sex
in the same place where the baby comes
out,
this little tiny penis and a fucking
baby supposed to come out of a hole that
keeps that thing tied
enough to create friction.
The human body should be like
a clam and she'd be like,
yeah,
you cook that baby
inside you and then boom,
patch it out.
You know,
a nice hard clam to protect the baby.
Everything's out a little,
open it up,
right?
And then that's how the baby comes out.
It's like your sexual organs,
this dual purpose thing,
it's just so nutty and pee
comes out of there too.
Right.
On the other hand,
I,
you know,
an engineer would say,
that's sufficient.
It's really efficient.
You want as few openings
in the body as possible.
That's what they said of the
model t when it came out as well.
I think,
you know,
one of the issues with human beings,
it obviously is that we are pretty much
the same as we were 50,000 years ago,
biologically.
But the world has changed dramatically.
Yeah,
sure.
And there's so many more of us.
That's right.
Yeah,
that's right.
So many more.
What's the future gonna hold
for overpopulation crazy,
man.
There's,
there's a whole category
of a sort of architecture thinking
that thinks about the density of stuff.
You know,
how we'll all live.
And,
uh,
um,
one of the amazing things that,
you know,
of these sort of things with
a megalopolis as these huge,
uh,
cities of greater than 30 million people,
and they think that in the
next like 15 to 20 years,
uh,
we're going to have several of them,
you know,
uh,
logos Nigeria is on course to be a 30
million person city by whatever that year
is.
Unbelievable.
And so the patterns of life,
you know,
for when we're living in cities that huge,
it's also really ridiculous that we
still have cities like New York City is a
perfect example where
there's not a single farm.
There's no one's growing shit.
You have 8 million plus people living in
this one tiny little island and you've
got to get all your food
from somewhere else.
Yeah,
that's right.
You don't get your gas there.
You don't get your,
your food there.
Right.
I mean,
I think that's one of the most ridiculous
things about human beings that we
still rely on shipping and transportation.
Right.
It seems that we should,
I mean everyone says you
should source things locally.
It's good for your environment
and good for your community.
That's all well and good.
But it also,
for survival sake,
when you see like what happened with
Hurricane Sandy where New York City was
just shut down New York City and most
advanced city in the world shut down,
no one can get gasoline.
Like wow,
you got to rethink this whole thing.
Cause that fucker was designed
when people were on horses.
Yeah,
that's right.
That's right.
Are highly recommended.
Book the World Without
us by Alan Weissman,
uh,
who,
writes about like what would happen if,
if human beings vaporized
from our places now,
like what would happen on the next day?
Basically,
and it was his stuff about like,
you know,
everything from like feral cats,
right?
Would,
would those that weren't locked in,
you know,
the ones that were locked in would die
and then this number of them would be out
there and they would decimate
the rodent population.
Like he basically takes that fantastical
moment when everyone is vaporized.
And then he's like,
how long will the nuclear
power plants last?
How long before the houses,
you know,
a breakdown we a hundred
years and they all fall apart.
This office plaza were just like
come apart in a hundred years.
You know,
that kind of stuff is,
is a fascinating and,
and it's because like it requires so much
little gritty granular maintenance to
keep something like New York City going.
Well not only that,
the world,
the erosion,
the,
the changing of the seasons,
the moving of the dirt on the
ground due to seismic activity.
We don't think about it in our time
because we only live to be a hundred years
and in a hundred years,
not a whole lot of things happen.
But over the course of a a billion
years plus there's nothing left.
Nature will have its way
with you with everything.
I was in Montana recently and
one of the coolest things about,
uh,
I was in the badlands and when we
were hiking through these hills,
you find seashells all over
the place because Montana,
that area,
Montana used to be something called
the Great Western inland sea.
Billions or millions of years ago,
they used to be fucking dinosaurs in
Montana and an ocean and inland ocean and
you're like,
wow,
like this.
It's not,
this ain't permanent like this.
This sort of thing just
keeps changing and shifting.
I mean,
California,
yeah,
we're live,
right?
All these dramatic seascapes and so forth.
Although,
you know,
waves crashing on the
beaches and all that stuff,
all that imagery.
Like,
man,
we are utterly,
uh,
living in a place that's
crumbling into the ocean.
It's just being eaten away.
And the people who have
a house on the beach,
you silly ass hole,
are you crazy?
Like I knew a guy who was building this,
I think it was like a
several million dollar house.
He's super rich.
She's his whole family's rich.
She's like one of those old money.
Dude's just some seems
to always have cash.
And we were talking about this play
shows me these architectural designs.
I'm like,
that's on the water.
What makes you think the
water is going to stay there?
Like it doesn't,
what if it goes back?
What if it goes from
yellow to contingency plan,
right?
No,
no.
You're just going to spend fucking $8
million on his crazy ass house that's on
the water right there.
Like total a lake.
So big,
so much more stable for a
few more for a few years.
We have a nice place to live,
but you're right.
But can you even get insurance
that the ocean will eat your house?
They know better now,
right?
I talked to a guy,
I interviewed a guy recently who,
um,
uh,
is a,
his job is,
is he owns a contractor,
a construction company or a deconstruction
company really that pulls oil rigs
out of the ocean,
wrecked oil rigs.
And he,
he in the,
uh,
in his twenties was designing oil rigs
and was describing what it was like to,
to design them back then.
And he said that,
uh,
um,
the,
uh,
the instructions from the instructor
back then was build it to this 60 year
storm standard.
And he was like,
but we've only been designing
all the rigs for 35 years.
How do we know what a 60
year storm looks like?
And they're like,
nevermind kid,
you know,
keep drawing.
So he's making these things and
he was explaining to us by way of,
of his then experience when Katrina hit,
um,
the,
uh,
the waves were so massive.
It was like a hundred,
you know,
was greater than a hundred year storm.
Um,
you know,
where were these decks that were designed
for 60 feet got hit with a hundred
foot waves,
you know,
it's unbelievable and
everything got torn down and
this guy now runs a versa bar.
This,
this company that,
that,
uh,
builds the,
this thing that can pull a whole oil rig
out of the ocean and carry it into land
because there's so many
that got wrecked by Katrina.
It's like its own industry.
Yeah.
And buy a hundred year storm.
You mean once every 100 years,
something cozy every year there's
a one in 100 chance or whatever.
Yeah,
exactly.
It's a,
it's a,
the a hundred year storm.
That's right.
That's one of the creepiest ideas about
what's going to happen because of the
warming of the planet is that these
storms are going to happen more and more
often.
And we had a guy on here that was talking
about the possibility of hurricane
sandy being something
that happens every year.
Yeah.
Right.
You're going to have one of those a year.
Maybe that could change to two a year.
That could change the three,
you know,
the,
the planet is built.
I mean,
you know,
the planet has built for equilibrium.
It's,
it's always trying to get
to equilibrium and yeah.
It just keeps changing.
That's right.
And you're a,
you're in northern California Guy,
right?
You live up there.
I live a weird life actually.
I go back and forth between New
York and California every month.
I'm in New York for one
week a month and then I,
my wife and daughter and are
in Oakland because we just,
we love California and I
happened to be living here when,
when the job came up,
so,
oh wow.
So,
you know,
in today's Day and age,
how much do you physically
have to be in a location?
I live in,
uh,
I,
I am sort of testing out that theory
that you don't have to be right with the
people you work,
you know,
so you work with,
so my staff is all in New York and I
communicate with them largely through the
phone.
I would say most of the time now.
But I went hard at the video telepresence
thing and I found that it's really
useful for a few kinds of conversations.
You know,
I can like make an announcement
or I can settle the debate,
you know,
I hear two sides and I make a
decision or something like that,
you know,
but it's not good for like
catching up with someone.
It's not good for,
you know,
sort of a confession.
Right.
Or,
or,
or you know,
uh,
you know,
personal,
personal stuff.
Anything where you want to win trust
or influenced something you're like,
I don't want to meet somebody that
I'm trying to impress that way.
And instead of trying,
you got to be face to face to
really connect with somebody.
I saw a fascinating aspect of the human
being and the human mind is the need for
like,
like if we were having this conversation,
there was six more feet of
desk between us that would,
that would change the
nature of the conversation.
Right.
We're not sitting at
this table the other way.
That's right.
That'd be like a banquet.
I mean,
we have headphones on.
I could see you if you were over there,
but it would feel weird.
It was like a good amount of distance
where we're like four feet from each
other.
That's right.
You don't touch toes under
the desk too many times.
You know that theory.
That's why I made it this.
Why,
but at the ice house,
we have another place to the ice house.
And I was always touching toes with
people on the death changes the
conversation.
That's fucking footsie.
People wonder,
is he trying to say something?
He's trying to,
he's trying to talk like if you,
when I want to talk,
I'll touch your foot
now.
But what is that about
humans where we need this,
this sort of a,
we need a close,
I mean,
I think there's a,
I don't know,
but it's,
it's definitely hardwired.
There's the,
there's the uncanny valley
is this whole thing that,
uh,
they determined where
basically if you,
um,
if you show somebody a fake human face,
right?
The brain immediately,
it's like,
oh,
this is fake.
Uh,
and if you,
uh,
make it more and more lifelike,
basically roboticists study this and
trying to create a robot that could fool
the human right or making
a human comfortable.
Um,
and so like when you take a kid,
well,
so,
so when it gets more and more uncanny,
right?
More and more like a person,
there's a point at which just before real
acceptance where you've really filled
a person where it,
the,
the acceptance rate drops off like,
like right.
As you get,
the closer you get to actual reality,
the more it freaks people out
to be talking to a fake person.
A really lifelike fake
person is way scarier than a,
not at all.
Like,
you know,
like a really lifelike fake
person that wants a fuck you
creepy with that.
I'd be like this man,
I don't think if you don't know
what it feels like to be a person,
you just imitating it.
I say,
no,
what the fuck are you going to do?
No means yes.
Yeah.
Like a fake,
fake,
crazy robot girl that wants
her deck and you gotta go,
listen,
this is not going to work for the red.
What did,
what is your thoughts,
if any,
on remote viewing?
Are you aware of the
phenomenon or redevelopment?
Is that,
is that real?
I don't think it's real or at least it's
never been really enough that we wanted
to do a story on it.
So I don't think of it as a real thing,
but I'm interested to hear any
thoughts everyone has about it.
You know,
I don't know if it's real,
but we're having this guy,
uh,
his name is Russell Targ
and he's a physicist and uh,
he's,
uh,
he's also one of the,
a pioneer in the earliest development
of the laser and he's still a future
upcoming guests.
And,
uh,
he's written quite a few books on it,
on a man,
on listen when I'm remote viewing
and one on the reality of Esp.
It's called a physicist
proof psychic abilities.
I just got it in the mail today.
I haven't gotten into it,
but at the Stanford Research
Institute in 1970s and eighties.
Targ and his colleague,
a guy named Harold Lauff
cofounded a 23 year,
$25 million program of research into the
psychic abilities and their operational
use for the u s intelligence travel chair.
Like I said a couple of months ago,
including the,
I don't know what that means,
including the CIA Defense Intelligence
Agency and the army intelligence and
these abilities are referred to
collectively as remote viewing.
And they both expressed the belief
that it's possible and that they,
they,
they believe that there is actual physical
evidence that proves that people can
accurately describe and to pick things
that exist somewhere where they're
nowhere near.
It would be fascinating to
know whether they can prove it.
I've looked at any of that yet.
I mean,
I know about it.
Right.
You know,
in the spirit of not saying
anything negative about something,
I don't know a lot about,
you know,
I don't want to like shoot
it down right off the bat,
you know,
but it sounds,
it doesn't sound likely.
It sounds like fuckery.
Right,
right.
It does.
It sounds like it to me,
but I,
I you,
I,
we've had
a,
a friend Tim Ferriss in here who
described studies that are done,
um,
where,
where people accurately describe
things through remote remote viewing.
So,
uh,
I'm,
I'm really interested in that.
It also has been,
I don't,
this should say this is controversial,
but it's been written at least that it's
been proven statistically that people
can tell when people are looking at you,
that someone can more often than not be
accurate about whether or not someone is
looking at you.
Like you could feel the eyes on you.
I don't know.
I don't know whether that's true or not,
but I do know that there is a,
you know,
there's,
uh,
if you talk to a police detective,
you know,
they'll tell you that when
you interview witnesses,
they,
you know,
to an auto accident,
let's say.
They typically say that they saw the tar,
the cars collide,
when in fact they typically heard the
sound world around and then saw the
aftermath of the actual collision.
But their memory tells them,
this was me seeing the cars collide.
And so I wonder how
much of it is hindsight,
you know,
where's the memory stored?
Yeah,
good question.
Good,
Right.
I mean,
the,
uh,
the ability to,
to,
uh,
you know,
really know where stuff is
happening is totally unbelievable.
You know,
you've got the like,
um,
the prefrontal cortex like
controls how you move your arms,
like we know some things
about where stuff is kept,
but like how it is affected,
how it truly is stored.
Is it,
is it binary or is it analog,
right?
Is it zeros and ones or is it like,
uh,
you know,
some sort of physical
arrangement of stuff like,
you know,
we don't know.
And we know that if you stimulate
certain parts of the brain,
you can rekindle memories,
right?
Or at rekindled the way,
the ability you have to retain memory.
I don't know that you can bring them back,
but you can certainly,
you know,
you can stimulate the part
of the brain that can,
that can,
uh,
help foster that for some reason.
But again,
this is us,
like it's us like poking on
the outside and seeing like,
oh sorry,
there's a far side cartoon from years
ago where the a group of doctors around
the table and one of the legs is going,
don't y'all,
y'all,
y'all on one side.
And the,
and the doctor,
the nurse says,
you know,
careful doctors,
don't touch that part or leave that part,
you know,
or whatever it isn't.
That's totally,
you know,
we're,
that's sort of where we're at in terms of,
of,
you know,
brain research.
I read this speculation once where there
was thinking that it was possible that
memories were in fact
stored in the neurons.
And the,
um,
the idea behind it was that human
cells regenerate every seven years.
Like pretty much every cell in your body
is completely regenerated every seven
years except the neurons.
Neurons tend to stay with you
for the rest of your life.
Yeah.
So that's the best thing.
Might be the only place for memories.
But I've thought about it and I said,
well maybe that's why your memory suck
when they're older than seven years old.
Cause they're like copies of
copies like an old VHS tape,
things would just get real,
get screening.
It's a little grainy.
It's in fact you were the
hero of that story instead of,
right,
right.
I've gone back over thing.
I mean I have some really definitive
life changing moments in my life that I'm
pretty sure I have the events clearly.
Right.
But if I allowed you into my
mind to look at what data I have,
I mean you basically have me regurgitating
some shit that I might've said when I
was 10 and then I'm saying it
over again when I'm 13 and again,
when I'm 16 and again,
you know what I mean?
And it's like I've kept repeating this
and referencing it or considering it.
So I have this,
this image of it.
But if you looked into my head,
some of the things that
I've done in my life,
you know,
and some of the things that,
really big moments in my life,
all you'd find,
it's like a few fucking blurry images
and maybe some reference points.
And if you look at the way that,
that,
you know,
we have learned,
I mean,
one,
one place that we have learned the brain
pretty well is anesthesia because you
end up,
um,
uh,
w we know now how to turn off
things like short term memory,
so the latest forms and we eat well,
is that the way to do solid.
Exactly.
Um,
but if you're going to crack open the
chest to get the baby out or whatever the
thing is,
clammed the clam,
uh,
you know,
you're going to need a different,
uh,
you know,
need some serious drugs.
So they turn off the,
they turn off the,
the,
your memory basically.
And it's not so much that they're turning
off the body is a sensation of the
pain as much as they're
turning off your memory of it,
uh,
so that you're not really
experiencing it consciously,
but you still in that state,
your blood pressure goes up.
Like your body is feeling pain and an
anesthesiologist is managing that pain for
you.
But the idea is to turn off your,
your memory more than
your nerve receptors,
which is amazing.
So when you're unconscious
in an anesthesia,
the in,
in an anesthesia steak
or an anesthetized state,
right,
your,
your body still is sending the signals,
right.
But not like a sleeping
person who would wake up
the memory shutoff.
Yeah.
You're not even,
you're not having the
experience consciously.
Uh,
so your,
your body is not jolting you awake.
It's just turning that off so
you're not absorbing it at all.
The hippocampus is not
translating that into,
into long term memories
for whatever reason.
I'm not sure quite how it works,
but as a result,
you,
yeah,
your,
your body still is free to respond.
I think that an
anesthesiologist would say,
hey,
it really depends.
There's some procedures
where that's not the case.
Um,
but it also is healthy or
not to turn off too much.
You don't want to turn off
a lot of the body you want,
you know,
they have to sometimes
depending on the procedure.
But you want to,
I think,
keep a lot of it as you know,
going of its own accord
as much as possible.
Well then there's
brain surgery,
which is even fucking crazier.
And the fact that there was a of
general consensus amongst doctors and
scientists just mean how many decades
ago where they were doing lobotomies were
there are gone,
this dude's fucked
up,
let's drill a hole in.
His brain's scrambled
that frontal lobe and see,
see if we can get a
nicer person out of it.
Yeah,
yeah.
No,
I know.
It's uh,
the,
the idea that anybody would sort of really
mess around with the brain back then
considering how little we know now,
you know,
the fact that we need $3 billion worth
of research to get oriented is basically
what that would do.
A man,
you know,
like yeah.
Nobody should be scrambling anybody.
Yeah.
What does that,
what was it called?
Trip panning.
Think where they would drill holes
in the skull to release pressure,
man,
man.
And sometimes they have to do that,
you know,
like emergency surgery,
you have to,
you know,
somebody will whack their head,
and then they,
they have to do that sometimes.
But yeah,
the idea that you would do that to try
and sort of like affect behavior is nuts.
You know,
on the other hand,
they have discovered things like,
um,
uh,
you know,
what's it called?
Um,
shock treatment,
right?
Was,
was this desire to sort of,
you could calm the brain
in a way by hitting,
by jolting it.
Um,
and uh,
it comes,
it was discovered basically
by the original sort of
discovery that led to that
was a in slaughterhouses,
uh,
they would stun the cattle ahead of time,
with like a shot to the,
you know,
to the brow basically with a,
um,
on one of those,
uh,
not nail guns but a rivet gun.
And as a result,
the and the,
and the,
the car,
the cow would go incredibly calm and then
a whole body of research sort of grew
out of that dynamic
trying to figure out like,
what is the shot to the
system that calms the body.
It calms the mind for a second.
And for the longest time they weren't
doing electroshock therapy on humans.
They stopped doing it.
There was the sort of one flow is the
one flew over the cuckoo's nest way of
looking at it like,
oh,
you just ruined that guy.
He had calmed him down,
but you shut you,
you know that Jack Nicholson drooling
at the end of the movie where it's,
Oh,
he's gone,
he's fucked.
He cooked his brain towards,
now it's,
it's commonly done to
people that are fucked up.
I think they also known now.
So back then you had what were called,
uh,
you know,
we're back on site and as iconic here,
but there was,
you had positive and negative
symptoms and that's a technical term.
It doesn't mean good or bad.
It means a positive symptoms
where the symptoms where you,
you have an outburst side,
they're outwardly noticeable,
uh,
outbursts,
you know,
yelling,
hallucinations,
potters are part of it.
And the negative is a lack
of emotional connection,
lack of reasoning or cognitive
abilities starts to go away.
And those are,
those were,
you know,
a whole separate category of symptoms.
And back then in the early days of
something like electroshock therapy,
they typically only had
something like thorazine,
lithium,
um,
to sort of turn off all it,
all it would turn off was
your positive symptoms,
but it didn't affect any of your,
uh,
um,
negative symptoms.
The,
the,
you know,
being you're still lethargic,
he still can't make connections to people.
You're still not thinking,
well,
plus you're sort of sedated.
So they talked about
the thorazine shuffle,
you know,
that was back.
And so I wonder if some of it,
I'm just making this up,
but I wonder if,
if some of it is people
would get jolted and then,
um,
after beyond this medication typically
and be shuffling around and people would
all be like,
oh,
that guy was never the same since
he had his electroshock therapy.
But maybe he was also on the drug
that was turning them all right.
I'm just,
I dunno,
I'm just making that up,
but it certainly couldn't get involved.
It's so funny how we look
back at those days and go,
oh,
those fucking dummies.
They didn't know they were doing.
But guaranteed people a thousand years
from now are going to be looking at us.
We're so silly.
We didn't know anything.
We didn't even have artificial brains
yet cause they were still driving
ourselves.
Yeah,
that's right.
What is your thoughts on
a ray Kurzweil's idea of,
of humanism that we are eventually going
to be symbiotic with some sort of a
machine counterpart?
I love it.
I mean,
I think it's a,
it's a really interesting,
you know,
it's a great time reference.
That's basically what he's
trying to do is say like,
here's the next great milestone
in innovation and development.
You know,
and I,
I,
I think it's a nice,
uh,
a really good organizing principle.
It's inspired a lot of great thinking.
You know,
whether it's going to turn out that
we really do create like a symbiotic,
you know,
relationship.
I Dunno,
but in a way we already have,
right?
Like if you've got the new galaxy,
blah,
blah.
And with Google,
when you turn on that first a
little screen that tells you like,
here's the time,
here's the weather near you.
Um,
you,
it will also follow,
uh,
you,
you know,
it'll track your day,
your time,
like where are you are and begin to pick
up the history over time of where you
are.
And it'll start to suggest like,
here's a better route to
take to work or you know,
here's food near you and your w it's
telling you information before you're even
asking for it.
Which for me is a totally new,
you know,
are crossing this line
where it's no longer like,
oh,
I'm hungry,
I want to go eat something.
And then you pull out your phone to ask
it how to do that instead of the phone
is telling you,
Hey,
I've got an idea,
why don't you get a burger?
And you're like,
thanks phone.
And so in a way we've
almost already gotten there,
you know,
and the biggest giveaway is how weird
you feel when you leave it at home.
Right?
Your phone.
I didn't use my phone for
almost two days this weekend.
It was the best feeling ever.
And I've noticed that one of the biggest
things with hipsters nowadays is that
they don't have cell phones anymore.
And I could kind of see
myself even going back there.
Really the big thing with
hips or heard of that.
Yeah.
The new thing has hipsters
don't have cell phones,
so that's great.
And that they just,
they just write letters.
I'm being a hundred percent serious.
I just found out about it this way from,
uh,
this girl I know is working on a movie
and I guess there's a couple of people
that are so hipster.
It's that they don't have phones in the,
so she has to like email them.
That's,
so that's great.
Like wow.
It's like the steam punk thing.
Looking back at that time,
trying to find out from this is
good if you don't have a phone,
that's ridiculous.
That's so stupid.
Why you don't have to use her dummy.
But the fact that you don't have one,
but I'm
not using your phone for two days.
It's
a ate mushrooms and swam with dolphins.
It when I went to Montana
for six days for six days,
no cell phone.
Great.
Right?
Yeah.
It's,
it's,
well,
it's also good to get the
fuck away from the hive,
you know,
cause we were camping for
those days that were out there,
so it wasn't just no cell phone,
there was no contact with civilized world.
It was just the natural world
of walking around and hiking.
And it's a,
it's a completely different feeling than
when you're constantly checking your
email,
constantly watching the CNN screen
at the airport and all that,
that,
that they leave the constant
input of information.
Do you have any experience at all
in a sensory deprivation tanks?
No,
not me personally.
I am really interested in,
you had said earlier when we were
looking at that footage of the,
um,
the cumulus cloud and the
soldiers running toward it,
like how fragile the body is.
That's my,
like,
that's the subject I
geek out on the hardest.
I really am fascinated
by exactly that and like,
you know,
sensory deprivation tanks.
It's just funny.
Like,
we're,
we're so vulnerable,
we're such vulnerable little creatures
and it's so unbelievable that we move
around the world and live
around the world where we do,
how we do,
you know,
Louis C K as that great thing about,
uh,
people complaining about the Wifi not
working on the flight and he's like,
you're being thrown through
the sky in a chair and come on.
And,
uh,
and that's totally how
I feel about everything.
Like when I look at,
you know,
uh,
airbags,
you know,
sure.
Safety,
restraint systems like
pressurization on plans,
all that stuff.
It's unbelievable.
So,
yeah.
Yeah.
What I meant though is the actual effects
on the mind or sensory deprivation,
right.
You,
you know,
you'd never experienced that at all.
I haven't,
I haven't gone in and done a tank.
No.
Why not?
I've never done it.
No,
I just haven't had the opportunity.
I'd love to.
It sounds great.
You're leaving soon.
Otherwise I would just
suggest a place here,
but in northern California,
there's a gang of places you
go to and I'm sure Twitter,
Twitter,
people attack.
Go send them some links.
Um,
you got to try it.
If you were fascinated by the human mind,
you really need to try that state.
Cool.
Cause it's not available
anywhere else in the world.
How would you describe it if you have it?
Oh yeah.
I have one in my house.
I do it almost every week.
You know,
I had many times all week.
Yeah.
What's it like?
What does the,
what's the effect?
Well there's no,
there's no census coming in.
I mean even having this conversation,
there's no distractions
but every now and then,
you know,
you hear that truck goes
by or next door or your,
you feel you're,
you have to shift your butt cause
you know it gets uncomfortable.
All that input,
all that's input.
When you're in a tank,
there's nothing,
there's no input and much like
we're having this conversation.
If a truck goes by,
it's a slight distraction.
If you're trying to formulate words
and that truck was really loud,
it will be annoying because you
have to deal with that input.
You have to deal with that.
That information is coming towards
you when you're inside the tank.
It really is.
The only environment in the world where
you don't have your body talking to you,
right?
You're floating in water.
That's the same temperature as your skin.
There's a thousand pounds
of salt in that water,
Epsom salt.
So you float like you're,
you're completely buoyant,
and because your temperature of
the water is the same as your skin,
you don't feel it after a while,
you literally feel like
flying through space.
What does it do to the total darkness?
Your most silence?
Well,
your mind has no sensory input,
so there's no distractions.
So it's super powered.
It's ridic.
Just as your brain is compromised,
when there's a Jack Hammer next to you,
your brain becomes equally
magnified when there's nothing.
If I have any problems whatsoever of
these things that are bothering me,
I go in the tank and it's like
having a seminar on my life.
It's like all of a sudden I
could see things so much clearly.
Hmm.
And so much more clearly.
And you're,
you're completely outside of the world.
I mean,
you're not lying on a bed.
You're not in an osh rom.
You're not even in a human body anymore.
It's your consciousness,
literally untethered from the human body.
That's awesome.
Yeah,
you need to do it.
We'll,
I'm in,
I'm in.
That sounds great.
I didn't invent this fucking thing and
I can't believe that I tell so many
people about it and they're like,
wow,
I need to do that.
I'm like,
Jesus,
this is 2013 why the fuck are
these things not everywhere.
There's so incredibly beneficial.
And they give you a lot of the benefits
of psychedelic drugs without any of the
worries about tripping
out and losing your mind.
And you know,
a lot of people know someone that's lost
their marbles on Lsd or something or
had a bad emotional
experience on mushrooms.
And so when they think about the idea
of taking a drug to detach from the
reality,
to gain a fresh perspective,
it's terrifying.
But you can achieve
psychedelic states and in,
in a sensory deprivation
tank with no worries at all.
Totally.
I,
I will.
I will try it out.
I've never done it that on it.
So we're just that Sherman's,
it's better.
You don't even know.
You don't even try it.
An isolation tank.
How are you talking about?
It's,
it doesn't beat my mushrooms.
You don't know that.
You don't know anything.
So you're saying isolates
and taking Pete's terms.
I'm saying it's the
same sort of experience.
You can have the same experience that you
can have on a heavy duty mushroom trip
in an isolation tank.
And by the way,
a mushroom trip in an isolation tank
is a thousand times more intense way we
eat.
Is Mark for you?
Self examined me.
That's the last thing you want.
Um,
it's,
it's a,
it's just a incredibly unique environment
that I'm shocked isn't available at
major universities.
I think it should be everywhere.
I think people should have that.
I mean it should be,
you can go anywhere and you find a
yoga studio and try find her sensory
deprivation.
Reason Joe is that a lot of
people it doesn't work on,
that's not,
that's not the reason.
Brian,
I reason why it's not available
is not because a lot of people,
it doesn't work on.
No,
I mean that's why it's nice popular
because a lot of people do the isolation
tank and it does nothing for them.
So why would they go back to doing,
what are you basing this on?
I know several people that have come up
to me and talked to me about isolation
tanks because they've heard it
on this podcast and they've,
they were like,
I've done it three times.
It's nothing to me.
It's just kind of boring.
I just sit there and
that's happened to me,
at least for you.
These are the people that
are desperate to talk to you.
They have limited resources.
The right,
I'm telling you because I
fucking have one in my basement.
I,
you just need to learn how
to let go and concentrate.
It's not like it's an
immediate jolt into hyperspace,
but what it is,
is the,
uh,
an environment where you can truly be
away from the influence on full body.
And if you're on any sort of substance,
any psychedelic or anything,
it's magically enhanced inside the tank.
You eat a cookie and get an isolation
tank and tell me that's not a trippy
experience.
I'll tell you,
you're crazy.
It's,
it's,
it's so beneficial.
There's a couple of issues.
One,
most people who do it,
they don't do it enough to get
truly relaxed in that environment.
Because a lot of the sensory deprivation
tank experience is about letting go.
It's about learning how to relax
and learning how to let go,
and not concentrating on the fact that
you're in a tank and not bumping up
against the walls.
You got to get good at it and you got to
get good at the whole letting go thing.
It's not easy.
It's just like meditation.
It's a difficult thing to do,
but you can achieve some pretty
powerful states in meditation.
You can achieve much more powerful
states if you're meditating inside of an
isolation tank.
Hmm.
I just want her to know if you knew
anything about the actual effects of the
mind.
Do you remember that movie
altered states when they do,
was wired up with all these electrodes
and they were monitoring his mine lives
in there.
I haven't seen it.
You haven't seen altered states?
What was all based on John Lilly?
Um,
who was,
uh,
by the way,
used to take acid and talked to dolphins.
That was his thing.
Pioneer an interspecies communication and,
uh,
Lilly,
would get an isolation tank and a set
it up right next to a tank filled with
dolphins and the hop in the isolation
tank and trip his balls off and have this
experience.
But He created the
sensory deprivation tank.
There was a couple of
different versions of it.
The first one,
he was a vertical with sort of like
a space helmet on for his heir.
And he would like float
based on this tank.
Like he would kind of be
floating from his head.
Yeah.
And then the second one,
he figured out,
okay,
if you live vertically and
fill the tank with salt,
you'll float.
So he,
he even rigged it up so that he could,
he had like a tube that was collecting
waste and sucking waste out of it.
So he spent a long time there.
Well,
lily was also famous for
his love of ketamine,
so he would,
uh,
take ketamine and go on these a six
hour Kay hold trips inside this tank.
And if you gotta take a leak,
you know,
just pulls it out of you.
Yeah,
I was peeking hard during these,
uh,
this mushroom trip though.
Like I ate,
I just ate a cap.
I just went into a little and I started
like to the point where my hands were
melting and I had to go into
this water and it was intense.
Like sure.
I was like trying to like talk
to the dolphin with my mind,
like staring at in its eyes
and stuff and it didn't go,
it wouldn't have pretty good.
I mean it was pretty ridiculous.
But the,
the crazy thing is that the
dolphin racked me twice,
didn't hit anybody else and then at the
end busted me on the lip with its tail.
You got lucky.
Two dolphins are strong.
It was like,
so what are you thinking of?
The Dolphin was like hearing your cries.
I wanted to beat the shit out
of you cause you were annoying.
I have no idea.
And the only other thing I can think
of is I was at the end of the line.
So when,
when,
when they were like,
all right,
we're going to flip the dolphin over.
Everyone pet it.
Stomach.
Well,
I was petting the vagina the whole time,
didn't even know it,
and then she,
she's like,
see that's,
this is the vagina and there's a slit
on each side of the vagina that the
dolphin feeds out of.
I'm like,
Whoa,
I'm touching it.
Like,
like she is.
What do you mean you didn't know?
You've told me about that.
And that was true.
Mean Dude,
I was like touch item that's in front
of you didn't even know what it looked
like.
I mean,
at the time I was just like,
wow,
it's soft.
It's awesome.
But then did you get to right you,
you,
you did this before,
right?
Oh I'm,
I'm,
I'm really against dolphin captivity.
I think it's really fucked up.
I think the idea of taking
a superintelligent animal
like a dolphin and putting
in a swimming pool and having a bunch
of people touch it is just like taking a
person and putting them in a fucking
box and having a bunch of fish come and
stare at you.
I think it's ridic.
Yeah,
they do eat like crazy and they seemed
all very happy and dolphins are the only
ones that you know,
if they don't like life,
they just stopped breeding like
they're there voluntarily breathing.
They're,
they're the only species
that voluntarily breeze.
And so like that's why a lot of times
when dolphins will just commit suicide if
they're unhappy and they would all
commit suicide if they were unhappy,
wouldn't they?
I mean it's,
you're saying that their
life has to be so horrible,
the commit suicide.
There's a lot of people that are
ridiculously unhappy in prison that aren't
committing suicide.
It doesn't mean the prison
is awesome by that logic.
That doesn't mean
wouldn't there be some dolphins that
killed themselves to then if they were
unhappy?
I mean they just have,
do you know anybody just got home fed
the whole time I was watching them?
No,
man,
they have no freedom.
Not only that,
they steal them from their mothers.
The killer whales are
very famous for that.
And killer whales,
by the way,
the only incidents of killer whales,
they'll ever murdering people.
It's been in captivity.
They hate it.
They don't want that.
Dolphins have killer whales.
There were dolphins are just
cousins of killer whales.
I just think it's a fucked up a replica.
It's a remnant of the past where
we didn't understand these animals.
These are super,
super intelligent animals and just like
the cove is fucked up cause it's fucked
up to murder them.
It's fucked up to imprison them too.
It's not like these were bad dolphins and
we had to remove them from the dolphin
population,
which dolphins by the way are fucking bad.
They do a lot of crazy shit.
They rape,
they kill babies.
I mean they don't just
because they're intelligent,
they don't fall by the morals and the
ethics that human beings would like to
think of flipper having right now.
Dolphins do some dirty shit.
We,
the story coming up in a couple of issues
about by this Guy Brian Lam who runs a
thing called the wire cutters.
Cool guy.
But I mean,
he,
he's a good writer and did a story
for us about a basically going,
and I'm tagging along with this kind of,
not quite rank tank crew,
but like,
you know,
crew scientists,
but they there by their nature are
a little crazy and that they're out,
um,
uh,
hand tagging sharks.
They'd get them up on the boat,
you know,
like dangerous,
hammerheads know the whole deal.
And
they tagged them with these very
improved tanks that are far more
technologically Fisker
than what we have now.
And as a result of giving us all this
new data about sharks and what they do
with it live with,
you know,
how deep they go,
all this stuff.
Um,
but he was describing what it's like to,
in the story he describes what it's like
to try and get to be in the water with
a shark and how incredibly scary that is.
Like those things are
just built for death.
They are,
you know,
the nature's perfect weapon.
Those things.
Yeah,
that must be absolutely horrifying.
Um,
one of the things,
one of the reasons why I'm so adamant
about the dolphin thing was that I had a
psychedelic experience with dolphins,
two of them eating pot and being on a,
a boat.
And that's that,
that bit that I do a store that I wrote,
I,
these dolphins were playing with us
and they were jumping next to us by the
boat.
And they're,
they're,
they're really playful and they're
really obviously intelligent.
Like they don't fall for the hooks.
They're not biting our bait.
You know,
we're,
we're fishing and we're not,
they don't worry about it at all.
Like,
no one catches a dolphin on a hook.
It's just doesn't happen.
The only way you catch
them is by netting them.
Like,
you know,
corralling them in where they're fucked.
But you don't hear about
dolphins falling for a fake worm.
You know,
it doesn't happen.
I've always liked the people who say,
you know,
people who've,
who've spent time with them sometimes say,
you know,
man,
it's,
it seems almost as if they've
evolved past where we are.
You know,
like they shed their possessions.
We don't have the ability
to change their environment,
but other than that they have an amazing
ability to communicate and they have a
nice environment.
Have you seen it?
Have you seen their ears,
Joe?
It's like a higher technology than us.
It's a pinhole.
It's just a little dot.
And they're also born with mustaches
when they're young and like you could see
the holes when they're older where the
mustache used to be on their lip and
there's a bad ass.
They were born with mustaches.
I wonder what purpose it serves.
No.
Evolutionary fresh looking,
fresh little.
A nice little pimp,
thin stash.
Like I think it is too.
And I think it is a pin stripe,
like one of those Eddie Murphy ones
where it's just a tiny line of hair above
the lip.
Yeah,
I dunno,
I just,
I,
I think it's cool that
you did that and you know,
I mean they're,
they're going to be in that seaworld
placed whether you go there or not,
but I don't want to go there.
I've been to the zoo
high and I don't like it.
You know,
I wrote this whole thing
when I went to the zoo about,
it's like this animal prison.
You see these primates
screaming in their cage.
I was at a zoo once
and this is one monkey.
I don't remember what monkey was,
but it was by itself and its little cage.
It was smaller than this room and
this fucking thing was screaming.
And I was like,
that is madness.
That's an intelligent animal that someone
has decided to make it stay in this
one spot and it's going insane.
Screaming.
What,
what seemed like that to me was the
ship moves or that the killer whales and
that to me,
like I didn't think that,
I thought the dolphins looked like
they were all having a great time.
But,
uh,
the killer whales looked that was kind
of fucked up cause it was just a huge
tank and they just were
swimming in circles,
not stop.
That's all they did.
They,
yeah,
that,
that was awful.
But,
but I thought the
shampoos were pretty cool.
You know what?
It's all physical.
You know what I think
it's called about boa.
Is that what it's called?
Where?
It's like a dolphin,
but it's white and it's got a
huge like crazy mushroom head.
Oh I know what you're
talking to him about.
Nine.
So type of,
it's a type of dolphin.
Yeah,
it's a white,
I think it's actually a type of whale.
It's a,
yeah,
I know what you're talking about.
They will know the name of it opening up
next month where you can hang out with
those guys and that Shit looks bad
ass cause it looks like star wars.
This is how they should do it.
If they really want to have
a relationship with dolphins,
they should give them food and put up
a center in a place where the dolphins
live naturally and put
people in submarines.
But the idea that you know you should
put them in a fucking fish tank,
and by the way,
that water's probably chlorinated how else
they're going to have it.
It was salt water.
It was salty.
Tastes like Saltwater and Oh,
okay,
that makes sense actually because
I have a saltwater pool like you,
you know you can have,
you can get away with that without those.
The same principle of the isolation tank,
not getting funky.
Nothing really can grow in the salt water.
Right.
But I just think we don't
need to do that anymore,
man.
It's just a,
even zoos,
I mean,
I take my kids to the zoo
because the zoo is there.
And for them it's fascinating
and they go crazy.
But it was up to me.
We wouldn't have zoos.
It's just seems crazy to
have a prison for gorillas.
They're staring at you and they're fucked.
You know,
just the whole thing is,
it's,
it's a relic I think.
Yeah,
no,
it's true.
I,
you know,
the,
it's funny when you go,
there's the American Museum of Natural
History in New York has this whole wing
of it's stuff that it inherited of like,
um,
you know,
stuffed animals.
And,
uh,
I,
you know,
I'd love the Americans are not state.
I think they do amazing work,
you know,
but the,
um,
you know,
it's just funny to go and
stand in front of like,
what was the zoo back in the 19th century,
18th century.
The desire to,
to,
uh,
you know,
shoot and stuff and animals.
How about African men?
Well,
there was there,
there's been a exhibits at zoos
before where they had black men.
I think they had pygmies.
It's zoos before,
Huh?
Yeah.
I mean they've uh,
the,
the ability to justify the
imprisonment of an intelligent animal.
It's really weird when we start and think
about what an intelligent species from
another planet would do to us if
they came here and found out that Kim
Kardashian was the most
famous woman on the planet.
What is to say that they want
these dumb mother fuckers,
let's just lock them up in
a cage and give him food.
As long as they have food,
they'll be happy.
There are,
I mean,
the,
on the other hand though,
I would point out that there's like,
you know,
there is some,
at least some understanding
of what animals need to
thrive in an environment and
just do,
do a great job.
We're trying to do a great job in the
way of creating environments where the
animal is,
you know,
maybe trick is one way to put it,
but like you know,
is,
feels comfortable in the environment
and there's all kinds of crazy optical
illusions at the Seattle Zoo.
There's a,
the Savannah kind of curves,
it's almost like you're,
you're on the top of the dome sort of,
but it's a very gradual dumb,
but it's enough that for a long time it
looks as if there's a long horizon out
in front of you.
Uh,
it blocks out the background that's,
no,
you're not seeing a
trees in the background,
whatever,
because it's sloped up just slightly.
And you know,
I wonder if that's,
I don't know.
But I imagine that that's
like designed to make,
you know,
to keep a lion's eyes sharp or whatever
the thing is that they're trying to do.
Well,
if they really want it
to be nice to the line,
they like goats Lewis.
They would also look at growth
there like they do in Asia.
You know,
in Asia,
the way they treat tigers,
they,
it's really not sporting whatsoever
because they back a truck up and they,
they lift up the fork lift in the
back of the truck or whatever the,
uh,
the cab in the back of the
truck and the goat falls out.
The Tigers just tear it apart.
Wow.
Have you ever seen that before?
No,
I haven't.
Cue the video.
It's the,
um,
there's a,
also a zoo in Iraq and that's one of
the first videos I ever saw about it on
online where they,
uh,
they released a goat and these lions came
running out and rip the goat apart in
front of all these,
a gis that were there with cell phones.
Well,
yeah,
it's,
um,
at least that's normal.
That's what they do.
That's right.
The idea of sliding a tray under
the cage with some cold meat.
Yeah.
The whole reward system
that an animal has,
especially these predators,
their entire reward system is based
on chasing and catching things.
Right.
I mean if you roll a
ball in front of a cat,
it's going to go after it
and it's because it's got,
and they say the,
one of the big things about mountain
lion attacks as they attack joggers a lot
cause they think you're
trying to get away,
right,
right.
Thing they tell you about a pickup,
any small children,
uh,
in order to,
because of mountain lions instinct is
to go after the smallest one and little
kids or are prone to running away.
And that is what turns on the instinct,
the prey drive so that you have to pick
up your kid if you see a mountain lion.
Well and coyotes as well,
you know,
there was a big bear,
um,
last year there was an attack of five
year old was attacked by a coyote right in
front of his father.
Oh Wow.
And the coyote tackled
the kid and just tried to,
tried to fucking eat them.
No,
man.
Yeah.
As a father I would be,
I'd freak out.
Yeah.
So here they dropped this thing out and
they just grab a hold of it and just
start pulling it apart.
Wow.
What is that?
Uh,
as it is,
it beef some sort of a sheep or a
goat or something like that and these,
uh,
this is lying.
So those things are strong.
Yeah.
The lion's take a little
more time than the Tigers.
The Tigers grab ahold of it and
it's almost instantly a wrap.
They just yank them and rip on Florence.
But it means if you're going
to have animals like that,
it seems kind of fucked
up to have them in a,
in a place where they can't run
around and they don't have any chase.
Right,
right.
Their whole reason to live.
That's what they were involved.
All these incredible abilities,
right.
Th the teeth and the
pre drove the eyesight,
all that stuff.
And you do need to keep that right.
Sharp vegans who feed
their dogs Vegan dog food,
like,
Oh,
you fuck,
how dare you?
Like,
you know that dogs barely
surviving on that shit,
by the way.
I was talking about a
Beluga whale earlier.
Ah,
yeah.
That's it.
Are they as smart as
a dolphin or anything?
Oh,
that's a good question.
I think it's the same family.
I mean they're,
they're definitely the,
the,
you know,
it's that family.
Yeah.
I think there's a whole gang,
a smart marine animals,
you know,
and we're willing to in prison,
all of them
let's really awesome.
Amazing.
It's seeing the sting rays,
they have this whole thing where it's
just this pool where you can touch and
feed sting rays and these sting rays would
just come up out of the pool and they
look like little dogs that
instead of having feet have like,
you know,
like,
like wings on those.
It was really amazing because
they're so domesticated.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I've fed him.
In Hawaii there's a tank and
at the big island where you,
uh,
you swim with them,
he put a snorkel on swim with the sting
rays and all these other fish and fish
poop by the way.
Everywhere you look,
it's not even a tank actually.
It's like a Gel,
like a big pond and they'll allow you
to feed them and little kids feed them.
They hold food out like scallops
and stuff in their hands and the,
the stingers come up and they,
they're crazy miles and they just
suck it right out of your hand.
Uh,
series C row.
It's bad ass though.
That's all I have to say.
Yeah,
I agree.
I mean it is bad ass,
but are you,
I can't agree with it morally.
I just think,
I think they're intelligent and I think
we have to sort of draw some sort of a
line as to how we deal
with intelligent beings.
Our attitude is like,
what are you saying?
I can't understand you.
Do you want a fish?
Then you have to do the trick.
You know,
it's kind of fucked up.
I had a friend who was a trainer,
I don't know where,
where it was somewhere in Hawaii.
He was trained to dolphins or he,
he was a graduate student.
I was doing this work.
And,
um,
he said that by the end of it,
the dolphins had trained
him that basically like he
was only getting to the pool
when he was like they would behave a
certain way to get him to behave a certain
way is how he just wound up one day
realizing that not disagreeing with you in
any way but it is nuts that they're just,
they're really,
really intelligent.
Yeah,
I'm sure.
I mean they're,
they're trying to express something and
if he's paying attention he's going to
sort of catch on and,
and move with it.
Dumb.
They would do that.
They would do the trick too to get him
to give them the treat but then they
would withhold the trick
and then do it really well.
They would do like they'd mess with them
and essentially ended like train him to
just deliver the fish.
If I could live comfortably and
not have to worry about money,
I would just take care of dolphins for my,
for my job.
I that's how,
how attached to that,
that experience to me wise,
it was just that there's
something with dolphins there.
I haven't been found out.
Yeah,
they're amazing.
And it hasn't been found out.
It's just,
we can't understand them.
They,
they're very intelligent.
They're cerebral cortex.
It's 40% larger than a human beings.
And,
um,
I mean I,
that,
that experience that I had when I
was in the boat in Hawaii with those,
uh,
wild dolphins playing that was a,
it seemed very tangible to me and it
changed the way I look at human beings.
It changed the way I look
at consciousness in general.
I started thinking that
their consciousness is
probably quite a bit like a
human's consciousness.
They just can't alter
their environment there.
They,
we can't them and they can
alter their environment,
but they seem like if you,
uh,
encountered,
I mean we,
we,
we take for granted the fact that the
way they move is very much like a fish.
So we sort of categorize them sort of how
you were talking about trucks earlier.
Like,
oh,
that's a truck.
Oh,
that's a dolphin.
Their method of locomotion is one thing.
But if you met a dolphin in space,
if it was like something like that where
it had that sort of intelligence and it
was communicating and moving
around more like a human,
if it had,
it was bipedal and it was,
but it,
you looked at it and made
noise and interacted with you,
you would freak the fuck out dude.
Run.
Yeah.
Well you would just freak out.
You'd be so flabbergasted that you're
dealing with this alien intelligence.
It's just like you,
it's dolphins exist in this world where
they can move through three dimensional
space,
so they don't need to be able to touch
things with fingers and all manipulation.
There's all kinds of studies about,
um,
uh,
you know,
the,
the inner life,
the emotional life of animals.
You know,
elephants that bury their dead,
grieve for their dead.
Elephants can recognize
themselves in the mirror,
know who they are and like
all that stuff is amazing.
They'll do paint themselves.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
That's a trip.
That's a man.
You see the elephant painting
an elephant with his nose.
And grief is a big one that we like.
When we look back at the evolution of,
of uh,
uh,
people,
one of the great turning
points in evolution is,
um,
when we began burying our dead and the
idea that we began having these sort of,
you know,
a scientist would say,
sort of imagine,
you know,
inner lives and imaginary life almost,
right?
We just develop an
abstract sense of death.
That's when we become sophisticated.
You know,
that's when our brains,
meaning brains begin to really do it.
That's one of the things that trips me
out the most about Ray Kurtzweil is that
he believes he will be able to transcend
death and we'll be able to download
content onto a computer and
it takes 100,000 pills a
day and watches his diet in
order to extend his life to that
point where he gets to do that.
Yeah,
that's a very,
I wonder if I would opt for that.
You know,
like I find myself thinking about
like how I would want to go given like
infinite technological stuff.
I would want to go out on top.
I wouldn't want to let
you know what I mean.
Like you don't want to fade anymore.
You want all the medical research working
to make you think like you are playing
in,
you know,
game six,
the world series.
It's a real wrestling match between our
instincts and the reality that we're a
finite being and the reality that
we are also a part of a process.
One piece of a super organism,
which is the human race and,
but our ego tells us,
no,
I'm the most imply,
must survive.
I must,
I am important.
Yes,
it is.
I,
she was me,
you know,
it's the thing thing that
is always amazing to me about people who
can be so brave and reckless with their
bodies and so forth.
It's like they're,
they're getting there.
They're taking what you're
describing and sort of,
uh,
somehow of resisting it in a weird way.
Like your brain has evolved
to basically keep you alive,
keep you out of danger.
And the idea that people can sort of
voluntarily enter dangerous situations is,
to me an amazing
fighters are,
fighters are like,
you know,
I a suit people.
Yeah,
exactly.
Exactly.
Extreme athletes stuff is unbelievable
to me that I just think that's so,
you know,
it's amazing and thrilling and
wondrous and also scary as hell and,
and sort of nonsensical from
an evolutionary perspective,
like the idea that you would
voluntarily leap off a cliff.
You know,
you have to resist so many
millennia of programming to do that.
And you know,
it's nuts in a,
in a great way.
I guess we have the luxury of doing that.
And it's also that weird thing that we
do where we try to outdo each other and
who can do the wackiest craziest,
scariest shit.
And that's how these x games,
things like that.
They've had to like put
limits on people like say,
okay,
you can't do that any more
because someone just died trying,
like stop with the quadruple
flip off of the top of this ramp.
It can't,
you know,
it's not going to be done or it's going
to be done and 20% of the people are
going to die.
And that's not acceptable.
Right,
right.
I mean,
you can't really regulate
what people are going to do,
you know,
just give them a suit.
You know,
those guys are mostly doing it illegally.
But man,
just the ability to,
you know,
I was once interviewing a fighter,
a test pilot went on
to become an astronaut.
And I was asking him,
how did you,
how do you not freak out when you are
sitting on top this bomb on the launch
pad?
Like,
how do you not just like you were saying,
you know,
about getting out of the
sensory deprivation tank,
like,
you know,
leap to your feet and
scramble at the door.
Like,
how do you resist the impulse to do that?
And he said,
well,
you know,
we're,
we're trained,
you know,
were,
were recruited and trained for a specific,
uh,
ability,
you know,
and situational awareness
as we described it.
And,
uh,
he said that one of the examples of it
is what he called winding the clock.
And I was like,
what's wanting o'clock?
He had been a test pilot out
of Edwards over here and uh,
was one day assigned
to shoot down a drone,
uh,
to test a new air to air missile.
And so he comes out of this steep turn,
fires the rocket,
and it doesn't leave his wing if the,
the,
you know,
he hears it go,
but it doesn't actually leave the jet.
She looks over and it's armed,
right?
And he's done.
He's ready to blow up,
ready to blow up.
It's getting back.
Fuck.
And you're done.
Right,
right.
And so the moment right there,
the reaction you're having
even to hear the story,
right,
it's the same reaction I
had on the same reaction.
So many people would have like
eject immediately are like panic,
you know,
whatever.
It's just bad news.
And he said that in that moment
they're trained to wind the clock.
They literally would reach up to a,
a cheap clock that they had duct taped
to the dash of this fighter and wind it
to keep it going.
And you're trained to do that to
in order to have a little downtime,
to think through what
you're going to do next.
And in the amount of time it takes
him to reach up and crank that dial,
he is,
uh,
hearing,
you know,
thinking through,
okay,
well it's kind of a nice day.
Would I go out?
Shall I go out across Los Angeles
and over the ocean and ditch there?
It's like,
well,
no,
first of all,
you know,
that's,
that's a lot of people and I can't go
over with an armed missile over a lot of
people and then I don't want to be,
the guy lost the $40 million airplane.
So he then thinks it through this morning.
Mornings.
Like the weather's pretty good today.
I think I can probably make it.
And by God he lands it totally like go
does the corkscrew and comes in and lands
of playing with live arm at a time.
Oh,
it makes it right.
And that's what they,
what are they telling him
at the base when he's like,
hey guys,
I'm flying in hot.
I wonder,
I bet there's a procedure,
right?
Air Force people would probably
have a procedure for that car.
And they stepped,
fuck you.
Who Does it?
They get every general mile radius,
you know.
But I said to him,
like,
I don't understand how you're able to,
I'll do that.
And he's like,
yeah,
we're just trained to,
you know,
we have that ability,
you know?
And,
and that's true when you look across all,
uh,
you know,
there's another astronaut story.
This guy,
Franklin Chang Diaz was a
Costa Rican national who,
who,
uh,
was an astronaut,
a on the shuttle.
And he narrowly avoided being killed in
both the Columbia and the challenge or
disasters.
He was training for both.
And through a fluke of scheduling did
not go on either and saw all of his
friends and colleagues killed
in these two disasters.
I mean,
unbelievable tragedy for this guy twice.
And he still hold shares the
record for the most times in space,
uh,
and,
you know,
was,
uh,
has done more,
I think more space walks in.
Anybody else or something like that.
It's just absolutely
superlative human being.
And he had this story of a
floating out there with this,
you know,
$60 million piece of equipment that
he's got to move from this place to this
place or whatever.
And as he's doing it,
he looks down in the clouds of part of
beneath them and there's Costa Rica and
he realizes I'm the,
I'm the only person in my,
of my nation who will ever have this view.
Um,
you know,
in all likelihood.
And he's got his camera attached
to his belt and he was the city.
He was thinking to himself,
I can just reach down and grab
the camera and take the photo,
uh,
of,
you know,
that all Costa Ricans will
have on their wall basically.
I'm sure you didn't have that thought,
but to,
you know,
to me that's where it is.
And he doesn't do it because he would
have had to let go of this piece of
equipment and go for the camera,
you know,
and he's got a duty to perform.
He's like,
they put me,
they brought me here to do this job for
me to do this job and he scooted over.
But again,
that's a piece of programming
that he's resisting.
You know,
like by his training and his steadfastness
of whatever it is in his brain.
Like,
man,
that guy doesn't just do
what I would have done.
We just throw the piece of
equipment out into space and take,
you know?
Yeah.
Training is a fascinating thing,
right?
The idea of developing your skills and
your mindset to the point where you can
do extremely dangerous things and
keep your composure and that that's a,
that's it's,
it's,
it's very attractive to us.
So we'll wear a fascinated by heroes.
That's why we need them.
Yeah.
We need them.
They have to be able to do that even
when it doesn't mean anything like this.
I think that's part of the reason why I
think like x games and stuff along those
lines.
If it's part of the evolutionary
process to compete against each other,
to see who can do the more
and more fucked up things.
Yeah,
sure.
And that there's something that's
gets developed along the line.
Totally.
It's testing the limits of the human body.
I think everybody's just
really wants be able to fly
or do whatever.
You know,
there's,
there's this extreme,
and it's cliche to say about it,
right?
An extreme or you're trying
to find the extremity of your,
of the law of life.
You're trying to find how
close to death can I get
and in finding the limits
of human performance.
And I think it's a part of the grand
equation of the human race period.
It's like,
it is a part of the,
of,
of the,
the numbers right now.
We know that people can
run a four minute mile.
Now we know that people can do that.
You know,
it's all of these things as sort of
aid and the progress of the race.
Yeah,
that's right.
Some,
yeah.
Well you need,
you know,
you need the person to go first.
You need the person to come pull
people out of burning buildings.
There's a,
there's Europe say,
right?
There's a,
there's a,
you know,
a,
a purpose to having that
kind of Alpha person
the,
as we become a more and more
advanced society that need sort of,
maybe it's going away.
That's,
I think it is.
I mean,
that's why a guy like you can,
you know,
you're obviously a
successful intelligent guy,
but you're like joking around about,
oh,
I can't handle fear.
Right.
You know,
it's cause you don't have to.
Yeah,
I know.
Well,
and I never will.
That's exactly right.
Well,
I mean that's not true.
That's not true.
I might write and,
and I have in my personal life experience,
you know,
extreme situations.
I'm sure everybody has,
everybody has tragedies in their lives.
You know,
the stuff that's gone on.
But you know,
the,
the concern,
the consistent ability to,
to resist fear and do you know,
the needful in the face of terrible odds.
That is a crazy thing.
You know.
At the same time though,
we're also,
you know,
we just did a story recently about how,
um,
there's a whole Darpa a challenge around
creating rescue robots that would,
that would replace firefighters,
would replace people.
Not In all circumstances,
but in circumstances where like Fukushima,
where there's radiation,
you can't send people right
into the middle of it,
but you want to be able to send in a
robot that can cut its way through a door,
look around,
maybe bring somebody back.
And so the challenges that the Darpa
are putting out there include like
literally being able to cut
through door with a saws all,
uh,
you know,
drive a car.
The thing has to be able to get
into a car and drive away with it.
It's literally like the,
the rules have been written
by an eight year old.
I mean,
it's incredible the challenge that they're
putting out in front of these people
and people are doing it.
The Dharma robots are some
of the creepiest things
that have ever been created
by humans.
Dogs,
uh,
Cheetahs.
Totally.
The,
the one that looks like a,
looks like a pack mule or disturbing
to look at the latest model can throw
things.
And now I forget like bricks,
I think it is.
I can throw bricks.
Oh,
a Jack's.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
There's a whole,
also,
there's a whole field of study
around trying to make robots.
We were,
we were messing with this on our cover
when we were putting together the cover a
couple of issues ago.
We put one of these robots on
the cover from Virginia Tech.
It's a real robot.
What we put in there,
I was like actually what it,
you know,
could somebody look like it's
definitely what it's headed for.
And uh,
they've built the legs
and the whole thing,
it's just unbelievable.
But,
um,
when we first put the cover together,
it was reaching for you,
trying to save you through a broken
window basically in this sort of ruined
environment.
Um,
which is,
uh,
the,
the environment that the thing
is going to have to compete in.
But it looked like it was
reaching for you to kill you.
Like it a scary cover.
The robot looked frightening and the,
we decided in the end like,
wait,
we've got to make this thing not look
like it caused all this damage because we
as people are terrified of,
uh,
robots.
They just look scary.
And if you make them all
black and militaristic,
you know,
like,
you know the graphite look is scary
and so you've got to paint them like
ambulances is what these
guys are all learning.
Look at this robot throwing a cinder
block just whips out now the lock itself.
Yeah.
Yeah,
but look how he uses his legs too.
I mean it does look like the shot talk
kicks in and that's a cinderblock man.
I mean,
could a human even do that?
And what if that's a grenade
instead of a cinder block?
Yeah,
you showed this to little kids and it
just scares the hell out of our lives.
Yeah.
Creepy spider looking thing like our
natural instincts or be terrified of that
Sheila that has antlers.
It's got defect that's growing antlers.
It's a real transplant.
There's another,
a robot that they've found they've
invented that drives up to a wall and they
can spring up through the air and
you can clear like these big walls.
Totally.
We give out an award this year.
Yeah,
it's an amazing thing.
I can jump like 30 you know,
30 or 40 feet.
It can clear a single story building.
The idea being that it can,
uh,
you know,
get in wherever you need it to.
Right.
You're up on a ridge,
you send it down and it can leap,
you know,
off a cliff.
That's the other thing is you can roll
it off a cliff and I'll survive the fall.
It's incredibly Harvey.
It's crazy.
Does that translate?
That has grown at birth defect that
started growing antlers and jam bands.
Scared of spiders.
We just found out as,
he can't even look at this photo
thing.
Those little antlers.
Well that's like when a
person is born with a tail.
You're like,
what?
What is going on in the genome
where that's representing itself.
That's strange.
Strange little animal.
Well,
spiders in general or creepy as fuck.
Yeah,
no,
I,
I have trouble with the snakes.
I have the like the natural
evolutionary response to snakes.
They've just,
that's literally spineless quality
video phobia of spiders thing.
It's called a video phobia.
Yeah.
It's very common though.
They just move in away that I'm not,
it doesn't like to follow up.
Well,
people that,
um,
you know,
I think the proponents of epigenetics
with would say that it's probably
somewhere in your evolutionary past or
somewhere in your genetic past rather
than someone got fucked up by a snake
and either some one of your ancestors saw
or one of your ancestors was wounded.
And we did a story about,
um,
we have a section of the magazine
where we basically ask incredibly dumb
questions of incredibly smart people.
And,
uh,
and it's great cause they,
they play along in this wonderful way.
So one of them was,
what's the world's grossest sound?
And literally there was a guy who had,
you know,
done a study to determine it.
And he had determined that the sound
was the sound of vomiting that,
uh,
that,
and they simulated by pouring a bucket
of baked beans into another bucket while
somebody else was making yakking noises,
they,
and they played all these different
noises for people and was the one that was
grossest.
And the reason they think the evolutionary
purpose of that in theory is that
when you as a group,
you know,
we're eating diseased,
uh,
elk or whatever around a fire,
you know,
20,000 years ago,
um,
and someone started to get sick,
everyone would know it and would
also throw up so that no one ate,
you know,
and no one in the tribe ate the diseased.
That's totally makes sense.
He's wondered why like,
well,
Dab also,
by the way,
can be bypassed.
And I can tell you that
from personal experience,
because when I was a kid in high school,
if like someone threw up in the hallway,
which always happen in school,
I would start throwing up and a lot
of other people start throwing up to,
you know,
no,
it's a,
it's just built in like that scene
in stand by me hiding contents,
these throws throat.
Well that doesn't work on me anymore
because of all my years of fear factor.
I've seen so many people throw up.
I've seen.
Really?
Yeah.
That's really interesting.
I don't know how many
people I've seen throw up.
I saw I,
we did 148 episodes and every episode,
somebody through a
totally are a test case.
That's really interesting.
So nothing makes me throw up anymore.
I could be right next to someone throwing
up on the ground and it doesn't bother
me.
In fact,
my wife threw up in her car once and
she was all upset because she couldn't
clean it because she would
throw up again and I was like,
I'll clean it.
Like it didn't bother me at all.
It's smell puke in her car in
August and it just got away from,
that totally goes away.
I can be at a bar and
someone threw up in a urinal,
a piano.
It doesn't freak me out.
Wow.
Gross is sound.
It's two guys fucking anyway.
I don't think he knows.
That sounds like busted.
I got to son.
Well,
unless you were gay then that'd
be the most awesome sound ever.
Well that was like the,
the idea of like,
do gay guys get accustomed
to the smell of poop of,
you know,
of it.
Was that,
is that like an okay smell to them
because they're in the anal sex?
I don't know.
I mean the,
the what,
what causes certain connections,
what causes you to be repulsed by certain
things is always very fascinating.
Yeah,
sure,
sure.
Yeah.
But that thing of the throw
up sounds totally makes sense.
It's just makes it,
it makes perfect sense.
Yeah,
that's right.
And you know,
anything liquid wishing death is,
I think awesome.
Actually.
The words that smell,
the smell of it and that is all sorts,
that's also a useful instinct.
Yeah.
You smell it.
You want to go the other way.
That's a good idea.
Yeah.
When I was a kid,
someone died in our apartment
building and they didn't find the,
it was an old lady and they didn't
find her body for a while and it was,
the entire floor had this horrible,
horrible odor to it
where you would walk in,
you know?
And then eventually they found out that
this lady had died and they went and
cleaned it up.
But the smell lasted forever.
Sure,
sure.
Took the longest time to clean that out.
It's not like any other dead smell.
Yeah,
no,
I mean it's,
it really is that thing of like,
it's also too,
we were just talking about
many hours ago about,
uh,
trying to have as few openings
as possible in the bundle.
And that's the other reason
you would want as few as,
and if there was some,
some
stuff you got to keep in there,
you don't want it out in the world.
And I think the fear that smells
probably to discourage predation.
Yeah.
And,
and,
uh,
when we were really starving to death
and people will find a dead person,
right.
And we'll fucking mountain
might as well just eat them.
That is part of it.
Or I would,
I would,
I'm sure one could make
that argument and you know,
the feeling of,
of there being a,
you know,
a purpose to,
uh,
staying away from,
you know,
that like dysentery results from,
if you don't have adequate waste
systems and people are writing,
if it infects the drinking water,
like there's so many
reasons to stay away from,
from,
uh,
yeah.
The,
the dirtiest parts of people.
That's right.
Yeah.
The evolutionary desire
to escape stinky people.
Right,
right.
So there's a whole thesis there.
I'm sure somebody,
why is bad breath so horrible then?
I mean,
that can't really affect you for real.
I guess it can.
Maybe if the person sick though,
right.
Sometimes it can be a symptom of disease.
That's interesting.
Yeah.
Maybe that's why.
That's right.
This guy's not well.
I gotta get Outta here.
That's funny.
Well,
this is a massive,
massive,
fascinating,
this has been fascinating.
You guys are good company.
This is really a lovely place.
Tom,
you'd like to do this again.
We do it.
You have your way just
to say this right now,
but you guys are like on
it and this is a much,
uh,
like I was on my toes this whole time.
Like,
you know,
no dummy Joe Rogan not dummy.
Thank you.
I'm glad you had a good time.
Uh,
if you want to take mushrooms in,
hanging out with Brian and a dolphin tale
experiments going on like that,
because I,
if I had a dolphin,
I would be doing weird things.
There's two,
two researchers who could compare
notes and come up with the,
you know,
something like that.
You should read Lilly Bell,
John Lilly stuff.
He was a pioneer and
interspecies communication.
He actually like,
you know,
peer reviewed stuff on
Dolphin intelligence because
of psychedelics and and
getting a dolphin tanks or
getting an isolation tank.
You need to take an isolation tank trip
to man did all this crazy poopooing of
it without any person.
That's,
I'm just saying that,
that I'm sure it doesn't work on some
people because I've had people tell me I
didn't work on it.
That word and it doesn't work
is like saying,
you know,
I have a computer and I don't
know how to get on the Internet.
Well I think like,
you know,
don't know how to use minds are just too
active to slow down to the point where
that would be helpful for them.
Like they're,
you know,
almost add p I agree.
I agree with what you
said except the word too.
I don't,
I don't believe that,
that their minds are too active.
I believe their minds are active.
I believe they don't
know how to manage that,
but that can be taught.
The amount of the emails
that I get every week,
the amount of Twitter messages and
Facebook messages by people that have
positive experiences in isolation tanks
and how much it helps them and changes
them.
Fighters,
a lot of fighters started
using them to meditate and to,
to,
to practice relaxing.
Plus,
it's an awesome source of magnesium.
You just need to do it.
Me,
dude.
I mean it's so crazy.
You haven't,
yeah,
no,
it's not like you're busy all day.
What does that destroy hat?
What does that destroy?
What does that on the hat did on a rocket?
I think it's the red skull
or a seat on a rocket.
That's fucking bad ass.
Where'd you get that?
San Diego harmful.
San Diego.
Awesome.
Isn't it?
I would almost moved there if
it wasn't for the military.
Uh,
like presence,
presence in like the
people are all ex military,
so everybody acts like crazy.
Like the bouncers of every bar.
So much more strict and intense.
Like this woman came up to me and I
was smoking a cigarette and she goes,
are you smoking pot?
And I'm like,
no,
this is a cigarette.
She goes,
let me see that.
Okay.
And just walked away and I'm like,
fuck no.
I had no idea what she,
yeah,
she was.
You could tell she was
military chick though.
And then it was just like,
that was everywhere I went.
It felt like that.
And then,
and then,
I don't know,
it just,
it just felt
sit,
sat town.
That's without a doubt of side
effect of a military area.
If I could live near mission bay,
I tell you that he's the most
beautiful area and in the seat,
what does that sea lions,
there's retarded animals of the night
that just go like listening to that is
some of the funniest shit ever
out of nowhere.
That one would just quote.
Oh
by the way,
that's also what attracts sharks.
Oh really?
Sharks love to eat the
fuck out of those things.
I feel bad for those guys.
They're just like a big fat retards
that live in these popsicles.
Right.
So delicious.
To tie what they're there for.
I mean,
what else are they doing?
They're providing food to sharks
looking up in the sky like,
yeah,
you ever saw these for it for Walrus
that polar bears run up to and they can't
get away.
They're there on the ground.
Why can't they get away?
Because nature doesn't
want you to get away.
Domain meet Sicko feed this big guy.
Well listen man,
thank you very much.
Really appreciate this.
I'm so glad we did this
and let's do it again.
That sounds great.
And uh,
you could follow Jacob on Twitter.
What is your Twitter handle?
You got to punch out an underscore.
I was showing I was late.
I'm sorry.
So anyway,
it's underscored Jacob Ward.
I'm score but Jacob Ward,
just search firm that search warrant
my name and you'll just find me.
Jacob Ward.
It's underscore Jacob Ward underscore.
Sorry.
You need to change that.
I don't say it out loud ever.
I would say this is the only time
I've ever had to say it out loud.
It's just like easy to find.
Go Jacob Ward it.
Just look for my name on Google.
You'll find you have a little a check
next to your name so everybody knows the
real you or you verified.
No you're not.
Oh I didn't even know about that.
I haven't even done that.
I'm sorry.
Yeah.
Once you get,
you got to get into that
world of fake Jacob Wards got,
I've got to get verified cause a bunch
of people are going to have fake Jacob
Ward accounts and post a
bunch of nonscientific shit
and attributed to you that
could happen.
Sucks Joe is that I don't have it and I
have a bunch of fakes that are actually
acting like me and stuff like that and
I just found out there's this guy that's
on Twitter that has like 2000 Twitter
followers and his name is like spilled bag
of ice and and he's terrified.
He's verifying a bag of ice.
Let me show you.
I know that account because you do,
you know it's built bag of ice came from,
came from a UFC fight where a bag of ice
build in the octagon and I gave a whole
commentary for like three minutes
on these guys up the ice because it
was so ridiculous.
And I was like,
get back in there.
And it was funny.
And so this guy became spilled bag of
ice and he's verified and he's verified.
That's the Internet telling
you to go fuck yourself.
I'm done listen and wipie yet.
But he's been,
he's got a Wikipedia page
two I'm escaping live at.
Dolphins can tell you how to get verified.
I'm sure there's,
there's a convenient way to do it.
You just hit it to find
that it's supposed to be,
if people,
if there's enough people that
are acting like you and there,
there's so many people,
like even like,
I don't want even to say who I know is
acting like me online and people are
actually asking him questions like,
Hey Robin,
what's going on?
Talking about that crazy dude.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Okay.
Yeah,
I wouldn't be surprised.
but you know,
what do you have the most right?
Huh?
How many?
There's at least two people maybe
that are thinking this is him.
Maybe that's what this is.
I think you've made it and you've
got people pretending to be you.
Check mark.
Yeah.
He just wants,
he wants a Wikipedia page
and the blue check mark.
The kids are legitimate and he's hurting.
It's hurting on the inside.
Underscored Jacob Award,
underscore or do a Twitter search for
Jacob Ward on Popular Science magazine.
Editor and chief saw.
Very much man.
Really,
really awesome time,
Scott.
Thank you everybody for
tuning into the podcast.
We apologize again one more time
for that drunk podcast of last week.
But that's what happens folks.
That's what happens when
you go off the rails.
Submit that to the podcast.
The words,
uh,
thank you to [inaudible]
for sponsoring our podcasts.
Go to rogan.ting.com
and save 25 bucks off a,
it's a service credit or device discount.
Um,
and uh,
it's uh,
an awesome cell phone company
that supports our podcast.
Thanks also to,
uh,
Squarespace.
If you go to squarespace.com forward
slash Joe and enter in the Code Joe Three
you can save yourself 10% off of
any new website that you develop on
Squarespace,
including the a,
the ability to create
your own online store,
which is very fast and very easy.
Squarespace,
everything you need to create
an exceptional website.
And remember squarespace.com forward slash
Joe entered the code word Joe and the
number three together to
save yourself 10% that's the,
this is the month of March.
If you're listening to this,
if it's April,
I'm sure we'll be Squarespace for,
but right now,
Squarespace three you mean Joe?
Joe Three.
Yeah.
Fuck.
Am I even talking about a,
also on [inaudible] dot com go to Oh and
and it and use the code name Rogan to
save 10% off any of the supplements.
We will see you tomorrow
with our buddy Jay Dee was a,
a longtime member of uh,
the website and then we'll be here on
Wednesday with Ben Hoffman from comedy
central's new show.
What is this show called?
The Ben Hoffman show
or something like that.
But very cool guy and a very funny guy,
and we'll see him on Wednesday.
All right,
my friends this weekend,
Nashville at Xannies,
me powerful,
Tom Segura.
Um,
Friday and Saturday night
tickets are going fast.
There's not much left,
so get in there son,
and we'll see you tomorrow.
We love the shit out of you.
Bye.