You dirty bitch and we're back.
This episode of the Joe Rogan podcast is
brought to you by ting.
Ting is a mobile phone companies that
we've talked about on this podcast many
times,
one of my favorite sponsors because you
would think like if you look for
something cool,
you'd say,
well,
you know,
maybe like a a company that sells
paintings is cool or a company that
makes sculptures is cool,
but you don't think of like cell phone
companies as being cool like what are
they?
They're just cell phone companies.
But when a cell phone company goes out
of their way to give you a service that
first of all it's is like it's Kinda,
it's,
it's a better deal.
It's,
it feels more ethical.
Like from a business standpoint.
They allow you to cancel your contract
at any time they credit you on unused
service,
which I've never heard of before.
If you use less than you thought you
would,
ting actually drops you down and they
credit you the difference on your next
bill.
They drop you down to the next level.
Whatever you actually did use.
I've gotten so many twitter messages
from people that tell me that they're
saving money every month since I
switched over.
Like one dude was.
He was spending like 90 something
dollars on another cell phone company
and he said he brought it down to 18.
Now that that's fucking insane.
I don't know.
You know what his use was like,
but if he's telling the truth,
if he's not just some crazy troll making
shit up,
I kind of verified or deny.
I bet he was like on an iphone,
barely using it on a verizon plan and
they switched down to like a galaxy s
three.
You know what I mean?
It is.
Iphone iphones cause a lot of money.
Just you look at the mega yet.
Yeah.
We looked at it last week,
but did you.
Did you take a look at it?
Fucked with it or investigated now?
Apparently they're going to do two of
them.
Whatever.
The fucking what they have.
The Samsung Galaxy note too is amazing.
If you want like a giant phone,
you really don't need anything more
giant than that.
I don't think.
I mean,
I never thought you would need one this
giant,
but they haven't attained.
Um,
they also allow you to combine your
service so you and your wife or you and
your friend,
whoever you can,
you can share a bill and split time,
go to [inaudible] Dot [inaudible] Dot
Com and save 25 bucks off either service
or one of their phones.
Uh,
we're also brought to you by hover.
Hover is uh,
the internet domain name company.
This is actually owned by the same
people that own Tang and they have the
same sort of attitude about it and it's
an excellent service.
The service that I personally have used,
if you,
um,
if you use it,
you can get things that most domain name
companies would charge you for the give
it to you for free.
Like who is domain name privacy where
you know,
if you want to,
you want to like register Dick Party in
my mouth.
Dot Com.
Hey,
take in my mouth.
Do you think there's one of that?
Let's go look for that Dick Party in my
mouth.
Party tea party.
In my mind I just registered hot.
Do things when I had a bunch of things,
I shot a bunch of videos with hot girls
do and things like soccer.
I'll step on me just doing random stuff.
Hot Girls Step on me and they just saw
these girls in high heels on me.
It was they wanted to raise money for
this,
a web series,
this girl pants and I was like,
just have you guys should be in bikinis
doing stupid things like hot girls,
hot girls,
scold the shit out of me.
They just doing all kinds of random
stuff.
It's going to be good.
What's the promotional code?
Go to hover.com
forward slash rogen and you can get 10
percent off your domain name
registrations.
They're a cool company.
They support the podcast.
We support them,
so please go get yourself some sun were
also brought to you by [inaudible] dot
com.
That's o n n I t powerful.
Steve Rinella is here.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we just figured we'd get the ads out of
the way before you got here.
Not to bore you.
Sunglasses,
you,
you sexy savage,
you please have a seat set.
Big hands an animal and we're going to
be such a manly man.
Watch some hike this weekend.
I watched the whole episode.
They shot nothing.
They hiked in Montana for days.
Cold.
Yeah.
Dead Dodi was sleeping outside.
Terrifying episode.
Where there now that they were there in
November before Thanksgiving and slept
outside.
No tent.
You're crazy.
Let me get through this.
Add real quick.
If you go to [inaudible] dot com,
there's a whole bunch of new shit that's
been added to a on it,
especially in the strength and
conditioning department.
We started this new company called
primal bells.
The first one is this chimpanzee that
looks like he's biting your Dick off.
And uh,
that's the face.
That's why I like to think of when I'm
working out.
That's what I'm trying to avoid.
So these,
uh,
we've got more common.
We got this bad ass gorilla common and
there's some other.
I don't want to tell you all of them,
but a lot of really cool ones coming up
and they're essentially an art.
We're hiring people to sculpt these
things,
these ideas that we have.
And we were getting people that work in
the special effects companies,
the ones that chimpanzee ones are a
little obsessed.
It's amazing by the way,
for you people in French,
it's pronounced cheekbones z.
She ballsy.
He gets his bed.
He used to get in there,
son getting their cakes,
brother.
All right,
there's something had to die to make
butter or things go to o n n it.
And uh,
if you use a code name broken,
you will save 10 percent off any of the
supplements,
including Alpha brain,
shroom,
tech,
all the,
the groove of Shit that we talk about on
the podcast all the time.
Um,
there is always new,
always new Shit and interesting shit
that we sell from on it.
You know,
anything.
Every time we find out anything cool on
the web,
like Blendtec blenders or when we found
out about bulletproof coffee and a lot
of coffee has,
according to Dave Asprey,
lot of coffee that you're getting has
fungus on it,
mycotoxins.
And you know,
you,
you don't get the same experience from
drinking that as you do from a drinking
coffee.
That's fungus free confidence,
fungus free.
He believes is way less wearing on your
system.
He thinks a lot of the crash that people
associate with drinking coffee is
actually your body reacting to the
mycotoxins and regular good clean
coffee.
Like what he sells is called bulletproof
upgraded coffee is a mycotoxin free and
it should be drinking right now.
St Michael or Mike.
Mike,
go mycotoxins there.
They're tiny little fungi that grow all
over coffee apparently.
Haven't seen that show.
Dangerous grinds.
No.
Or deadliest.
Whatever the fuck it was called.
It was a guy would go all dangerous
grounds.
A guy would go all over the country to
really exotic places where they would
make coffee,
where they grow coffee.
It was a lot of coffee's grown.
Yeah.
Wanda and um,
and some of the best is in Hawaiian.
Yeah.
Um,
but these,
it requires like a specific climate and
this guy would go there and he said one
of the real issues is an alum of this
stuff gets toxic.
It gets mold grows on it,
and if you drink that,
you're drinking like mold soup,
you know,
that's,
that's really interesting.
Totally makes sense.
And something nobody ever thought about
before,
but Dave asked,
we thought about it and he,
we were like,
let's sell Dave asprey shit.
Let's sell bulletproof coffee.
How does he keep it from being a mold?
They get it from a single source.
One.
One company takes care of it.
From the moment the plant is grown,
they,
it's all about putting it in the correct
environment and making sure that it
doesn't have access or exposure to ntds
funguses.
So,
uh,
so we,
we saw that shit on it.
Good on.
Oh.
And it use a codename Rogan.
And Go fuck yourself.
All right.
Steven was here.
Brian counts here.
Let's get freaky.
It just got to music.
Brian Cho who Rhogam.
He is the best to do Brian already
forgot.
Oh,
I know what he's doing.
He's gonna.
Put the silly one.
I forgot to do it.
Do you have the silly one?
That's all right.
We just played that one a couple of days
ago.
Mr Rinella.
What's up,
brother?
How are you,
man?
Good to see you again.
Where's my bear?
Me.
You know,
we evolved,
gone through a,
a very,
uh,
unique and spectacular experience
together.
You do it on a regular basis,
but all of us like doing that together.
I'll never forget that.
I'll never forget that trip for the rest
of my life.
We had a great fucking time.
I watched the episodes twice and I love
them and I thought it was shot really
well.
I thought the music was amazing.
I thought it was amazing.
It turns,
it turns you into blood brothers out in
the field.
No doubt.
Yeah,
it's a totally.
Yeah.
And to see how people respond to,
to like waking up in the fucking
freezing cold and nobody bitched out.
Everybody kept it together.
That's important.
You can take some fucking set through
green type characters with a on the
road.
Sorry,
Seth Green.
I don't know why I picked on you.
How about me?
How about Joe Rogan,
tub chair white.
That doesn't make sense because I did
it,
but I mean there's a lot of people out
there.
Sorry Seth,
I have no reason to take shots at you.
Do you know?
Did I tell you that what they
anthropologists,
they did that study about how men who
show up in a bar all done up and jewelry
and and why they get beaten up
traditionally or why,
why there was this so much like actual
violent pressure for men to actually
conform to a haircut and to a look like
they.
The joke is men,
they have two criteria for how they
dressed.
They don't want to look like a pussy and
they want to be comfortable and and they
mainly don't want to bring attention to
themselves.
Like you don't see a guy unless you're
wearing that ned retardy shirt,
but you know those guys usually they
jacked and ready.
But for the most part men will wear
things that are like blues and grays and
you know,
simple stuff.
Because this part at the Santa Claus was
talking about the idea that if you.
It goes back to how men used to hunt in
groups and if a man,
if you guys were all set and we're going
to go hunting and all of a sudden I show
up and a bunch of sparkly shit and
bangles.
They're making a bunch of noise.
You guys come in and you're gonna spoke
to fucking deer.
They can see it a mile away and you're
making like hanging,
hanging.
But I like these and I don't know,
getting shut down,
son.
I want to hear your point of view on it
because look at how.
I mean,
look at the way that a lot of,
uh,
of,
of indigenous hunters today still will
adorn themselves.
Yes.
But they don't,
they for not,
not when they rented though,
right?
Isn't that for,
for positioning,
dancing stuff,
but not all.
Like you might go and you might go to or
go into battle with like face paint or
elaborate jewelry or there's,
there's so many accounts of like
command.
She who would wear wedding veils and
stuff that they gathered during raids
and just crazy.
I would always wear a wedding baile.
I think that's,
I don't want the deer to see what my
expression change your,
your thing that I,
that I,
that I contested it and I don't,
I don't mean.
I don't mean to aggregate on the final
it,
but it reminds me of what it reminds me
of something similar that's equally
interesting and just like I was reading
this book on human evolution,
he was arguing how could it ever be be
beneficial to be a daredevil,
right?
They'd be like,
what is the selective advantage to being
a daredevil?
And this guy argues that it's,
you're saying to a man is saying to
females,
you're like,
I am so ridiculously fit.
You know that I can do something so
stupid.
Instill,
thrive,
instill,
still breed.
You know,
like that's how I did it.
I
think we ended with this shit like
wingsuits fighting bulls.
Men would fight bulls.
Fighting Bulls is kind of a scam because
there's a lot of other dudes involved.
Like it's not just a matador and the
bull.
There's other dudes stabbing the bull.
They put poison darts into the bowl to
creepy shit.
It's crazy.
Yeah.
There's another dude that stabbed the
bull.
Yeah,
the peccadilloes.
but when you're in a fucking wingsuit,
you're in a wingsuit.
Okay.
Those crazy assholes that jump off those
mountains and they're going 100 miles an
hour and those suits.
Have you seen him fly through cities
like through the middle of buildings?
No,
dude.
There's a guy jumps out of
a plane in fucking Brazil.
Okay.
Jumps out of a plane and does this wing
suit shit and he goes flying over the
city through buildings.
There's a gap in between these two
buildings and he shoots through these
two buildings before he pulls his
parachute and land flapping.
Gliding.
It is.
It hurts your head when you're watching
it.
What is it going to fucking die?
Yeah.
I mean,
how much can you really totally control
it?
I don't know.
I mean,
I don't know how much you can really
steer it.
Yes.
I guess this guy he and see.
Okay,
this.
Are you kidding?
That's.
No,
it's him and the wing suit.
This is the camera.
Look at that.
Oh my God.
Oh Jesus Christ.
Look at this.
Are you kidding?
By the way?
It was misty.
Okay.
Stories up any gap that is only 26 feet
wide.
Oh,
that guy's a bad ass.
So who's behind this viral bolt through
the Air Norwegian Yogi summer and
Freshmen Ludovic worth stuntman
sponsored by red.
Well,
it was more endorsed,
sponsored by red bull gangster.
You do an urban spots of the highest.
It's death defying.
Not to mention illegal jump.
The team took it this at 5:45
AM there 20 minutes before the first
commercial flight would appear on real.
Supervise it.
Oh my God.
Imagine you gotta be
calculate when the first flight takes
off in the air by a fucking plane going
500 miles an hour.
Yeah.
Do you think you can time the plane,
how fast the planes coming at you as
you're flying down towards the 600 miles
an hour you.
You ain't gotten away from that thing.
That's a rocket ship.
And so if that guy lands and in a woman
is like,
I am so impressed by that,
I'd like to go out with you for drinks
tonight.
It would demonstrate that there's a
selective advantage there.
Yeah,
there's a selective advantage and being
a daredevil.
Yeah,
there's definitely.
That totally makes sense evolutionarily,
and it also makes sense that we have a
disdain for people that are like wearing
jewelry and dress and flashy and
tracking a lot of attention to the to
ourselves because classically that that
person who like aims to stand out so
strongly ruins everything.
They get too loud,
they turn things into fights,
you know,
that the person is like really loud and
flamboyant and they usually.
It's just a natural instinct.
It's the feeling you get is like,
oh,
look at this fucking guy.
Like,
what?
What is this guy going to bring to the
party?
Like what?
He's not a team player.
He's not,
he's,
he's some crazy asshole with jewelry on.
Right?
What's he doing like criss angel?
Why is he wearing?
If I get annoyed at Chris Angel,
because he's too,
he's too into his body and he's doing it
was ripped jeans and I'm always like,
I don't know.
I'm sure I'd like them,
but when I see them I'm like,
punch that guy in the face,
man.
The fact that he's really muscular,
it's kind of a good looking guy,
so I'm a little jealous of them.
At the same time,
my and I don't like that guy.
Maybe I'm a little attractive.
That's probably one of the best ways to
get girls ever to be a beautiful
magician.
Oh,
he's awesome.
Beautiful Council magician with a great
boss.
Great.
Must be ridiculous.
Got To love the guy.
Yeah.
It's like there's an evolutionary
advantage in that way.
Are you kidding?
The muscular trigger match to be able to
trick that many people into thinking
that your mysterious,
he's awesome.
I mean,
what are you doing?
every magician,
it's Goddamn trickster,
but that's all they're doing.
They're just tricking you.
I'm friends.
Pretty good.
Very good friends with David Blaine.
Women.
Have Him love him.
I'm good friends with Penn Jillette and
women.
Love him about that.
That's even more impressive.
That's impressive because Dave's a good
looking guy.
He's got a mystery and you know,
tall and dark and stuff.
Pendula.
Lots of bad mother ever.
Tell you about Penn.
Like penn and teller is awesome.
David Lane,
who tried to fight Mike Tyson,
what's his story?
Tried to fight my david on the on the
street and he's.
He's just checked.
I mean,
he felt like me,
but he was just so muscular.
I was like,
david,
what are you doing?
He goes,
I was training for eight months to fight
Mike Tyson,
and when he went to a trainer,
it might've been teddy atlas,
something.
He goes,
I want to find my tights.
And I think,
I think it was teddy.
I'm sorry david.
If someone like that.
And he goes,
the trainer goes,
well,
what's the trick?
And david said,
nothing.
I just want to last three rounds and the
trend goes not in this lifetime.
And he goes,
no,
we've got to think of.
I train hard.
He goes,
you're not gonna.
I'm not training you to fight Mike
Tyson.
You won't last five seconds.
You never fought in your life.
You're a magician.
If there's not a trick,
it's not going to haPpen.
And Mike Tyson,
you know,
things.
David's magic apparently.
So.
So that didn't happen.
So he goes to another trainer and the
trainer goes,
what's the trick?
And a,
because there's no trick,
I just want to do it.
He goes,
I'll take your money,
but it ain't gonna happen.
I'm gonna tell you up front.
He goes,
no,
I want to do it.
So david pays him a crazy amount of
money and they start any trains for six
months.
And finally they put him in the ring
with his cruiser weight.
Just a guy who's their cruiser,
right?
Tall,
thin guys,
you know who can,
who can box.
And david said that david said that the
guy jabbed him once,
bam.
AnD they went,
oh my god,
oh,
he thought I was going to die.
And the guy goes,
yeah,
all right.
And he goes,
I don't.
And then he hit him again.
And david was Like,
that's it.
I can't.
He took two jobs because I can't fight.
This is crazy.
He'd never,
he had no idea how hard somebody could
hit.
And the guy goes,
we've been telling you that the whole
time.
That's a jab from a cruiserweight who's
not even a top pro if you're talking
about one of the hardest hitters in the
game of all time.
They was like,
oh,
well I guess I could never do that.
When was he trying to do?
This is a long tiMe ago.
I like when mike Tyson was boxing still
a.
It was right when he retired,
I believe.
Right when they with Mike Tyson do that.
He's ridiculous.
Why would he think that Mike Tyson was
going to do the.
I don't know.
I'll talk to dave and I'll come back
with,
but it's kind of insulting for him to
even think that Mike Tyson one,
the greatest fighters of all time would
be willing to do that.
Well,
david's david's kind of guy who just
loves endurance.
He loves thinking about the,
the hardest thing to do,
like he wanted to cross.
I don't know if I can say it on air
because he made me a fighter.
Only has.
I mean even though Mike Tyson would run
through him like a hot samurai sword
through a molten piece of butter.
Yeah.
Fighter only has a certain amount of
fights in
his life in a certain amount of times.
You can punch him in the head with your
hands without them breaking certain
amount of times.
You can explode moving on somebody and
not tear a muscle.
You only have a certain amount of those
lights that Mike Tyson would waste one
of them.
Even if it would be a quick crushing,
why would he waste one of those?
FighTing a guy like that's so arrogant
like he should have fucking.
You really think you.
You could be a boxer and fight Mike
Tyson.
Have an amateur fight.
Just one image.
I think a lot of guys,
it goes back to what we were saying.
A lot of Dudes,
and we meet a lot of these guys in la.
A lot of guys don't really understand
what it's like to be hit by somebody who
can really hit you.
You don't have that experience.
You are you are you.
Your experience comes from what movies
where you see a guy get punched in the
face and he comes back and hits against
you.
Think that's how it is.
Until you get hit by a guy who really
understands how to hit and your whole
world,
your whole world changes,
it's very difficult to relax to when
someone's hitting you and one of the
things that happens to people as they
freak out and there's their stress level
goes up so high,
they lose complete control of their
ability to control their breath and they
get exhausted and they fall apart.
It's like one of tHe main things that
happened.
It's because they can't process the
actual reality of getting hit.
If you've been hit before,
you can calm yourself down like even
though you know that like,
wow,
I just got hit hard,
but we got to keep moving.
We got it open.
Keep your eyes open,
hands up,
and you start like calming yourself
down,
but that's a process you have to get
really,
really used to it.
You ever see boxers were the gods taking
a jab and then he has his eyes open.
Is countering eyes open while guys
touched on their face,
like they get so comfortable with it.
They eat jabs with their eyes open.
It's incredible.
DIaz.
Nick diaz is really good at that.
Nick diaz can actually eat your jab and
keep coming.
He's one of the few guys I've seen who
has got that.
That's a good move.
He just always get the fuck away from
punches,
man.
Did you see the hbo boxing this weekend
that I'm donor fight?
No,
but did you see that bradley fight with
bradley and he said a chick fight.
No one was.
You're not seeing the bradley.
I'm hopkins.
No,
no.
Who?
Bradley.
What's that guy from siberia was the
fight of the year.
I just recently.
It was the craziest thing I've ever seen
in my life together.
He fought in rocky three.
No,
this siberian guy fights out of freddy
roach,
his gym,
and it was the craziest thing.
It's the.
It's the school.
I know.
I know exactly what you're talking
about.
Russia eyes were shut.
It was a crazy fight.
Yeah.
Don't tell anybody what happens because
it's so crazy.
Anyway,
it's the best part of it makes you
people who have no respect for that,
like people who have never been beaten.
You don't have any idea like what those
guys are sacrificing to try to entertain
people like it's the most.
It's the biggest,
the biggest sacrifice you could ever
make physically without dying.
It is.
And what's really interesting is some
people have a genetic,
like an ability to take punches that,
that you as a human being should never
be able to deal with.
Like,
like even watching big country when he
was taking those knees to the face.
Do you ever see that?
Then you call the fight.
Incredible.
Like how he can take that kind of
punishment to his head as the nuttiest
thing I've ever thought of it as it is
mine to a lot of it is your
determination.
Does the physical building your face.
That's one big piece.
Mark hunt like that big fucking thick
head.
That samoan hell.
What'd you say?
The physical.
What are your face?
Physical build of your face?
Construction.
It seems that guys with really thin
faces like narrow jaws have more of an
issue with getting knocked out.
Whereas big square jawed guys are
fighting trainers look for.
They look for a short neck and a wide
face that supposedly as the david to a
perfect example,
one of the best chins of all time,
like lennox lewis cracked him on the jaw
and he just flopped,
sort of wobbles back and forth and keeps
moving forward.
And david had a ridiculous and its head
is as wide as a football field.
I know his,
uh,
I worked out with his strength coach for
and who got him ready for,
for his first fight.
And hIs strength coach said that david
had never squatted and he put them on
the squat rack.
we put four 90 on the squat rack and
two,
uh,
went from.
I'm like,
he,
he went from d,
took them wait 490 pounds and didn't do
a regular squat.
He did a deep squat.
He did an all the way down squat and
then came back up with no problem and he
was like,
you,
how much Do you practice squatting?
And two,
it was like,
I don't,
I don't practice squatting.
I'm just,
you know,
how much weight was that?
And he goes,
that was 490 pounds with no belt or
anything.
You just put it on your body and went
all the way down because you're not
supposed to go all the way down and you
just have to go down to like where you
put your button.
Shitty trainer is that guy.
Well why the fuck did you put too much
weight on and why did he tell him how to
do it?
First trainer sounds like a douche bag.
That story sucks,
man.
Hey man,
about that man.
Henry,
let me retell it.
warmed them up.
It's.
It is definitely important.
You got to edit that one a little bit.
You know what?
Squatting doesn't help with hunting when
you're out there trying to stalk a deer.
I see.
I disagree with you.
I think all those bodyweight squats I
do.
That totally helped me.
I don't hike.
No,
I know I never go hiking.
We were hiking for fucking hours.
I was like,
there's a couple points where I was
like,
whoa.
Like I'm breathing really heavy.
Like,
this is a really taxing,
you know,
and someone who's in shitty shape and
you try to do that badlands hiking all
day.
You're,
that's not good for you.
When we had to have out all that meat.
Yeah.
Well it was a small thing.
I thought it was happy and I was like,
I was concentrating peculiar.
It's like a,
like a peculiar
kind of in shape,
just like walking around on uneven
ground.
Yeah.
Know I remember when I,
like I grew up in Michigan and you
couldn't,
you couldn't find a good,
you couldn't find where you could,
where you needed to walk,
you know,
like a,
like a mile walk.
It'd be a big walk there.
And um,
we were,
you know,
we all consider ourselves pretty about
that kind of stuff.
Like honing in Michigan and traffic and
stuff.
When I moved out west and first started
hunting elk we would get,
were like,
we'd hike in,
we might hike in like eight or nine
miles somewhere to hunt and hanukkah
days and come back out.
And then we get into,
in the truck and drive to a gas station,
you know.
And you go in to get like a fountain pop
and pop that soda for you.
So we're not living in the fountain,
the pot belly washer.
So,
but by that point in time you'd pull up
and open the door and couldn't get out
of the vehicle.
Like just that 20 minute drive and like
my legs would just seize up so bad that
it would take days to recover from it.
Wow.
And then now I don't understand like,
no,
it just like doesn't have that.
Even if I didn't go and do that for a
year,
maybe not a year.
If I didn't go do that for six months or
something,
I feel like I would just be fine.
Do you want me to like something like
goes away or comms or breaks or heels or
something from just like those long
arduous hikes,
you know,
it
is incredibly adaptable.
I mean there's things that people do.
If you go to a martial arts school and
watch guys who have been doing jujitsu
their whole lives and watch,
like how you can move your body around,
how you can manipulate your body.
The only way you could do that as if you
just do it for years and years and years
and years and you're hiking up those
crazy slippery slopes like all those
places we hiked up were really slippery.
You know,
it takes like a specific kind of balance
and a leg endurance when you're moving
through muck and stuff and you're just.
It's a skill,
you know,
you're just really good at it.
Yeah.
You were barely getting tired.
It was crazy.
I was really impressed.
I was like,
this guy is barely breathing heavy.
Like we get to the top and he's like
glassing and I'm going,
he's barely breathing,
but at the same time,
keep in mind,
I live in fear of.
I'm catching a direct hit from a two
year old.
He gets big time out for that and I'm
like,
I'm kind of cover my face.
Like I can't take a hit from him.
He's 35 pounds.
That's a big one.
Take one was matchbox cars and you
bought into deals me a blow to the cheek
or something like that.
It puts me out why kids can.
They can hit you hard.
They don't pull.
My daughter decided to take her healing
to me.
She went,
she jumped on me.
I was lying in bed.
She jumped on me and started riding and
she took her heel and my rib and I went
crazy.
I was like,
how'd you get that much power,
that heel strike.
Do you teach them martial arts yet?
Not yet.
My son will definitely be learning.
Train tHem when the role in the four
year old and two year old,
because they wrestle around together
naturally,
so I trained them positions and I was
like,
thIs is not what you want to stay.
If you're in this position when you want
to do you a to.
That's it's important to teach somebody
how to do that.
Like my wife today,
honest,
honestly,
my wait like two hours ago,
my wife sent me a message on my phone
asking if I thought that our little boy
would
like a karate classes.
It's really good.
I never did anything like that.
A lot of hunting,
known a lot of physical things.
I think men need a lot of physical
things.
I think the idea that a man that it's
natural for man to have no explosive
release physically for the rest of his
life and just sit in a cubicle and just
go through life with shiny shoes on the
fucking tiMe your body's going to break.
There's This total.
That's a totally unnatural thing you're
asking of it and if you don't,
you don't.
You have some sort of physical release
or at least understand how to manage it.
You know,
you got to understand how to manage it.
Like managing it.
It's super important.
Well,
it also,
it also hormonally for a man doing
exercise like that hormone changes
hormonally when you don't,
when you don't exercise,
you lose it,
man.
Yeah.
Oh no question.
No question.
Way healthier to actually lifting heavy
is a good thing too.
We're talking about for little kids,
the little kids like learning,
like learning how to do difficult things
like early on.
So important because well think how
normal it is for you to like sleep
somewhere that's fucking cold as shit
with a sleeping bag and like,
all right,
well this is what we're doing.
Here we are.
You and moe curled up together in that
van,
freezing your ass off that for,
for an average person,
that's like some walking dead type shit.
That scenario never comes up and if it
did that they would fall apart.
They wouldn't be able to deal with it.
They'd be complaining and whining.
I mean,
how many people would complain and
whine?
Well steve,
you shed some light on this because I've
read accounts of where the settlers,
when they would move west and they'd
come in contact with native americans,
it'd be a barely cold winter or
something and they would see like native
americans and children who's not not
dressed warmly dressed in like,
you know,
or,
or not warmly compared to west.
So they'd be,
it'd be like,
you know,
10 degrees out or something and they'd
be in two skins and.
But,
but not nearly as bundled up as you
would expect tHem to be.
Yeah,
I think that.
I think the people,
I think the people acclimate to that
kind of stuff and you see your own minor
version of it just like the way you
might behave throughout the winter.
Do you know what I mean?
Like you get,
you get just general,
you cost them to It to all of the year
and then you see like mild variations
where people who might grow up at
northern latitudes moved down south.
They come back home and can't hack the
cold,
you know,
I wonder what that is maybe.
And maybe your body naturally starts
preparing for that are heating up.
So yeah,
make something shifts and then he looked
like.
Even then if you look at cultures like,
like,
like inuit cultures,
I mean just in that small amount of time
and that's not like a relatively.
that's not a very ancient,
that's not a very ancient people are
very ancient culture but they're fairly
new arrivals in the arctic but they
already like demonstrate physical
differences and physical adaptations
that would help them adapt to the cold.
Like how much,
how much stuff you spread out,
like how much blood you send to your
extremities and how well you can shut
that off and control it either.
Another thing is there's this thing,
it's called the bergman principle a,
it's a principle in,
in while in while they physiology and
the bergman principle holds that like if
you have a species,
okay,
like let's take white tail deer in the
southern extreme of that species range.
The Animals are going to be much smaller
than in the northern extreme.
So if you look at white tail deer from
alberta,
they're just monsters up there.
He's the eyes to get lIke 280 pound
deer,
whatever down in the southern extreme of
their range.
They might weigh 90 pounds and what they
find is that a bigger,
like generally a bigger animal has less
surface area so that bigger animals
better able to retain body heat in a
smaller animal and a man will shape a
smaller animal,
has a greater surface area and Is thus
better able to shed heat.
So it comes down to hear shouting and
heat retention.
And when you look at like human
cultures,
wait,
so a smaller animal,
say again,
like a bigger animal.
If you have it,
let's say you have exactly the same
shape dogs.
Okay?
But one of those dogs is 200 pounds and
one of those dogs is 50 pounds,
right?
The larger dog has less surface area per
unit of mass and suicide in the smaller
dog has greater surface area per unit of
mass.
And so that's a way In which animals
help,
you know,
shedding heat and keeping it.
And another thing you see in species
like now that we look at the wooly
mammoths,
the wooly mammoth,
that very small ears,
you know,
we think of elephants,
I haven't really.
Elephant tine giant ears,
the woolly mammoth.
It various small hears.
It was the arctic and subarctic
inhabitant.
Then you look at like the african
element in near ecuadorian zones,
big ears.
So it's like the ability to sheD heat
to,
to send a bunch of blood into that big
year and drop that heat on it.
What I'm saying is not just the body
size thing,
but just like attributes,
long legs,
you know,
things that long legs would help you
shed he squat legs,
he'll be retaining.
So when you look at human cultures,
like human cultures from ecuadorian
areas in human cultures from arctic and
subarctic areas will in some way
demonstrate that same tendency of have
that same physiology of being squat and
compact,
being able to handle cold.
So I think that,
you know,
it doesn't take that long for.
I mean whatever your feelings are about
like,
you know,
when I talk about evolution dies just
like tangled up,
you know,
people think you're making some
grandiose comment about religion or the
or,
but I'm just going to like,
the things are different,
you know,
things look different where they come
from and it doesn't end.
I think thAt it goes pretty quick.
And in species and humans and stuff
making,
you know,
like acquiring adaptations that help
them deal with climates.
And you talked about guys going out
west.
I mean like settlers going west,
who is going to wind up thriving,
the guy,
they're gonna have to call the guy who
can sleep out.
You know,
that's what I think like on an
individual level.
I think so much of it comes down to I'm
getting comfortable with discomfort and
that was something I learned,
you know,
that was something I learned over a long
time of,
of like hunting in the west and hunting
Alaska was just kinda like the,
the mental attribute of getting
comfortable with discomfort.
Yeah.
Well they,
they said that the seal teams,
uh,
they tried to figure out what prototype
would do well in the,
you know,
a stocky guy or whatever.
A lot of guys are stuck here.
A lot of guys were wrestlers.
There are three sports they recruited
from,
believe it or not,
a cross swimming,
a wrestling and one other football's on.
But,
but they couldn't actually,
they've never been able to really
pinpoint who makes it and why.
And they certainly can't even do it
physically.
Like some guys just defy the odds and
they shouldn't do it,
but they do.
So there's no like,
well that guy has this,
this,
these,
these six qualities.
He's definitely gonna make it through
buds.
No,
it's just a very difficult thing to
pinpoint why would have been talking.
A cam cam just walked in.
We only have one extra mic here,
so you guys are going to have to close
to each other and talk.
Are you,
uh,
you,
steve,
steve's friend.
You guys know each other?
We know eAch other a little bit.
I've gone on cam show a number of times.
Yeah.
Steven and I are both on sportsman
channel.
I,
uh,
Do cameron company,
which is 5:00
eastern monday through friday.
A big fan of steve's and we've talked
about.
So I thought I was confused.
I thought you guys were good buddies
traveling together.
You're not traveling together.
Not traveling together.
I got to know my information suck.
I don't know where I'm getting a wire
from.
Um,
so,
uh,
you are here to promote
here to promote,
uh,
your appearance on mediator and talk
about the,
you know,
the,
uh,
the mma week that we're developing for
cam and comedy coming up last week in
april.
We're goIng to be having steven on and
hopefully having you on.
Randy couture is gonna be joining us.
We're going to talk about,
you know,
the,
the.
I think a lot of the similarities in the
crossover between the mma world and the
world of hunting,
um,
you know,
you talk about what,
what attributes it takes to,
you know,
make it as a navy seal and he talked
about what attributes it takes two to
make it as a hunter.
You know,
I think that there's all kinds of
commonalities there when we talk about
what it means to actually be better than
what we are and to grow ourselves,
whether it's,
you know,
the,
putting yourself in that,
that state of discomfort,
um,
where,
you know,
a lot of people bug out.
I mean,
they don't want to do that anymore.
We live in a world in which our entire
existence is based on how comfortable
can we be.
But you know,
again,
you don't,
you don't become better unless you're
pushing yourself unless you're,
you're breaking out of that comfort.
Yeah.
It's a sad thing to see a whole
generation of kids growing up that don't
experience that as young men.
They don't hAve difficult tasks to
perform.
And I think that's a critical aspect of
like your,
your behavior and your character and
growing your character.
You gotta fail,
you gotta,
you gotta be pushed.
You got to get to a situation where you
pass your limits.
Are you surprised yourself with new
limits and you changed your own
definition of yourself.
But if you don't test yourself,
if you don't get into bad positions,
you're always gonna have that weird
insecurity about yet.
Like that weird insecurity that guys
have that have never been in any kind of
conflict ever.
And you know,
know how they would react.
There are certain people I know exactly
how they would react if the shit hits
the fan,
but those other people.
But like,
ah,
you squirly bitch,
she might fall apart on me.
Like you always say to,
you know,
if you're,
if you are,
if you're trying to be really good at
anything,
you can find all those.
Although you can find all that
discomfort and all those plateaus and
everything just in trying to get great
at the guitar or whatever it is,
there's a certain amount of humility and
an understanding of what's really going
on that you develop when you sort of
make any strides in any really difficult
thing or if it's playing chess,
whether it's,
you know,
whether it's writing know whatever it
is.
It's,
it's a matter of doing something
difficult and testing your boundaries
time all that time.
All that came more naturally.
I think if you just look at the way
people's lives used to be structured,
you know,
in even just,
not even 100 years ago or so.
It wasn't like we Had to manufacturer
opportunities for stress.
I mean it was just like you had things
you had to do,
like you had to clear land or,
or,
or people would actually have children
because they needed the additional re.
They didn't look at children as being a,
a deficit.
They looked at children as being like an
addition of resource resource to have
kids because they'll help me do more
work.
I'll have kids so that I can pump money
into them and pump resources into them.
I'll derive from them and now I find I
certainly don't live that way now.
I find that I manufacturer,
I try to like in small dosages
manufactured that feeling for my kid to,
to like give him this.
He doesn't see it as artificial,
but given this artificial sense of him
having to have output that I'm doing
something and maybe I'm doing something
completely unnecessary,
like he wants to make a birdhouse so
we're going to make a birdhouse,
but at a point it becomes just like
arduous,
you know,
there's a part where the fun dies and
now we just got to get it finished and
to make it and to turn it in.
LIke,
no,
we're doing this,
we're doing this.
And it's like,
and I don't care if it's enjoyable to
him anymore and he's so little.
This is all just like experiment now.
We're just trying to like create that
sense of that you have to now in some
way do something you don't want to do.
Yes.
That is his is.
That's part of life practice,
right?
It's a part of that,
you know,
you get,
you start getting good at soMething and
just,
you know,
if you're Trying to be a good wrestler,
whatever.
There are days you walk in and you're
like,
I don't want to wrestle.
I don't want to do anY of this.
I don't even care about this anymore.
It's all a bore.
I don't like that guy.
I don't like any of this and you.
It's like getting into a cold bath until
your skin gets acclimated.
You know?
That's,
that's,
that's a huge part.
It was like didn't really interesting
thing that where they put it,
get comfortable with discomfort.
I don't think you can get good at
anything unless you,
you'd get you,
you get comfortable with this because
one of the things about wrestlers that
separates them from,
in my opinion than almost every other
athlete wrestlers go through such
horrendous stress throughout high school
between sucking wade and the training
rustling is the most brutal fucking
training you can do and then you're
doing strength and conditioning or hill
sprints,
whatever kind of crazy.
You know,
weight lifted program,
they have you on your,
you are broken down all day,
falling asleep in class,
you're dehydrated,
you're sucking way,
you're eating fucking Turkey,
breast and lettuce with lemon juice on
it like you,
you're essentially starving while your
lifestyle.
And these guYs,
they developed this unbelievable ability
to just grind through shit and they
break a lot of fighters just with their
sheer will because of that,
that,
that the mentality that comes with being
a successful wrestler.
It's like,
well,
I'm doing,
you know,
tomorrow I'm having ronda rousey on the
brian callen show.
Everybody and sorry to push my podcast.
But um,
she,
um,
I look forward to.
I think I changed the name of that
stupid thing from man thoughts.
A lot of people want man thoughts back.
He used to be called man thoughts and
then joe was like,
come on dude,
just have it.
The brian counter.
I was like,
all right,
I'm changing it back to the brian
calender.
Everybody.
Men thoughts.
It's not,
it's not.
You know,
people look for the brian cowen
podcasts,
they're not going to google manto.
Exactly.
There's a little disconnect there with
people finding it.
It was an idea to but can't do any on so
bad labeling.
It was the first modern rousey ronda
rousey because the ufc champion and I'm
out.
The point is I'm making is that I think
part of what makes her so great.
She was an olympian in judo,
which is so difficult.
That same kind of training and when you
get into you get into the octagon with
ronda rousey man.
She's been through the muck.
She and I,
and that's what I'm going to talk to her
about.
What her.
She's an extreme winter,
you know,
and I want to talk to her about how,
what her mindset is,
how she keeps that going,
how she deals with the pressure,
how she deals with her mother developed
her,
her mother's a judo champion as well as
her mother taught her to be a total
badass.
You know,
so she said in an interview,
rhonda said,
and I'm gonna talk about this is when
something bad happens to her.
She immediAtely says,
wow,
I wonder.
I wonder what i'M going to get out of
this.
You know,
I wonder,
oh,
This is good.
This is the socks right now,
but I wonder what good is gonna come out
of this because something goods is
getting something good.
I'm going to react in a good way of my
reaction is going to create something
positive in this atmosphere.
That's a great way of looking at any
kind of adversity.
Sure.
Until you get kicked in the head.
Well that's true,
and then you go,
okay,
ain't that the truth?
That's the ultimate equalizer man scene.
He used to say,
who was that for your younger listeners?
He was a world champion boxer and ray
man,
me and he said,
my father always said,
you're a tough guy.
Telia not bottom line.
Somebody hits you in the face.
You're not a tough guy anymore.
Age doesn't start to get to an age where
your references don't work anymore.
I was like,
how olD are you?
Does it seem that like,
I'll like make something about mary lou
retton,
which in my mind was like the only
athlete I knew about because she was in
special k box.
Jumping around
about how about when bruce jenner used
to be the wheaties guy,
not some freak on a fucking reality show
about that.
How about when bruce jenner had or had a
man knows?
How about when bruce jenner was a man?
What's going on when you,
when you become like this,
this guy who's on this reality show and
all your your daughter upturned nose,
all in the news and everyone's mad.
They're all crazy.
They're completely crazy and it used to
be a champion.
He was,
he was one of the best in the world.
He was a gold metal and handsome and
then decides he's going to go and get
his nose done.
Try to flash forward 20 years into the
future and find out,
you know,
like think okay,
what celebrity that I know now who's
normal is going to be that fucked up 20
years from
no too easy to make fun of the ones that
are fucked up right now.
I'm not really into fucking the stock
market of celebrity douche this.
I'm looking for them to be fucked up
right away.
I mean there's always something that you
picture like if someone just rubs you
the wrong way for whatever reasons,
one to fantasize turns that could
happen.
Right?
You know what?
What'S really fun is when,
what you don't like
and that actually happens and you get to
watch even watch them fucking skid and
hit the and older you can kinda,
you can kinda get.
You get really good at figuring out.
You look at Some celebrities and you go,
oh,
there's a lot of flash noise there,
but you're not drawing from much
brother.
You're working with one bag of tricks
and that's getting empty.
I can watch it again and you're like,
you've got to come up with something.
But you.
a lot of times you'll see that it's a
very disappointing thing when you
realize that there's all these really
douchey people that on camera and they
have the,
like the sort of like artificial active
they put on and then they'll do films
where they really,
really good at pretending to be someone
else.
So they do that and then you know,
you get to meet them and you see them in
the elect.
This guy is a douche bag,
like a straight,
a great a douche bag and a boar.
Yeah.
Boring,
crazy psychopath who's just all about
themselves.
Pathologically self-involved.
I know a movie star like that.
It's just I,
you know.
And you grew up watching him with it,
ya know,
and you get.
And I got snowmen.
I was like,
you are an absolute cuckoo bird.
You are all about yourself.
Never asked me a question about my.
I for many,
never asked
me one question about myself.
Not one question I didn't even.
how you doing?
Never another a question.
No interest.
It's all about him.
He's truly the center of his own
university.
I had a buddy that I had to cut off
because I could never just have a,
hey,
what's going on man?
I couldn't have that.
I couldn't say no,
no,
no.
Because when you would say,
hey,
what's going on man?
He would just go into his career.
I know this.
I mean,
it was like a fucking five minute
diatribe on how well this audition when
and he's pretty sure he's gonna be back
for a,
a second pass at that and I think once I
can get in front of producers,
I can show them what I could really do.
I know what you're talking about too.
It can it.
Can I interrupt you long enough?
Just the briAn,
how's your family and
dude,
I can't believe he wants to make sure
he's off.
Steve are now.
You will never be on that list.
Yeah,
you can do your,
you can do no wrong when we're talking
can.
before you got here,
we were talking about how it seems like,
um,
you know,
brian and steve and I are a.
Because we went on this crazy trip
together because we went to Montana.
We have this weird blood brothers shit,
blood brotherhood ship thing going on
it.
So he felt that way when I was watching
the episodes.
I was like,
damn,
I miss those guys like Ryan Ryan
for five days.
We had a great fucking time with no tv,
no cell phone.
We're all asleep right?
Remember that didn't,
I mean we slept like rocks.
We slept when the lights went out.
Basically we ate,
slept and.
But getting up,
it didn't seem that hard.
it was.
It was really.
It was probably because we were going to
bed at eight and wake up.
Yeah.
I did get about 14 hours of sleep.
I didn't even need a nap.
I'm rugged.
It was hard
to figure out how to sleep at first,
but I realized eventually that the
softest way to do it is to keep your,
your not just your sleeping bag,
but your jacket on as well.
Let me get all my clothes,
all my clothes on my jacket and my
sleeping bag and the down jacket and the
sleeping bag was like,
this is just enough.
Let me tell you something.
the next time we go hunting,
I'm bringing a sherpa and guess what?
He's going to carry a big fucking
mattress on it.
Back.
Portable Heater.
And fuck you guys by the portable.
I want to fucking matches with a big
pillow.
Remember we passed that one will lose
something though,
man.
Whatever.
What dId we just talked about?
Oh,
sorry.
Sorry,
he's a famous quote,
I can't remember who said like,
you don't really know a man,
you know,
100,
100 with them.
I wish I forget that.
I don't know the guy,
I don't know what he said or who said it
was really destroys my point.
But broadly I was and say is it,
there's like a.
I was talking to one time with the older
friend of mine,
he was talking about being at his
fishing camp and he was trying to
describe why he likes to be known as
fishing camp with his buddies now is
fish held and Alaska and he's like,
everyone's just so,
so competent,
you know,
and it wound up being like that.
He just kind of appreciated that.
Like hanging out with people who like
have the ability to just to take care of
things,
like to do things.
And he was saying like,
you gotta wait in line if you want to
wash a dish,
you know,
with this crew of people who's out with.
And I think that in ways,
none of this thing,
this is exclusive to hunting.
I mean,
I,
there was many things,
but it's like going on a trip,
you know,
going on a trip with people where things
aren't so great all the time.
LIke there's,
there's elements of being cold was
elements of having not slept enough,
but it's kind of having this feeling of
um,
everything's gonna be okay.
like these guys are like great people to
be with and they're just really
competent people and right now we're
doing those behind like we're doing like
this little crew show on like the media.
It was just on the one that's coming up
or kind of about the guys I work with.
And when I watched it I kind of see that
where I just feel.
So I'm like comfortable being around
people that I've spent a lot of time out
hunting with.
And again,
I don't want to make.
I tHink that sports teams feel something
similar.
You know,
I think there's guys served together in
the military,
but it just kind of a way of,
uh,
being away from things and sort of
relying on other structures,
you know,
relyIng on other things and not having
assumptions about people holding their
weight or if you could complain,
make it funny.
Yeah,
that's right.
That's right.
You know that when I went spent 11 days
in Afghanistan doing the uso tour and
one of the things I came away with was
I,
I realized I went,
you know,
I've been in la for a long time where
I'm the center of my own universe and
everybody around me is always about
them.
And one of the thingS i founD very
refreshing about being in a war zone,
if there is such a thing as being
professional,
is that when you're in the military,
you're a marine,
you're an army guy,
you come last,
those guys put themselves last and
everybody around them comes first.
So when you get off a bus and you're
unloading bags,
there's always a line of people
unloading everybody else's bags.
Everybody's looking out for the other
guy next to him.
and that's that ethos that is,
that is quito in,
in the military,
that's,
that's drummed in you.
And I got to say that having come from
la,
which was the exact opposite of being
thrown into that experience,
was very,
very kind of.
It was really.
I didn't expect it.
It was just one of the most ridiculous
places to live in the world.
If you wanna,
if you want to find like actual real
humans to talk to,
real,
authentic.
It's true authenticity and loss and with
men and women,
it's like it's,
it's such a brutal grind to try to find
people that are your friends.
So you can talk to.
I've cultivated a group over the years
and I'm.
One of the things about,
about doing your show is that I knew
that if I was going to do it and I
brought this motherfucker around,
I'm like,
will change the whole tone of the show.
Like this show is just going to be a
five day silly,
fast.
This is the perfect thing to do.
Because.
And also I knew that brian cowen holds
up a new.
No matter what happened,
they fucking asteroids can become and
that we'd be looking at each other.
Well pal,
it's been a good time,
but I don't see us survive in that
fucking thing.
I'm always ready to go out with a bang.
I will.
I will stand by your side no matter
what.
That's how I think of friendship.
He's my four in the morning.
I got a body to get rid of guy.
Yeah,
it's true.
If I had,
if I had a guy that I had to call up and
go,
dude,
I'm meet me.
I would take her risk for you.
Tell me in your parking lot.
You know I.
I take that very seriously.
My real friends,
my real friends.
I always said,
I'll take a risk for you to take a risk
for her to show that hurts my feelings.
You.
Oh,
you too,
sweetie.
I totally carry more.
Yeah,
he can carry your body now.
You might get uncomfortable walking
through the desert.
I also got holes.
I got holes.
I got holes in stores.
I've live where I will have to stop for
cigarette breaks,
but the evidence away,
but you're not just looking for someone
who'd be cool with the fact that you had
a body.
Right.
It'd be someone who'd be.
Who'd be helpful in getting.
Oh yeah,
I know exactly how to get rid of it.
You've got to go into mission mode.
You got to get rid of that fucking body
because that's the way it is.
We know that fossil either.
It's like it's like jimmy burke's friend
who is his.
His car.
He comes home.
His girlfriend is having a fight with
her boyfriend.
My boyfriend is hitting his daughter.
He comes home and his daughters in a
fight with her boyfriend in the backyard
and the boyfriend's starts hitting her.
He comes out and he's a construction
worker.
He comes back here.
Can you back up one step?
So,
so yeah.
So not that.
Oh,
I don't understand the story.
Okay.
So the story is my buddy,
my buddies,
my buddy,
my buddy.
Your body.
Is it your buddy?
My buddy grows up.
It grows up with a guy named uh,
can't fuck with his name.
Is he comes home,
he comes home,
his daughter is in the backyard with a
boyfriend and they're fighting.
They're having a fight.
Boyfriends starts hitting his daughter.
He goes out in the backyard and tries to
break it up.
The boyfriend,
I guess get smart with them.
He kills the boyfriend with his bare
hands.
He fucking kills him.
He punches him to death.
Now he says to his daughter,
go inside and he's got to get rid of the
body.
So he calls his buddy guy,
you should you be telling a story and
it's fine.
It's fine.
People in jail.
Yeah,
so.
So he,
he,
and this was a long time ago,
so he calls his huge friend.
Bozo.
Bozo was not called breaker.
Who his claim to fame was.
He had the longest tongue on the,
on the planet.
He was sticking his tongue out and you
go,
jesus christ like that.
He'd scare people with his fucking
tongue.
That was the size of a cow's.
Anyway,
bose was a giant men.
Bozos shows up.
Bozo goes,
I know we're going to do calm down.
He goes,
well,
he goes,
I'll be right back.
Bozo goes and gets a dolly.
He takes the dolly,
he ties the guy to the dolly.
They fucking in the middle of the night,
they take this guy,
they dolly him to a gas station around
the corner and they leave and behind the
gas station.
Oops,
get dropped something.
Then they come running back like we did
it.
Good job buddy.
Plugged brothers.
I got to get rid of a body.
Well,
here's what they didn't think because
they were a little drunk to calm down.
Oh,
the guy's hand had dragged,
dragged along the ground.
So when the cops showed up,
they brought the dogs and the dogs went,
oh,
well let's just follow where the dogs go
in and they just went around the corner
and found themselves little house and
started barking costs like knock,
knock,
knock.
Hey you guys a dolly,
a body around the fucking thing.
Sorry we did.
You're going to jail and so are fucking
you.
Pounce.
And they.
They did some time.
Not that they didn't do 25 to life.
They did some fucking.
So your point is you don't want any old
dude getting rid of a body.
You've got to have a plan through this
shit beforehand.
Yeah.
You got to think through the better.
Rehearsed this shit.
And you got to get his body up before it
stinks.
Support tech blenders guys.
Yeah.
One blender at a time when there was
that guy that fed the body through a,
uh,
I guess he had a hog farm and fed the
body first through a tree shredder,
shot all the,
all of it into the hog thing.
And the hogs hate it,
but they still let you know.
This reminds me that link,
like joe said,
you sent me a link reasonably.
You like the great cannibals of the wild
west,
the great cannibals of the west with
wild shit,
isn't it?
What's that like?
The donner party similar,
similar,
but one of them was a guy who,
uh,
his wife got killed by the cherokee.
So he went on a rampage,
is killed a bunch of indians and ate
their liver and they called them liver
eating.
Johnson,
johnson.
He just,
he would kill guys and eat their liver.
So that was the sydney pollack.
That's a serial killer who fantasize
about that his whole life.
He's like,
they killed my wife before I could eat
her liver.
He later became the sheriff.
He later became the sheriff of red.
Is it red lodge on something?
Some,
some.
He was,
yeah,
he was a sheriff in red lodge and then a
sydney pollack made that movie.
Great movie.
Jeremiah johnson and jeremiah johnson
was based loosely off of the legend of,
of liver eating johnson.
And it was one of liberty johnson liver
eating.
Johnson used to cut firewood,
um,
for the,
for the boats on the Missouri breaks.
Wow.
Where we did our float.
Holy shit brings this whole deal way
full circle in a weird way.
Yeah.
I had an eight inch tongue.
Your stories man about the old west were
so great.
You know,
you,
you know,
so many cool fucking stories.
Like when we were like brian,
when we got back when we were on the
boat and you were like,
oh my god,
that's the last day of being on the
water was so fucking cold.
My god,
I didn't even notice because steve kept
telling me all these cool ass fucking
indian stories about how this guy got
away and this guy hitting a beaver's dan
and this guy,
they told him he could run naked.
You can try to get away if you can,
if you can run away,
and so I was so frozen and I saw you and
it was so cold that you had like there
were icicles out of your beard and you
were just smiling the whole time.
I was like,
how is he not cold?
Right.
So you did your
job,
you distract them.
I was enjoying myself,
man.
I never bothered.
I mean knowing that the cold was only
like a five day thing.
I was like,
as long as it's only a five day thing
and when we were walking around in the
day,
it wasn't bad.
As long as you have gloves on,
even if you're.
If you're done upright,
if you're wearing the right shit,
it's not a bad deal.
It's.
The thing is,
it's like a,
it's like a paradox almost where when
you get uncomfortable and cold like
that,
some part he wants you to stand there,
you know,
but the only time you're actually
comfortable is when you're out screwing
around.
YeAh.
You got to move around as soon as you
start moving around,
but there's something intimate.
You stop,
something comes something and habits you
in and makes you want to just like stand
there,
be cold and it's like the guys that are
good about it are the guys that just,
you look and instead of hanging around
and talk and there was like walking up
and down a little hill and they're
totally fine.
Well,
it's weird how comfortable we got sweaty
even though it's like nine degrees out,
you know?
There's a lot of times we're fucking
sweaty,
moving around a lot.
That's why kills,
right.
You know,
when you get sweat needs,
you've got to have wool.
The opposite of that is,
are you familiar with paradoxical
paradoxical undressing?
It's like when people,
a free fine hypothermia like victims
will hypothermia that they'll.
They'll often have often shed their
clothes but an erratic ways taking
jewelry off.
I'm taking one sock off,
but there's this thing that happens
where you spend like your body.
When you start getting cold,
your body spends a lot of energy.
It constricts certain blood vessels and
stops the flow of blood out to your
extremities,
to the tip of your nose.
You know when you get cold,
like tip of your nose will get kind of
numb in white is your fingers get that
way,
like your body's working really hard to
to stave off the heat loss so it doesn't
want to send as much blood out to places
that lose blood easily,
but as you tire and you start to peter
out,
that gives way your body can't expend
the energy necessary to do that and it
opens those up and it's a rush of heat,
so it's like your.
Your fingers have gotten very cold.
Your lives have gotten very cold.
Your face got very cold and all of a
sudden you body's like,
I can't do anymore.
And all that hot blood rushes out to
those things and people apparently get
this feeling of intense heat.
Wow.
Grunden start.
Yeah.
And then so they'll find someone and
it's always like,
you know,
he's got some clothes over here and his
wedding rings land over that way and you
know,
burn.
But you know what man I got,
I Just,
I was down fishing in Florida.
I got built by black flies real bad.
And uh,
and for the first time since I got
married,
I took my wedding ring off for a day and
a that's all good.
I got like a guilty conscious feeling
and I had to put it back on and
uncomfortable because I just felt
guilty.
And then I get here and I'm looking
through my bag and find my wife's
reading wedding ring in my backpack
because like a week ago she didn't know
where to put it.
And I put my backpack on and be like,
do you even know
like here,
a bunch of dudes in the background come
back to the hot tub.
I know.
I didn't know he had a hard time trying
to scratch undermine,
you know.
And hers is just in some unknown
location too.
I left my,
I left my wedding ring at a spa where I
got a massage from a dude.
I go,
I've been getting,
I get messages from dudes now I gave up
because girls can't do it hard and they
can't.
I need,
I need deep tissue.
And it's brutal.
It's painful,
it doesn't feel good.
But you got to have a man doing it
because women just not strong enough to
do it.
Some women are,
they used their elbows really well,
but I'm borderline.
He has to have a mustache.
Borderline violent.
It's that hard to come with a guy
though.
It's not that hard.
So,
um,
anyway,
I,
I go and I come back and she always
makes fun of me for getting massaged by
dudes.
Right.
And then I go,
fuck,
I left my wedding ring there.
So I run back,
I get the,
when I come back home she goes,
was it in his ass?
That's so awesome.
Oh yeah.
It was fucking hilarious.
By the way,
did you actually go to dick party in my
mouth and see what that was.
I just made that up.
Good.
Check it out.
Go check it out.
It's powerful.
We were talking about,
um,
who is domain name privacy that when you
register a domain you can also register
it anonymously.
so people don't know who owns dick party
in my mouth.
Dot com.
They're going to be surprised.
Why was it surprising?
It's,
it's pretty shocking.
Okay.
That's going to tell you at the
beginning,
but pretty shocking with the url.
I mean like alex,
what's your next?
what's your next trip?
How do you talk about the constitution?
How weird is this?
Oh,
it is.
it's death squad team.
That's hilarious.
Did you just transfer it?
I bought that during the commercial.
That's good move man.
That's a smart move.
And how much does something like that
costs?
13 bucks.
Because I used to keep our code rogan
and save 10 percent.
Guys,
while we're doing this,
are you gonna fucking pump up?
You've got to try to tell people where
you going to do if you're happen to be
in edmonton,
April 25th,
26th,
27th,
28th,
and come to the comic strip if you're
there.
I meAn,
but otherwise don't.
Steve,
you are the,
you're the only hunting show that I know
of that shows on a regular basis.
You'll show if you get skunkeD,
you know.
Yeah.
We call them sculling curse you,
you'll show you.
He'll have a whole episode.
Like there was an episode where you were
going after our dad wasn't that one.
You got so close but it was too Dark for
you to like,
we've done four.
We've done for skunk.
You can't get nothing getting skunked
like.
No,
no,
no.
skunk.
The skunk is not getting anything.
The first time we filmed a dunker I'll
stop using that lingo.
the first time I will hunt.
Right.
um,
I was very nervous and I was trying to
make the case.
We uh,
wouldn't air it.
I don't know know,
it seems stupid.
We're at the time,
it seemed like a good idea.
We wouldn't air it.
And then one time we went out,
we went to hunter mountain lions with
hounds with a friend of mine and went
and spent six days hunting,
didn't get anything,
came back,
went back out again,
been I think seven days hunting,
didn't get anything.
And at that point we just had it.
So then we cut that into one and
oftentimes the winds up being that I'm
not oftentimes,
it's almost like the normal way is
people will then pick those out as their
favorite shows.
Really.
No,
and I think it gets back to that thing I
was talking about earlier,
like is um,
is that whole thing of like courting
uncertainty.
do you know what I mean?
And like,
like things that are challenging and
things you won't figure it out.
So I think people like to see that
represented.
Also,
I'll say that there's a big rift in um,
in hunting as experienced by the
american sportsman in hunting as seen on
hunting television.
You know,
for me,
growing up,
like we were start hunting deer,
the Bowl on october one and you can hunt
deer right up almost the rifle season,
which was November 15th and you had 10
days to hunt with a rifle.
Then you'd pick your bow bAckup and the
hunted December 31st and it would be
plausible that you would hunt pretty
hard through that whole thing and never
get a deer.
It was just the thing that happened,
man.
You would like,
you know,
most years you get deer,
but it'd be,
you might not.
And there's a lot of guys were not there
right now.
It's Turkey season.
There's a lot of guys around in this
country facing the prospect that they
work pretty hard and haunted five,
six,
seven days and they won't get a Turkey.
So I think that people.
And,
and I think that the assumption is
always that people do want to Get
something and they do.
And so when they're watching something,
like when they're watching television,
that's a form of escapism.
And so you want to see people achieve
what you wish you achieved,
you know?
So there would be a thing that you'd
want to go and see,
like I dream of killing a big buck.
I want to watch a guy shoot 10 bIg
bucks,
you know?
and that's like one form of
entertainment.
I think at the same time,
people like to see in some way their
life reflected back to them.
I think more and more people actually
are going the route that you just
described.
They wAnt to see that,
that authentic experience,
especially because a lot of reality tv
now is very unrealistic.
It's very safe.
You got to pull up my.
Sorry.
It's so hard.
But a lot of reality tv right now,
it's not really reality tv at scripted,
you know?
And so there is something completely
unscripted,
you know,
it's real.
If you're watching meat eater and you
don't get anything,
I think you know,
that's a real show.
No,
that really happened was it wasn't like
we actually got a bunch of stuff and
then it's better to just,
you know,
show that sometimes you don't.
Exactly.
But you know,
and that's the thing.
I mean,
you talked to anybody who's hunted for,
for any amount of time and a huge part
of the huntington is,
is about going out with the guys that,
that you're going hunting with and it's
about the experience.
It's About
what you bring home in terms of the,
the game.
Whereas what you bring home up here and
in here.
Yeah.
I think um,
it's important to show that you don't
always get something because it's,
you're,
It's a real show.
The everything you're doing is real,
you know,
and that's,
that's part of the whole thing.
You got to,
it's got to be A part of the whole
prison presentation also lends to the
drama.
no,
actually when there are assumptions you
don't get it.
So now that our dad,
sheep one was a great one,
even though you didn't get one,
it's just like seeing you like in the
dusk where it was just getting like,
you're like,
I need five more minutes,
five more minutes of [inaudible] light.
and you just couldn't get it.
Like shit.
Like you had it,
you had the,
you had it right in your sights.
ThAt's real.
The mountain lion thing is real and I
wanteD to talk to you about the mountain
lion thing for me.
Let me,
I want to add
one thing,
the what you were saying.
I do want to talk about the mountain
lion thing because the jaguar thing too.
But yeah.
Um,
we did have a guy email one time.
All the emails you get like people
saying,
I love that you show like some failure.
We had an email from a guy who was
following.
He'll never watch the show
again because he has enough failure in
his life.
He doesn't want to see other people
fail.
That's hilarious.
So awesome.
Honest.
Yeah,
me too.
I appreciate that guy.
Fucking dvd show.
I'll tell you what,
I watch ted nugent ever week.
God damn ain't never misses.
That's like steve burns joke where a
girl calls up and she said,
you'll never guess what almost happened.
He's lIke nothing.
Because it was almost like a ted nugent
shoots.
He'll shoot three deer with a bow and
arrow in the first five minutes of a
show and I'm not bullshitting.
He shot three deer with bows and arrows.
Yeah,
I mean it's not my favorite part about
it.
He,
he,
after he shoots a deer,
he goes,
can you believe that you believe you
just fucking did.
You just shot one,
five minutes.
I don't know what kind of limits ted
nugent hazard is.
Backyard land management issue.
You know where you can.
You can make the call if you've got a
high fence operation in Texas,
like how many take out
you can do your do your own manager.
Yeah.
I don't know.
That's management and he sitting up
there in the fucking tree stand blast
and deer with his bow and arrow
variability.
It surprises people that surprised
people that,
that don't have familiarity with
hunting.
One,
it surprises people that there's
regulations at all sometimes like if you
grow up,
you know,
I,
I have friends in New York who were
pleasantly surprised to hear that wild
game is managed.
You know,
and,
and I think also beyond that,
it's surprising to people at the very,
the variations from the different
states,
their strategy and how they're managing.
And I think a lot of it comes down to
what a lot of it comes down to how much
of the state's public and like Texas,
they even got to school,
got rid of school trust lands.
So like you used to be the one in every
36 sections belonged to the state and
they could use that to either build
schools on or use that land to fund
school construction and they threw
mineral leasing or timber rights or
whatever.
And at a point in Texas even scrap that,
they even sold that off into private
interests.
So they,
it's like there really is like public
trust.
Wildlife isn't as vital in a place like
taxes because there's not publicly owned
land with publicly owned wildlife on it.
Wow.
You know,
that's kinda crazy,
isn't it,
that you take a state like new guys,
everything is privately estela you guys
that you guys have humongous national
forest.
There's a lot of public trust land and
public trust while.
But even in places like California,
so yeah,
you have a,
you have the government plays a much
stronger hand in a much more detail
oriented hand.
And like,
what's happening,
all this stuff was our harvest like that
in some states where it kind of tends to
be like,
well,
it's your land,
you figure it out are
show on the mountain lions.
One of the specific reasons I wanted to
bring that up is because the,
the idea of hunting with hogs or hunting
with dogs rather is,
uh,
they,
they've done work it off
too hard.
I cannot get a mountain lion with these
stupid dude.
I,
I'm sorry.
My iphone road hogs.
I meant you need trained dog.
Fuck man hunter.
I told people I'm a hunter.
Now look like an ass on facebook
dogs in California.
You can hunt with dogs anymore.
And uh,
people,
uh,
some people are concerned about that.
I've heard people say that they're
worried that the mountain lion
population is going to get too strong if
they do that.
Especially people have lost dogs or who
knows,
people who have been a fucking bikers
and shit.
They get taken out,
but California doesn't allow it anymore.
Coincidentally,
I saw a mountain lion last week in santa
barbara.
A small mountain line wasn't very big.
I thought it was a chaotic at first
could,
but it wasn't,
you know,
coyotes.
They move kind of stiff.
This thing had like this bounce to it.
Tail put.
It wasn't a bobcat.
No,
it was the tail and the long tails.
Mountain lion.
It was probably 70 pounds.
Wow.
Yeah.
I think you're seeing like.
Yeah,
and I don't mean to say I hate to,
I don't want to sound like,
you know,
like taking cheap shots,
at California or anything,
but you're seeing a pretty,
a real erosion of haunting.
Right?
Like a gradual.
Not even grab a pretty steady of rowers.
No hunting rights in California there
was a debate that was easy because
there's a thing.
There's the thing,
I mentioned this somewhere where you can
go to american or you can go to the
american public and say like,
yes or no,
like do you approve of,
of regulated hunting.
Okay.
And you get the vast majority of
americans.
It's something ridiculous.
Like 74 percent or 75 percent of
americans will say like,
yes,
I approve of honey.
but then you start asking them,
you know,
like,
well how about with dogs?
Right?
And in those numbers start to go down
when you start [inaudible] because you
can kInd of,
it's easy to sell people on.
The idea is easy to sell.
People who've never seen a hunting dog
there were never had experienced with
dog.
I've never laid eyes on a line.
It's easy to sell them on the idea that
somehow there's no challenge in it.
And so then you can,
you can have a,
a way to chip away like a way to chip
away at liberty,
like personal liberty and stuff.
it's just to do like one little thing at
a time,
you know,
we'll do this,
we'll do that,
we'll do that.
And so like,
They'll never be a thing like we'll ban
hunting.
It was be that you can't hunt on this
kind of land.
You know,
you can't have this kind of animal this
way.
Well in fact we don't want you to
hunting that kind of animal at all.
And you see that in certain places.
Colorado's had some experience with
that.
We know you got the lead ammo ban and
the uh,
California conduit range that they're
trying to expand statewide.
So you couldn't use lead ammo to hunt at
all.
Well,
there even places where there are no
cars,
even the places where there are no
condo,
right?
I heard a big debate about this mountain
lion issue and one of the things that
the guy from the fish and wildlife
service said is,
well,
you guys don't realize is if you're
actually a preservationist,
the majority of money that we collect to
preserve the land you like to hike in
comes from hunters.
It comes from Hunting licenses.
That's where the fish and wildlife
service and these different
organizations that are responsible for
maintenance of the land that is hunted,
hiked on and camped on.
That's the 90 some crazy amount of 95
percent,
some crazy amount.
I can't remember.
The percentage comes from hunters and
the dues and fees they have to pay to
hunt that land.
So I think that the debate has to be
couched in those terms too.
If you really wanted to get rid of
hunters,
we wouldn't have revenue to actually
maintain.
Well,
I think there's also this part need to
appease a certain liberal said,
I'm part of the population that is very
uncomfortable with hunting in the first
place and would like to look at people
hunting with dogs as okay,
jesus christ,
that's part ferric.
Your sicking dogs on them and then
you're shooting them.
It's poor defenseless animals,
especially when it comes to predators.
There's a population management issue
that they're not willing to address and
if you don't address that,
you're going to deal with it in the
suburbs.
okay.
They just shot a fucking mountain lion
with a tranquilizer dart in glendale the
other day.
Yeah.
Was all in the news and they killed that
one in santa monica a year ago.
That was 90 fucking pounds.
I saw one in santa barbara the other
day.
I mean it.
I'm not comfortable like with those
things like getting more popular.
I'm.
I'm never,
I'm never comfortable with terms like,
like overpopulated because it's just
like.
I don't know really how to define it,
but overpopulating the sense that you're
gonna wind up seeing impacts that might
be counter to what it is you're going
after.
You know,
like you'll lose in infringe Areas.
You might lose species
to,
to predation and predation have a
serious effect on species that you may
be.
We'll want back at what happened with
wolves in yellowstone is not what is
happening or you know,
you seem like a radical,
radical decline.
Radical,
very localized decline.
An elk and moose.
Okay,
and it's hard for people.
If you look at a map of the country and
what used to be wolf territory and at
the time of european contact,
it was wolf country,
the country,
the entire nation was in some way or
another had had wolves,
not the entire place,
but a lot of adults.
Now let's say you're a guy and you live
in Colorado.
All right,
and you hear that hunting wolves,
Montana.
You're probably thinking,
but we don't even have wolves in
Colorado.
We do,
but there's not many.
And it's kind of controversial.
Whether it is a stable breeding
population or not.
And you're telling me that they're
killing them right up in Montana because
it's hard for people to visualize the
localized impact of these things so you
can have too many wolves in Montana and
then jump down through Wyoming and you
enter Colorado and you could have not
enough.
You know,
why is that the wolves?
I guess they stay within a certain
territory.
They stay within a certain territory and
they have a really.
I mean they have a profound effect and
stuff.
You have To think like,
have you guys been to yellowstone
national park kid?
You also national park,
you know the last,
like yellowstone national park was
hunted for,
you know,
nine or 10,000
years.
I think the oldest artifact,
they found that they have reliable data
from yellowstone,
something like a spear point from 9,000
years ago.
So it hasn't those joe's,
but the last one,
hundred years,
no one's hunted it.
Yellowstone park,
when he also parked became a park.
There was still an indian war,
like the nez perce went through there
and killed some tourists while they are
fleeing the u.
S military.
Okay.
After that,
they banned hunting yellowstone national
park.
Anyone who goes to yellowstone national
park now,
we'll see the way the elk and everything
just like has no concern for humans.
Right?
They've ruled out that humans are
troublesome,
so you had this long absence of no
wolves in that ecosystem and when you
put wolves back in,
it's just taken those animals a really
long time to figure out how to get back
to,
to get back to knowing what's going to
be.
And so we had inflated.
We had inflated numbers of elk and
somewhat argue inflated numbers,
elk,
someone arguing inflated numbers of
moose and when the wolves came back,
it's just.
I mean,
just plowed into the ground.
There's tea,
there's hurt mountain range that maybe
had $9,000.
Now they're down to less than 2000.
I was talking with a guy from a
conservation organization that deals
with elk and they're looking at the very
real probability of if the wolf
situation ever does get under control in
the area of having to reintroduce elk
into some mountain ranges because
there's a paucity of breeding age,
female god,
because they're all getting killed by
wolves and it's just like,
jeez,
you still have groups that are trying to
stop the wool funds in Montana and
Idaho.
Well,
the problem is also,
I heard you can't actually,
you can't shoot your way out of this
problem when it comes to walls.
In fact.
Rise to hear that.
yeah.
But then that,
that,
that poses boxes and all that.
You're talking joe.
I've never been a fan of wolves.
People,
uh,
try to pretend they're dogs and get all
attached to him because you know,
it looks like your colleagues,
that's a fucking wolf and that'll eat
you.
And they've eaten people before and
fact.
I told the story on the podcast about
France,
France.
I say brian France used to come in
people before they cornered them and
killed them.
I mean they've really,
I mean I don't think there's any real
argument be made that there's a human
risks not yet the highway.
Now there's an argument to made that
there's an ecological risks.
I think there's still a human risk.
I think if you get around a big pack of
them and you just.
A child happens to be in that area.
While that's called going down,
someone sneaks out of the house and they
have a farm and there's a story I read
online about this woman who is watching
these wolves tear apart sheep in her
backyard.
It was fucking wild.
I don't play around.
She said they got into this,
they have a pen of sheep and they got in
and there was like four or five wolf's.
We're just running through ripping these
sheep apart and you just heard these
horrific noise is tearing and grappling
and horrible sheep screens.
He's looking out the window watching
this going,
holy fuck.
Imagine that.
That's going down in your yard.
And then they know that this is a.
This is a place where food is.
How big is it?
Timber wolf.
They go to like 100 and 2,030
pounds bigger than that.
Well then the real big ones that they're
experiencing now mean these deer are
getting very large for meeting all these
elk and even all these deer that didn't
know they were coming there.
There's people that are shooting them.
They're taking pictures of him and you
would swear it's a photoshop.
These are enormous fucking wolves.
So you're like guys holding them and the
thing that looks as long as them.
I mean I don't know what it waves.
It's more than a hundred 50 pounds.
They're big dogs are big wolves.
I actually like,
you know,
I don't want to get rid of all the wolf
man.
Like I support.
I support wolf recovery cam.
You got,
I mean you deal with wildlife.
No so much while they.
PolItics was sort of like public
perception of public opinion.
Would you say that?
I mean hundreds of being billed as
being,
wanting to destroy rules,
but I think it's not really.
That's not what I hear.
Destroying
the wolf.
It's just pulled that mic up.
It's about getting that balance back
right now.
I mean,
that's the thing.
So you've got these groups that are out
there trying to stop the wolf and they
want to put the wolf back on the
endangered species list,
even though the wolf is no longer
endangered,
the wolf isn't threatened in these
areas.
Again,
these local areas that We're talking
about here know in the state of Idaho,
the state of Montana,
um,
there,
there is a way to try to manage the
wildlife so you get that balance.
But right now,
what have you seen as sort of,
it's out of whack and right now the wolf
has the advantage and we're continuing
to give the advantage to the wolf and
some of these states.
And I think that's why you're trying to,
that.
That's where that,
that battle comes in right now.
What one wants to see,
I don't think anyone wants to see wolfs
pulled these unrealistic urban people.
And that's really what it boils down to.
The people that are really,
almost all the people that are against
hunting or against,
uh,
the,
the idea of a wildlife,
wildlife management.
Almost all of them live in cities when
when people live in a place where you,
you have to contend with it,
someone has to be the top predator and
if it's not going to be a person,
it's not going to be people and you're
living around these animals,
it's going to be them and that's just
the reality of the food chain of life.
If you're a meek person and you're
wandering around through the woods and
you stumble into a pack of hungry wolves
and haven't seen an elk because it
decimated the population,
they'll kill you.
I mean that's reality happen.
Might not happen,
but it's happened before.
A woman died in Alaska recently.
She was killed by wolves and it was also
wearing an alc.
So that was the first documented case in
a long time.
I was like 100 years in that state.
I think that 90 percent of the 95
percent of traditional wolf habitat in
Alaska is still occupied by wolves.
Wow.
And they.
And they have very,
very few fatalities.
I think that moose kill more people.
Yeah,
they do.
They're in.
Anything else?
You also naTional park the greatest
cause of injury.
Now yellowstone national park is getting
gored by a buffalo.
My parents live in Utah in park city.
You know what they always tell you?
The locals,
they go,
hey,
be careful of moose.
Please don't think of them as dear to
not approach them and what do people do
that like there's going to take a
picture and the moose is like,
nah,
I'm going to trample you now.
People get kIlled by moose.
Yeah,
they'll fuck you up.
People are getting used to say,
you know,
urban areas.
A lot of people who,
who grow up in urban areas only live in
urban areas have very unrealistic
expectations of what aniMals are.
They have this anthropomorphic,
you know,
operaTe.
It's bambi and they don't understand.
No,
they,
you know,
I just became a,
a,
a farmer now,
so I have pigs and chickens and I,
it's,
it's so completely different actually,
like sit down and study these animals.
Are you doing for your business?
Are you doing it for me to provide for
yourself?
Yes.
All of the above.
I mean,
eventually I'd like to get to the point
where I can sell some,
you know,
we're doing a heritage livestock,
where is it doing something like this
recently,
I was like,
it seems like if you have resources and
you could get a plot of land and hire
people to take care of it and grow it
and have animals that you slaughter
there and have food that you grow.
They're like,
why wouldn't you do that?
Great.
If you could do that,
why wouldn't you do that?
Absolutely.
Really?
But,
you know,
it's like,
it drives me crazy to hear these people
say,
oh,
but look,
the biggest smiling and the pig is happy
and the pig is the pig.
Loves you.
And how are you going to kill that pig
and turn it into bacon?
I'm telling you,
the pig doesn't love me.
The pig,
the biggest pig and my doesn't know in
my.
I'm a lovable guy.
But uh,
you know,
I'd be honest with you.
I think we'll talk later.
A good way to look at man's thoughts
that some thoughts together.
Good way to look at it.
He's not going to live forever if you
don't kill that big,
so I got to turn into a fairy and cure
cancer.
It's a fucking pig.
They lived to be about 15.
Then they die when they die.
If you don't eat them before they die,
you lose all of delicious meat.
This pig,
the pigs that I have on my farm would
not exist unless we were going to eat
them.
That's the only by that logic.
We could make your own kids and start
eating them.
We weren't listening earlier.
I made kids because where I live at
goodchild.
See I made kids for the free labor.
See I've got.
Unlike steve,
I've got time and hell yeah,
it's about doing the chores and all this
stuff.
I don't want to do get out there and all
my yard to pull it up.
Three or you have three?
Yeah.
so you.
You don't have a.
You don't have a facility where you
would do this,
this or agriculture?
No,
no I don't,
but I would.
I would think about buying a piece of
land.
Just getting something positive.
Man.
It looks sweet because it'd be like
prominent podcast host,
comic actor in farmer.
I think it makes,
well I have chickens,
you know,
just just recently got chickens so that
I could eat their eggs.
But uh,
I've been thinking about this for a
while,
like everybody's worried about gmo foods
and everybody's worried about like,
you know,
monsanto when they're worrIed about
what's organic,
what's not organic and what are the
standards on grow your own shit.
You know exactly what it is and you can
take care of your soil.
Italy still Italy if you go through.
I took a train to Italy.
Trend for the north is trying to become
sophisticated.
Again.
This will read a story about when I went
to Italy.
For me,
I say I'm a.
Everybody in their backyard grows her
own food.
Like it's so common.
So my gRandpa,
the gardens man,
my grandfather did not have a big yard
in New Jersey,
but every part of the get we got coconut
water.
What do you want,
man?
I'll take coconut water.
You want a coffee?
You want?
You ever have bulletproof coffee?
Bulletproof coffee.
Do we have any roots?
To me,
yeah.
Bulletproof coffee.
Not just no mold.
we have any more trouble.
I don't want to try.
Not trouble.
We're here.
We're partying.
You want to be here in a Minute on beer?
I beg your pardon?
There's a couple of beers,
a jamie.
Bring out some beers,
man.
That's right.
Son dick.
What dig party in your mouth?
Dr a.
I forgot exacTly what we were talking
about.
Becoming a farmer.
The idea has been fucking around with me
for the past couple of months.
I didn't know you got cHickens,
man.
You could just have them read at your
house.
Yeah.
Built a chicken coop.
Do you have somebody taking care of it
or is it just real easy?
Like.
No,
it's not that hard.
I just,
I just built a planter.
I didn't.
My beard.
I had a planter built.
I just think it's a great idea and I
think that the idea of reliant on
somebody else for
your own food ultimately it's like,
why would you do that if you have the
resources yet,
you know,
and is there only one left?
Is that what is bring them all out?
Um,
the,
you know,
the idea that we,
we,
we all rely on supermarkets.
You knoW,
you look at what happened with hurricane
sandy,
New York,
I'd shut down.
I was talking to my buddy tommy.
he's like,
I had a drive hours just to be able to
use my cell phone.
Towers were down,
everything was down.
There's no power.
Everything was fucked.
And you know,
him talking about.
he's like,
dude,
that was scary as shit Man.
He goes,
because I realized like This whole thing
is like very fragile.
If you don't know where your food's
coming from.
He goes,
we went to the supermarket.
It was just insane.
It was just empty shelf after empty
shell.
People had just taken everything.
There was nothing left.
So there's not a supply.
Sam,
what about water?
Water reserves have underground tunnels
have nothing in my basement.
Now I'm getting to be like an old weird
man where I save 'em,
freeze dried food and stuff.
My base,
very smart,
but I still haven't done the water
things.
When you got to do,
I got to get,
you know,
our tech,
the farming deal home farming.
My brother,
he has those pack lIne was you've seen
those packs.
I love those things,
so he bought a 10 acre pasture,
like a very unpicked your ass just like
an irrigated pasture and realized his
llamas are just inhabit like a back
corner and when you use diddly of this
pasture,
so just because he's just a pragmatic
resourceful person and he thought it's
out there.
It's getting wet and growing grass.
So he started putting out lambs.
He put out goats now has got a calf out
there and this guy,
he hunts so much so he hunts off his own
neat and he eats the media hunts and he
just puts it out there and takes care of
it,
make sure it has water and then it gives
all that stuff to his friends who come
over and butcher the lands and take them
home and feed them to theIr kids.
It just kind of a sense of like if the
lands there,
you know what I mean?
It's like it's there.
It's been manipulated by man.
It's not that he's preserving some kind
of like prime evil ecosystem.
It's just an irrigated pasture of
alfalfa.
He's like,
why not have that be like have output.
It's just pleasant to look out my window
and be like,
it's producing,
producing,
but when you have,
when you have,
when you have an acre of land or
whatever that is and how he's growing
alfalfa,
is that all you need for the animal to
live?
Basically,
if you just put it out there and they
just live on that?
Well,
I'm delving into stuff I don't
understand now,
but I know that camper,
I speak to this better because that he's
got alfalfa,
but it's an old alfalfa field,
so I think people typically in some
areas I know replant alfalfa every seven
years because eventually the alfalfa
loses out to other plant species is my
understanding.
I don't know for sure that there's a lot
of animals.
If you go out and put them on just that.
I'm sure there's a lot of guys that know
a lot about this,
like cringing right now.
If you go and put my just alfalfa,
it's considered to be like a hot food
and they'll overeat
is too rich and it can damage themselves
if you put them out on just pure
alfalfa.
That's interesting because I read the
deer that eat out of alfalfa fields are
delicious.
That there they actually have like a
little more species can hack it by.
No,
I think that I've been told that i'M
horses.
Does any of this makes sense To you?
A little bit,
but I'm more pig and chicken as opposed
to a lamb and stuff.
Does that make sense?
With alfalfa making the deer tastes
better?
Yeah,
I think it was.
The deer is not going to just be eating
alfalfa either.
I mean the deer is going to be,
you know,
roman and getting a lot.
Of course.
How much land is a farmer?
Do you need to grow,
you know,
your own meat and your own vegetables?
Not much.
I mean really not much.
You could do it on.
So we've got 40 acres,
but right now we're only using about
four and we've got,
you know,
we've got our big garden,
we've got our chickens that are free
ranging,
we've got the pigs,
we're going to be getting some dairy,
goats and really like,
you know,
and really four acres is,
we don't even use all that space.
I mean they're spread out the picture
over here,
the chickens were over here,
uh,
you know,
the goats are out in another,
uh,
outer past where you guys could,
you guys could feed like 30 people or 40
acres or we're way more.
Yeah.
That's why,
you know,
eventually what we want to do is to get
into the business side of it and to
start selling some stuff.
And,
and,
and really even like some of the
vegetables,
uh,
you know,
I want to do a,
uh,
I'm gonna do a pickle company one day.
I want to start pixeling shit.
And you know,
what are your,
what are your pigs,
what do you feed your pigs?
So right now that's as whole human
asshole tsa workers.
Um,
We have pig feed right now that they
sound like big old dog food bags.
We're going to tractor supply and get 50
pound bags of pig feed.
They,
they,
they eat the roots anD the pig pen and
then we're going to,
uh,
we're about ready to move them out to a
bigger area that's going to be about an
acre and they'll,
they'll wander around,
they'll,
they'll eat,
you know,
a shitloaD.
When I was a kid who never stopped
when I was a kid and my stepdad was a,
he was in school and one of the
agriculture classes that he had to take
was like this co op farm that people in
the school all did together.
They had animals and they grew plants
and I mean it was like pretty like
involved thing.
And I remember even as a kid saying what
a cool idea.
The idea that they all like chip in
together.
Everybody does like a little piece of
something and everyone's sort of
communicates what's,
what needs to get done.
And if you think about that in a real
neighborhood man,
you could have as long as you had the
soil and as long as you had the
resources to get it started and then
make it so it's self sufficient.
If you had a sizable piece of land and
everybody sort of chipped in and you
grew livestock and you grew plants and
you know,
you fed them and everything like see it
seems like it would be so economically
manageable.
I mean like people would get all their
food.
Keep imagine if like we all got all our
food from like a lot down the corner
where we all knew that this goat had
beaten all these foods that we had given
it.
And you know,
you knew exactly where the tomato
came from because you put the seed in
the ground.
This is happening to the point where in
cities now they have flat bed trucks
that you can rent where you have a flat
bed truck.
They got a bunch of soil on that flatbed
truck.
They're also doing an unruly.
And so what people are doing is getting
timeshares and saying,
I want to buy a share of that flatbed
truck.
Flatbed truck comes out,
you garden it,
you take your vegetables for the day and
it moves on to the next house.
Also they're doing it with like.
There's a lot of roof space.
Like in China,
they built a whole city,
I guess where the rooms are basically
planters to grow the food for the city.
I just saw a story out of chicago where
they're using some of the old warehouses
and they're just turning them into
indoor farms.
You've seen those two cia workers whose
house got broken into and Kansas.
The fucking dea came in guns blazing
because they thought these people were
growing weed and it was former cia
agents and they were growing tomatoes
and vegetables in their basement.
THey had a whole hydroponic vegetables
systems set up with lights and.
Well they these assholes drive around
looking for a heat signature from your
home that shows that you're using some
extraordinary amount of light,
which mostly people using the to to grow
weed.
So they come in fucking guns out and you
know,
dea,
dogs and shit.
No pond.
It's too fucking former cia agents
going,
you crazy assholes.
The fuck is wrong with you.
How about you knock on the door.
I show you my badge and my fucking
tomatoes right now.
I want to,
I want to write.
I want you to a fucking search of the
guy who lives there.
Oh,
it said cia guy.
Let's fucking,
let's go arrest him and his wife.
They're probably selling weed.
Cia.
I make sense.
Yeah.
Yeah,
exactly.
Crazy fucks.
W we had this thing happen reasonably.
It was like this perfect,
uh,
a cohesion of hunting and farming where,
um,
we're down in Florida and we're hunting
turkeys on this guy's ranch and the guy
keeps coming in and getting this because
he wants us to go out at night
run hogs hound dogs
and what it is.
He's got a cattle ranch near okeechobee,
Florida and there's a,
I heard two figures,
55,000
or 45,000
acre nature preserve down there.
It has a lot of rare native birds on it.
And the nature preserves emo is they
just acquire agricultural land when it
comes up for sale and they take out the
dike systems and put it back into bird
habitat.
And it's funny because this guy actually
has sold this preserve some of his land
and he is putting his whole place into a
conservation easement so that at a time
he was like,
my whole place is going to be part of
that.
And he was,
he was actually glad about it.
He liked,
he liked the preserve but a big enemy of
the preserve as wild pigs,
which consumed a lot of ground nesting
shorebird x.
So they have a guy,
the preserve Is so tight,
so tightly administered that you can't
in most areas,
you can walk around in there.
okay.
And they haven't got a contract to kill
wild pigs.
So this guy has a contract where he's
supposed to kill x number of pIgs every
year.
He can't in any way keep up with them.
This guy that has his cattle ranch lakes
to hunt pigs and he would always go back
and hunt the,
the boundary between his ranch and the
preserve.
Because so many,
there's such a great influx of pigs
coming off the preserve at night,
coming down to his ranch to get into,
you know,
less utilized land and uh,
but it's dogs would chase them in.
The pigs have promptly run back into
that preserve where he can pursue him.
So he gets some hard proof fence and
builds a 400 acre enclosure,
a budding the preserve on the wall of
his fence that actually adjoins the
preserve he puts in trapdoors hinge
doors.
Okay.
So the pigs can come in and out and so
they can't go out.
No.
Well,
he,
he props the door open.
Okay.
Any kind of watches and he's always out
there checking for tracks and after
awhile you'll realize there's a lot of
pig traffic coming out of the preserve
onto his land.
Then what he'll dO,
he knows that they come out after dark,
they come onto his ranch and before
daybreak they drift back to the
preserve,
closes the door.
He goes out at four in the morning and
pop up shirts.
All those doors.
He's got these doors strung out and
strung out for like a mile every 10
yards.
Stick.
hold this thing down,
pulls all the sticks.
That's hIlarious.
And it cuts his dogs loose.
Oh my god.
So we go out with him and right away we
go out logs like pitbulls or pitbull
ask.
I'm not good enough for dogs but not
got.
He's got a bloodhound over brad pitt.
He's got trailers and catchers.
So different types of dogs.
His bloodhounds find them,
but they won't.
He don't like to let the bloodhounds
actually catch the pig is a pig.
In fact,
one of his dog that really tore up.
But uM,
then he puts a holding dog out.
Big pit bull like dog who secures To
pick the first pick we catch.
I mean just barely those argentino dogs
to Argentina and they use them as well
as american bulldogs to this guy.
The first one we get,
it's not even dark yet.
And he gets,
we get one.
It's a big boy and he's intact.
He's got his nut sack on him still.
And the guy that.
This one's not dogs usually pull off.
No,
I'm getting a little ahead of myself.
Just just hold that piece.
May hold up.
He's information from it.
Not for a moment.
John,
and he says this,
be any good to eat.
Like they're too lean.
They gotta let it testosterone.
They don't take good care of themselves
and he takes his pig and it's a big pig,
you know,
not big and not like the ones you see on
the internet,
but the size of 170 pound pig and he
puts in a trailer just to confine in
there.
We go out and hunt again and a violator
of the dogs bus this other pig out of,
uh,
out of a palm grove.
They call the hammock like an island of
palm trees out in tHe grasslands.
And they catch it in this pigs castrated
and a castrated like a bore that'S been
castrated as a barrel hog.
And the incision where they were,
the hog had been castrated is all healed
up.
And they told me that we,
when we catch a boar,
we always castrated and then turn it
back loose because two things happen.
One,
the pig won't procreate,
won't contribute to the problem that the
preserve is having the problem that he
has for pigs on his land route in his
area and it'll and it will do what he
says is take his mind off grass and put
it on,
know,
take his mind off ass and put it on the
grass and he says in 90 days that will
be fantastic eating and they'll have a
layer of fat on them.
So we cut the juggler on the castrated
pig and cut the meat and it smelled
great and was beautiful.
The next day we go out with the board we
caught and they take a knife and
castrate that bore and turn them out
knowing that sometime down the road
they'll be lucky and catch that bar
again and he'll be a barrel and then
he'll be good to eat.
So these boys,
these boys do this every year.
How do you secure a bor?
A powerful boars head?
Don't tell anyone dogs these dogs take
them guys are cattle ranchers.
These guys are cattle ranchers.
So they,
I mean it's a daily occurrence for them
to rassle like,
yeah,
one of the dog does it because he
grabbed by the ear,
grab about,
hadn't pinned them down.
Now the tracking dogs caught the pig and
the pig caught one of the tracking dogs
real good.
And he was going to take that dog to the
vet and I asked him,
I bet Your vet probably,
you know,
doesn't like you bring in dogs that
probably they may have gotten injured
and something that the vet might regard
as unnecessary or he goes,
yeah,
that's why I go to a vet who likes to
run pigs with his dog.
Well,
once he start realizing how many pigs
there are there,
especially Texas has millions oF feral
pests.
Millions,
they have a real millions,
millions.
They have a real problem.
Look,
I know you don't like that show pig,
man.
But the,
uh,
I like that.
I don't say that
there's just,
there's like there's a,
I haven't an intellectualized having an
aesthetic.
I haven't hunching aesthetic and an
approach to wildlife that,
that,
that I,
that I admire and that I tried to stand
by.
No,
I know you do.
We had long conversations about it.
So helicopter gunships or your.
There's not mid on it.
It's not really hunting.
I mean what they're doing is they're
getting away with being psychopaths and
if you haven't seen it,
brian,
pull it up.
It's eradication.
Pigman and ted nugent.
Shoot pigs from a helicopter on youtube.
The meat to the needy,
but look,
look.
And by the way,
it's a real fucking problem.
They really do have to eradicate these
populations of pigs.
They tear up.
I mean they show these crops that are
getting fucked up by these pigs in the
episode and I want to hog.
let's go hunting.
Can we do.
Is what I wanted to ask you.
What is the one with his nuts?
Tastes like?
You didn't tell us that we haven't
cooked yet.
We're cooking it on April 25th,
but it won't be as good.
You don't have to think.
No,
I'm sorry.
no,
we.
Okay.
On April 25th,
I'm cooking the castro the barrel hard
right now.
I have eaten boars with their nuts,
but I've never even a board that was
aged and as venerable is that one you
could tell that he was a very old battle
scarred bore and very lean and these
guys I'm going to have eaten and thought
it was okay.
And it might be that these guys have
very high expectations,
you know,
they pick on enough or they have a sense
of like what's best and not best the
same way that uh,
you might disregard a hotdog,
half a hot dog laying on the side of the
road,
but another person might be in a
situation where they really appreciate
that hot dog.
So for these guYs who hunt boar is a lot
like love to eat them.
They were like,
no.
And when I expressed interest in the
indian tact hog being like,
I don't care,
I want it.
They were so adamant that it wouldn't be
good that they were denying me getting
it like they didn't want.
And it wasn't because they were in love
with the pig.
They're like,
no,
we'll get you good and we'll get you to
go.
And that was no good for you.
Maybe that was their,
that was their take taking more.
I,
I tend to like leaner meat anyway.
I really.
But I will tell you this,
when they do an in and I have pretty and
I've done a few,
I've done a bit of picone and,
and they can get where they do have
quite an odor to them and this board
just stone dork,
you know,
but this comes from guy who will the
black bears that have been feeding on
salmon and what does that like dead
salmon.
It's like ryan's saying meat.
The meat tastes like rotten salmon.
yeah.
Because I'm telling you man,
like the fat is so the fat does carries.
There's a book on the side of the harold
mcgee's book on cooking science and lore
of the,
of cooking or science,
lower the kitchen.
He has an explanation there.
Why animal fat is such a reliable
indicator of what the animal's been up
to and I should read that on your own.
Yeah.
Refer your listeners to that rather than
try to explain it myself,
but you get on your show when you van
bear with that and eaten blue runner as
it's just like unbelievable and you can
just drink the fat.
You can melt the fat and drink and it
tastes good.
Now the fat on a salmon berry,
you really have to carefully,
and this is in the spring when they
haven't actually eaten a salmon in six
months or something yet.
The very carefully trim that fat away.
Then the flesh becomes more palatable,
but it's just like kind of atrocious.
And I got a friend of Montana,
he shot a bear over overwrought and
cowen time.
same thing.
He thought it was nearlY inevitable.
So what do you do when that,
when you have that situation,
do you continue to eat the animal jam
and respect?
Like if something.
If I'm eating meat,
that's great.
Okay.
Super high quality meat.
I cook it in a high quality way where I
do as little as possible.
I'll take a lot like,
you know,
we ate some pretty straight up meat when
we were out,
right?
Like just like me,
malicious to warm with salt on it,
you know,
so a good meal.
I'll do that if I get an animal that's
funky.
I and I killed it.
I killed a female pig one time.
That was probably one of the worst game
animals I've ever done.
A,
I'm just going to eat it.
Okay.
It's like for me,
any displeasure I experienced eating
off,
tasting flesh isn't as bad as the
displeasure that I would experience from
having killed a big game animal and not
consumed.
That's a very great statement.
So I'm going to eat it and then whether
I make pepperoni sticks,
if it's bad,
I make pepperoni sticks.
I eat thing,
you know?
And I haven't always done it.
Like I explained to you many times.
I used a lot of fur trapping,
sell animal furs,
but now at this point in my life and
like my relationship with the hunting,
now I,
you know,
like to eat what I hunt for,
to the point.
I mean we ate a coyote not long ago down
in Mexico.
How you're the only person on the
planet.
I did this.
What's great about the podcast,
and we had this weird as saying,
I killed people sometimes.
Oh my god,
why don't you eat a coyote?
That's great people.
So often I get it
asked like as the guide is eating stuff,
I get asked all the time like what is it
like to eat this,
eat that.
And I have field the question about
what's kyle's so many times that I
started to feel like it was
professional,
like malfeasance for me to not have a
good answer,
you know,
national malfeasance.
We've not have a good answer.
What a fucking coYote.
So it's like
as professional development I wanted to
know and we got a coyote and a.
So you have to eat the whole coyote now
in your mind you we ate like,
well there's a handful of us there and
we put the vast majority of that thing
down and
that has been burned the hair off.
Oh,
we burned all off it
and enroll enrolls.
Wow.
It was skin on what it tastes like.
Well I got a,
like the best description.
I steal this from my body ramey warrant.
I was homeless and ramey warrant tastes
that and this is the esoteric
comparison,
remy warren and tasted that.
He's a hunting guide and he said,
uh,
it tastes like overcooked diver.
No know you explained this to us on the
trip to die.
There's diver ducks and floaters that
with a call.
The other ones?
Yeah,
like
a,
like a non
a taxonomy would with docs.
It'd be like a puddle ducks and diver
ducks and,
or people call them dabbler duck.
So docs that don't go underwater to hunt
and the ducks that eat fish are the ones
who don't want divers eat a lot.
Divers eat a lot more animal matter and
diver ducks and puddle ducks eat a lot
more vegetation.
You that expression and overcooked
diver.
Doug totally made sense.
Folks on the subway right now going,
I don't know what.
Fuck this guy's a fucking over.
Could do that.
The next tiMe I eat something I don't
like.
I'm going To back man.
This tastes a lot like divert.
yeah.
You had a couple shots,
uh,
on the uh,
the,
the show at,
uh,
at pheasants too,
right?
We couldn't quite get it.
what do they call those?
Realize that some ducks are carnivorous.
I never thought carnivorous
and even some puddle ducks,
some puddle.
Dr dabber dogs eat a lot of plant
matter,
so of the puddle ducks,
one of the like one of the not great
tasting ones as a northern shoveler in
northern shovelers.
Eat a lot of animal matter,
but you can take the bag like the best
duck on the planet in my mind,
be like,
I love mallard ducks,
but if you get mallard ducks in
southeast Alaska,
like near my cabin,
you can barely eat those mallard ducks
because even though they're mallards and
in most areas they taste great and
southeast Alaska,
those mallards in the in the late summer
or just sitting there hammering
invertebrates,
so they're.
ThEy're hunting the tide line,
eating expose invertebrates up and down
there and to get those docs and it
tastes like kyle.
They're eating invertebrates,
meaning meaning a clam
little little insects and you know
people
who who don't understand modern methods
of farming and the way that animals are
fed and the foods that they're fed don't
understand the whole corn versus grass
fed debate.
It's becoming such become a,
we've talked about so many times in the
podcast that people like hashtag things
grass fed when it has nothing to do with
it.
They're just being silly,
you know,
but counselors are supposed to be
fucking grass and when you give a
counselor corn it,
the whole thing is,
it's like giving a person that corn,
right?
Like we get fat as fuck,
you know,
cows,
syrup and shit.
That's why they have four stomachs or
whatever it is to break down that grass.
Not only that,
I bet you the corn doesn't grow as good.
Magic mushrooms,
a batch of the corn poop.
I bet it's a fucking mess.
It's not grass pumped through the
stomach of a double annually.
Cow corn.
We're using big words.
You used to wear a poor fucker eating
corn grown abscesses in his body.
Have you ever seen that?
A food.
That's why they have to.
They grow their livers.
Abscess.
That's why they have to give them an
antibiotic.
Meanwhile,
goddamn,
it's delicious.
That's a problem.
It's so good.
A good ribeye,
a fatty corn fed rib eye.
Oh,
it's perfect.
Like when I'm feeling healthy and um,
I like grass fed,
sirloin,
lean,
you know,
but the best meat I've ever had in my
life was a grass fed with a corn fed rib
eye from whole foods.
And I cooked that and I'm telling you,
me and my buddy had it and it was,
it was just high.
I wasn't obviously,
I was sober.
I think the best meat I've ever eaten in
my life was two things.
One,
the liver and the heart of that,
that deer that we ate when we were
sitting there by a campfire chopping up
and we had to cut around the bullet
hole.
We were also angry though,
and we'd spent three days eating those
bad mountain bath doesn't adopt.
I'm telling you,
I thought that those mountain bags,
we're going to taste way worse than I
thought.
I thought they were delicious.
It's situational.
Yeah.
But it's not as good as the meat.
No.
We work with a guy.
We were a good guy.
And um,
he's like,
I don't care about food.
I just want to be full and then go do
what I want to do,
and so he's always talking about.
He's like,
yeah,
I'll be home and I'll be home and I'll
eat freeze dried food because it's just
more efficient for me.
I just want to be done and then go do
what I want to do.
Well,
I can understand being obsessed with
something else,
but you know,
you can enjoy food as well.
Yeah,
dumb.
Fuck jesus christ.
I like foods.
Awesome.
My buddies,
my buddies,
a stunt man,
it hit the back of his head in an
accident and he lost his sense of smell
and taste and he doesn't care that much
about food.
That dude probably eats ass like a
champion.
Can't seem to be the greatest ass eater,
the universe who's going to a big deal.
I know timmy burgeoning me broke one
time,
said to me,
he goes,
I said,
uh,
he sits on like,
I hate her ass.
And I kind of made a face.
He goes,
what's the matter?
You don't stick your telling them it
grows as you're going to get shit on
your tongue.
So fucking what?
I can't talk to you,
and he just walked away.
I never said anything.
All I did was make a little face.
He natural to make that face.
Unless you've had four jack and cokes
and been in that situation where you
really try to impress a girl.
We've all gotten in that sexual herzon
sun.
You're getting that frenzy where you're
like,
do you have that video of the ted nugent
pigman adventures?
Whether there's just like a 32nd.
Yeah,
that's fine.
Check this.
I want steve reno's take on this.
If you've never seen this before,
ted nugent and pigman are in a fucking
helicopter and the fucking crazy.
It's now legal to hunt in Texas from
helicopters.
It is one of the most entertaining
episodes of any television show I've
ever seen in my life,
is watching ted nugent and pigment take
out wild hogs from a fucking helicopter.
I'm like,
this is some shit that after the fall of
America,
a thousand years from now when they're
trying to decode our history,
they're going to watch that,
that thing.
Holy fuck.
They were flying in helicopters joking
around about head shots.
He killed it.
He killed 455 pigs that day.
No.
Yeah,
yeah.
Fifty five.
That's a lot of pigs.
Ted nugent killed Florida.
She from a helicopter or bill maher for
bill maher.
Bill maher's,
very frantic hunting.
Or he's in peta.
Bill maher.
Bill morrow supports peta,
which by the way,
kills more cats and dogs in anybody,
you know,
96 percent of the,
uh,
animals that come into the shelter.
I put them down,
which is,
you know,
I just don't even know what to say about
that.
That's like,
they get so crazy.
It's like,
when is it okay to kill and what was it
not okay to kill?
You're killing puppies and you're mad at
people that are killing deer and they're
eating them.
Like,
I am losing the script here because that
doesn't even make any fucking sense.
That's one of the craziest,
most ridiculously hypocritical they
never heard of him was what do you mean
drop when people go to [inaudible] and
say,
you know,
I've got a stray dog here.
I found,
you know,
my,
my puppy,
my dog just had puppies.
I don't know what to do with them.
I'll give them to the animal lovers at
peta.
These dogs die like most of them
they put down because they have to
because they don't have the resources to
take care of those dogs,
but that doesn't matter when you,
when you're looking at,
I don't care if you don't have the
resources.
You're killing puppies and cats.
Okay,
and by the way,
you try to keep it secret to you.
Don't go advertising and telling people,
hey,
listen,
if you don't come down and take these
things as pads,
we're going to kill them.
No,
you're doing it on the sneak tip and
people have to find out about it through
the internet and then on top of that,
you're criticizing people that are
hunting and feeding their family with
what they know to be a really healthy
animal.
Instead of this mystery fucking chain of
command that happens when you buy a
cheeseburger from burger king or
wherever with name your fast food joint.
Who knows what the fuck happened to that
cow before it was converted into
cheeseburgers?
You know,
you don't know a goddamn thing,
but the fact that they would go after
one while killing puppies and kittens,
that's,
that's insanity.
That's,
that is insanity.
You know,
a thing that rings false to me.
And,
and you know,
I'm walking on like I got,
I got,
I got to tread delicately here on the
issue of,
of,
of the helicopter thing.
Hm.
But
well no,
the awesomeness of it.
One thing that rings false to me though
is when
guys like when guys do so hard to cook,
it's like no matter what you think,
it's like dan,
if you do damned if you don't try to go
for it.
When someone does,
if someone goes out and shoots a bunch
of something because it's there,
they're overpopulated for a rancher.
It's like in some way you have to be
self honest to and acknowledge that
you're not just doing an altruistic act.
You know,
like I enjoy the hunt,
you know,
so when I have my body's ranch in
California,
I'm glad that he figures he has too many
pics because it allows me to go pig
hunting and I liked to go pig,
I like to
eat pigs,
but I would never like,
I don't then say to my wife,
I'm like,
ah,
I really don't want to do it,
but my body's in trouble.
He's got a lot of pigs and I'm going to
go out and as much as it's going to be a
drag I'm going to go out and help him
because we need to fight our way through
this pig problem and we all need to give
our share because if my buddy had called
me and said,
you know,
I got a real problem with my fences are
down.
Can you come out and spend a weekend
fixing all my fences?
That really is the problem I have right
now.
I'd be like,
no.
What are those pigs up to you having a
problem with them?
It's natural to.
First of all,
the hunting them is natural and the
dealing with the overpopulation is a
real issue for people that do have farms
and do have ranches like you got to deal
with that and to get bullshit to take,
to take crap from people that are
killing puppies and kittens like,
man,
we need to come to an understanding
here.
Here's the real issue.
It's not pizza.
It's not the problem of being ethical
towards animals.
It's crazy assholes that do illogical
shit and that's the problem with a lot
of animal activist.
That's the problem with a lot of people
that claim to love animals more than
they love people.
You're out of your mind.
If you love a dog more than you love
people,
you're out of your mind,
your body,
your mind you.
That's a one way relationship.
Jesus christ,
that thing doesn't talk to you about
stuff.
It doesn't challenge you on issues.
It doesn't tell you it loves you.
It doesn't help you grow.
It's goddamn dog and I love my dogs,
but you're crazy if you like animals
more than people and the people that are
involved on a,
just for whatever reason,
there's a certain percentage,
it's not all of them,
but a certain percentage of people that
are involved in animal rights movements
have a distorted perception of the
relationship between humans and animals
and their relationship is not one of
admiration and respect.
It becomes what you were talking about
though.
The anthropomorphic sort of a thing.
It's like it's bambi or it's like,
you know,
I saw someone who was talking about when
the mountain lion got shot in santa
monica,
you know,
they should fucking shoot people.
I'd be happier if some,
a person was shot and that mountain lion
like that was on the mountain lion in
fucking santa monica.
Man.
Santa monica is really urban.
Yeah.
Okay.
There's no parks,
there's no parks.
There's no giant places where there's
all trees.
There's no central park in santa monica.
Years ago,
few years ago there was a black bear in
bergen county,
New Jersey.
Do you remember that?
North jersey and same thing.
That's what joey diaz is,
you know,
you gotta,
you gotta black bear wandering around
hoboken,
hoboken.
Fuck.
Where are you from?
Oklahoma.
Jesus christ.
Sorry about that.
Might be for North Korea.
What is your background?
So infiltrated our defensive.
So here's,
here's my excuse for how I mispronounced
what does it?
Hoboken.
Hoboken,
hoboken says New York times.
So I've got a little bit of a,
of a,
a beef with hoboken because when I was a
kid I lived in ridgewood,
New Jersey for a year.
Ridgewood had a law on the books that
said you can actually not play video
games until you were 16 years old.
There was a ban on video games in
ridgewood,
New Jersey.
So as an eight year old in north jersey,
I had to go to hoboken to a diner to
play a german version of pac man.
So when I think of hoboken,
I don't really think of how to pronounce
it.
I just think of my,
my fond memories of a german version of
pac man with the name of the ghosts were
like,
you know,
18 characters long and you know,
so that's the thing.
I think diners,
I think black bears,
I think pac man think hoboken and joe
rogan will kick my ass if I ever missed.
So there's the issue,
there was a bear in that area
there.
There've been bear sightings in every
county in New Jersey,
every county in New Jersey.
And they just made bear hunting legal in
the last half a decade or so.
Right?
Yeah,
it was illegal for a long time.
They brought it back.
Um,
and then when a couple of years ago when
core zine was governor,
they put a stop to it again over the
objections of the wildlife commission.
They're in the state.
And how do you get wildlife commissions?
That's what drives me crazy.
How do you get wildlife commissions that
are run by people who are animal rights
activists and why does that happen?
And how is that possible that,
that happened?
You got it in California right now
because you know,
the governor,
uh,
points so many people and they're going
to have so many hunters and now they're
gonna bring a,
you know,
they're going to say,
well,
okay,
so the 100 is get a seat at the table,
but we also have to have the animal
rights activists have a seat at the
table too.
But the idea that they're trying to mean
an animal rights activist,
it's automatically going to be anti
hunting.
Right?
Absolutely.
It just doesn't make any sense that
someone could be in charge of wildlife
management.
It'd be anti hunting.
That sounds.
That's what that is,
is this convenient ignorance that a lot
of people that don't understand wildlife
have.
And I,
I didn't until I started getting into it
before I started paying attention,
whatever it was,
a decade started paying wildlife
management councils,
et cetera,
have done a pretty good job of doing
their job.
And I don't,
not in liberal states though.
The issue is when states,
like in California,
where they're making logical decisions
like the lack of dogs and black bear and
in a mountain lion hunts,
they're hard enough to fucking kill and
to control the population and especially
when you're dealing with predators,
like you have a responsibility as a
human being to keep the population in
control.
I'm not saying you should run them to
the point of extinction,
but you have.
I think every human in a community has
a,
if,
if possible to control predators.
You should.
There should.
There's a responsibility to keep a
certain,
a certain amount of control on the
situation and when you start doing shit
like saying,
well,
you can't hunting with dogs or you can't
do this or you can't do that,
you,
you what?
You should be.
What should be as.
How many numbers are they killing?
Okay.
And there's not a
lot of mountain lions getting killed.
It's not easy to do.
You know,
they're not in danger,
right?
No,
not dangerous anymore.
Right.
Now you're seeing an expansion and range
and it's different than what people
think because some of the states that
have the most heavy hunting for mountain
lions are actually turning out to be
areas that are population sources,
so there's a movement right now was just
reading this paper recently where they
were doing some work on lines and they
were thinking that with the abundance of
lions in California with the loss of
hound hunting that they would be seeing
californian lions going into phil
ecosystems vacated by harvested lines in
Nevada with their fine and instead is in
spite of all the basin and range country
in Nevada in spite of the hunting is
still able to produce lines and they're
seeing lions going in a different
direction.
They're seen lions going,
spreading out displaced young males
spreading out from Nevada into
California.
No,
it could be two things.
It could be somehow that their buddy
called him in from California and said,
dude,
come here.
They will not mess with you.
These people are soft.
I'd use dogs.
I don't know what it is,
but so much stuff
like there's always something that
violates all your expectations into the
answer.
Like do state fish and game agencies do
their job?
I have no one,
no one has complete faith in everything,
but in general I have a lot of faith in
state fish and game agencies and you
guys have all had the luxury,
like I have the travel around the world
a fair bit and I used to have this naive
idea that you'd go to a developing
nation and it would be that you'd
experienced this great abundance of
wildlife.
It's just in your mind.
It's like,
oh,
it's like back in time somehow.
You know,
I remember like the first time I went to
Philippines,
the Philippines do a magazine story.
I brought my snorkeling mask and I
thought it'd just be this explosion of
sea life,
you know,
but in fact it's not because they use
cyanide to fish on the reefs and they go
to a fish market there and the fisher
and inch long tops or they or it's
either there's a bunch of inch long fish
or they've just jogged into big whale
shark and they're hacking the department
machetes.
Okay.
So it's like the reality is is that the
us,
we have very progressive game management
and we have like a hundred base
management system in the us.
When you factor in how many people live
here,
where we're at in a technological sense
where we're at in an economic sense,
it almost doesn't make sense that we
have the wildlife we have,
we do a phenomenal job and there's a
richness of wildlife in the United
States of America that's unparalleled by
any country in a similar situation.
There's nothing to compare it to me.
Let me
pick it back and I don't want to
interrupt you,
but now you did the us.
The us also has been really responsible
for many,
many years.
Also,
and if you want to buy timber from say
Indonesia,
our rules and guidelines for how that
timber is harvested and where is
incredibly stringent.
It's countries like China and Japan that
are not responsible,
but keep going.
Sorry.
You're right.
You're absolutely right there and we've
had to use.
We've had used certain things to try to
control other countries.
Abuse on the high seas,
like we'll even go after people and be
like,
not only were you not by your fisheries,
but now we have the capability to
boycott your electronics.
Exactly.
If you're not going to get with the
program,
a high seas,
fisheries management in general in the
us,
I attribute it gives us a start
installing.
It starts selling a documentary,
but I'm saying that like the wildlife,
the north american wildlife conservation
model,
which is a model based on creating
abundance so that you can have a limited
sustainable harvest of resources has
proven to be the best system and it's
not even debatable
and people don't understand that when
they're in urban areas and they become
animal rights activists.
They talk about how much they love
animals.
They don't understand things like
keeping deer population down so you
don't die in car accidents because they
don't have natural predators unless
you're going to go fucking like what
they're doing with wolves and
reintroduce wolves and deer and
ecosystem,
and then what happens?
What are you gonna control the wolves?
Well,
they're not funding research,
right?
Like a guy that wants and he buys
firearms and ammunition,
which has a federal law which has
essentially a self imposed excise tax.
It was voted in by sportsman.
They have cell phones pose,
excise tax,
where money goes to the federal
government.
It's a percentage that goes to the
federal government that purchase.
It's earmarked for wildlife
conservation,
so you're talking about enforcement of
laws,
which I think peter would agree with
greatly that someone needs to enforce
these laws.
That's how.
That's how we're funding that.
In forest went hunting,
license sales and pittman robertson act
funds.
Also buying a hunting license goes to
create state fish and game agencies.
Many of these agencies are self
sustaining.
They don't get any tax payer funding.
Their funding comes through fees and
licenses and they do wildlife research.
Pete is not funding wildlife research,
you know,
it's like they're just making noise,
but like the conversation so often comes
down to peter,
but peter has become a joke.
I mean when peta makes the news,
it's always like one of those guys up to
now is always the tone out.
I don't think that taken seriously.
I don't think the animal right now,
I don't think that people who self
identify as animal rights advocates are
actually dangerous.
Right?
They're not significant.
I want to disagree with you.
If we can snuggle and share a
microphone.
There we go
because I think that peta is the clown
shoes of the animal rights movement,
but they're there in a way to be a
distraction for like the hsus is of the
world he made.
He made to the United States and
everyone thinks that the humane society
is your local dog and cat shelter.
Right.
But nationally,
hsus,
the society of the United States doesn't
really fund your local animal shelter.
They try to raise money off of you
thinking that they fund your local
animal shelter,
but instead they're the.
They're the non clown shoes.
Animal rights group,
they're the suit and tie in lobbying.
Go to politicians,
they know how to raise money,
they know how to be effective.
Talking to politicians in banning
certain types of hunting.
And pete is there.
I think really just be that sort of
distraction,
you know?
Oh look,
it's the chicks who were getting taken
and tigers.
It's the people who are wearing like the
little lettuce bikinis,
but michael,
mark,
harry and,
or wayne pacelli at,
uh,
at hsus.
Their goals the same.
I mean,
wayne pacelle,
you said we want to see a day when there
is no hunting in this country.
Why do you need to hunt anymore?
You can go to the grocery store and you
can get your corn fed.
That's what's really insane is that
someone would want to take away your
ability to acquire,
meet your way.
That somehow or another it would be good
to only be able to get your meat from
farmer.
I think they want.
I don't even think that I want to get to
a day where we're growing meat and
laboratories and we've got,
we've got our test tube van.
I think you're right,
but I think they don't understand that
be this insane imbalance in the
ecosystem that would probably lead to
the,
the rise of predators and not to mention
the loss of humanity.
I mean,
you know,
there is something innately human about
taking your food.
Then I think we would lose if we grew
our food and in the laboratory.
Your definition of human is what they
want to change.
I think what they want to change is they
want us to evolve.
It's this need to be reliant upon our
primal instincts and my,
my thinking,
my thinking on that as always,
I understand the idealistic or utopian
sort of pull in that direction,
but there's also a reality about the
time that we live in.
Although we can see like a bright future
where we become beings of light who can
read each other's minds and you know,
the internet is used to travel on,
you know,
maybe that's the future.
Maybe that's a million years from now,
whatever the fuck it is.
But reality is right now.
Animals don't live forever and they're
delicious.
When you eat them and you guys are
getting crazy,
okay,
you're not going to live forever.
Neither that deer,
neither is that cow like this is nuts.
Like the idea that you shouldn't torture
them a 100 percent.
I'm with you.
The the idea that you shouldn't
psychologically damaged them by leaving
them in cages their whole life.
Then finally shooting them and eating
them and yeah,
there's a lot of bad karma that
wouldn't.
That would make me think that the people
that would be the real animal activists
would be the ones that want to encourage
the,
the natural food chain,
like you're not going to stop people
from eating meat.
You're just not.
It's too.
We like it too much.
There's too much scientific evidence
that there's benefits through
cholesterol is for brain function,
inflammation and there's a lot of
benefits of eating meat and vegans don't
want to believe that because a lot of
vegans what their.
What their thing is is that they used to
have an unbelievably shitty diet.
They used to eat fucking bullshit and
cheeseburgers,
shitty food and blah blah,
blah,
but now that they're eating vegan,
they feel so much better.
Oh my god,
and now they're like these proselytizing
for the vegan religion and they're going
around telling everybody how amazing it
is,
how amazing they feel to be vegan,
but I'm like,
I understand you're right.
There's a lot of great nutrients in
vegetables,
but end meet.
There's a lot of good in that too,
and I'm a person who never did like eat
their body away.
I never did eat shit food all the time.
I understand that the direct correlation
between nutritional supplementation,
eating healthy vegetables,
eating good,
lean meat and feeling better and your
body actually performing,
especially in something like really
intense when you.
When you get into like jujitsu,
any kind of martial art,
the stakes of you being good or bad or
you getting your ass kicked and that's a
terrible feeling that every man wants to
avoid and you understand what's working,
what's not working.
Pragmatism comes into play when you're
involved in anything,
any competitive athletic,
especially combat sports like you better
eat the right shit,
you better take your fucking vital
because if you don't,
it's a difference between you just
barely getting out of a submission and
getting to a dominant position and
winning or you tap again.
Right?
I mean it literally.
Sometimes it's that close.
It's a Few beats of a heart.
it's,
it's whether or not you have just that
extra push of oxygen in your,
in your body.
People that do that,
they like me.
Most of them,
you know,
they,
you know.
Not only that but it's life.
You know,
if you look at nature,
that's such a classic and stark example
of how life eats life.
That's always been life eats life by the
way,
whether or not you're eating animals,
you're still kivit telling,
living thing.
This is the
thing I've always wondered about and
actually maybe like I'm relying on the
expertise of your viewers and this isn't
something that.
This isn't a question that they'd be
able to answer through a format.
Like twitter will take like a lengthy
email.
if someone knows and whenever I have you
do,
don't give out your email right now,
they're,
it's going to go to you and then you're
going to send it to me if it's good,
but whenever I ask this,
people think I'm being like that.
I'm trying to demonstrate absurdity by
being absurd,
but it really is something I wonder
about and I'm sure there's a great
answer for it.
In the,
in the mindset of a of a,
of a diehard animal rights person who
feels that human life is equal to animal
life.
What do they propose we should do?
Like once we conquer the problem of
humans consuming animals,
human induced animal suffering,
what do they propose is gonna look like?
What will it do with control?
No.
What will they do with the bottle?
Nose.
Dolphin.
Like how will it be that he is forced to
stop consuming fish and I'm not trying
to be like a smart ass.
Like what will,
what will you do to get coyotes?
If life is life is life okay?
When will they be offended by the
actions of a coyote who's killing things
to survive?
I know it's like he has to,
but really if you caught them all in
separate and you'd be
able to feed them a good question.
I'm not trying to be as smart as like
what is the answer?
I think they make a very distinct
difference,
a big difference between humans and
animals right now as far as they're
concerned,
there is a big difference because human
beings have a choice.
Our choice could.
We could be herbivores and exclusivelY
herbivores and according to them,
even healthier than meat eaters,
which I disagree with.
I think everybody and I read the China
study,
everybody you know,
but it's like I'm a.
I didn't read the whole thing by the
way.
I sure did.
No,
you didn't read that whole thing.
Faculty chapter eight is the best part.
In fact,
is that where pinocchio gets us out of
the whales?
All you have to do is read the end
actually because he talks about how how
the,
how industry hijacks the sort of the
high jacks,
government agencies like the school
lunch program and what the military
feeds his soldiers into buying their
food scientists.
TheY stacked the deck and get scientists
to say that 25 percent of your fucking
diet can be simple sugars because
there's a lot of money and high fructose
corn syrup and for the corn refiners,
et cetera.
It's a very,
very amazing though people don't
understand like how that happened,
how all the sudden like the government,
it gives farmers money to subsidies on
corn,
like to encourage the growth of corn and
it's not just.
It's not family farms.
Remember everybody,
it's huge industrial farms.
They get the bulk of the balkans somehow
know that they watched each other's
hands and figure out how to slap each
other in the back and stack the deck.
I mean the t dot collin campbell does a.
He was a scientist on one of these
boards.
They do a.
He does a very good job as a scientist
who is involved in the stuff and he
names names because he's friends with
these guys who are on nestle and coca
cola is boards who say,
guess what,
soda?
High fructose corn syrup has nothing to
do with obesity.
You can eat as much as you want.
In fact,
25 percent of your the food and
nutrition board that sets the standard
for the school lunch program and
mothers,
mothers with dependent children,
etc.
You can eat 25 percent.
Twenty five percent of your diet can be,
can be a simple sugars.
Go ahead.
Listen to what monsanto was done at.
Monsanto has bought up a company that
was the leading company on be research
because those are the people that said
that monsanto's pesticides and all the
shit that's in their food is a causing b
populations to decline,
so monsanto buys them.
Then monsanto develops a fucking robot.
Be okay.
I thought I joked around about it in my
act.
I said that bs as such country animals,
I hope that we make solar powered robot
bees that fueled themselves by.
They have dicks.
They're actually vacuum cleaners and
they just fuck real beat to death and
suck the life out and burn inside the
combustion engine and I was just joking
around.
I mean anything anybody would actually
make a robot be.
But I was like,
how tough is it to pollinate a fucking
plant?
They didn't even know they're doing it.
They're doing it.
I mean santa stealing your material this
past.
Well,
they thought about it like.
I bet they thought about it before me
problems,
but it takes a long time to develop a
fucking drove.
But they have a robot be monsanto has
fucking robot beat.
Yeah,
they're,
they're the.
Pulled up a picture of it.
Pull up a picture with someone.
Monsanto,
robot b is in the news today.
Along with that fucking explosion in
boston.
Is there any new evidence on that or
what's going on?
We should probably know.
Huh?
Let's see.
Kid guide.
A eight year old kid.
Really?
Do they know it was it?
Was it like a sophisticated form?
it's.
I think it's a,
it looks like it's a fire and it looks
like there was ball bearings in it,
so it looks like it's probably just one
of those ones you can find out online,
like a doMestic produced.
Unbelievably horrific.
This is 741.
People have been injured a 144.
At least 37 of orally 17 rather are a
critical injuries.
Dr sara pulling ball bearings out of
people.
Yeah.
Oh my god.
Now monsanto,
monsanto,
robot be.
No,
that scares me.
They're going to come up with wasps that
can distinguish that thing.
That's the one with the quarter.
The one right next to it with the
quarter.
Look at that.
That's the one up in The upper right.
That one right there.
Look at that.
Look at that fucking thing.
That is monsanto's robot b and that
thing is going to have the same function
that had actual ob does like there'll be
able to get them to fly back and forth
and pollinate plants.
oh yeah,
we killed off the bees.
Don't worry.
We got terminator bees tHat we developed
specifically.
It's like,
don't sweat it.
Dude,
in my,
the way Montana will probably,
monsanto rather owns the copyright on
the east and nobody else can make their
own robot.
Bees are going to have to buy robot
beach,
monsanto and like a real baby.
They only last like a week.
There was a,
um,
in the 18 hundreds there was this,
uh,
there was uh,
my mind is escaping was the guy who
started the one who studies plants,
herb there,
there's a botanist who was her
biologist.
Botanist was making.
I was making like an exploration of the
american west and he was talking about
and he wrote for awhile about the
advance of,
of the honeybee.
Know the honeybee is not a native,
not native to this continent.
Really?
Yeah.
He's talking about the advance of the
advance of honeybees across the,
across the continent.
Come on,
chips.
People brought it up.
They brought it on purpose.
Yeah.
Like I'm,
again,
I'm escaping like,
not an aviary but a ap or people brought
them for honey production and they went
feral very successfully and he was in,
in this bondness describes and he made
his trip,
like if some,
you know,
I remember he made his trip and 1811
because his getting home was interrupted
by the war of 18,
12 and he was on the Missouri when the,
um,
when that great earthquake,
the earthquake struck,
that actually switched the direction of
the mississippi's flow.
Whoa.
Uh,
he was there and then it got delayed by
the war.
18,
12.
But anyways,
shit luck,
you know,
he had this guy,
this guy had bradbury.
Bradbury was his name,
like the novelist,
his name is brad bird.
He had amazingly bad luck.
He thought he's Just going on a little
trip and it took them seven years to get
home and all the material,
all the material,
the bradbury,
all the material.
He gathered all the plant specImens he
took,
he got done and he wanted to take a
different route home.
So he sent his assistant.
Homewood is stuff,
right?
But it's assistant gets home years
earlier and by the time this dude makes
it back home,
assistant has published all the material
under his own name.
But anyways,
in this book he has this really
interesting,
that's really interesting passage about
how fast bees are advancing and how they
always keep pace.
They're always out ahead of the
frontier.
So at the time when he was writing,
he was talking about like the be
somewhere in North Dakota or whatever,
be saying like reliably,
you know,
we were in st louis in a,
in a strong way and bs or 40 miles out
and they'll bs will continue to march
across.
That's what I like.
Colony collapse disorder is interesting
is it is.
I don't think of it as a wildlife issue.
I think of it as an agricultural issue,
right?
Because I'm not naturally as a non
native species,
it's a,
it's an agricultural problem and it's a
saturday or cultural problem.
But I don't.
when I think of like wildlife politics
and the wellbeing of american wildlife,
which I have a vested interest in,
like I don't look at colony collapse
disorder as it's a serious economic
problem.
So there's that.
These animals are these bees rather if
they didn't exist,
if they hadn't been introduced here,
would agriculture be drastically
different?
Yeah,
I would say so because they're able to
use them in such a targeted like,
you know,
a guy that raises bees is doing two
things,
is producing honey and he's providing
pollination services.
So they do these things in tAndem.
You know,
when I was a,
when I was in college I worked for a
beekeeper and he would all the while
he's collecting honeycomb,
but at the same time he's moving stuff
around.
So at the beginning of the year he's
done.
He'd go down to Georgia,
he truck is bees down to george and he
do pollination services down there and I
think that it's just a way that you can
do like very targeted,
very fast synchronized pollination of
plant species that if you were relying
on native species of bees and moths and
butterflies that I gathered would take
much longer.
What are the native ones as opposed to
the.
The honeybees are not native.
Honeybees are not native.
So the north american indians,
they never got any honey.
But when we came along.
Okay.
Psych.
I think that the honeybee produces like
a high,
like good quantities of a high quality
honey.
There are similar products produced,
there are similar things produced about
other things,
but it's kind of like the reason that
goat's milk isn't really
a big,
strong product,
but cows can crank it out,
you know?
And so in that way they were brought for
that purpose.
But there are many poLlinating insects
that were native to the us.
But like the specific honeybee is,
we know it wAs introduced species.
Were they here?
I don't know,
but I would.
I'm sure they were.
I like to be the son of a bitch.
You introduce wasps to the United States
who brought,
who decided,
you know what bees they make honey,
I think.
Let's see what happens.
We bring wasps over here.
That guy from animal planet.
Screw that guy.
He had a short lived show on animal
planet and it was,
he was an entomologist and he was a
really weird dude.
And he goes,
he goes,
look at this.
And he had this huge spider and he goes,
watch this.
And he put it in his mouth and then they
pulled it out.
Was this huge transplant?
He goes,
now I won't bite me because I'm not a
moth.
If I was a moth that would bite me,
but I'm a human so it doesn't know the
difference.
I'm like,
all right,
if some filipino thing.
Right.
So I said,
I said that his claim to fame is he had
been stung by every,
every insect.
And I said,
there is some,
uh,
there are some wasp out there that can
hurt you.
And he said,
oh yes.
Oh yeah.
And I said,
like,
what?
He goes,
well,
the tarantula hawk or the 24 hour and
that you find that Panama,
if they sting you,
you'll fall to the ground and scream for
hours and hours.
He goes,
they call it the 24:00
AM because when you do get stung,
you can't sleep.
You can't drink,
you can eat for 24 hours.
The pain is so intense.
I said,
what was the pain like?
Is I liken it to getting your hand
slammed in a car door and being shot
with a 45 at the same tie.
He was this really weird guy.
I was like,
well,
I'll be staying away from the tarantula
hawk,
which is indigenous to this area in
Nevada.
Whenever you talk about any of that
really evil fucking bugs in the soil,
the shit out that's really.
That really drives me nuts about animal
rights activists because those are
animals too.
Okay.
This is a whole broad ecosystem and a
lot of these things that are out there,
we can't live with them.
If we live with them,
they kill us.
Like,
do you understand that there's ants in
africa that kill elephants?
They climb up in elephant's leg and they
go right through the fucking ear and
they start eating.
The elephant is actually your first
fuck.
Yeah,
that's true.
That's kind of find them and then they
communicate with this with the other
aunts and they're evil colony and they
find this poor fucking outfit and they
climb up and they eat him ears first.
Did you.
You must have,
if you're competing because you know
this guy is my boys in san antonio who
made this big promotional video for me
that said no cons.
Coming to brian,
that squad,
you kind of hit show no cons,
please.
Is that from you?
Is that you're a.
I mean,
I think that's the number one problem
with human beings.
The number one problem,
if we eliminated all kinds males,
by the way,
there's a transient hawks.
We show them that show.
How about that?
You want to get that motherfucker.
TheY actually catch tranche though.
Oh,
they do come home,
man.
What a monster.
Flying monster.
I'm peeing out of my dick.
I'm like pointed.
Go ahead.
My point is that if we eliminated that
from the world,
it was just an era and everyone left had
to figure things out.
I think magically 99 percent of the
world's problems would immediately be
eradicated.
I really do believe that.
I think most of the world's problems,
whether it's crazy out of control
bankers that are fucking stealing
resources and robbing the country blind
or whether it's evil corrupt politicians
or whether it's you know,
whatever it is,
you get caught,
all the county human beings out of that
equation and new resolutions
automatically begin to show themselves
and people automatically begin to try to
find ways to work together and stop a
environmental devastation and figure out
how to be profitable while still being
ethical.
It's an issue.
We have like this huge civilization
issue that's really a contest shoe,
but if you ask them all the line up,
you won't have people who self identify.
Of course not.
So you need a really good court system
or mushrooms.
Mushrooms would help.
You know when people need to do is that
your ego can convince you from some
pretty horrible shit because we're in
this.
We're,
we're sort of a species that's in a
stage.
We're in a stage of not quite being
animals,
being self aware,
having the ability to communicate,
but not really being completely,
fully,
wholly enlightened,
and there's a lot of things that slow us
down along that way to being completely
wholly enlightened and enjoying this
experience as brothers and sisters.
And the problem is people that don't get
life right,
whether it's genetic or whether it's
behavioral because of their environment
and the conditioning that theY
experienced growing up.
Whatever it is,
those people that don't quite get life
right and they're just fucking insulting
and stupid and annoying and constantly
creating their own issue is constantly
causing problems so that they have some
sort of motivation to get through their
daily day.
That's,
that's a big percentage of human beings.
It's a complex organism that doesn't
come with a direction manual,
so a lot of people fuck it up and You
develop from the ground up and you do a
shit job and it's addicted to drugs and
it's stopping that with these drugs and
you're filling these holes and you're.
You're cutting up.
You got to have something that allows
you to see if it's possible.
Some people,
it's not possible.
Some people are so psychologically
damaged by the time they've come in
adult.
There's almost nothing you can do for
them,
but if someone did have enough sense to
just stand back and look at their life
as if they were trying to give
themselves advice,
like if you.
If you.
How would you give yourself advice?
Have you met you and you saw your
issues?
What would you say?
If I give myself advice,
it's a great move.
You know,
that's,
you know,
I think it comes from a move.
I think some of it comes also from.
There's something that a human being
like,
like somebody wants that the scientists
were saying,
if you got rid of all the ants on
planet,
the earth
would last five years.
In other words,
all the other animals would die in five
years for a whole bunch of reasons
because it's part of the ecosystem.
If you got rid of all humans,
animals and everything else would be
just fine.
It would flourish.
Now,
that is an interesting thing to say.
I thought about that because I thought
the,
a lot of people when you couch it in
those terms,
and I think as a human being,
you kind of grew up knowing in some ways
that we are somehow a burden to the
ecosystem,
you know,
we are a burden to this world,
the natural world,
and it's something we have to steward
properly.
That kind of.
There's a built in sense as a human
being that in some ways you are a bit of
an intruder and interruption and a and a
burden to that which is life sustaining.
I always think even now that's so
personal,
man.
I don't agree with that.
Not saying that I agree.
I'm just saying I think that is part of
the human psyche and always has been.
I think so.
I think especially,
I think that's where conservation
movements and speed and things come from
as well.
I disagree with you to pull yourself out
of the hole.
Did you hear about this?
The newton,
uh,
families from the,
the victims of the school shooting?
Yeah.
Uh,
we're in the last mile of the,
uh,
it was dedicated to the last mile was
dedicated to them,
so that's where they were all sitting
and that's where all the bombs went off.
No.
Yeah,
so that's a conspiracy going on one of
those individuals,
um,
in june.
Well,
I'm not sure because they're not saying
who's been there,
just they haven't suffered enough.
Man.
I got kids that age.
Yeah.
And that's something that,
uh,
I guess that would have been public
information.
Oh yeah.
Where those people were.
Yeah,
because they,
I guess they,
they,
it actually,
there's,
there's a,
I'm trying to find a video or a photo of
it,
but there's actually people taking
photos in front of it,
like the families and stuff like that
before it happened.
So weird.
Oh,
here we go.
Yeah,
check this out.
Uh,
it's on hollywood life.com.
And like there's a photos.
Have them sitting right there,
the last mile.
That's crazy.
I just got to say,
that was one of the most satisfied
pisses I've ever had my life.
Congratulations my friend.
Something about taking leaks.
What is that?
The school shooters were sitting in the
last mile of the boston marathon from
newton.
Oh my god.
Yeah.
And so did they get hurt?
Probably,
but they haven't said he's gotten hurt
though.
So that's what they were.
Ah,
something soccer.
What the fuck?
This whole thing is terrifying.
Cnn.
Don't go to cnn.
Fox don't,
don't,
don't even go look at the front page.
It's horrific blood everywhere.
It's of problem.
It's a con providence current problem.
That's,
I mean there's obviously that
simplifying things to the extreme.
Don't send me twitter messages.
I know what I'm doing.
I know what you're saying.
You're absolutely right.
I agree with you,
but that's obviously missing the point.
You know,
you know,
human human beings,
man is capable of amazing shit.
You know,
I've definitely said that like we could
figure out how to get people to everyone
get their shit together and that's the
bipolar rape.
We are the most bipolar rape.
Yeah.
But I don't think it's.
I don't think it's important.
I mean,
I don't think it's necessary for our
survival.
I don't think we have to be shitty to,
to in order to move forward.
I agree.
I think that's the right date.
Didn't have technology.
I think that's the case.
You know,
it's like the when one of the things
that I put in it puts it into
perspective that a couple of thousand
years ago if someone showed up on your
shore,
those fucking people were dangerous and
you had to kill them.
We're probably going to get raped and
pillaged and sold into slavery and now
you welcomed them as an important part
of the tourism industry.
You know,
that's a completely new development in
human history.
have fucking rosetta stone so you can
figure out what the hell they were
saying.
It's so true,
man,
that's so much of the world and up until
literally 300 years ago,
less less,
what am I talking about?
One hundred 50 years ago was in
servitude of some kind and usually a
form of slavery.
Well,
what's really trippy,
it's to see North Korea still rocking
it.
old school today,
still rocking a full.
I can't figure out what's going to
happen.
I mean like in some way,
in some way it seems that the state
department and in the military is like,
oh my,
like what do you do with these guys?
And their hand.
Then the other half of it seems like a
car,
like,
seriously,
I can't tell it.
Is it not serious or serious?
Well,
it's blessed.
Flustered.
North korea's always busted.
However,
the problem is this kid is
29,
maybe 30.
They don't know a lot about them and
they're not talking about the ruler of
North Korea,
the sun john il now or whatever.
I think his name is.
They don't.
Yeah.
They don't know enough about him.
And uh,
it used to be his father.
There was a method to his father's
madness.
He would create a lot of heat to get
wrinkled,
negotiating.
Tam will get more aid or whatever.
And this kid is,
they think probably rattling his sword
to get the respect of the ancient
generals that actually run that fucking
country.
We need to bring dennis and back.
You're right.
And I'm glad you brought that up and
bring that into a sentence.
That is.
What did you think of North Korea when
you have desk robin and your counsel,
why does it need bring dad's broadman in
and with the United States,
like hook it up and just provide him
with,
you know,
a thousand korean chicks and just let
him run it when we need him in that gene
pool.
Anyway,
yoU imagine if the north koreans love
Dennis Robbins,
so much so that they let him become the
king and then somehow or other,
in some strange world,
he goes over there and then all of a
sudden he starts giving press
conferences
that dennis rodman is now running North
Korea,
North Korea.
Listen man,
it's not outside the realm of
possibility.
How many steps removed from that?
Is arnold schwarzenegger running
California?
How many steps removed?
It's only a few.
A few chapters of ridiculous parody that
Minnesota had a toy governor for a
while.
I was on a navy seal and I know about
chem trails on thermite.
He can't say he was a pro wrestler.
Yes,
he was a navy seal medic.
And uh,
you know,
a huge man.
The conspiracy theorists to the extreme.
Yeah,
he's got that show called conspiracy
theory,
right?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
It's always looking for thermite does.
Does the.
Does the leader kim il young on name,
is that correct?
Laura was so.
It's so american and not be able to show
moon.
Kim.
Kim jong.
Does he have.
Does he have the legal authority or what
passes for legal authority to commit
forces the same way that like the us
president can commit forces for 60 or 70
days.
They declared war on North Korea.
South Korea though.
Well,
he's essentially a dictatorial were
never actually ended up in a ball.
Has been in the state of what was
essentially a dictator.
Right.
so I mean,
yeah,
but he liked.
I liked the iranian president who is now
really like a very different.
He's like a god.
I mean he's a.
He's a godhead of.
He's a religious.
He's a religious figure.
they,
the north koreans are,
have been indoctrinated.
For example,
every north korean home,
from what I understand,
has a speaker and when he,
when the dear leader would speak,
you had to,
it would blast in your home and you had
to memorize that speech.
Oh jesus,
man,
if I had one of those and I can make
everybody do that,
what would just be to be around.
Although I think of something good
though,
man.
It's like,
what would you say if you could say so
over cook diver?
Dark people will be like,
what the fuck is our dear leader talking
about overcooked divert.
That is people.
Sugar's bad.
Total.
So social problem.
I know there's cupcakes aren't good for
you,
but god damnit.
Here's what we gotta eat enough.
Good food that you could do this.
So that's the balance to life.
Balanced life is pell shakes and
cupcakes.
Yep.
You got to be able to work them all
together in a tee shirt.
Kale shakes and cupcakes.
It was important.
Been delicious.
Food.
Passion will wine.
I love wine.
What's important?
Hey,
we gotta drink some good wine.
Pay since you're richer than I.
I'll do it.
I don't give a fuck,
I love going.
Rogue is the greatest.
We've go to dinner one time and this and
I and I was like,
I had been reading about wine,
so I looked at the list and I was like,
I'm going to choose.
I guess we'll get the right bank board
doe here and now I'm asking questions
and rubbing the,
hey,
fuck face.
Let me show you the joe rogan way of
ordering
wine.
He goes,
oh,
that's expensive as shit.
We'll get that one.
You're ruining everything.
I'm trying to impress people.
I'm like,
no,
brian.
We like pretend to understand.
See,
one of the reasons why I have very
little tolerance with you when it comes
to that is that I have my other good
friend,
matt and lichtenberg,
who's a huge one fanatic and legit think
I has a fucking crazy wine cellar
temperature control.
That's how ancient wines and shit and
all these important ones and that
motherfucker knows why you don't know
what you're talking.
Shit.
I called matt up.
I can call matt up and go,
hey matt.
I go,
uh,
this is my choices.
You know,
a bordeaux from blah blah blah,
or a bubba bubba and he'll tell you
about Oregon in 2007 is this shit.
If you can get a pino from Oregon for
2007 and it's this particular vineyard,
he just knows.
He knows he's a,
he's a legit wine kind of.
I went to his birthday party and they
had this really nutty dinner where they
gave what they call flights of wine.
That stuff.
Yeah,
and they were all like drinking it and
describing the earthy tones.
And this one is oak and this one.
That's my favorite thing to do.
I'll do that all day.
I will.
What I will do,
I'll sit there and I love.
Pretend I.
I love it.
I'll wear it.
I'll wear a tweed jacket.
I'll wear a scarf.
You wear.
I would definitely wear a scarf.
Yeah.
When I'm bringing up is the vertical.
there's a vertical and the horizontal
flight,
right?
I don't know.
Vertical flight would be a horizontal
flight would be where you take a year
and you go into like all the,
like all the great bordeauxs and you get
their bordeaux from that year is a
horizontal flight,
a vertical flight is you take a specific
vineyard and you collect all the years
from that specific vineyard,
so you might host a vertical and it's
like chateau whatever,
19,
20 to 1945 and you're going to taste a
25 year span out of that.
Wow.
Right now I'm in the reason I know this
and I want to do a shameless plug.
My buddy ben wallace has this great
book,
the billionaire's vinegar and it's about
the most expensive bottle of wine ever
sold,
but like what is good wine?
Do we know good wine when we taste?
It's fascinating.
Well,
if you get really old shit,
most likely it's not good anymore.
Right.
The problem is as his book explains is
the problem is no one.
This is a bottle.
The most immense bottled wine ever sold.
Why don't be in fraudulent,
but it was purported to be owned by
Thomas Jefferson.
Okay.
So for like steve forbes zoned it for
awhile and all these different guys on
this bottle of wine,
one of the koch brothers don't want it
for a while and in the end there's no
one around who can go.
I've had a lot of wine from that year,
right?
That's right on the money.
It isn't it crazy though that these
different rich guys had the wine and
sold it to each other.
Like they passed it off.
The
forbes stored in a.
They put it in a in their corporate
headquarters and they had an a box,
like a glass boxes of decoration,
but they had standing upright with a
heat lamp in there laying dried that
cork out of the bottle.
So later when people were trying to
analyze what was in it,
there can never rule out the intrusion
of foreign substances,
which will not allow them to find out
what it was.
The guy that eventually like is why the
guy who created the hoax would take
really good wine and do weird stuff to
it.
Like he put a little bit of vanilla
extract and air or he'd put some dirt
from his gutter and they're just weird
things he could do to kind of throw
people and then guys that are like big
swinging dicks about wine would taste
and be like,
oh yeah,
great.
I got it.
It's a brilliant book.
I got invited by him
by a,
by a popper,
a huge guy owned a paparazzi company and
he invited me to a wine tasting and he
said,
he said,
and he goes,
I,
I don't want.
You can't really.
He was trying to be really nice
sneakers.
I'm going to bring one for my seller for
you.
I said,
why?
He whining,
I don't want to be a dick to you,
but you can't afford the wines were
going to bring.
And I go,
all right,
jeez.
How much was the most expensive?
like literally I was doing in 1961 stony
hills.
I mean I was drinking like wines that
you would cost,
costs you a thousand dollars to drink
either.
The taster for zach,
he's wine.
The guy who sets the standard was there.
So anyway,
I,
I do,
I go there and I'm drinking crazy.
Nineteen,
60,
19,
63.
Nineteen is like,
what is it like?
Well,
for me,
because I love wine so much,
there is a difference now.
Now here's the thing,
if you spend $300 on a bottle of wine,
there's a big difference.
You're going to taste an amazing wine if
you know what to get versus a $50 bottle
of wine.
However,
the difference between $300 and a
thousand dollars,
I don't think there's no difference.
Now you're talking about scarcity.
okay.
now you're going into like years and
there's one left and stuff.
I want to back up though because I want
to clarify.
It's too easy to hack on one kind of
sewers.
I want.
I do want to say this,
the handful of times someone did present
to me what's like critically regarded as
a good one.
I was able to taste that one and say,
I get what you're saying.
there's something going on here that was
not going on.
And all the other one I've had my whole
life,
it's wasted on me.
It's always something.
But I recognize what you're saying,
there's something going on,
so I don't want to act like it's all.
I don't think it's all smoke and
mirrors.
It's not all bs at all,
all bs.
And it's amazing the subtle differences
in,
in different glass one.
And
I,
I always equate it to this.
Like if I drink,
I'd amazing bottle of wine,
like say 500 or whatever.
Like my friend made a fortunate that
he's huge wine guy.
Like your buddy.
I always describe it this way.
I go when I drink an amazing glass of
wine,
I say to them,
I,
the way I,
the reason it's expensive,
I go,
nothing else tastes like that,
that,
that taste,
that experience stands on its own.
You don't compete.
You go,
oh,
it tastes just like this.
No,
it stands on its own.
It's so complex and it's an experience
for me.
I love it.
If you had to choose though,
if you had to choose between like no
wine for the rest of your life or blend
food,
what would you like?
What is more important?
The taste of food or to go 100 percent
right?
I can live without one.
No problem.
Yeah,
I to go.
I don't need one.
I like it.
Yeah.
When I'm.
When I'm eating very high quality.
Good food though.
I won't have again.
I typically I like to.
I like to eat it with water.
Yeah.
Me too.
sometimes you have food that's so good.
like I was just just in Louisiana this
weekend and I went to this restaurant
called revolution.
I had a nokia lobster and yucky.
I don't like the way you say.
We say Afghanistan.
I don't like any of these endeavors.
Knowledge.
I had a crawfish crawfish given a nod
toward.
No,
I like it.
Yeah,
but I'm not going to start doing.
But like you're kind of saying like,
yeah man.
More to the earth.
There's more to the globe.
No,
I liked they're going to demonstrate
this,
but to me it's like the gold chains of
language.
He just showed up with a bunch of
fucking language.
Gold trades.
I was in Bahrain,
spend time in France.
I worked on in Afghanistan.
The taliban,
when I was visiting Chile,
we,
I say it,
steve,
his family's had good rabbit,
but if really,
really good food is,
is another thing that's transcendental
man.
I don't need good wine,
but I do need good food.
You know?
That's why when we were talking about
your friend who doesn't like food,
I have a friend who's just like that
too.
He's like,
I just want to.
I just want to eat and then get done and
then do my thing.
It's like,
man,
I was like,
I get it,
but maybe he's just tastes things
different than I do.
A dane cook has to be.
Some people like shit and other people
hate it.
Like I love sea urchin.
I think it tastes delicious too,
but I've tried to give people sea
urchin.
They're lIke,
this is gusting.
Oh my god.
Like they spit into a napkin,
like,
oh,
I like dangerous.
We'll make a,
make a monastic decision.
They're kind of,
they're kind of like,
you know,
with all,
whatever,
all the human suffering in the world or
whatever.
It's like,
you know,
I don't want to be a glutton in that
way.
I look at it differently.
I look at it as I have the.
I have the opportunity.
He incredible food.
I'm gonna.
Eat this for the people that can and I'm
going to pay attention to support.
Okay.
Of
all the suffering people,
I'm going to enjoy this meal.
yeah,
as long as you're not victimizing
someone in,
in,
you're enjoying that food,
you should just be enjoying that food.
Enjoy that moment.
The idea that human beings have to be in
perspective of $6,
million other fucking people is so crazy
because otherwise you'll never be happy.
You'll never be happy because the world
is filled with suffering.
I mean,
there's just always tragic instances
happening all over the world where
people getting hit in the head by
coconuts,
okay,
you should not be.
should not be eating and enjoying your
steak because some,
some poor farmer got hit in the head
with a coconut and fucking dog because
that shit happens 150 times a year.
Right,
and not only that,
but what about the fact that are people
who can really cook,
that's an art form to dedicate their
life to it and it makes your life if
it's just makes the world a better
place.
I want to live in a world with bad,
with bad food or food to where people
don't take care of you.
Do you'd rather live in that world,
the not being alive.
Someone said,
all right,
no,
no good food,
but also knows ombuds or good food and
zombies,
so I can have an arsenal.
She could have an awesome.
You can have an arsenal.
Can you imagine what pigment and nugent
would do if we had good food in zombies
in this special on twitter the other
day,
the best show ever would be a
combination of the walking dead and duck
dynasty.
These dudes that go out to have theIr
fucking wacky stunts like pretending.
Well,
I couldn't open the door,
so I called bob up this fake scenario
and then all of a sudden they all get
eaten by zombies.
I just ripped that fucking throats out
as they're filming that shitty show and
they start their either beard.
I made their and brains mixed in with
beard and they're trying to choke it
down,
throwing up zombies throw up because
they can't eat their beard.
No wonder one of the first time,
like one of the
tv meetings I ever had was years ago now
it was like,
I think it was 2004.
I had a tv meeting where a guy in an
assigned explained to me the most
brilliant show that he was doing,
but I don't think that ever happened and
it was going to be.
he was trying.
He was pitching around the show that was
going to be.
It was gonna start like a reality show.
We make our big live in a house.
Okay.
And you know,
you foment the typical like inner
personal conflict.
All right.
And as it would go on,
things would start getting so unusual.
He was already like,
right when reality tv was starting,
he was already.
He was already trying to think of what
he was ahead of his time.
He's already thinking like how to toy
with it.
Then he wanted to have it get like
increasingly outrageous to build up
where people would say like there's no
way,
there's no way.
And he wanted to bring it to the point
where there was a murder,
whoa,
you know,
and then there'd be a murder and then
the people in the reality.
So it'd be trying to like hide the fact
that they killed one of the roommates
and they would make this very gradual
segue into drama.
And I was like,
that is the most genius thing,
but I don't think he ever.
Well,
was he trying for an actual real murder?
No,
no,
no.
He was just going to do you going to
fake it.
A scripted reality.
He's got the script that like a reality
show.
The viewers would like.
The viewers don't really understand that
reality shows are cast and scripted.
He was going to like toy with this idea
right when it was starting to happen.
Like real real world to mtv real world
type thing,
but build it in as he lost,
as he courted like in an incredulous
response.
And is viewership being like,
there's no way,
there's no way they didn't do that.
That didn't happen to like push it so
far that the final tipping point would
be they actually kill somebody in the
house,
but they don't really kill someone in
the house.
It's just that,
that point it jumped to being like,
we've been drawing.
Yeah,
we've been messing with you the whole
time.
This is all just us playing with you.
That's duck dynasty.
That's the fucking show.
Maybe that was the guy I just never
heard anything about beards.
They fade out and dress it up and beards
because they looked like zz top.
I love these.
Listen,
we've got to wrap this pitch up and
bring it home.
There's been a lot of fun.
Cam.
Thanks for coming on,
man.
Sorry you had to share a microphone.
But this is a really low tech fucking
studio.
I need to get my act together is the
most people who've ever had a microphone
and it worked out.
We did it.
This is awesome.
thanks for having me on man.
Um,
and so,
uh,
April 28th is uh,
the,
uh,
the show on eater.
It's on the sportsmans channel,
uh,
can find it on the internet and your
local.
Why don't we do in a skin man?
When we were hunting again,
what are we do?
Line it up.
I have like,
I could always justify it.
Let's do it.
Yeah,
come on man.
Let me go.
I think we should do a wild pig thing.
Let's do it from the ground.
From the ground.
Yeah.
No helicopters do.
April 25th,
26th,
27th,
28th.
Because I'll be in edmonton at the comic
strip.
I'm not playing in alberta.
Canada.
Yeah.
I'll just be there to explain it.
But at the April 25th,
26th,
27th and 28th.
All right.
We're going to work it out,
but we're all going together again.
Absolutely committed northern
California.
And so you'll see our show.
I've watched both of them.
It was really fun,
man.
It was such a good experience.
Some of the best food.
I've it most satisfying food I've ever
eaten in my life.
We're sitting down on the ground 10
degrees outside cooking deer over a
fire.
we'll do it again.
Couldn't have been,
couldn't have been more fun.
Cashmere killer.
The cashmere cashmere.
I'm writing a blog about the entire,
uh,
event that I will put up this because I
have pictures of brian taking a shit
outside and we put a flag and aluminum
foil in it and we're going to offer a
money on twitter,
like a thousand dollars.
You could find it and take a picture of
their face next to brian shed.
If you can find it on the Missouri
breaks.
We'll give you a rough description of
excluded.
Yeah,
you're excluding.
Turns out We had a,
we had to put the poop and
biodegradable.
These bags,
you have to take your poop with it.
You're not supposed to leave your poop
behind.
So it was often more tricKy to find
shit.
Bags were space,
a space age.
There's nothing quite like the first
night being outside the tent,
shitting into a bag.
My pants down,
pouring rain.
Just not quite cold enough to freeze,
which just pouring rain.
I'm shitting into a bag on.
Whoa.
I was trying to clean my butt with my
thermos.
How sound of running water to me,
I was like,
ah,
I ran out of water.
I'm cleaning my fucking,
but I have to.
I have to ask this before we.
Are we going to release the ravine,
comer footage and put that on the
internet.
Is it possible?
It just isn't because it just isn't
because it would.
I worked for people.
Is there a way that you can't have me
coming in?
Here's the better answer.
I'm not the guy that's dead serious.
I'm not the.
I wouldn't be the editor over there.
Whoever is the editor.
I got a bag of weed with your name on it
and I know,
okay,
let's make this happen.
We need to get through ravine calmer and
we need to get it on the internet and me
pulling quotes out of your rump.
Yeah,
that was fun.
I know that we made.
That's,
that's out there on the internet.
Is it on the internet or if they were a
family program,
but we that's out there.
We're putting that.
Okay,
beautiful.
Yeah.
Brian,
for like an hour of pulled was a quilt
out of my ass,
you know,
it was very heartfelt man.
it was very heartfelt and it made me
appreciate you guys' friendship.
You were joking about it.
You were joking about it,
but he did it.
Oh no,
look.
You know what I mean?
A lot of dudes would just be like,
do it.
And I would do it for him in a fucking
heartbeat.
Yep.
Alright.
What's that big party?
Big party.
Yeah.
Thanks.
So [inaudible] dot com for sponsoring
this program.
Go to hover.com.
Forward slash rogen.
Get 10 percent off your domain name.
Thanks.
Also to ting for sponsoring our podcast.
If you go to rogan.ting.com,
you can save yourself.
What is it?
Twenty five bucks,
25 bucks off of either a phone or
service.
Thanks.
Also to [inaudible] dot com.
That's o n n I t use the code name.
Rogan.
Save 10 percent off.
Or you could follow steven rinella on
twitter.
That is his twitter name.
It's steven rinella with a v,
not some fucking ph.
Like some freak.
The likes to spell.
Why would you spell it with a ph when
you can use a v and I know exactly what
the fuck you're saying,
huh?
Um,
follow him on twitter and follow
mediator on twitter as well and get the
sportsmans channel if you don't have it,
if you want to see us,
uh,
on our,
fucking amazing life changing hunt.
It was a great time.
Thank you my brother.
Appreciate it,
man.
Don't do this again.
We're going to do a podcast again.
We're going to do.
We're going to hunt again.
We'll get we got to live.
God damn it.
And you're going to live too.
We're going to get through this shit.
Stay together.
Keep it together.
Love your neighbor,
kumbaya.
Eat meat and come and ravines whenever
possible.