The joe rogan experience.
Hey everybody.
We're doing a podcast tomorrow from a
west side Barbell Louie sentence.
So,
uh,
we decided to check our set up.
You'll have to move in.
Let's take care of what touching,
touching the table.
We,
uh,
so we decided to do a practice run here.
Young Tony Hinchcliffe is here.
Hello?
Doing surprise.
It's me.
How long is it's Tony?
And of course a young Jamie Vernon.
Hey,
and I'm old Joe Rogan,
Columbus,
Ohio.
Just got done having a nice meal and uh,
talked to a bunch of shit.
And so we said,
hey,
we should go do a fucking podcast.
So here we are.
Now we're silent.
It's all happened until we talked
ourselves out.
We're talking about this woman.
Uh,
we didn't talk about too much,
but we should.
This woman who was the woman that
Hillary Clinton brought up,
uh,
during the trump debate because she was
saying that Donald Trump humiliated this
woman because he shamed her and
humiliated her because she gained weight
while she was a missile.
Olympia,
I missed this.
I was in the bathroom and you guys had
this time.
She got up to 170 pounds according to
trump,
she went up from like one 20 to one 70.
According to him,
probably not right.
It's probably gained like 30 pounds.
But apparently she really did gain a
fuck load of weight.
And um,
and Hillary Clinton made this big deal
about like how awful it was.
He did that to her and then they had
these commercials already planned for
the next day.
So they launched these commercials the
next day.
And the commercials they show this
woman,
she's speaking any Spanish.
It talking about Donald Trump is
terrible what he did to me.
He made me feel bad.
He made me,
he was scared.
So then after that comes out,
people start researching her.
They find out that she drove a getaway
car in a murder.
That she threatened a drudge cause the
judge who is going after her boyfriend
at the time that she drove away in the
getaway car that she threatened,
the judge said that she was going to
kill the judge.
She had an elite,
uh,
illegitimate baby with a Mexican kingpin
drug dealer.
All of the Mexican drug cartel kingpins
came to the baby's Christening.
Wow.
Then she went on big brother.
Okay.
Big Brother.
She was engaged to some baseball player.
Went on big brother and fuck some other
guy on the show while the cameras were
on her and she was yelling out in
Spanish that he has a magnificent
caught.
Wow.
The same lady that I used in our
commercial,
so then they have her on cnn,
my ga,
so Anderson Cooper interviews or on CNN
and Anderson Cooper says some people are
saying that you threatened a judge and
that you drove the getaway car.
Like is this your saying?
Everybody have a pass.
Okay.
I'm not angel.
I met a bad person,
but they had tried to take away from
what he did.
What he did was wrong.
Okay.
What I did was 20 years ago,
what he did was 20 years ago to heal.
All we did was calling fat.
Yeah.
But in his defense when she probably
was,
she got fat.
You see these pictures of her.
She definitely got fat,
but you know,
ordinarily that's a very rude thing to
do.
But when your job is to be a
professional hot chick,
it's like if you just decide,
say like if you're a model for like a
shaving cream,
like give you like your,
your whole thing is about your legs and
you're showing your legs.
Like I touched the,
I'm sorry,
but your things about your just sleek,
smooth legs and you're like,
you know what?
Fuck it.
I'm letting these bitches grow.
I never was like,
hey,
um,
you can't,
you job is to have sleek,
smooth legs.
Fuck that.
You're known for your nice flakes.
Yeah.
She's known for being a professional,
attractive woman.
Any it he shouldn't objectify women.
That is the whole point of being mizell
Limpia
so hillary paid her to,
obviously if she's an anti trump course
then that means he already paid her.
Right.
Um,
might not be money.
It might just be attention because it
gave her the opportunity to get back in
the limelight.
Apparently she's a giant attention
whore.
Gotcha.
I saw some class year or something.
I think she wrote a book.
Thanks.
So about the Donald Trump where your
fat,
we were looking at up,
they all have a past.
We all want to have a pass.
Okay.
It's really funny you should fucking say
it.
One thing I noticed the other day was
this commercial,
the Anti Trump Hillary.
It's a pro hit this message approved by
Hillary Clinton commercial where it's
all the compiler nation of all the worst
things that trump said over the past
year or whatever and um,
and it,
and it literally his voice and the clip
of him doing all these things and you
know,
Mexicans are rapists and murderers.
All the little soundbites and the
commercial goes,
uh,
and there's,
it goes back to little kids back and
forth,
like pictures a little kids and it then
it goes,
is this what you want your kids to see?
And I was watching this commercial and
it was like the middle of the day and
I'm thinking of myself,
you paid to put,
you're putting that stuff out there.
That's your commercial.
Yeah.
That all played once you just put that
out there for the kids to see and over
and over again.
Right.
Then the whole commercial,
it's like,
is this what you want your kids to see?
And it's like you just spend 30 million
bucks on that commercial.
Right,
right,
right.
But in her defense,
you know,
this is what you kids just wanted to see
as the leader as like their role model.
Hang on.
As the leader of the free world
comp is biting his tongue,
we all know it.
Once he drops that blow job card,
the whole world explodes.
He's sitting on like a clothes or
liking comedian Lewinsky cards.
Oh,
you'll be instantly they're telling him
not to do it.
Apparently they're trying to talk to him
to say,
do not bring up the Monica Lewinsky
stuff.
Cause he in the post press conference
thing,
he was saying how,
you know,
I,
I'm,
I'm very proud of myself that I did.
I didn't bring up Bill Clinton and his,
his dalliances.
I don't even think he has to mention
Bill Clinton.
I don't,
I don't even know if he had even said
those exact words like I think he's just
like,
let's just say there's a lot of things
that I'm not talking about that I could
maybe bringing up.
I could bring up that wouldn't be good
for her.
I don't need to say what they are.
You know what they are.
I have a winning temperament.
One thing about me,
Everyone knows this,
these debates that are whole areas,
but what's really funny is they both
sucks so hard that all this dirt that
comes out about them,
it's like no big deal.
Can we do a fight companion for the
next,
what we're talking about doing that?
We were talking about that if I'm in
town,
if I'm not working during the next one,
we're going to,
we're going to hook something up.
There's two more,
so two more.
Okay.
There's one we're going to need to bring
someone legitimate end to like andy
stump wants come in.
My,
in my friend,
former navy seal and Andy,
he'll be,
he'll probably come into and maybe we
bring in someone else that like knows
Paula.
I'll drop some hot puns on that one too.
Yes,
you're good for that.
But who knows politics like really well
at Fitzsimons does.
He'd probably be good at that,
right?
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
Who else did you see some of the,
there's a conspiracy talked.
I was like,
this was going on during the debate
first was like she was,
has,
she had an earpiece fed stuff when I saw
last night was that uh,
she got caught scratching my face like
this six times and they were signals to
Lester Holt to like hit me,
hit it with a Zinger now,
like you're saying something and she,
Oh,
and then next would be like something
for like a pre predisposed talking point
for it to get out.
Well trump was saying that the,
the Lester Holt Guy,
the narrator,
what was he,
the announcer which call a,
that the moderator was against him and
he's like,
it was a bad deal,
was a bad deal.
You know,
it was a rig d microphone.
He says Mike was fucked up.
That's where digital is.
I heard them loud and clear at home,
but he caught it,
caught him on some real shit,
like the fact that trump supported the
Iraq war,
and even if you only said it on Howard
stern it,
which is apparently where he said it,
he only said,
you know,
break that down.
I guess what he said it in passing the
kind of statement like,
uh,
yeah,
sure.
Right,
so we're,
we're like,
what?
I was heard someone said,
I didn't hear.
Yeah,
you gotta be careful about things like
that because if you do one day plan on
running for president,
you can't just say,
yeah,
sure,
I support your back war and say,
I never supported that war.
It's an interesting thing where it
almost seems it's everything backwards
helps him.
Every time he messes up,
it sort of helps him.
I don't think this time it dead,
he looked bad.
I thought he,
and I'm not picking sides here,
I'm just totally judging the debate.
I think that the fact that people are
even wondering who won or who did good
means,
that's a huge victory for
trump.
I don't think people are wondering.
I think the polls really pretty
overwhelmingly on her side.
I think it was like 70% of the people
pull or 68% of the people polled thought
she won.
I thought she won,
but in his defense I didn't see the
beginning.
Apparently he did really well in the
beginning and she did really well.
You know,
one of the things that she said that I
thought was really crazy,
like she was going on about this thing
about him calling women pigs and all
these different things and that he said,
uh,
something about women being pregnant and
working.
I forget,
I forget what that quote was,
but one of the weird one was he said
that women should only get paid as much
as men if they earn it,
which,
yeah,
that's what I said.
I,
I had it playing.
We were getting ready to do kill Tony
and the belly room and,
and we,
Josh Martin had his phone plugged in to
the overall speakers in the room.
So like the whole room,
it's empty.
It's just me and Josh just setting up
and stuff and you're playing at night,
literally set out loud,
you're damn right.
Or whatever it was.
I remember that part.
Exactly.
Well imagine you just said the opposite.
The men should only get paid as much as
women if they earn it and everybody
would go,
yeah,
well that makes sense.
But the idea that women should somehow
know they get paid as much as men if
they don't earn it.
Like,
I mean maybe we should like find the
exact quote here.
Let me find the exact quote.
I think he gets taken out of context,
not a good speaker.
Even though he speaks a lot in public.
I just think he's not good at
articulating the things he actually
means or wants to say.
And I think when the media does take him
out of context,
and Ben's what he says a little bit,
but people notice that.
And then when he does say some crazy
stuff,
I think that that only helps him when
that happens because it's like,
oh,
here they go again.
Ben Didn't trump,
I'm stuck here.
I think he likes her.
Right?
Even though it's going to happen to
cause he's not complaining.
Yeah.
I'm telling you.
If he is down in the third debate,
you know he's given it time.
Now he's playing a strategy,
but if he loses the second debate and it
gets down to that third debate,
he's going to drop that Bill Clinton
blow job shit out of me.
Nobody cares anymore.
Do they?
About that stuff.
You know?
It's interesting like immediately the
first hits when it's what Hillary and
trump on women salon.com right away.
Here's why it's wrong.
Here's why it's terrible.
I mean if he just said,
if trump said the words in succession,
like the only reason you ever became
secretary of state was because your
husband got a blow job in office.
You know what I mean?
Like if he went for it,
I mean,
do you think you could ever do that
though?
Can you really go for it like that?
Can you that
this election is different.
Everything that we've ever seen before.
So I think the ground rules are just
getting made and I think he'll do
anything to get the maximum amount of
press out of this.
Of course,
my computer just froze.
That's what happens when you start
talking shit about your computer and it
said you need a new one fucking thing.
Just locked right up.
Do that.
But that's what happens when you talk
shit about Hillary.
It's also what happens when you go to
salon dog,
all your emails or deleting themselves
right now you're talking about Hillary
too.
Well,
that was the other thing that's kind of
crazy.
It's like how many emails she's deleted
and she's like,
why won't you release your tax returns?
Excuse me,
that you deleted 30,000 fucking yeah.
How about you release you God damn
emails,
all of that.
How about you release the transcripts of
those conversations that you got paid
$250,000 an hour to speak in front of
those bankers.
How about you?
How about you do that?
Like,
what are you talking about?
Me,
me
may release.
It's very bizarre.
That email things crazy.
She was like a hotmail account or
something.
She's,
yeah,
it is very strange man.
It's all of,
it's very strange.
You know what else is very strange?
Well,
there's a a bunch of things that are
very strange about it all,
but the email stuff is like,
you didn't know that you were deleting
all those emails or you just did it.
Like how's that?
Like you're not allowed to do that.
That's illegal.
That's highly illegal there.
When we had Mike Baker,
the former CIA guy on the podcast,
he's like,
all I know is if I did that I would go
to jail.
It's like I'd be in jail if I did that.
I don't remember who I discussed in this
part of it,
but is there any way that what the email
thing,
like what does she's in her seventies,
right or close to it that she's just,
uh,
not,
I guess competent might be the word.
She doesn't understand what's going on
with email.
Like is there any way it was in college?
She gets it.
She looks at it weird or like how people
look at,
they're like old people look at their
phones like,
I don't even know how
this is the kind of lady that,
it's probably a three blackberries for
last 20 years.
Yeah.
I mean there's no way she didn't know,
but also not only that,
the guy who was in charge of her email
server was on reddit a couple of years
ago.
Yeah.
Ask him about
how'd I get rid of stuff for your or,
exactly.
We wanted to make everything disappear
and every lawyer who,
Huh?
Then I guess I guess it could be adding
that to what I was just asking.
Is there any way she didn't even know
what was going on or she had to,
if there's no issue every way,
if someone was doing it thinking this is
what would be a great move,
I better just do this.
Oh,
I don't know.
I gave me a good raise or my kidney,
a good position later down the line and
found out like I took some initiative
here.
I,
I just went in and deleted them all.
You become as a new head of the NSA or
some shit?
No,
no.
I'm just curious.
Just,
I mean maybe,
I mean when a guy thinks
that she's gonna win and become the
president and he wants to Gig and I mean
all of those,
that's part of what we're sitting here
is like all these people,
we're all connected and sort of sort of
a weird,
like a sneaky fucking way where they do
a bunch of sneaky shit for each other
without even saying anything about it.
It's like,
like it's all like implied
and we all seen house of cards now too.
Like after saying that we definitely are
all like,
oh,
we think we get it because that seems so
true.
I bet that's going on,
right?
Yeah.
I mean that shit's crazy.
It's all real now.
The house,
the cards stuff's coming alive.
I know,
right,
because the storyline is crazier than
anything.
It's like it's like they realize that
veep and veep was winning Emmy's every
year and how's the cards started
changing the game of the mes because
that was the first thing from Netflix to
really start.
All of a sudden there was a new network
at the Emmys,
which was like an old,
I mean that's them crashing and old
party with just NBC and CBS and ABC and
then,
yeah.
Do you remember at the end of like
Bush's presidency that they were,
there was TV shows made about how goofy
he was as a president?
Yeah.
Comedy central head.
What was your old made a hole.
Yeah,
he was him for a thing.
Like how if somebody was Obama talking
about like how goofy Obama's presidency
now would that,
would that work?
Or like,
no,
it wouldn't worry.
Wouldn't even be the thing,
but if a trump presidency happened
again,
they could definitely make a whole new
nightly.
This is what trump did day.
Well,
snl,
they just announced they just signed to
Alec Baldwin to be trunk to be trump for
the next year,
which is crazy.
Then the next year,
if they made it like a special deal that
they don't normally do,
they're paying him like a butt ton of
money to do this trump thing.
It's all very funny,
man.
It's all very funny.
It's just like,
it just proves my point that I've been
talking about for awhile that nobody who
smart wants that job.
I mean Hillary wants a job cause it's
like sort of the cap of this long career
and sort of,
um,
you know,
it's a historic moment.
If she wins,
she becomes the first female president.
But she's centered to criminal
investigations and they're also saying
that if she doesn't win,
it's very possible.
But the FBI might in tighter for a bunch
of shit.
There's the bank,
Ozzie stoked.
There's the email stuff.
There's,
there's a lot going on here.
It's just,
it's so disturbing that this is the best
we can do.
Him or her,
both of them.
I think trump is going to pull it out
because I think people are going to want
to shake this shit up.
I think that people talk a lot of smack
now and they want to seem like this and
that.
But I think when once they're in the
booth and it's just you and two boxes
and one says trump and the other says
Clinton and you think,
you know what?
Let's make these next four
years a little more interesting.
I think people are going to check it.
That's what they did with that brexit
thing.
No,
I don't.
I think brexit's a totally different
situation because brexit,
I have a friend,
my friend Steve Hilton,
remember Steve from the podcast.
Steve Hill was a very smart guy and used
to be um,
David Cameron's right hand man.
He's pro brexit.
He's like,
it's much more complicated than people
think.
He's like this idea that anyone from any
part of Europe can immigrate to the U K
is disastrous.
He goes,
it's not racist.
It's like the,
the UK has a lot to offer and if it does
in his mind,
it is my paraphrasing him,
but I believe what he's saying is that
if the UK does let everybody come in
from all over Europe and immigrated to
the UK,
that what's going to happen is there's
other parts of Europe does,
aren't doing so well.
Those people are going to go to the
place.
It's doing great and it's going to
fucking balance everything out
eventually.
But Europe is going to,
or UK rather,
it's going to suffer.
While while this is happening,
I don't know nearly enough to comment on
it,
but as a complicated issue,
but it's also one of those issues were
like super lefties,
really progressive liberal people
immediately want to say racist.
You don't want people to immigrate to
this country racist,
you know you don't want,
but that's what we're seeing here.
You can't just immigrate here from
Canada,
man.
If you want to just move from Canada to
the United States and we're start
working.
I've had a bunch of friends come over
here from Canada.
It's a long process management and easy
and that's like pretty white p from
Canada that look just like you,
you know,
we're all talking about like Mexicans
who look different or talking about
people who look like white European
people have an incredibly hard time
getting a green card.
A lot of them.
Mary,
my friend married some guy.
She married some guy just to that
Canadians and yeah,
she was Canadian.
Wow.
Yeah,
I know another dude,
Matt.
Well,
she was rushing Russian factor to use
walker,
but he married her just so she could
become a citizen.
Hmm.
That's super common that you have to
like go through all these meetings,
have to make sure that you really are
husband and wife loans.
So your finger,
her show me.
You mean do you think if trump won,
he had actually built a wall?
I think if trump won,
he would hire a bunch of people to do
the job and they would start a new
reality TV show would like him on his
underwear,
his underwear on a yacht or fireside
chats live from the White House.
Probably something like that.
It'd be hosting,
you know,
you make do with what?
Donald Trump channel.
He figured out a way to make it a law.
So here's what's stunning to me is the
illusion that he's some good speaker.
His economy of words is terrible.
He makes a point that it repeats that
point and then he repeats that point
again.
Yes,
I said that.
Yes I did.
Yes,
I did like the Mexican wall thing.
Like when he said that,
I told them the wall just got 10 foot
higher.
Now,
if he was a real master speaker,
he would go from that right into
something else.
He goes,
yes,
I did.
That's what I like.
He,
he rambles on too much.
It's getting too much unprepared like
speeches like and that's what we saw in
a debate.
Like it's in contrast to her,
like she was very well prepared.
Like she,
she nailed a lot of like very important
points.
She set him up pretty good.
One strategy that I noticed that she
applied,
which I think was really smart,
was she kept her answers extremely
short,
extremely to the point.
She did not ramble at all because she
knew that he was going to do that and
she knew that he,
she could get him to make himself look
like a fool if she just plays it.
Absolutely cool.
Zero extra words because he does.
He overuses everything.
He repeats everything we're going to,
I said it once,
I'll say it again.
We're going to build a wall.
It's going to be great.
It's going to be a great wall.
It's going to be a great big wall.
People love it.
I love it.
You're going to love it.
America is going to love.
It's going to be great.
We're going to make America great again.
One thing about me,
I have a winning temperament of winning
temperament.
Like that was so embarrassing,
really was.
There's certain points where he throws a
punch that misses so hard that you know,
it's like,
oh,
that's a huge dent.
He would,
he did it to himself.
What was that one moment where he said a
bunch of stupid shit in?
Then they went to her and she went,
well,
hi.
And she like laughed and smiled like she
handled that so smooth.
Yeah.
This is so embarrassing that first of
all,
why does an Al Gore run?
I don't understand that.
Yeah,
and they just became president.
Like,
why wouldn't you run again?
Like if he ran,
he would give the nomination like first.
And everybody fucking loves me because
trying to save the world,
right.
Wanted to be the president at one point
in time.
Maybe it's just like too hard on you.
He was just too exhausting.
And maybe he,
maybe he just doesn't want it.
Maybe he knows how bad the whole thing
is.
Maybe knows something we don't know and
he probably does.
Also,
he has made a fuck ton of money since
he's been in white and the White House,
someone said that he is going to be the
first [inaudible] they call it cold.
I forget what they call it.
Green billionaire or they were,
they were talking climate change,
billionaire.
He's going to be the first climate
change advocate slash billionaire.
I apparently it's just made a ton of
money on speaking fees and all kinds of
other shit and he's just doing really
well telling everybody the sky is
falling.
He's come a long way since man,
their peg,
this man bear pig
and south park,
they had a couple of seasons where he
was chasing a man bear pig.
This is like their analogy to a global
warming.
13 it says,
isn't that worth,
is gross more than $200 million since he
lost the presidential bid in 2000 so in
like 10 years or so,
gain $200 million being the president.
So much money and be in a pile.
What's the dig?
Lift up the whole storyline producers
like there's so much money and making a
failing product.
They tried to make a shake.
Maybe should he play?
What if now is it donald saw that he's
like,
I'll just do it.
Al Gore.
Did he get so close to winning?
Not when.
I don't think we would say that.
I was like,
it doesn't want to win.
He doesn't want to.
I think that people believe that.
I think they might be right.
I just don't think he expected to do
this.
Well.
I think he expected to get to a certain
point,
getting knocked down and just talk shit
about everybody who wins.
You know,
Talk Shit About Marco Rubio or Ted Cruz,
by the way.
I prefer Donald Trump.
Ted Cruz.
Yeah,
right.
That's,
it's really crazy.
Like Donald Trump is preferable.
Ted Cruz is fucking crazy.
Dan.
Creepy.
Oh,
it's a weird religious fucking fanatic
man.
He's a nutty guy.
It's got all sorts of problems with gay
people and he suck.
He's sleepy.
He to me,
appeals to like the dumbest of like
religious ideologues,
like the dumbest of really fucking
fanatical religious people.
Yeah,
Jeremy.
Yep.
And the way he like,
uh,
though it's,
you see when he kissed his daughter that
one time
video so gross where they show the
outtakes and the one where he punched an
elbowed his wife on stage right after he
locked,
clipped her right in the face,
act to just being a congressman right
now,
Senator Ted Turner.
Is that what he's back to doing now?
He just fist,
it's a good question.
Back into the life he had before.
Not Everybody knows all this weird shit
about them.
How's that work?
Yeah,
it has happened.
I guess it definitely happens.
Well,
what's weird is it that you could run
for president and keep that job if
that's the case,
like how the fuck you don't have the
time to do your job right.
How can you just run for president and
also hold a job in public office?
And remember,
like they were saying Bernie was going
back,
he was,
he was taking hits on the campaign show
because he was going back for all those
things he had to do in Washington.
Like he would fly back every other day
or weekly if he had tiffany go for a
vote or something instead of campaigning
where Hillary would be off campaigning
cause she didn't have to be in those
votes.
And it's like,
well why isn't she doing her job,
the secretary to stay?
We're so lucky Bernie,
that nit Bernie got through all the
hippies would be fucking,
there'd be going through the streets
screaming,
cheering.
Well I think it'd be,
I think it would be more one sided than
it is even though Hillary supposedly be
Bernie.
I think Bernie,
as weird as it is,
maybe I'm wrong,
but it seems like in the battle of
styles,
I think Bernie would be housing trump
right now.
Oh,
he would do.
He would do.
I think it'd be clearly like 80 2090 10
more in there than even this.
You know,
whatever.
It seems to be
just one of the most disturbing things
about all this stuff is the Democratic
National Committee,
the DNC leaks that show that they were
conspiring.
It's Bernie Sanders is really bad cause
you,
you're,
you're literally rigging democracy.
Like your party is supposed to be the
Democratic Party,
right?
I mean you're supposed to like try to
find,
let's find the best representative.
What do the people want?
Like you guys are reading it.
Yeah.
You read a vrf existence,
defend what they did,
but I think uh,
one might say did what they did.
I think this is just a thought.
They were trying to stop someone who
wasn't a Democrat from just coming in
and taking over their party because he's
not a Democrat as far as I've heard.
He's just an independent,
right.
Which is why he's can't take over now if
she would've got sick.
So like there are preventing some wild
card like Donald Trump,
I guess some guys just became super
famous and just being like,
ah,
I'm going to fucking ruin everything you
guys been playing on for the last 10
years.
How does that work?
He's not,
is he does,
he couldn't he just go back and forth
from being a Democrat or an independent.
Right,
right.
See I thought he was a Democrat when she
was super
hot coffee.
People that actually know about politics
right now.
You fucking
moron.
I think Bernie had a lot of positive
qualities.
Yeah.
There's first of all,
when he was in that debate with Hillary
and he was talking about,
Oh you know,
why won't she release the transcripts
for most speeches?
And he goes,
you can read my transcripts cause they
don't exist.
So that I would not accept money from
banks or,
yeah,
it was,
it was interesting.
He's just,
he,
I think he's,
what he's done is let people know that
there's a market for that.
There's a market for the outsider that,
you know,
lives a frugal life and does it really
make a ton of money.
But his one,
if anybody has ever been running for
president and represents the average
person and I'm really ethical,
average person,
it's Bernie,
but a lot of peoples on the other side,
a lot of people think that this whole
democratic socialists thing,
it sort of supports people don't have a
good work ethic and supports people who
are lazy sports people want government
handouts and what he's trying to do
with,
you know,
jacking up taxes and some of the crazy
shit that he said.
It's just like take from the poor,
the rich and give to the poor and he's
is a big part of his platform was wealth
inequality,
which is a big issue with a lot of
people.
It's understandable.
It makes sense,
but I don't think anybody has solved the
riddle of how to overcome wealth
inequality.
Yeah.
Sweden seems to have a real knack for
it.
Free hospitals,
free college,
and we were there.
The streets were beautiful.
Everything's clean,
free public transportation,
Free Hospital,
street college was the other thing.
Something else.
Well,
those things were already much,
everything's free and they pay,
what was it?
I think 30 or 40% tax.
I don't know the exact I at all numbers,
but they pay a very high sales tax on
everything.
You pay it on everything.
New pair of shoes.
Fuck you pay me a new tee shirt.
Fuck you.
Pay me
Sweden.
It's a beautiful
2015,
10 that's an a world superpower.
That's an army that can take police and
even edit your time.
That's a good point.
The number of people is a good point
too.
Like when you get to like 300 million
people and you start talking about like
universal basic income,
you know,
which is an interesting conversation
that keeps getting brought up.
Uh,
you know,
uh,
that was what Eddie Wong brought up on
the podcast.
We started talking about it.
That's not,
it was crazy initially.
But then I've read some of the things
that some economists have said and some,
some people believe that if you just
gave people certain amount of money
where there's $12,000 a year more or
whatever it is,
that it would alleviate the stress of
paying bills.
People would have like a certain amount
of income.
And it would be far less crime and then
the government would need to spend far
less money because it'd be far less
issues,
which I think is fascinating.
I don't know if it's true.
I don't know if it's right,
but I like,
yeah,
it's very out of the box and when a
country's is fucked up as we are,
we have these ghettos like a with
Michael Wood was talking about with
Baltimore where there just is systemic
racism,
systemic ghettos where they've like made
it so like black people cannot buy
houses any place other than these areas
and that these areas outside of that are
only for white people.
Like when you have like something like
that that existed until like,
I think you said the 1960s is when those
laws were still in at,
in in effect,
right.
I think,
I don't know at least that I would say
at least that.
So that's my lifetime.
I was born in 67 so during my lifetime
these laws were being enforced,
which is just fucking crazy.
Like you,
when you have a system that's that nuts,
like you got to,
you got to have a radical plan to fix
it.
So there was a neighborhood outside of
Baltimore that was only white people.
You could not buy a house there if
you're black,
we would not sell.
You have a d at the address to this.
How dare you.
I thought you were in a fucking black
girls man.
Isn't that a new thing?
Just kidding guys.
Just kidding.
Hey,
your new thing.
Uh,
I think black girls do have a warmer
vagina than white girls.
How much warmer?
I think just a few degrees warmer.
Like if you took a white vagina and put
it in the microwave for like five
seconds.
And how many black girls have you had
sex with?
I noticed there was only only two and it
was a one summer about three years ago.
And,
but I noticed it with both of them and
it wasn't even at the same time.
It was just the same summer.
I was no setting for my friend in the
Hollywood hills and they'd be,
it just felt warm or cause you were so
excited to be bringing a black chick
that your dick was going.
Woo pretty much was either that or they
had fevers and they just,
every second these girls with malaria,
they coughing a lot and then they were
when mine.
All right.
It's so silly.
You,
have you ever been,
have you,
did you ever hook up with a black woman?
Oh yeah.
Did you ever notice anything different
with their darker than me?
I noticed that
one time when I lived in Boston,
you know,
it was like the winter I was,
it's really,
you know,
pales like this,
like cloudy and I was Pale,
you know,
I didn't have very much a time to go out
in the sun.
And A,
I hooked up with this black girl I met
in Pittsfield,
Massachusetts.
Wow.
Which is way out in the middle of
nowhere.
And she wasn't black like beyond,
say black.
She was black like check Congo,
black,
dark,
whoa,
dark.
And we had sex in my hotel room by the
light of the television,
right.
So the TV's on and I'm having sex with
her and she's dark light Cole and I'm
white paper.
We're going at it.
And I remember thinking about it cause
we were doing it doggy style.
I remember,
look down at it,
she had an incredible body.
All my God,
this girl,
to this day,
it's like one of the best bodies I've
ever seen in my life.
It was like cartoonish or body was
incredible.
But I remember to this day thinking
like,
wow,
this is so crazy.
They're like,
we'll like,
she's so much darker than me.
I'm so white and I'm not even that
white.
I'm Italian,
you know?
Mostly.
But I mean it just,
the contrast was so interesting.
But the girls that I have had sex with,
it just,
maybe it's a coincidence,
maybe sound,
but all the black shirts that had sex
with,
we're fucking freaks.
Like they were so much more
enthusiastic.
Yeah.
So much more vocal,
so much more aggressive.
You know,
like Kenya,
come on,
Oh,
oh,
hold that good tech.
Like whoa.
Jesus.
Plus,
while it's happening,
you know,
as a comic hall,
stuff like that's happening.
Like,
oh my God,
I remember this one.
If it's a bit near,
yeah,
just take it.
No,
I could never make a bit out of it
though because it seems so phrases.
Yeah.
Just even say how dark she was and how
wide I was.
It was like,
how do I say this without sounding,
I mean it's just,
it's such a racially charged thing.
Like even if you're,
if it's not the jokes not racist or the
discussion of the subject is not racist.
It's so racially charged,
you're better off just leaving it alone.
Plus,
one of the things I've noticed,
um,
I had a conversation with this girl that
I was dating at the time.
Um,
and uh,
she did like,
you know,
it was one of those years have sex with
blog.
Yeah.
Maybe you're having sex with a black
girl.
Yeah.
A couple.
How many,
you know,
those kinds of conversations.
But I was telling her how dark this girl
was.
Like she was getting upset
so she was dark.
But I mean it's like if I asked her,
you know like how bill,
how black ones,
this guy,
you know like how blog [inaudible] blog,
you know like Congo black like dropped
out of the jungle.
Boy,
what are we talking here?
He had the skin of a good year tire.
No,
no,
nope.
I heard drummed
is for whatever it is.
Got.
She got upset that I was,
I,
I'd fucked this bar girl in the past.
Like is the shade that offended or the
most though she's racist.
She's from Staten Island town.
That'll do it.
Tiny girl from standing out.
Racist.
Oof.
Two more now.
Park row
one day.
But here's the thing,
here's what's fucked.
You know,
like someone said to me once,
one day everyone's going to be like mix
because like right now the only reason
why race existed in such specific like
distinctive ways like Chinese people,
African people,
like really distinctive differences is
because those people very rarely met
each other.
But now everybody goes everywhere.
And a place like the United States,
which is essentially just a melting pot
of immigrants,
does own the only people that were here
originally where the indigenous people,
but even the indigenous people came over
from Asia,
they all came on the bering strait.
I mean all the people that live here
that we think of as native Americans,
they've done like these DNA tests on
them will think if they come from
fucking Siberia.
You know,
you know,
it's really funny now,
who did the DNA test to find that out?
So really rich dude who was a mormon who
wanted approve.
One of,
uh,
Joseph Smith's statements was that the
American Indians were in fact the lost
tribe of Israel.
And he thought that he could prove that
and prove that the,
the,
the Mormon doctrine that the book of
Mormon was correct.
And so he spent all this money to get
the DNA test done,
turned out there from fucking Siberia
because the kids are not high.
Oops.
Did he tried to,
well,
I don't think you can.
I don't think scientists let you hide
the data and to get it done.
Maybe some extra money to get it fucked
up.
A real lab that's doing those kinds of
DNA test.
I would imagine that would be like an
important finding and they would want to
release it.
I would again,
oh yes.
Scientists could cover up data then we
wouldn't know that mushrooms can care.
Chronic depression from the studies.
That was a Carnegie Parkins John Hopkins
University.
This has been a few studies now are
showing that.
Yeah,
I no man,
it's um,
it's everybody has come.
What I was going to say is everybody has
come to the United States from somewhere
else.
Right.
And then one day conceivably that people
keep fucking,
that we're all going to be like one kind
of thing,
one shade.
We're all be like this sort of Tan that,
but the problem with that is it's kind
of cool.
You know,
what do you walk down the street and you
see this dude who's black flag coal and
it's got a little Chinese girlfriend and
like,
whoa boy,
I want to watch this to do it.
It's kind of exciting.
I mean,
it's kind of fun that people are
different,
but we can handle that fun.
Some people can't handle it right.
Without being racist.
And not only that,
because of racists,
we can't make racial jokes.
Like if you can't even talk about like
pretty obvious differences in the races
without being labeled a racist,
like things that are really just so
obvious and less.
You're making fun of white people.
You can make fun of white people till
the cows come home.
Nobody gives a shit because why?
People are,
the majority white people were thought
of as the oppressors.
White people owned slaves,
you know,
et Cetera,
et cetera.
So you can shit on white people all day
long.
Nobody ever gives you a hard time for
shitting on white people.
Yeah,
yeah.
They're the,
the,
it's,
it's in,
it's no fun to make fun of white people
either.
That's,
you know,
it's just sorta like,
well,
it's always no fun to make fun of
someone who,
well,
when someone is in charge or someone is
on the,
uh,
oh,
someone has power,
right.
Those are the people you're supposed to
just fuck with.
Cause it's useful to punch up.
Right.
You should always punch up and comedy
Tony.
Yeah.
You should always punch up,
which is not necessarily true because
sometimes the people like my purse,
my classic example of why punching up as
an,
it's funny as the sand Kansas bit about
starving people in Africa and one of the
greatest bits of all time and it's
literally talking about starving
children.
It's fucking hilarious.
But you know,
I think that like when,
when someone is in a position of power
though,
it's open season on them as opposed to
someone who comes from a marginalized
group.
Like what?
Even if it's something funny or if
something from a marginalized group and
it's a really funny thing.
If you talk about it,
you can get in trouble.
Yeah.
Do you,
uh,
have you ever gotten in trouble for
anything racial and like,
I mean,
doing the stand up,
like did you ever cross the line or
crowd wise or anything?
No.
I never got in trouble,
but I've never,
I've never been like a a racial comic.
Right.
That's not really my thing.
You know,
like Russell,
like we were talking about the other
day,
like Russell Peters,
Russel's half his act is about race,
but he can get away with it because he's
Indian.
Cause he's brown because he's Indian.
She's the,
the chosen one.
He's a brown guy from Canada that
America,
like he's got it all.
Yeah.
He can make fun of everything and be
like,
yeah,
what do you want?
Tom Brown,
Brown from Asia just got the whole thing
wrapped up.
Yeah.
It's got this thing on lock.
I mean,
right.
India,
Asia,
right.
Hmm.
Yeah.
I had to ask.
I was sure what I said.
Then after I said it was okay.
It was like,
yeah,
right.
Yeah.
Right.
Okay.
But so was Russia,
right?
That's what's weird.
That's just,
yeah.
Wow.
Russia is part of Asia.
Yeah.
It's just the most people that live in
Russia don't all live in the Asian part.
Yeah.
Live in the European.
It's like Egypt,
Egypt,
Africa.
Everybody thinks of Egypt as the Middle
East.
Well,
it Kinda is,
but it's also Africa.
Yeah.
My mind is blown right now.
Egypt is a part of Africa,
you know it's fucked up.
When I went to Italy,
Egypt like right there,
like you're fucking swim to it.
Not really,
but I mean the d,
the distance between Egypt and Italy is
like,
it's fucking hop,
skip and a jump.
How it's how the Moore's invaded Sicily.
They were right there.
They got of raft,
they went over and a raft.
He just raped everybody.
It's real close
man.
And that's how people started getting
browner Italians if every race or aren't
did the differences in race in some
situations based off of geography.
Sure.
Yeah.
So that's why I was just kind of think
that,
I was thinking that thought too,
that everyone will end up looking the
same color,
but that's a fairly well live in the
same place.
Right?
That's the sort of people live there.
They declared that ended up being
darker.
They'll be well live further away from
it.
That's good point.
But how come everybody in Arizona so
fucking white in there and stay inside
away from the sun?
He punched Chicago cargo or dark.
Wow.
See what I'm saying,
it's no reflection and go to the south
side of Chicago and then go to
Scottsdale and you go like,
what the fuck is going on here?
I mean the origins of those people.
Yeah,
for sure.
If you lived in a continent like Africa
where the sun's beating down on you all
the time,
you need more Melanin to protect you
from the sun.
If you lived in a place,
it's always like,
you know,
Norway or something like that where it's
very little sun nor we have very little
sun I would imagine.
Right.
I slammed all fucking white people.
Uh,
we were talking and I forget someone was
on the podcast this week and the Tower
of Babel came up in giants in new West.
Yes,
it was.
I wrote something down when I came up to
Santa thought that,
and I'm not sure I could've looked it
up.
I guess that,
uh,
I wrote down like Internet and English
could be,
that was my phone.
Could be that,
uh,
that time Babel sing senior language.
And I guess what I mean when Internet
English is that like aren't most
websites coded and English because of
the Internet started and like over here
the West where people all speak English
to me like html.
Yeah.
Like wouldn't,
a Chinese website has to be coded in
html and they could have some program
that's translating their stuff that's
easier for them to do it.
Hmm.
Was getting into my head like that's
almost in some way like 15 or 30 years
that most of the Internet,
which is a worldwide will all be
communicating and us with a similar
language.
I said that to my friend.
That's kind of why I brought it up and
he asked if I ever heard of Esperanto.
You ever heard of this language called s
upper antone?
Yeah,
I have,
but I don't remember.
It helped
in 1887 by some guy that was literally
trying to create one language and it's,
if
you look it up now and you can find out
that it's not dead and there's the more,
the fastest growing languages apparently
for people learning to speak something
different.
Right.
Never fucking heard of it though before
this week.
Oh,
I mean it's one of the fastest growing
languages.
It's like what else is out there?
Like I know there's no really gross like
English,
Spanish,
Chinese.
That's broad.
That's right below Russian is weird.
And then I'm going to stop and learn,
start to learn Russian or a sephardic or
weird language.
I just learned,
I just slammed how to speak times new
Roman.
Anyway,
a
style,
you know what I mean?
Been into lately is uh,
did you watch narcos?
Yes.
Well I went,
started doing more research after that
cause I was like Jonesing for more
narcos and they're done for now.
No season two did you go to high?
Just watched all the seasons.
Four episodes.
It God,
is it good?
And it leaves you just wanting so much
more in the end and it's great.
It's great in a good way.
It leaves you wanting more.
And uh,
so I started watching more and more
documentaries and holy shit.
What,
what is going well,
what goes on down there might be one of
the most amazing things in all of the
world.
Which ones you want,
uh,
that something temporary.
Most likely it's in,
it's got a Spanish title and it's in
Spanish with English subtitles and it's
got all the videos and all the pictures
of Pablo Escobar.
All of it.
Like all of it.
Videos of him getting dragged off the
roof
had the,
the,
when he's young,
when he's spoiler alert,
a lot of people don't know he's dead.
Tony,
everybody that's like Hitler.
Spoiler alert.
Well,
it's funny.
It's funny you mentioned that because I
started a documentary,
uh,
yesterday about how on Netflix about how
or might still be alive and living in
the Andes and it was the dumbest
documentary.
I W I so badly wanted it to get my
attention at all.
And it was just,
it had nothing half an hour in.
I had to shut it off.
Wasn't there a history channel show
called fighting Hitler?
Well,
they go searching for Hitler because I
thought that maybe Hitler escaped to
South America.
Wouldn't that be great?
He's in Argentina.
Well,
you know,
that was where a lot of Nazis went.
Yeah.
A lot of Nazis escape Germany and went
to South America.
Wouldn't it be great if people that went
out looking for Hitler ended up finding
big foot and the people,
the people that went out looking for
bigfoot,
like I'm forest and just Hitler walks by
and like go about your business.
They found bones,
a little mustache or
my friend Adam Green tree who's on the
other day was telling me about
aborigines.
He came over my house last night.
We had dinner and he would
some stuff that I really wished he
brought up on the podcast because it's
fucking crazy to Abbott or aborigines,
not in Australia.
Not only do they not have like a re,
most of them don't have a written
language,
but they could live.
Someone could live here and then you
could live 10 miles away and it'd be a
totally different language and they call
their tribes mobs.
They called it,
they call my mob.
That's like,
so you have one mob and then you have
another mob that's like 1520 kilometers
away.
The totally different language.
And I go,
how many of them are there?
Like how many different languages?
He's like,
Oh fuck thousands.
I was like thousands.
And he was like,
not only that,
when they die,
like nobody knows that language.
Nobody knows their history,
it's all gone.
And there was this one cave,
like literally a fucking cave for these
people were living in.
And they were apparently when,
you know,
they settled this area,
like the aborigines obviously were there
first.
And then when the white people came and
settled,
when they raising cattle,
the aborigines were stealing the cattle
to them.
They didn't think of it as stealing.
They thought it was a ho,
hey,
here's some food,
I'm gonna eat it.
And so they ate the cows and the
ranchers got pissed.
So they brought them food and poison
them.
And there's this cave that he found that
he took all these photographs.
Adam did office site,
you probably find it.
I'm on Adam Green trees of photography
page and yeah,
and it is filled with bones to bones of
these 30 people that live there were
part of this mob cause they're,
they live in these really small tribes
and they poisoned them.
So they brought them food and they put
it,
he said,
we found like babies,
little tiny ribs,
like a little three inch long ribs from
a baby that got poisoned and he's like
the entire tribe.
She's dead and their bones,
which is there just laying inside this
cave and he's got photographs with this
cave.
It's really crazy.
Like he'd go inside the caves,
all this weird art work of all these
weird animals,
including some animals that like doesn't
even exist anymore like dead
brontosaurus who's depicted on the wall
like with the long neck or [inaudible]
or something like that.
But the idea that these people live
there for so long and had all these
different dialects,
they're like someone 20 miles away would
speak way different than people here and
none of it was written down.
Now their history was written down.
Like all of it was just like stories
that they told over the campfire or
whatever.
I thought you were going to go into the
uh,
big foot Australia thing.
I was in that.
Do they have it?
Did they talk about it there or if you
watched finding big foot,
they say they have one.
Okay.
What did he do?
Get on?
Uh,
get on a ship.
I grew up there.
He grew up in Australia.
They have their own,
they have their own portals or
something.
Well,
there's um,
an animal in,
I think it's Vietnam.
They called the Orang.
Pendek.
I think that's what from Vietnam for
somewhere around maybe somewhere else.
Maybe it's an amnesia,
but uh,
the Orang pendek was like a,
as like a small hairy monkey man that's
like,
but I think it's a little,
I think it's the only like four feet
tall or something like that.
And they think that that thing,
at least the legend of that thing is
probably similar to that.
Hobbit,
man,
Homo flory is four.
He assists four yeses.
I think that's what you're saying.
I think that's it.
It's from the island of Flores.
They found these a hobbit.
People legitimately were a different
species of human,
like this really weird look in three
foot tall little hobbit person.
Creepy.
Oh yeah.
And they existed fairly recently.
Like,
I think they found bones that were as
recent as 14,000 years ago.
Geez.
Yeah.
So 14,000 years ago,
there's a little hobbit.
People were running around.
Not only that,
they think that they had like real
problems with people at the interact
with each other,
fight with each other,
maybe prayed on each other.
Yeah.
Well not like hobbits or they liked the
hobbits,
Lord of the rings.
There were like three magical people or
something.
Kind of,
no,
no.
I don't think that they were respected.
Right.
Yeah,
they did.
Did some street cred.
Yeah.
I mean they were cool.
Maybe they got fucked with because they
were a little right.
And it's just trying to remember,
cause I feel ah,
they didn't wear shoes.
Did that they were like hairy feet
number.
Big Hairy feet.
That's a little creepy.
Okay.
Yeah.
Potentially.
You know,
when Dominic Monaghan was on a podcast,
I literally almost forgot that he was a
hobbit.
You know,
cause I,
I thought of him as the guy from Los
Charlie.
Charlie from loss or drowned.
Yeah.
So sad.
He said,
Charlie,
he's back.
He's alive.
We were,
um,
yeah,
he's great.
So yes,
I been getting more into these,
uh,
Pablo Escobar documentaries just live in
that kind of lifestyle,
you know what I mean?
Just live in that life for him.
Smoking joints,
watch and Pablo Escobar,
smoking joints.
Yeah.
I liked what he wore were like grandpa
sweaters and shit.
Yeah,
he went to worst clothes.
Yeah.
He had like bad running shoes.
Pretty sure the Cardigan.
I warned my special,
he's one at some point and
I was just hearing that some people
think that uh,
El Chapo might have more money and more,
uh,
reach then Escobar did,
but not more power or at least not more
power within the countries.
Right.
Well,
definitely not now.
Yeah,
it's definitely different time period
too,
but he's fucked now.
He broke his leg trying to get away.
Jumped you there.
I think the reason it got brought up was
because this lawyer is currently
complaining that he's being tortured in
prison and how's it being tortured?
He was in prison for a long time before
though.
Right.
He's in prison for a long time.
Then he escaped and then they got them
again.
They just keep again,
skip four times.
I think
he's a freak.
He's a big time freak.
How crazy.
This is.
Sean Penn went to meet him.
I went to meet him and did an article
for rolling stone shaking his hand.
I mean,
it's unbelievable.
What was he thinking?
You're a movie star,
Dude.
Why do you want to go meet Pablo?
Not Pablo Escobar,
but El Chapo
didn't.
Did he give her and he,
and I'm giving them,
they're like,
did he have to tell someone where you
met him?
Um,
or don't know why he says word
journalistic.
Uh,
like
freedom.
I don't remember,
but I do remember that there was a girl
that he knew there was an actress that
hooked it all up.
Yeah.
She banging them.
But that was going on.
I'm like,
I hope so.
That's,
that's what I like about narcos to
report a check.
Did he bang?
So every now and then,
yeah,
breaking news.
But that life's crazy to think about
that and they'll look at how they ran
that and just scaring people.
And to be able to fight your own
government and lock yourself in and
escape.
And I'm the people for you,
but with you,
and it's
scary.
But let's look at it this way.
Is it scary than the people that sell
oxycontin?
The kills thousands of people every year
and nobody does a thing about it.
They do a completely legal and
everybody's paid off.
That might be scarier because yeah,
they don't have to use violence and
shoot people in the street and threaten
people and scare people.
And people don't live under this blanket
of fear that they lived under during the
Pablo Escobar days.
But just many people are dying and just
as much money's being made,
maybe more people are dying.
You are right.
And I mean about the fear thing,
like granted,
it's tough to compare the two,
but if you compare all the people that
have been afraid of getting caught with
marijuana over the past,
you know,
decades,
because that I feel like has mostly been
brought on or at least kept in place by
big medicine then and all of that stuff
that stemmed from marijuana and like a
selling marijuana and having a gun for
marijuana and this and that and all that
stuff.
Then you put all that together.
It's a much bigger imprint than it
seems,
you know?
It's a big imprint,
but here's the,
the weirdest one now in 2016 for the
first time,
more people are using pain pills.
Then tobacco in the United States,
including cigars,
Chu cigarettes,
the whole thing,
everything.
More people using fucking prescription
pain pills.
Wow.
Then using tobacco,
which is nuts because you can go down
any street and see people smoking
cigarettes everywhere you go.
Oh yeah.
Not too long.
Or You,
I think you'd tried to have me look up
how many prescriptions with like our out
for adderall and the u s and as I was
trying to look it up,
I don't think that that's like public
info.
Like wouldn't want that out there with
it.
Well sometimes that stuff gets out in
some sort of a way,
you know,
cause I could,
I had a hard time finding it.
I just had like rough guesstimations
different things.
It's always happening based off of
whatever.
But yeah,
so we were like,
who lives in Florida?
You could go get 10 oxicon things like
this and you just go over down to things
like those are being tracked.
Same any more.
They used to be like that,
but it's way different now.
Back then when they were doing that,
the oxycontin express days,
there was more people that were getting
oxycontin prescriptions in Florida than
the rest of the country combined.
Damn,
that's a Florida at Florida.
So crazy is the strongest painkiller
that just makes you basically my heroin.
It's not even the strongest painkiller,
the strongest painkillers.
That's tough.
How do you say it?
Phenological fentanyl,
fentanyl and fentanyl is spending a shit
load of money to try to keep marijuana
illegal in Arizona.
They spent $500,000 to try to stop the
legalization of recreational marijuana
in Arizona
downstairs.
Is that not a red flag then?
How are they,
how can they do that
creational thing on the ballot for the
California?
Yes,
I remember it being discussed for
English.
It's like it should be talked about a
lot.
It should be talked about a lot.
Um,
it's pretty much like established in
most people's eyes isn't just going to
pass.
Yeah.
I mean once they see how much money
Colorado is raking in,
plus Jerry Brown's,
our governor,
that walking a hippie and a half
wanting to the front of the shell or the
money too.
I was,
I saw articles in bring up recently on a
podcast,
but I forget how much they,
it's,
it's as much as Colorado if not more.
And then I just saw some reason
Colorado's going $66 million,
they're going to go towards bully at
like advocacy or something like that.
Like they have that much of a surplus.
How,
how do you stop bullying with money?
What do you do?
Programs and stuff.
I think.
I don't know that they will.
I'll tell you how,
what you do,
you give the bullies the money.
That's how you do it.
You get the bullies,
the money.
All of a sudden guess who's lunch money.
They're not taken.
Do we be little sons?
How about that?
Let's solve the epidemic right word.
Okay.
The real way to solve it would be to
teach them how to fight.
Teach a martial arts.
Yeah.
They wouldn't be beaten each other up.
They'd be competing,
you know,
or they look like pussies.
When I was in like middle school that
try this thing was migrated school cause
we were known as like the ghetto school
up to like six or seven little catholic
schools in our area because we had black
kids at our school.
And that's why you were known as the
ghetto school?
Yeah,
I think so.
I mean what,
we weren't in the ghetto or anything
like that and it was a private Catholic
school.
It's not like it's not,
it wasn't a free public.
What was ghetto about it?
We don't like it.
It riverbank.
Any black girls not.
And I was in middle school.
No,
no,
but not anyway.
Um,
anyway,
so we have to,
the dances we were delivering were like,
this is the 19 nine in mid 96,
96 we're like rap music was still like
gangster rap was getting big.
So some of all black kids liked it when
they put it on it or a dance then start
like we jump around and everyone get
little kids at a party raise 13 either
way all the parents or the kids at those
schools didn't like it.
So we got complained to or against and
for the next two years we had what they
called conflict resolution as an actual
class instead of like art for some,
for like a year where we had to like do
workshops and worksheets about how to be
acting with other kids in situations
like it was,
no one took it seriously at all.
But like they told us that's what it was
for us because we weren't acting like we
got banned from the dances at those
schools that we couldn't go there and
get to have our own.
Did you feel like a rebel?
No dumb.
We didn't understand why it was done
when they were being picked off.
What'd you guys literally it came from,
I remember an incident where there was
like a song came on and a bunch of kids
from my school specifically gotten a a
circle and we're like jumping around
like put their hands up.
I don't remember the song.
I've been slammed by Onyx and through,
yeah it's so like all the white guy
went,
this is what I think happened and I'm
pretty sure it did.
Like all the white kids were like
freaking out like what the fuck's going
on and what has been the teachers that
were watching it over and won't like
what are all these kids doing from the,
that school ghetto school over there on
the east side.
We can't be having that with our kids.
Fuck that.
And they think they complained and then
two years later,
once all those troubled kids are up in
high school and there's some new kids in
an aren't act enough,
we'll try to dance and see how it goes.
And then
I only went away and I got a dumb
question.
That earpiece.
So you weren't [inaudible] has a
microphone on it.
That microphone is picking taken up,
right?
I'm just saying that you're thing man.
So they segregated the dances.
Who wants to go to the all white people
dance?
You know what I mean?
Why people don't want to be around black
people?
Well I mean black people have the best
dances,
I'll tell you that right now.
What if you're in a line dancing though?
What have you like super into like
white,
white dance.
Go.
I'll,
he was blind.
The incident at least not around here.
I was in the,
um,
I was in a country restaurant bar once
and they all started lion dancing to
some fucking song.
They knew the song and they all started
doing this like dancing together and we
were looking at each other like,
what fuck is going on?
Like they all knew the song and they
were all dancing together.
But I do the dance,
like the electric slide but not the
lectures.
Right.
But like a
backhoe fucking country dance.
Yeah.
It's like wow.
Have you ever seen a big group of black
people do like,
uh,
one of those dance flashmob things?
Yes.
And it was awesome.
Wasn't it better?
I thought I saw one,
two,
three,
three or four summers ago in San Diego.
I remember.
It's when,
um,
Kanye and Jay z got together and they
made an album and he made a song,
Edwards words in Paris and it's stole
this summer and it was just one of those
songs where you are hearing it all
summer and it had a big beat and
everything.
We were in an outdoor bar in San Diego
and all of a sudden it came on and it
was like a hot Saturday night,
middle of the summer.
And all of a sudden it came,
they came around the corner like doing
like it was almost like you were in the
music video thriller and,
and I'm looking at them and then I take
a moment cause I'm sorta like creepily
aware,
you know what I mean?
To look around and see what the white
people are doing it this like outdoor
bar and everybody was just mesmerized.
It was like,
I dunno like Cirque de Solei except it
was just a bunch of cool black people
dancing,
walking down the street at the same time
in synchronization with each other.
Yeah.
So many videotapes,
some flash mob in the middle of New York
City on a day like,
yeah.
They had some thing where everybody
agreed to meet at a certain place at a
certain time.
Then when the clock strikes midnight,
everybody fucking jumps in and gets
crazy and dances around.
I love shit like that.
Yeah,
because that's not organized by a
company that's not like some marketing
campaign from some cell phone provider.
That's an organic thing that people just
decided to get crazy.
Yeah.
When the intentions are just to be
silly,
just to have fun.
That's what makes it worse.
Yeah.
To kind of happen.
When we were in San Francisco this year,
the Nag,
I walked to the top of Fremont Street,
that's what the lining one.
And uh,
the meeting of the naked bike bike ride
was up there and it was just,
it was all guys Lombard Street,
our street off for much the naked bike
riders,
medical guys all over 40.
None at like all out of shape.
But they were all button naked on a bike
in the middle,
like noon mill coffee on their huffy.
It was not the right flash nod to be
walking into worst flight ever naked
dudes on bicycles.
The flashing,
flashing flash mobs.
Interesting.
Then that clothes are mandatory if you
take your clothes off the throwing of
fucking jail.
Well there was a thick cops there that
weren't really doing anything well in
San Francisco.
Yeah,
I was thinking about that the other day
cause I was driving back from Sacramento
middle of the day on Sunday.
And I literally,
I went through the drive through,
they gave me a burger.
I didn't,
they didn't put Napkins in the bag.
And I'm like,
I'm eating on the road,
I want to make it back to la,
blah blah blah blah.
An hour later I'm finishing my coffee,
just state that Burger,
no napkins and the car finished my uh,
or no,
I didn't and that anyway,
and I start to have to shit and I mean
like badly and I mean like it's an
immediate emergency and I'm looking and
it's one of those stretches in northern
California where it's like next rest
area,
43 miles and I'm looking as I'm driving
on the freeway,
I'm looking to see like what kind of
bushes there are and stuff and there's
like nothing and I mean nothing.
It's just fucking cow pastors forever.
And I'm like,
fuck,
can't ship behind that can't shut behind
them.
You know,
you're just driving down looking,
you're squeezing them and I'm squeezing
and squeezing so hard that for the first
time in my life I was like standing up
while driving like I was,
I was,
I was up on my left foot because it felt
like my butt cheeks could get tighter if
I like was in a standing position rather
than setting and I mean I'm doing
everything.
I'm literally praying to God for the
first time in like five or six years.
I mean like I'm literally like whatever.
If anything is controlling any of the
universe,
I need your right now
I can't ship
because by the way,
they were also,
I was wearing these like gray shorts.
They're like cloth shorts.
I mean it would have been so terrible,
so terrible.
And
what the fuck were we just talking?
No shirt.
Oh,
about not having clothes on.
I realized right then like I'm like,
I'm Ha,
I'm going to have to pull over on the
side of the street and without a Bush
I'm going to have to,
shit boobs going to come out of my butt
no matter what happens.
And people are going to drive by and I'm
thinking to myself how illegal that is.
Cause I think like he can't even pull
your pants down and get away with it.
Well that happens and I'm thinking
that's crazy being naked.
It's crazy.
But we all Poop and pee all of us 100%
of all people.
But you have to find a public bathroom.
Like you can't just knock on someone's
door of the freeway public.
It is.
I'm kind of,
yes it is.
Yeah,
but you're not allowed to shit outside.
Like if you pee outside,
here's where it gets really interesting.
Yeah.
If you pee outside,
you get caught.
You can be arrested as a sex offender.
It happened to people before it,
especially if you were in view of a
school,
you could go from a brown alert to an
amber alert real quick.
Okey dokey.
How did you resolve it?
Wow.
What ended up happening
was my prayers to the universe ended up
working because like,
you know how every once in awhile,
how close you've been to shitting your
pants lately.
But like it bubbles up and you're like,
fuck off.
Fuck off.
Fuck.
You know what I mean?
And then sometimes it'll just be like,
all right,
let them,
you know,
let them go for a little bit and it'll
just be,
everything will be okay for like two
minutes.
Oh my God.
Did it pass?
It's like a hurricane.
It's like when you hear people
describing hurricanes,
I thought the eye,
the eye of the storm Rd.
And then two minutes later it Garner and
I ended up making it.
And what's crazy that I do remember
about this and I made it to the first
gas station that was 41 miles.
I mean I was just sweating,
dude,
I don't know how to describe it.
I'm like 40 miles quenching emergency
shit.
You bought off the chair the whole time.
My left leg was sore,
my whole alignment is off.
I get adjusted to go to a reiki master.
And what's crazy is that because like
there's actually another piece to this
amazing puzzle is that after you've been
holding it for 41 miles or whatever and
you know even do all this shit and once
you make it to the closest restroom,
that first gas station off that first
exit and you go to the men's room and
you're in,
there's only one stall there.
Okay.
That is the stall of
demolition my friend.
I mean once I was in and I was,
I mean you just notice there's graffiti
everywhere.
There's toilet paper.
Every everything you've ever seen is
everywhere because that is the stall of
anybody who's almost shit there.
Every man coming southbound from
northern California that had to shit in
this 40 miles span class through that
door and the glass through that stall
door and just,
I mean it is the stall.
So that's what's crazy is that like yeah
there was a few other gas stations on
that exit but I'm like,
I remember literally being like,
ah,
like I was in that final red light.
Cause you're,
once you see it's a weird thing your
body does too.
It is,
once you see the gas station,
you see the restroom,
that's when it's like,
you know,
it's like real people,
like I said,
a fixed set of faces but just like can't
take it anymore.
It's like there it is.
It is really fucking bizarre that you
are not allowed to be naked.
Yeah.
Like that your body comes like out of
the box with no clothes.
We require you to purchase clothes or
make them,
I mean if you,
I guess you could have a bunch of leaves
glued together.
No one could stop you as long as no one
can see your genitals.
And then even then we have like rules
for that.
Like a girl can wear a thong.
So literally she can have a string that
goes over her asshole and then just a
little Dorito that covers her clit and
we're like,
we're good.
We're good.
Oh do you have uh,
some bandaids for your nipples?
Cause I don't want to see your dirty
fucking stinky brown skin,
Brown nipple skin.
You dirty bitch.
Like you'd see all the,
the voluptuousness of the outside.
It's very weird.
We're real weird with clothes.
It is like you could have like beaches
where people get nude,
but you have to have an agreement.
Like this is the,
this is the beach where everybody's
allowed to not wear clothes,
but for the most part you have to wear
clothes.
That's
it was interested to hear for,
we're moving a camera,
taking a picture,
like eight guys in running a camera or
canoeing down the thing.
They stopped and it was like drinking a
beer and everything like that.
Everyone took a picture and I was like,
let's get the fuck outta here.
You're like,
oh,
let's take a picture.
And then I was like,
all right,
I'll take a fucking picture.
So everyone's,
I moved the camera,
so we did.
And literally like two minutes later out
of the woods in the middle of nowhere,
a sheriff comes down like,
hey guys.
Hey,
we're all like,
what?
What,
What's going on?
He's like,
hey,
why don't you come over here?
We're all like,
aw fuck would we do,
and also the half of us are under age,
like some like 20212120120 two,
the 208 people I think.
And you're not supposed to be drinking
while you're canoeing too.
So we knew we were kind of fucked.
Uh,
but he makes us all walk over to him and
he's like,
Hey,
just so you guys know what you just did
is absolutely legal and we're thinking
about it.
He's like,
we,
he's like,
we're thinking about uh,
taking you all in right now for indecent
exposure and we're all media.
Like,
what the fuck are you talking about?
He's like,
who's we first was like,
oh,
we're all,
we spent up there watching you through
all five of us going up binoculars.
We'd been here for,
washed your class 25 minutes.
It's like,
guys,
we should have definitely left.
It should have so left.
And he like pulls the,
to underage people up next to him.
My girlfriend at the time and this other
kid,
he makes us dumped out all of our
liquor.
Like one girl,
I kept the bike hit a bottle of Jack
Daniels in any,
if I was like,
all right,
you know what we're going to remember,
we'll let you guys go but get the fuck
like get the fuck out of here.
Nothing ended up happening.
But enemy,
he also meant,
he said they're like,
it's okay for all you girls to take
pictures with your tops off
but
no asses.
That's illegal.
We're all like,
Huh.
And like I guess from then I've always
like thought or that's I think when I
learned that like girls are allowed to
walk around with their tops off.
Honestly I think it's some states that
we're in Ohio now.
Yeah.
And then the different New York you can
do it right.
That was like a thing that they fought
for it because men can walk around with
no shirts on in New York.
But you know,
up until like the beginning of the,
to the turn of the 20th century,
it was illegal for men to walk around
bare shirt and it was like a big Oh
yeah.
There's like a big movement where I
think,
I want to say like the early 1,980,
the teens,
they uh,
they duked it out.
Like they,
you know,
they,
they fought to have decency thing too.
Well,
I mean men fought to,
to have the right to walk around
shirtless cause fucking hot out
sometimes,
but women couldn't for like a long time,
I want to say until fairly recently.
And apps obviously like,
look,
I understand that a woman's breasts is
more titillating,
no pun intended.
But you,
you can't say like,
men can walk around with their dicks
hanging out,
but when we can't show their vaginas,
that's just crazy.
It is.
Besides that,
are there nipples have to be covered in
our nimbleness or just like,
who's looking fuck monitor useless slam
my nipple and a fucking bag fault.
I wouldn't feel it.
It's different.
Numb.
They don't,
they literally don't feel like anything.
They don't do anything.
I had a girl suck on him once.
I was like,
you could just stop.
Why don't you just suck on my elbow?
It's the same thing.
It is.
So my elbow might be more sensitive.
Yeah.
That's so true.
It's weird because women's nipples get
erect.
They get excited,
they perk up,
no milk shoots out sometimes,
you know,
excited.
Whoa.
Yeah,
they really,
they really like it.
I think that for a long time I always
thought that a boobs for girls were the
same like for guys.
And it was like not that much feeling.
So I sort of like always ignored them.
This vagina thing is the most important
and uh,
man,
I learned a little bit later on that
like girls like that their boots are
different than our boobs.
Yeah.
Like last week,
a couple of weeks ago.
Yeah.
That's interesting.
It's interesting that the differences,
what we're allowed to get away with,
what we're not allowed to get away with.
You know,
like imagine it men wore skirts to
meetings.
If Mandy can have like little skirts,
no killed.
Yeah.
Kind of do.
But that's like this does,
does a dress I think goes down your
knees.
Yeah.
And it's got like a big belt buckle and
stuff to make it cool.
I think thinking of pilgrims
sometimes they,
I got a little Satchel thing,
it's like a fanny pack.
You mean like,
I'm sorry but it had,
I pooped off that side of that road and
just been like poop coming out of my
butt and like a police officer comes and
arrest me for that.
I would make no pun intended,
but I would make a really big stink
about that because I mean it's like it's
supposed to shit your pants in your car,
just deal with it.
I that's the question,
right?
What do you do?
And by the way,
it was a rental car.
I knew there was one more thing I was
forgetting a rental car with the gray
interior gray cloth Interior Nolan
that you pay for the insurance or how's
that work?
Well you should take that cup from the
coffee and just shit right in that
coffee thing was,
is that it was a fenty.
It was tall.
I'm already shit in it.
We squeezed shut,
tossing out the window.
You put it right back in there.
You keep filling it up.
Ah.
Have you ever taken a shit where it
comes out like a volcano above the water
and you're like,
oh my God,
this is an above ground shit.
I could literally so much shit that it's
rising above the water.
The toilet,
my 12th my current one's a little too
small for me.
All your shit and a lot of shit and
hardcore.
No water in there.
A lot of meat.
Does it ever a climb all the way up to
get that extra smell?
You're like,
well shit,
when the smell becomes three D
it's literally going above the water.
It's out in the air.
It's quite strange.
Well No,
I mean not entirely,
but obviously I'm walking up bathroom
just so much shit.
Well it's still gas,
but I need a steak.
It's a bit traps a lot then there.
Yeah.
What's with the matches?
Is that like burning the gas in there?
Is that what that's supposed to be
about?
I would just set it out a lot.
I think at a,
the fire sucks oxygen,
so must have to be sucking some
other gas and fucking with it,
but I think it's,
I think it's just the,
the software.
That was the thing that I need.
Just know that someone shitting there so
better than smelling shit,
you know it's getting in your,
on your tongue because it knows it's
fitting and you're tasting it.
Right.
Just smelling shift molecules.
Yeah.
If you could smell it in the air,
it's everywhere.
[inaudible] dealt with the gas
molecules.
What am weird design and that every
animal has he eat things.
Anybody's like I would take all is
useful stuff.
We've got a lot of garbage.
I was just get rid of that stuff.
It comes out like there's no way he did.
There's no way you can eat just the
right amount of food where you don't
ever shit or you don't ever piss.
It just goes to your studio.
I've been here,
I've heard a recent story again it on,
remember why this came up,
but like recall rectal implant.
What's that called?
The feed fecal implant.
Fecal implant.
Some guy I was sick and he had to have
his friendship with them or something
like that and it made him better.
That's disgusting and really weird how
that works.
That does work.
Somebody else's shit put into something
wrong.
He got somebody else to shift with them
and fix this,
this stomach.
So yeah.
Well,
Gut Flora is one of the most important
aspects of health that is only really
being understood over the last few
decades.
People really didn't know that the
bacteria inside your gut has not,
not only does it just affect your
stomach,
but it affects your personalities.
Are Neurons in the guide or some affects
your mood?
Well,
not that it's just the,
there's a,
some sort of a symbiotic relationship
that we have with our gut flora.
And when your flora is bad,
it has all sorts of negative
consequences on your immune system.
I'm big enough probiotics.
Over the last few years I've been eating
a lot of Kimchi.
I drink,
um,
what is that stuff called?
Dot.
Keifer is a Kefir or Keith,
I think a key for it,
but I don't know.
I never really say it.
And read it.
Um,
Kombucha,
lots of different probiotics.
I take those on it.
Total gut health packets.
If I've got a stack with me,
I travel on the road with it and don't
go on it anyway without it.
But acid awfulness,
like all that kind of stuff,
like having a healthy gut flora and it
makes a giant difference on whether you
get sick,
how long your sickness and lasts you
can't his or can you take too much of
that where your body just get rid of it?
If it doesn't want it to be a question,
I would imagine.
Well,
it's healthy.
I don't know if it's,
I don't think it's like,
uh,
like certain vitamins are fat soluble
and if you take too many of them in,
it could fuck with you and you really
want to make sure we get the right
amount.
I don't think that's the same with,
um,
with,
with healthy bacteria it's really,
it's like almost like troops.
Like you're bringing in healthy troops
to fight off bad,
bad bacteria,
like for people to do Jujitsu.
Anybody who's listening to this and does
Jujitsu,
super important that you take
probiotics.
It's very,
very,
and never wash yourself with antibiotic
soap ever.
Cause when you wash yourself with
antibiotics,
so it'd be stripped your body of all gut
flora or of all skin flora of the good
stuff to you.
What you want to do is use something
like defense soap that has healthy oils
that only promotes healthy flora and,
but it doesn't kill the,
uh,
the good stuff.
It promotes healthy flora and protects
you from the bad shit from getting like
ring Marlin's.
Yeah,
but it's not an antibiotic bacteria.
So like antibacteria so I had a friend
of mine who was a Jujitsu guy who had a
ringworm.
He started washing themselves with
antibacterial soap and he got fucking
ringworm everywhere because his body
couldn't fight it off
legal now or something.
Or it's antibacterial is something or a
certain kinds of,
there's a certain camouflaged most of
them.
Well we don't have jamie to check facts
check.
Jamie started talking about throwing
around questions,
start thinking about things that,
I remember,
Jay,
if we were doing the regular podcast at
the studio,
Jamie would have the answers up on the
screen.
But now Jamie's like throwing the
question.
Yeah,
yeah.
FDA
issues,
final rule,
safeties and effectiveness of
antibacterial soaps.
Bands try glisten and 18 other chemicals
from soaps to track.
Listen is something that it was found in
lots of things like from toothpaste to
have antibacterial soap.
I guess it's no,
it's no Bueno.
What's the deal with fluoride?
Like what's the real deal with fluoride?
Because fluoride is fucking poison.
But I've heard people say that fluoride
is good for like for uh,
for healthy teeth and prevent tooth
decay.
But then I've heard that's total
bullshit.
And the only thing that's helping your
tooth decay is that you're not broken.
You know,
you're,
you're cleaning your teeth and that's
what's healthy.
But it's not the fluoride,
nothing.
They put it in the water supply and
people thought that that's poisoning.
Yeah.
That's where people think that it's like
designed to make you stupid.
This is a shitty new search to know
about that.
Yeah.
This is a terrible fucking research
podcast.
This one,
you're upset at this.
You should be a very rough
fucking guys.
All they have is questions.
No accident.
We're going to have a companion podcast
to this where we actually check
everything
then as usual.
It's kind of funny though that
we do have this whole ecosystem thing
going on in our body that it's not just
your body.
You have to prep your body from invading
bacteria.
No,
your body is filled with bacteria.
It's like the whole thing's bacteria.
It's like you're like a little planet.
Yeah.
It's weird.
We were,
we made,
we were made from like calm being in
like a hot vagina.
Even crazy math were made from stars
exploding first.
Okay.
It had a star had explode in order to
create the very building blocks for
life.
What in the fuck
it didn't much shoes last week.
Uh,
lot of stars out there,
Joshua.
Yeah.
Rarely felt like nothing.
Did you love it?
This is amazing.
Yeah.
It's so great.
I need to get out to Joshua tree.
It's so beautiful out there.
Wait,
when,
when is already do that?
Shrimp fest is July,
I think it was September this year.
It rotates either in July or August or
September.
A lot depends on the super moon.
Oh,
he only does it during the supermarket.
Yeah.
The weekend of the Super Moon.
Like the week of we can go outside.
Yeah.
Mm.
Bright Moon.
That was interesting.
This one was a different one because
this wasn't officially stream fast.
We just went cause we all missed,
well I missed shroom fast,
which was a couple of months ago or
whatever.
But uh,
and this one didn't have the moon out
right away.
So it was actually my first time in four
or five years without the moon.
Crazy as that is.
But it was there in a few hours,
but it wasn't there the first few hours
in the stars out there.
I mean there's just no way to describe
it.
They're just fucking everywhere you
would do when you can't look at a
specific place and not see it.
A huge column for them.
And you can't look at the sky for 30
seconds to two minutes in a row without
seeing another shooting star.
It's impossible.
Wow.
If you're not seeing one,
then you're looking down.
Isn't that crazy that those are rocks
from space?
It probably came from millions of miles.
Well,
and I was out there.
I was thinking about how that was the
natural,
how that had to be like the first form
of entertainment.
Like what else would you watch?
Yeah,
there was no falling asleep to Netflix.
It was,
I saw the stars last night and uh,
that was it.
And you hear a twig snap behind you that
was entertaining.
You're out there wandering around on
mushrooms.
You worry about spiders or anything like
that.
Yeah,
I was afraid of a little,
we had a little,
a little mouse that kept running around
our campsite that at one point I was
like way too afraid of,
was it a mouse or the tiniest little
mouse?
Little Cutie mouth.
It was freaking me out.
Yeah,
it was freaking me out.
I'm just getting too close.
It seemed like it was on mushrooms with
us.
And I'm like,
get Outta here dude.
Maybe like new.
You guys were vulnerable.
It felt like it did close it on.
Yeah.
Animals definitely know the difference
between dark and day.
I think it really bold at night as
opposed to during the day.
During the day they keep the fuck away
from me and be like deer at night.
They're not nearly as worried about
people.
That's like almost like they know all
these fuckheads.
They can't see that good
like look bears.
It's really disturbing.
Like bears at nighttime they didn't do
very,
very like confident.
They're not nervous about people at all.
If you ever around bears at night,
as it starts getting dark,
they start closing in on you and looking
at you differently.
Did bears have good nighttime vision?
Oh yeah.
A lot of them were very nocturnal.
All animals are.
Oh,
you mean almost all animals can see way
better
and then we don't.
We have nothing.
We have no
mission there,
but we have night vision goggles and
guns and cars.
It's not like biological evolution,
but it's,
we still,
we still got there.
We have a machine gun.
If sitting out the sunroof and played
Panama from led Zeppelin or from a van
Halen rather.
I was like blown away
Panama.
Got them down.
Fuck your evolution.
How about that?
I'm a fuck you night vision.
You could see you bitch.
Stop trying to eat me.
Yeah.
Bugs,
snakes.
All those things out in Joshua tree are
fucking creepy.
Coyotes.
I told her I haven't seen any of those
things.
We've heard coyotes out there and the,
that's creepy when that happens,
but you know they're like in the
distance.
You just here.
Ooh,
that's cool though,
right?
Yes.
Super Cool.
It adds a real,
like you're almost like,
was that a human being fucking with us.
But
do you know coyotes or wolves?
I don't know.
They're wolves are small wolf.
Hmm.
They're all in the same family.
I think that's how they make those coy
wolves.
They interbreed with each other back and
forth.
They're there.
They make viable offspring to there now.
They don't make like,
like some animals make a hybrid and the
hybrid can't give birth or can't get
pregnant or can't make another animal
pregnant.
Not coyotes.
Coyotes can fuck dogs too.
Wow.
So can walls,
will can fuck dogs.
It's really interesting.
But what a coyote is,
is like when they first,
when they first discovered coyotes and
uh,
the,
the settlers arrived,
they called them prairie wolves.
That was the first name for them before
they call them coyotes.
Variables.
Yeah.
It's a lot kit or anything coyote.
It's a lot more memorable.
But then the aztecs called them Kaiyote
and then the Spanish called them Coyote
Otay and then that like there was a
Spanish pronunciation,
the Aztec name for coyotes prairie dog
and go for it.
And same thing.
No,
no.
A prairie dog is different that I could
go for a golfer.
It's different
prairie dogs at groundhog and Zoetis who
has those stupid
questions over overs are smaller
probably,
right?
Like,
yeah,
usually fuck up.
Like Garden.
Yeah,
we have gophers.
I'll go first near my house still the
bigger,
I'll find like she's a little mounds of
dirt.
It's a little fuckers poked out through
my lawn.
It's like weird.
It's like somebody just left a pile of
dirt,
but it's really just a gopher pop
through.
Does prairie dogs though,
man,
they shoot the shit out of those things.
It's really kind of crazy because they,
they're a real nuisance on cattle
ranches because they dig these holes and
then cal step and then they snapped
their legs and it becomes a real
problem.
So they shoot him like crazy and so
people will set up on these fields and
these high powered rifles with scopes
and just waiting for this little
fuckers,
talk to head of them.
Boom.
That sounds like fun.
Was video brock lesnar shooting a
prairie dog with like some ungodly gun,
like a 50 caliber gun and he says hello.
That's the kind of hunting I can get
into.
I could go out and be like the prairie
dog guy.
That's your your new thing?
Yeah,
prairie dog.
The prairie dog.
Prairie dog.
The bounty hunter.
I could see you going out hunting with
like a Bandana on a cruise.
I got the lead singer of poison.
I can see you with like a prairie dog
Bandana with like fake hair if you put
on like a wig,
fake longer hair.
Eh,
he's dated a prairie dog out there that
are surrounding
and then just get to go out.
He's supposed to meet people out there.
They get,
they get out there a little early and
you don't expect them to,
you're out there fucking a dead prairie
dog.
Hey,
Whoa,
we'll you let me know you're there.
Eh,
we roles as a stone.
Every prairie dog.
Yeah,
you can,
you can shoot nuisance animals.
Isn't that interesting?
Like those,
what's interesting is I was in her dog
and I was trying to figure out how to
work prairie dog and then it would take
somebody out and try to find somewhere
for them to shut up a
public.
That'd be your show.
Yeah.
Prairie dog.
And that with Tony.
That's what I call prairie dog.
There was a,
there's an animal called a ground
squirrel.
It was very different than a tree.
Squirrel and ground squirrels.
You,
he can't eat them.
Tree squirrels apparently are very good.
They taste good.
I've actually eating them.
I shouldn't say apparently of actually
eating them.
They taste good.
It's a weird little animal.
But,
um,
ground squirrels are so common in some
places like to home ranch is 270,000
acres is huge ranch in California.
It has cows,
it has bears,
mountain lions,
deer,
elk,
Turkey.
There is more biomass in prairie dogs
that all those other animals,
there's so many fun,
not prairie dogs,
ground squirrels,
there's more so many fucking ground
squirrels.
So like when the guy was telling me
that,
I was like,
wow,
are you serious?
He goes,
if you weighed all of the ground
squirrels on his,
he would weigh
as much as everything else combined.
Like how is that possible?
So,
so then we're driving down the road,
he's like,
just pay attention and watch 'em off.
And so as we're driving down the road
and you see them,
like as they hear the car coming,
they've jumped out of their holes and
scatter and run to another whole jump
out of the whole scatter.
And you're seeing them all over the
place,
like 20,
30,
40 in,
in your immediate vision,
just popping out of holes are running.
There's dig a little holes in the
ground.
Dive into them.
Creepy.
Yeah.
So they go out there and try to kill
them.
But you only see them for like a half a
second.
Like you barely can get a shot off a
good day.
You killed like two or three of them.
But this fucking thousands of them just
running around.
Well it was doing anything.
So there's a hanging on underground.
Well they spread diseases according to
this guy.
He's like certain Mites.
Mites become a real issue.
Apparently Mites are real.
I found out about [inaudible] Mites when
I was in Nevada are telling me you you
can't handle a jackrabbit.
Like if you shoot a Jack Rabbit and
handle it and if you don't have gloves
on,
you can get these mites on you and they
can give you a serious bacterial
infection that you got to need
antibiotics for.
It's like it's seriously dangerous and
people have died from it.
People have gotten that bacterial
infection not going to treat it and
fucking died from mites.
Oh rabbit.
That's crazy.
Yeah,
man.
More useless facts.
That was crazy.
No diseases on any animals and then
nuts.
Yeah,
no salmon knows.
At least that's why.
What's his face?
Jai depth.
Got In trouble bringing his dog over
there.
Hey,
fuck it.
Yeah.
Australia,
China depth.
Trying to ruin the party over there.
God Damn.
Piece of shit.
That's a funny show.
Do you watch that on Netflix at all?
Australian border security.
Yeah.
Great show.
Our TSA is boring as fuck and we don't
film stuff like I for some reason our
government doesn't care to make money
like that.
You know what I mean?
Like make a production out of it.
Right.
But Australia is like fuck it.
And pretty much they just get all these
people coming in from America,
Chai and I Canada,
your plane lands,
you're going through Tsa.
They just start fucking like check out
this guy right here.
He's acting on a little suspicious.
Right.
And then they'd come through and they're
like,
why are you suspicious?
And he's like,
nothing suspicious.
What's going on?
And like it just like,
you know,
then they ended up finding that,
they show you the suitcase x ray and
they were like,
this seems to be a little something
here.
And then maybe we want to tell us what's
in your suitcase.
Is there anything else thing they're
always like,
no.
And then you know they find cocaine or
something like that and it's like
they're smuggling it in from wherever
and they're just busted and they show
you right at the end.
Like he got sentenced to 20 years in
Australian prison.
Like he just landed there and then it's
been good.
Hello,
welcome and good bye done.
When you go to a place like that,
do you give up your rights?
So he filmed a cause that work or do
they like to say,
I really don't think it's,
you're in their country,
it's not.
And I like to know you're not an
American.
I rated for roles.
I really don't think they give a fuck.
I think they wrote their roles around
like,
hey,
if you don't want to get caught bringing
drugs and then follow the rules while
they're really rough on immigrants,
have you come there illegally and you
don't get a chance to like settle down
and made your case.
They put you on a fucking boat and they
sent me to an island number of jobs is
apps just talking about it.
He's like,
it's really kind of fucked up like what
they do,
but they have a very strict anti
immigration policy like illegal
immigrants do not get treated with any
respect.
It's like what?
What trump was talking about pales in
comparison to what they do on a daily
basis in Australia and Australia,
which seems to be like a place that's
really killing it right now and doing
really good.
They're doing really well.
There are economies super strong.
There's only 20 million of them in a
country the size of the United States.
How many were you up here?
We have 30 million in California.
Oh,
we have 330 million in the country,
so we have 310 million more people than
they have in the same size.
Kind of like half as many people.
I'll show you just in Ohio,
but then it put it in perspective.
I think we need a new car selves.
It's my,
no,
I put it in perspective.
India.
I think India is a third the size of the
United States.
It's got like a billion people one
point.
Oh yeah.
Is that how small it is?
You know,
they make it so when you look at a map,
they make a lot of kids.
But it's another thing on that too.
Sorry.
More questions for us.
The Brazil is a gauge drawn the size of
Brazil's Rome on a map.
Oh yeah.
It's way bigger than [inaudible]
perceived like Africa.
Oh yeah.
Afternoon.
Wade bowling perceived Brazil itself is
also way bigger than it looks like on
that.
How big is India and compares?
What do you guess?
I'm guessing the third.
I'd say slight.
No bigger than like Texas plus a couple
of surrounding states.
So that's close to 30.
Really?
I think it's like half his big.
I don't think it is.
All right.
Let's see.
How big is India?
Any comparison?
Why don't you guys talk while,
you know,
Indians have a lot of kids,
but I never see a,
uh,
Indian porn.
Oh,
you got to look for it.
I mean,
I've seen it a couple of times.
The important stars.
Mia,
she's uh,
she's era brand.
She does like,
like isis porn or something like that
that he said had shot the job.
Something like that and gets down.
Yeah.
She does.
Slightly more than one third of the U s
nailed it.
How'd you find that quick?
I just typed
in India compared to the u s oh yeah.
Things come up right there.
I just got it.
Yeah.
That was pretty crazy.
Amazing.
And a billion people.
So compared to Australia,
you know,
I mean,
think about Australia is three times
larger than India and India has a funk
and million people in it.
Those are perceived.
That's what's crazy is in India,
I'm pretty straight.
You can go anywhere and pour it on your
pants and take an emergency shit.
You can where people do it.
Yeah.
Well our city saw people doing China.
Wow.
Some people just pull over and start to
share.
It's the size of Brazil compared to the
u s and so unless the same size.
Wow.
Yeah.
It's real close to Indiana top.
I'm 30 shirts.
Brazil.
Wow,
that's crazy.
Well,
Africa's the nuttiest one.
When you see African comparison to the
United States,
you know?
Wow.
Like you could fit everything in there.
You could fit America,
fit China,
you fit Asia,
you could fit Europe.
Yeah.
I mean Africa is fucking big man.
Whoa,
whoa.
Exactly right.
Wow.
It's bigger and blacker and everything
started there.
That's what's bizarre.
It's all from there.
Chris Rock special,
right?
Bigger and blacker.
Best word.
No,
that was a no,
I'm not thinking bigger and blacker.
I'm thinking the one he went to Africa
and did stand up when you had that one
is that one whack me out.
Skip changing clothes like I didn't
understand why that was a good idea.
I like this definitely cutting edge at
the time,
but I don't know.
No benefited.
I don't think it was,
I just think it was just a bunch of
shows put together,
showing off.
You're in a bunch of different places,
but it also it,
it releases the veil.
It pulls aside the veil or the same
thing.
The same set up punchline every night.
Like that's like the hidden sort of
subtext to it.
You're letting everyone know like this
is like,
he does it the exact same way.
It sort of exposes a little bit of the
magic of what he's doing.
You know,
great comic.
Like Chris Rock is so smooth on stage.
You get caught up in this,
like you don't thinking that this is a
well prepared,
well-written,
well-rehearsed bit.
You're just laughing at the idea.
But when you see him perform the set up
in one place,
the punchline,
the other,
then you're forced to sort of
internalize like,
oh,
he does this the exact same way
everywhere he goes.
He said it a hundred times four.
It's almost like seeing it twice in some
sort of a way.
We,
you see someone who's really funny and
then you see them again do the same bit.
It's not as good.
It's like even if you really love them,
it's a little less good,
you know?
And so he kind of had that in a special
kind of built in.
It's still great,
you know,
but not in my mind,
not as good.
But that's one of those things where you
just keep trying to do something weird.
Yeah.
Yeah,
keep trying to mix it up like,
like if you did your whole special like
from the beginning to the end with one
camera,
like you showed up and found the whole
thing is just kind of
genius idea.
One shot on Netflix,
Tony Hinchcliffe go see it now.
Are you doing another one in October and
he decided I'm not,
you know,
I'm not going to,
do you want to do what your next one?
I don't know.
I'm going to wait to see when somebody
comes at me with an idea or something
like that and I dunno.
We'll see.
Then again,
if nobody comes at me soon,
maybe I'll just make another one at some
point.
You made yours and then you sold it to
Netflix,
which is,
yeah,
I feel like what I did with the Ice
House,
I can pretty much pitch that to anybody
in the,
I think they'd be down,
you know?
It was a pretty cool deal so,
well it's also shawn,
this was the way you did it.
It's like you really get the sense of
the intimacy of a comedy club,
which I think still is the best venue
for a special,
you know,
cause you're like,
you're in,
in your,
where you're watching television at
home,
you're in your living room,
you're sitting on a couch just like that
usually.
So like stand up should be in a small
room,
you know?
Yeah.
The club,
it's,
it's so cool.
When I did the Ice House with you last
week,
Sean Sullivan,
the GM there came up to me and uh,
we were talking a little bit about it
and he goes,
man,
there's people that come to this spot
right next to the parking spot here.
And they even,
they checked with the employees and us,
they got,
isn't that the spot where Tony starts
and then he goes in and then he comes
back there?
Yeah.
So it's sort of like his like opened up
there,
sir.
You know,
it's sort of like a,
a cool spot.
Like I guess like when you see that
bullet hole in the back of the belly
room sign,
like kinnisons thing.
Yeah.
It's like there's like a little bit of a
language.
They never fixed that sign.
They,
they're trying to fix too many things.
They're trying to fix the patio floor
now and just see that debacle.
But next,
not shiny now.
It was shining.
It was cool.
Was about to slip.
I was like,
what?
And then they sanded it down.
It looks like it's bad.
Why would they fix the bullet hole?
The Sam Kennison putting that sign.
That's like history.
I have to keep that sign.
It makes half to one the one that they
fix the hole.
The hole.
Right.
Okay.
I hope so.
I hope they had to throw it out.
It makes zero sense to fix that.
It still has the bullet hole in the
back.
Oh,
just doesn't have it through the glass.
The plastic part was lit up.
Oh,
I didn't know that was a thing.
Yeah,
he shot right to the fucking thing.
Really?
What a crazy little cane.
Steph an asshole.
Is there a good question back by the
size?
Someone pointed it out there again.
I was like,
I didn't know there was one year or two
probably.
I mean if he shot a 38 at close range is
I believe that's what everybody said it
was.
Who would definitely go through that and
into the wall.
By the way,
the photo for the cover of one shot shot
by
Jamie Vernon.
Vernon.
Yes.
Accidentally got cut out of the credit
though.
Steve was there literally
in there and then he literally wasn't
after that.
It's just a complete technical layer
from the person who was on my first non
credit.
It won't be my last,
these motherfuckers in non credits.
God dammit.
I'm done talking.
I'm the king of a non credit.
We can uh,
we can continue this tomorrow.
I have to show or it can just,
we can edit it on this too.
It could be like make a part to a denim.
Maybe I'll just turn it on and see if
there's anything fun or something like
that.
Yeah,
why not?
Fuck it.
Um,
yeah,
we'll just put it on the green room.
Talk some shit.
So this podcast for now is over,
but I'm,
so we did like a couple hours and it's
an hour and a half hour.
40 good.
Plenty of time,
and so we're doing a west side barbell.
Tomorrow we're going to be meeting up
with Louie Simmons,
who's the famous a power lifter and a
strength coach of Westside barbell.
You want to go Tony,
who give you some fucking pointers?
I get jacked powerlifting and me.
We really don't see eye to eye live with
me.
I'm getting bigger,
but I'm just send the bag right now.
What average dude?
I've been lifting Omari.
I'm,
I already looked pretty much better than
you.
It's been like three months.
I told him I think he's a little bigger
than you.
All right.
Well,
Jamie does dead lifts and tomorrow's
podcast.
We're going shirt with a jacked and gets
down there.
We're going to have,
we're going to let the audience to send
it tomorrow night life and just how the
fuck her.
Let's just get arrested.
Who can hold that shit in the longest?
Let's have a contest.
All right.
We're going to wrap this thing,
so goodnight.
Bye.
Fuck you right.