How do I pronounce your name?
Calling on the war.
Colianni.
Okay.
Yeah.
Now there's a conspiracy out there.
Okay.
I made this name up.
We'll talk about that.
We're talking about that.
We're live already.
How'd you do that so quickly?
Oh,
you're a wizard.
What's the conspiracy about your.
Your name is on noir.
What's the conspiracy about your name?
That I made it up to hide who I really
was.
Oh,
type shit.
Like I'm like,
everybody gets to have pseudonyms except
for me when you're talking about guns,
you don't get to have pseudonyms.
Did you have a different name?
Yeah,
my name is collins.
Oh,
okay.
So you did change the name?
Yeah,
I did.
But there's a conspiracy behind you
changed your name,
but that's not real.
You just decided you wanted a different
name.
I got into guns and I wanted to start
watching gun videos and so I wanted to
make a youtube channel and I didn't want
to use my real name because I thought
that wasn't cool enough.
And so I said your name wasn't cooling
to know I didn't want to,
uh,
African American thing.
Yeah,
pretty much.
I mean I know comedians had changed
their names,
like earthquake.
Earthquake is fucking hilarious.
Convenient man.
He's hilarious.
But a white dude couldn't call them self
or earthquake.
Hey,
good.
Nah You could.
But nobody would wrestler.
That was a restaurant name earthquake.
But that's different.
That's different.
That's a big giant guy.
Right.
So what's your original name?
What's your actual full original name?
I'll give you my first name.
I'll just,
I just don't want to make it easy for
people to show the um,
Collins Collins and around it.
Yeah,
it's a fine name.
Something wrong with that.
What's wrong with it?
Why that name bother you to the point
where you didn't want to have it on?
No,
I just thought it'd be more fun to just
come up with a pseudonym for my youtube
channel.
I didn't start my youtube channel
thinking,
all right,
I'm going to start this channel and I'm
going to build this whole brand behind
that.
No,
it was just for fun.
Yeah.
My friends call me.
One of my friends,
he called me killer corleone.
Right.
That was kind of a little nickname that
I had.
And so I was like,
okay,
well just use going on and then I'm
like,
I'm always in black.
Why did he call you killer cold?
No idea.
When I talked to him to this day,
I still don't know why he called me
that.
Yeah,
there's nicknames,
man.
That just happens sometimes there is a
rapper and Houston by that name.
Killer corleone.
Yeah.
Oh,
okay.
Yeah.
Um,
so I don't know if maybe he listened to
him and then my name Collins and then
called me on and so forth and so on.
Yeah.
So,
so how did you get wrapped up with the
NRA?
So we should,
we should cover a couple of things here.
The origin story.
Yeah.
So you're kind of like a spokesperson
for the NRA,
not official spokesperson,
not official.
Unofficial.
Today.
You are a member of the NRA.
Do they recognize you?
Do they appreciate you?
Like how does that work?
Okay.
So the way it started,
I mean,
I'm going to start from the beginning.
Okay.
Alright.
So,
um,
my had a friend of mine,
a good friend of mine who called me up
one day and was like,
do you want to go shooting?
And I was like,
because at the time I really wasn't pro
gun and this was about,
I was around 24,
I'm 34,
so this is 10 years ago and I hesitate a
little bit because my background growing
up,
like I didn't grow up with guns in the
house,
um,
no one in my family had a gun and for me
the idea and the notion of being a young
black male with a gun,
it's always,
I only saw three exactly through the
lens of,
you know,
Gang Banger,
drug dealer,
so forth and so on.
So that's the mindset I had when with
respect to firearms,
I'm unconsciously,
right.
I didn't even realize it wasn't even
conscious of it until I started getting
into this very heavy and realized,
okay,
wow.
I was thinking like that didn't realize
it.
And so,
but at the same time I told myself,
why am I afraid of essentially what is
an inanimate object?
Right.
So I think to myself,
I'm like,
all right,
I really don't want to go,
I'm a little terrified,
but you know what,
I'm going to go ahead and do it.
And so I remember getting to the range,
we get to the range and we walk them
through the door and then I hear the
door for where the actual bays are and I
heard a pop pop,
pop go off and I'm like,
holy crap,
this is actually happening.
And so I kind of had this nervousness
but I'm with my friend,
right?
And so I don't want my friend to feel
like,
okay,
you're acting kind of like a bitch.
Right.
So I kind of kept it to myself.
You get to the counter,
we do all the paperwork that,
you know,
represent paperwork,
like billy phones all that.
Um,
and he has his gun,
we get to Malmo,
we go to the lane,
I remember it was the very last lane,
it was a,
maybe the range was top gun in Houston
and so we go to very last range.
It gives me kind of like a brief
instruction about how to shoot the gun.
How to load it,
so forth and so on.
And so at that point,
remember picking up the gun,
terrified not knowing what to expect,
not knowing what was gonna happen.
So I remember picking it up.
It was a little tourist ptsd,
11 1:11
millennium in 40 caliber.
And this was a subcompact probably not
the best first time shooting the fucking
gun.
Well,
the gun itself was small caliber
example.
Lot of kick you.
Exactly.
So my experience,
anybody who watched that as a gun person
would be like,
oh,
this is not gonna end.
Well.
So I remember standing at the bay and
then taking a gun and pointing it and
shooting it.
And I remember just the concussive
force,
the explosion,
the gun dancing in my hand.
And I was like,
holy crap.
That was terrifying.
They're to shout it again.
I was like,
I liked this shit.
And the weird thing is it not in a way
that most people think the nerdy aspect
of my brain kicked in,
right?
I'm like,
holy crap.
Like I'm taking this project down.
I'm launching it right several feet.
Um,
and I just,
the second shot allowed me to realize
what just happened.
I just contained an explosion in my
hand.
Right?
I'm like,
if you don't find that amazing,
you don't have a pulse.
It's amazing.
The thing that people are bothered by is
what comes with it and how people use
it.
And I think an analogy that's a fair
analogy,
but people reject is driving cars and a
lot of these fucking psychos that have
been running over people in the street.
I mean,
it just happened again,
Perlin somewhere somewhere in Germany.
Some guy ran a bunch of people over and
then blew his brains out.
It's,
it's an object,
right?
It's a thing that you use.
And I'm a huge car guy to Sam as well.
Yeah.
I love cars.
I mean if someone said we have to ban
cars because people started running
people over with cars,
they'd be like,
well,
okay,
I think we're dealing with a whole bunch
of problems.
And there's,
there's a bunch of things that I think
we will probably agree on.
One of the things we can agree on is all
these mass shootings are horrific.
Absolutely.
They're terrifying.
It's.
It's an evil,
terrible thing that here's another
thing.
No NRA members are doing that.
That's one of the things that's really
kind of fucked up about people getting
angry at the NRA.
Yeah.
We've never had a mass shooting ever
that,
that I can recall that was done by an
NRA member.
I looked.
I tried to find one.
I can't find a mass shooting that was
perpetrated by an MRI NRA member and I
think it's.
So the biggest problem that a lot of gun
owners,
especially NRA members have,
is like the conversation that's being
had is basically coloring or actually
forgetting the human element behind
those three letters.
Like the NRA isn't like this demigod
that just sits in the cloud of Olympia
and it is just one big guy that just
orchestrating this entire thing.
Yeah.
It's,
you're talking 5 million people,
you know?
Right.
Like I'm a,
I'm,
I'm a member,
I am a gun owner.
Right.
That that's who I am along with 5
million other people who were that way
and then there were a ton of other
people who think they're in our members
in art and then a ton of other people
who probably don't mind being an Ra
members,
they just haven't gotten around with
doing it and getting the membership and
the vast majority of those people.
And I'm saying that just to be safe.
They're good people.
I think there's quite a few good people,
um,
the people that are perpetrated,
all these mass shootings are definitely
not good people.
But what's wrong with them?
Well,
I'll tell you what's wrong with them.
Guns not guns that are wrong with them.
They use the guns to express what's
wrong with them.
You know,
and everybody wants to look at the
object,
which I get what's easier?
Well,
it is easier and it's something that
everyone's pointing to.
Like,
why do you need an Ar 15?
Why do you need to do this?
Why didn't you do that?
These are good questions.
Why do you need these things?
Why do I need that Fucking Samurai sword
over there?
I don't know,
it's like what do you need?
And that's another thing too though,
and I've said it before,
I think we are a victim of our own
success in this country,
right?
I do think this is the greatest country
in the world,
but the problem with that is is
this country was built on an ideological
foundation that I think it aids in that
our ability to be as great as we are,
but we live in a world now where people
don't see the necessity for something
that was never,
that was never supposed to be seen
through the lens of necessity in the
first place.
The Second Amendment doesn't give me a
right.
It preserves something that already
existed,
but what happens is we have a culture of
people who don't,
who look at the second amendment as a
privilege,
not a right there,
look at it as a privilege.
So that's why they say,
well,
why do you need that?
Why do you need more than 10 rounds?
Why do you need this?
Why do you need that?
And I'm like,
first of all,
reframing the entire conversation
underneath when that's not what the
second amendment is about.
It's a right that I've already had.
It's a natural right that I had the
moment that I stepped foot on this earth
as a person.
The right to self defense is,
is universal.
Yeah.
And the people say,
okay,
it's a right,
but obviously there's a problem so we
have to do something about it.
So you're going to have to give up your
guns.
This is,
this is the common conversation and it's
very flippant and it's not well thought
out and there's no,
no consideration whatsoever to mental
health issues.
I think because I think this is.
I think that's the primary problem
that's.
I've been saying this from the get go.
I think it's the primary problem.
I think it's a mental health issue and
people say,
oh,
that's simplifying it.
I don't think it is.
I think it's the opposite.
I think it's,
it's ignored it.
Look,
it's there's something wrong when you
have this many people on mental health
medication.
And then when you look at the number of
mass shooters,
it's almost universal.
Almost every single one of them is on
some sort of psychiatric medication.
But that's not a part of the narrative.
That's not a part of the conversation.
The conversation is always get rid of
guns.
Now I don't want crazy people to have
I don't think you do either.
No,
don't.
So outside of taking away the rights to
have guns from normal law abiding people
like yourself and myself,
I have guns.
What,
what do we do?
Okay.
So first of all,
I think we need to frame the
conversation and into specifics,
right?
You're a lawyer,
I am.
Okay.
Yeah.
So you understand bills and amendments
and law.
Okay.
And so I think one word lumping the
entire conversation in one category,
right?
If we're going to talk about school
shootings,
let's talk about school shootings,
right?
So the first thing I say is,
because for one thing,
a lot of people in it,
so I'd like to say is,
well you guys just don't want any
gun laws and you say no to everything,
but you have no true.
But to stand up for that,
it's because all they want to do is take
away the guns.
Yeah.
They're saying,
let's take away the guns.
You're saying we're not going to take
away the guns.
You guys just don't want to get your
guns taken away.
Yes,
you're right.
You're right.
No one wants to get their guns take
away.
And then I get labeled a monster as a
result of saying exactly.
You want kids to die and it's a fucking
real sneaky conversations.
Disingenuous.
Yes it is.
And that's the odd thing about
it is it's you see anybody who's paying
attention to the discourse in way it's
happening.
Especially on social media.
Right.
Anybody who follows my twitter,
my twitter account knows this multiple
occasions I've tried to have a rational
conversation with people who are on the
complete opposite side of my spectrum
of,
of this issue.
Is there any of this online or like
debates or anything like that?
Well,
no,
I mean it's just on twitter.
Tweets going back and forth.
Didn't do anything rational.
You can occasionally,
you got the American people being
friendly.
You wouldn't see me flustered,
respond to me rationally because I'm
always,
you know,
had this right of course,
and I actually have to check myself
about that a little bit because how am I
any better than the people on the other
side if I had the same at the same
energy that they have towards me.
That's a very good point.
And so I've started,
you know what,
let me,
because I can be incredibly snarky like
I can and it's partly due because of my
friends.
They're all assholes,
just like all the friends I grew up
with.
I grew up arguing with a group of guys
who when they were losing it logically,
they went to jokes.
Right?
And it's like a man pretty much,
right?
It took me a second to realize it
because I was the one in law school,
right?
I was the one that was going to law
school,
law,
all that stuff.
So everything I did was focused and
center through the idea of logic,
logic,
logic.
You're not making any sense and you
crack a joke and everyone's laughing and
I realized there's some power to that.
Right.
You know,
humor,
I mean you should know something about
that.
Just a little for sure.
Yeah,
and so I took on some of those qualities
in the way that I advocate for firearms,
you know,
because it can be a little disarming,
but the disarming aspect of it can be
beneficial because it causes people to
drop their guard a little bit and then
when you drop your guard you can take in
information more objectively,
more so than waiting or looking for
confirmation bias or in instigating your
cognitive dissonance because you just
don't want to hear the thing that is
contrary to what you already believe.
I just think you need a lot of
character,
like as a person to be able to
communicate reasonably on twitter and
there's a lot of people that are just
lacking that.
So it's almost like the ability to steal
and no one's looking the ability to shit
on someone with no ida,
eye contact,
no social repercussions.
No know you're not feeling anything from
that person.
You say something rude to them.
They're not in front of you,
so you don't feel terrible saying that.
Yeah.
No,
it's,
I'm not gonna lie,
so twitter isn't dirty place,
it's a dirty place,
but it's a great place to.
Sometimes it is,
it has its benefits,
right.
There's some really good conversations
to be had on twitter and I've had a
really interesting moments on twitter
where I've learned a lot about things
where people have sent me links and I've
retweeted them and I've,
I've learned a lot of things,
but it's hard sometimes,
man,
because there are so many people that
are just unreasonable and they're not
good at communicating and they're happy.
They're not happy people and does a lot
of people out there that just aren't
happy man.
It's,
you know,
and it'd be honest with you,
I didn't realize it until I got to the
notoriety that I am now in the space
that I'm in.
Well,
you're in a weird space because you're
in the space of defending guns,
you know,
and I'm black.
Yeah.
And I'm relatively young.
There's a lot going on there.
And we were a lawyer and I worked well.
They tend to disregard that.
Well,
they should probably pay attention.
it doesn't matter because I have,
I'm doing,
I'm advocating also with certain three
letters behind me.
They automatically assume as the devil
for now.
How does the NRA feel about you?
Do you know?
I mean,
do you have conversations with them?
Are they saying good job or they.
Are they pleased or as far as I can
tell,
they are.
We still have the relationship we have.
It's very much a very symbiotic
relationship.
It's a weird one right now because it's
like,
this is what I hear from the NRA.
I hear colon and then I hear Ted nugent.
Those are the two that I hear it.
I gotta be honest.
I'm not,
I'm not the biggest fan of Ted
techniques rhetoric.
Um,
but I do know where it's coming from.
But then again,
I didn't grow up listening to Ted
nugent.
Yeah,
that's not my demographic,
but at the same time to a new job,
it's still an individual and people fail
to understand that.
Like we,
like,
we may be monolithic on that,
on the issue of firearms.
We're not monolithic in the way we go
about expressing it.
Well,
he's right about things.
Just because someone's outrageous
doesn't mean they're not right.
Like if you ever seen his,
uh,
the,
the debate that he had in a gun store
with the Piers Morgan.
Yeah.
No,
the funny thing is to do just incredibly
bright.
It is smart guy.
Crazy as hell.
I don't even think he's crazy.
I do.
You can only.
You can only kill so many things for
you.
Lose your fucking marbles.
Ted Lives on a ranch in Texas where it's
all fenced in.
He's just shooting all animals.
He hunts every day.
He's a psycho and I don't,
with all due respect,
I'm a big fan of strangle hold.
So what,
so how,
what's,
where's the line of demarcation between
becoming and not hurting enough in terms
of becoming a crossing over that line
into,
into sociopath?
Well,
I'm just joking.
I'm a hunter.
I mean it really depends entirely upon
what he's doing with the meat.
And I know he gives it to hunters for
the hungry.
I know he gives it to neighbors and
friends and there's nothing wrong with
that.
And he asked.
He actually has a,
he has an obligation to be the steward
of his land because he has a lot of
exotic and stuff and I'm just totally
joking around.
Oh No,
I know.
But when you,
um,
when you listen to his conversation with
Piers Morgan,
which Piers Morgan takes that flip in,
left wing knee jerk reactionary,
you know,
regionally paragons.
Yeah,
he's a cunt.
And when,
when he's on with Ted,
Ted just knew everything about the
actual facts.
When you start running around with
statistics of gun violence,
he's like,
do you know how many of those people
were bad guys that were shot cops?
Yeah.
Do you know how many of those people
were people that were shot when they
were breaking the people's homes?
Do you know how many of those people
were people that were killed in self
defense?
There's a lot.
Yeah,
it's not in the,
you know,
how many of those people,
when you say talking about gun violence,
how many of the people were suicide?
Uh,
yeah,
there's a lot.
Keep in mind that's recent suicide.
Well,
no.
So here's what happened.
So when I started getting really deep
into the advocacy component of it,
the everyone was screaming,
30,000
people die from gun violence,
people a day.
That's what they were running with.
And they were scaring all the suburban
House moms.
Oh my gosh.
We got to do something about gun
control.
We got to do something about guns.
So I,
I jumped into the pool and I,
I,
I just like,
something doesn't seem right about that
figure right now.
I'm not saying I'm is wrong about it.
It seemed inflated.
I don't know what it was.
It's on a subconscious level as or
maybe,
or maybe it was me looking for
confirmation bias,
right?
Because I felt the way I did about
farms,
I'll be honest and say that.
And so what I did is I kind of
researched a little more than I realize
holy shit,
over 65 percent of that 30,000
suicides,
65 percent real.
He's just Christ.
So what does that like 18,000
people a day shoot themselves,
man.
Something crazy like that.
What do we say at the top of the show?
And people are miserable,
man.
That's a fucking crazy number though,
That's a Kevin Hart concerts pretty much
altogether.
Goodnight everybody.
Well that's really what it is.
18,000
people.
That's fucking incredible.
So then it.
But then it begs the question that you
brought up before the mental health
aspect.
Yeah.
How much?
How many lives would we actually save if
we took the same energy we applied to
just making guns evil and trying to ban
guns and take that energy and put it
towards understanding what it is.
Why as a society we have a society that
is so eager to really not want to be
here anymore.
Hm.
Expand that a little bit more.
Because we have all the guns in the
universe here in America,
right?
Compared to any other country.
But yet our suicide rates should be
exceedingly higher than all the other
countries that don't have as many guns.
But it's not the case.
Right.
You look at the UK,
you look at Japan,
Japan has double our suicide rate.
Does it really?
Oh yeah.
Double.
Yeah.
Wow.
So 60,000
people a day in Japan or whatever the
fuck per year.
Smaller.
Not Everyday.
It's every year.
Yeah,
per annual.
One hundred 23.
But I said that you go complaint numbers
again.
I fucked up.
Did I say a day earlier or did I say a
year?
Earlier.
A day?
Yeah.
Because you owe $30,000.
What did I say?
Day $30,000
a year.
Doesn't sound that bad because $300.
Million people.
Oh yeah.
So you would,
you would think about it predicated on,
on a daily basis?
No,
no,
no.
Annually.
That doesn't make any sense.
Why would I think that?
I think he might've said on accident
too.
Oh really?
But everyone.
Thirty.
Yeah.
Thirty thousand pounds in a year from
gun violence.
Call it gun gun fire.
But in reality you break those numbers
down,
makes contact with San Francisco,
65 percent of those are suicides in
about five percent of those are,
um,
are God dammit.
I think justified homicides including
times when cops shoot someone in self
defense and it's justified right in self
defense shooting.
So forth.
And so they count times when cops really
shouldn't have shot somebody,
but did,
I'm pretty sure they do.
Yeah.
Yeah,
I'm pretty sure they do.
But even then that number would be
exceedingly marginal comparatively.
Right?
So then you have the remaining number
which are.
And then you have like three to five.
I know,
I think it was 15 percent of justified.
Three to five percent are accidents.
Three to five percent a lot.
Yeah.
No,
it's with 900 people.
900 people a year.
Right.
So,
and I tweeted this,
I said again,
if we focused on firearm safety
education,
we could,
that number will drop in half.
It might be you're not gonna,
you're gonna fix the intelligence level
of the human.
See as fucking around with guns.
That's where you underestimate the fact
in the nursemaid how those people are
dying because accidentally,
because there were a lot of people who
don't understand basic gun safety,
right?
Within that 900,
it's a lot of them.
Um,
when you see some of the accidents that
happens with firearms,
they're easily mitigated by just simply
knowing the four rules of firearm
ownership.
And when you get into the gun community,
like as a whole,
you follow that rabbit instance like we
are,
we're crazy about gun safety.
You,
you,
you put your finger on a trigger and a
picture.
We're slaughtering you.
Yeah.
Not Literally,
but you know what you're saying.
Yeah.
Like we're going to hold your
accountability.
I have a friend who has so many guns.
He doesn't know how many guns.
How many guns you have.
I don't know Justin.
I know you're listening.
He's a legit gun.
Nut and great guy.
Yeah.
And I don't know how many guns I have,
either a fucking crazy person.
I mean hell,
I mean I guess.
I mean,
but then again I didn't shoot my first
gun.
Toilet Twenty three,
24.
Yeah.
So that,
did that just become crazy all of a
sudden?
I think I was about the same age.
Yeah.
Well,
I think I shot one when I was real young
and I definitely shot one in camp when I
was like,
I guess I was probably 12,
but at that I didn't count that I've
shot my first handgun when I first came
to California and I might've been really
on it.
Well,
what's ironic is it's way easier to get
a gun here.
That is New York.
I lived in New York too.
Fucking hard to get a handgun in New
York.
Almost impossible.
You legally?
You mean?
Legally or illegally?
Okay.
Yeah.
No,
I mean when I came here it was a 1994 I
guess,
maybe 93,
94.
I bought a gun and I was like,
I can't believe I just buy a gun to the
check.
Yeah,
yeah.
I bought A.
I'm about 38 special about a Walter p,
P K,
and I bought a glock nine millimeter
or made a good taste.
I'm a fan.
I'm a fan of the PDK as well.
Yeah,
it's a cute little gun.
Well,
when I first came to California and her
all this crazy shit about drive by
shootings and gang violence,
I just thought it was just going to be a
fucking war zone out here.
There's a funny thing about it is it's
your natural disposition was I need
something to protect myself.
It's such a natural thought process.
I don't know why we've perverted it to
this deal where it's like something has
to be wrong with you.
If you had that mentality or that
there's a lot of people that haven't
experienced real violence,
you know,
and then if you've experienced real
violence and you've seen what happens
when you have a terrible person around
people that aren't terrible,
that's for sure.
That's a reality that people don't like
to face and they don't like to look at
the other side of the coin.
Like whenever there's an instance where
there's a shooter,
the shooter gets taken out by someone
who's a trained person who's trained
with firearms and and knows tactics.
Nobody wants to talk about that.
That just gets brushed off.
They don't.
There's not a balanced conversation to
be had.
There isn't an interesting thing is I
have a group to have a group chat when
stuff like that does happen,
they write it off as just anomalies.
Right?
How's that an anomaly?
That's what exactly what it's supposed
to be used for.
Again,
like I said,
confirmation bias and cognitive and
distances are,
are,
is a bitch.
We all suffer from it,
right?
To an extent.
For sure.
Um,
but when you add in the component of
fear,
right?
For a lot of people,
they don't necessarily hate guns.
The sequences of being shot or someone
they love being shot in.
One of the thing about it is though,
you know,
those people never put themselves in a
position of being the shooter.
They always put themselves in a position
of being the victim of a shooting.
So that's why you get,
well,
why do you need that?
Because they don't see it as,
okay,
this allows me to better defend myself.
They look at it from the perspective of,
well,
if you're able to have that,
then you might use that against me.
And you know,
there's also the,
the looming specter of the mass shooter.
It's just so fucking common these days.
It seems like every three or four months
there's a new instance,
how many times per cent happened.
Perception is a bitch,
but the reality is the absolute reality
is they have happened.
They are horrific and there's more of
them here than anywhere else in the
world.
That's reality,
but here's the good.
So when you say that you're talking
about the developer world,
correct your,
because that's usually the caveat they
like to play on.
There's no mass shootings in the
undeveloped world is people don't just
go into a fucking mall and shoot people
up.
What's windshield shade?
It's rare.
Very rare.
Where people take it happens more than
people realize.
It just doesn't.
A report on how many people die in
Chicago in a weekend,
over a weekend that doesn't get
reported.
That's true,
but we live in America where we have
complete access to information that is
true,
but it's a different kind of violence
because it's people that are actively to
get people that are actively trying to
get them.
It's gang violence.
Whereas school shootings are completely
innocent.
School shootings are the worst,
right?
Because it's a child and some fucking
psycho decides to make the most noise
possible by going into a school and
shooting it up.
That's the scariest and the worst for
most people.
For most.
When you think about gang violence,
you say,
well,
that's violent.
It's terrible that people got shot,
but it's people that are trying to shoot
each other.
All right,
so then when I tell you that the
remaining homicides in this country,
right at 30,000
number that I gave you manually,
over 80 percent of that is gang
violence.
That's crazy to think and believe it.
I believe you,
but it's when you see Sandy Hook,
when you see Parkland,
when you see any that the shooting in
Colorado,
Aurora in the movie theater,
when you see these mass shootings,
these are what terrify people.
Yeah.
People are not necessarily terrified of
the gang violence in Chicago.
You know,
I'm going to Chicago in a couple of
months and not one fucking person has
brought up,
hey man,
it places a warzone.
Everybody's like,
oh,
I love Chicago.
You're going to get deep dish pizza like
nobody knows your fly.
Is that what it is?
Yeah.
No,
I'm not going to the south side.
Do.
See,
that's the thing.
I just went to Chicago.
It was just in Chicago.
I was here and they were like,
well,
you locked and loaded.
Did you wear a vest?
Yes,
I'm dead serious.
I got all those questions,
but I said I was going to Chicago.
Those are the first things that people
told me.
Now,
granted I did go to south side.
I did feel like.
Yeah,
we did.
Would you.
Were you nervous?
Were you walking around?
I wasn't nervous.
I'm not superman man.
So when you're walking around,
he's strapped a not in Chicago because
it's illegal for me to be.
That's what's crazy is that Chicago has
really strict gun laws and that they
don't work at all.
I was driving down a road where there
were like six,
seven,
eight dudes who jumped in front of the
car when we drove in there because we
didn't look like we belonged there and
I'm positive.
Every single one of them had a gun.
They jumped in front of the car.
Well,
they didn't like little lob,
their bodies in front of the car.
But you know,
you,
you said Carl,
this unfamiliar driving down the side
streets.
So they tried to stop you.
Uh,
they didn't try to stop me.
I think you're trying to figure out who
the hell we were going over.
They were just trying to surface.
Yeah.
So it's kind,
Kinda one of those things,
right?
But then again,
when you're driving around,
you're driving down the side street and
south side Chicago.
We go pros on the car.
Oh,
that's true.
Right.
So you kind of have that.
Um,
so we all agree that gun violence,
especially in terms of mass shootings is
one of the biggest problems that we have
in terms of like a horrific public image
problem,
right?
It's uh,
it's,
it's something that you see in
everybody.
When I say public image,
I should,
what I should,
I should phrase that what I mean as a
public perception problem.
Like you,
you see it and it's just death and
violence and children and innocence.
And we as,
as people I think consider the death of
innocence to be one of the most
egregious and horrific deaths.
So I think we both agree on.
Absolutely.
So.
So that's 100 percent across the board.
I think with any decent person.
These mass shootings are horrific.
I think in my opinion,
the,
the number one aspect of the argument
that's not being discussed is the mental
health aspect of it.
Are you opposed to more screening of
people to get guns?
Yes and no.
Yes.
In that,
in an ideal world,
if we could minority report it and
figure it out.
Who you.
I mean,
minority report.
I mean just like check to see if they're
on metal,
mental health medication.
But I mean we,
we currently have.
We'll see.
Here's the thing,
this slippery slope with that too.
So what would constitute somebody being
on mental health medication that's
prohibitive,
but if I would,
if I deal with anxiety,
if I'm on Susanne's prescribed,
is that prevent me from owning a
firearm?
That's a good question.
In California for the longest time,
they were trying to make it.
If you had a medical marijuana card,
you couldn't have a firearm.
I think they were doing that federally.
I think that there was a federal thing
that if you had a legal medical
marijuana card that they were trying to
prevent people they were trying to
prevent people from.
They were trying to be trying to cripple
the marijuana industry because they knew
that people wanted guns because to be
honest,
it's intellectually dishonest.
If I can,
if I can go to the store with a gun on
me and buy alcohol,
right?
Like,
and you know me,
I'm not,
I don't even smoke.
Right.
But let's just be honest about it.
Like alcohol,
weed.
I mean I think utilizing that as a
prohibitive means to own a firearm.
I think it's.
I think that is true.
But if you were under the influence,
some of the Shit I got in the studio,
I.
No,
you're super paranoid.
I didn't undo a gun and say,
I didn't say under the influence.
I said if I could all the all the
marijuana card.
Does this allow you to buy it?
No.
One hundred percent.
But I'm saying that is an issue if
you're under the influence and you have
a gun,
right?
Yeah.
But I'm allowed to.
But I have you go to my house right now.
I have all types of whiskeys at home.
Right.
But if you're under the influence,
right?
Yeah.
But yeah.
So I can't,
I can't carry a firearm and then drunk.
Right.
You can't,
you shouldn't be drunk with a gun.
You shouldn't be high as fuck when the
gun.
Neither one of those good ideas.
And nor should you be driving.
Nor should you be driving.
So should you be on Xanax with a gun?
That's the question I don't know the
answer to because I've never had xanax.
Exactly.
Me Neither.
I don't know what it's like,
but I do know that there's been people
that have killed people when they were
on Xanax.
And you know that guy in Vegas,
this shooter in Vegas,
that guy was on anti anxiety medication.
I didn't know that Chris Cornell was on
anti anxiety medication when he killed
themselves.
Look,
it's got a profound effect on some
individuals and it's not uniform the way
it affects you.
It might affect change with different.
Totally different.
It's a different.
I mean I know,
I know tons of people who are on it.
Yeah,
I do.
And they respond.
Like you said,
they respond to it differently.
Yeah.
And I know tons of people on it will
also drink while they're on it,
which you're not supposed to.
Yeah.
And that,
that's not good either.
Yeah.
It's screening with the screening
component.
Right?
You got to be careful because what it
then does,
it's like,
it becomes a de facto way of preventing
people to own firearms arbitrarily.
Right.
So I was like,
oh,
well you have anxiety or even even
somebody who's maybe dealing with PTSD,
not everybody's dealing with PTSD is as
a potential murderous,
ravenous 100 percent person who just
want to go out and kill people.
Um,
so with the screening component,
that's why I say yes or no.
Right.
If you can find a way,
if you can find a way to establish a
screw,
a mental screening bit,
even then no,
because there's,
there's a,
there's a due process aspect to it as
well.
Right?
So you can prevent me from owning and
you can't prevent me from exercising a
right if I haven't done something to
absolve myself from being able to do
that legally.
Right.
Okay.
So what if they come to your house and
you've got,
let's say you've got like a cork board
up and you've got all these pictures of
schools and fucking arrows pointing to
the emergency exits and plans of how to
block things off.
And then pictures of Jodie foster and
pictures of serial killers up
everywhere.
And you're on anti anxiety medications
in the cops.
Talked to you and your fucking squirrely
as hell.
You haven't done anything?
No.
Arrest me.
Then if you can arrest me,
arrest can't.
If you can't arrest me for,
for a crime or possibly attempting to
because like,
like you know,
like the legal standard is like taking
substantial act to commit a crime even
though you don't do it.
That's attempted.
Did you hear about the kid that got
kicked out of school?
Um,
what was the school?
Who was an Asian kid?
Died his hair blonde,
started collecting bullets,
got a semi automatic rifle.
His friend started freaking out,
they called the cops,
cops came to visit him,
he bought another rifle and I believe
they deported them.
They deported him for reasons not having
to do with the firearms.
They deported him for reasons that he
wasn't actually going to anymore is on a
green card or visa,
I believe.
But the way the sheriffs were framing it
was they deported because they wanted
this fucking psycho out of the country
and they think that they might've
prevented a crime.
They probably did,
but they still had.
They still had to establish a legal
basis for deporting did all they had.
Was that,
that he didn't go to class.
I mean,
that's something you've done.
I've done.
Yeah.
I mean everybody is.
But then again,
he wasn't a citizen.
Right.
So,
and that was,
that was,
that was a requirement for him to
continue to be here.
But it was really,
it was Kinda like Kinda got like Al
Capone,
you know,
they got a component by tax evasion by
way of,
you know.
Right,
right,
right.
But he really had guns and was acting
crazy and that's why the kids that were
friends with them called and that's why
they acted and they just found that
loophole.
Yeah.
So what do you do with someone like
that?
Other than that,
I mean this guy,
we had something.
What if this kid was still going to
school?
I mean it be,
it'd be pretty bad,
pretty bad.
But,
but then again,
we still,
we still have our laws for a reason,
right?
We have,
we have our inherent rights for a
reason.
Have to due process for a reason.
Because if we didn't have those right,
anyone could just come up and say,
man,
you know what I saw I saw calling you on
the war on instagram the other day.
He a picture of a god and he
was like cursing people out because
they're making fun of him in the water
he was drinking and so you know what?
Somebody needs to go check on them and
make sure he's okay and somebody is
going to take his guns away from him.
You've got to.
There's got to be through process.
I appreciate that.
And I agree with you and,
and it's,
it's unfortunate in that some people may
slip through the cracks,
but,
but I can arrest someone for something
that they haven't done yet.
You just,
you just can't.
Well I agree.
And so that's where we are right now.
So then,
so then that now we're getting to the
complexities the hardest of the hard
questions,
right?
What do we do?
How do we put something in place to
catch the people who do happen to fall
between the cracks?
Right.
So then you go,
okay,
well try to keep up.
Sorry,
I'm moving.
I don't know if you saw a hydro.
The complexities.
Yeah,
it's,
it's a very complex issue,
which is why we're not largely not
having it and we're having it here
because no one wants to have this
conversation on the national scene
because it's hard and it doesn't make
for great sound bite and it doesn't make
for good TV.
Right?
Because if I hate doing cable news hits
because I have two minutes to basically
reduce a complex issue that we've been
debating for decades,
almost centuries.
It's the worst and it's also people
talking over each other and there's one
or two boxes,
one guy here,
one guy there.
Usually you're not even in the same room
to go there.
You're talking to those earpieces.
There is a delay.
Those things are a disaster or horrible.
One of the worst ways to communicate,
which is why I try to establish my
platform or my show war.
I try to have it as a platform that's
open to people to come on,
hey look,
you want to come on and discuss this
issue?
By all means come to it.
Have you had anyone that's the really
strict anti-gun on.
Yeah.
I had A.
I had an entire season,
so what we did in the season,
I think it was two seasons ago,
we brought on a young lady and a guy
from New Zealand,
I can't remember,
but he came on the show.
They were anti and so what we did was he
had a round table discussion at the end
of every episode of my show and we will
bring up a specific topic and we discuss
it and so they basically was like two
against one essentially until they would
talk to me about what their thoughts on,
on what we talked about in the show or a
particular gun control issue and we had
that conversation had an individual.
I sit down with her as well when we
talked about it and then took her to the
shooting range to shoot for the first
time,
you know,
but that's going to be overlooked.
Right.
They know they ignore it.
Well they probably aren't even aware of
it because I wasn't aware of it.
Another,
wherever you think people who need to be
aware of it,
aware of it because like for instance,
I bring this point up and it makes me
come across as if like I feel some type
of way cause he didn't mention me,
but it's not really that.
It just speaks volumes to what I've been
pointing at for the longest.
They ignore rational discourse.
John Oliver did a 20 minute monologue on
Nra tv about NITV,
right?
Twenty minutes.
You know how long?
Twenty minutes long.
I guess that's a long time.
He didn't me once.
He didn't mention my shot.
I have three shows on NITV,
three shows and I had the second
longest,
longest running show on nitv.
He didn't mention me once.
The level of detail that they went into
within that monologue lets me know.
They watched everything on that
platform.
They watched it all.
Why do you think you left?
Because they didn't fit the narrative.
Right?
Also because he is a progressive guy
with glasses who's white and you really
shouldn't you really sit and say
anything negative about black people?
How so?
He's but he's not white though.
He's a minority.
Just like me.
What is he?
He's.
I don't know.
He's like,
I don't want Oliver.
He's white.
It's not white.
What is he doing?
If he's not white?
I'm not white.
What the fuck is he?
Irish,
Irish.
My white.
If I'm not,
what the fuck is.
If I saw you on the street,
you are in the olden days.
I wasn't.
My grandparents weren't white when my
grandparents came over.
That guy's white over white.
He's white.
White Paper,
isn't it?
Yeah.
Oh Shit.
I'm wrong.
Well,
there you go.
What did you think he was?
I don't know.
I never thought about him confused with
the daily show guy.
I probably am Trevor Noah.
You know,
not trevor.
I know,
but I know about trevor.
Yeah,
he's white as fuck.
There's a white Englishman.
Minimum Racist.
But for a guy like that,
guys like that have dave.
Here's the thing about progressives and
I like John Oliver.
I'm not.
I'm not negative against John.
I'm going to start doing a show.
I have.
I had this perspective up until this
point.
So I'm going to shut off.
I'm going to shut off my belief system
and listen to you and listen to what
you're about to say because I haven't
thought about this because I thought he
wasn't white to this entire time.
So.
So yeah.
So now he's white as fuck,
right?
I mean,
it might not even above what.
Bye.
He did it.
He might've found the worst examples and
maybe you were too reasonable and it
doesn't fit the narrative of being
funny.
I mean his show,
although his show has points and he
makes these very clear conclusions and
you know,
but it's funny.
It's a funny show.
That's the whole thing behind it is like
any girl who's dating me knows like I
have enough episodes on,
on,
on that platform.
You could find some stuff to make fun of
me about Paul.
I'm sure they could,
but I don't think that's the kind of
thing they're trying to make fun of,
like individual personalities that say
stupid shit.
I think what they're trying to do is
point out the disingenuous narrative
from the NRA while ignoring the
disingenuous narrative from the anti gun
advocates.
Okay.
I could possibly see that.
I'm trying to.
I'm trying to be fair and reasonable
because my mind wants to go,
Nah,
he saw he.
He realized that by mentioning me.
Right.
It's going to.
It's going to peak curiosity with the
audience in which he's trying to.
So you think your two reasonable into
logical in that since you're not like
this redneck,
he haw type character that like talk
about you.
It doesn't fit their narrative salicious
ignore him because that's a trade on the
dummies.
Think about it,
but everybody was still real though,
right?
Don't have domains on all sides.
That's true.
But it's pretty easy to find like pro
gun dummies.
You can find quite a few of them.
I can pretty easy to find dummies on the
other side as well for sure.
But you wouldn't be looking if you were
on that side,
right?
If you're on the anti gun side,
you're looking for program dummies.
Pro Gun dummies.
Yeah.
Pro Gun dummies are easy to find.
They are right.
There's plenty of them right now.
You can go fucking find him on instagram
and twitter and there's,
there's dummies all over the world and
say,
here's the thing though,
the thing about what John Oliver does,
and that's the thing.
This is the kind of disingenuous nature
of satire and political satire.
It,
I call it the,
the,
uh,
the comedian plausible deniability card.
Right.
Okay.
So you can make a joke about something
and then say,
oh,
it has no influence because it's just a
joke.
It's not.
But he's not saying that as he.
He's not saying it doesn't have any
influence.
What exactly he understands the
influence at wields,
but he's.
But he's saying,
but he can.
He can always swipe the plausible
deniability card and say,
well no,
I wasn't making an actual political
statement like I know that there
reasonable people on the other side.
No,
you're pushing a narrative that has been
pushed for decades about an organization
that fights for the second amendment,
the same,
the same narrative that's being pushed
by groups of people who say the only
thing standing in their way of more gun
control is the NRA.
So what do you do?
So where does it to make it as power
from?
Because they,
they,
they talk out of both sides of their
mouth.
They don't get the power from there.
I'm sorry.
They don't get power by their
membership.
Right?
Right.
So what do you do?
You do your best to stifle that
membership.
You make it seem as unattractive as
possible and then you also,
your audience has already largely
uneducated on the issue.
Right,
and he was already this perceived notion
at the Nras,
just a bunch of racist white rednecks.
Right?
So then what?
Then what do you do to further that
narrative?
You talk about their platform and then
you pull out all of those things that
further drive that narrative while
ignoring the most popular figure on the
platform,
which is,
which is me,
and so who so happens to be black.
So what does that say?
It tells me that this,
that it was deliberate.
I really do want to agree with you and
say,
you know what?
He's white.
He didn't want to be seen as attacking
the black guy.
So forth and so on.
I think there's a little of that,
but I think there's also.
He's doing a show and let.
Let me,
let me explain how the show works.
He's got a team of writers.
There's a ton of people back there.
They are just trying to be funny.
They're trying to make points for sure,
but they're trying to find stupid shit
that they can mock and why would they
concentrate on the guy that makes sense
if they're looking for stupid shit that
they come up,
they're not trying to make a balanced
reasonable argument like maybe we would
do right here.
Right now.
What they're doing is doing a condensed,
edited down,
very smooth,
polished television show with that rent
has been dissected and gone over by a
team of writers and they have video that
corresponds it and photographs that they
shoot go to and they have clips that
they show them.
They mock the clips.
It's a comedy show.
They do have a point,
but it's a comedy show.
Absolutely agree with.
That's why they didn't go after you is
because maybe you're a lawyer.
Maybe you're articulate.
Maybe you is because you're young and
black and they just don't feel like it's
a smart thing to do,
but it's because they're making a show.
I agree with you.
Now.
Let me tell you why my panties on a
ruffle about it just because I
understand the influence of that show.
When people make political decisions,
but don't you think it's preaching to
the choir that show?
What do you mean?
That one,
that show?
Yeah,
John Oliver show.
I think if I had to guess how many
people who are watching the show are
left wing leaning,
democratic leaning,
liberal leaning.
I would say it's a giant percentage.
Here's the problem though.
The number of people who come to me and
say,
I don't.
I don't deal with the NRA because
they're racist and there are a bunch of
white rednecks who says that?
Oh God,
I get it all the time.
The evidence that they point to,
they just assume that they're racist.
They,
that's,
that's just it.
Because in their,
in their attempts to just make a show.
Right,
and I agree with you wholeheartedly.
I absolutely agree with you,
but we can't undermine how influential
that show is at crafting people's
thoughts about particular issues and
ideologies within this country.
Right?
And so I stand back and I'm like,
man,
this is dangerous because to meet the
second amendment is incredibly
important.
Right.
I don't know what the funny thing is.
I thought the monologue was hilarious.
Funny Dude.
Mama monologue is hilarious.
I'll give.
I'll give him the model I'm arguing
with.
My log was funny then.
Isn't even funny dude,
because he said that funny.
He was a funny dude during that 20
minute mile.
Sometimes he's not to demonstrate you
got.
No.
You got to demonstrate consistency.
Consistency.
You give me some consistency.
I'll let you drop the ball a couple
times here and there.
That's fine.
But as far as consistency,
it's tough job.
Know John Oliver Guy.
He's got a tough job.
I think it's.
I think it's incredibly tough.
I think.
I think comedians don't get enough
credit.
I make sure it's even a real comedian.
Stand up.
This John Oliver,
is that.
Is that.
Is that the barometer for being a
comedian?
Stand up for us.
It's a big.
There's a big difference.
I stand up to me,
terrifies me,
but the thought of ever having to keep
them on.
I'll get in front of a million people
and talk all day long,
but the thought of Standup,
see I get to quote some of my humor and
seriousness.
Right?
So it's easier,
right?
I can do stuff here and there,
like,
oh,
he's kind of funny.
Well,
no,
it's only because it's contrasting
against something that's serious and you
don't expect to humor.
Do you remember the way you felt before
you walked into that shooting range and
those guns were going off and you're
like,
holy shit,
it's really happening now.
Think about how you feel now when you
walk into the range.
Like I go to the range.
Yeah.
I go to the range all the time.
You know,
especially when I was rifle hunting,
I would go to the range least once a
month.
Yeah.
And you know,
got used to it.
You Go,
you hear the bang,
Bang,
put your headphones on.
He just walk up and say hi to everybody
that you see there all the time.
Everybody's super polite at the range.
That's one thing,
man.
People polite as fuck at the range
because everybody around you has the
ability to kill you.
They're just not everybody around you.
Especially when.
I mean I was in the rifle section,
I've got a 300 win mag.
I'll blow a fucking door outdoors,
outdoors,
Jesus.
That's the God damn cannon,
you know,
and everybody around you got one of
these things to.
Everybody can kill everybody and
everybody's like,
hey man,
how you doing?
What's up?
How's everybody doing?
Everybody super friendly but shaking
hands.
There's a mutual respect there,
but it's interesting.
That's an interesting.
I mean that's a weird statement that
gets thrown about a lot of times that,
oh well armed society is a polite
society.
Let me.
There were two times in my life where I
felt vehemently insecure the first time
I carried a gun out of my house and my
first mma class.
Oh yeah,
that makes sense.
But what I was going to say is when you
go to the gun range a bunch of times,
then it becomes normal comes life.
That's what standup is.
Gotcha.
Same thing.
I mean you still can eat plates,
a Dick's on stage on occasion to go
south and it's terrible.
It's the worst feeling good about Texas.
Fucking dead on and hilarious.
Oh,
were you there?
No,
I just thought which,
which bit?
Which bit where you were basically about
bikinis or all the Lions and tigers,
people that keep the Tigers.
That shit's true.
Basically talking about we need these
people without fighting wars and people
who have Santa Monica.
That is true,
man,
that people who've never been to Texas
do not understand.
That is the America of American don't
play.
No,
we.
Texas doesn't play.
We are the most arrogant some bitches on
the planet.
It's also like what?
When people think of America overseas,
they think of like these fucking crazy
people with guns that have jacked up
trucks that are driving too fast.
The girls have big tits.
The guy's a fucking crazy.
That's what we think of.
That's Texas like this,
not American now as a whole.
It's Texas is the most exaggerated form
of it.
Texas houses the most exaggerated form
of that.
Yes.
There's a lot of cool people in Texas.
Texas is way more diverse.
People in Austin,
which is like super left on the Austin
is like California and Texas a little
bit,
but I think it's a little cooler.
It's smaller,
but it's the.
The thing I said about about Texas
that's true is there's more tigers in
captivity in Texas than there are in all
of the wild of the world.
More Tigers in private collections.
That's fucking true,
and when I read that,
I was like,
oh my God,
I have to figure out a way to make this
funny,
craziest fucking statistic I've ever
heard in my life,
in people's yards.
Not gonna lie to you.
I grew up.
I grew up my entire life in Texas
wanting to Cheetah Cheetah and they're
beautiful man.
Beautiful,
And just watching.
The funny thing is I get a cheetah and
put it in and put it in the yard.
No bigger than this room and inspect to
see the beauty of it running.
Well,
you know,
it's also fucked up.
I don't think you're allowed to like
just feed them animals.
I don't think you're allowed to just let
loose a goat and have a.
have the Cheetah tackle the goat and
fuck it up.
I think you have to feed them meat.
You know,
like,
like already curing process.
You're allowed to have some wild kingdom
shit.
Go down in your yard.
I don't think they allow them.
Oh No,
you did say we only have three pages of
law.
So if it's not to say,
you know what I'm saying?
Shit about tigers ordered enough new,
order it up.
You know,
the funny thing about it is when I got
into firearms,
I lived in Texas my whole life and I
went 23 years without ever shooting gun,
touching the gun.
And when I got into it,
I started the first thing I wanted to do
with shoe competition.
Right?
And so you should competition do this
competition.
It's like John Wick style where you go
to bang,
Bang,
Bang.
Three gun,
they call it three guns,
three guns.
So basically three gun consists of three
different,
three different platforms or rifle,
shotgun and a handgun.
So how does this competition work?
So basically they just set up basic set
up various courses where you have to
utilize one of those three platforms.
Some of the courses you utilize all
three.
And so it's just,
it's just in there,
you're set to a timer.
You got to clear the courses as fast as
possible.
Uh,
yeah.
In the clearing the choruses are you,
is there like walls that you have to
look behind you?
You're only limited by your imagination.
Do you ever see that shit with Keanu
reeves was preparing for John Wick Two?
Yeah.
Oh,
you were there.
I wasn't.
Okay.
So I was there not for that particular
video that went viral,
but I was there one day when he was
training and so I met him after the
fact.
How is he different?
Is He,
he's,
um,
a spacey.
Spacey.
Yeah.
Interesting.
But not in a bad way.
It's a very,
very calm energy.
Um,
you know,
why,
why that's how he handles being that
famous.
Gotcha.
And I just shut up.
I picked up on it immediately.
Then it wasn't,
it wasn't bad.
It was,
it wasn't a bad thing.
It's a good thing.
You got to realize he's the matrix guy.
That's some over the top fame.
He hit that Johnny Depp or Tom Cruise
level of fame and then just became this
super chill,
mellow guy that can just like go through
crowds that kind of goes and sits on the
subway by himself.
No,
like freaking awesome.
Yeah.
But there's no obvious outward displays
of wealth from him and he's insanely
wealthy.
When you see him.
He's dressed like me.
He's got like a regular watch on and
sneakers.
He's normal as fuck man.
It's,
it's real weird.
Like he's,
he's figured out a way to avoid like
there is right there on the fucking
subway,
just chilling,
you know,
and he looks like a totally normal dude.
Yeah.
Well,
and people freak out.
They're like,
is that no,
I can't be like,
people ignore him because he's figured
out a way to just sort of just layer in
plain sight.
And then even if you talk to him,
he's just normal.
Like everybody that I know that's met
him.
I said the dudes like totally look at
it.
He lets his chicks it down,
you know?
He said,
do you want to sit down?
Go ahead.
Boom.
And he just stands up.
Look at it,
I mean even the ways he's not,
no body guards,
you know,
what's interesting about his demeanor
and how he doesn't have this sense of
entitlement and I'm bringing it back,
bringing it back to the gun thing a
little bit.
The first time I carried a gun.
Um,
remember I told you those are the two
most,
the times where I felt more insecure was
my first day in mma and carrying a gun
for the first time.
But carrying that gun for the first time
made me realize,
Oh shit,
I'm not the only one.
Right?
So it actually humbled me and from the
standpoint that knowing that you don't
know who you're dealing with and when
you carry a firearm on you,
you have the ability to go from zero to
100 like that.
And so you develop a respect for that.
Also,
you start to develop a respect for life
as well because you understand how
fragile you start to realize how fragile
it is.
And so for me,
I actually became more docile.
Like I don't get road rage because I
understand and because I live in Texas,
we don't do that.
No,
it's not.
But I also know that like there's so
much responsibility that comes with
carrying a firearm.
It's an unreal.
Um,
and so for people who go out of the
means to learn to do it and be able to
do it,
like there's a certain level of respect
you have to have for it because it comes
with a lot.
There's certain places you can't go.
Certain things you can't do things you
have to be cognizant of.
Like,
so I started,
I actually started staying away from
certain places because I knew I had a
gun on me and I never wanted to have to
be put in a situation,
actually have to go for it.
Did you wear a gun all the time?
What if I can do it legally?
I have
really?
Yeah.
And what is the idea behind that?
Is that like it's better to have it not
to need it than to need it not to have
it?
Yeah.
Yeah,
it's,
it's an,
it's no different.
It's literally just a part of my
routine.
Watch,
watch keys,
phones,
wallet,
Gun,
one of the chamber or no one in the
chamber.
Oh and yeah,
safety on chambered the gun.
I usually carry doesn't,
they don't have external safeties.
It's just I,
I carry in the holster.
So if you carry the holster it shouldn't
be an issue.
Wow.
Yeah.
That's interesting.
So you just want to be really,
really ready.
Yeah.
Well see he don't want to have to know
and see.
Here's the thing.
That's that.
That's progressive.
I wasn't always like that.
I started off not caring with one in the
chamber.
Why wouldn't you just start putting one
in the chamber?
When I started understanding and
trusting the mechanics of a firearm,
because when I started caring I knew
about guns.
I didn't trust the mechanics.
Right,
right.
So you,
that extra step,
you don't feel like it's necessary of
like.
No.
What do you mean?
In terms of like having A.
Well,
I understand that.
I understand.
So I started doing training,
right?
And started training with the guns in
self defense and stuff like that.
And I started realizing,
you know,
so the gun isn't,
isn't an end all,
be all right.
It's just a tool that I carry with me
that could possibly save my life.
I still dog with a gun
on me for sure.
All right.
Um,
but I'd started weighing the
disadvantages and the advantages of
having one in the chamber.
Right.
I might find myself in a situation
where,
you know,
what I have time to,
okay,
I'm behind here and I have time to rack
it and do what I need to do.
There may be other times where I won't,
but if I already have a round in the
chamber,
those times where I will have the time
and not have the time won't make a
difference because there's already one
of the chamber ready to go.
Yeah.
So from that perspective,
um,
as I got more comfortable with the gun
and realize,
holy crap,
the gun never just went off on its own
because it was an inherent fear there.
Right.
It's like,
you don't want the gun to go off while I
was in your pants.
You have like one of them Chi decks
holsters.
It's form fitted gun.
Yeah.
I have tons of holes.
I have a box for the holster show you
because I reviewed guns and review and
gear and stuff,
so I'm constantly switching,
which is a gift and a curse because you
know I never perfect any platform,
but I can you put any pretty much any
gun in my hand I can use decently now
when things happen,
whenever there's a mass shooting or
something,
immediately people want to blame gun
owners or people that want to protect
gun owners and specifically NRA members.
This comes down on you.
Sometimes it's always a problem.
It comes down to people that want guns
and the people that don't want
regulations and don't want additional
screening.
We.
Yeah,
because you've got to think about it.
So like the figureheads when you,
when you started talking about Wayne and
there people go after them clearly,
but then also you have the personalities
of the brand,
which is me,
Dana and Dana.
Dana,
Dana last,
right.
She's an official spokesperson.
Right.
It's a very nice lady.
I met her.
Exactly.
And then you have mentorship,
Cam Edwards,
it shows.
Well,
exactly,
and so what tends to happen is I get it
a lot via social because that's how I
built my brand.
I built my brand through social and so
most people will when they can't
descend,
like I don't think Wayne Lapierre has a
twitter page,
you know what I mean?
He doesn't have an instagram account so
it was probably in a bunker somewhere.
He's not counting ammo.
More noble than I believe you.
Well you're.
What you are is an interesting version
of the NRA is like,
oh this is the NRA too.
Like there's a kind of a new thing.
It's multifaceted.
I dare anyone to go to the NRA annual
meetings and then if you can,
I don't know how secluded is.
Go to the board meeting.
You have a dinner meetings.
You'll be surprised they'll have I every
race you can think of different
sexualities.
You name it.
Oh,
I believe it was in the NRA forever.
I just admired,
let my membership lapse like a year and
a half ago,
but I was in the NRA because I just felt
like I know people that are just like,
we've got to get rid of the guns.
I'm like,
man,
I don't think that's going to do it and
I don't think that's going to stop
anything.
And I ask people this all the time.
I've done it on my show.
I call it the big red button question,
right?
So he put a big red button.
I'd asked him if I put a big red button
in the middle of table,
if you push this button,
all the guns on the planet disappear.
What'd you do it?
And then I'll get various answers,
but I wouldn't do it.
And people are like,
why?
Like why would you not be the end of
violence?
Not really.
It's also the end of defense.
Exactly.
Especially when you're talking about
military.
I mean if you can't,
if you don't have guns,
like what are we going to fight with
swords and bows and arrows and shit.
Do you know the interesting thing about
that too is a lot of people are either
side will say they were like,
why?
The same people will say,
well why do you need an Ar 15?
And then in an inverse when I say the
Second Amendment is actually not about
hunting,
it's about defending ourselves from a
tyrannical government,
domestic or foreign.
They're like,
oh,
you think you little stupid guns are
going to be able to defend against the,
against the government.
And I'm like,
well then why don't you give me the guns
that the government has done?
And then they get quiet because they
realized the contradiction in what
they're stating.
Well,
it's also the government.
When you say the government,
like protect us against the government,
we are the government.
The government's filled with people like
the cops are us.
The problem is,
is this separation of us.
If you gave me a red button,
said would I,
could I end all senseless violence by
hitting that button?
I would say yes.
And then when people say it's a gun's
problem,
I said,
do you know that London Past New York
City for the first time since 1800 in
homicides,
and they did it with fucking nice with
knives to the point where that goofball
mayor of London,
that Dork on his twitter page said,
there's no reason to carry a knife.
If you get caught carrying a knife,
you will be prosecuted under the fullest
extent of the law.
This is the fucking knife.
But I've got a knife.
Oh I don't have it on me right now,
but I have a knife on me all the time.
It's the same country that the utilizes
the shining example of what we should be
doing in America.
Exactly.
And they have more murders in London
from knives.
And here's the funny thing about that
too,
you know like in.
So they have an uptake and acid attacks.
Sorry,
I think I'd rather be shot.
Yeah,
that acid.
Well that's a,
that's a thing that people are doing to
ex wives and shit too.
Yeah,
that's ducks.
I mean is that is dark.
That is some human shit.
But it's also will all of this stuff,
it comes down to like what makes a fully
developed person instead of looking at
what's available to a fully developed
person and what would allow fully
developed person to commit horrific
crimes.
What turns a person into that we should
be looking at it from the root to the
fully grown.
Like what is the process that allow
someone to become a mass shooter?
What's the process that allow them to
throw acid in someone's face?
Because I have,
you know,
I clearly have to frame everything to my
perspective because I know what the
best.
But like even for me,
like I said it in video before,
if I ever had to pull my gun and shoot
someone to take a life,
I'm going to.
I'm going to need therapy.
Yeah,
I am.
Because because I value life that much.
I value it.
Great.
Do you have children?
No,
I don't.
Let me tell you something,
man.
If he had kids and some guy was trying
to hurt your daughter and he shot him,
I think he'd sleep like a baby.
But you know what?
That's interesting you say that because
when I talked to women about firearm
ownership,
right,
like none of the girls know girls I've
ever been in a relationship with were
like pro gun.
Right?
But over time,
you know,
dealing with me,
I mean when you walk into my house and
there's five rifles on the table,
you kind of just have to get acclimated.
But in dealing with women who started
off initially as anti,
a lot of them talk about not wanting
guns because they can't see themselves
taking the life.
But the moment I asked them would they
take a life to protect a child?
Oh yeah,
I'm blowing that sucker away,
you know?
And it's interesting how that works.
How we.
And I,
I felt like I agree with you,
I'd be the same way to a child and you
know that whatever it is that turns a
child into some monster there,
Katrina,
but school,
I think that's what needs to be
examined.
I mean this is not a part of the
narrative.
It's not a part of the discussions.
No one's bringing it up.
All people bring up is the event
themselves,
the gun violence,
and we need to keep.
Keep the tools away from people.
I just think the tools are one part of
the problem.
I definitely think that you should.
If there was a way we should figure out
a way to keep psychopaths from owning
guns,
but how do you determine whether or not
someone's a psychopath so they do
something psychopathic?
Yeah,
and then someone will talk about,
well,
you know Australia,
they had one mass shooting in the 19
nineties.
They took all the guns.
There's 18 people in Australia.
It's as big as the United States.
There's less people.
Not to mention crime went up after they
did that,
did it.
Bottling crime went up when they did
that.
That's what people don't want to talk
about.
And in your right,
like people forget context.
They're like two people in Australia.
What do you know?
What about this one town in Georgia were
firearm ownership is mandatory.
I do remember hearing it and they made
it mandatory and violent crime and
everything dropped radically.
Break Ins dropped radically.
They made it mandatory.
Everybody has to have a gun,
and everybody was like,
fuck a crime.
I think about it.
I need to find a new way to make a
living because most dudes like,
look,
most dudes who engaged in crime,
right?
Like of course you have your Sickos who
just loved the violence,
right?
Most of them just crimes of opportunity.
So they're looking for victims.
They're looking for easy victims,
easy targets.
If you're going to deal with someone who
possibly is going to kill you,
they don't want to die.
Which is why you've seen a lot of these
videos with these home invasions where
you watch when the actual homeowner has
a firearm.
Once the shot start,
once the bullets start flying,
they're gone.
They're taken off.
Nobody wants to get shot.
So and so.
It always boggles my mind when people
are like,
Whoa,
you don't need a gun for this,
or you don't need to go.
I'm like,
no,
I do.
And they're like,
well,
the chances of you ever needing it or
using it,
that's a stupid idea.
It's an incredibly moronic.
Sure this.
Chances are you've gone through life
right now,
however old you are,
when I'm talking to you,
you haven't been shot.
So the chances are 100 percent that you
didn't need it.
Right?
But that doesn't mean you won't need any
crazy conversation.
I don't think the conversation should be
about the tools.
I really think the conversation should
be about what makes a person capable of
doing that.
I mean,
if the conversation is what makes a
person's such a fucking nut,
that they have so many guns that they
don't know what to do with that.
I mean,
you have so many guns you don't even
know how many have is that bad?
I don't know.
Seemed like a reasonable guy.
I'm worried about you,
but even then I can only use one gonna
come.
I only have two hands.
I get that.
But the idea is like,
what if someone breaks in your house and
steals your guns?
I'm sure you haven't been a safe,
but if somebody breaks in your house and
steals your gun,
it's like,
what?
So that's my fault.
Now that somebody wants to break the law
and breaking into my house.
No.
The idea is like access.
Now you're giving access.
Yeah.
But you eliminate limited.
It's a very different argument.
You're very different.
Yeah,
exactly.
But you still live.
But that fundamentally goes back to the
idea that people want to undervalue this
is a constitutional right,
right?
Yeah.
Um,
and so what we ended up,
we find ourselves doing is finding ways
to limit that ripe because of the few
bad people in our country,
you know,
and I just think that's the wrong way to
go about it because we're basically
evolving ourselves down to a point where
we're not going to have any rights left
because there are a couple of bad people
here who might do something bad with the
rights that you have.
I think it's the wrong way to go about
it too.
Um,
but if you,
if we had no violence in this country,
if something happened,
human beings evolved.
If our switch changed and there's no
more violence,
would you still want to have guns?
Yes.
You want to happen for recreation
because you enjoy them.
Yeah.
That's something people don't want to
hear.
Yeah.
Like I always tell people,
if you've never shot a gun,
if you've ever gone to a gun range,
you should probably should because it is
actually fun.
It's fun.
Now if you do that activity and you're
not thinking about hurting someone and
all you're thinking about is focusing on
the target,
trigger control,
all that stuff.
Is that bad?
I mean,
we do it.
Do anything on my show.
We call it athletic shooting.
Right?
So my background before I got into guns
was sports.
I was in the basketball,
football.
I ran cross country track,
you name it.
So when I got a gun,
so my,
my dream was to go to the Mba when I was
younger.
Right.
I'm clearly that didn't happen and it
wasn't going to.
But you know,
there was at that athleticism still in
me.
So what we did on the show when we were
talking about coming up with a different
shooting competition was how do I
incorporate.
I thought it,
well,
how do I incorporate some of the
athletic athleticism into shooting,
right?
Um,
which is essentially by and large a lot
of running and just shooting a different
position and so forth and so on.
And so when we're doing that,
I know thinking about shooting a person
that's not the type of shooting them
doing,
doing target,
you doing target shooting with some
athleticism involved in it.
And so,
and people undervalue that,
like it's kind of like how can you not
see that these are other ways that
firearms are used it,
which is why I started my brand new pew,
Pew Life,
right?
People.
Life is,
is
predicated around the EWP,
Ewp for people who don't understand that
people who use guns like exact firearm
lifestyle.
Yeah.
Hashtag Po Po.
Because mean,
think about it when we were kids was
also simple,
right?
It's like cops and robbers with gun pew,
Pew,
we do that.
And so,
but then so I,
I,
I want to capture the,
the recreation involved in playing cops
and robbers as a kid,
but then also understanding the very
definitive and distinction between the
good guys and bad guys,
right?
People who live this lifestyle are good
people.
They enjoy guns for recreation,
they also understand that we live in a
world where not everybody is good,
right?
So we also own guns for our own self
defense and so it's this culmination of
this lifestyle that comes together and
we appreciate guns in a way that some
people think is perverse,
but,
but how is it any less?
How is it any different than me
obsessing over the Aston Martin DB?
Yes.
For the last 20 years.
That is that perverse.
It's still,
it's still a mechanical item.
Yes.
The potential for violence is what,
what scares people and if they mean when
the guy kills 86 people nice with the
truck right now.
It's a good point.
I mean it is a very good point and no
one's trying out outlaw trucks.
No,
but it's this thing that we have in this
country where we have more guns than we
have human beings and that's,
that disturbs people yet because they
inherently vilify the firearm,
which is why I have another Hashtag that
I call still waiting,
still waiting for what?
Still waiting for my gun to jump up on
his own and kill somebody.
Um,
it's,
it is relatively tongue in cheek,
but at the same time what it does is it
transfers to focus.
And then I say,
when a drunk driver gets behind,
gets behind the wheel and kill someone,
we don't blame the vehicle for it.
We blame the driver.
Right?
So when somebody goes out and commits
violence with the firearm,
why aren't we focusing on the people who
were doing good instead of focusing on
the firearm?
Well,
I think we should certainly be focusing
on the people as we said,
we should certainly be focused on
focusing on what happens to a person
that makes them develop into the type of
person that can go into a movie theater
and shoot it up like the rural Colorado.
Let's talk about that a little bit
because that conversation and we don't
have honestly,
and I'm not going,
I don't have the answers.
I can think of several things.
You know,
the easy answer for me is to say is it's
our culture,
right?
We maybe have a culture that facilitates
this or you know,
we have situation where there are people
who do flip between the cracks.
No one pays attention to them.
There's certainly some of that.
And I do think there is a lack of hand,
right?
Pay attention to everybody you can't.
But then also I think there's,
like I was raised by a single parent
mother,
right.
And My mother over compensated when
raising me because she understood the
limitations of her being a woman raising
a young man.
Right?
So she was unnecessarily hard on me.
My mom has zero tolerance for my
emotions,
absolutely zero.
So what she taught me growing up was how
to deal with adversity,
taught me how to deal with failure,
how to get past those things,
taught me how to be self assured.
And so what I think we're lacking to a
degree in this country is people not
having the coping mechanisms to deal
with failure or to deal with rejection,
you know?
Um,
so I'm getting worse than others.
I agree.
It
was definitely that.
There's definitely people that feel like
they're outsiders and they want to flip
the board over there losing the game and
they just want to flip the board over
and that seems like that Parkland kid
mean there were kids that were worried
about him before this ever happened and
that his whole thing was that his life
was shit and he wanted other people to
experience that.
Yeah,
and the thing is is like the hard thing
about it too is not a realizing that
just came to my mind.
I think sometimes I don't even want to
talk about the mental health aspect of
it in this particular case with the
parking street because I just want to
relegate them to evil.
Right?
Right.
Because it pisses me off like you're,
you're taking innocent lives because you
feel bad.
Go in a corner and shoot yourself.
If that's the case,
there's a romanticized version of that
too,
where people just want to take everybody
out,
take all the people out that you saw
that were doing well while you were
struggling.
There's that,
put them in,
but the world always flips and flips if
you've got a good attitude and you're a
healthy person like yourself,
but if you're mentally ill and your life
has been just tormented and abuse and
mental health issues and you're all
fucked up,
it's.
I don't know what the answer is,
know what the answer is,
but I do know that the problem lies in
the individuals that are capable of
committing that and how did they become
that?
Because you've got to make a great point
cause you got the mindset that you have
to be in a walk down the school hall and
just shoot people,
shoot kids to shoot him.
It just innocently just.
It's fucking.
It's fucking gross.
Yeah.
Whether it's sandy hook or whatever.
Any one of these things like you have to
be fucked up to do that.
Like as and how many people are running
around that are like three quarters
fucked up.
You only need a few bad things to go
wrong in relatively speaking.
When you think about the fact that
there's 300 plus million people in this
country,
these are relatively relatively few
people that they are capable and that
actually act on such terrific have a
act,
but what do you think can be done to
stop this stuff?
Have you thought about it?
Yeah,
I think about it all the time.
It's,
it's,
it's a harder question for me to ask
them to come up with ways of why we
don't need gun control.
Right.
You know,
because that's,
that's,
you know,
it's hard.
Especially when I'm taking gun control
off the table because people are always
saying,
you know,
you guys don't,
you guys don't want to move one inch.
When I was like,
yeah,
because we'd been moving in Itch for the
last 20,
30 years.
The problem is it's a,
it's a fucked up argument because the
people that are holding the guns are not
necessarily the people that are doing
these things.
You're,
you're,
you're trying to attack the,
the vast majority of gun owners are not
committing crimes with guns.
They're not.
So when I think about what can we do to
stop,
it's different types of shooting.
For instance,
let's talk.
Let's start with the.
Let's start with what types of shootings
that happened the most gang violence,
right?
So if you look at the statistics,
you think,
oh my gosh,
Americans' war zone,
right?
30,000
people a year die in an eight,
and in the vast majority of it that is
remaining is actual homicides is gang
violence.
So then we have a gang problem.
We'd have a gang problem in this
country.
We have a socioeconomic problem in very
specific areas in this country,
right?
Because I just came from south side
Chicago where I started in high park
where Obama used to live and enjoy a few
minutes into an area that looked like a
bomb went off.
They don't have the violence in high
park that they had in that area.
Why they had the same access to illegal
guns.
They don't have the same problem because
there's a difference in economics and no
one wants to do well.
No one wants to address that,
right?
If I'm a kid growing up in that
neighborhood and I'm going to a school
that Shitty,
right?
They don't give,
they don't give a damn about me.
I looked up and was able to go to good
schools,
right?
I went to schools where my teachers
cared.
I went to schools where teachers pushed
me when I was slacking off.
You know,
I had the ability to take out loans to
go to a good law school.
You know,
I had those abilities.
If I'm a kid growing up in this
environment and I can't find refuge in
my school,
I can't find refuge at home because my
mom's working three or four or five
jobs,
so she's never there.
Where am I going to go find parents?
I'm going to,
where am I going to find that parental
influence?
I'm gonna find on the streets.
So now I'm on the streets being led by
people who grew up in the exact
conditions that I grew up in and so now
I'm like,
okay,
well I have to make money.
What am I going to do for money?
Well,
then there's the Naco economy.
Very conveniently right there for me,
right?
So drugs.
So now I'm selling.
Now I'm saying on the corner selling
drugs,
I got to protect my product,
right?
If I don't,
someone's gonna take it from me.
So what do I do?
I get a gun,
I carry a gun.
Now I'm stuck in the true.
Now I'm just stuck in this violent loop,
right?
If that feeds on itself,
and so now I'm stuck defending myself
against the guy who shooting at me,
trying to take my stuff and I'm shooting
back at him.
Maybe not because I'm trying to take
your stuff,
but because he's trying to take them
out,
right?
So that's where you get that violence
that comes from that,
from those particular areas.
Now,
if we would have sat back and said,
okay,
we have hyper concentrated areas in this
country,
this is a widespread.
It's hyper concentrated communities in
this country that are dealing with this,
that are also the result of the vast
majority of our gun violence.
If we sat back and thought about it from
a socioeconomic standpoint,
how do we fix this?
What do we do?
How do we present opportunity,
I'm not saying go there and just hand
out stuff,
but how do we fix this from the
standpoint of improving our schools?
How is that can drive five minutes,
one direction and have a school that has
everything you can name and then driving
into driving the opposite direction.
The school has can barely have textbooks
to give to the kids.
Think about that.
So why?
Why aren't we focusing our energy on
building data up versus talking about,
oh,
we need to get the guns off the streets.
You did that.
You had that in Chicago.
You have every gun law imaginable in
Chicago,
but just outside Chicago still looks the
way that it does still as a violence
that it does.
Right?
So if we would,
if we provide,
when you give people something lose or
the lift for they don't throw away life
so easily.
Plain and simple.
So if my social economic status is in
the dirt,
I don't have a problem looking at
another kid down the street and shooting
at him and taking his life.
I don't have anything.
I don't have anything to lose.
But if we were to focus our attention
and fixing that same way we talk about
the mental health issue with respect to
mass shootings and school shootings,
we wouldn't have to worry about the guns
because we don't have people wanting to
do those things or have the capability
to do those things.
Right.
So then that deals with that vast
majority of the violence that we had.
They're focusing that energy in fixing
those communities.
I agree with you 100 percent,
and we've talked about this many,
many times in the show that I think that
if you wanted to make America a better
place,
one of the best ways to do it is to make
it easier for someone to succeed.
Make it easy and,
and stop pretending that it's a level
playing field.
Because I didn't grow up in a level
playing field and I got lucky.
I got lucky.
A lot of people did.
And if you go to somewhere like the
south side of Chicago and you don't
realize that you got lucky,
you,
you're,
you're blind.
Yeah,
there's,
we want them.
What's the best way to make America
stronger?
Less losers.
Less people who lose their how did,
how has that will give them more of a
chance,
give them more of an opportunity and
give them guidance,
ship community centers,
clean up the streets,
fixed buildings,
but that's a lot of fucking money that
we're spending right now in Afghanistan
and Iraq and missiles and all kinds of
crazy shit that we're not putting any
money into that.
But then who do we hold accountable?
We.
So for instance,
do we like when we talk about the inner
cities,
for instance,
[inaudible],
they had been democratically run for
ages.
Now the local leadership,
there's democratic,
right?
But there's no money there.
The problem is there's the money's going
somewhere.
I me look at Chicago,
just not enough.
I mean the,
the,
the money's going into the areas where
people are wealthy and that's what
they're supporting.
They're not supporting these
impoverished areas.
And then you know what?
You're absolutely right.
So if that's the case and we all
understand that and you know that stop
selling this bullshit about gun control
there,
but let's just tell you,
that's just one,
one aspect to the next one.
Yeah,
I agree with you there.
So in that sense,
in when it comes to gun violence,
it's very complex when it comes to gang
violence,
it's very complex and I agree with you
that they need.
There's no other way to stop that then
to fix the inner cities where people are
just in that cycle of constant poverty
and crime and that's all they see around
them.
So it becomes normalized.
Yeah,
absolutely.
So,
so now let's talk about mass shootings.
Mass shootings,
right?
So get rid of gun free zones.
No one wants to hear that.
Get rid of gun free zones.
If you're not going to establish a
perimeter outside of a building where I
can go,
don't tell me I can't bring my gun in
there.
A sign on the window is not stopping
somebody from coming into the building.
We've seen it time and time and time and
time again.
If the guns were the problems,
we would have mass shooting at every gun
show every single day.
What we don't.
Why the same reason you pointed out why
that one,
that one place in Georgia when they said
everybody had to have a gun,
crime went down.
People don't want to hear that though.
They don't want to hear that.
The answer to gun violence is everyone
has a gun.
Now,
not such a convenient answer for a guy
like you as very convenient.
So many guns can't count.
But here,
let's look at the alternative.
We've been living in it,
right?
Right.
And we know that there's a problem.
So why are we entertaining in the fact
that maybe that is the case,
right?
But do you think that like school
shootings for example,
do you think that these teachers being
armed would be the answer?
All right,
so what do you think there should be
armed security on the campus?
I say it should be multilayered,
right?
Because if you,
if you really want to put things into
perspective and the NRA didn't add about
this and people got pissed off,
but it's the truth.
Wherever whatever school the president's
kids go to,
they are guarded by guns,
right?
At school was protected by guns.
Right.
Anything we hold valuable in this
country is protected with guns.
No one is more anti gun than Hollywood.
When you hear about any sort of crime or
gun violence,
the left wing people in Hollywood are
the most vocal,
the most virtue signaling the quickest
to jump on their pedestal.
Meanwhile,
what percentage of their fucking movies
involve gun violence?
And if you look at the Academy Awards,
did you see the security at the Academy
Awards?
You see all these left leaning liberal
actors being protected by people of flak
jackets on carrying guns with fingers
outside the triggers.
I mean dogs,
but yeah,
it's crazy.
You know what it is though.
It's a loss of touch with reality.
Well,
there are also insulated and protected.
That's part of it because in their mind
their mindset goes like this.
Well,
I have security guards.
I mean,
Kim Kardashians,
the biggest.
I did a video on that,
so I did.
That was the first thing that came to
vegas.
What she biggest hypocrite on that,
right?
Because she's a dumb dumb of course,
but she's.
She also influences a ton of people.
That's unfortunate.
But exactly.
Steve Harvey hat or on family feud,
they were on family feud that
Kardashians the whether we're talking
about how fucking stupid kid was,
but we know this though.
That's the crazy thing.
There's no incentive for her to be
intelligent.
There isn't.
I mean she's good at making money.
Just show.
Absolutely.
Yeah,
absolutely.
And I don't fault her for that.
Hey,
make you money.
But we're.
But,
but at the end of the day,
you still,
she still has access to scores of young
influential rides.
I understand that.
That's unfortunate,
but there's nothing we can do about
that,
but other than you point out the fact
that she's
a dumb dumb.
Pretty much.
Yeah.
It's not terrible person.
I don't think it's been.
I don't know.
I don't know the one.
I just don't know.
I've heard her talk.
I just don't think she's really
interested in expanding your mind.
I just don't think that that's something
that's not benefits booklets her.
Here's the thing though.
The mindset though is there are people
who we paid to carry guns,
right?
I don't need to carry them.
Therefore you don't either.
So what you're saying about her is that
she is anti gun,
she talks about being anti gun,
yet she's constantly surrounded by
people who have guns.
That's a fact.
Absolute fact.
So you cancel this fact so then you
can't turn around and tell me that.
No,
you don't need a firearm.
Of course you don't pitch seven foot
tall dudes strapped to the fucking gills
all around you.
So it's,
it's,
it,
it's man.
It's frustrating because it's like,
I get it.
I would love to have eight dudes
standing out here with Ar,
15 slung over their shoulders ready to
protect me at have given notice where I
could afford it.
I pay for it,
not do it.
The funny thing is I still carry a gun
on me because I can't always be exactly
where I am.
Right.
You know what I mean?
That's a paranoid way to live though,
isn't it?
What difference does it make you think
about it?
How much does it affect me?
I wake up everyday,
put a gun on my hip and go out and do
the exact same thing I would do if I
didn't have it.
But you don't think about it.
So in the.
In a sense,
you feel like you're not paranoid.
I'm not paranoid.
No,
there's no.
no,
no more paranoid than any than any
person that has a fire extinguisher in
their house.
Think about it.
It's a.
it's like I don't walk around like,
Oh my God,
my God,
who's,
who's coming to get me?
That's paranoia.
What?
All I'm doing is being prepared right
now.
There could be levels of preparedness.
You start to get hit diminishing
returns.
Where starts to be in like it starts to
take away from your quality of life,
but me putting a gun on my hip and just
going about my business that doesn't
interfere with my life enough to say,
you know what?
It's not quite worth it.
You know?
It's funny what you said about humility
and that you like more calm and relaxed
since you've been involved with guns.
The same thing happens with Jujitsu.
Martial arts training in particular,
but Jujitsu in particular because you
get strangled so much.
My neck hurts right now because I was
rolling with a guy just before I came up
like last week.
And um,
it,
it man,
it's such a beautiful sport.
It's beautiful,
but it also lets you know your place in
the food chain,
especially when you first start out,
you start to realize you really honestly
can't call out an elite human until it's
too late.
What do you mean?
So when I started,
before I started really kind of getting
into mma,
so forth and so on,
I thought I could spot out the guy you
don't want to mess with.
Oh,
right.
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
And then I went to class and then he
knew my coach started pairing me with
different people and I'm like,
holy crap.
Like if I was seeing this dude was just
walking down the sidewalk,
I'm like,
yeah,
I can handle him.
And now I'm rolled up.
The Pretzel was nuts in my face.
Narrowed assassins assassins?
Yeah man.
At Tenth Planet we've
got a whole army of him.
He would still a computer dorks,
no kill you with their legs.
Yup.
The wrap their legs around your neck and
choke you to sleep,
but you can't even stop it from
happening.
That's crazy.
Nothing man.
And then my.
Now I always get stuck and I'm going to
overpower him and I'm like,
Nah,
you better off being week.
Believe it or not,
the best Jujitsu is weak man's Jujitsu.
I always say,
if you're going to learn Jiu Jitsu
learning from a small guy because you
learn from a small guy,
they.
They've never been able to cheat,
meaning they never been able to.
I've always had to have perfect
technique,
techniques,
everything.
When it comes to Jitsu,
literally you have to have some strength
for sure and strength with technique is
the ultimate but perfect technique is
where it's at and you get that from like
little guys like Barrett Yoshida,
Eddie Bravo,
heuler grace of the smaller guys are the
ones that you want to learn from because
they've never been the big guy.
The big guys are like top game guys.
Smash past guys.
Those guys were just relying on
horsepower and leg strength and shit.
Those,
that's not the way to learn,
you know,
the way to learn is to go around things.
Gotcha.
And you know,
the funny thing about that is it,
do you know why I started doing it?
Why someone said would if there took
your gun away,
Bro?
No one said that.
I said it to myself.
Oh right.
So to myself,
because I didn't,
I almost thought I was over dependent on
it because when remember the gun is a
tool.
She carried a knife too.
I used to.
She's like that's bitch I used to but I,
I float,
I float.
I'm in this weird space where like,
my jeans are kind of sorted a little too
tight and not so they're not quite
skinny jeans,
but it's Kinda like after a certain
point I have too much stuff going on in.
I got the answer for you.
My friend,
let's call called a fanny pack.
Uh,
you know,
they're not gonna let me get away with
that.
Fuck you talking about higher
primate.com.
You go buy one right now.
I'll give you one.
Do we have some here?
You would.
You never wear this.
You would never wear this.
I'm down to try anything.
Come on man.
Tactically,
tactical wallet.
Some of them,
but they have ones that are tactical
ones.
They rip them open.
Do you have a tactical and I'm all for
it.
No,
this is just a regular one.
So this should keep the shit on you so
you don't have your pockets all filled
with shit to here's my life.
Here's my favorite part.
This is what I consider fairly pack.
Oh,
that's a little big.
Yeah,
I know.
But then again,
I'm the guy who carried it,
but I'm the guy who runs around with Mac
book,
Ipad,
you know,
because I have carried when everywhere.
Pretty much if I can pay you back
because I'm constantly working.
Writing,
working?
Yeah.
What do you.
Would you like,
what kind of stuff do you write?
Script?
Pretty much 80 to 90 percent of my show.
Oh,
okay.
Yeah.
Oh no kidding.
Yeah,
I,
I write all,
all the videos I do.
I write them.
Do you write them in?
They put them on a teleprompter or do
you practice it?
Sometimes it straight off the tops and,
and teleprompter.
It just depends what we feel is going to
give the communicate the best to what
you're trying to achieve.
Oh,
that's cool.
Well that's,
it shows work ethic for sure.
I mean,
I don't,
I don't have a life,
you know,
I really don't.
All I do is work,
work out and eat.
So is this,
these videos?
Is this your tired life now?
For the most part,
yeah.
And in terms of your occupation?
So you don't work as a lawyer?
Um,
I do a little bit.
I still have things with a small firm in
Houston.
Um,
and then so other than that,
just other investments and things that
have gone on,
that's about it.
So you're able to make a living off of
these videos.
There was a time when you could do it on
youtube anymore?
Yeah,
it's real recent.
Within the last six or seven months.
Well actually a gun guy started noticing
that drop a long time ago.
Like I'm talking about.
We went from like to like half.
Yeah.
And then now it's like 70 percent.
So in that happened,
that happened like a couple of years
ago.
And how does that work in terms of like,
did they pick certain videos that are
just not eligible for monetizations?
I would have known before it was just a
drop in organic reach.
It just started like it wasn't,
it wasn't anything formal.
At least that's what I picked up on
because I started noticing.
I'm like,
wait a minute.
Like,
I mean I wasn't living off the youtube
stuff,
but I was like,
this is like,
I just kept my income cut in half.
It's weird.
Yeah.
Well there's,
there's been some people that have
investigated this and there's been some
inside sources have told people that
they actively target conservatives,
gun owners,
redneck.
They do it on twitter.
They do it a lot,
a lot of different places.
I don't doubt it.
I don't know.
One hundred percent.
Where's that guy?
American provider Guy that did those
undercover investigative reports.
He sent a bunch of people into like bars
and talk to twitter engineers.
Um,
you know what I'm talking about.
Yeah.
Now I will say this though,
there are so like there are certain
people in these places that are
actually,
they may not even agree with my stance,
but I've talked to them and they'll help
me out the best that they can.
You know,
some people on facebook,
some people youtube so and so on because
they're all those individuals,
you know,
the column column go support is in a
sense because you know they can be more
explicit about the,
you know,
yeah.
You're not going to have just a complete
uniform,
left wing ideology at any of these
organizations are going to be some
people that,
but they get stuck in these group think
environments like Google or wherever the
fuck it is and they can't speak out.
Which is unfortunate because I'm like,
isn't this country?
This country was founded on the idea of
having having a release,
undercover footage of twitter employees
and employees,
engineers and employees,
admitting that twitter employees view
everything you post on their servers,
including private sex messages and Dick
pics because that's why.
That's why I don't send them.
I've never seen engineers also admit
that twitter analyzes this information
to create a virtual profile of you,
which they sell to advertisers.
James O'keefe has completed the book
about the series entitled American
provider,
my fight for the truth in the era of
fake news.
Yeah.
So this guy has sent a bunch of people
to talk to like engineers and I've seen
the videos where they're explaining how
they a dog a rhythm and how they make it
so that these people don't even know
that people can't see their,
their tweets or give it all the time.
People to send it to me all the time
like,
hey,
you know,
um,
for some reason youtube is forcing me to
unfollow you.
Like thought I followed you,
but then I'm not following you.
And I think some of that's paranoia and
I do.
Some of it is,
some of it isn't.
Um,
but it still begs the question because
the numbers don't lie.
Right?
So like,
I know with facebook there was times I
was reaching millions of people but just
to post.
But then that got cut in half.
But largely that was due to
monetization,
that was before facebook was monetizing
itself.
So they wanted to cotton now there they
want you to pay to get access to your
audience.
You get what I'm saying so that I don't
like it,
but it isn't,
it isn't like some deep secret kind of
like,
oh,
I want to stifle your reach because you
believe in it's now there may be some of
that going on.
Right?
So I had,
for instance,
like I buy ads for my merchandise,
sell on facebook,
right?
Because if I just post a picture of it,
my entire artist doesn't see it.
Right.
And so somebody went through facebook
and just deleted all of our ads,
like especially toward money on ads and
they just delete,
disapproved them out of nowhere.
And so then I called the contact and
then it was like,
no,
that should've happened.
And then it went back and put it back
up.
So sometimes it's even individualized,
you know what I mean?
It's just an individual who disagrees
with everything you stand for.
Who has the power to do it.
When you remember when that guy did that
with trump is disabled,
is twitter really did it for a couple of
days?
You know,
there's definitely people that have that
kind of power and they abuse it.
I mean,
you see that everywhere.
You see that with moderators on message
boards.
You see that with every time people have
more power than you and they go,
I don't like this fucking guy,
this guy talking about his guns.
Fuck his ass,
and they just yank them.
The weird thing is though,
like I don't complain about it on my
platform at all because no one cares.
Yeah.
Because I remember the first time
youtube started taking off taking like
demonetizing my videos for ads.
I mentioned it and a lot of people were
like,
good,
I don't like those ads anyway.
You do realize I have to pay to get this
stuff done.
Right.
You know?
Well no one seems to care until it comes
and affects them because they don't
realize that essentially what they're
doing is they're,
they're censoring you by diminishing the
amount of money that you can make.
Yeah.
You know,
you could,
you could say it's not real censorship,
but it is censorship.
I mean it's,
it's,
it's pretty much what I'm dealing with
right now.
So for instance,
right now my videos don't come out as
consistently.
Like I do good reviews.
I'm known for my gun reviews.
Right.
And I liked my grandmother used to be
very cinematic voiceover.
I put thought into them.
I write scripts out from my videos.
The problem is too now before where I
could afford to hire someone to edit
them,
I can't write and I need that now more
than ever because now on the political
front of the things I'm running around,
I'm traveling.
That's why I was having my Mac book with
me.
I have to try to find places where I can
try to edit a little bit and get things
done.
But then the same people who were like,
we don't care about
the ads on your videos and you make your
money from your,
from your videos are saint people like
why aren't you making videos as much as
you used to?
Well,
I'm like,
well,
I don't have the money to pay someone to
edit the videos in order to keep pumping
them out the way I was doing it before
and I'm not going to give you some sub
quality crap.
Right.
I could just toss a video together and
just throw it out there.
It's just too much noise.
You can't listen to all those people
that are complaining and asking for
things,
which is true,
but I really.
I really do think that twitter or
youtube rather is fucking up because
they're opening up the door to a
competitor that is really invested in
free speech.
I disagree.
Really?
How so?
It's the advertisers.
They are at the.
They are at the mercy of the
advertisers.
They are,
but I know people over at Youtube,
they are deciding what they want said
and not Sacha,
and this is how I know.
I brought up Jordan Peterson,
this woman that worked at huge fan of
and she said he's a troublemaker,
and I said,
how is he a troublemaker?
She had no answer.
She radical left wing but not
thoughtful,
not,
not thoughtful.
Like she.
She'd just have a good argument for this
and when you did,
when you pushed back,
she's used to being the boss at work.
She's used to just dismissing you and
when I was pushing back with her like,
why?
Why is that?
Why?
Why is he a troublemaker?
Like you're telling me what's
problematic,
but what he says,
no answer to that,
but yet able to dismissively say
someone's a troublemaker when they're a
very highly respected intellectual that
has amazing points about a lot of
different things that resonates with a
lot of very,
very smart people.
I think he's the nature of our time.
He's a very bright guy in a,
in a really good human.
When you meet him,
he's a really good person.
So for someone just say he's a
troublemaker,
like okay,
no because he doesn't agree with you and
he's causing trouble with your
organization because you're censoring
people's views and viewpoints and it's
so convenient to read the label.
Someone all right or you know,
this is,
this is what we're dealing with today.
There's these hate identity politics.
It drives me insane.
It's crazy.
It's crazy how many people flocked to it
too because it's intellectually easier
varies.
It's very easy.
You can sit there and then you just re
just regurgitate all of the talking
points that you have.
This is why I don't do well on cable
news hits because what ends up happening
is like on this issue,
I intellectualize it,
right?
Like the conversation we're having now,
like I get the benefit.
I love this because we could sit here if
we need to think about something.
You know?
That's a good point.
Yeah.
Let me think about that for a little
like on cable news and you can't do
that.
You can't do that.
I just did this kind of platforms,
the best platform because the
conversation is never interrupted.
He never stopped for ads and no one can
tell someone to.
I'm about to go to the bathroom.
Here you go ahead,
man.
Sorry we could wrap this up soon,
but I wanted to.
I really wanted to get to other than not
having gun free zones.
Yeah.
I mean not having everyone armed to the
teeth and.
Well,
no.
Here's,
here's the thing.
Here's the thing.
I was saying if you're going to have gun
free zones,
make them real gun gun free zones.
Don't just put a sticker on the
window and then say you can't bring your
gun in here and then not have physical
measures in place to prevent it because
otherwise I'm allowed to prevent it to
have like some movie theater or
something.
If you have a movie theater,
have them.
If you're gonna,
make it a gun free zone.
Have a metal detector and the metal
detector goes off.
You're still fucking guns in the room.
And what are you gonna do you have armed
guards to keep people from?
So then.
So then don't make it a gun free zone.
Right?
Okay.
But even if you don't mean,
okay,
say if you have a gun free zone and you
have a movie theater and you put the
metal detectors on,
the only way to enforce that is to have
guns.
Okay?
Yeah.
But you know what I'm saying?
So if you want to hire,
if you want to hire,
if you want to hire armed guard to stand
there,
right?
With the metal detectors,
because of the metal detectors are only
as good as the person being able to
enforce it.
Right.
So we need to.
We need the executive.
Right.
So that would be an armed guard.
Right?
Right.
So we think about it though.
We do it at the airport.
Yes.
You know what I'm saying?
We do it at certain nightclubs when I
go,
I'm not admitting to go into strip clubs
where I am.
When I go to strip club,
I get patted down.
There's a guard there.
There's usually three,
three guys there with guns.
I mean,
and I don't.
Besides the people they let in who
shouldn't have them anyway,
she just.
There's always going to be cracks.
Right?
Right.
But at at least if you're going to make
it a gun free zone,
put up the physical preventative
measures to reinforce that.
You can't just.
A lot of people just don't sticker on
the window and say this is a gun free
zone.
The only people who are going to obey
that or the people you're not even
worried about anyway.
Well,
the thing about movie theaters,
there's movie theaters don't even say
this is a gun free zone.
When do they say there's some movie
theaters?
Is it state to state?
So for instance,
like in Dallas,
right where um,
there are some movie theaters where I
can bring my gun in.
No problem.
There are other movie theaters that have
these signs that say you're not allowed
to carry a gun in here.
Right?
And so it is state to state.
Some states they just require you to put
up a sign,
like it's business to business to it is,
it absolutely is.
So from that perspective,
it's like,
it's like even the courthouse,
right when I go to the courthouse
courthouse was a gun free zone minus the
fact if you were a cop.
But what do you have to do when you go
to the courthouse?
You go through metal detectors.
There were cops,
there were people there with guns.
So what do you do about schools?
Same thing,
but it's like these guys that are
showing up,
they're not even,
they're not even students to that
school.
Like Mr Glenn Hug.
Think about it like this though it.
This is where the argument gets really
disingenuous because it's like,
oh,
we want to save our kids lives in
schools.
Right,
so the inner cities have more violence
than we can think of.
Right?
There's tons of shootings that go on
outside of the schools in their cities.
Was the last time you heard a mass
shooting in the inner city?
Very,
very rarely.
Very rarely.
If not ever.
What's the one thing that they all have?
Metal detectors.
Huh?
What's the one thing that Parkland
didn't have?
Metal detectors.
What's the one thing that a lot of these
suburban schools that get shot up don't
have metal detectors?
Well,
you know,
it's one of the things that they've
found too,
is that it's a very strange sort of
situation,
but when you deal with places that have
a lot of violence,
when you deal with places that have gun
violence and crime,
which you don't have in those places,
is the random mass shootings.
You have one on one crime,
one arm,
but the tangible reality of actual gun
violence for whatever reason,
sort of eliminates these mass shootings.
The mass shootings tend to occur in
places where people think they're safe.
Yeah,
right.
Like schools,
movie theaters.
I think there's just,
there's a different dynamic involved.
You know what I mean?
It's um,
it's gonna become more of an unknown
because if you compare the violence in
the inner city to volunteer the suburbs
which present themselves and by way of
mass shootings,
if you compare the numbers as a whole
mass shootings account for statistics
for about one to two percent of all gun
violence,
right?
And so,
but does exceedingly higher number of
percentage of gun violence in inner
cities.
Right?
And it all really goes back down to what
I said before,
it's by the economics.
So you have a situation in the suburb,
suburban areas where economically
speaking,
they're good,
right?
Right.
So there's not really an incentive to
just engage in random violence.
You know,
there isn't a narco economy there that
that feeds on itself,
that requires you to engage in a certain
level of violence in order to survive.
Whereas on the other hand,
in the inner cities,
you do have that dynamic.
So from that perspective,
what ends up happening though,
even though there was an money,
isn't everything,
money doesn't care it all,
so you're still gonna have instances of
people who slipped through the cracks
because money doesn't cure everything
and so when it does happen to manifest
itself in these random acts of mass
shootings,
right?
Whereas here there isn't.
If I know I'm going to school and I'm
going to have to deal with,
I'm going to have to inevitably deal
with the violence outside of the school
anyway.
It almost,
it almost makes it unnecessary to engage
in random acts of mass shootings.
It's almost,
it's almost kind of like this perverted
distraction from,
from wanting to shoot a place up when
you have to deal with violence on an
ongoing basis every single day of your
life.
You know what I mean?
I think that's what their point was.
The point was that when violence is real
and it's around you all the time.
Yeah,
it's,
it doesn't become this attractive.
Blow up the game.
Why don't you go take a leak and then
we'll wrap this up and I'll get back.
Cool.
I'm young.
James is going to show me his collection
of guns while you're gone.
Carries one in his pants at all times.
Strapped right next to his deck.
Do you think you'd ever carry a gun?
Carry.
Oh,
like what if like what if someone came
in here and got us licensed for
concealed carry and said young Jamie,
you need to be strapped.
All you have to do is fill out this
paperwork and I'm going to make it
happen,
man.
I just don't personally feel.
I mean,
I,
I feel like it's also naivety or
whatever that I don't feel the need
to do it.
Well,
most of the time you wouldn't have the
need to do it.
Right?
Right.
The question is,
if you were at a place like,
you know,
fill in the blank,
whenever one of these things has gone
down a nightclub,
let's say that gay nightclub in Orlando,
maybe you're curious and you're walking
around with the theater.
I love about Batman the night it came
out.
Yeah.
How about the Batman one or there wasn't
a one,
an Amy Schumer movie?
There was,
yeah,
there was a mass shooting,
you know,
I think it was an amy schumer movie,
one of our movies because she became
like this big anti-gun advocate
afterwards.
Um,
what do you think that you would ever
find yourself in a situation where you'd
want a gun?
I mean,
after that happened,
I just,
I was,
I've gone to movies and pictured it
happening and I don't know,
you just think about what you would do
and I don't know that pulling out a gun
and firing back is even in my conscious
thoughts.
It's definitely in the cards.
If the guy has a gun and he's in the
room and you see one guy shooting people
and you're there and he's not shot you
yet,
it's definitely in the option.
I suppose so,
yeah.
I mean it depends on how long you're in
there too.
If it's also whether or not you can keep
your shit together while someone
shooting,
you know.
I mean keeping your shit together while
while guns are going off and.
But that is.
That is not a normal thing for you and
the amount of adrenaline will be pumping
through your body.
We're talking about if you were in a
situation where a mass shooting was
going down,
the people that think they can just pull
out their gun and shoot that person.
You might fucking hit random people.
You might hit the wall.
You might hit the ceiling.
Like,
here's the thing about.
I'll tell you,
I have a lot of experience in archery
and one of the things that happens with
people when they're shooting a live
animals,
they panic.
A big fucking moose walks in and you,
you might hit that moves in the Dick.
You might not even,
even things as big as a building and you
might miss it.
Totally.
I mean,
it happens all the time.
Twenty yards away.
People missed the entire animal.
They're just.
And that's something that's not even
going to fight back.
That's just a Moose for the vegas
shooting thing.
I any,
any,
uh,
witness reports and anything.
It's so hard.
I feel like anything,
even video reports,
there's such a chaotic situation.
Sunday night.
Everybody's wasted.
Yup.
So wasted.
What are you going to do?
You have no idea?
Well,
it's also one of those things too,
whereas it's real problem with the
conspiracy theories because one of the
things that happen out of the Vegas
situation was people would show up at
all these different casinos and say
someone's shooting.
So they would say were the security.
We go,
there's an active shooter at circus
circus.
There's an active shooter.
So the conspiracy theories were like,
look,
they're shooters everywhere.
There were shootings everywhere.
I know there was people everywhere that
were freaking out because this fucking
guy was just gunning people down from a
hotel room when they haven't learned
about being a lawyer.
Eye witness testimony is not reliable.
Eye witness testimony is dog shit,
man.
I've had people tell me about situations
where I was there.
I was there.
I'm like,
dude,
that is not what fucking happened,
and then you have to go over it with
them and they're like,
oh yeah,
maybe you're right.
I will.
This though.
People stopping mass shootings with
firearms happens more than people
realize it does happen,
but it's just what happens is it's very
disingenuous to deny it happens.
There's a lot of stories out there where
it's happened and people don't know
about it because they're not.
They're not going to push it.
So you think the elimination of gun free
zones would be the way to protect
people?
I say,
no,
I'm going to clear it.
I'm.
I'm cleaned up a little bit.
If you're going to have a gun free zone,
have physical preventative measures in
order to enrich,
to enforce it.
If you're not going to do that,
eliminate them.
I think they're.
I think first and foremost,
this will be the first thing that we
should do.
There should be some sort of a public
hearing on the use of Ssri
antidepressants,
psych medications and their
corresponding instances like the,
the,
the amount of instances where these
shooters are on these things.
I don't think people are aware.
I'll say this much.
To piggyback off what you're saying,
if I was diagnosed with a mental
disorder,
I first thing I would do is I would go
to a bookstore or go online and figure
out every possible way that I can tell,
help my way through it because I won't
touch the stuff.
Well.
One of the things that's just as
effective if not more effective.
I think Google this cardio,
I think exercise and running is more
effective to treat depression than ssrs.
I am almost certain that's that,
that that's the case.
I don't doubt it at all.
I mean,
I think or you think so many people are
addicted to marathons?
Yeah.
Oh,
believe me,
I wanted to get high.
Yeah.
There's something to it,
man.
I get high when I run for sure.
Is there anything in there?
Every time I go to the official site
that says it's not a real thing whose
blood official sense?
CBI Dot.
Where's the NCBI?
The like where they did a study on it.
Is exercise a viable treatment for
depression or they want to say no,
get pilled up,
but there.
There are studies that have been done
that show because I know Rhonda,
Patrick was discussing it.
I have to be freaking.
I hate taking medicine like I have to be
on the floor before take prescribing
exercise before medication.
A real big activity is shown to be
effective treatment for many forms of
depression.
So why are so many people still on
antidepressants?
Well,
here's one reason,
and this is not to dismiss the people
that are depressed because I know people
that are depressed and it's a horrible
thing and I know people that have been
helped by antidepressants.
I know people that have my good friend
Ray.
He was suicidal.
He got on antidepressants.
He's happiest.
Fuck.
Now he's off of them.
It helped him.
My friend Brian,
it was the same thing,
not the Brian that we know another
Brian,
he was a Jujitsu guy that I knew.
He had a real fucking problem,
got on Ssri,
turned his life around,
found a good woman,
got got an a great relationship.
It started his own business,
weaned himself off of him.
Now he's happy.
There's sometimes people find ruts in
their life.
We had a podcast with a guy wrote a book
on it,
a Guy Johann Hari,
who wrote a book on depression,
Ssri for depression,
heart failure patients not so fast.
This study should put to rest the
practice of starting ssrs and depressed
patients with heart failure in an
attempt to affect cvd outcomes would a
cvd.
Cardiovascular disease.
Oh,
okay.
well that's with people with heart
problems typically,
but it's also a depression.
People with depression and heart
failure.
Yeah.
Fucking exercise I think is is not.
It's a requirement of the human body.
I really agree with that.
Something even my darkest times,
so I'm never at my.
I'm more.
I'm never more at my best.
Then actually when I'm down,
when I'm going through things because.
Because my,
my response to it is what it is to
tighten up.
It forces you to folk.
Exactly.
Yeah.
And so one of those things that I do is
like,
I've been to the gym everyday for the
last two weeks,
right?
Um,
it forces me to one of those things that
happened that one of the things that
happens is I start working out more
because of the clarity of mind I get
after the fact,
right.
And then the sense of accomplishment and
then it Kinda starts me off in a way
where it's like,
okay,
now what's next?
It's like I'm chasing,
I'm chasing the next thing to conquer.
Um,
but.
But yeah,
I,
I agree with you wholeheartedly.
I think.
I think focusing on focusing on means
outside of just prescribing pills,
right?
I don't like taking pills.
I don't like things that alter my mind.
I don't,
I don't like it.
Maybe because I'm a control freak in
that sense.
I'm the guy with 100 guns is a control
freak.
I have something to say about.
It was just thinking about.
I had thought while I was using your
super toilet,
crazy toilet,
right?
You gotta take a shit.
That's the where to go.
Um,
I was thinking,
I was like,
man,
yeah,
I should get Joe Rogan,
one of my guns.
And then I realized you can't even
notice it here.
I can't.
Nope.
What can I own?
What do you have that I can own?
A was the first gun I ever.
The first couldn't.
I've done.
So this one just so happens to be one
that you can see.
You have a company that makes him.
Is that what it is?
Yeah,
I have.
Um,
what I did was I came out with a
signature series,
a line of handguns.
Well,
the first one because it's not allowed
to California.
What's,
what's wrong with it?
Um,
y'all have a list of guns that you're
allowed to own it.
It's not on.
And then like you would have to.
There's this micro stamping that's
required for any gun that's not on the
list and it's so prohibitive.
Yeah,
it's weird.
So what is different,
what kind of guns are they?
What is the other?
Prohibited the one that you have that I
can have.
Oh,
I can have him pull it up.
Sorry if you want.
You mean that particular gun?
What's about it?
Like what is this Spec state?
Just it just.
It just is like it's just a list of
guns.
I don't really know exactly the caliber,
the semiautomatic capabilities because
there some automatic guns on the list
that you're allowed to own.
There are other.
It was just arbitrary.
That's what it seemed like to me.
What kind of gun is it,
Jamie?
He'll look it up.
If you want to pull it up.
A full up tiered of t y r e d e f e n s
e t or defense.com.
Here we go.
Dump,
dump,
dump.
Yeah.
There's some weird shit.
I mean we've got Jerry Brown's,
our fucking governor.
That goofball.
Let's see.
Firearms transfers,
work order,
phone gallery contact with tier one,
tier one.
It'd be t,
t y r e t y r a.
There we go.
Bam.
Tyree,
you haven't certainly today coming up
that people are paying attention to.
Usually it comes up when I'm typing this
stuff,
so this is why people can't shoot Benton
Lincoln mass shooting.
Going on pressure.
Actually,
no.
You see one where it says the advocate.
Yeah,
that's it.
Alright.
What's the name of the gun?
Is the advocate someone might've been no
service unavailable.
Oh,
the hackers.
They got to it already.
It's the fucking Russians,
Bro.
Cassie problems.
Go back and get a pass.
City problems.
I don't know if everyone we've already
killed it.
Killed it.
He kind of take a couple hundred people
at it by the,
by the time that it hits youtube though,
isn't it a blender to latest seconds.
Twenty seconds to type in,
type in the advocate and then calling on
the war and then see what that does.
And in like erase tier defense though.
Here we go.
Um,
click on the top 10.
We killed that website.
Go to images.
Killed that website.
That's the gun.
Okay.
And why?
That seems like a normal handgun.
It is.
So what the fuck is wrong with it?
Why can't I have it?
I know.
I want to ask the folks that make
leaders in California,
but what are they saying is wrong with
it?
Like specifically,
I don't know why they make the decisions
they make in California to be honest
with what.
What is the specs of this gun?
What it is a nine millimeter handgun,
semiautomatic.
Is it because it's semiautomatic or.
No?
No,
I don't think so.
no,
just I don't.
I don't think that's the basis.
Like I don't.
I don't know the,
the complete basis and reasons for why
certain guns are allowed.
Handgun wines of California and others.
I'm pretty sure they're going to be tons
of people who tell me this because I
have a huge audience in California.
I think it's actually my,
one of my biggest audience,
there's a lot of gun owners in
California.
People people aren't,
you know the idea that guns in
California or somehow or another rare
you want.
The funny thing is the birthplace of
they are 15,
wasn't California now?
Well that's a weird gun.
It's a gun that people just have
demonized.
It's not the most powerful gun.
It's not the scariest gun nut but
military.
But they don't even use it in the
They don't use it in the military.
But to be honest with you,
if they did,
I'd want that gun.
Why?
Because it's the most effective means to
protect myself,
right?
Like I don't.
I don't understand this idea of
neutering guns to the point where I'm
too new to and get to the point of
irrelevance or ineffectiveness.
It's people that don't use guns that
have this idea,
and this is.
This is where we're at now.
I think one of the things that I'm
getting out of this conversation with
you is that there's not really a clean
answer.
There's not a clean answer.
And if there was,
people would have figured it out.
It's almost like society has to continue
to evolve and one of the ways society
evolves is having these conversations.
You and I having this conversation where
a few million people are going to listen
to it and then millions of people on
their own having conversations and
people looking at the reality and that's
in that way.
I think what you're doing is important
and what a lot of people are doing is
important where they're talking about
the actual numbers and the actual
statistics and letting us get a look at
it,
and that's the one thing that I try to
convey with my videos.
I don't care where you stand on the
issue.
I just will have a shit ton of more
respect for your position if it's from a
position of education,
if you actually have some knowledge.
I'm not saying you have to be a Jedi.
Master firearms.
Just understand the very basics,
the fundamentals.
We have politicians pushing policy based
on things that make no sense like it.
It actually exposes the fact that they
don't know anything about firearms and
so it was like you're going to push
policy on something that you don't know
anything about and so it.
It's disingenuous and an inherently
dishonest,
so that's the biggest frustration I
have.
I might look it up.
I'm going to educate you and give you
the information that you need so that
you can make an informed opinion about
it.
If at the end of the day I take you
shooting,
I tell you the stats I tell you about
how guns functioned and how they work.
If you still are anti-gun,
I can respect that now.
That doesn't mean you get to then push
your anti gun agenda onto me and limit
my rights because of it,
but I can respect that.
At least we can walk away and say,
hey look,
well I think we probably got it from a
different perspective.
I appreciate that and I think we're also
faced with the reality of this.
The sheer number of guns that we have in
this country.
It's a staggering number,
so you're not going to just take those
away.
What are you going to put them?
And that's just now there's some people
were like,
well,
we can devolve the number over time,
right?
We can just put these laws and they can
get bad for a little bit,
but then overtime doing that weird
voice.
When you do wear all the time,
just anti gun,
would you be interested in sitting down
like maybe on this show if I had an
antique gun advocate?
I beg for it.
Okay.
Not,
not to say not,
not reasonable.
Here's the thing.
I'm not trying to get up here in and
crush this person and,
and all that stuff.
I've done that to death.
Right.
But I do want to have the conversation,
right.
You and I've done it on my show.
The only problem is,
is it's too easy to ignore it because of
the platform that you had someone on
your show that made reasonable points,
like if somebody wanted to watch you
with,
uh,
in some sort of a debate with an gun
person,
is there a show that you could recommend
that people would go watch right now?
That was on?
Yes.
On your show.
On my show.
A.
We'll see.
Here's the thing though.
So the,
one of the biggest flaws of the people
that were on my show that we had that
conversation with is you could instantly
see it was more of an education process
because you could tell they didn't know
much.
So what would happen is that they make a
point about why they believe this.
Then I would give them information and
then it'd be like,
oh,
okay,
okay.
You see what I'm saying?
I'm sure there's someone out there that
is educated and in kids anti-gun.
We'll,
we'll have someone find them.
Well,
I have this.
I have a publicist will have him love
Matt stags on.
Please let me know because I'd be all
for it.
Yeah,
I really would.
There's probably someone out there
that's reasonable that has good points
and has a well thought out sound
argument.
It would be interesting to listen to you
talk to that person.
Absolutely.
But I think one of the things we can
take away from this is that this is a,
it's a messy situation.
It's not clean.
It's not like,
hey,
we're putting poison in the water,
stopped putting poison in the water,
clean up the water.
It is not that simple.
It's not super complicated.
Uh,
deals with mental health.
It deals with freedom and it deals with
law abiding.
People aren't doing anything wrong where
people are trying to take away their
rights.
They're enthusiasts.
They love guns.
And I don't think there's any like,
look,
here's a perfect example.
You are sitting here with a gun on your
shirt.
What kind of gun is at ar?
15.
You have an ar 15.
Actually selfies I have.
I have an archery shirt on.
I could walk anywhere with this.
No one would feel threatened.
No,
I'll kill the fuck out of you.
Right?
But no one would feel threatened.
But if you walk around with that,
people will,
you know,
you are one of those gun guy.
Are you telling people you have that on
you?
Is that what you're saying?
You warning people.
You're a dangerous person,
you know?
Oh,
you're an archery enthusiasts.
so I did archery at camp.
When I was in the boy scouts,
we shot bows.
I'm going to start opening girls at the
bar with that.
Yeah,
I shoot archery.
A bad movie,
man.
It's not a bad move.
So listen,
I appreciate the conversation.
I don't think we got anywhere,
but I don't think you can.
I think we talked about it.
I mean,
to be honest with you,
it's a conversation that needs.
So here's what happens.
Things happen in our,
in our reality that forced a specific
focus on the part of the conversation.
Right?
And so,
um,
of course we weren't going to say,
I don't know how long we been here,
how long we've been.
Two hours,
two hours,
right?
We've been having this gun debate for
how long now in this country for years.
Um,
but I think for a lot of people,
especially the people who follow me,
they wanted me to come on your show,
not because you and I were going to come
to an answer,
but to educate,
right?
Well also to have what we have on the
show where I try to have on the show
just discussions,
just talk.
Exactly.
And let people talk.
Let people express themselves.
And I think you definitely did that
today.
You Express yourself,
you're very reasonable guy.
Anybody looks at you and says you're a
maniacal gun nut.
You pulling that out of your own head,
you know,
um,
but I would love to do that and we'll
try to find somebody will try to find
somebody if you're open to that.
Absolutely.
Trying to find somebody that could,
could argue the point,
but thank you brother.
Thanks for having.
Great pleasure.
All right folks.
We'll be back very shortly.
We have a second round two today with
Sam Harris and Majid Nawaz.
See you soon.
That was great.
That was fun.