Joe rogan podcast all day,
the Joe Rogan experience podcast all
day.
Hey everybody.
Let me introduce you to everybody here
because we've got a large group of
humans.
First of all,
we have my good friend Dr.
Mark Gordon.
He's been on the podcast before,
brilliant endocrinologist slash all
around.
Awesome dude and his friend and patient,
Matthew Gosney and Matthew and I'm right
here to my left.
We have Jason Halls,
a screenwriter for American sniper and
we're going to get into a lot of things
on this podcast,
but one of the big ones that we're going
to talk about is Dr Gordon,
if you've listened to the previous
podcast that he and I did have,
you haven't.
It's excellent.
Go back and check it out if you're
bored.
Um,
but you're an expert in traumatic brain
injury and you contacted me about
Matthew and you've,
you've done some amazing work on
soldiers coming back from,
uh,
from Iraq and Afghanistan and also
athletes with ptsd and the issues that
come out of ptsd.
Not just psychological but traumatic
brain injury,
which is something that we're dealing
with more with these series of wars.
And we ever had before,
because of the advancements in medical
science,
they're able to keep people alive that
may have died before and also they're
able to recognize what's going on,
what shell shock is this term that they
used after World War Two and know would
they.
They changed it a little bit in Vietnam
that they altered the name of it,
but essentially we're dealing with the
same issues.
We're dealing with the trauma to both
the mind and the consciousness that's
happening to people that experienced
horrible things,
see horrible things,
but also experienced damage to their
actual brain itself.
Absolutely.
The point of a foundation is the
distinction between what ptsd is versus
minimal or mild traumatic brain injury.
Unfortunately about 410,000
vets were coming back with what's being
late.
They're being labeled as traumatic as
ptsd when in fact they have a form of
traumatic brain injury.
The distinction between the two is a
psychological one which has ptsd and a
physical one which is traumatic brain.
Under the psychological.
You've witnessed,
you know,
horrible things out there in the
battlefield where you've seen your
friends being gutted or ied,
blowing them up in being left without
any limbs,
and then in the psychologic,
in the physical one,
you actually have the impact of the
explosion or a penetrating wound like a
shot to the head or being bludgeoned and
in football,
and it's believed that under the
psychological one with the ptsd,
that reliving the event that
precipitated is what causes you to
become depressed and anxious and so
forth.
Under the minimum or the mild traumatic
brain injury.
It's the physical trauma to the brain
that leads to deficiencies of hormones,
which is what my whole premise has been
for my treatment of traumatic brain
injury.
So what's being missed is there are guys
that go out there in the field who have
already had issues of traumatic brain
injury because they'd been fighting a
firing weapons which caused jolting
action or they've been jumping off out
of planes and hitting the ground at 10,
15,
20 miles an hour.
These types of impacts are significant
amount of to make a traumatic brain
injury and interrupt the way that the
brain controls our hormone balance in
our body,
and this is all fairly new,
this understanding of these things like
jumping out of planes or even playing
soccer and heading the ball.
Correct.
That's what we're finding in in
football,
you know by the time you get into the
national football league,
you've already gone through peewee pop
warner in high school,
junior high school and so forth and
college football,
and by the time you get to the major
games you've already have the entire
process of loss of functionality in the
brain and then you need just one more
hit,
one more,
not even loss of consciousness to create
the scenario of inflammation in the
brain that leads to hormone deficiency.
Yeah,
it's the.
The issue has always been thought of as
when you.
When it comes to brain damage,
you,
you always thought of people who have
been beaten up like boxers that have had
long careers or football players who
have had long careers and they just
stayed in too long,
but we're finding that a lot of athletes
like mark Henry's,
his name was no,
what was his name?
The young guy,
Chris Henry,
Chris at the young guy who fell off the
back of a truck,
did something really irrational.
His girlfriend was driving away,
jumped on the back of her truck,
fell off,
died,
hit his head,
but then when they examined his brain,
like this guy has a brain of a 70 year
old Alzheimer's patient.
Right,
and it's all just be.
And he was 26,
I believe,
26.
I'm a mid twenties and just a career of
playing in the NFL as well as well as
college football,
high school.
The whole deal that like you detailed
had left this guy with a significantly
damaged brain before he was even 30
years old and he was running around
functioning.
Nobody had suspected this.
He was behaving like a normal person.
Correct.
If you look at the suicides that have
been happening in football,
when they're between the ages of 25 and
35 that committing suicide,
looking at their brain,
you see that they're aging a lot more
faster than normal person,
and in fact a study that was performed
by the nfl showed that there was an 18
times faster occurrence of Alzheimer's
disease in people who have had traumatic
brain injury playing in nfl.
We've had boxers as patient.
Two Thousand and seven did a espn
outside the line with a two football
players in a boxer,
James,
Tony,
and we showed his hormone levels were
down low.
The laboratory read them all as being
low.
I didn't have to interpret it.
The lab did so that verified the fact
that they were really low and he had a
lot of difficulties with weight,
with control and so forth.
And as the host of the show said,
how can you be testosterone growth
hormone deficient and still be able to
do that kind of functioning.
You know,
the personality takes over.
it's just the way that the person
projects their life hormones help to
stabilize it,
to make it available,
and then you as an individual get to
decide what you do.
And he was in the ring fighting as
though there was nothing wrong,
but he had a lot of problems outside the
ring.
So what you're saying essentially is
that is just his,
his discipline and his will that kept
him fighting,
but he was significantly depleted.
Correct.
He was unbelievably depleted.
And then looking at a gentleman by the
name of Brad legged,
who was the mariners and the patriots,
his hormone levels were incredibly low
when he talks about how his,
I'll use rejuvenation occurred where he
improved in mental functioning,
physical functioning and physiological
functioning.
When he had his hormones returned to
normal and pat harlow was on the show
and they all talked about their
experience when from multiple head
traumas.
I think pat said he had double digit
head traumas and um,
you know,
if we go back and start doing some of
the new technology,
like a dtm awry,
which has an MRI that looks at the
connectivity of nerves.
Look at a pet scanner spect scan that
looks at the flow of blood through the
brain and you can find areas of deficit
because they've been damaged and you
can't get them back.
And Matthew,
how did you get in touch with Dr Gordon
and had this whole process start?
I'll start with your shell.
Actually,
when he was on here last time I was in
the hospital for a suicide attempt and
was an avid listener.
Was listening to that.
He was on here talking about it.
You know,
I was at my last.
I had no other options essentially.
And you're a veteran explaining.
Explain your history for the people
listening to this.
Sure.
On the navy seal medic.
I've been out since 2008.
I live up in Washington,
got out,
started having all kinds of issues,
just kind of down spiraled.
Went into the va finally and said,
this is going on.
Immediately they diagnosed me with PTSD,
handed me about 10 medications and then
we did follow ups checkups can what kind
of medications?
The SSRI antidepressants,
antianxiety meds.
I have chronic pain,
so they dosed me up on pain medications
to cotton things along those lines.
Fentanyl,
morphine,
oxycontin.
It was on all three at one point.
Jesus,
by the way,
how high did you get
the ground?
Totally feel bad for them or jealous did
he share?
Wow.
And so,
um,
I was just having a lot of issues.
I was really depressed.
I started gaining weight.
I couldn't get up out of bed.
I was married at the time,
really struggling all that.
Then my wife left me because of what was
going on and I just,
I mean,
I literally had no hope because it,
I was thinking that I can't be fixed
because they're giving me all these
things saying this is going to make you
better,
this is going to make you better.
And my mind wasn't getting any better.
So,
you know,
I decided it was better that I just
wasn't here.
And ended up in the hospital,
was there for a week.
My wife actually brought me,
um,
my ipod and all my stuff.
So I was able to listen because she knew
that I and listened to the show.
And he was on here,
it literally,
the day I got out,
I went on and I applied,
got a grant,
had all my lab work done,
got sent to him.
Uh,
he sent me all my results back and so we
figured out kind of what kind of
protocol I needed to do and then I flew
down here to talk to him and started,
uh,
the trt.
So what do you think,
I mean,
if you could,
do you have like a series of events that
you can recall that caused your injuries
or is it just a,
just the entire entirety of your career
in the military?
Well,
I was in two IED explosions to the face,
so I have six bolts in my jaw.
I took shrapnel to the side of my face.
I was shot in my leg.
I'm just from all the damage of doing
everything,
not related to any mission,
but I ended up having surgeries on my
shoulder,
arthritis and all my joints I have back
issues.
I mean,
so it just all kind of compounded into
one of damage.
And then just,
you know,
shooting on fours all day,
jumping out of things,
rolling around,
you know,
even just,
um,
you know,
just hand to hand combat when we're
practicing things you can get thrown on
the ground and,
you know,
over time it's just,
that's essentially what it was,
is just so much stuff happened over
time.
Then that just compounded.
And did you feel this coming on slowly
or was it very quickly?
Was it when you got home was when you
were over there?
Um,
that's a hard thing to answer because
for me it wasn't very noticeable other
than the fact that I just didn't feel
good mentally.
I wasn't there mentally.
You learn to shut things off,
you become desensitized to the world
around you.
It as a soldier,
it's a survival mechanism.
And so emotionally I was able to do
that,
to turn it off where everyone else
around me could see something was wrong.
I wasn't acknowledging it because to me
there wasn't anything wrong.
Um,
but,
you know,
I just thought the pain that I had,
that was just going to be the way it
was.
I was depressed with everything.
I thought,
hey,
that's just life.
Now I went and did this.
Now I have to deal with that,
and you have this stubborn mentality
because you put all these goals in front
of you and you've always accomplished
them,
so now here's something that they're
saying,
yeah,
you have this,
okay,
I can beat this too,
but as you're,
you keep going.
You're fine.
Hey,
I'm not doing.
I can't beat this.
What's going on here?
So then you look at yourself when you
go,
this is just me.
And does it get to a point where it
seems like life is
so painful and there's so much
negativity involved in your day to day
existence that it seems pointless and
you just want to shut it off and ended.
Is that like what's the mindset before
you decided to try to take your life?
That's exactly the mindset.
I mean,
for me the breaking point was I think
when my wife left because she didn't
leave because she didn't love me.
She left because she couldn't live with
me.
And if this person that I love and who
loves me back,
he can't live with me,
then what's the point in me being here
and if she's begging me to get better
and I'm going to counseling,
I'm going on all these medications,
they're switching my medications up
every three months because the fucking
not working and you're going,
okay,
I can't keep doing this.
I can't keep going on meds.
I can't keep being stoned out of my
mind,
I guess you could say with all the pain
meds and just.
I mean I didn't even feel like a human
being.
There was this fog.
I didn't have cognitive function.
I could barely read.
I'm an avid reader,
I mean 10 minutes,
15 minutes.
And I was like,
fuck this,
I can't do it.
It just,
even even sleeping and was like,
alright,
I guess I couldn't sleep.
Struggled with that.
So even sleep wasn't even giving me
comfort.
And so it was just,
you know,
there was no point to be here.
And were you in contact still with a lot
of the guys you served with and did they
have similar issues?
Some of them did,
some of them had different kinds of
issues.
Um,
I think there's a stigma that ptsd
causes us huge aggression.
That's,
you know,
anyone I discussed with a and I tell
them,
you know,
I have ptsd like,
oh,
are you gonna you're worried you're
going to fucking snap and kill
everybody.
And I think,
um,
that's not,
I don't know if that's as common as it's
been made out to be.
I think there's just been some huge
cases and it's come out,
but it definitely is an issue.
But for me that,
that wasn't the case.
Excuse me.
For me it was more just internalizing
everything and shutting off and just,
um,
uh,
but you know,
having the ability.
I was telling Dr Gordon this yesterday,
you know,
for like for my wife,
she didn't know what Matthew,
she was getting each morning and there
was the matthew who was loving could
listen or whatever,
you know,
the one she married or she was in get
the math,
you could rip your soul out and eat it
right in front of her.
And she didn't know.
And I was never,
I never hurt her,
but um,
there's definitely,
when you shut off emotions,
uh,
there's a fierceness to that and it's
scary,
you know,
she would tell me,
your,
your face scares me and I wouldn't hurt
her,
but there it's a protection thing for
me.
And you just,
um,
you just learn.
So a protection thing,
meaning,
like your aggression,
it was almost like to shut other people
out.
Yeah.
Well,
yeah,
there's multiple things to that.
One,
I didn't want to deal with it.
And two,
if I could shut them out,
then um,
then I didn't have to acknowledge that I
was interactions.
I just don't want to interact.
I don't want to talk to you.
I don't even want to look at you just go
away.
And because you could see the pain,
every time they look at you and it's
just a reminder,
it's that case of,
you know,
you can't,
can't get better until you acknowledge
it's wrong.
So you just don't acknowledge it in the
same bucket.
So you,
you hear about Dr Gordon on the podcast.
You hear about this,
the treatment for traumatic brain
injury,
and you hear about hormone replacement
and the damage to the pituitary gland
that happens during these impacts.
You,
you get together and you start hormone
replacement therapy.
And then what are the results?
Well,
it sounds like an infomercial does.
I mean,
it almost sounds almost sounds like a
miracle cure,
but at this point,
for me it was,
um,
within 10 days,
the biggest thing for me was my
cognitive function.
Within 10 days the fog was lifted.
I could think clearly I could do things
again.
Um,
and even physically within those first
10 days,
I was able to get out of bed,
less pain,
you know,
I could move.
Um,
and then within like six weeks I started
feeling like matthew started feeling
like me,
okay,
I can go to the gym today,
you know,
and I can go do this today.
I can read today,
I can interact today.
I mean,
it,
it's so hard to describe because you got
so used to how it felt that once it
starts changing,
you're like,
Whoa,
this is unreal.
This is happening.
So this,
I'm a different person,
my real,
I'm the real me,
but a different person than you know,
or had been the last couple of years and
so it's,
it's almost an adjustment because now
you've got to go back and try to just
heal all the damage that you did around
you.
Wow.
You know,
so just replacing your hormones had that
significant an effect on your wellbeing,
how you interacted with people.
She cope,
changed everything.
That's amazing.
So what,
what exactly did you.
Well,
what'd you put them on?
Tell me what,
what,
how did it start as a medical issue of
talk about that now he's given me the
green light.
He gave me the green light for it.
You know,
we ran through a 28 point hormonal
assessment and that 28 hormones
assessment looks at brain regulation of
the peripheral hormones,
you know,
in order to make testosterone signal
comes from the pituitary and tells your
testicles or a woman the ovaries to make
Gastrin,
stoss drone and then whatever.
And in looking at his pattern,
he had a very deep deficiency of the
regulatory mechanism for production of
testosterone.
But testosterone is only one of the
multitude of hormones that we focus on.
There's Dht,
dihydrotestosterone is Dah,
da Di dehydroepiandrosterone sulfate.
And what we're finding,
you said we think of hormones as gender
or sex hormones.
Well,
the sex aspect of it as baby 30 slash 40
percent.
The roots,
the remainder is on repair and
maintenance of our body.
One of the greatest things about
testosterone's,
anti inflammatory.
What happened to your joint pains in
your back?
Pains on testosterone.
So reduced by half of that first week.
That's incredible.
And this is in the literature,
you know,
I won't get too technical because I
won't understand it myself,
but the issue is that the testosterone
growth hormone like estrodial
progesterone all regulate inflammatory
chemistry in our body,
our immune system.
And we've also found in the past seven
to 10 years that the brain makes its own
hormones and its own hormones being
testosterone,
dihydrotestosterone,
estrogen and so forth in the brain.
And what they do is they regulate the
ability of the nerves.
And I just gave a lecture that we
called,
um,
the non permissive environment which
talks about when you have head trauma
neurotrauma,
where you've been hit or explosion and
so forth were areas of the brain shut
down in their ability to produce
hormones that regulate how you feel in
your ability to have cognitive
functioning.
So not only on testosterone replacement,
we use physiological dosing,
which is,
you know,
an average 25 to 35 year old male makes
about four to 10 milligrams a day.
So we'll use 60 milligrams a week or 80
milligrams a week,
which is about a fourth.
The amount that's used out there by
traditional physicians who are replacing
testosterone.
And he got phenomenal response without
any of the side effects.
So the hormone replacement includes I'm
anti inflammatory medication,
which are all natural things like Pqq,
which is a form of Co q 10 that stopped
the production of oxygen.
They call it reactive oxygen species,
which are oxidative chemistry oxidants.
And that leads to death of cells.
And there's an incredible amount of
literature that has been out for many,
many years.
And now it's getting more focused that
in order for us to heal the brain,
not only do we have to replace the
hormones,
but we also have to protect it from this
oxidative stress that the brain goes
through.
Sounds like,
you know,
one of those trendy kind of statements,
but it's actually factual and there's
just thousands of articles coming out
and how much we need glutathione or we
need vitamin C dot Pqq,
Co q 10,
all the things that take the free
radicals that are damaging the ability
of the brain to regenerate.
And uh,
in this lecture I just gave back in
1911,
there was a guy by the name of Italo who
proved that we can generate our nerve
cells or neurons.
And then 19,
28,
and then there's a guy in Canada who's
like the guru and the ability to
regenerate the brain,
but you have to have the right
environment.
That right environment involves,
you know,
hormones.
And also to help step up the system's
ability to fight the oxidative stress.
Why is this a sort it,
if not ignored?
Why is this not commonly known by a lot
of physicians or by a lot of people that
talk about different neurochemicals that
change behavior because we think of
dopamine and Serotonin.
Those are the two big ones,
right?
When you think of Serotonin reuptake
inhibitors,
when you think of antidepressants or
when you think of people depleting that
with drugs,
you're thinking of dopamine and
serotonin primarily.
Well,
very rarely does he do.
The other ones get brought up.
Well,
I think
unfortunately there's a financial
motivation to things.
Matthew is on probably about 40 or 50 a
month of medication.
One of the medications that he was on
was a couple hundred dollars a month and
when you're talking about,
I think you said 15 total medications
that when you add up the cost per month,
you're talking about thousands of
dollars a month,
so it was history and keeping these
people in medical industry as well.
As you know,
the analogy that I make is,
if you remember back in Legionella
Pneumophila in Philadelphia,
which was a lung infection,
they went and gave these people know
thousand dollars drugs and it turned out
that it was a fifty cent drug.
Erythromycin that treated it.
We're looking for things that are so
brand new that we've ignored the very
basic fundamentals.
My martial arts instructor always said
back to basics,
back to basics.
Thank you young you.
So,
so Jason Hall,
uh,
you're a screenwriter,
you,
you wrote American sniper,
which has been directed by Clint
Eastwood,
which is a,
uh,
when is that coming out?
It comes out at Christmas and it's about
Chris Kyle,
a famous story of the book,
American sniper,
of course,
best selling book and a tragedy where he
was killed while he was working with
Ptsd sufferers and he was working with
someone on the range who was suffering
and he wound up getting killed by them.
How did you get involved in all this?
I'll say first that you know,
that's a,
that's a pending trial.
So we don't know if that guy had ptsd or
you just had a screw loose or what it
was.
He got approached by a woman who is
working to get that sucker right up to
your mouth.
Woman who was working in the parking lot
at his kid's school said,
you know,
my,
my kid is suffering and read your book,
you serve.
Can you help him out?
And that's about all he got.
And uh,
he'd been helping out a lot of vets and
uh,
you know,
this guy had it informed and uh,
it was,
it was a tragic story.
I met Chris,
uh,
in 2010.
He got out in 2009 and I'd heard his
story and I went down to Texas to meet
him.
And,
uh,
I'd never been to Texas before either
and had,
hadn't met many navy seal snipers.
Welcome to America to access and navy
seals altogether.
I showed up and it's like 60 cops,
60 Texas cops,
like half of all the Texas Rangers were
in the room and uh,
and I don't drink.
So I wasn't real popular at first.
The only way I could ingratiate myself
to them was one of them was picking on
me and call me Hollywood liberal and
this and that and panty waist and,
and uh,
so I throw them in a front headlock and
I had jacked him up a little bit and
then Chris finally started talking to
me.
It was like a choke him out a little
bit.
Yeah.
How did you get
involved in this?
You,
you read the story?
I heard this story.
Yeah.
I heard the story of this guy had shot,
you know,
you've got more confirmed kills in
anyone US military history.
And uh,
I called a buddy of mine who was
serving.
He had a,
he had been seal team six.
He was working down at the CIA at the
farm and I said,
hey,
this guy,
this guys killed,
got more confirmed kills than anybody.
And he hit a shot from 2100 yards,
confirmed,
kill at 2100 yards.
He's like,
I got news for you buddy.
Your guy's full of shit.
You're full of shit.
They're five guys on the planet who can
hit that shot in your boys.
Not One of them.
I was like,
all right,
well look it up.
So he calls back and he's like,
so uh,
Chris,
cause one of the five.
Wow.
Yeah.
There's a vortex optics.
Some,
a friend of mine that are provided me
with scopes and stuff for hunting.
They,
they actually got a call from someone in
Afghanistan that was about to shoot
somebody and they needed to know how to
adjust their scope correctly.
So they were talking over a sat phone
with the guys at vortex and giving them
the exact adjustments to make some
fucking thousand yard shot.
Yeah,
thanks.
Take care.
It's great when you get to like real
long distance,
like a thousand yards plus,
I mean a lot of it is just calculations
and mathematics and understanding scopes
and how much the bullet's gonna drop.
Yeah.
And I think some of it is,
some of it is instinct and I think some
of it is,
you know,
he said God kissed the bullet.
Yeah.
Jesus Christ.
Amen.
God's mean fuck or not either way kissed
it or he blew on it.
Whatever happened,
it worked.
Um,
so you get involved with these guys.
You start in just becoming immersed in
the world of the soldiers and their
issues.
And how did you get connected to Matthew
and to Dr Gordon?
Well,
when I met Chris,
you know,
I walked in,
I met him,
I looked him in the eye and I was like,
Oh shit,
you know,
this guy's not home yet.
Like you could see it in his eyes.
There was something going on and it
felt,
it felt like there was turmoil there.
It felt like he was still fighting and I
called my wife and I was,
I was like,
I don't know what I'm doing here.
I don't know what's going to go on with
this guy.
I don't know,
you know,
how he's going to work it out.
But he's,
he's got some stuff to work out and
it's,
you know,
it was hard to look at.
It was hard to look into his eyes.
And uh,
thankfully his wife and his kid showed
up the next day and I saw it change.
I saw for a minute the fog kind of
lifted and I saw him light up,
his kids ran into his arms and,
and I saw like,
here's what this guy was like before the
war,
you know,
this is the man who,
who was there before the war and,
and here's maybe the man that he could
become again.
Wow.
How many of these guys are just tough
and they just deal with this new
reality.
I mean,
it seems like that is a big part of
what's going on when you're saying the
guy wasn't back yet,
but yet he was physically and he was
going through emotions and living his
life.
But all the shit that probably was going
on in his brain and certainly going on
in his psyche,
I think most come back that way.
I think that's their first mentality is
like,
for me,
you don't,
you're not going to admit that
I've beaten things worse than this.
I'm going to keep going.
Especially seals,
right?
Yeah.
Just to get through buds,
just to get through any of it.
That's what I said.
But any,
any challenge has been in front of me.
It seems like I've completed it.
And so this,
that's all it was.
And once I finally realized that I
couldn't how broken,
because then I,
then I really felt broken because it's
never happened.
There's no light at the end of the
tunnel.
I just all dark.
It goes dark to the end of time.
Yeah.
I mean the best parts about me were gone
and had Chris Kyle,
if he received any treatment for ptsd
other than the standard dose of
painkillers and Ssrs and what have you.
No,
you know,
I think Chris,
I think Chris dealt with it,
doing some drinking and then he finally
kind of worked his way through it.
Got a little,
you know,
got back into church and,
and started actually helping these guys
helping other veterans and he found
peace in that he found peace and helping
other guys.
And you know,
I can't speak to,
to what he felt when he laid his head
down on the pillow at night.
But,
uh,
he found some real solace in,
in helping these vats and they'd,
you know,
they'd bring them up and they'd go out
shooting at the range or go hunting and
uh,
you know,
and end up talking around the bed of a
pickup truck for four hours with a
couple of beers in and then you,
you get a little bit of this comradery
and,
and they don't feel so alone.
We had a purpose.
Again,
you have a purpose while you're in,
you have a job
now and it's gone.
It's ripped from you and there's not,
you know,
there's no clear goal or mission in
front of you anymore.
So you kind of searched for that.
Like for me,
I kind of was trying to figure out what,
you know,
what the fuck am I going to do with
myself now?
What mission can I accomplish?
And it's not there anymore.
There's no people,
you know,
there's the structure of things are
gone,
the command is gone.
It's just you.
And I think if it hadn't been for my
wife,
I've never even would have gone in to
the va honestly because there's,
there's just happened to be someone that
lived with me the whole time who's like,
you need to go in or I'm gone.
And I mean if she hadn't been there,
I'd probably still be that way.
Now.
Honestly,
the UFC has done a lot of work for a
traumatic brain injury and uh,
in,
in helping to fund the Intrepid Center
for traumatic brain injury.
And one of the most shocking things to
me when we got involved,
we started doing these fights with the
troops,
was that there was no funding for this,
that they had to get funding from other
sources that they had to get funding
from donations and they had to ask
people to call in and donate.
And just unbelievably shocking to me
that we spend so much money to send
these guys over there.
So much money for weapons and so much
money for the latest high tech ways to
kill people.
And so little on how to treat
these guys when they come back.
And girls.
I mean it's,
it's an issue,
so little money and also so little
imagination and so little willingness
to,
to explore new things.
We're talking about a fucking blood
test.
Yeah.
He's talking about a blood test to test
their hormones and it's like,
oh,
what a crazy idea.
This guy's out of the box.
He's crackers,
you know,
and it's,
it's.
You look at the,
you look at,
at the symptoms,
they're having the same symptoms the
guys in the nfl are having.
It's the same symptoms that guys would.
Low Testosterone or habit and it's not a
huge mystery,
you know,
but it is a mystery to all these people
and you know,
we're also talking about Kris Carr who
was the Achilles of Iraq and like that
guy was having a hard time.
That guy had to go through the same
thing and go talk to somebody.
You know,
there's a lot of guys out there who
served and got no thanks for it.
They've got no recognition.
They got.
They were anonymous soldiers in a,
in a war that nobody wanted and they
came home and they were messed up.
Most,
most of them.
Most are like that,
you know,
and,
and look,
I'm sure there's guys who came home and
they were okay.
Like I,
I haven't met a ton of those guys.
I've,
some of the seals are like that.
They're fun,
you know,
God bless.
But I spent the last year after writing
sniper,
I'm adapting a book called thank you for
your service and this guy followed these
guys home.
He followed a battalion of army guys
home from,
uh,
from Iraq and followed their wanderings
into like how they were going to get
back into their lives and how they,
these guys were going to deal with their
stress and dealing with the Va.
And it was a nightmare man.
And you meet these guys that just,
they don't have any hope.
They don't have any hope.
And you know,
some of them have,
have,
have the ptsd and some of them have
additional injuries like matthew had and
they've got nothing.
They've got nothing in the va is like,
you know,
you're talking 22 soldiers a day kill
themselves for soldiers who have killed
themselves and have died.
And they'll correct which is the first
time in any war in us history.
Well,
the thing we keep,
we keep records of it now there's a
website which is called prevention and
awareness,
suicide prevention awareness,
which is a military site which keeps
track of all the suicides and also
things to prevent it.
And they keep records of the dod in the
22 a day I think is,
uh,
is not an accurate number.
and there was another report that came
out where it's like 40 today where it's
even more,
but you're right in 2012,
when they started really releasing the
numbers,
there were more people killed,
more people committed suicide.
Then people were killed in A year of
fighting in 2000 unfucking.
Believable from a patient standpoint
going into the va.
I liked the va and they've been nothing
but very kind to me and very good to me.
So I don't have anything in that regard
to say.
But when you go in there and you get
diagnosed with ptsd,
they you
one of the meds and to with all these
appointments to talk to people who want,
you're not gonna fucking relate to,
I'm sorry,
but ms dot susie over there,
hasn't seen what I've seen or done what
I've done and she's trying to engage me
in this conversation and all I want to
do a slim face on the floor because
she's trying to act as if she's my
friend and knows what I'm talking about
and she doesn't.
And I know she only has goodwill,
but as a patient sitting there and this
is supposed to help you and it's not
helping you like this is fucking stupid.
And that's what happens.
Most people go to like one or two
sessions and never go to counseling
again.
You cannot fix the mind when the body is
not working.
When it's physiologically not working
correctly,
the mind will never get better.
So that's essentially what's happening
is they're trying to fix these ma,
the mind and these mental issues without
fixing the physiological aspect of it.
And then wondering why none of these
people are getting better.
Okay,
well,
why are none of these medications
working?
How many more medications can we give
you,
you know,
before you end up in a situation like
mine.
And that's what's happening.
And it's that part of it is ridiculous.
And that part of it angers me because it
is such an easy fix.
It's such a,
it seems like an easy fix,
you know,
as a patient that was effective fix in
effect the fix.
But it's that,
um,
you know,
I remember when I first was going in
there for my chronic pain,
you know,
they started me off with like aspirin,
tylenol.
They went through this progression to
where they were.
And I remember my doctor look at me
saying,
I know what you need,
but I have to do it this way.
So not only did I waste another six
months to a year going on these
ineffective because I did need something
for my pain,
probably not what they gave me,
but that's just another,
you know,
um,
example of sometimes I think they know
that it's not working,
but they're in this bureaucracy where
they have to just,
that's,
you know,
it's a federal institution.
They have to do this.
That's what they have to have,
sort of a chain of prescriptions.
There's,
this just didn't work.
We tried that and documentation of it.
Is that what it is?
Well,
yeah,
I mean it's,
it's a rainbow of medications that
everyone starts off on it seems like.
And that's what everyone's getting when
they go in there and then they're
wondering while none of them are effect,
you know,
some of them are effective,
but as a whole they're not.
And so you go in there.
I mean,
I was going in,
you know,
I would go in after 30 days,
it's,
I really do anything.
All right,
let's try it another two months.
Okay,
here's three months.
Well,
let's either up your dose or let's just
throw that shit in the garbage and give
you something else.
So noT only are you taking something,
my body's been on for three months now
and then just introducing it to
something else.
you know,
that I was like,
I was becoming worse.
I was just becoming more just not when
the frustration,
frustration you need by the end of that
you need a stronger medication just to
deal with all the appointments you've
been to.
Oh yeah.
It's ridiculous.
I mean,
I,
I did stop going to all my mental
counseling sessions because I knew that
wasn't,
was,
wasn't what was going to help me.
I didn't need,
especially not talking to them,
you know,
maybe maybe a friend or something,
but a lot of that stuff that happens
over there,
I don't want to talk about it at all.
It's very sacred.
It's very personal and intimate and to
me it's not a game.
Most of the people around you talk to
you and it's a fucking video game.
It's cAlled a duty and they sit there
and they talk,
you know,
they talk and he was at that like that
and you're like,
listen,
this is not okay,
so you just don't say anything.
Not only that,
I'm not going to tell my wife because
she doesn't need to know any of this
horror stuff that I went through.
So you just internalize it.
You internalize it,
you're buddies.
You almost don't want to talk about it
because you know either you're still
buddies or just anyone else she knew in
the military because then you're
bringing it up to the surface again so
it just becomes this thing where you
take the deepest aspect of your soul and
you just shut the fuck in there and then
you pray and walk away and that is part
of the problem and it's a mental issue.
It's that mental issue of like,
I think it progresses down this,
this slope downhill because when your
body just starts smell functioning,
all this stuff that you're trying to
deal with mentally goes with it.
It just all goes down and then you then
you can't start handling just the daily
things of life around you can't handle,
oh,
they got my coffee wrong.
All right,
well now I'm fucking pissed and let's go
break a ton of shit.
You know,
just simple things like that,
that everyday it's like,
no,
it's not a big issue,
you know,
but you can't handle the little things
around you and you don't have a buffer.
Yeah,
there's no buffer.
There's no nothing.
I mean,
and you find things to do.
I tried to find all kinds of hobbies to
do and they work for a week,
but then you're just,
you realize you're right where you were
and you just keep moving on and it just
never gets better.
And that's the thing that was so
frustrating about it.
It's also got to be frustrating for you,
Dr.
Gordon,
to know that there's sort of an
ignorance involved in just treating the
mind or just treating the symptoms of
antidepressants with these kinds of
medications when you're dealing with so
many different things holistically.
The entire body has so many issues that
aren't being addressed and they just
addressing this one thing because this
is all these doctors know,
correct.
It's really an a masking process that
they're doing.
The patient has complaints of isolation,
which matthew had isolation,
withdrawal,
and hedonism.
He weren't enjoying doing the things you
were enjoying before.
And that's classical depression.
So we'll put them on an antidepressant.
Uh,
you're having difficulty sleeping and
put them on tresona and put them on
whatever medication in the frustration
is.
The literature is so clear.
I mean,
I didn't invent anything.
I just sit in front of the computer for
eight,
nine hours a day and read the literature
that's coming out from all over the
planet and they're so compelling that I
put it into clinical application,
uh,
with not only the veterans but with the
civilians who have had traumatic brain
injury from motor vehicle accidents,
slip and fall,
what have you,
and the responses across the board.
Once you find the laboratory proven
deficiencies or insufficiencies and you
replace it,
you get these incredible responses.
A woman 32 years ago who had an motor
vehicle accident head on we're neck,
hit the steering wheel and crushed her
karate and she had a stroke on the
opposite side,
32 years of being on a multitude of
medications and then she comes in and
within a month she's feeling better.
They had her on adderall to counteract
the side effects of the five
psychotropic drugs like the ssri is and
whatever and whatever,
and I'm at one month goes back to her
psychiatrist in the south and she says
to the doc,
a female doc,
she says,
I'd like to get off these medications.
The doc says,
honey,
I put people on antidepressants.
I adam,
take them off,
and that's the mentality that we have to
start educating that there are all our
alternatives,
but they're being told the quick fix is
to put them on an antidepressant.
Listening to matthew story,
in 10 days,
the clouds started to lift.
The fog started to dissipate and by six
weeks he was coming back to who matthew
remembered himself being.
That's the place.
Then that's the place where he can deal
with the other stuff that has been
suppressing.
Yes,
correct.
Exact.
Because these are.
These things are not independent of each
other.
You know,
in the past I started in 2004.
I had four head traumas and when I was
between 34 and 46,
I think I shared this with you once
before.
Between 34 and 46 I started developing
depression was depression was on paxil
just wasn't a happy camper.
What will your head traumas from,
let's say at four years of age,
playing jungle gym in New York during
the winter,
hit my head on the metal bars,
landed up in the ground at,
believe it or not,
I was sitting,
dare you shut that off,
shoot it.
And then when I was riding my bicycle to
a hebrew school at between twelVe and
13,
I was hit by a car and knocked down or
cut my face,
cut my chin.
let's see.
At 18 years of age on the swim team,
I was screwing around and hit my head on
the swimming poured.
And then in the February 9th,
February 9th,
19,
71 sylmar earthquake,
before you were born,
a shelf,
a large shelf fell on my head and
knocked me out.
So I was,
you know,
went through undergraduate medical
school,
residency.
Everything was fine,
but between 34 and 46 started developing
all these symptoms and then I went to a
facility and I had my hormones checked
and I was thyroid,
which you saw me take earlier,
thyroid,
testosterone growth hormone deficient
and uh,
started on it.
And within a period,
let's see,
august to November 3rd,
I woke up totally different person,
similar to what matthew was stating.
And not until that was 99,
not until 2004 when I read an article
out of Turkey,
Turkey,
they have a lot of pugilist.
I like boxing.
And there was this one article that said
that boxers in Turkey were found to have
unusually high amounts of growth hormone
deficiency.
And the following year,
muay thai in Thailand came out.
And then that was my epiphany.
I went back to the literature and
started finding one,
two,
five,
10 articles talking about head trauma
associated with hormone deficiency and
from 2014 to present,
that's all I read is these relationships
and we know in gerontology and geriatric
medicine,
internal medicine that as mail gets to
be in sixties and seventies that you see
them go through a process that they
called dysthymia,
which is a mild kind of a blue,
you know,
feeling blue depression and they have
significant testosterone deficiency.
When you replaced it,
they get better.
so why can't we see that things that
accelerate your last head trauma leading
to testosterone deficiency causing
depression,
that looking at the older generation who
have,
or the older age individuals who have
hormone deficiency,
both males and females that they
developed depression.
Why can't you link the two?
And that's where the problem's been in
linking the two issues.
Hormone deficiency for whatever cause
can predispose you to,
uh,
issues of,
you know,
uh,
psychological problems and psychological
problems like depression is the number
one is fatigued.
Did you have fatigue,
fatigue,
fatigue with out being able to sleep,
correct.
Fatigue,
insomnia,
depression,
rage,
just for no reason.
You just start being angry and rage,
screaming at people.
Patients has gone,
a libido,
sexual drive is gone.
You start doubting yourself.
A sense of wellbeing is gone.
A plum has gone confidence and
assertiveness has gone and that's this
issue of what they call co-morbidity.
When you're arguing the fact of it being
ptsd,
psychological versus a physiological
cause for that psychological,
I think the head trauma creates the
scenario biochemically to allow you to
have sensitivity to these things that
are called cycle effect of disease or
cycle neurotic diseases or whatever
they're using today.
So it predisposes it so it mAkes you
susceptible to the correct or the bad
thoughts.
Correct.
What's the difference between,
you know,
you were talking when you were talking
to jason,
that when you saw,
when chris saw his kids,
his personality changed.
That was the stimulus that was something
that,
you know,
put them on a peak.
Same thing with hormone correction.
It can correct those thoughts and we're
finding something called neuro steroids,
which are the minor hormones that run
through our body that are lost during
inflammatory processes throughout the
body can affect the brain that stabilize
our ability to not be schizophrenia.
Our ability not to be depressed,
our cognitive ability so that the long
neurons that conduct information over
long period of time to ingrain our raw
memories and so forth are stabilized.
And if you lose that stabilization,
it's like pulling the plug.
You lose that ability to control it or
you know,
turning the sound all the way down.
So by correcting the hormones,
that allows for the sound to come back
up to where it should be so that you can
function at the level that I'm matthew
is.
We have a lot of people that have had a
multitude of injuries.
Um,
what happened was because of a
laboratory access medical lab in
Florida,
they gave me a grant.
And what happens that they gave me a
chunk of money and I matched it out of
my pocket of my practice to provide the
type of services that matthew in a large
group of other vets from the green
berets from the navy.
Unshipped navy.
It's same navy,
right?
Yeah.
The st louis side,
the blue side.
Right.
And,
um,
in fact,
matthew matthew was the last one to get
in on this program and because we ran
out of funds and,
uh,
we did a radio show a couple of weeks
ago and one of my patients calls and
offers US the money to get the system
back up and running.
And last week when I was lecturing in
vegas,
I'm approached by someone who had put in
a grant with deal with the dod,
uh,
doctors and get a patty and dr dash at a
university test of Texas who are now
helping me to apply for a dod grant so
that I can continue doing the work that
we've been doing.
I'm still taking money out of my pocket.
And uh,
the lab is still providing us With the
funds so that we can have a trickle of
people,
but before we get 10 people at a time
and they've all gotten better,
just not a lot of people that are
talking about this though in the sense
that the way you're talking about it,
like did you see the hbo real sports
piece on traumatic brain injury in
football players?
No.
Well you're,
you're seizing all these pieces on these
guys that have all these issues,
but what you eat,
well they know what they're saying
essentially is we have to be careful
with the amount of damage these guys
take and football and there's gotta be
some sort of methods in place to
mitigate this or at least to monitor,
like put sensors on the helmets,
but they're not talking about hormones.
They're not talking about an another
avenue of treatment that is based upon
doing the right testing to see what the
problem is.
They're not doing the testing to find
the hormone deficiency.
Defining,
finding brain damage.
They're finding you're going to find
dte,
the encephalopathy from trauma.
You're going to find that.
And what the literature is I referred to
earlier is showing us that we can
regenerate neurons.
It's been done,
we can heal the brain.
And the piece that came out in life
extension magazine a couple years ago,
you know,
they interviewed me for this thing about
healing the brain with hormones is
happening and healing the brain,
regenerate neurons.
Like how has that done and what's the
process involved?
Well,
it was my three hour lecture,
so I'll make it as short as I can,
having head trauma.
It initiates a group of inflammation,
inflammatory cascades in the brain that
have,
that changed the chemistry of the brain
so that the natural ability of the brain
to regenerate nerves is lost.
we're finding that thyroid hormone,
specifically thyroid three trial to
directing,
is extremely important to help stem
cells in the brain,
which they just found,
you know,
recently in the past 10 years that we
have stem cells left in the brain that
could regenerate the brain.
so when you're thyroid deficient,
what happens is the cells lose their
ability to stimulate growth factors for
nerve regeneration.
And so having all the hormones back,
removing the trump,
the inflammatory processes in the brain
can foster a neuro permissive
environment with the nerves will grow
and the sciences there,
they showing the things that stop the
things that stimulated and in head
trauma,
the not have been testing it because the
difficulty is in order to know what's
going on in the brain,
you have to take a brain biopsy.
They'd been trying to get a markers.
s 100 is one of the markets they're
working with right now.
That just tells you that it's happened.
You know,
we're doing so phenomenal at diagnosing
that you have traumatic brain injury and
seeing it on one of the neuro
radiological techniques,
but they're failing in treatment.
What about the connective tissue between
the brain and the skull itself?
I mean,
isn't that an issue with boxers and
fighters that have had repeated trauma
to see the connective tissue gets
damaged?
What happens is subdural hematoma,
which is a bleed between the pia mater
in the brain.
And then there's intra,
um,
cerebral bleeding that occurs.
And what happens,
the cause for loss of consciousness is
because you've torn,
you've shared is what they call an
shearing or too few secs o'neil trauma.
You've broken the long nerves that
connect everything to keep you
stimulated to be awake and through this
process called an mri or a dtm mri,
you can actually see a where nerves have
broken and when you break them,
that's when you lose consciousness.
And so we can detect it.
We can not regenerate those directly,
but we can build secondary pathways and
that's what they're finding.
There's a chemical called nogo a and o,
g o a,
which actually inhibits the ability of
nerves to regenerate.
And it's by controlling the environment,
you know,
using ivy gludethyon,
using some of the products that we have
that can allow the brain to have an a
environment and environment where it can
regenerate.
So the,
the,
the trauma to the brain itself,
the nerves that get damaged will never
be replaced.
But the secondary pathways that are
created to in response to that damage,
can they put someone back to the same
state that they were at?
Will they always be diminished?
Like say you're talking about a guy like
you know,
an unnamed mma champion who at the end
of his career starts getting knocked out
a bunch of times and we see that with
guys who used to be able to take
tremendous punches and now all of a
sudden they get hit and they just go.
Is that because of all those nerve
breaks that have happened over the
course of their career and the secondary
pathways just simply inadequate or is
there another response going on where
the mind is protecting itself?
This is what I've heard described to me.
They're shutting off quicker because the
mind has recognized this pattern,
oh,
we're receiving trauma.
The best way to do to mitigate this is
just shut off.
Well,
that's a simplified version of it.
I'm not to make it too deep,
but their tolerance has changed.
We're in the past,
they have a regenerative capacity or
they have endogenous system inside that
can help to keep things in balance.
When you've lost the ability of this
automated system to control things,
you pass out whether or not it's the
vascular.
You're more sensitive.
Vascular,
so on the head trauma,
the blood shunts from one area to
another,
so you lose the blood that keeps you
awake and you pass out.
Um,
neurologicAlly,
yes,
they could be breaking more nerves and
therefore I'm losing it more readily.
It's about resilience tolerance and how
much of that you've lost.
So you no longer have $100,000
in your bank account.
You got a penny.
So when you buy that piece of gum that
you can't buy you your empty.
So any shot,
I mean that's what we just shot a shot
to the head.
They just start going and that doesn't
get fixed.
correct.
Can't answer whether it gets fixed or
not because it depends on the individual
individual looking at their hormonal.
May lou looking at anything else that's
a cold morbidity,
things that are predisposing them to
have a more sensitive response to it.
Uh,
you know,
certain drugs,
alcohol,
I mean a lot of the drugs that we use,
there is one drug that's used a lot,
I won't say the name,
but deals with cholesterol that doesn't
allow cells to regenerate.
Also wax your vitamin d and your co q 10
when something like that.
I can't say the name because I want to
get sued.
Doesn't want the fucking evil army
comIng after them.
Well,
there are articles showing that to know
that the cells
breakdown more readily and there's a
process for processes in the brain which
regulate a nerves staying strong and
then being destroyed by.
So anyone who's on those kinds of drugs,
like anti cholesterol drugs,
they're risking a lot of damage to their
body.
There are multitude of levels you shut
off because I have a friend who's on it.
Well,
anthony bourdain's on it.
Uh,
you know,
and he's,
he's on it because he won't stop eating
pork.
Is it kosher?
No,
I don't believe he's jewish.
He may be the port kosher.
Obviously he isn't,
it doesn't.
Dad's french,
right?
It could be jewish.
I don't,
I don't think he was a.
Well he's not religious,
but he,
the Libya.
So it doesn't matter.
Yeah.
But my point is he's,
he's taking this just because he doesn't
want to do anything to reduce his
cholesterol because he,
because he enjoys fatty.
Awesome food and enjoy it,
but that shit is not good.
Right?
Well,
so if cocuten vitamin d in one of the
chapters of the new book where I talk
about,
um,
treatment for hormonal,
the first case that I presented as a guy
who came in to me who was on one of
those cholesterol lowering drugs and
his,
all his hormones were down because
cholesterol is the precursor to all our
hormones are androgens and estrogens.
So cortisol,
cortisol,
pregnenolone,
testosterone,
estrone,
island,
dht and dah da.
And they were all reduced.
all we did is stopped.
Is staten drug and it all came up.
I didn't have to do anything.
And what do you do to reduce cholesterol
other than diet?
Like for a guy like that?
well,
opens up nice,
warm the box of worms.
The question is,
is cholesterol really the issue?
When you look at the statistics,
50 percent of all heart attacks happen
in people with low or normal levels of
cholesterol.
So the question that any intelligent
person has to ask,
excluding myself,
is that I'm than what's causing it?
How did these people get heart attacks?
if the cholesterol is normal or low,
why don't die of a heart attack with my
cholesterol between 75 and 3:49,
and my ultrafast ct scan that looked at
my coronary arteries were perfectly
clear.
how is it that when my best buddies,
who's a fighter pilot,
uh,
has a cholesterol 1:40
to 1:50
and he ended up having open heart
surgery because his cholesterol is
calcium count was greater than 2000.
Mine was zero.
His was greater than 2000,
less than 100.
Great.
Greater than 400 dangerous.
He was greater than 2000.
He had 95 percent occlusion of the main
artery.
The left anterior descending ends up
having open heart surgery and you know,
hard to re replaced from his leg.
How do you account for it?
Well,
we went back and we did a series of
tests which were gifted by this
laboratory.
I work within Florida,
which called the [inaudible] that looks
at the inflammatory markers,
inflammation markers that lead to heart
disease.
So something called pla.
See small density,
ldl,
homocysteine,
c reactive protein.
There's a whole group of chemistry that
causes inflammation to lead to the
hardening of the arteries in the body,
responds by putting calcium down.
That's the atherosclerotic lesions to
try and work like a bandaid.
And,
um,
what spinoff that you've heard of
culation therapy?
Well,
culation therapy for many years has been
pooh poohed by medical community.
In three years ago,
the federal government did a study and
what did they say?
Culation therapy works.
What is culation therapy relationship is
a two levels of it.
One is to remove all the toxins from the
body.
Our focus was to try and remove the
castle calcium deposition of in the
arteries and use calcium edta,
sodium edta,
festival title coleen chemicals that
remove it.
There's a,
a,
another product which is called k one,
two,
three,
and seven,
which helped to remove calcium
deposition from the lining of the
arteries.
So if you can remove the calcification,
you improve the atherosclerotic lesions
that narrowed the blood vessels and lead
spasming and inflammation that calls and
cholesterol.
Cholesterol is has two major functions.
One is to supply the cells with the
precursor to all our hormones except
growth hormone and so forth and thyroid
and all the sex hormones,
and also to repair the wall of the
arteries and studies that were done
where they took a whole bunch of stuff
like trans fatty acids,
nicotine,
sugar,
uric acid,
cholesterol,
c,
reactive protein,
testosterone,
estrogen.
They put it in cultures of the lining of
the arteries called endothelia.
The only one that didn't cause
inflammation was cholesterol.
Wow.
And then a lot of articles you know that
talk about this,
the myth of a cholesterol myth,
and that's what I see.
Otherwise I have hardening of the
arteries,
but my genetics on this panel that we do
an lp six,
all my inflammatory markers are low.
My cholesterol is high in keith.
His inflammatory markers are high,
but with low cholesterol.
And so is this just a legacy?
Diagnosis is just something that we've
said for so many years.
The cholesterol causes heart attacks and
it just imprinted in our brains.
I do remember when people say sodium
causes high blood pressure,
but if you have no fucking salts,
a mineral,
goddammit,
it's an important part of your body like
you.
You need salt,
you need certain amount of it.
Correct,
and I think they're making generic
statements where they're selective.
It should be selective in certain
people.
Sodium might be bad in certain people.
Cholesterol might might be bad.
I don't see it
wasn't that sodium.
The whole diagnosis of sodium causing
all these health problems.
Wasn't that like inherently flawed in
the first place?
Yes.
What was that?
Did you remember what it was
specifically,
but they were saying that overload of
salt in certain racial groups.
Can I say that?
Yes.
You don't say the blacks.
Okay,
fine.
Then I won't say that.
I'll say in certain racial groups
they've always been known to be more
susceptible to a kidney related issues
and fluid retention on sodium,
so it predisposes them to enlargement of
the heart,
congestive heart failure,
fluid retention in high blood pressure.
So in treating certain racial groups,
use diuretics that make you go pee to
lose the fluid and the blood and other
groups use beta blockers to relax the
contraction of the heart,
other ones to stretched the blood
vessels and so forth.
So every,
um,
genetic predisposition has a specific
kind of medication that works best.
So you can't ubiquitously say,
okay,
everybody needs a stat and drug.
Everybody needs water pill,
everybody needs a beta blocker.
You have to be very selective and this
is what's being lost as matthew
experience in his experience.
You walk in wiTh any of his symptoms and
everybody gets on a prepaid prepaid
package of medication instead of
individualizing what he needs.
He just needed a blood test,
a $179 blood test to look at just his
testosterone related issues and find out
he was deficient and replace
it.
Any.
Are you still on your medication?
Any medication?
Nope.
You're on off everything you go through
withdrawal will that morphine and uh,
I'm sure it's been awhile,
but I know I still take oxycodone and
they come down to um,
between two and three pills a day.
So it's five,
three,
25.
How many were you on at the peak?
Eight a day.
A day to day.
And that's with morphie?
Um,
I was on four day.
And then you're still taking oxycodone
for pain?
I do,
yeah.
And what is the,
what,
what is causing your pain?
Um,
well,
my gunshot wound in my leg,
uh,
developed compartment syndrome in there.
So essentially I guess the easiest way
to describe that as the blood goes into
the tissue,
it doesn't have anywhere to go.
So the pressure builds up and it starts
breaking down muscle,
a muscle tissue and it's painful.
Um,
I have six titanium bolts in my jaw from
one of the explosion,
so I have a lot of joint issues and I
took shrapnel in the side by my ear
canal.
So I just have joint pain from all the
movement.
Um,
yeah,
just stuff like,
I mean it's not,
I'm not near where I was.
I mean I have arthritis,
things like that.
Um,
But yeah,
I mean I think I was on fentanyl 25.
Was it micrograms I think is what it
was.
Twenty five milligrams every three days.
So it was a patch of morphine and was
I'm 40 milligrams a day I believe
because I think they're 20 milligram
pills.
I'd have to remember that.
And then oxycodone was a five,
3:25
and I was on eight of those and then.
So now I'm down to no fentanyl,
no morphine and uh,
just three.
Oxy was a day and it seems to me,
I mean I'm ignorant to this,
but that still seems like a lot of pain
medication for your body to absorb and
process is that.
It is a lot,
but you know,
he's got a detox and then you can go
through cold Turkey.
So I've been on um,
the testosterone replacement a little
over three months and from there I went
from um,
I got off the fentanyl a little bit
before I started that because I just,
I couldn't function with that and
there's too,
too high.
Not high,
but I didn't feel high because I was in
pain,
but I felt down like a suppressed
immunosuppressed I guess,
something like that.
So I went off the morphine and then
within three months I went from eight
oxies down to three and so,
I mean it could be two or three,
just kind of depends how I am during the
day.
So I might take one in the morning when
I wake up and then maybe one at night.
And is the goal to eVentually eliminate
that completely?
Yes.
Yeah.
Hopefully three months Is a pretty
significant improvement.
I mean,
that's amazing.
It's such a short period of time.
That's the pain meds.
That's even the antidepressants,
anti anxiety.
I mean it's all this stuff.
I mean,
the only thing that's left out of like a
12 medication panel is literally just
the three pain meds.
How,
how did it,
your relationship at home and you have
kids almost impersonal.
I mean this is what we got divorced.
So that.
Yeah,
that end you have,
you have a couple kids,
right?
Yeah.
Um,
yeah.
I mean I'm,
yeah,
I mean we're divorced.
I mean I interact with,
uh,
with my ex every day,
but
um,
I'm pretty sure she's got a bitter taste
left in her mouth.
But does it,
um,
maybe that was the wrong way to phrase
the question,
how has it affected your ability to like
deal with day life stuff?
Yeah,
it's much better.
I mean,
it's hard to even describe it because
it's so normal.
I mean,
I feel so normal now to where it's not
an issue.
Um,
I mean I'm not having that issue of just
the biggest thing for me I think was um,
the ability to let go when things are
upsetting,
you know,
little things that people everyday just
tap in this part of life.
Whereas for me,
it was end of the world and you know,
I want to tear things down.
We're now at,
just kind of goes off.
Um,
my interactions with the ex have been
better.
There's a lot of hurt there.
So that comes out sometimes and on both
sides because a lot of mistakes were
made in anger or in pain.
And,
you know,
that's for me right now,
the big thing is physically I'm getting
to where I want to be and I'm getting,
you know,
I'm not,
I'm not 100 percent there,
but I'm 80 percent physically where,
where I want to be and you know,
I still got a little ways to go.
Now the second half of that will be
working mentally tr,
trying to figure out what it is I need
to do to mentally get 100 percent
clarity of where,
um,
I can think is clearly as possible and
deal with any of the things that have
happened,
whether a pre military military and
after.
And it is going to be a challenge
because,
you know,
I'm trying to heal broken relationships,
my wife,
my ex and I,
um,
she's with someone and very happy.
So does nothIng there.
Um,
I'll always love her.
You know,
she was the only woman I've ever loved.
And so that's there.
But I want the best for her and it
wasn't with me at that time and she's
moved on and that's okay.
It wasn't okay for me beforehand because
I mentally couldn't brought us it,
whereas now I can look at it objectively
and say,
I get it.
I just want you to be happy and that's
awesome,
man.
Good for you.
But it's an attitude that,
man,
I wish more people would take,
but it's not.
It's not easy.
Yeah.
That's incredible.
That's not easy.
Now,
how many other people have you turned
onto this?
I mean,
you,
you must know other guys that are
suffering from similar conditions or at
least you suspect they might be.
Sure.
Um,
that's this process right now.
It's part of coming on the show is we're
creating a dialogue as we would like to
say Because no one knows us.
We want to empower veterans to be able
to say,
hey,
go into their doctor and with something
just to say,
hey,
can you do this?
Because now they don't know.
And if they know they can at least start
something or contact me or maybe jason
now or Dr.
Gordon and just get some kind of info
and get it going.
Um,
and that's the thing,
you know,
we're kind of limited because it's
almost like there's just a handful of
people that are doing this Dr.
Gordon and then a few doctors that he's
trained and gone over and,
you know,
they're not,
they're not in every state and every
city and every va in every practice.
It seems like they're getting an attack
to me.
I mean,
I,
I got introduced at a naval special
warfare event to a guy who's doing some
of this work down in Texas that kerrick
and,
you know,
you,
you look him up and people are attacking
him and no,
this and that.
And it was getting attacked by a doctor.
Other doctors,
people saying they were licensed to do
this or,
or it's experimental medicine or you
know,
these kinds of.
yeah,
nothing that we're doing is
experimental.
It's all written about doctors are
treating it whether they know it or not,
you know,
they're,
they're treating patients who are
testosterone deficient.
They never go into great depth.
Ask them their history because I know I
get a lot of patients coming from other
men's clinics type of organizations and
there was a guy recently who wanted to
transfer from his organization whereas
from his clinic to us and I asked them
to send a copy of his original labs and
to make sure it wasn't about using
steroids for bodybuilding or something
of that nature.
And he sent to the lab silver and
screaming on the lab results.
Very limited but significant enough you
can see that he had traumatic brain
injury in the past.
So I called them up,
use 41 years of age,
called him up and introduced myself.
And I said,
um,
uh,
were you ever in an accident?
He said,
yeah.
At 18 years of age he was broadsided on
the car and his head whip lash and hit
the glass and broke the glass window.
So we need to go and do a better job at
history relative to traumatic brain
injury.
We're finding people who have hormonal
deficiency and never ask about their
history or someone comes into their doc
because they're depressed and the first
thing they do is they put them on drugs
instead of asking them,
have you had any head traumas or any
slip and falls or anything?
well,
there's that delay effect too.
It doesn't have to be wrecked car onset,
so when you go in there with this
problem,
no one's thinking to go,
hey,
did you have this?
Because it might have happened 10 years
ago,
and so that's an issue with fighters.
It's a big issue with fighters where I
see guys who have retired and then even
though they've retired,
like say if they're retiring like 2010,
you will see them three,
four years later with no fights at all.
They have deteriorated significantly
over that period of time,
like what it is.
How long does it take?
I've heard 10 years.
It can be up to 17 is an article that
came out just recently that said that it
can take 17 years and it might be that
all their fights brought them up to the
edge and then something silly like
getting into a automobile accident,
five to seven miles an hour,
push them over the edge.
We had someone in san diego,
they had traumatic brain injury from a
five to seven mile an hour rear end,
but they've had history of trauma in the
past.
It's just how much of the hormone may
lou do you have to lose before you flip
into symptoms?
You know,
we have a lot of reserves,
systems In our body,
a growth hormone reserve,
and when you lose that reserve,
you start deteriorating from growth
hormone deficiency with same thing with
testosterone,
estrogen,
all the hormones.
We have a reserved mechanism where
there's a little bit hanging around and
when you lose that reserve,
um,
you lose the battle.
You then become a susceptible to all the
situation,
you know,
the depression,
the fatigue and so forth that occur.
And how'd you get.
How'd you guys all get involved
together?
How did jason get into this?
I looked him up.
You didn't look me up,
looked you up on the internet.
Did you really?
Yeah.
What would,
what did you put in Mark Gordon or what?
No,
I just,
you know,
I've been,
I've been hanging out with these guys.
I looked up ptsd,
hormone therapy and your name came up,
you know,
a tbi,
ptsd hormone therapy.
Okay.
And how did you hear about the hormone
therapy?
I've heard of some,
some pretty well known a navy seal's
going out and getting this therapy that
clearly wasn't available to the army
guys I was talking to who have never
heard of this at all in any way,
shape or form.
And uh,
you know,
because this guy had some ways and means
and,
and was,
was known.
he was able to go get this therapy and
is able to go get it and you know,
it significantly helped his,
his quality of life.
And so to me,
you know,
this,
this movie that we made is about a guy
who's,
who makes this huge sacrifice,
you know,
when he sacrifices spiritually,
mentally,
hIs family,
everything for his beliefs.
And he comes home and he's,
he's got to fight another war,
you know,
this guy fought as hard to get home as
he fought over there and uh,
and I just feel like we're looking at
this thing and it's kinda like the
public is just standing outside of glass
and banging their head on it.
everyone's like,
well,
why are these guys shootIng themselves?
They hear the statistic that are like,
why are these guys putting guns in their
mouth?
So I don't get it.
They're not even asking that question.
Just the general public is completely
ignorant to it.
I mean,
the average person you walked down the
street and say how many soldiers killed
themselves?
They would have no idea that it would be
as many,
if not more than that stigma I was
telling you about.
You say you have ptsd or something and
they meet,
whoa,
we need to lock you up.
You know,
there's that mentality that now you're
dangerous.
And it's so.
I think they,
it's,
you know,
ignorance is bliss.
Let's just snow.
It's hard to talk about.
It's hard to like,
it's hard to dig in,
you know?
And it's hard to,
we have this thing where we're like,
thank you for your service and it's the
polite thing say,
and it kind of
also puts a hand up at the same time.
You're like,
thanks for your service.
I don't really want to know what you saw
or what you did,
you know.
And a lot of the guys correct me if I'm
wrong,
who served or like,
hey,
you wouldn't thank me if you knew what I
had to do here.
You know?
And,
and it's uh,
it,
it kind of prevents conversation in a
way.
Well,
there's also that movement out there and
it's not support the troops,
you know,
and it kind of,
I mean,
I remember coming back a few times and
seeing protests and it's,
it doesn't anger me,
but it was a,
a situation of it's like you,
if you just knew this wouldn't be what
you're doIng right now.
So convenient to protest it mean just
saying that you support the troops and
just saying that you,
you know,
you want them to come back home is
really support the troops come back
home.
But that's all.
That's very convenient.
It's very correct.
You know,
we all would like less war in this
world,
but the reality of supporting the troops
and the reality of the protesting as
you're dealing with these people that
have gone through something that you're
never going to be able to comprehend,
it is absolutely impossible for you to
be able to comprehend just
psychologically what they're dealing
with and to add in this physical aspect
of it.
The traumatic brain injury,
the loss of hormones,
the the loss of the ability to cope
because of this hormonal deficiencies.
There's so much going on.
there's so much going on and when you
see people protesting,
getting upset at troops,
you're talking about kids.
You're talking about 18 year old kids
that are in unbelievably easily
influenced that are sent over there and
essentially brainwashed.
You're immediately thrown into your.
You're thrown into these training
courses that treat you how to block
things out,
how to become a trained killer,
and then they come back and people want
to protest against them.
Like what do you expect them to be
unbelievably unique and be able to deal
with this and process it in some sort of
a strange and very unusual way where
they don't they,
they become a conscientious objector.
They step outside of it.
I mean,
when I see people protesting the actual
soldiers themselves,
it's very maddening because that could
have been me.
It could've been a lot of us.
It was you and it could have been
anybody who joins the military and that
that shit drives me fucking crazy that
you're blaming the soldiers for what
happens.
It's one of the,
one of the most infuriating things and
I've seen it time and time again.
It's so easy to do and it's so short
sighted when there's also no course when
you get,
when you're getting.
I mean really,
there's no.
I mean they do all these training things
to help you deal with getting out,
but there's no like magic course that
you take and all of a sudden you can
fucking deal with life again.
I mean,
you're used to a structured life almost
every day.
Have you do this at 6:00
in the morning?
You do this at 10:00
in the morning,
you do,
you do this,
you eat here,
you eat when they tell you this much,
you do this,
and then you go over there and you're
doIng the same kind of.
You do these routines,
you do these routines and then you get
out and you're literally left to just
fucking figure it out.
Guys say that about prison as well.
Yeah.
Well why?
A lot of guys want to go back
to prison.
I mean I've known people who have gotten
out,
couldn't handle it and went back in
because they were so used to that
structure life.
It almost is that kind of indoctrination
of when you're 18 in a way because
that's all they've known and they're
still babies at 18.
They don't,
you know,
maybe that's just how life was.
That's just what they know and they go
back and it's comfortable.
It's comfortable.
Yeah.
Three or four years ago they had a
strategy.
Anyone coming into the military had to
go through assessment and then when they
exit they're supposed to go through some
kind of exit assessment.
Is thAt being done?
Don't know.
You don't know collIns,
I think doing it,
yeah,
you always go in with some kind of a,
a basic assessment physically just to
see if you meet certain criteria.
Um,
but when you get out,
I mean,
so as like a person who is in charge of
most of the team's health type of thing.
You do like physicals,
you do their lab work,
you do all this stuff for them.
But um,
yeah,
I mean if it checks out,
you just go,
okay,
you're good to go.
I mean,
you're not,
I'm not doing anything extensive that
needs to be done.
Do they give you any psychological
counseling about like how to reintegrate
to society,
how to deal with protests,
how to deal with people calling you a
baby killer or whatever the fuck
Vietnam?
Uh,
I,
no,
not you go through like things where you
have classes,
like when you're a pqs and out or
however you want to call it.
Um,
that just,
you know,
that teach you basic skills to how to
get out of reintegrate into the world,
but I mean it's very basic on like you
can learn like job skills.
I mean,
I didn't personally do any of those
courses.
I did different things,
but they have these things for them and
you go through these things but nothing
like.
And can you train anyone really to how
to deal with being called a baby killer?
I mean,
you can't,
I guess.
I mean you just,
I don't know.
Well yeah,
we put all this money into training them
to fight it and then no money into
training them to find peace.
It's a very good way of putting it.
Yeah.
The internal piece that they need,
that we need.
And there's this uh,
I don't know,
you know,
I look at the met,
I've been doing a lot of thinking of the
medication lately and stuff like that,
just because I can't believe everything
that I've been given and you know,
it is,
it's like there's a market in this ptsd
thing right now and it's just like
everyone's coming back.
If you have this symptom or that
symptom,
you go in there and you fall under this
blanket of that and they're,
they're gonna put you in there and
you're not getting out of it because no
one's going to look any farther than
that and that past to change.
They,
they're treating everything backwards
and so who knows,
man,
that's the info.
Just needs to get out there.
Well,
I think this is going to help,
but obviously it helped you the first
time.
I'm Dr.
Gordon talked about it in the podcast
that you heard.
For sure.
Yeah,
I mean I deeply indebted that you have
people on here that are coming in and
sharing new ideas or just things that
people need to hear.
Um,
yeah.
I mean this.
Yeah.
I have no idea.
I mean I could be dead right now if that
hadn't happened because I mean let's be
frank are probably would be dead and
that in a way probably needed to happen
for me to get enough courage to say this
is something I need to try.
I mean,
I had nothing,
nothing to lose by applying or nothing
to lose about coming down here and just
seeing what was going on and trying
nothing to lose.
And the problem right now is we need to
get money so that we can help people.
We need funding,
we need to get the word out there.
Um,
we're trying to get a non charitable
going so that we can get donations,
things like that.
Um,
you've been a nonprofit five,
zero,
one c,
three non charitable or thinking of
charity in my head and I'm just so
people can get money because how many
people are on a waiting list
right now?
We have about 28 and we just got another
to sober up to 30.
ThAt's just your practice and how many
people like you are doing this all over
the country.
We not just know fornia,
no one.
Jesus jason looked.
I've got a couple of people who have
looked.
There's no one else doing it and now
they're doing some very basic hormone
because since 2004,
I've been going around the world
lecturing on traumatic brain injury and
hormone deficiency syndrome,
but it doesn't have the nuances that are
in there,
so they start off by giving.
Just to start from.
One of the issues with just giving
testosterone is we have a mechanism in
our body.
If you give a hormone or a chemical into
the body that's normally there,
it shuts off the origin of that
chemical.
So upstream precursors are shut off.
So in testosterone,
the two very important upstream
precursors or pregnenolone and dah da.
So it takes about four to six Months
before you shut off those two and they
affect the brain.
So what you'll see in patients who are
just put on testosterone is that they'll
start complaining that they're not
experiencing the same effect.
They're losing the benefit and the
commonest thing that's done is they
increase the amount of testosterone,
increased the amount of estrogen.
They get bitch tits,
and they get,
you know,
feminine kind of attitudes and so forth.
What are you trying to say by feminine?
Well,
how dare you.
I've got three daughters,
you know,
what are you trying to say?
You're going to get the feminist as
well.
As long as they're pretty.
That's pretty feminists.
You just said jumbo tron,
military intelligence.
So I think it took huge balls for you to
come down here and do this too.
I had no idea.
Was was
three months.
Like.
Honestly,
that's fucking awesome.
It think that's a success story,
but you know,
it's just how many other people do we
need to have the same thing so they can
wake up and there's guys,
there's guys out there suffering,
man,
you know,
we have a captain families,
you know captain
who is.
I'm 21 years after his initial,
a traumatic brain injury and five weeks
he was 70 percent better.
He gets better.
He gets redeployed to Afghanistan
because he's better at for a year.
He comes back and he's up in the eightY
percent improvement.
Ninety percent now he's been a have five
shaped building in Washington over
wherever he is and he's trying to help
to find the avenue for us.
Because you know,
he's living,
breathing proof that what we do is it
works and it is very simple basics,
back to the basics,
replace the hormones that are deficient
and protect the brain and it works.
And the other thing is that we're
missing or things like alzheimer's
disease,
we talked about traumatic brain injury.
We think it's just blunt injury to the
head while ionizing radiation from
excessive x-rays,
ct scans,
regular dental x rays,
skull x rays can cause damage to the
control mechanism in the brain called
the hypothalamus.
I'm also subdural hematomas,
which is bleeding in the brain from
like,
boxing has now been associated with all
the same symptoms and hormonal
deficiencies akin to traumatic brain
injury.
So strokes or it's another one,
um,
surgery.
Uh,
I have,
uh,
one of the robin williams issue that
this is that now there was one article
that came out that started looking at
this,
uh,
where there are some 20,700
articles that had been written on.
I knoW that because I use something
called google scholar and it tells you
in zero point zero,
one seconds,
it pulled up,
you know,
20,700
articles and you put in,
um,
cabbage,
which is coronary artery bypass graph
and depression,
and you see 20,700
articles come up talking about
postsurgical post heart surgery,
um,
depression and robin williams in 2009
had a major heart surgery on an air
valve replacement.
And now what we're also finding is that
thyroid changes the thyroid production
in the body changes after prolonged
surgery and it generates a form of
thyroid hormone that's inactive and
associated with low thyroid is
depression associated with damage to the
pituitary from prolonged surgery is
hormonal shutdown.
So I believe that it probably is,
you know,
contributory,
especially when the pathologist came out
and said that there were no drugs and no
medication,
no alcohol,
no medication in his blood,
but of course they're not going to look
at the hormone may loop to see if there
was a deficiency.
Low levels of testosterone leads to
depression,
and you can find a 70,000
articles in this chapter on
neuropsychiatry and traumatic brain
injury.
There are 432,000
articles on growth,
hormone deficiency and depression.
There are 235,000
articles on thyroid.
70,000
on testosterone,
a dah da has about 17,000.
Estrogen has a large amount of
progesterone.
All have depression articles that have
been written since 2000 2013,
almost 850,000
articles.
What?
No.
Instead just producing it.
They're just publishing them to publish
it and no one's reading them.
So essentially what we're dealing with
when it comes to happiness and avoiding
depression is the entire body as a unit,
as an individual unit has to be
balanced.
Correct?
You have to be healthy,
you have to have the proper nutrients,
you have to have rest and exercise,
and you have to have your hormones in
line.
If they are not in line,
you're going to deal with all sorts of
issues,
compensatory issues,
depression,
the all the buffers that caused you to
lash out,
to not lash out.
All those are gone,
correct?
Yeah.
This is a crazy thing to talk about.
I'm starting to revenue,
but it's just.
It seems like there's a rush to get this
information out here while these 40
soldiers of killing themselves a day and
we're just talking about soldiers were
not dealing with people in car
accidents.
People will kick box,
you know,
the people have played football that are
all dealing with thiS.
There's a lot going on here.
There's more than enough going on and
the resistance of the industry,
my industry and the medical industry is
what is perplexing on one part because
we went through,
you know,
medical school and hopefully we all read
the hippocratic oath and we're supposed
to serve the betterment of humanity and
trying to help fix them.
And I don't think that's being done.
I don't think it's really being focused
on.
I think unfortunately I believe that
we're more pawns in a game of chess
where pharmaceutical companies are
dictating to the insurance companies.
Insurance companies are dictating to
both the patients and to the physicians
on how to run medicine so that you walk
into your office and you know you're no
longer an individual,
you're just a number on a card,
but the pen will dial bill.
Yeah.
The people getting this treatment are
the rich 45 year old white guys who can
afford it,
who are all on testosterone,
who are all finding some benefit to
their,
to their,
to their body and mind,
but even that is not being done
correctly.
It doesn't sound like it's being done
correctly at all.
It's they're doing it as an entry point.
I mean,
I've been giving classes on andropause
which is testosterone deficiency amount
of pause,
which is growth hormone deficiency and
menopause and how to balance female
hormones a little better since 2001 and
a lot of docs are listened to it.
A lot of docs went into the industry to
make money and therefore they go to one
class,
one class for three days,
like I just participated in and they
walk out and they are the expert.
I don't consider myself an expert on
anything.
I think I know a little bit and try not
to get in trouble by keep on reading so
I know a little bit more.
and what I do is I go out and I share
this information I'm at and uh,
when I was in chicago at a,
you know,
teaching in medical school there and
that's just my personality.
I read a lot and I find ways to deliver
it so it's palatable and usable in a
very relatively short period of time.
But you have to change,
you know,
unfortunately since 2008,
everything is financially oriented.
So I've put my family life and the
quality of my life partially on the line
because I try to make it so that my
office comes as close as possible to
breaking even and my outside lecturing,
whatever is what really I get my sound.
You put in the wrong place,
uh,
to,
for,
to be able to do it.
And our pricing,
I mean,
the laboratory tests,
uh,
patients are paying a third of the
average.
I'm medical director of education for
the laboratory in the lab has put a lot
into what I do.
They support what I do by matching the
funds that I personally put into it so
that people like matt and I have some
patients who are not in the military,
not in law enforcement and other areas
of government government who are just
great cases that I want to,
you know,
I want to see it work and it works and I
can back this.
I know you do this because I know you
very well and this is a real labor of
love for you.
This is a very important thing for you.
This is not just lip service.
This is something that you've.
From the moment I met you,
you've been very adamant about this and
it's because of guys like matthew and
this is one of the reasons why you
wanted to bring matthew in here and you.
You contacted me right after he started
treating him and right after he started
experiencing positive results and I
could tell that this was something that
was very important to you,
which is why we brought mathieu in here
to discuss this.
Right.
And I'll tell you,
jason is in an arena where I've been
trying diligently for the past three,
four years to get some champion for what
we're doing.
Someone in the entertainment world to
step in and to pick this up and to
spread the word to spread,
help spread the word,
you know,
I think without saying their names,
some of the people in the industry that
I,
um,
I see I work with could do it,
but they don't want to be looked at as
being out there on the fringe because
I'm.
Even though I'm in core medicine,
everything I do is called evidence
based.
Every single thing I do is An article
and you know,
I have a collection of 7,000,
$400 articles that I've gone through in
the past 10 years that address each
area.
And you know,
colleagues says,
you know,
I'd like to see an article on
testosterone and heart with that
craziness that was going on.
So I sent them my portfolio with,
you know,
600 articles about heart and
testosterone and all the benefits.
So there are thousands of articles,
benefit of testosterone in the heart,
and you come up with these three
bullshit articles that you know,
try to taint the benefits that
testosterone.
And we had one of the,
one of the top guys in harvard,
dr abraham mergenthaler wrote the book
testosterone for life that refutes
testosterone causing cancer.
He came to us in the beginning of the
year to an organization called age
management medical group and phenomenal
dissertation on the bullshit of these
articles showing that they show a three
percent,
they report a three percent increase in
coronary artery disease,
greater heart attack onto stastrom when
the actual statistic showed a 30 percent
improvement,
but the way they picked and choosed
everything.
But hOw,
how is it the fringe?
These guys don't want to be perceived as
being on the fringe,
but they're coming to you as patients.
Well,
it's,
that's what I,
you know,
personal and public,
right?
It's about personal image and paulo,
but how do you,
how do you push this thing across the
line so it's not fringe.
I've been on the phone with them
frequently trying to get them if they
don't want to stand up and be a
participant,
direct me to someone directly,
stuff like this.
I think.
Yeah.
I think stuff like this,
especially something like this where
it's a long form,
uninterrupted conversation,
you could really get deep into the facts
and the reality and your anecdotal
experience.
Controversy is not new to you.
Yeah.
Everything I do is controversial.
I don't worry about it.
What's the hottest controversy are in
right now?
I don't know if it's cage fighting,
forcing people to eat animal.
Dick's dirty jokes.
I mean a pot advocacy.
I mean I don't have a single thing that
I do that doesn't have somebody hating
me,
so it's okay enough yet,
but I've been through after everything
I'm saying though.
No,
I think we're good at everything.
I'm saying no.
W,
w,
w regardless of whatever it is,
whatever the subject is.
This was what I truly believe.
I don't have any other motivations,
so I'm fine with the controversy and I
think hormones have a stigma in this
country because of barry ponds and
fucking sammy sosa and all this crazy
shit where everybody's like,
oh,
this fucking cheaters in baseball.
They ruined everything and sports and
everyone is so concerned with what we
hear about with cheating and steroids
and athletic performance.
That means you're missing out on a core
essential aspect of being a human being.
Being a man,
especially the lack of testosterone
directly related to depression,
directly related to these.
These people that start hitting age
regardless of traumatic brain injury,
they start getting older and they feel
like fucking shit.
They feel like shit and I've talked to a
lot of them.
They get on testosterone and all of a
sudden their glow again.
They have energy.
They want to start doing things.
There are active and someone I've talked
to,
guys who are on testosterone that don't
like to talk about it because they're
worried that someone's going to look at
them first of all as being inferior
because they need to add artificial
testosterone to their system and that
they might be a roid head.
Now they might be a cheater and some
like,
what are you fucking playing?
You're 55 years old,
are you playing major league baseball
beHind my back with life?
You're life cheater.
You're doing too good with these new.
meanwhile you'll take aspirin if you
have a fucking headache,
you take ibuprofen,
you'll take medication if you're sick,
like why won't you take testosterone?
Why won't you get your hormone levels
change?
I have a very good friend that won't do
it because he's afraid of all these
other things,
bro.
You look like shit and you're tired all
the time.
Right?
Like what are you worried about?
But the,
and the difference to me is like us
being there and these guys who like I
sat down with a guy two weeks ago,
wrote a script about a metal for the
first time.
Lovely guy,
like the sweetest,
sweetest,
nicest guy,
loves the fish and all this and I'm
like,
so how is it like we really get down to
basics.
He's like,
it's good man,
it's good,
but some days I just have to find a
reason to go on living and you're just
like,
you understand at that point how
different it is for these guys,
how much more drastic it is,
how much more important it is to reach
out to these guys and,
and
somebody's got to do it.
Well,
this is a subject is very near and dear
to my heart,
both because I know a lot of guys in the
military from martial arts and just from
life in general and I know a lot of guys
have had head trauma from fighting and
I've had a bunch of head trauma myself.
So explains it.
Yeah,
I'm sure there's some bad shit going on.
There must be.
It doesn't make any sense,
but it's a,
it's a subject that's very near and dear
to my heart.
And once we started getting into it and
we started discussing it,
it was very confusing to me that it
wasn't hearing this echoed in other
places.
And when sometimes when you hear things
and you don't hear it echoed in other
places,
you say,
well,
maybe I'm talking to a crackpot.
Maybe this guy's fucking crazy.
It's just try to get everybody on the
juice.
But when you look,
when you research it and you find the,
all the hypocrisy and the contradictions
involved in the,
the counteracting of it or the,
uh,
the people who are against it,
you start realizing like,
wow,
this is not a rationally approach
subject.
This is a subject that for whatever
reason is either the people who were
talking about it or ignorant of it,
they don't have personal experience in
it.
They don't have,
they don't have a conversation with a
guy like you that has spent decades
working on this stuff.
There's,
this is not.
This is not a really well understood
subject for a lot of physicians.
They don't have pharmaceutical reps
coming in and telling them that they
need to replace testosterone for
whatever reason.
We're stArting to see it with an issue,
right?
The pharmaceutical reps coming into the
offices.
What?
Which doesn't make any sense because
there are what?
The underarm deodorant to testosterone.
There's the rub on deodorant,
testosterone.
It's a.
It looks like an underarm deodorant
thing to try to avoid contaminating your
loved ones with excessive amount of
testosterone cream.
Put all of your body.
We don't use any creams per se,
except for fun issues.
Well,
don't take how dare you.
Don't.
The creams have also some sort of an
absorption issue as well.
Well,
what happens is when you put a cream,
a 10 percent or five percent gel or
cream of testosterone and skin,
the little hair follicles have an enzyme
in it that converted from testosterone
to dihydrotestosterone,
which is the active form of testosterone
that you want in the cell,
not floating around in the blood to
cause loss of hair.
At one point in my head,
motherfucking loss,
loss of hair,
shrinkage of the testicles pointed me
again.
Plenty large was set over there at your
monster over there.
The werewolf and the world will and a
enlargement of the prostate.
Uh,
you know,
for women,
enlargement of the clutter is not bad.
It's an imbalance,
an imbalance or lack of dht along with
the too much dht instead of having free
testosterone that you need to get into
the brain.
So we have,
we're interacting with some other
delivery technologies,
uh,
aside from injectable and topical,
that increases the amount of
testosterone that gets into the brain
and we see the major benefits in our tbi
and,
or a head trauma,
neuro trauma patients where they do
phenomenally well.
So it seems that,
well,
it doesn't seem that there's a whole
panel of things that have to be balanced
out in order for you to have a said
happy body.
You said at the beginning of a holistic
approach,
you need to have physical activity and
nutrition and you have to have a balance
of everything you take into your body.
Whether or not it's A medication or a
hormone or a mineral or vitamin.
You sent me another thing.
This is very important to talk about
because I sent it to a buddy who was
experiencing some depression that you
sent me,
something about propecia or [inaudible]
or whatever,
the finasteride finasteride and dressed
drive direction that has been shown to
cause depression in people and I have a
buddy who got on that shit and he was
experiencing some hair loss.
Get on that shit and became really,
really depressed.
The reason being is that to stop when it
gets into the brain,
goes through a cascade of changes from
testosterone to dihydrotestosterone 300
scenic diane,
and then it stimulates a chemical called
adenyl cyclase,
which gives us our upgrade feeling.
And when you block the conversion of
testosterone,
dht,
you lose all that stuff down the road.
So you can have issues with anger,
depression.
We have a couple of people who were
developed it within a short period of
time,
like 18 months on the finance
finasteride and,
uh,
had to put them onto hcg little clomid
and a little testosterone.
Six months,
they're back in line.
They were depressed,
they'd lost their libido.
And it's because the effect of dht and
testosterone,
the brain,
testosterone and growth hormone also
work in an area of the brain for memory
recall,
and the ability to learn new things
called the hippocampus also are
panoramic vision and our panoramic
memories.
So you look at something panoramic or
you have a sequence of,
of,
um,
of memories that you can lose if you
lose your testosterone in the perry
campus area of the brain,
it also kills your dick like pesticide.
Oh,
dah di,
that fucking that print finasteride
stuff.
Oh yeah.
That's because dht is important.
Testosterone's important dht in the
brain.
So when you use stuff that converts the
dht in from the application on the skin,
it gets into the blood but doesn't get
into the brain.
So you have to generate your dht in the
brain,
in the cells,
not in the blood.
And when I look at people who are on
some of the topical products out there,
you see free testosterone's good.
Total testosterone is outrageously high.
Dht is sky high.
And they're wondering why their hair's
falling out in handfuls.
Almost their testicles are disappearing
or else,
you know.
But they are straight strengths up
strength from dhd,
but it's this,
this pill that makes your hair fall out.
I mean that's like,
that's one of those things like if
someone could come up with a pill that
makes you,
that keeps your hair from falling out,
boy,
that's a,
that's a very popular thing.
And then you look at the side effects.
I was like,
don't give it a pregnant woman.
Your fucking kids going to be fucked up
if she touches it.
Like you can't even touch it if you're a
pregnant woman.
Like don't take something that a woman
can't even touch when she's pregnant.
And the reason is that they found that
d,
h,
d helps to distinguish the brain's
gender orientation,
dht,
dihydrotestosterone,
gender orientation,
so that you can have externally a,
a,
you know,
a male body.
But If female mentality woe and it's
biochemical.
so do you think that this is a maybe
possibly related to transgender people
that are there that say they were born a
man physically but they brought born the
wrong sex dht related?
I think it's,
that's it.
It's not.
I don't believe in the social,
cultural reasons for it,
you know,
someone becoming a homosexual or lesbian
is,
you know,
as a ptsd kind of response.
I use the data.
A gal who was a lesbian who would just
go out.
No,
it was my goal to fix her if she needed
to be who she was,
but she had been raped.
I'm kidding.
yeah,
I know you were.
She had been raped multiple times when
she lived in this country.
That's always conflicting over there in
the east area.
Okay.
Now,
okay.
And uh,
I don't know what you're saying,
but middle east area and you know,
that country that everyone's picking on
because it's a warmonger income country
and creates all the wars.
Syria,
Israel,
Israel.
So she was raped in Israel bite.
Oh god.
Some people there.
And um,
she feared men,
she had a ptsd.
Every time she got close with the guy,
she would freak out and she didn't have
it with women.
And that was,
you know,
the pts.
But I think,
uh,
you know,
they say it's a choice.
Well,
I don't think it's a choice in all the
cases.
I think in the transgender they were put
into the wrong body.
Their mindset was in the wrong body or
their body was right.
The mindset was treated with hormones
that created the,
the other gender,
and they're fulfilling it by transgender
surgery.
You know,
I worked in Thailand for the past,
uh,
four years going back to starting the
project and was exposed to a lot of the
transgender or the gender reassignment
individuals relative to hormones.
And um,
there were people who were in the wrong
body.
I mean their physical expression in the
opposite.
Then sex they were born in was obviously
the wrong body and they went through
surgery to have things corrected for
them.
And do you think this is related to
these hormones in the wound?
I think it's hormones.
It could be,
you know,
alcohol,
cocaine,
crack,
meth,
any kind of chemistry that is introduced
to the woman's body during that very
frightful period of time,
the first seven weeks where everything
starts developing and the change in
hormones,
whether or not it's externally
introduced or internally manufactured
because of things that they've been
taken into their body like alcohol,
which can alter chemistry or smoking
weed that can cause an elevation.
Esther dialed levels.
And if you have elevation to dial dial
levels in a,
in a male,
you can predispose them to be female
brain,
physiologically male,
female in mental.
This is an issue that a lot of people
get very emotional about when you're
talking about transgender folks.
And yes,
and when you break it down to a chemical
relationship and you break it down to
this,
what,
what you're saying about the
introduction of the certain chemicals in
the womb,
people resist this information.
Yes they do.
They like to say that,
you know,
they're always female.
Uh,
they want to be female or male or male.
Sorry,
I just preference or female regardless.
But um,
yeah,
it's a very heated,
very emotional because you don't want to
have that doubt that they were a male.
You want to eliminate the fact that they
were a male and that there are female,
as you know,
in,
in mma.
The situation that's going on,
the situation that I'm involved in,
well I'm involved in it because I was
one of many people that thought it was
incorrect.
There's a woman that was born a man.
She was a man for 30 years and then had
gender reassignment surgery two years
later.
It was fighting women in mma fights.
Never fought as a man and he's fighting
and beating the fuck out of these checks
and not letting them know.
The first two,
at least that she used to be a man,
which I thought was just completely
incorrect.
And I based it on my knowledge of
martial arts,
my knowledge of things like the size of
hands and shoulders and the different
relationship that the body parts of the
hips,
there's the,
there's the structure of a male body is
very different.
And then if you take steroids,
one of the things about steroids that's
hugely problematic,
people that cheated and then don't cheat
anymore is that when you cheat,
when you take steroids,
and I'm not talking just about
testosterone and talking to them like
real radical steroids and a lot of
people taken you enact permanent changes
to your body,
not just permanent changes,
but permanent changes that improve the
performance of your body forever.
You there,
there's been many studies that have come
out recently that people have taken
steroids,
you know,
x amount of years ago and been off them
for a long time,
still have the benefits of taking those
steroids.
If you've taken 30 years of testosterone
in a male frame,
I'm a male frame which has different
tendons,
which has different,
uh,
different jaw structure which changes
your ability to absorb punishment.
Two years of estrogen therapy.
How much of that is going to change that
externally?
It'll change.
Estrogen has a counteract some of the
Benefits of testosterone.
So the question is,
is there also supplementation of
testosterone at the same time,
it taking estrogen or are they using gas
testosterone to convert into estrogen as
a means of getting their estrogen?
You'd have to look at how they're being
treated and you know,
their personal selection of what
cocktail of hormones that are taking.
Usually what happens is [inaudible]
acetate is a drug that's used to block
the androgen receptors so that a woman
can develop the or transgender woman can
develop the softness and the femininity
of her body.
But if the individual,
the transgender female as a female
maintains a lot of the muscle striations
and contours of a male,
then they're probably not getting
adequate amount of estrogen or they're
supplementing with one form of another,
of either testosterone or deco or
nandrolone or a loan.
Um,
what androgen,
a nfr some of the other dht like
products.
So it'd be interesting to find out what
the chemistry,
the bIochemistry is the individual,
but you're right,
muscle muscle response,
time,
absorption,
hips,
tendons,
cartilage and joints,
resilience,
thickness of the bone.
Men have more dense bones,
more dense jaws than women.
Um,
mIndset.
The aggression,
there's a totally different direction.
Imprinting,
imprinting right from that 30 years.
Men are different for a lot of ways.
The way we analyze things,
so we're not fair,
but when it comes to bone density,
um,
african american women have similar bone
density to white men.
Correct.
For whatever reason,
my significant other is a dentist and
would share with me over the past 30
some odd years about the difference
between different racial groups and the
african american have much thicker
bones,
much thicker bones comparable to a male
or female to male,
yes.
And astrogen.
In taking estrogen post transition
transition,
estrogen allows the bone density to
remain because estrogen,
which is one of the issues in
osteoporosis,
is when women go through menopause,
their body stops producing estrogen,
so their bones lack density.
So in giving a transgender male
estrogen,
it actually preserves bone density,
so keeps them with a male.
That's correct.
They don't lose it as long as they're
making sure that not only vitamin d but
extra dial testosterone growth hormone
all help with bone density.
In fact,
a growth hormone works about point one
point six percent increase in bone
density in a year,
so it raises the bone density.
We have patients who are growth hormone
deficient with thinning of the bones.
We put them back on physiologic dosing
of growth on,
you see in six months to a year that
bone density responds where in using
some of the medication that are out
there,
which I won't name,
you know,
can take,
I'm 23 years,
and bone density is also altered by
weightlifting,
correct?
Correct.
The body responds through pulling.
I mean people.
The most common,
abnormal,
uh,
example of that are either achilles
tendon spurs or plantar fasciitis spurs
from pulling a muscle or tendon on bone.
It stimulates more bone to be made.
So if you're stressing the bones is
really what it is,
you increase the density.
So if you look at people who are
sedentary,
drink alcohol,
blonde,
blue eyed,
male or female,
you'll see scandinavian study.
You'll see that their bone density is
less than people who are dark skinned,
dark haired,
and physically active.
These are things that helped maintain
and promote denser bone.
What happens to tendon strength and
things along those lines,
because tendons play a vital role in
striking in,
in combat sports.
That's right.
Uh,
specifically about tendons I can't
answer other than the muscle.
IT improves the muscle in muscles are
connected to tendons.
Tendons are a inert kind of tissue.
It's the muscle that pull on the tendon.
So it's the muscle issue,
but the muscles decreased with estrogen
therapy.
They can do decrease with estrogen
therapy,
but if they're also on something that
puts back testosterone,
you can generate a balance.
So they get some softening,
but they don't lose the muscle.
And then estrogen,
you'd have to look at the biochemistry
of it to really answer it because if
you're being strict on the process of
total transgender transformation,
you need to give them lots of estrogen
in diminished the testosterone which
competes with the estrogen.
So if you want to be a dominant estrogen
dominant to be a female estrogen
dominant,
then you have to wipe out the
testosterone.
Well,
this has been such a highly charged and
emotional discussion and it becomes a
transphobic or an anti transgender more
than it becomes an argument of fairness
involving a sport where the very goal is
to use your body to hurt somebody else
and if you have some sort of just
natural physiological advantages over
that person because you were born male,
not because you're.
I meAn this is a spectrum involving
women.
There's some women that are very
feminine,
very petite,
and there's some women that are very
thIck and very physically strong just
naturally,
but from the womb,
you know,
no added hormones,
no added anything.
So.
but the idea is that that's mitigated by
weight classes.
The idea is that a 135 pound woman in
135 pound woman,
you know,
they're both 135 pounds.
They're pre,
whether they're,
you know,
there's variations,
but pretty close,
let's,
let's have them compete against each
other.
But 135 pound man versus 135 pound
woman.
Very different.
One hundred and 35 pound transitioning
man to transgender woman.
Still different than a biologic,
a woman,
they would have undue disadvantage.
The competitor,
female natural born,
digital born female,
would have undue disadvantage against a
transgender female from male to female.
Genetically,
you know,
you're always going to be a male
genetically,
so it means that the biochemistry,
when you put these things into it,
the body wIll respond to preference
male,
unless you totally put in chemistry to,
uh,
to stop that.
And that's that cypress.
But let's assume that they even do put
the chemicals in to stop that.
Would they still have significant
advantages in any area?
Yes.
For a timeframe they would.
Until the optimal effects that you're
looking for by giving estrogen for
softening the musculature,
take effect.
well,
it's still,
there's a 10 percent benefit that men
have over women,
like across the board and reaction time.
Would that still be a factor if they had
transitioned to a woman?
I really don't know.
That answer
is.
There probably hasn't been that many
studies on this as well.
I think the biggest problem in this one
case that you're talking about is that
there's really no precedences,
no wealth of documentation where they've
actually looked at someone who goes from
male to female and gets into some male
sports within and not wrestling or
grappling or mma or whatever the
situation is.
Or baseball was there.
Someone recently went into transitional.
Went into a sport
that cyclist.
Yeah.
Michelle,
do more ask.
Yeah.
This,
it's a fascinating story.
She transitioned.
She had sex reassignment surgery,
became a woman,
and started competIng in biking in,
and in her first she,
she entered a novice female class.
Her first finish was two point five
seconds faster than the winner of the
professional female category.
She went on to win the fall in 2002.
She,
uh,
she was awarded a license to race in the
women's category.
Three weekS later,
she entered her first race in the pro
woman's class,
finished third the following week.
She plays first beating her compete
competition by 10 seconds.
And this is,
you know,
a novice,
a person who's just just entering into
this world of professional racing and
she's just stomping these women a wave
of protests and sued and petition was
created and signed by female and a few
male racers asking her to be
dIsqualified because she had a race
licensed.
The request was denied.
So it became this huge controversy.
Um,
and you know,
this is another example of someone who
has an unfair physical advantage or is
thought to have that tech chemically.
Um,
there's another problem with this is
that there's a lot of confirmation bias
about this and there's a lot of
emotions.
They're riding on this.
And this person who we're talking about,
the person in question has become
essentially a poster boy for transgender
rights and transgender acceptance.
And I couldn't think of a worst possible
example.
It's one thing to say,
hey,
you know,
this person wants their own personal
freedom to be living their life.
As a woman.
Do you accept that?
Absolutely.
Change your name,
change whatever,
whatever you want,
but when you're asking for that,
right?
But you're entering into combat sports
with natural born females and literally
beating the shit out of them.
Boy,
that gets really fucking tricky.
That gets really tricky.
So what do you think the resolve will
be?
Have a separate organization that only
deals with transgender.
That's the best way.
I mean,
that's probably the best way to
professional.
I mean that's the.
But if there's a point at which the
body,
the body provides homeostasis as a woman
after doing all that testing.
Isn't,
isn't that measurable?
It's measurable,
but It's going to take a long time.
They might be in their seventies by the
time it takes.
So it takes.
Yeah,
but the point is they're genetically
there.
Whatever you throw into their body,
their body's going to respond to it as
their original gender.
so the testosterone that you're talking
about,
the problem that people have that I've
talked to is if I start taking this
thing,
I'm going to have to take it the rest of
my life.
If you're deficient,
I used to get this for the past 14
years.
You're a diabetic who needs insulin,
right?
What are you going to do?
Rest of your life.
Correct.
Same thing with testosterone.
Thyroid.
I'm committed to my thyroid for the rest
of my life because without it I gained
weight.
My thought processes are slowed down and
now I race all the time.
Brain wise it's.
So you have to treat it like a,
like a disorder,
a disease.
It's a deficiency syndrome.
Efficiency.
Yeah.
To do,
you know,
I don't understand why,
my colleagues tend to isolate it just as
you,
you know,
positioned it.
If you're deficient,
you replace your replace or replenish
it.
bringing it back to where the normal
love.
Liz,
the other thing is we have developed a
statistical models for at 20 years of
age,
you need this amount of hormone at 40
this mount which is less and at 60 this
amount,
what do we replace everything to one
word,
the healthiest between 25 and 35 and
that's the premise of our practice and
that's why we get the responses we do.
We don't return a 70 year old to the
average 70 year old level because they
weren't getting any benefit in the past.
So we bring them to a level that has
the,
the peak of it.
Do you have a seven year old wives
coming in and go,
let's do one stop fucking man.
We fucking dose back.
Jesus christ.
I had a.
You brought it up,
you brought it up.
Ninety four year old guy comes in with a
walker.
Rice 94 year old guy comes in on a
walker,
was brought in by one guy that I talked
about,
keith and he'd been using the walker for
about 17 years.
Comes in,
come in,
and we put them on two hormones now in
the past I would draw the blood,
get results and then starting.
But he had a classical syndrome called
the frailty syndrome.
He was holding onto the walker and
shaking because he didn't have muscle
tone to support his own body.
That is classical,
uh,
fatigue syndrome.
So I put them onto a middle of the road
treatment protocol,
low dose regiment,
and waited for the labs,
come back,
told him to come back in six weeks,
came back in six weeks and we started
them,
you know,
reviewed the labs and he was on
appropriate mount and drew blood again
to monitor him.
And we chit chatted a little bit.
And as he started leaving the room,
he turns to me and says,
oh,
by the way,
Dr.
Gordon,
I probably should tell you,
I finally had sex with my 60 year old
girlfriend.
And that tells you that at replacing the
hormone,
that psychologically you have to be
psychologically attuned to want to have
sex.
You can't just have sex because the
brain is,
you know,
not with you physiologically.
everything that has to be working in
physically,
you have to have the moves.
Well,
that's what he did to me.
He's got some.
The other thing is he
carried his walker in.
He knew it,
didn't walk on it.
He carried it in under his arm.
And I said to herman,
I said to herman,
uh,
why are you carrying the walk?
He says,
well,
I've used it for 17 years.
I've had to continue using it.
I said,
did you use it today?
He says,
no,
so we'll leave it home.
He says,
but I'm afraid I might fall.
He's committed to his walker.
Like,
you're committed to your thyroid.
Absolutely.
So,
um,
I think it's different.
That's like if he needed,
he didn't need the thyroid,
he's still taking it with them.
How about levitra or stylists or
something like that?
It does help your testosterone does
allegedly allegedly know anything about
it?
So the answer is yes.
You've had some 90 year old dudes.
Fucking the shit out there.
I shouldn't say it like that.
Well,
no.
Um,
what,
um,
if you ever had negative responses,
people,
you've put them on some of a hormone
replacement protocol and that becomes
issues.
Absolutely.
What are those?
Um,
let's see,
uh,
a gentleman who was put onto 60
milligrams a week of testosterone and
all they wanted to do is have sex with
anything that walked.
Uh,
so we had a lower them down to 40
milligrams,
three patients who had a panic attack
because this process of testosterone in
the brain going to this thing called
adenyl cyclase.
If it's the wrong person or too much
relative to their body,
they can get a panic attack,
which I've had in three patients.
You load those in,
disappears.
What is,
what's causing the panic attack?
It's a chemical called adenyl cyclase,
which is like a stimulate in the brain,
just,
it just pushes you over the edge.
So is it that they have so much
testosterone and then their body thinks,
well,
we must have,
we must be in a dangerous area.
Is that why we have.
Okay,
it's relative.
Hormones are relative.
It's not absolute.
You can't say 100 is what everybody
uses.
You know there are people who need 20
milligrams.
I have one gal that the average
production of a woman in a week is about
20 milligrams.
She would use 20 milligrams a month and
she meet her it by her libido.
so average weekly dose she used every
month because she was super sensItive to
it.
Women,
when they get on testosterone,
get super horny,
they get assertive,
which is great.
They get allegedly,
it was mostly living with them.
The confidence,
assertiveness a,
they start feeling great.
They absolutely feel better,
a competitive and it's all degrees of.
It's all acceptable degrees of and when
you overtreat them then you get into,
I want to be fucked now in our and in
two hours and three hours in four hours
and you know,
you're using science from personal
experience.
Absolutely not just a.
I had to go back and take human
sexuality classes so that I can feel
comfortable saying the f word on your
show.
Really.
Absolutely you to take.
I took it years ago.
It helped me with dealing with my own
upbringing and my conservative
conservative.
When you grew up in a time with no
internet man,
the world's changed.
Absolutely.
working it out.
Doctors dot dropping,
f bombs left and right.
And these days,
oh you got a fucking broken leg kit and
being from New York,
you know,
fuck is the what?
And his first and idea is second and
fuck his third.
yeah,
it's a common one.
It's a common one,
but there are better words in some of
us.
there are better words.
Again,
this people have this response to the
testosterone.
They developed this anxiety issue,
panic attack,
but what exactly is a panic attack like
what's going on when you,
it's an explosive fear of the unknown
where they think something bad's going
to happen to them and they get
hyperventilation and they get a fast
pulse and from the hyperventilation they
can actually pass out because they
changed the ph of the blood.
We had a guy in the ufc that was in the,
um,
in the locker room about the fight,
had a panic attack and was
hyperventilating and they actually
pulled them from the fight,
haven't breathed it into a brown paper
bag or a plastic bag or put one of those
black hoods over their head.
Well,
what does that do?
What the lag.
What it is is,
uh,
when you hyperventilate,
you're blowing in,
you're getting in too much oxygen and
getting rid of your calcium and it falls
out of solutions in calcium's,
responsible for a neuro conductivity.
So when you breathe in too much or
giving you a hyper ventilate,
you create a change in the acid balance,
acid base and calcium is used to try and
stabilize it.
So what happens is it falls out of
solution.
Calcium hydroxide.
What does the black bag do?
A,
I was just being funny.
Brown paper bag.
I like plastic over brown paper.
Brown paper makes too much crunching.
Noise,
cocaine.
So the idea of a bag being that you're
not getting all the oxygen from around
where you're breathing in carbon
dioxide,
you need to bring back your blowing from
hyperventilation.
You blow out a lot of carbon dioxide
which your body actually needs.
You know,
if you give someone pure oxygen,
you can stop their breathing because the
balance of breathing is between oxygen
and carbon dioxide.
The carbon dioxide is actually what
stimulates you to breathe.
What about those like oxygen bars,
places?
What's the actor's name who has such
with age?
A woody harrelson I think has a lot of
the action bars.
Yeah,
they're great.
Uh,
you know,
Michael Jackson used to sleep in a
hyperbaric chamber.
He did,
and that has higher oxygen
concentration,
so getting more oxygen,
you know,
in las vegas,
you go to the airport,
I was just there and they have all these
oxygen bars there.
So after you had been bombed out for
three days,
playing every night until two in the
morning,
we're never getting to bed.
Oxygen can help you,
uh,
with some improvement in improving your
focus.
But don't they pump it into the casinos
as well?
Yes.
The supposedly is what they said.
I don't know what the true keeps you up.
That's what I've heard too,
but I don't know if that's true.
We need to find.
I don't know if they would ever fucking
admit that you bring an oxygen meter in
and if it's a 21 percent or higher,
you know they are because it's,
I think 19 percent in the natural world.
The fucking tackle.
You want them to oxygen.
That's why they have all those cards
tackle them.
That's why they have the cameras up
there to make sure you don't bring
oxygen meters and the frisky for oxygen
meter walk through the door.
And the idea that the oxygen keeps you
awake,
is that what it is?
Correct.
WhaT he says is false.
Snopes says it's false.
how the fuck do they know?
It's just the gambling.
Gambling is.
Could you ask him,
is it true that when you ask for a
drink,
when you're playing craps,
they put a lot of alcohol in it,
so it disinhibition so that you put more
money down then you have.
Well they definitely give you good free
drinks when you're gambling.
that was good.
That is a crazy fucking thing that
they're allowed to do.
Give you free drugs That lower your
inhibitions and cause you to make
irresponsible decisions while you're
doing something that involves gambling
and fucking crazy.
But so they got oxygen there.
I supported him 100 percent with it.
I've done those.
Um,
those oxygen bars.
I did one in vegas once we sat down and
tried it and my friend eddie and I was
like,
you're feeling anything.
He's like,
did you get to sit in their flavored?
Probably was going up my nose or sucking
on it.
I don't even remember.
But I remember like given up after
awhile,
it's like,
this isn't new,
this is not enough.
It's not like you have a shot and you're
like,
woo,
like this is working.
Maybe you awake.
that was the problem.
You had to be asleep to do it.
Oh.
So if you're asleep and you have little
oxygenic does better.
The guy at the float lab,
he pumps a oxygen into the isolation
tanks.
He uh,
has an oxygen scrubber,
like one of those ones that make those
weird noises and you know,
those auctions,
scrubber things,
it pumps air into the isolation tank to
enhance it.
Doing that tomorrow for the first time.
Where,
which,
which place?
Venice float lab.
Yeah.
it's awesome.
I love it.
Yeah.
So I wrote lab a life changing word.
I going to have some flashbacks or
something.
You mighT.
how long are you in the tank?
Depends.
You could do it for as little as an
hour.
Miki.
I've done it for a half an hour.
If I just want to relax,
I have something to do and I'm just
trying to unwind.
I got three kids,
so I'm thinking three hours signal
deprivation it.
Two hours is good.
It helps.
I do it every time.
Come down.
Yeah.
What,
uh,
what helps about it?
Um,
you think in a clear fashion like things
are coming to you and I believe,
you know,
it's just,
you,
you're able to kind of work through it a
little bit better where there's no
distractions.
The distractions,
there's not.
Yeah,
you don't got other stuff going on.
And,
and I,
I work better internalizing things like
that.
Like Was talking about the counseling
for me,
that's just my personality would never
work because uh,
the person I'm talking to doesn't know
what I went through,
but in my own mind when my own dialogue
is talking to me back because I,
the last time I was talking to,
I remember talking to myself and I was
talking back to me it was,
yeah,
it was very,
it was very strange.
But that's what was happening was I was
bringing up things and I was talking and
I was responding in fashion with what I
was talking about,
like calming myself down.
And it just worked better
the way I describe it as a,
the first 20 minutes or so,
me and the tank is sort of like a
seminar on my own life.
So giving myself advice because the mine
untethered from the body's very
difficult to get to that state unless
you're doing some really fucking heavy
meditation for long periods of time.
It's very difficult to achieve this kind
of state.
You get in an isolation tank after half
an hour just floating.
It takes me a while to get there.
Yeah.
You got to compensate.
I don't know.
I don't.
I mean I don't do it often.
Yeah,
that's a big of it too.
It takes me a while,
but once I'm there it yeah,
it does help.
I do leave clear and it is something
that I think is a benefit,
especially for things like ptsd and
mental issue.
You know,
if you had one near you and you could do
it on a regular basis,
I think it would help even more because
it's part of it is relaxing with the
experience itself.
The experience to me,
because I have one of my basement,
it's a very natural part of life.
I go in there all the time,
so it's a natural thing.
It's not like,
oh,
what are we doing here?
It's like,
here We go again.
You know,
it's normal.
It's almost over,
buddy.
The other thing too was for me with my
body,
just wIth paint,
you know,
I'm used to walking around at a certain
comfort level of just the way my body
works.
Some laying down in there when my body's
not supporting itself,
I was able to let that go.
I let that go and just kind of focused
like I said on my mind and that's a huge
thing for me.
Like I.
It wasn't until I did that the first
time that I realized how much my body is
impacting my mind,
you know,
really just because you get used to
feeling a certain way the whole time,
especially with like pain or my leg or
my knees.
You take that out of the equation,
oh,
you know,
your mind's like,
okay,
this let's we can focus on something
else and that it is nice and besides the
alleviation of pressure,
because you're not carrying your weight
anymore,
there's also absent salts in it,
which is an excellent source of
magnesium,
which also relaxes the muscle.
So you got like sort of a dual effect
going on.
You have this no gravity effect because
you're completely floating,
you're bobbing in this water and then
you also have this magnesium when,
and this,
one of the things that people always
recommend for muscle soreness is epson
salts and this delivery method of
getting the magnesium through your skin
that way supposed to be excellent as
well.
It's the biggest organ in the body.
So it absorbs a lot.
What do we need to do to help more
people out here with this?
To spread the word out about this,
about what you are doing.
And matthew,
thank you very much for doing this and
coming on here.
And uh,
and jason,
this is,
this is a very important issue.
And,
uh,
I think all the things that we've
discussed here today,
the,
the benefits I think could really
greatly help a lot of people.
So how do we,
uh,
how do we spread this?
Well,
as we found out in january,
you had an impressive response curve for
the program that we did.
We talked about,
you know,
big foot and we talked about narrows and
we talked about,
yeah,
the injection,
you know,
everything we've talked about and then
lead up to this area of tbi.
I think finding A multitude of avenues.
That's why I've been dragging matthew
with me to some of the guys that I know
around the states that have shows not
similar to yours but not as grand and
have each helped to make a little dent.
And we just need someone to come up and
champion a.
I'm going to get in touch with howard
schultz,
who's the ceo of starbucks who,
uh,
yesterday I had this really great
statement he made that we need to honor
our vets by giving them a concert and a
job now in order for them to go to that
concert.
And I appreciate and enjoy it and have
that job.
We have to fix the underlying problem
not to mask it and therefore letting
vets know that there is an option and
next year,
uh,
april of finished my book by january and
then put on a class which will be
limited to a hundred docs to come in to
be trained in this process,
these protocols which are relatively
simple,
um,
and then go out and start being
representative of an alternative to
antidepressants,
antianxiety meds,
bit of an uphill battle that has to be
fought also with the idea of
supplementing hormones to achieve a
balance in the body.
Because a lot of people,
when they think of soldiers,
what do they think of?
They think of these testosterone fueled
savage men.
And then,
you know,
you add testosterone to that boy,
like you're just gonna make more
aggressive,
crazier.
It doesn't work that way.
The reason what is up yet,
it's uphill battle.
If they weren't in the military,
they go into a clinic.
Now what's happening is you might have
low testosterone syndrome,
let's check you.
And they do two tests.
And I find that they're low
testosterone,
but they don't know the cause for it
because they didn't do an extensive
enough to say that it's due to head
trauma,
you know,
whichever way they can do it,
to get guys onto a ask the history of
trauma,
do the lab tests and get them on it,
but the resistance is because of the
controversy that has always stood there
with testosterone and with the balco and
the barry bonds and all these things
relative to public guide that negative.
They demonized growth hormone,
they demonized testosterone instead of
talking about the benefits of it and how
it could be utilized in this specific
situation and it works.
So anyone who's listening,
you know,
I know someone who might be there to
connect us with the right people in
government and so forth to go and do it.
That is the issue.
Knee jerk reaction,
right?
Immediately people want to think of it
as like,
this is a.
This is a cheating thing.
This is a bad thing,
right?
Just like the salt thing that we were
talking,
we'll stop everybody's estrogen
replacement stopped everybody's insulin
replacement or thyroid replacement.
Our body had it from when we were born,
so why do we assume that it's not
necessary?
I mean,
I've had a number of women who came in
who were significantly testosterone
deficient with the all the symptoms that
a woman get from testosterone
deficiency.
they're not nice to be around and their
doctor says,
well,
you don't need it.
You just need your estrogen replaced and
they don't even replace the progesterone
and you need to have that balance so
they don't get sleep deprivation.
Developed depression,
panic attack,
and ended up in the emergency room every
two weeks
like we see.
My thing too is that I think,
I don't think this is a cure for
everybody.
Every single person is going to fall
into this category.
You went to war,
you know,
you suffered some through some stuff and
now here's your cure.
I don't think that's what it is,
but I think that there's a.
There's a two stages here.
There's the stage where,
you know,
like math,
you talked about where he admitted he
didn't feel okay and he was willing to
go seek some help for it,
you know,
and hopefully this movie you're watching
chris,
who's a guy who was tough as nails,
he was the baddest,
baddest,
you know,
seal there ever was.
He found a way to admit that he didn't
feel okay and went and sought some help
for it.
Then then in seeking help,
there needs to be more pragmatic
solutions.
Like right now we're looking at the
thing and it's like,
it's a grab bag,
you know,
and to me this feels like a,
a mind body solution.
This isn't,
this isn't freudian counseling,
this isn't some lady sitting there,
you know,
god bless these women who work at the va
in the men too.
Who are these counselors?
Did they go through hell?
I mean,
imagine sitting there every day.
They're on the clock,
they're seeing guys on their lunch
breaks.
They're seeing people After work.
They have huge hearts,
but they can't handle it,
you know,
and after awhile you shut down,
you hear this story over and over again,
you see the misery and it's just like,
it just sucks the life out of them,
you know,
and,
and so I don't think that's the solution
for everybody.
I think that there's,
you know,
there's a,
there's a number of things that are
going to help people,
but If this,
if seeking blood work and seeking a mind
body solution through medicine is
available and,
and is out there in the public and is
getting vetted through other doctors
and,
and spread among the medical community
than these guys have a chance.
But if it's not,
if it's just one thing,
one doctor sit in here and uh,
you know,
some guy in Missouri is not gonna make
it out to see Dr.
Gordon.
I think it's really important that you
said what you said about the it's not
the solution for everybody and it's only
one part of it that what we said before,
thIs is a holistic approach,
but if you don't heal the body,
it's going to be incredibly difficult to
put the mind at peace and it's healing.
The body's not necessarily going to put
the mind at peace,
but it's a step in the right direction
where there's.
I mean it's you have nothing to lose.
You do it and you try and if that's not
really what's going on,
then you take the next step,
but you don't know if you don't look.
Yeah,
you don't know.
You don't know.
And matthew came down,
we took a look and it's a simple blood
test.
Simple blood work.
Okay,
so for the guy out there or the gal with
ptsd,
with depression that's dealing with the
things that they have some sort of
traumatic brain injuries in their past,
it could be contributing to this.
What's their step?
What do they do?
Well,
they can go to the website which is tbi,
medlegal.com.
Tbi,
medlegal,
tbi,
med
legal.com
and put in an application and those that
are coming through and it asks military
and asked the type of injury you had and
what medications you're on and the
military get put into a separate
grouping and we're waiting for funding
to come in.
Uh,
so that we can start takIng more of the
people.
and this is the laboratory testing has
always been a 100 percent covered.
The treatment wasn't met,
paid for some of them,
but I help him in his,
uh,
in all their situation and we're hoping
to get someone who will champion with
some money.
I had one patient offer a significant
amount and that'll help to cover about
100 patients.
So it'll cover everything for a year and
cost for treatment.
I meAn the blended to start from that we
developed about 10 years ago is $100 for
six months supply.
Well,
let's talk about doing something through
this show and let's talk about promoting
something like maybe through a
kickstarter or go fund me or something
like that at all.
Contribute to it and we'll try to get
other people to contribute to it and
let's just try to get something where
there's at least
a point of.
Have a starting point for a lot of
people.
It'd be great.
Let's do that on my end.
One thing you can,
anyone can reach out to me on twitter.
Matthew gosney to black dicks coming
your way soon.
Those send it off to going to be awful.
Just I'll send it right back.
What is it again?
Matthew gazani too.
Don't let me down folks.
you can uh,
send,
send me,
you know,
if you're a veteran and you just,
you're hesitant about this and you don't
get it,
you know,
you want to know more.
Contact me.
I also have my own kickstarter up right
now.
You can search it up.
It's called hidden wounds.
And what is this for?
It's a two part book I'm putting
together in the first half is about tbi,
tbi,
and just my experience of going through
it in the second half will be about ptsd
and my search to kind of deal with that,
which that's my journey right now is
going on that and figuring that out and
then once the book is done,
which I'm hoping by June,
2015,
a 25 percent will go into this nonprofit
organization that we got going
and when is american sniper coming out
and who's in it and give me the clinics
with directed film.
Right.
Clint eastwOod directed at bradley
cooper stars in it.
Bradley started out,
put it on 44 pounds.
He looks good.
His incredible.
Yeah.
Comes out christmas in a few places and
wide.
January 16th.
Beautiful.
Thank you guys.
Thank you very much.
Thank you jason.
Thank you matthew.
Thank you mark.
This was a,
I think this is a really important thing
to talk about and I think,
um,
you know,
you guys come in here and taking your
time and matthew especially expressing
your story and doing it so honest and
openly to huge,
huge for that.
Thank you.
Thank you everybody.
Anybody that's tuning in to this,
uh,
that is,
is benefiting from this.
Please.
One more time.
Go to the website.
Mr.
Gordon.
What is it?
Cheap
phoebe?
I medlegal if they google me and put tbi
in it,
it'll up first.
And uh,
to my friend mj buddy,
rob king,
Who,
uh,
I sent a video to yesterday.
I want to give a shout out to you
because this,
he's going through exactly what we're
talking about.
Thank you everybody.
We'll be back tomorrow with matt full
tron.
Love you.
See you soon.
Thank you.
Mad man.
He got mad.