Hello Freak bitches.
But I look at that the same way I kind
of look at music or the same way I look
at writing or comedy or anything.
So it's fascinating to me watching
someone go after something and,
and,
and put it together and make something
that is almost unfathomable take place,
whether it's a creation of an album,
whether it's a,
you know,
a comedy special,
whether it's a,
someone writes an amazing book.
I love when people get shit done.
Yeah.
I do too.
It's a beautiful thing.
Yeah.
Right.
Well,
as artists,
right?
Like,
does that,
like,
as,
as an artist,
does that inspire you when you see,
like if you go to see a great movie or
read a great book or something like
that,
does that inspire you to want to create?
Yeah.
It doesn't inspire me to create a write
a book.
Right,
right,
right.
But,
um,
I think I kind of know what my lane is
at this point.
Yeah.
You know,
I try and stay in it.
Yeah.
Um,
but yeah,
I mean definitely go see a movie or,
or,
or read,
uh,
you know,
and,
and it,
it'll get my creative juices flowing and
you know,
inspire me to be,
to just be better and try and
contribute,
you know what I mean?
Contributes something good or be
positive and make,
make myself feel something to make
somebody else feel something.
I Dunno.
It,
it does something to me.
Definitely.
It's hard to describe.
I was still can't describe what it is
that makes this creative thing,
um,
click or explain how I do what I do.
But
definitely seeing movies or hearing you
know,
here and um,
you know,
great musicians,
great guitar players,
you know,
the freak me out.
Oh Shit,
don't get too involved a little bit.
You know what I mean?
And I'm like,
well,
no hunger.
Yeah.
Though.
It's like,
okay,
I respect that.
Let me go get you hit on my game.
And yeah,
this guy was born in the 60s you know
what I mean?
Exactly what we're here to take over
yogas,
thousands of years old,
the balls,
the balls on this guy,
literally all tucked away.
And that little grape smuggler any
worse.
There was a guy in my class that used to
go there for a while.
He used to wear the crepe smuggler.
He was very sot nom.
He was very [inaudible] know,
hit a man bun to smugglers and a man
bun.
I want to beat you up in the parking
lot.
Oh,
totally.
Totally.
And I think the other women look at you
over there and your Nike workout stuff
and they're like,
all right,
he's,
he's fine.
They think so.
Yeah.
They're like,
thank you for not doing that.
I hope so.
I don't know.
The place I go to is very nice,
very nice people.
But again,
it's not like the hot young hard,
but I'm probably the best looking girl
in the class
a road.
It was a joke.
I couldn't help it.
That's not true either.
Some cute ones,
but the point being is that's not what
it is.
It's a,
you know,
but there is a sexual vibe there.
D I mean,
you're just there to do yoga,
but yet there is that kind of thing and
which is why I'm not too big a fan of
the classes.
The team you up where they want you to
partner up for this thing.
Yeah.
You ever have that?
No.
Oh,
like you stretch you out.
Yeah.
They're like,
I get a partner.
Get unhappy baby with your legs behind
with your partner pushed down on you and
you're like,
you know,
you're fired on this lady.
Don't what happens.
That'd be actually the smart board as a
married man.
That would be the smart man.
How much porn takes place in the Yoga
Student Yoga Studio where the yoga that
teacher says,
um,
I would like to review some poses with
you after class.
I'll give you some tips.
That'd be like,
if you were,
let's,
let's just be as politically correct
about this possible.
If you were single and the person
actually was into you and this all went
down according to this,
this,
that would be the greatest like fantasy
ever.
Like you're in that hot yoga class,
all hot and Sweaty,
and afterwards the teacher wants to fuck
God.
Damn.
She's like,
Tom,
I just really feel like your practice
could aid with just a little private one
on one instruction.
Yes,
sure,
sure.
The first,
we're going to start with a foot
massage.
Um,
okay.
Slide on your back.
Um,
all right.
Oh,
okay.
And she's rubbing your feet and lifting
your legs.
I'm just going to stretch your legs out
and she's rubbing the inside of your
thighs and you start moaning.
She moans back and the next thing you
know,
it's on Tom Papa.
Oh,
I'm gonna stay
[inaudible].
Okay.