The joe rogan experience.
And that's really what I'm doing at a
level that you can start in bed,
right?
So there's no more fucking,
excuse me,
fucking excuses.
And that's so tam important and it
gives,
people can feel sorry for themselves.
They can say they can't do it.
They don't have the energy there to beat
up.
That's bullshit.
There's always something you can do.
That's always something if you,
but if you give yourself that fucking
excuse,
that's the problem.
What I love about that video is if
anybody had an excuse,
it's that guy.
Absolutely that guy,
I mean two canes,
giant belly blown out,
knees blown out,
back veteran paratrooper,
guide guide me jumping out of fucking
airplanes over and over again.
Blows his body apart and you fixed it.
That and he fixed it.
He fixed,
I just literally like credible.
So what I sent him the food plant right
from,
from Fred Bucci is the ice cream,
the food plan because it's just regular
food.
But like what do you have the meeting
like chicken,
steak.
Let's,
let's,
let's finish your,
so you'll hear me say in my program over
and over and over and over and over
again.
Make the DDP,
why your own bike.
And I explained to Arthur when I called
him.
Well here's what happened.
So He um,
[inaudible] I sent him the food plan.
Let me just say,
and if he writes me back,
I think I can do it.
I'll give it a try.
You go crazy.
No,
I go,
hey,
awesome.
Keep me posted.
But he said four words or he wrote four
words.
I can do this.
I said,
give me your number right now.
And I called them on the fucker up.
If you say you can,
you say you can't,
you're right.
You know that you say you can or you say
you camp,
you're right.
Right.
Do you know said that originally who
Henry Ford is,
right?
Yeah.
And I always say,
what the fuck did he ever do?
You know,
But for when he said,
I can do it,
I said,
give me your number.
So I called them and I said,
Yo,
we talked for about an hour.
Two weeks later he calls me back.
The main thing I talked to him in in,
in that conversation,
which is again what positively going to
stop the war is all about as important
as the workout is as important as the
eating plan is 10% of the equation.
The 90% is right between your ears right
here,
that six inch piece of real estate,
the story you tell yourself and I said,
if you can really just get past that
story and start re telling yourself a
different story.
An example would be when I had,
when I went from my whole theme
induction speech in front of 20,000
people in millions of people on USA and
on the wwe network,
which is only nine 99 about a wife.
It's like a ribbed bottom line is,
is that I wasn't in the back going,
Oh God,
I hope I don't fuck this up.
what if I forget what was going to say?
Oh God,
this sucks.
When,
what if like what if I fuck up?
I wouldn't say.
Now I'm saying it's going to be best
thing I've ever done.
I'm going to blow people away and make
them laugh,
make them cry.
I'm going to inspire them.
And that was my inner voice.
I went out there,
did the best thing I've ever done,
like it's the best thing I've ever done.
But it's about that story that you tell
yourself when you get all this shit.
And that's why people listen to you
because they want,
they need to be reminded over and over
and over again.
You know,
the way you think about things is so
important.
It's so important.
It's almost more important than the
facts,
right?
The Way and the way this guy decided
that he was going to change his life,
that that video is so important to
people.
I mean,
if there's ever,
that's the best testimonial video you
ever going to say?
I'm running boldly with an l by my name,
right?
So I'm trying to change the Brian.
So it's a decent brand.
It's what I'm doing.
Are you putting the button on my stuff?
I'm always libertarian.
So I'm trying to,
to build the brand out to be a better
brand.
So if I win the brands better people,
we'll do that.
We'll raise my money.
There'll be a real third party.
I mean,
there'll be a third party in the United
States which will make better democrats
and better republicans will literally be
a better nation,
a better,
uh,
a politic we better in in America if I
actually win this damn thing.
But let's say I lose Sam wrong.
My things in my mind is a wrong whatever
people want,
great.
I lose.
Doesn't matter.
The bold ideas are still out there.
What you heard,
what your audience heard is still there.
Someone's going to pick this up.
Some wasn't a talk about it.
And if you're fine with that,
100% what?
Yes,
please.
I want to fix things I'm not concerned
with who gets the credit for it.
Let's fix it.
I want a better place to live.
This cutters in trouble.
Nielsen is the perfect example of,
of where we're going.
I don't want that to be the rest of this
nation.
We can fix,
steal.
All my stuff.
Please steal it all.
Awesome.
I hope you steal it.
I hope California copies me and does
everything I said it'd be amazing.
Please do that.
It'd be awesome,
but if people don't hear me,
if I don't get out there,
if I don't even debate stage and I don't
come in second or third,
then no one's going to hear me because
I'm going to be forgotten.
But if I come in second or tight third,
there'll be a microphone in my face for
the next two years and every time it's
out there I'll be saying stuff just like
this again and again and again and maybe
my education system isn't perfect,
but guess what?
Someone will figure out the right one.
It won't be just keep giving it money.
It won't be that.
It'll be something that'll actually
work.
It'd be something brand new and exciting
and get people to come back to our
state.
What I don't want is what's happening
now is kids get educated,
they leave,
they don't come back with the edge,
get someplace else and never come back.
It's the wrong answer.
I'm really into crafts from shit man.
I always have been.
I love handmade pool cues and this desk,
which is a handmade desk and I feel like
it's one of the things that I really
appreciate in this modern digital world.
And I also feel like unfortunately it
may be one of the things that slipping
away.
It definitely is slipping away.
I think with,
um,
you know,
with technology,
technology has been great for us and a
lot of different ways.
Like we couldn't be fucking talking into
a piece of metal and it's recorded on
the computer going through a wire flying
through the air.
Like it does a lot of great things.
But in doing all those great things,
it actually has taken us away from
really creating and working with our
hands.
And so like,
you know,
even this whole like a farm to table
movement where people even growing their
own vegetables,
you've got your own chickens,
they're,
they're laying eggs for you.
Like knowing where this stuff is coming
from,
having like firsthand contact with that.
Um,
just having that relationship in general
with it brings so much more value to the
overall experience of eating those eggs
are using that knife or sitting at this
fucking table right here
and it seems like a fairly recent
movement in that direction.
Right?
Like it feels like things got so digital
that people are like,
whoa,
Whoa,
whoa.
What the facebook and the fucking
instagram I want to I I,
you know,
I want a wood table.
Yeah.
I want to saw this bitch myself.
Your hands on it.
Yeah.
I don't want it to be fantastic.
I want real stuff.
And there's something about handmade
things,
whether it's a handmade pair of boots
are handmade bag like this.
Like there's something about things that
are made by hand that people get at like
a deep appreciation of,
for sure.
For sure.
Well,
and I think it,
I think it also kind of goes back,
like I was saying,
like as technology has advanced,
we've kind of grown away from these kind
of what's considered like blue collar
work and craftsmanship kind of work.
But I think people really are driven by
a sense of achievement and when you're
doing data entry that literally millions
of people fucking monkeys can be trained
to do.
Not to like diminish anything that
anybody's doing,
but literally like
to be able to go into a craft and to and
had a hands on experience is very,
very,
very different in that sense of
achievement.
Even when somebody comes out of
something and maybe I taught a class on
how to make a knife and it looks like a
fucking Turd,
they're going to think it looks like the
most beautiful fucking knife they've
ever seen in their life because their
hands and their creativity touched their
energy,
their,
their sweat and pop.
Probably some of their blood is put into
creating that thing and that brings that
much more value to it.
Like,
like I was,
like I was saying earlier,
you could get kids to believe in
anything.
You get brain.
I could,
I could get my son into Satan easily.
He'd be all in all about Lucifer.
Boom.
I got them into the Brown kids,
you know?
Yeah,
totally.
He's so into the dodgers because his
grandpa isn't at the dodgers,
so he's all about the dodgers.
And I got them into the browns.
He's all in the browns now too,
because I could get them into anything.
So I sat them down and I say,
you are,
I'm going to sit you down and I'm going
to show you the master of the nunchucks.
And it's Bruce Lee.
He's number one dude.
He's the guy.
He's the greatest martial artist of all
time.
I broke them and I sat him down and put
them in front of the TV to,
they should have filmed this.
I did you fill the whole thing?
You filmed you saying it to him?
No,
I didn't film that,
but I filmed,
I filmed him watching Bruce Lee.
Um,
uh,
first I showed him the greatest nunchuck
scenes of all time with Bruce Lee that
you can go to youtube and you can get
there.
There's compilations.
They put together the one from the stuff
in end of the drag and the stuff in a
Chinese connection,
uh,
a way of the dragon or return of the
Dragon.
And,
uh,
so I sat him down and go,
I'm going to blitz them with this shit.
I'm going to make sure that whenever he
thinks about fucking nun chucks,
he knows that Bruce Lee's the master.
Right?
So he's just completely blown away.
Then after I showed him all the
nunchucks scenes with,
I sat him down and I want to show him
the greatest fights of all time.
Bruce Lee versus Chuck fucking norris
come on that.
So I just wanted to leave that just in
his DNA and I fell on that.
I filmed him watching a chuck Norris and
Bruce Lee,
and he always wants to know he,
he loves,
he loves Bruce Lee instantly and he,
he,
he needs to know who wins the fight.
So if I,
daddy does Bruce Lee,
when I go,
he always wins.
Sunny always wins.
And,
but my natural reaction,
cause he,
he's constantly asking questions.
He's constantly,
does he win?
My natural reaction would be just watch,
watch you gotta watch this because it's
going to be sweeter.
If you watch it and you go through the
ups and downs and he goes,
no,
Daddy,
you need to tell me now.
And I go,
no,
you're gonna like it more if you just
watch it,
you got no daddy.
This Bruce Lee,
when he wants to fucking know,
he don't want to be disappointed.
Yeah.
So he got years old.
He got completely blown away.
So a week later,
a week later,
I got today you're going to watch the
greatest martial arts movie of all time.
Enter the Dragon.
Cause it's Bruce Lee Dad,
isn't it?
I go,
yes,
it's
the real me.
Maybe chimpanzee.
Yeah.
That was gonna be like some Disney
thing.
I was like,
holy cow.
What movie was at?
It's literally called chimpanzee.
Whom is it?
A documentary?
Yeah.
It's kind of like a documentary.
I was like,
damn,
I'm,
I mean,
they're mean.
Yeah,
they're cool.
Yeah.
They're there.
They're calculated.
Yeah.
They sneak up on each other and like,
I didn't realize chimps did calculator.
Cruelty.
Yeah.
How's pretty,
ah,
I left that meeting thinking,
Whoa,
this is dark.
Right.
Well,
we know better because we've advanced,
but if we hadn't,
we'd be like,
man,
I don't want to fucking live in a house.
I like the champ ways,
bro.
Chimp ways to go.
This is it man.
Chimp life.
So I'm,
I now,
but we in a way to the AI might be like
those chimps.
We like these stupid Fox launching
missiles out of drones and shooting each
other underwater.
Like we're crazy.
We got torpedoes,
submarines and fucking airplanes.
It drop nuclear bombs indiscriminately
on cities were assholes.
Yeah.
They might go,
why are they doing this?
It might like look at our politics and
look at what we do in terms of our,
our,
our food system.
What,
what kind of food we forced down each
other's throats.
And they might
go this,
these people are crazy.
Didn't even look out for themselves.
I don't know.
I'm like,
how much do we think about chimps?
Not much.
Very little.
It's like,
these chimps are at war.
He's like,
look,
it's like groups of chimps just attack
each other and they kill each other.
They torture each other.
That's pretty bad.
Um,
the hunt monkeys,
uh,
there,
but like,
this is probably the most,
but you know,
I mean,
when's the last time you talked about
chimps?
Let me,
yeah,
all the time you do talking to the
carwash podcast,
dude,
that's talking about chimps episode.
People are laughing right now.
Okay.