Joe rogan experience podcast.
Why can't,
why can't that work?
It was.
The computer is restarted in it.
Every time this computer restarts,
all the sounds fucked up on it.
We will soon be free of this
technological nightmare and into a new
one.
And Gentlemen,
we've got to try castor coming.
We tried to order the Sony thing,
but it didn't work for us.
It just wasn't for streaming.
It wasn't the right piece of equipment.
So we're getting a tri caster,
but John headphone don't give a fuck
about that.
Ladies and gentlemen,
John have fraud comic standing.
Hilarious comedian.
It's been awhile.
It's been awhile since I've been on
here.
It's been a while since I see you.
First Time I saw you at the store.
So we haven't seen each other in two
years.
Three?
Yeah.
Yeah,
because I had to do that thing where you
tax them,
like who?
I don't even know what I mean.
And then like all my famous friends,
I never put their names in my phone as
their real names.
Who am I?
I would probably,
I think probably don't tell me because
then yeah.
Yeah.
So just just in case,
not that I'm,
I'm like,
but just in case you lose your phone,
like I was wondering like really famous
people who have famous friends like
Paris Hilton loses their phone all the
time and then two people hack into it
and get Lindsey Lohan summer.
I mean it's kind of hard to hack into an
iphone unless it's connected to the
cloud.
Right.
Like if they got ahold of it,
probably be pretty difficult.
Crack your pass code.
They actually I think have programs I
teach,
they're just logging in and I'd like
taxi drivers I think do it and it turns
off all the tracking and then they
resell it like immediately.
Really?
Yeah.
Because I've had,
I've had the cloud on my girlfriend's
phone and she left it in a car and like
in five minutes it was already disabled.
It never turned back on.
Yeah.
Well the thing.
I bet you're right because the thing is
they have a lot of places that buy cell
phones now.
Yeah.
I don't know if they ask like,
is this yours?
I don't know.
But uh,
I've seen places that,
by cell phone.
Have you ever sold an old cell phone?
No,
because I'm paranoid because I know you
can just take anything off a phone like
that.
Like I could take her phone even though
you've deleted it and even reused it for
six months.
I could still take stuff off of there
for like two years ago.
Santana,
I keep mine.
But then I was thinking I'm going to do
something with it.
Like I have every version of the IPAD.
I'm like,
well I'm just going to use this for my
home security camera.
Like,
and it never,
this ipad it's only gonna be for pre
show music and then I leave it at a club
and I used to try to do that too.
But I felt like I used to bring an
actual ipod.
I was oil.
I want to have an ipod is by itself.
You don't just want to have my phone,
but now that's ridiculous because
you're,
the new phones have 128 gigs.
Yeah,
come on.
You're not going to use all that.
If you do,
you're an asshole.
What's going on on your phone?
Yeah.
Movies on there.
Get the whole whole world plan on your
phone.
John headphone.
So yeah,
so it's been a year and somebody just
tweeted to,
uh,
they asked him.
Now I'm a little bit afraid because I
haven't seen you in so long.
And then you invited me to be on a
podcast.
People were worried on twitter that you
were going to give me an intervention
and that tells me I should quit comedy.
I would never do guys.
You're hilarious.
Standup comedian.
This is,
trust me.
I took that on my own.
He's joking around about a conversation
that we had with Brendan Shabazz.
It was intense.
I still feel like shit feel like shit
today.
I felt like shit while we're doing it.
There was um,
Brendan last.
He got beat up and stopped by this guy.
Travis Browne is one of the best in the
world.
And you wanted to talk about it on the
air.
You know,
I wanted to talk about what we felt like
on the earn and I asked him if he short.
He was like,
yeah,
absolutely.
I want,
I want to get it out there,
I want to get it out there.
I want to hear exactly what you really
think.
And I mean,
I'm sure what he thought I would think
and what I did think was different,
you know,
and then as we were talking I kind of
realized like I feel like his
perceptions of where he's at and the
dangers of what has happened to him and
the reality of where he's at and the
dangers of what have happened to them
were off.
And some people feel like I should have
done that conversation off the air.
And I feel like I probably agree with
you.
Um,
you know,
all,
all things said and done.
The only good thing about having it on
the air is that other fighters can hear
this and they can,
um,
they can form a,
I want to say educated opinion because
I'm definitely not a doctor or a
scientist or even smart.
But I know a lot of information about
chronic brain damage from seeing it,
from talking to people who have it,
from talking to doctors who are experts
on it too.
And to know that I don't see a lot of
people that are at the front of the
tunnel waving a light in mma saying,
hey,
you know,
you guys got to slow the fuck down.
We don't know what's up here.
And I think that that's the case with a
chronic brain damage.
Nfl is just dealing with now these
players from the seventies and eighties
and the nineties and even the two
thousands that are just fucked up.
Now.
Look in the Buckeye player that just
committed suicide a couple weeks ago
from looking at him,
you know,
look at.
There's just a long list of players.
I watched some guy get k Oh the other
day.
Oh my goodness.
Somebody sent it to me on twitter.
It was a vine of these two football
parents colliding helmets.
They just see that one.
Jeremy,
you're j.
you're fucking football freak.
Jamie.
Probably.
He'd probably want him.
It's fantasy football.
Street stakes.
Yeah.
Was I was reading from A.
Somebody tweeted about it and then I
went to.
I don't even know what the website was.
And then had tweet about like,
why you were talking.
And,
and so I just read the tweets like
somebody was paraphrasing what you were
saying and without even really known the
story,
all I got out of it was you wanted him
to just be careful with,
with getting smacked in the head because
that's not gonna work out.
Well,
it's not that I wanted them to be
careful.
I'm one of them to consider ending it
because I know he's going to end it.
He wanted,
it ended.
He was talking before this fight about
like when he's going to get out after
the fight.
He talked about two years.
So they had a 42 year idea,
you know,
and the reality of getting head trauma
is cumulative and that guys who get
knocked out a few times,
it becomes easier for them to get
knocked out again.
And the damage is all compounding.
You're waiting.
It's like buying a bunch of shit on
credit and you're waiting for the bill
to come and you've,
you're driving around this nice car and
you have this cool watch.
But the reality is you owe a fuck load
of money.
You're going to have to work your dick
off to pay that shit.
You're not thinking about that right
now.
Well,
the chronic brain damage things,
a debt that you can never pay,
like you're putting damage on your
brain.
It doesn't manifest itself immediately.
Always.
It takes a while.
A lot of these players were fine when
they retired and then you've seen them
like Jim Mcmahon,
the sports illustrated article on,
Oh dude,
it's terrifying.
When I was a kid,
I didn't know shit about football,
but I don't know who Jim Mcmahon was.
He was goddamn legendary quarterback,
you know him and the bears and that
whole,
you know the,
the superbowl shuffle and no one knew
who those guys were.
He's Foxville now.
You know,
he,
he will find himself in the middle of
his house not knowing how he got there.
He's just looking for his keys.
Are Looking for what,
what?
He doesn't know where he was going to
do.
He forgets things all the time.
You know,
I was talking to Brian Stan,
we were text message and back and forth
today and he was talking about people
that he knows that got it from being
soldiers from blasts and he's like,
it's horrible.
It's horrible.
Like these guys,
they,
they can't remember anything.
They have no energy.
They're depressed all the time.
It's not everybody and it's not.
I mean there's.
The thing about fighting is you never
know when it's too late.
It's like some guys can get knocked out
once and go on from that to have great
careers.
Some guys can get knocked out a couple
of times,
but they're still in their bunny.
They're just fighting beasts.
Like perfect example.
That is Michael Bisping gets knocked out
by Dan Henderson,
comes back,
very successful,
gets knocked out by Vito Belfort,
comes back after that beats the shit out
of Kung lean,
one of the best fights of his career.
You know,
like he's,
he's been Kao to a couple of times,
but it's only because he's fighting the
elite of the elite at the top of the
level and you know,
he's just smudge it off.
That's it.
I mean,
Michael Bisping is one of the best in
the fucking world,
but I felt like we shop.
I was,
I was seeing that it was going to happen
more often and um,
I,
I fucking loved that dude.
He is a great guy.
I mean,
Brendan Schaub,
he's a really interesting character
because he's this big,
hulking dude,
but he's a sweetheart.
He's like the nicest guy.
He jokes around about how he's like a,
a dolphin and a shark outfit on the
outside,
but he's a dolphin on the inside.
He's hilarious.
He's really honest.
He's like really honest about everything
except like is fighting ability,
I think is fighting ability or his
position.
He's got a slightly elevated sense,
but that's why he's a bad motherfucker.
You have to have this sense that's
almost distorted in order to be a
fighter in the first place because when
you first started out,
how could you imagine ever getting to a
championship level when you first
started out and you're getting hit every
time you move forward and getting taken
down every time someone wants you to.
It's,
it's weird,
you know,
it takes a long time.
So you have to have like almost this
like crazed idea of yourself to be a
fighter in the first place.
It's just extreme confidence and you
know he's got that for sure.
And there's a lot of fighters to have
that.
It's great when you're winning,
when you're winning that that extreme
confidence is awesome because that
extreme confidence like gives you like a
boost over some other people who don't
have that.
You might have like a psychological
boost.
Maybe it's in training,
maybe it's in how confident you feel
before the fight so you don't get as
nervous as he does.
There's all sorts of variables,
but when you start losing,
that's when that can be a motherfucker
because that thing doesn't want to see
the truth.
That ego is a tricky motherfucker
because it can help you and a lot of
ways they can push you to success,
but it can also fuck you up where you're
not seeing yourself the way you should.
You can't like you.
You don't see yourself in a,
in a negative way.
You don't allow it in so you don't look
at the flaws.
You don't look at like.
Especially true in martial arts,
which is a hyper critical,
you're,
you have to be extremely self critical
to be a competitive martial artists
because the stakes are so high.
You're getting kicked in.
The face is one of the worst steaks and
all of sports.
The possibility to this guide,
I'll say his name because I fucked it up
during the broadcast,
we're seeing salmon at some on police is
the correct pronunciation.
He won this weekend with this fucking
destruction of the head kick.
He switched head kick the student the
face and boom,
the lights go out and the guy went
stiff.
It was one of those classic like worst
case scenario,
the worst thing that can happen to you
in the octagon,
and it was just a beautiful technique.
They've just shuffled that front leg and
Boehm Shin to the head,
you know that is the stakes.
So you have to be so fucking critical
about your technique,
about your conditioning,
about your dedication,
your psychological outlook on fighting,
all those things you have.
Keep those in a row.
It's so fucking dangerous.
If you don't,
and when you start,
if you lose and you know,
you start looking at yourself in a
delusional way,
it can hamper your ability to work on
all those areas they can hit like
anytime you have a delusional
perspective and introspective outlook,
that's just not accurate.
You're not doing yourself a favor like
you need someone else to give you
advice.
You know what I'm saying?
Like you not see you're selling,
you're not seeing like things that you
can correct and when you're in that
state,
as a martial artist it becomes very
dangerous and it's,
it's common to get to for fighters
because being a fighter's extremely
nerve wracking,
you know,
I am barely qualified to speak of it
because I only did taekwondo tournaments
and some kickboxing,
but I just remember competing and being
scared out of my fucking mind.
I was a kid,
you know,
it was 19 or 21 actually when I retired
in between 18 and 21.
We're all the really dangerous fights
like national level fights.
But you,
you,
you experienced these extreme fears and
extreme highs and extreme lows.
Like when you win,
it's the greatest feeling in the world
for these guys.
Like you see guys that win like Johnny
Hendrix,
when he won the title drops down.
He's just fucking.
You see this rush of joy that goes
through him that you and I are never
going to experience.
I've never experienced that in a
taekwondo tournament because it was.
It didn't mean as much.
That's what these guys are doing is like
this insane top of the mountain high.
And so when you get to that top of the
mountain high,
the guys who have had those big wins,
like Brendan's had some big wins.
He knocked out Mirko Cro cop who's like
a legendary cancer.
Mirko was legendary.
I mean he's a.
He was like one of the best kick boxers
ever to enter into the glory days of
pride.
You know,
when Mirko Mirko has like a head kick
Kao highlight reel,
that's like one of the greatest of all
times.
But if anything,
the Mirko Cro,
cop fight should prove my point to
Brendan because if Mirko Cro cop and he
fought back when Mirko Cro,
cop one,
the pride heavyweight Grand Prix,
that would have been a completely
fucking different fight.
That was a different guy back then.
It was just a different guy and
everybody knows it.
He fought Gonzaga in the UFC.
He fought a 80 Sanchez first beat him
and they fought Gonzaga and he got cro
copped essentially.
He got head kicked by Gonzaga,
who's a very strong guy.
Gonzaga's like,
oh,
he walks onto the stage like when they
have to weigh in on Zaga sounds
different than everybody else.
Sounds like it's made out of stone.
Just a big,
powerful fucking dude.
Gonzaga is a beast.
Gonzaga correct.
One off the side of his head.
And from then on,
man,
he just wasn't the same guy.
I think those two fights,
like in the UFC,
he was never the same.
His first two fights.
He had some good fights in UFC.
He was never the same as.
He wasn't pride.
You think a lot of fighters like stick
it out longer than they should because
there's no fallback.
There's like,
okay,
I'm a fighter.
I,
I don't.
I mean those guys have skills,
but like I don't have any like me as a
comic.
If I ever decided I'm not going to be a
comic,
I have zero other skills.
There's almost nothing that,
that I know how to do.
Yeah.
I even said when I was trying to like
make an analogy,
I made a bad one.
I even said if I was a comedian,
you know,
and I was fucking terrible.
I would want everybody to tell me that I
should stop if there's something that
happened to me and I wasn't funny
anymore,
but I'll still going onstage.
I would want someone to come and tell
me.
That's a terrible analogy.
Okay.
I was just looking for something and
after I said I was like,
that's not good.
Obviously being a comedian,
it doesn't cause brain damage if you
just suck at something,
you know the difference between sucking
at fighting and I shouldn't even use the
term sucking.
Being unsuccessful at fighting and being
unsuccessful at like writing a book.
If you write a book and it sucks,
everybody goes through,
your book sucks,
but it doesn't,
it doesn't give you a concussion,
you know,
and it doesn't give you concussions and
training that you kind of try to ignore,
you know,
dudes land on your fucking head and
training,
you know,
even in grappling guys collide,
collide heads all the time and these are
all,
you know,
these are all points against your brain.
Every one of them points against your
brain.
Obviously comedy doesn't have that.
If you think I suck,
that's,
I feel bad,
but it doesn't hurt me.
You know,
he had been losing fights lately.
Well,
he had a real bad fight with her lawsky.
It was like it was real clumsy and just
look like both of them were just way out
of sync and are all.
Obviously it was super nervous because
it was his first fight back in the UFC.
And then our last,
he subsequent performance,
he fought big foot Silva and looked
fucking great.
Knocked him out in the first round and
looked smooth,
so like he got over his jitters for his
second fight back because he had been
out for eight years.
Our last was the UFC heavyweight champ
at one point.
It's just Brendan looked super obvious
like he was like telegraphing is shot.
I was worried about them and I'm also
worried about him because he.
Before that he got knocked out by Ben
Rothwell and then he beat,
what's his name?
Lefarge Johnson,
who's a beast of our Johnson's fucking
scary.
He's a vicious puncher.
Beat Lavar by taking them down and just
holding them down.
That's basically how he won that fight
and even kind of said like,
Hey,
I'm not standing with that fucking guy.
Which is very intelligent of was a good
win for them.
Fought Matt Mitrione and condom and it
darce choke and put them to sleep,
which is a big one.
That was huge.
What I worry about is not those fights.
What I worry about is a fights where we
get hit with Ben Rothwell hit him.
Ben Rothwell hit him with one left so I
can just shut the lights out.
His body dropped and Roth was on top of
him dropping bombs know,
and then he talked about it on the
podcast.
He was saying that he actually got hurt
before that in training sparring with
Shane Carwyn.
Shane Carwood apparently heard I'm
really bad with a punch.
So you have to factor in.
How many times did he sparely Shane car
when my mind starts going,
hmm,
you're probably spawn with Shane Carwyn
once a week.
At least.
Shane car one is a mother fucker.
You want to talk about a dude who's
built for war.
I've met a lot of like freak athletes in
the UFC.
Like John Jones,
a freak athlete.
Daniel cormier has world class wrestler.
I met a lot of freaks,
but
you know,
if you,
if you think about like elite level
fighters and elite elite level athletes,
you know,
there's,
there's so many of them that are so
fucking good that it becomes,
you know,
it becomes a matter of whether or not
you want to be the kind of guy who loses
five or six fights in a row or whether
or not you want to take those five or
six fights back now.
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
I want to.
I just think it.
I think it's,
it's scary that you're concerned with a
friend because you work in the business
and it's interesting to see where this
new information comes in,
how danger it is,
how you can sit there and even be
friends with anybody but
without.
It can be friends with a man because you
can take a certain amount of punches.
Just gotTa know when to get out.
Your friends got to know to let you out.
What I was saying about freaks,
man,
Shane Carwyn,
St Darwin has fists that I'm not
shitting you.
They look like.
See that Marshall amp over there?
That's like Shane Carlin's fist.
They're the most ridiculous thing I've
ever seen in my life.
He had like four or five xl gloves,
like it was always a big thing that
brock lesnar had these giant fists until
he fought Carwyn.
Like Carlin actually had bigger fist and
lesnar.
I mean,
you're talking about things that don't
even make sense.
It's like his.
His body structure is so odd.
He came into Jujitsu once.
I was training at a mall Easton's place
in Boulder,
Colorado.
It's the best Jujitsu in Colorado in a
mall has this beautiful gym where
everybody's rolling,
we're in class and this guy walks in and
I go,
that's not even a fucking person.
Like,
what is that?
Right?
This guys got like a gene,
like a,
like a pair of jeans on and a like a tee
shirt.
You probably,
it's probably like a double xl,
but he's built like a fucking superhero.
Yeah.
So then I realized it's Corwin.
He don't realize how fucking big car
when is until you see him out with
regular people in a normal sort,
almost like everybody else has just
walking around their normal clothes and
then this guy walks in and it doesn't
even look like he's a fucking human.
Yeah,
I mean just go villa.
And that guy was sparring with Brendan
on a regular basis.
He hits
he,
he knocked Gabriel Gonzaga dead with a
punch from like seven,
eight inches away.
Just just,
just crank,
boom.
I mean,
he was a destroyer and so shane was
getting in sparring sessions on a
regular basis with Brendan.
So he's getting hit all the time.
There's Shankar wins.
Fists are on the right.
And Brock Lesnar's are on the left.
Yeah.
What is that?
He's a God damn gorilla.
He's a goddamn shaved down white
gorilla.
He could hold that iphone plus that
would have been a,
he would have been a champion.
You know,
he had a few issues.
One of them like back issues from um,
all of his years of playing football.
He had some serious like,
like stingers and discs issues and stuff
like that.
Those guys are just colliding into each
other,
big giant dudes that size colliding into
each other,
but if he wasn't,
if he just went straight to mma,
wrestling and mma,
I think that dude would have been a
world champion.
He was athletic freak because she was so
fucking strong,
you know,
it's just like he was one of those dudes
like you couldn't let him hit you if he
hit you.
He fought Frank Mir and it was one of
the most brutal beat downs I've ever
seen in all my years because the way he
did it,
he muscled Frank Mir up against the
cage,
got him in like a collar tie or maybe a,
maybe a tight overtook.
I don't remember which one it was.
And then he starts blasting them with
left upper cut.
It's just boom,
boom,
and you could see me or stock can't get
out and can't take these shots.
And he's just.
He just sprinted at him,
just sprint out on him with bombs and
the mirror went down and they finished
them off on the ground and that was a
brutal,
brutal knockout.
So Brendan was sparring with that guy on
a regular basis.
So it's not as fight.
I only got hit,
I got hit maybe twice in my life where
like I thought I was done with like
stars in that weird buzzing sound that
happens.
One was a,
I've told this story before,
Danny bonaduce and then the other was a
Stephan Bonner.
This was years and years ago.
We were sparring for some reason or he
was sparring with Stephan Bonner.
He was at.
I don't remember the thing.
We were at Krav Maga.
He was there,
I think it was training for a movie or
something and some of the guys,
the stunt guys were so anyway,
so we,
we started sparring and then he gets
into the sparring.
So I'm thinking oh he's probably just
wants to know how to fight.
So I've been kind of bounced around.
Next thing I know I just heard ringing
and whatever.
He kicked me in the thigh that not like
to try to like we were sparring so he
wasn't trying to full blast,
you know,
whatever is 30 percent is is my 150
percent with the 40 year olds I box,
you know what I mean?
So it was nothing to do with him,
but that was the first time in
everything was ringing and I'm like Oh
God,
that was once.
It's too many look and imagine
that over 12 years and just not just
those like football injuries to.
Brendan also played football I believe
college and high school and you know,
he was a,
he was a fucking,
he still is a really good athlete and
that's why he's become a good fighter.
But the difference between a good
fighter,
I mean he's a very good fighter,
but the difference between that and the
top of the heap guys,
there's a leak,
there's a leap,
but there's a bridge that you have to
cross.
Could you cross that bridge physically?
You never.
I mean he's only 30 years old if he
became like super dedicated and went to
a very strict Moitai camp.
And learned like really wicked,
wicked,
stand up and didn't fight for it.
But how do you feed yourself when you're
doing that?
You know when you're a pro athlete.
That would be really.
If he did that though,
if he just stopped only training and
competing for fights and I know he works
on a skills as well,
but if you just completely dedicated
himself to the scariest part,
which is the kickboxing,
that's the scariest shit.
That's the shit that everybody should.
If you're,
if you're,
if you're coming into it with nothing,
that's a shit you should almost
concentrate on the most because it's the
most dangerous.
If you don't have it good defensively.
Like if you get submitted,
it's bad.
You know you can break your arm for
sure.
You can get choked out,
but they can fix your fucking arm.
You get too many knees to the head from
a guy like alister over him.
You know you don't.
You don't want that.
You know the fighting is all about
mitigating damage.
It's all about inflicting as much as you
can,
but mitigating as much as you can.
And one of the best ways to mitigate
damage is technical proficiency and
that's something that people don't think
about.
They want to think about strength and
conditioning.
They want to think about running up
hills.
The most important thing is technical
proficiency.
It's the most important thing by far.
And there's some guys that unfortunately
for them,
they come into striking late in life,
like some guys come into striking and
they have a background long background
of wrestling and so they're.
They're not used to jumping forward and
throwing combinations and footwork and
drills and it's alien to them.
For whatever reason,
their body doesn't adapt to it.
You see a lot with white wrestlers.
Sorry,
white guys.
But it's true.
There's a lot of white wrestlers that
for whatever reason,
there's just slow with their punches.
There's some guys that excel like it.
Jake ellenberger,
obviously Johnny Hendricks,
obviously those guys started out as
amateur wrestlers,
but learned along the way to blast power
punches.
But some guys never do.
You know,
there's guys like Ben Astron who I think
is one of the best hundred 70 pounders
in the world.
He's a wicked wrestler.
But his stand up is just really to close
the gap.
It's just to close the gap and then he
gets in on you and you're fucked.
He's just too good.
He just.
His wrestling is so much better than
everybody else's.
He just,
when he gets in on you,
it's Foxville,
right?
So his thing is all just about getting
it on you,
but,
but the,
but starting out with a deficit in
strikings,
the most dangerous because if you're one
of those guys that doesn't have that
fast twitch body,
like a tyron woodley body or Hector
Lombard body,
but you started off as a Grandpa,
but you can pick up the strike and
really quickly if you don't have that
kind
of body and you don't have that kind of
coaching and you know,
have that kind of training and the gym
with her going over technique with you
with a fine tooth comb.
It's a fucking dangerous aspect of
fighting.
It's the most dangerous aspect is the
one thing that you don't want to suck
out.
The one thing that you don't want to
fail at is striking.
And if you fail at wrestling and you
didn't just get taken down,
you know,
it's not good,
but it's a little bit better than
getting fucking wheel kicked in the
head.
I was good at striking.
My problem was,
is I stopped striking about five inches
away from your face,
so that's not good.
So I could never figure out how to get.
That was my thing.
I,
I'd always throw everything and you can
literally just stick your face out and I
wouldn't hit you because I would never.
I was afraid to always take that,
you know.
Then I'm like,
what am I doing?
I'm doing this.
Well,
we talked about it before when you were
sparring in class.
I was like,
how far?
Like you gotta be careful.
You told me that somebody had grabbed
your foot,
you threw a kick that grab your foot,
held onto it and knocked you out.
Yep.
And I was like,
come on man,
you can't be doing that kind of spark.
I used to bring my box,
he stuff on the road and then I go to a
bar,
you know,
a boxing.
I get a trainer for the day,
this is back when I was.
I would wake up,
but I.
I would go and do that and then sure
enough they'd always say,
do you feel like sparring?
Keep in mind,
this was 10 years ago when I'm like,
yeah,
let's.
And then with defined out your comedian
or whatever.
Then they just want to kill you.
It's a better story for them to knock
you off.
Then too lightly spar just so people get
their sweat on you.
Right?
Yeah.
That's hilarious.
So,
so I stopped doing that.
Some people are rude with them and they
don't think it's a big deal to Knoxville
me the fuck out.
So rude.
It's like,
you know,
it's fucking.
You could really damaged someone's head
and I know that's the point of fighting
and in a way it makes me a hypocrite.
I'm fully aware of that because I do
enjoy fighting.
I love watching it.
I'm not going to not watch it.
I just.
I'm a big fan of brandon as a human
being and Brendan Schaub is a guy with
options.
He could do other things.
Brendan can.
He'd go on and people from your pod,
like I only know him from the podcast.
I didn't really even know him as a
fighter,
you know,
they got money when he's a guest here.
He was always super entertaining to me.
He is always funny,
dude.
Yeah,
yeah.
He's a funny dude and he's a.
he's a really good dude and I think a
lot of people don't understand him
because of some of the hype surrounding
some of his fights.
He would talk a lot of trash,
like he talked about trust in this fight
and people get mad at him for that and
they think he's that guy,
you know,
they'd get mad at them for maybe over
assessing his possibilities being a
champion,
but he's a fucking great dude.
He really is.
He could do anything.
He,
the dedication that led him to go from
football to mma,
he could go from MMA to having like a
super podcast and career,
which is a real option now.
I mean,
even better and better.
Where's the fucking John Hef Rancho.
You know what?
I had one for like a second.
You and repad a show for me and her ipad
to show and then stopped doing it and
then I stopped for a long time and then
I started one called the state.
I'm in a and I was like,
I'm going to talk about what,
where I'm at physically and mentally
that'll be that way.
I've seen,
you know,
so I don't have to figure out.
That's a good idea.
And then.
So I had like Martha Quinn on and I,
you know,
I had.
Did you interview her after she got out
of jail?
Martha Quinn,
the MTV Vj.
Thinking of Martha Stewart.
Martha.
So it started off really,
really good.
And then I think it's been,
I think I'm up until a month and a half
and I haven't recorded one.
So mark don't know how to do it by
myself.
Like how bill does this podcast with
just him?
That's his art that I don't know.
His new special.
So good.
It's really funny man.
It's so him.
It's like the,
in my opinion,
the best one as far as capturing him
doing like a regular set.
He so loose up there.
That's where like I,
I know I have three specials and I'm
going to get ready to shoot my fourth.
I haven't done a special yet that I
would go,
yeah,
that's how I am.
If you come and see me alive.
Who's the closest for me?
This last one's the closest.
And you did it in Denver at the downtown
or the comedy works downtown?
Yeah,
the little one.
There was 250 seats and stuff.
I've recorded two cds there.
It's the best.
It's one of the.
I mean there's no the best club in the
country because there's a few clubs like
that,
like there's helium and Portland.
You know,
there's a,
there's the element,
helium and Philly,
that's another one.
The comedy works.
Original Room.
It's like one of the all time great
rooms.
There's a bunch of those.
There's a bunch of foam.
That fucking place in Utah is really
good.
Man.
Wiseguys.
Oh yeah.
Oh my goodness.
Utah Salt Lake City is filled with
really fucking cool people.
That was weird.
Like I figured we're going to go to Salt
Lake City.
Everyone's gonna have their fucking
pants pulled up to the rib cage is going
to be very weird.
They're all gonna,
have the straight and we met a few of
them.
Like when I got there I met some lady in
the elevator and it was talking about it
on stage because you could tell just by
how friendly she was and she was a
mormon,
like shoes.
Either that or she was looking for Dick
and she wasn't looking for deck,
so she was a mormon.
She was like a mom and we got in the
elevator with her and she was just like,
hello,
where are you from?
How's everybody?
How's,
how are you today?
Right.
There's this weird like as far as
Cultco,
Mormons are some of the coolest
motherfuckers.
They're like,
Jen,
they don't fuck with people.
They're gen generally.
Pretty friendly though.
It's like a really good call.
Yeah.
I've met her many,
many moons ago.
Met a stripper who was Mormon,
was the whole thing.
Oh my goodness.
Like that's a mess.
And then she got kicked out of being
Mormon.
Know that club that I worked at this
year that I've ever been to Lexington,
Lexington,
off-broadway,
Kentucky.
I used to do the Improv there,
right.
So this place I believe it's like,
it's off Broadway.
It's in like a strip mall,
but the club's been there forever and
it's one of those ones when you go and
you see the head shots,
but they're from dudes from the
eighties,
you know,
you see all that.
And then so in the place list lung
shitty.
So in my brain I'm like,
oh,
okay.
It's give me one of those weeks every
show.
It took me till show to,
to figure out why the audiences were so
bad ass.
They don't serve food or nothing.
So it was when.
So you're taking out the element of
people eating steak and mashed potatoes.
It's terrible.
It was terrible for comedy,
which is still really fun.
I never would have thought like great
shows.
Nobody healthily or nothing.
I know it's,
it's nice for people because they can
get like a dinner and a show in at the
same time.
It's good for them,
but like for the show itself,
the overall performance,
like sometimes you're,
you're looking down at the crowd and
they were literally looking sideways,
like everybody's looking sideways and
they're eating meals and you're doing
standups like you're doing stand up in a
restaurant and this.
That's fucking weird,
man.
You are dinner,
whatever.
This past week I'm doing my stuff and
I'm like,
why did I lose half the room?
And then you see two waitstaff with
pieces of cake,
but they had like 20 pieces.
So they're passing out cake to everybody
at a birthday party or something.
Yeah,
like the guy.
But if you're going to eat cake,
you're not gonna pay attention.
Anytime cake runs around is usually when
the focus goes onto the cake no matter
no matter what.
So it was Kinda.
That's the one benefit of doing a
theater because you're doing a theater.
They have a bar in the very back.
You had to go through the doors to get
to the bar and no,
there's no way.
Checks,
no checks,
no waitress.
Get your booze for the show.
Show generally starts about 15 minutes
late.
Give everybody a chance to get back
their seat,
their drinks,
and then just sit down.
Yeah.
You know there's.
There's something about comedy clubs
though that's better.
The setup is better.
The low ceiling and the irony is the
only way to make that setup work is
you've got to make money and liquor and
the only way to make money with liquor
is you got to have waitresses to do it.
Theater,
you kind of.
It's like they're just very different.
It probably depends on what side you're
on.
Like I do four to five clubs a year.
Let's say.
I would love to just do some theaters.
I would love to blow into a town.
Be there one night,
shoot the Wad,
take off the next day just because you
just read today,
age or whatever.
When you go home,
I going to kill five days in Dayton,
Ohio.
Then the following week,
Toledo,
are you shitting on Dayton and Toledo
last order that I would like.
What?
Do you know what?
I know what you mean.
Well,
that's one of the reasons why you should
always like if you can take a friend on
the road with you to open for you a
giant and it changes the whole game to
take a friend with her.
You're having a good time.
You know you and him are just the shit
and laughing.
You can go to the movies.
You can do all kinds of shit.
Get to enter together.
Side note,
I mentioned kippah data because I'm
obsessed with him.
Why?
He's obsessed with.
Okay,
I have to wait.
I have to watch what I say because
here's what I'm obsessed with.
But he like,
he's been.
He goes after Internet trolls,
I guess from what I'm,
what I'm figuring out from other youtube
videos he puts out,
but he says people's names and phone
numbers and he just goes and he does
this whole thing going.
You can come to my website and post
something bad about me.
Joe Rogan.
Well I will tell you,
don't use my name.
You call them candies,
but.
But he has like,
he has one video where he's talking
about somebody pulls out a gun and he
takes out all the bullets and then he
kind of looks through the barrel wise
talk.
He's like,
yeah,
maybe scary.
So that's why I'm obsessed with talking
about that off the airflow hanging from
a thread.
Comedians,
we tend to be fucked up.
You think it happens when we get older?
Like we're talking about like your
instance,
right?
Like there's a lot of guys that just the
older they get or is it just trauma
somehow we get head trauma.
Well,
I think as the older people get,
you know,
they're more likely to go crazy anyway.
Yeah,
right.
So grandma and Grandpa weren't,
they weren't the same as when they were
ready to call it a,
a life,
you know,
my grandfather before he died,
it was,
it was sad.
It was just like he was barely there.
You know,
they uh,
pupil people get real weird when they
get old.
Yeah.
My,
yeah,
my grandma's 91 92.
And you have to ask her the same
questions.
And then she started asking what my mom
was doing.
My mom passed away so I didn't like.
Then I had to that conversation with her
and then she got legitimately sad is if
she just found out this information.
I'm like,
this,
just this,
uh,
when they get Alzheimer's that's really
spooky.
Whether they really don't know where
they are,
they'll wake up like in the middle of
doing things and not be sure where they
are and they don't know people that
they've known for years.
Getting old sucks the fat one dude,
you know,
luckily we'll be young forever to tie it
into.
What I was saying about Brendan is that
all that shit is coming worse if you're
dealing with head trauma,
all the other shit that everybody else
has to do with it was coming,
you know,
threefold.
Hopefully not.
Hopefully it gets out now.
It'd be all right.
There's a video of Terry Norris,
somebody,
uh,
we were talking about on the podcast.
Somebody put it up on the message board,
I think it was or twitter,
one of those.
And I watched again Terry Norris when I
was a kid.
When I was like in my early twenties,
Terry Martin Harris was the welterweight
champion I believe,
or 1:54,
I forget which way,
but God,
Tammy was good woo.
He had this
fucking lethal left hook man and.
But he would get tagged a lot and
fights.
He would,
he would fight guys and get hit.
You get nailed.
It happened a few times with him.
He was a just a blood and guts super
warrior boxer born with that,
right?
Like I don't know about that.
I was talking to them.
My point is that now he could barely
talk.
He can barely formed sentences.
It's really hard to watch and you know,
he was,
he wasn't that old when you retired,
you know,
it wasn't like he was Bernard Hopkins
fight and deep into his forties and then
Bernard Hopkins because of his skills
doesn't really get hit that much.
So he's fine.
He's 49 years old and he's fine.
Huh?
I don't like reading books lately,
have just,
I'm trying to get like that.
I've read this book called on combat and
it's just basically talks about when
you're in a combat situation would like
guns and stuff,
like a lot of people get tunnel vision
and then you get all and like how to
work through that so you can not get
paralyzed with fear,
you know?
Um,
and I just do not have that thing like,
you know what I mean when it comes from
a lot of it comes from overcoming
difficult things,
you know,
it's like the idea that you just get it
and then you have it like a lot of guys
that have it,
like,
especially like martial arts fighters
who talked to them like they've gone
through a decade of college wrestling
and high school wrestling and tried out
for the Olympic team and wrestling and
they're used to like high pressure type
situations and they're used to being
super uncomfortable.
That's one of the big keys to success in
athletics is you got to be willing to be
super uncomfortable.
You know,
like you've got to get up and do
training that you don't want to do.
You've got to work out when you're sore.
And especially in MMA,
you know you're going to get hit while
you're tired of getting hit.
It's like there's a lot of factors going
on.
So these guys that can rise to the
occasion,
they've risen to the occasion a lot
their whole life.
You know what I mean?
It's,
it's a normal state for them.
So for a guy like you who hasn't had
any,
you know,
amateur mma fights are doing Jujitsu
class against black belts on a regular
basis,
you're not experiencing like very
difficult situation.
So they,
they tense you up,
you know,
they become alien.
Like Jujitsu is a perfect example.
Like I've seen people go from being a
type of people that were like super
timid and like had self confidence
issues and then they started doing
Jujitsu and they'd got to purple belt
and Brown belt level and now black belt
level.
And when you meet these guys,
like I have a bunch of friends that are
like,
they're,
they're not big guys at all.
Like they're,
they're very slight and very like you
would never think that this guy's a
fucking killer,
but their technique is so good and
they've become that guy over the course
of like a few of them of course with me
knowing them,
they become this more confident person
and it's just a matter of going through
trials like getting,
getting beat down and then recovering,
getting like getting dominated.
Then you figure out a way to survive
getting dominated and fit out,
figure out a way to turn it around a
little bit and then you slowly keep
raising your level of ability both
physically and mentally to deal with
various scenarios and challenges that
come up with different guys you spar
with.
I think even what we view as comics like
that can happen because I got a,
you know,
my shows when I go to them,
I usually people who maybe know who I
am,
you know,
or they're my type of crowd,
but even whenever I saw you guys a
couple of days ago at the comedy store,
I would show in my head like I went on
stage in the first minute or two.
I felt my voice having that crack,
which,
you know,
I've done this for 20 my voice usually
it doesn't get,
but it's because I never performed
there.
Uh,
the,
the crowd that was there necessarily
didn't want to hear.
So I'm 44.
Here's some of the things I'm going
through,
you know what I mean?
Because they were 20.
So I had,
I had a moment of that.
Then afterwards when I was driving home,
the show will end up going,
but I'm like,
yeah,
I need to,
I need to do that more.
Like throw myself in scenarios that are
just in.
Just eat it.
Yeah.
You know?
Yeah,
absolutely.
He needs to eat it so I can like.
Yeah,
it's good.
Well that's one of the good things about
a place like the comedy store or any
kind of show where you're practicing.
There's like eight guys on it and you
can take some big chances with material.
You can.
You could.
I mean that's like one of the best
places to come up with a completely new
bit.
You have an idea in your car on the way
over.
You know what?
Only one way to try.
Fuck it.
We'll just throw this out there and you
know,
you sandwich it in between one good bit
and then you slip this new one in there
and he'd throw some water on it.
You see what you got?
What Ms Dot last time if you like.
When was the last time you ate?
Like ate it mentally in your head.
Maybe the audience like the audience
sometimes doesn't know.
You know what I mean?
Right.
They think,
oh that was a great show in your head.
You're like,
I have those all the time.
If I fuck up one bit,
I'm super hard on myself.
I had one last month I performed for
Dale Earnhardt Jr.
Oh right.
And his race team.
WhOa.
And it was his birthday charity event.
Right.
So 600 people.
I get up there,
dAle earnhardt sr introduces me get on
stage for I know no shit.
At least seven minutes,
seven minutes of bulletproof stuff,
stuff that's never,
you know,
it's been tried and it's not even like
giggle laughs,
right.
Stared at me.
I,
I talked for for at least five minutes
of zero laughs and sweat bust out on my
forehead.
And I'm like oh my,
this is idle.
And for some reason at minute six I did
a joke and everybody started applauding
and laughing and then for the rest of
the show,
you know,
they were cool.
How weird after like some of the people
walk by and go,
yeah,
you were really funny and you started
off kind of slow.
Like that was the thing that's still in
the guy who brought me this heffernan
guy and no relation.
He said that they had What I thought.
Yeah,
right.
They sAid they had rape.
Um,
jeff foxworthy billing like other shows,
like they just had to listen to you and
not maybe understand how you talk for
the first six minutes of playing and
talking fast.
Oh you talk like a foot.
But dude,
I was sweating and I'm like I have not
had this happen.
And you know,
I remember we went to,
I think it was dallas,
no,
atlanta,
it was atlanta,
one of the first times I did the
punchline down there and we did a radio
station and they were asking us all
these nascar questions and I was like,
what?
Like why would you think I would know
anything about nascar?
And then I realized,
oh,
everybody knows everything about nascar
down there.
And it's one of those things like when
you find out about country music artists
that no,
never heard of,
but they sold $50,
million albums.
there's a lot of those.
TheRe's a lot that's a whole that south.
So a whole different culture,
man.
Whole thing,
whole different culture.
It'S a complete different world like our
world of,
you know,
you think like,
fill in the blank,
you know,
whatever band you like,
queens of the stone age and you know,
I heard the new iphones out there,
fucking the new duck call came out.
They're all,
it's so realistic.
They're in their cars driving on the
highway.
I mean it's just,
obviously I'm bullshitting,
but there's parts of atlanta that are
liked that parts of Georgia that are
like that.
Georgia is a fucking great country,
a great state court,
great country.
Atlanta,
Georgia is a great city,
but george's george is an interesting
place because I'm like a lot of guys you
wouldn't think of or from Georgia like
David Cross from Georgia,
that greeley smart,
sensitive,
intelligent guy.
He's from Georgia.
You know,
rem.
Rem.
Atlanta is a different kind of city man.
That's where belieber a taped is a
special.
His netflix special.
That's outright now.
I please,
please get this.
If you're going to get a comedy special,
go get this.
Get mine too if you want,
but get his.
It's fucking great.
I'm a big bill burger fan.
I love that he's out there.
I love that.
He's always writing new shit and then
he's just silly and fun and you know,
his act is,
it's a silly,
fun act.
He does his bit.
I don't want to give it away.
I'm not going to say anything about the
bit,
but he does it bit about helicopters.
Yeah,
that's all I'm going to say.
It's so great.
It's so silly.
Fun,
man.
I really,
really enjoyed a set.
I just love him.
He's just a good dude.
He's a licker genuine good dude.
That's why I love performing with you
guys a couple days ago cause you guys
are all who you are.
So then lIke seeing you guys perform is
different than like when I'm on the road
and there's some little feature that the
local features,
I'm not saying don't suck,
but there's different conversations you
have in the green room and the,
you know,
the,
the material is all kind of.
So it's nice.
Yeah,
I know exactly what you mean.
I went to a headliner camp for like,
you know better.
Okay.
Then that's why I like doing those ice
house shows.
Man.
The other day,
the ice house we had ready for this
chris delea,
brian cowen,
bill burr,
tony hinchcliffe,
ian eDwards in me,
it was a motherfucker,
a motherfucker lineup,
but you guys wEre just murdering after
murdering and for a few bucks to 15
bucks,
what all of you cost individually on and
your theaters are clubs for the most
part.
Everybody you mentioned iS,
you know,
a 20 dollaR plus ticket.
It's a sampler pack.
Yeah.
But it's for 15 late shows actually cost
me money because I take all the money
that I get from those shows.
I tip everybody out,
all the comics and that he usually,
either I make 100 bucks or um,
our breakeven.
Yeah.
I haven't always money every week.
But they're there.
So the place,
first of all,
the ice house is a slice of heaven.
It's just one of the greatest buildings
in the free world.
It's amazing.
Their club is magic.
It's like that club and the comedy store
that.
But the ice house has magic in a whole
different way because it's pasadena.
It's not hollywood.
So it doesn't have.
It's like full of itself vibes.
So people like a little bit more chIll
in pasedena.
So oldest comedy club in the country,
the owner couldn't be nicer.
I mean bob fisher is one of the nicest
fucking people that's ever breathed air.
He's just so sweet.
He's always liked that.
He's got a great diy like always to
everybody.
You can walk up behind him.
He doesn't know you're there and he's
talking to the manager or the wait
staff.
He's Always smiling.
He's just a sweetie.
Just a sweetheart of a guy.
So like the staff there is awesome
because of that,
because of this like good vibe.
Like all the waiters are so cool.
Like every time I go there I'm like
super happy to give everybody hugs.
It's just,
it's,
it's a beautiful environment.
And because of that,
like doing shows,
there is like,
it's kind of special.
There's something special about it.
I'm there wednesday night.
I love that fucking place.
We do.
I do wednesday night at 10:00,
like every other week,
every two weeks,
every three minutes just to set it up,
just to,
just to fuck around there and have some
fun.
And also just to get people to keep
going in that spot.
That spot.
It's awesome.
It's been some 19,
60 something.
What was the brand?
It's been 53 years.
I think it is something crazy like that.
So 61 or something like that when it
opened.
I can't think of it.
There's some really old school.
Huge comedy albums recorded there too.
Oh,
I'm sure.
Yeah.
I want to do my next special there.
I'm committed.
I'm committed to doing specials in
comedy clubs.
I'm committed to that.
That's a different thing then.
Yeah,
that's what I'm trying to do,
just because I think I might pay for
this special all on my own.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
Film in a comedy club and just,
you know,
so that's just cheaper and it's just as
just as good as walking around a
theater.
Let me.
Theaters are nice too.
I think it's better.
I think it's better just I'd have a
better show because it's,
it's what I normally do.
Yeah.
I performed in theaters all the time.
Then I would probably want to shoot.
Especially,
although I have to say the burst
special,
he filmed at the tabernacle,
which is the same place that I felt my
last special,
the one before this one and the
tabernacle is a great spot for,
for doing standup.
It's not too big.
I think it's only like,
I want to say like 1300 or 1500.
It's not like a massey hall,
which is like 3,400
and you get to that size theater,
like joey diaz and I went to see Louis
Black once we were,
we were playing the next night.
We're playing on friday and he was
playing at the same theater on thursday
and we sat in the crowd and uh,
it made me realize like there's certain
shit that you can't hear the guy say
because everybody's laughing like you
gotta be really careful with like subtle
shit.
You got to make sure,
like you don't hear any laughter still
when you're doing something subtle.
So your timing kind of changes in those
really big rooms.
But the rush of the big room was like,
yeah,
I think that most I've ever done was I
think 10,000
to some corporate event.
It was,
it wasn't.
People showed up to see me.
I was a sammy hagar was on and steve
miller,
I was on.
Wow,
you worked a sammy hagar and steve.
but what does steve miller looked like?
Did you even recognize him?
A note because the album was only the
white horse like,
so by you know,
teenage years I've listened to me.
I've never saw what he looked like.
He looked like a dad with a blazer and
jeans and just went out there.
That's the thing about steve miller.
He is the least recognizable major.
He walk around rockstar.
He could walk,
run anywhere and it seemed like he never
tried to become famous.
Or you're going to out him on the
podcast that steve miller.
That's what it looks like now.
Dude.
He had some fucking jams.
Jungle love.
that was that whole album.
Reminds me of high school.
Take the money.
And this is still about billy joe.
We thought we.
We thought we were cool too because
we're listening to classic rock that was
technically we're into this,
not this new edition,
you know,
it's really fucking weird man.
I went to high school in 1981 and in
1981 I started hanging out with these
kids.
I just moved into town into a newton
upper falls and I started hanging out
with my friend jimmy and jimmy and all
of his friends were all from the other
side of town.
They,
they're all like the north part of
newton and they were all like everyone
adores tee shirts and they were all
smoking weed and it was like they
introduced me to all this music that I
didn't even know existed.
But when I think about it now,
the shit was only 10 years old.
Yeah.
Like the allman brothers,
they were,
they were playing like some almond
brothers are some doors.
That shit is from like 1969,
1970.
So at the time were talking.
I went to high school in [inaudible]
one.
That was my freshman year.
This is,
what is it?
Twelve,
13 years old.
Fuck nothing.
That's like some music from 2001 that's
contemporary,
you know,
like a song from 2002 you could still
hear like on a regular basis that would
be on a radio station that was eighties,
nineties and male sex and can day.
Yeah.
You can hear that.
You could eaSily hear that someone can
play that non.
Ironically on a regular radio station
they wouldn't be saying,
oh you remember this shit.
That would be a song they would play.
But that sex and candy song came out In
like like 99 or some shit.
Yeah.
So think about that.
Like that.
We wouldn't say,
yeah man,
that was the classIc.
Something fucking happened to time.
Time is not what it used to be 10 years
ago doesn't mean shit anymore.
But 10 years ago back then meant a lot
when I was in high school.
And then in 1981 and 1970 car was a
mother fucker.
If you had a 1970 chevelle or a 1970
barracuda you what?
A fucking sweet car.
oh you got a classic muscle car.
It's only 10 years old.
What the fuck happened?
And he does that when it happened.
The acceleration,
just information.
We're pumped.
We're going to the library every single
second.
We look at her phone,
you know,
that's what's happening,
right?
That is what's happening.
I was talking,
I talk about music onstage and I always
ask people in there are,
you know,
people at the shows that are like 21 or
all of their music has been digital
their entire life.
Completely crazy.
There's like never physically touched
anything.
Just that's not even a a process that
they have in their head.
I asked five people last night if they
knew sissy space was and no one knew.
That's insane.
If you haven't seen the original carrie,
you're doing yourself a massive
disservice.
That original carrie was a masterpiece.
Is that brian depalma?
Who made that?
God damn,
that was a good movie.
That was like one of the best Stephen
King adaptations and sissy spacey
knocked it out of the fucking park with
a light saber.
Just.
I mean,
she was so crazy in that movie,
like her character was.
So it was.
There was something about the
ridiculousness of someone having
telekinesis,
but somehow or another she sold it like
you bought it,
you believe when she came out there with
that fucking pig blood spoiler,
she came out there and she had that pig,
but they don't pick blood on her head.
They played a trick on her to get her to
think that she won the uh,
the prom.
They all voted for it just so they could
dump blood on her head and she just tore
the city apart with her brain.
And you're like,
get out of here with this stupid fucking
movie.
Like,
that premise has been tried before and
everybody goes,
get the fuck outta here.
But in that movie it actually works.
It's awesome.
That's a great movie.
Do you ever watch that show?
It's now on netflix.
Carrie santa maria is the one that
turned me on to,
I believe in black mirror.
Black mirror.
Have you?
Yes.
Oh my god.
Great.
Just watch the first episode on netflix
and you'll be hooked.
It's like twilight zone mixed with
technology.
It's beautiful.
In the first episode is one of my
favorites.
It's really good.
I don't know why that is on in America.
Yeah,
it's on bbc America,
right?
Yeah.
That's how I think I got it off of.
I think I got it off a direct tv,
like one of those instant plays.
You can do that.
It's on netflix.
It's on netflix right now.
Yeah.
That's a good show.
So amazing.
Like mayor.
Yeah,
I think it might be right about
technology making like years seemed
quicker because we were watching an
auction,
you know,
one of those,
uh,
those car auctions was on the tv show,
the green room and uh,
it was in 2002 camaro and they rolled
out this 2002 camaro and everybody's
like,
who fucking cares that thing out of
here?
nobody wanted it.
They were looking at is 2002.
It only has 17 miles.
There's a reason for that.
Do you know why would I get a 2002
camaro?
What'd you can get?
A 2014 and it's fucking dope.
Or a 1969 and it's dope.
It's weird because I also,
I get jealous of new cars,
not because their new cars now it's
because of the gps is in their
territory,
their technology that's in it.
Like I want that car.
Terrific.
I,
I have a really nice expensive car but
it's an old oh six.
So the technology,
I cAn't even plug my phone into it and
well If you like the car,
you know,
you can always just get aftermarket
stereo.
Those are so much better anyway.
And the nav system now they updated and
now embed it so much that I'm looking at
it right now to get the apple car play
and my old ford edge,
but they embed the sink in like sO I,
I will lose so much if I get a factory
or I'd take out the factory,
like I'll get my oil change reports,
my emergency gps thing that kicks in if
I've been in an accident.
Oh all that's gone.
Well that's annoying.
And then the,
the,
so the,
you can't update the navigation system
on those cars either?
Absolutely.
Right.
It reAlly pissed me off because with
sync at least sync would update it
within like the first year,
like there'll be updates and there'd be
sync is the word,
but then they just gave up on it and
then I was like,
yeah,
they just know they stopped giving any
updates and so my shit's like doesn't
even halfway work with my iphone
anymore.
Louisiana market.
I have an aftermarket stereo in the
porsche and I can download new maps and
you can download updates.
It'll tell me.
it'll send me a signal and then I could
just download it through the,
through the wifi on my phone or the
cellular connection on the phone.
It's a pretty slick.
Let's talk about all fast technology.
When you probably moved to los angeles,
he had a thomas guide.
Yup.
Yeah.
I'm surprised that they haven't really
made a doc type thing where you just put
in your like your ipad when you get into
your car and it turns into like a car
stereo and it hooks up immediate
automatically.
And bill burr had a fucking thomas guide
as recently as 2008.
They'll do the hardest.
He fucking showed up at my house and I
go,
what is that?
He had a map book on his front seat.
He goes,
yeah,
I'm a fucking technology.
I don't want it in my life.
I don't need it.
I don't.
I don't need the gps.
I don't need anybody.
No one where I'm going.
Did you hear him?
But they know.
They know that watching will.
You know they're watching you.
They know what your fucking car is.
Cool with that.
You're cool with them knowing where your
car is.
That last podcast I asked if he was
still using mapquest.
He goes,
no,
I'd do it on the phone now.
Finally gave up,
but he's got a phone that's like for
four years back.
Just the character man.
Thomas guys were were like,
imagine telephone books with maps on
each page,
but then the find your street.
Remember you had to go to the white and
then you had to get a protractor and
fun,
but you would all.
You do this all while you were driving
by the way,
not like members remember going on
vacations or parents that they have like
aaa triptiks where it's just like,
all right,
turn next page.
Yeah,
that's rIght.
I remember now I did this college tour
when I was 20.
We had to go around the country and we
had a game show.
It was called crack me up and you'd have
to pull a student.
You'd be a student and I'd have to see
you in a chair and then I would have a
minute to make you laugh.
Oh,
I've seen something like that.
I can give you.
If you didn't laugh,
you got 25 bucks.
If you laughed you got tee shirt.
So I did maybe 200 dates of this tour
just in a van with two other comics.
I'm driving around the country,
but we had a big rand mcnally map and
then you'd highlight it and then you
would drive and when you got 50 miles
outside of the city you would go to a
payphone and then called the school.
Like it was such a.
Like that was not that long ago,
you know?
I know that sounds archaic there.
We got on the horse.
Did you have a goto move for,
for that show?
Oh my god.
Dude,
it's a.
Yeah,
I had a couple characters because we
have props.
How many seconds did you have to make
them off?
Uh,
I don't remember.
Thirty seconds or a minute.
Seems like a lot.
It could have been.
I don't remember.
Are you comfortable telling us what you
did?
You're comfortable revealing your
secrets.
Okay.
Here's,
here's the one that would get a.
I would do this guy called book report
guy.
Okay.
So I put on like a random funny hat and
then I was.
And then so we'd have like one of the
comics would go now coming out and then
you would say the character's name kid
given a book report on a book he didn't
read and I would just literally make up
a book report and just she would just
wing it.
Yeah.
And then they don't owe us.
if people laughed,
doctor quam here.
Here's character.
now coming out dr.
Karma.
We had a japanese completely japanese
head thing.
You,
you went japanese,
japanese,
just a.
And I put on a doctor's thing and then I
would move my lips and the comic behind
the wall would talk.
So it wasn't ever sink top.
Wow.
Did it work?
You know.
And,
and where it was scary is we would do
all these colleges in like if we thought
it was a,
like a predominantly black school,
we knew we were dead in the water.
Like a lot of times we go because we're
like three white guys.
one time,
I'll never forget mccook Nebraska,
we did a show,
the basketball team comes and sits on
the front row.
Uh,
one of the comics we're with,
um,
was mixed.
It was half black,
half white.
He went out,
he went after these guys just kind of,
you know,
trying to make fun of them.
Keep in mind,
this was nineties,
so like def jam was kind of in people's
brain that that's how comedy was,
was that type of.
So he went after this a basketball team.
So we do the show,
we leave,
we go to a local pool hall,
uh,
why were in their seven of the
basketball team come to the pool hall
and surrounded us and then they go to
the other comic,
jason.
THey're like,
don't ever say something in front of me
again like that,
but blah,
blah,
blah.
I'm like,
dude,
these guys are going to fight.
we're dead.
we're,
we're completely dead.
So I remember I was racking,
we were playing a nine ball.
I was racking and then I grabbed the
two.
You were ready to go to war.
There was,
I thought we going to be killed.
I thought we were going to.
So I'm like,
here we go.
So then,
uh,
they said,
you better get out of town.
You guys better leave or you're in a
western,
a western.
So in,
here's how I would handle myself in
western.
We ran back to the hotel as fast as we
could through all of our clothes,
just into one bag.
Jumped in the car.
But we're in mccook,
Nebraska.
It's all corn.
So as we're driving,
we returned in,
you'd see headlights coming and you're
like,
okay,
they're following us.
this is where,
this is where we get shot.
Well they told you to leave.
If they were going to do something new,
they wouldn't have told you to leave
there would say stay right here.
That's true.
And then they would have just killed.
It was just beat your ass.
The only reason why they would say you
better get out of town as if they knew
that you were driving a long way and
they could overtake you along the way,
push you into a ditch,
and then their cousin who's the cop
would stall on the way over there and
avoid some of the evidence.
Who dodged the bullet?
There was some statistics somebody put
up about how many people get killed by
cops and in what places like
albuquerque,
apparently albuquerque,
New Mexico is just like one of the most
violent places for like police and
civilians.
Like cops in albuquerque.
They've killed a gang of people like the
number.
Like everyone is going crazy and
berkeley.
Have you guys been paying attention to
this?
They're stopping the highway like every
night,
like these kids are just blocking
traffic on the highway and they're
getting arrested in their live tweeting
while they're getting arrested and part
of me is like,
well,
look,
at the very least they're making a big
fucking deal,
right?
There's like a lot of eyes on this.
They're stopping the highway every
night.
There's all these kids,
they're wandering through the street
signs.
They're fucking active,
they're active,
they're making people think,
and is it possible now?
I'm not in favor of shutting down the
highway because if you do shut down the
highway,
there's some people that might be on the
way to the hospital.
They might have some heart attack and
you lose your grandpa because some kids
thought it'd be cute to support that
support the ferguson trial in the middle
of the berkeley highway,
but is it possible that just knowing
that there's that much of a reaction,
that people freak out that much over
some shit that happened in Missouri that
it might make them second guess where
they pull the trigger?
I say it probably does.
Yeah,
probably does.
Right?
All the shit that you're seeing on the
news on a daily basis,
every time something happens,
people get in trouble every time.
Look at hollywood and highland.
No,
the other day I can't believe that guy
got shot on right in the middle of
every.
You know,
the center of hollywood in front of
everybody and the only had a knife.
What happened with that?
What is the official story?
Do you know?
It's still being investigated because
I've heard all sorts of ridiculous
conspiracy theories involved in costumes
and that he was one of those players
that pretends to be cosplay.
Yeah.
Well there was a kid who was a cosplay
kid who got shot with a samurai sword.
Just see that.
Yeah.
Some kid had a fucking samurai sword and
he was walking around pretending to be a
samurai and the cops fucking starts
shooting at him.
Killed him,
you know,
and I don't think he threatened anybody.
Do you think because it's aLl on the
news now.
Our cops like zero generation of cops
that got really shitty training that
like shoot people first or do you think
it's always gone at the same numbers?
We have now,
it just,
we've reached an age and with news and
now I think it's more that they felt was
all consistent.
Yeah,
I think so.
I think if anything,
it's probably less now than ever because
some places are starting to implement
body cameras on the cops,
which should be mandatory.
It's a crazy role to role of having
ultimate power over another civilian.
You know,
another another fellow citizen.
That's a crazy role and that kind of
power like the state.
We've talked about this before,
but if you haven't heard this,
google the stanford prison experiment
and it's all about how they had a these
kids and these one,
one group of kids would play security
guards.
The other group of kids would be the
prisoners and they fucking went bad.
Quick.
People are gross like you can't.
he can't give that people that kind of
power like power,
like to shoot and kill other people.
It's just people's default setting is,
is pretty shitty,
but we just have just enough.
We changed the stuff a little.
You also have to think that if you're
dealing with a cop,
okay,
a cop is experiencing violence and
murder and theft and robbery and crime
on a rate that the average person will
never know.
You will never know wHat it's like to be
someone who every single night is just
going to war every single night.
You're dealing with bodies and people
that had been shot and people that have
you fill,
fill in the blank,
everything.
Rape and murder and child abuse and
you're just constantly seeing horrible,
horrible things.
So when something happens,
like a lot of these guys,
they're so ptsd out there,
they have just fucking trigger finger.
They almost can't control their.
They're experiencing like lifetimes of
trauma in a year.
I mean,
yeah,
if you're a cop and you're in a bad
neighborhood,
you're experiencing a lot of fucking
shit and it affects people in different
ways and I think it's just an
unbelievably hard job to do.
Yeah.
It's an unbelievably hard job to
instill.
THey get killed too,
man.
You know?
That's another thing you have to take
into consideration.
I think 53 people,
50.
How many comps a year get killed?
I was reading the statistics.
I don't want to.
I want to botch it.
We just found,
um,
I,
my grandpa,
I guess I've never met him.
He was a cop in detroit and was shot and
we somehow came across the tIcket book
that was in his pocket and there's a
bullet hole going right through the
parking ticket.
The ticket book.
Yeah.
Jesus christ tent.
Wow.
Kind of a weird artifact to like locate
though that 150 deaths per year.
That's what it is.
One hundred 50 cops per year get killed.
How many of you know?
Um,
I don't know.
That's a good question.
Okay.
900,000
dollars.
sworn law enforcement operators,
officers,
whatever you call them.
Well that's a lot.
You know,
150 of them get killed in here a lot.
A loT of fucking people.
They kill a lot of fucking people.
You're too.
Okay.
How many people did cops killed?
What's guessed that?
How many people are cops?
A lot of them.
Bad guys.
Let's just.
We're not,
this isn't a judgment thing.
We're just trying to find the number.
How many people do cops kill every year?
I do want to get a 150 copies a year.
A thoUsand 400.
Seems like 400 per year.
$400.
I was going to say almost triple what?
It was a couple of different sites that
say it's 400 per year.
So it seems like things low does it?
Yeah.
Well,
I mean I guess half of them are still
like,
oh wait a minute.
Hold on a second.
It says local police involved in 400
killings per year.
What the fuck?
She's per city,
Washington dc.
Oh my god.
Okay.
Nearly two times a week in the United
States.
A white police officer killed a black
person during a seven year period ending
in 2012.
Whoa.
That's fucking crazy.
That's a crazy statistic.
Two times a week for seven years,
a white officer killed a black person.
Like at what point in time do we have to
say that there might be a little bit of
a problem.
What?
How high do the numbers have to get with
crime and police and police shootings
and how high the numbers have to get
before people go,
what the fuck is going on here?
Like how,
how many black people are getting shot
by white cops?
How many black people are committing
crimes?
How many white cops are looking to shoot
black people?
Like what are the answers?
Like if you were the people that were in
charge of overseeing the police
department,
I don't know if they ask these questions
but that will be like the first thing
that I would want to address publicly if
that fucking statistic.
You know,
people started talking about that more
often.
Twice a week,
twice a week of white guys kill a black
guy.
That's,
that seems like a lot.
I mean I don't want to laugh talking
about that,
but that seems like a ridiculous amount.
Like that's a good argument.
And anybody that says that like you
know,
that there's not at least the potential
for racism.
Like how could you not look at that?
That number right there seems slow.
I think Just in los angeles.
Twice to two cops.
Shoot a black guy.
I don't know about that.
Well,
they were talking about killing 18
percent of the blacks killed during
those seven years were under the age of
21 compared to 18 or eight point seven
of the whites.
Man,
you know,
and it's,
it's a,
it's a double problem.
So this is the thing.
Everybody wants to blame one side,
but there's,
it's a double problem.
It's not simply a problem with the
police officers killing the black kids.
It's definitely that,
but it's also crime ridden
neighborhoods,
how to stop the momentum of crime ridden
neighborhoods and kids that are coming
out of those crime ridden neighborhoods
that commit crimes.
Okay.
How do you stop that?
It's not,
I don't believe it's the children's
fault.
I don't think it's the fault of a 16
year old kid that grows up in an
unbelievably harsh environment and it
becomes a criminal.
I don't think it's his fault.
I think he's an unfortunate victim of a
terrible situation.
I think nationally we have to figure out
what the fuck is causing that and if
there's anything that they can do to
mitigate that in some sort of way.
It's just a waste of resources and life.
You're,
you're,
you're asking people to grow up in an
environment that's sold,
likely going to fuck them up for live or
you.
Yeah.
Or you have to do whatever the
environment asks or you're dead.
That a survival.
You're like,
oh shit like that.
You really feel like doing this,
but you know,
no doubt man.
No doubt is not.
And everybody goes,
well,
you go to choice.
You should fuck off,
man.
If you live that guy's life,
then maybe you could judge,
but you really don't know.
You don't know unless you live there.
And I'm just guessing.
I'm just totally guessing.
No,
you know,
I just think the whole thing,
ultimately it's a wakeup call for
America.
I think there's a lot of people that are
pretty fucking tired
of the way things have been going in
this country.
You saw that video that,
that boy,
like the boy with the pellet gun.
What did you know?
My friend justin told me that that guy
was fired from another police force and
they picked him up because he had
already gone through all this training
and they picked him up and this forest,
but they had already decided this guy
might be like mentally unhung two
seconds.
So I think you see it.
Brian saw it,
but I don't pull it up.
Jamie.
I don't want to watch it,
but I didn't want to watch.
I didn't watch it.
I just read it.
That two seconds they start shooting
them like as the car is moving still
don't get it man,
I don't get it.
And then I read you read the comments
and it's always like,
well if you don't,
if you don't want to be shot by the cops
then then don't do stuff.
Like somebody was kind of like,
like bagging and it'll keep it as a kid.
I remember running around with guns cap
guns and you know,
playing war we go said let's play war.
And of course it's 12.
Of course,
I definitely would have done it the
exact same thing and if I was in that
situation and I was black and I was
doing the exact same thing,
I might've got shot,
they said he was scaring people and
pointing the gun at him and he's
probably a disturbed little kid growing
up in a fucked up place,
you know,
it doesn't mean he has to get shot.
We were like the last generation to
actually have realistic army guns for
sale at toys r us at a point like in the
eighties we had guns that looked like
real uzis rob banks with those.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
No orange,
orange thing.
I think that was like in the nineties or
something.
You can always cut that out.
Yeah.
I know a dude with a drill for that
fucker out.
Make it look real.
We had a game,
uh,
I lived in a subdivision,
probably had like 40,
50 kids,
deep different ages.
We,
I created this game called tag.
It was from a movie town,
the assassination game,
and we had profiles.
We had everyone in high school or
whatever grade we were in your school
pictures and then I'd write brian's
home,
here's what bassy road,
here's his address,
and then you'd pass out those profiles
and then you'd have to kill the guy that
whoever you got.
And I remember the john dory come in my
house,
knocked on the door and my mind says
somebody is there,
open it.
It's during he pulled out a gun,
you know,
like one of those ones that shot the
suction cups under the plastic with the
pulled up black gun pointed right in my
head.
Shot me right in the face with it.
My mom was standing right there.
Didn't you know,
it's just like a son just got ya.
You know.
But wall toy.
Yeah.
We're all walking around with guns,
knocking on people's doors,
pointing guns instead.
You're doing it with all friends though.
Like you knew the dude,
right?
Some of the guys,
like if you got the profile,
you didn't know him well and you just
have to show up to him and shoot him.
But they were all playing the game.
You all looked at it.
Yeah,
it was all like mob hits and that sounds
fun as long as someone's not genuinely
mad,
like you know,
someone like maybe like to grow up.
The other guy wound up where they are.
The only rule we had was you couldn't
shoot somebody on the way to school.
Like that was our big thing just
because.
And I even bought a,
we had the spiderman things you put
around your wrist and you could shoot
the rubber things through the spiderman.
I wore that to school just in case
somebody wanted to get shitty with me.
After school though.
It was actual weapons that you would
push,
like where the spiderweb would come up
and it would shoot the rubber bullets.
I'm talking about those rubber suction
cup guns.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
It would shoot one of those so I could
point.
So I had one shot.
It was like a derringer.
Why do you have that up?
I was going to show you what he was
talking about.
They actually have to do a thing called
street words where it's a whole city.
Thirty days,
24 slash seven water gun.
It's destination.
Oh,
that's hilarious.
That's a great idea.
That would be a fun thing.
As long as you're doing it with cool
people that aren't going to actually
kill you.
I remember making the profile,
so I would take your picture and then I
would with stencil or whatever,
you know,
home office stuff we had,
I would make a little profile and I
remember my dad going at wish you'd
spend more time on your homework then.
Like I was obsessed with this game.
Yeah.
But your dad was incorrect because uh,
you,
you gravitated towards fun and now
you're successful.
Standup comedian dad was totally
incorrect.
Yeah.
Parents are often incorrect,
man.
Got to get out of your fucking kids way
sometimes.
But then the other thing is I bet by
like not encouraging you to do stand up
comedy.
Like you probably like,
like by saying like you gotta get your
shit together.
Why you spent all this time playing the
stupid fucking game.
You should be doing your homework.
But by,
by doing that,
like they put a little pressure on you
and it makes sure that I'll show you.
Like some kids don't have that.
Yeah,
I'll show you because their parents were
always super supportive,
so if shit goes wrong they don't know
what the fuck to do.
My parents didn't know my.
I did stand up for like five years.
Really never even told them and then
somebody saw me like at an open mic and
asked my dad and then my dad goes and he
was you doing standup comedy and it was
weird.
Like I was probably.
My dad was probably whatever the math is
my age now.
So just like imagine like you then
you're like,
it's so you think your dad was an hip
and cool and wouldn't want to be,
but there is a major advantage to
raising kids when you get older,
you know you have your shit together at
least a little bit better.
Like when you're 20 or 21,
like I couldn't imagine raising a kid at
2116.
That was a lot of people to do it.
my life wasn't 16,
17.
My wife was 19 when she had her.
God damn man,
that's crazy.
It's just what an unbelievable
responsibility when you're barely and
she's in rome,
nervous.
She was in the military and having a
kid.
It's crazy.
You're barely an adult.
Barely.
I mean as an 18 year old or an adult
technically.
Yeah,
but we all know 18 year olds,
they're like children.
You know the children that know a little
bit more than the average child.
They're just experiencing life and
they're still trying to figure.
I mean,
when I
was 18,
I was a fucking moron.
I was a moron last week.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I was a moron a couple of hours ago.
Know you're 18.
god,
you're fucking super duper moron,
but are 18 was
way dumber than today's 18?
Oh yeah.
No,
a million times.
No doubt about that.
We were dumber,
heavier.
Fuck.
it didn't have access to as much.
They're super fucking experienced.
The kids of today,
they're super experienced in like not
just like physical experiences but
experiences like understanding like all
sorts of different points of view and
different information,
different sides of things.
Like they're mOre informed.
They're just more on their brains are
working at like a higher level.
I really believed that.
I've talked to some 20 year olds and I
feel like I'm talking to like a young
adult,
whereas if when I was 20 and I would
talk to other 20 year olds,
I was talking to mo ron,
other fellow morons who we would give
each other advice and tell each other
more ron facts that weren't real at all.
You know,
that was back then.
I mean it's so nice to live like now if
you have a random trivia question,
are you like how many cops were shot?
SomeBody you have access to that but,
but like back in the day guys at bars,
it would have to debate it.
Like nobody knew that,
you know,
knew the answer to anythIng.
You would just have to.
Yeah.
It's really interestingly if you play
video games nowadays because you're,
you're matched up with kids all the
time.
So you're online talking to other adults
and then you have thIs like 22 year old.
That's an analytic guys I'm ready in its
people are like havIng full on
conversations with these kids.
It's so weird.
They don't seem like kids anymore.
Yeah,
I gave up playing.
Yeah.
There's,
um,
there's just a new reality.
Men is a new reality that we're
experiencing.
I had this guy on last,
yes,
less yesterday.
he's a futurist and he just a,
just kind of a guy who's invested in the
idea of trans humanism and all this
advancement of technology,
but he was talking about how in 20 years
we may not even talk to each other
anymore.
Everything might be done through like
mind interfaces that work like the
internet,
like this,
this device that they recently tested.
They were able to transmit thoughts
through the internet over like,
you know,
500 miles or something crazy like that,
like a very far distance.
And you wear this thing and like you
think,
like,
say if you think of hello,
you think hello?
Like you,
you keep saying like hello,
hello.
And it reads what your brain is doing
when it says hello.
And so then it recreates that.
So the person on the other end on the
internet has his helmet on and they hear
in their head hello.
And you're not saying anything like
you're not using your mouth.
You're using your fucking brain.
Hey,
you're sending a word through your brain
to someone else's brain through the
internet and it's really crude right
now.
Yeah.
I wonder if there's auto correct for
that.
Like think something switches.
Right?
If someone's got like a deep like
chicago aksana and that's what I meant.
Shock each cac.
What the fuck did you say?
I was thinking that technology to even
drive and I had a meeting today that was
just like,
I thought I wish I could just hollow
grandma.
Like at this point I'm eating right?
Yeah,
but that'll probably be in our lifetime.
Don't like.
I've seen technology biff of like cisco
was doing.
Have you seen magic leap?
Seen tupac?
Have you seen magic?
No.
Magic leap is the new shit.
It's this ridiculous technology there.
There's a video that they show online
where a guy's his hands out and there's
a little baby elephant that is 100
percent realistic and it's dancing in
his hand.
So like some new hologram technology.
It's just they're just releasing part of
like this.
It might.
Who knows?
It might,
It might be a hoax.
The whole thing might be like pumping up
some fucking new movie that's coming
out.
I actually think that this photo that
you know,
or this video,
I think this was just maDe to like,
this is what it should be like,
but I don't think it seems like they
don't.
They don't explain enough,
but watch this because it's so bizarre.
Dude.
This guy has his hands out and as his
hands are out,
this elephant starts dancing around in
his hands.
Were going to pull up the video part of
it.
Yeah.
We'll just show it to over here.
It's really crazy to watch and there's
another one where there's a little girl
like,
look At this.
He opens his hands up and look at this
elephant dancing around inside of his
hands.
I mean,
come on son.
Fuck.
is that the thing is making shadows.
How's it making shAdows?
Like what is that?
Find that dude.
Find out if that.
Yeah,
it was the seventies.
We'd be at a bar and we debate it.
Why don't you google jamie google
whether or not that's real,
because that sounds like no one knows
some new technology,
some new technology.
All right,
we'll figure it out motherfucker.
Like five years from now we're going to
be looking back at that and then it's
going to be something sIlly that I
remember.
We thought that was a real,
you know,
what they're doing with this voice
technology thing.
If that really comes true and you really
can communicate through words in each
other's minds without talking and then
there's no more spoken language and then
there's like a universal language that
everybody adopts.
This is the idea that you're going to
wear these fucking headset things and
you're going to go into a virtual
reality,
so you'll have this headset thing on.
Then you'll have like an oculus rift on
and you will like be in a meeting with
these people and you know they can have
avatars to represent who they are.
Like you can go into this three d,
virtual reality with this headset on and
see people and you don't even realize
they're fake until you try to touch
them.
I think it have couches set up.
They could have a room set up where you
could have like a three d meeting and
everything looks exactly the same on
both sides as far as the furniture so
the person can come in,
sit down,
talk,
hang out with you,
and you literally will feel like you
were in the room with them and you won't
know you're not until you try to touch
them.
I'm just going to be like the matrix
where everything just going to be gray
and dingy,
but in your virtual world is going to be
beautiful.
That the life.
Yeah,
and then that seemed so silly.
That's going to happen,
right?
Well,
it will definitely have ruin the
environment,
right?
If we ruin the environment and it seems
like we're kind of on that path.
I mean there's a lot of concern about
the environment now and there's a lot of
people that are making all these big
efforts so generation is going to get
good at saving the environment.
Well actually that's not true because
Norway has zero,
zero garbage now.
I believe it's Norway.
They figured out how to completely
recycle all their trash so they have
like,
I think it's Norway.
Let me find out Norway and have to
figure this out.
Yeah.
Right.
Years ago,
I think they use all of us.
I believe it's Norway,
Sweden,
Sweden runs out of garbage.
90 nine percent.
Sweden,
Norway.
I'm going to stockholm there in january
for a 99 percent of sweden's garbage is
now recycled.
That's fucking incredible.
That's incredible.
I mean that is like almost zero trash.
One percent trash.
It's amazing.
I saw something on water.
I think it was a documentary about los
angeles or California running out of
water and they had some plant that had
sewage,
like literally it was sewage water and
an hour and a half later it was as clean
as bottled water drinking.
They have that drinking straw where you
can just drink and it filters anything
and they have like a guy,
like a video of a guy drinking straight
p out of it,
filtering it.
How dare he.
Have you seen ian candidate?
The moving?
Yeah.
The new one or the original one?
I think I've seen both.
Yeah.
That's an interesting movie about how
they had implants put in and how they
can control.
Um,
and yeah,
I think I fell asleep during the new one
for some reason I was probably tired
when I was washing it,
but the first one was pretty
interesting.
The idea is pretty interesting.
That's like an,
an idea that always gets bandied about
and conspiracy theory circles like they
believe that someone could be in a
manchurian candidate and like the guy
who took out,
martin luther king didn't even know what
he was doing,
you know,
that kind of shit.
Yeah.
Jack ruby technology,
a cool story.
My brother in law was a hit,
was blown up in Afghanistan.
He blew off.
So.
So his quad got blown off,
right?
Yeah.
so it is that you've topped muscle of
your lake.
Kind of dumb about this.
Yeah.
So the,
the,
the quad got blown up.
So he's been in a wheelchair for four
years so far.
This is one that happened,
rIght?
Um,
gained a bunch of weight and then the
created this almost
iron man bionic leg that he can put
around his leg.
And then there's like a computer where
your knee would be and it,
it moves his legs,
100 percent paralyzed in this bionic
leg,
moves his leg for him.
And then it also has a,
uh,
like a,
a fall feature where it senses if he's
going to fall,
then it locks up so it acts like a
kickstand.
And then he was talking about that
they're doing stuff like you were saying
where you could have thoughts and
eventually control it to say move
forward or kick hard.
Like you can start to give it more now,
which is kind of like,
you know,
stabilizes them so we can stand up and
he,
you know,
he walks with that.
But I mean you got to like walk and hold
his wife's hand for the first time in
four years,
like standing because he's a big dude.
And that's the biggest thing is,
is he just said hates being in a
wheelchair,
like going out because people,
because he's always talking to people
like looking.
You used to be in a big.
But the technology is pretty bad ass.
It's getting better all the time.
We,
uh,
we talked about that on the show
yesterday that there's now a soft
exoskeleton suit.
They used to be like,
they had these big hard exoskeletons
with like,
you know,
like metal pipes are rods down the sides
of it and joints and hinges.
The new ones are like way sleek.
They almost look like,
just like pants,
you know,
and there are those things that make you
like live like strong way stronger.
They make us stronger.
You can,
you can do things,
you can go longer,
you can go up hills.
Like for soldiers,
they're gonna enable soldiers to carry
much larger packs and they're gonna be
able to walk for much longer because
it's going to barely take any effort.
There'll be like 50 percent effort.
Yeah,
pretty crazy,
right?
Yeah.
I mean there,
there's just an endLess amount of super
smart people out there that are
constantly coming up with new inventions
that we're just like every now and then
one pops up on your google news feed and
you're like,
what the fuck?
Man?
It's like,
it's constant.
It's every day,
there's some new thing every day there's
some new breakthrough,
new technology,
new discovery that now they're saying
there was something that I tweeted
today.
They're saying there might.
The big bang might have caused a
parallel universe where time moves
backwards.
So we mIght have a mirror universe like
this universe is going this way,
right?
There's another universe that's going
on.
Exactly.
Taken his sat,
hating it.
No,
the opposite.
It's like the fucking earth has ended
and it's slowly forming back to the big
bang.
oh,
okay.
So who knows what time it is in this
other one?
If it's backwards,
I mean,
who knows where we are in the life of
the universe.
We know that we're like 14 point 7
billion years,
so if we're for or whatever the hell it
is,
if the universe is 14 billion years old
that this other one is 14 billion years
and the total opposite direction is
right when we die,
we get reborn in the new world and we
never die maybe.
Right?
Maybe qmap.
I mean,
we,
we assume that this is how time goes,
that you know,
you do this aNd you do thAt and you move
forward and you cloSe your laptop to get
in your CAR and you say goodbye,
but it's only because that's how we've
always lived.
Like the idea of everything going
backwards is incomprehensible.
But if everything can go forwards,
why can't it go backwards?
I meAn,
who's to say that things can't go back
to their source?
Who's to say that like you can't like
start off in some sort of a neutral
position and have everything
instantaneously be you when you're 90
and then slowly go benjamin button style
back to zero again and crawling your
mom's pussy.
I mean,
why not?
If you can come out of a person's pussy,
that's just as ridiculous as you going
back in it and,
and,
and reentering the hive of the universe
is just as bizarre to come out of a
pussy than it is for you to become an
old man.
And then a child in,
you have this other organism that you
recognize as your mother that is going
to take you into its body and it's going
to absorb your soul,
and then you pass into the next
dimension.
Then you're born on earth in our time.
Start over and start all over again.
Would you be happy if you knew you were
going to live your life as john heffron
over and over and over again?
Would you be willing to do this again?
If you knew that life really is like
some kind of a bizarre video game where
you're going to play the same character
ad nauseum to the end of the time until
you get it right?
Yeah.
Right?
Because so it is like a video game.
If you don't make it past level one,
then you go back and eventually I would
love that.
If there's a way you could talk to your
future or your past self to let you know
that what you want to know.
I don't know.
Sometimes I think that's what days you
have a movement.
Like if you haven't deja vu,
it's because you've done this a billion
times.
No,
no,
I don't think they.
I think they have a scientific
explanation for vu.
I forgot what it is.
It's something about your eyes.
It just.
It's like a half secoNd.
Taking the info.
Are we guessing?
It's a backfire against.
Why are we guessing?
Explanation idiots,
because we're all had passed at 70.
At a bar date.
Your watch is going to go.
That's not what it is.
How stuff works.
What is deja vu?
Here we go.
The term dejA vu.
It's french and it means literally
already seen those who have experienced
the feeling.
Describe it as an overwhelming sense of
familiarity.
That's what we all feel.
Right?
Right.
okay.
Let's see what the reason is.
The phenomenon is rather complex.
There are many different theories.
Okay,
so no one really knows.
Swiss scholar arthur hottest guys name
ready for this swiss scholar,
arthur funkhouser.
That's his fucking name.
Phone call.
He's my new favorite person.
Yeah,
arthur funkhouser.
Oh,
that would be the greatest character in
a movie ever.
The funkhouser a classic rock dj arthur
funkhouser was going to tell you about
deja vu.
how crazy is that?
Get them on your podcast.
He says,
have that guy on.
I know he will.
He lives in Switzerland.
Maybe I can.
Yeah,
we won them over there.
He asserts that in order to better study
the phenomenon,
the nuances between the experiences need
to be noted.
The examples mentioned above.
funkhouser would describe the first.
Oh,
so there's a bunch of.
Okay.
They believe there are several different
deja experiences.
There's deja visit tei,
which means already visited.
There's deja vec who,
ecu.
I don't know if I'm saying it right,
already experienced or lived through as
much as 70 percent of the population
reports.
Having experienced some form of deja vu.
A higher number of incidents occur and
people 15 to 25 years of age.
Huh?
That's bizarre.
It's been firmly associated with
temporal lobe epilepsy.
Reportedly,
deja vu can occur just prior to a
temporal lobe seizure,
so it doesn't mean that it's exclusively
connected to temporal lobe epilepsy,
but that it's connected to to.
I mean,
for some people have temporal lobe
epilepsy,
they experienced age.
I will not necessarily the other way.
Just because you have deja vu,
it doesn't mean.
I think that's what they're saying.
Well,
what the fuck dude?
So they don't really know.
Not as romantic when people go.
I just feel like we've been here before
together.
It's instead of night,
go ahead.
Kind of feels like a temporal lobe.
I think our software is just bugged.
Yeah.
I always associated with,
um,
with,
with simulation theory,
like,
uh,
the idea.
First of all,
just the idea that you could have
dreams,
you know,
you can have dreams.
Like I wrote about this dream.
I'm an instagram because I was in vegas
and I passed by this thing and they had
this wall,
this hotel,
and they would write down famous quotes
everyday on the wall and one of them
said,
if you can dream it,
you can do it.
Well,
I went to sleep.
I took four alpha brain that day kind.
I went to sleep and I had this dream of
a sex dream with mermaids.
So I put it on my instagram.
I had a dream that I could breathe
underwater and I dove into the ocean and
found a civilization of beautiful
mermaids.
They all sang gloria songs and
surrounded me with loving hugs.
One of them reached into my pants and
start jerking me off under the day long
continuous streams of beautiful flowers
came out of my dick and filled the water
around us,
and then I wrote,
so yeah,
walt disney didn't know what the fuck
you're talking about it.
It's like those dreams.
That's a real dream.
Just think about that dream like that
was a very realistic,
vivid dream,
a dream like that.
What is what's going on there?
Okay.
Obviously it's not really happening,
but when you're having a really vivid
dream that's completely ridiculous,
like you're in a fucking avatar dragon.
You're flying around while that's
happening,
you're,
you're essentially thinks,
yeah.
While you.
While it's.
I mean,
it just shows you how slippery regular
reality really is.
If you can have these experiences that
are totally ridiculous,
but yet while they're happening,
you buy them.
You know you,
you buy that.
You and your friend really are running
away from godzilla.
God's oh really is coming and the whole
city knows and you're running into
people that you knew from high school
and you're saying sorry,
and you know dudes,
you got in fights with your hugging
them.
We're all Together on this now we're
going to get the fuck away from
godzilla.
And then you hear and you hear that
fucking thing coming over the hill.
You,
you're there,
you're there.
And then you wake up and you gotta pay,
you know,
like what the fuck is wrong with me?
I really thought god godzilla's is real.
I had my,
I don't,
I'm not stressed about anything but I
had my reoccurring dream that I've had
since I was like a little kid.
It was basically somebody shows up at my
window suddenly like a appear in the
window like that and I start running
from him.
So I'll run up the stairs and then
there'll be a ceiling panel and then
I'll push it and then I'll pull myself
up and then I'm in like an attic and
then I'll run and there'll be another
little door and I'll slide that.
So I'm consTantly running from somebody
who's below,
but I have all these secret passages.
Then I was watching the discovery
channel and they had a thing about
ninjas.
This ninja house.
This guy got out,
he would move a sliding panel and he
went through and I go,
that's it.
That's why I enjoy fighting.
That's why I'm having this dream.
I was in ninja.
Not kidding you.
The thing they showed in thing was the
exact dream that I've had.
I think that that happens in almost
every ninja movie.
I know you've seen ninja movies.
that is a much better explanation than
you used to be.
A japanese dude back in the days where
there really were ninjas.
That seems like a bunch of generations
ago,
man.
What happened last life?
You know?
How come you remember that shit was
probably what?
The forties.
It was kind of boring.
I think they have a photo.
There's a photo that was just going
around recently.
Brian,
see if you can pull this up.
It's the last known photo of a samurai
and actual samurai before they somehow
or another,
the culture was abolished.
I don't know how they did that.
I mean they made it illegal to walk
around with swords or I don't know what
they did,
but this is a.
I think photographS were discovered or
were figured out in the late 18
hundreds,
I believe.
Right?
was that right?
Does that make sense?
So this guy existed with swords.
You know,
I'm walking around with a sword in the
18 hundreds.
I'm pretty sure this is the google
episode john had put them on.
I'm wondering,
you're dumber guests so I can't drop a
lot of those.
So not true.
That's not the photo that I saw,
but it might be another one that's
similar.
This last known photo of a samurai.
See if you google that will look at
that.
Dude,
that's what I googled.
You ever see those ninja classes like
that ain't the one I saw,
but it's still pretty dope in martial
arts,
like magazines or even online.
There's like guys that teach you how to
be a ninja.
They teach you how to send you a ninja
black belt and then you have to promise
you're going to watch the videos.
I'm serious.
I saw like a native american martial
art,
it was like indian martial art,
but that's what the guy did.
Oh yeah.
He sent you a black belt and then just
through the honor system in to watch the
dvds.
That's so.
Well that's just people trying to make
money.
That's the one thing about martial arts
is a.
You can.
You can definitely learn some things
from a dvd as long as you get one on one
instruction as well.
Like the originally get one on one
instruction like it.
It's way quicker path.
If you have someone showing you where to
put your weight,
especially jujitsu,
right.
It's hard to see what's going on.
like if you're watching the guys strike
like you're seeing things in real life
like you're seeing.
Whereas his chin is his placement.
It seems like there's less variables,
but when you're seeing jujitsu like you
don't know understand like where he's
his holding his balance and and how he,
how he passes the garden a certain way.
There's so many different things that go
along with like setting up a submission
has all these steps along the way that
are super critical because you've got to
know the defense of those steps and you
got to know the counter to that defense
and you've got to have two different
paths out of there.
You can't just have one.
So like while you're teaching someone
like a jujitsu,
like a setup for a submission,
you're also teaching them the defense of
that submission and you're also teaching
them like usually you're teaching them
what the counter is,
you know,
especially if they're like bluebell,
bluebell,
leverage,
something like that.
So there's just so many lIke to teach
that with a dvd,
it's so hard to do.
You can kind of teach basics like real
simple stuff and if you paid really
close attention,
you can kind of learn that,
but way harder.
it's way better to have somebody move
you like show you like here,
like not turn it like there and you're
like,
ooh.
Because it was like some like subtle
variations just in the way you hold a
choke,
right?
Because this guy who one in Brazil,
one of the last,
uh,
cars that we did.
No,
no,
no.
Mexico city.
He caught this dude in a good team and
he did this new thing that a lot of guys
are doing called the pretzel grip.
And like,
if someone doesn't show you how to do
that grip,
it seems.
It seems real weird.
Cavan mimic you doing that.
Yeah.
My friend was watching you on video.
My friend denny showed it to me,
but it seems goofy as hell,
but when you actually do it,
it really works.
It's awesome.
It's like this crazy new grip that guys
are doing.
That's one of those things like
someone's gotta like put your hands
there.
You got to show it to you.
You got it done to you.
Yeah,
exactly.
Exactly.
Getting it done to you is another big
one.
I've always been kind of like a workout
equipment or video whore.
I'm not so much lately,
but I would buy a lot of stuff.
And uh,
this was years ago,
I actually bought a,
it was a russian martial arts video of
how to fight and water.
I'm not kidding.
Whoa.
Yeah.
Oh,
you told me about this.
we actually talked about it on the
podcast,
I believe way back in the day.
oh,
good.
Mike,
I know you've told me this story though,
how to fight in a shallow pool and then
like
there's different techniques.
If you're treading water,
look at this.
This is a photo of a japanese dude about
to commit a ritual suicide.
Are that wonderfest real?
I want to pretend it's real,
so I don't want to even research it.
Find out if it's not real,
but this is all these different photos
from samurais 19th century.
So the 18 sixties,
the photos were taken in the late 18
sixties.
Literally those guys.
Well,
they weren't very tall.
You know what I mean?
Japanese folks back then.
Especially.
Is that guy doing it to himself or is
that a movie?
It looks like a movie,
but supposedly through.
Oh boy,
this chick was the same.
Right?
That's pretty hot.
I bet they did take photos.
Oh,
that chick samurais damn powerful chick,
samara.
I bet they did take photos of them
killing themselves.
Oh dude,
this one though.
This guy's bleeding and this one,
look at this.
This guy's fucking bleeding,
man.
He's actually doing it.
She's,
oh,
two data is dark.
So there's a photo of them sitting
around while this guy actually kills
himself and the blood's coming out of
his,
uh,
the top of his kimono and down into it's
like leaking down into his crotch area.
You see it and I'm still looking for it.
There's a lot of photos.
Yeah.
Go to the daily mail article.
Just it says,
end of the samurai stunning portraits of
japan's warrior class just ended the
samurai daily mail have ever taken a
martial arts weapons training stuff.
No,
I think we burned like on paper.
It's not like.
It seems like it'd be cool like David
Lee roth does the samurai swords.
Yeah,
that will be awesome.
And then you scroll down,
scroll down to one there,
right there.
That guy's killing himself.
We're hugging and they're all sitting
around just chilling.
It doesn't seem real.
Teenagers might not be posed like it's
like,
look at us,
we're,
but it might be real.
You know what I mean?
When you're dealing with someone that's
going to do a ritual suicide,
like the kind of willpower and then they
had to be as gangster as possible when
that guy is stabbing himself in the
stomach and cutting his guts open with a
sword,
it's probably.
That can be a real picture because it's
probably colorized whoever,
colored eggs,
like,
you know what?
Add this little.
Yeah.
Well I think that the whole photos got
to be colorized,
but they didn't have photos back then.
So this is all colorized.
The,
uh,
the photos that are black and white.
I kind of prefer a test.
I don't want to.
A shirley temple fakeness.
Yeah.
I don't want to see that,
that fake color.
I'd rather see a black and white and
know that that's what it looked like to
the person that was holding that camera,
that made that photograph and then
developed it.
It's really amazing when you think about
the fact that everything past like the
18 hundreds,
whenever it was,
when they invented
cameras,
everything past that is accelerated.
Like our visual understanding of the
world is accelerated in a,
in a way that we don't really think
about that much.
Like no one knew what the fuck africa
looked like back then.
Like if you were,
if you were living in Wyoming in 18,
20,
you have no idea what africa looked
like.
You had no idea.
No it United States look like somebody
tried to tell you.
Somebody trying to tell you about the
animals that were over in africa.
They might as well be talking about like
people that live on the moon,
what?
There's black people and there's other
plane and elephant.
Yeah.
You know,
they didn't even know gorillas were real
until the beginning of the 19th or the
20th century.
The 19 hundreds.
No,
they didn't go marry.
Well,
they were in the jungle and then like
one or two dudes that african people
knew they were real.
But I mean when we,
I mean us goofy white people to black
people.
We didn't know him.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
The discovery of the gorilla.
I'm pretty sure it was the early 19
hundreds.
Hold on a second.
This is the google show gorilla.
Great babe.
Okay.
Discovery of the gorilla.
Uh,
they had to have known before.
Right?
Because has no to discovered in 19.
Oh,
two nuts discovered on October 7th,
19.
Oh,
two on the ridges of the volcanic.
I don't know how to say this.
Virunga mountains by german explorer.
Captain Robert Vaughn,
burying b e r I n g dot the mountain
gorilla was named gorilla gorilla.
Been in gay.
In honor of the captain.
Yeah.
How fucking crazy is that?
So weird.
Yeah.
That was a conversation at work,
like the day after that were people are
like,
hey,
did you see that there's a thing like us
has hair all over it?
Well,
how about those dudes?
Those explorer dudes from the early 19
hundreds,
you know,
that would show up and you know,
they have like fucking their wives would
be with them and they tried to like make
camps in the Congo,
you know,
like that was,
that was the subject of so many movies.
Like that was the subject of king kong.
Remember this is an explorer.
They brought the actress and they showed
up with his island like and these like
the ghost in the darkness.
I remember that.
Yeah,
like the white people and all the black
people working for them.
They're making a railroad and africa
crazy.
Yeah.
This is a.
They have his,
uh,
this is pretty cool,
man.
They have is actual account of like,
of,
of meeting a girl for the first time
from our campsite,
we were able to watch a herd of big
black monkeys which tried to climb the
crest of the volcano.
We succeeded in killing two of these
animals and with a rumbling noise,
they tumbled into a ravine which had its
opening and a north easterly direction.
After five hours of strenuous work,
we succeeded in retrieving one of these
animals using a rope.
It was a big human like male monkey of
one and a half meters in height and a
weight of over 200 pounds.
His chest had no hair and his hands and
feet were of enormous size.
Unfortunately,
I was unable to determine its type
because of its size.
It could not very well be a chimpanzee
or a gorilla.
So they did know some gorillas.
In any case,
the presence of gorilla had not been
established in the area around the
lakes,
so they didn't know what it was.
This is so confusing.
Look at the photo brion pull.
Pull that up because it's a crazy
picture of this.
These people standing over this dead
gorilla.
This is one of the first gorilla.
So that's a mountain gorilla.
So,
but he said gorilla.
So that's kinda weird.
So what does that mean?
Like when did they discover the actual
gorilla?
So there's other kinds of gorillas other
than mountain gorillas.
Then that's the only thing that makes
sense to me,
right?
A physical characteristics,
discovery,
communications,
intelligence tool use interaction with
humans.
Here we go.
Okay.
Five hundred bc and implore explorer on
an expedition in the west african coast
encountered a savage people,
the greater part of whom were women
whose bodies were harry and who are
interpreters,
called gorilla.
The word was then later used as a
species name.
And although it's unknown whether these
ancient carthy gains encountered were
truly gorillas,
another species of apes or monkeys or
even humans.
Wow.
Okay.
So that was the first account of
gorillas.
It's written down.
That was 500 years before christ.
So the first westerner to see a live
gorilla was in 1856.
He brought dead specimens to the uk in
18,
61.
The first systematic study was not
conducted until the 19 twenties.
So yeah,
I mean they kind of knew about gorillas
back then that it seems like it wasn't.
Look at that thing.
Isn't that weird?
Fake god,
that face looks fake.
Yeah.
But they couldn't do fake back then to
fake that.
They had actually looks pretty real
dude,
if you will look at that face that face,
like get close up on it.
Like that thing that's a dead monkey.
But those mountain gorillas,
they have those chest plates,
you know,
plus you gotta,
you gotta realize that's like the worst
cell phone picture ever know.
That's what like the best pictures were
back then.
The best pictures.
I mean this is 18,
what?
It was at 18,
60.
What?
Yeah,
the dude had to set up that thing that
they didn't have flashback.
Now he's in 19,
19.
Oh,
two nine.
that's the 19.
Oh,
two picture.
Fuck man.
Yeah,
so that's the mountain gorilla.
So I guess like they had some different
species of gorillas,
but it wasn't really until the 1800 that
us white people started figuring out
that they were even real.
I think the first thing he does when he
sees him as he tries to kill him,
I know felt like the first like,
oh,
what's this?
I kill it.
Don't you think that's what happened?
If,
if aliens landed here,
I do think we shoot first.
They'll be like,
hey,
that's just what they.
Are there certain people that would
definitely shoot for.
Yeah,
there's,
there's people out there,
man.
Like it goes back to what we're saying
about cops.
Like there's some cops,
they're just getting out of the car
shooting right there.
They're looking to shoot.
Right.
And I think there's probably like some
human beings that have aliens showed up,
would do the same thing.
They would see the alien and they just
start shooting.
They wouldn't even think about if they
had a gun on them and they were worried
about their life off the alien.
Went like put,
put his hand out,
you know,
you,
you'd weird out if it was trying to
communicate with you,
like the,
you would have to be so vulnerable to
like allow an alien close enough to you
to communicate with it.
You'd have to assume that it's not going
to eat you.
Like,
how would you know?
could you imagine how stupid you would
feel if you came up to an alien?
You're like,
hello friend.
And it's like throws a net on your
cinches it uptight,
holds you up and take some selfies.
Yeah.
Fucking throws you in the back of its
spaceship.
And you'd be like,
fuck,
I should have shot him.
You know?
So who knows,
if they're like us,
maybe we should fucking shoot them.
They're.
Or maybe that brain thing where you can.
Your thoughts.
Good thing.
Maybe that's the piece of eQuipment we
need to actually talk to them.
Did you see a europa report is pretty
interesting.
Uh,
it's um,
it's a movie about these people.
It was a scifi movie about theSe people
that go to europa.
Europa is one of jupiter's moons And it
apparently has water on it.
I think it's jupiter's moon,
right?
So julie's mom.
apparently it's frozen solid.
It's a ball of ice.
And under the surface there's cracks on
the surface.
It indicate there's some sort of flowing
water underneath.
And so they,
they're trying to,
in this movie,
they go there.
I don't want to spoiler alert for
anybody but they go there and have
encounters.
But the way,
uh,
it,
like,
you think about like someone coming from
another planet and landing on your
fucking planet,
you're going to automatically assume
they're hostile is fuck yeah.
Like you're going to automatically.
Yeah,
yeah.
Aliens are dead.
They're dead or were dead.
That word that one of the other figure
there knows,
maybe they dIdn't.
Maybe they have really low testosterone.
Maybe they breed.
How about this?
What if aliens evolve to breed with no
sex?
So there's no competition for breeding
and the competition is all about
surviving against their elements and the
predators and their area.
So they don't have,
they don't have like this,
this male conquer thing like we do.
they're all androgynous.
That's why they don't have decks.
They don't have a giant,
they don't have big titties.
No aliens don't have beauty videos.
There's no twerking in the alien world.
They don't care about sex.
It doesn't mean anything.
The number one thing to us is sex.
It's like we need.
We have this crazy desire to procreate.
We have this crazy desire to be with
other people of the opposite or in some
cases the same sex.
It's a big factor for why people become
successful.
It's a big factor for why people sell
items that use beautiful women to sell
things and dudes with fucking six packs
of cell genes and jimmy dean sausage
isn't shit.
You know,
that's just a reality of being a human
being.
So it's really hard for us to separate
that idea from living organisms.
But like there's a lot of organisms that
don't have sex at all.
You know,
there's plants and some,
some fucking slugs and shit.
I guess they fucked,
but there they are,
the male and the female.
The male could fuck them.
They,
they're both like,
I think a slug is like one of those
things is by its bisexual in a weird
way,
not like you're in the chicks,
but the way you have both sexes.
They're hermaphrodites.
I got it.
Yeah,
and I mean we could have.
that could easily be the case with some
being from another planet and if that's
the case,
they might not understand aggression.
They might not understand how locked out
we are and then they just show up.
You know,
like if the aliens land and they show up
very hippyish were just,
they might not understand violence.
They might have somehow another grown up
in this goldilocks zone that's like way
better than our goldilocks zone where
there's no predators.
Everyone eats plants.
All procreation is all procreation is
done through like this mutual experience
of the entire tribe gets together and
has,
has babies together and that there's no
sex involved and it's all just
community,
friendship and love.
And then a child is born out of that
love.
That's just as look.
How weird is it?
You shoot a load in someone's pussy and
that's what makes a person that's
fucking ridiculous.
IT's so ridiculous.
It's not just as ridiculous to think of
a community of evolved beings and all
get together and hug,
you know,
and then out of that hug,
a tiny child appears and they all care
for it together.
That's just as possible.
And then they get lost,
show up on earth and we waste them
within 15 minutes.
Crazy.
Craziest pollen.
how crazy is the fact that plants need
bees to take pollen and pollinate their
fucking plants?
You know,
polly take flowers and distribute like
literally genetic material from those
plants distributed all around.
If that's a part of the whole ecosystem.
You have these bees that are responsible
for these plants growing and if these
bees die off,
everybody's freaking out.
Like what kind of lose the bees were
gonna lose society.
People are going to starve.
Like what?
Hold on.
we got workers.
We got these little worker bees that
they work for us.
We don't even know about It.
Like we need them to feel like they're.
They're important for almonds.
Like what would be the other day,
I didn't feel mother fucker,
you terrible person,
terrible person,
but think about that.
That's an actual reality of nature is
that bees pollinate plants.
It's a reality of nature.
It's so bizarre,
but it's responsible for like the
progression of plant life.
That's like a big part of how it goes
down.
Like I think there could be an infinite
number of different styles of life out
there in the universe.
And that's one of the things is europa
report thing was about,
wasn't the best movie,
but it held my attention.
It was interesting and it was about like
an alternative type of life that could
exist on a predictive aliens land.
It probably began to be skinny.
I would think they would be so slick
that they would be right here.
Right now.
We'd have no idea.
I think they're hiding in the asians.
There's so many asians in China and
stuff,
a lot of places to hide.
Well,
that's because they had a landmass over
there.
I think,
um,
that was one of my more stupid theories
when I was into the idea that human
beings are genetically engineered from
aliens.
They took people and they added alien
dna to people and that's why we're so
different from all the other monkeys
that exists.
All the other apes.
My big thing was that like they had like
different,
different levels.
Like they'll put like a little less
alien,
some people and there'd be like a little
less,
a little hairier like doing it.
A lot of back hair with the.
Yeah.
You ever go to the beach and see some.
Some fucking dudes are just.
Harry is iranian dude.
Get everyday the fucking iron sheik or
see an asian guy.
No hair at all.
You know,
the different,
complete different features.
Smart,
very,
very little body hair.
Notoriously good at mathematics.
That was my stupid theory that they were
more alien.
So dumb.
I,
I'm,
I'm forward.
So you know who's for it?
Dennis mckenna.
Really?
Dennis mckenna thinks it's very possible
that some sort of other advanced life
form has visited earth in the past and
subtly or actively re-engineered or
engineered human beings that they had
some hand.
He said it's possible and he bases that
on like a bunch of things like what we
would do if we could do it like if and
and the idea that we're a fairly young
planet lIke earth is only like four and
a half billion years old.
So the universe was around for 10
billion years before earth was or
somewhere abouts roughly.
That's a long time.
If something just had a 100,000
year headstart,
that's it.
That's all it needs.
100,000
year head start from where we are now
without blowing yourself up.
Could you even imagine what kind of
freaky shit we're going to be able to do
and 100,000
years is a blink of an eye.
So if we could show up,
see if the Congo was a planet instead of
like the Congo with these guys show up
and they start lighting these gorillas
up.
What if there was a planet and we found
this planet and it was all apes.
There was no people and we did like an
accurate survey.
The planet like tom cruise style,
we land in this fucking little white
outfits.
We've taken like biological for a guy in
a hot chick,
hot chick,
right?
And uh,
that he tries to keep me,
saved her life.
She gets an injury.
I mean,
that's just a scout parties.
You've got to do your own scale party.
Yeah.
You know,
maybe like you guys scale part of it
likes to tAke naps and he saw something
but you didn't,
you file for sure.
False reports,
travel.
And then there'll be like,
there'll be like a protagonist who's,
who's the,
they would have to be a woman that's
like a powerful woman,
like sort of balances it out.
Will you guys get that job done?
You're down on planet Congo,
get the job done and get back up here.
And maybe there's like cylons moving in
and we got to get back to the planet and
fucking.
But point being,
if we landed on planet Congo and there
was only monkeys,
if we thought that they were just like
the chimpanzees here,
for sure,
we'd steal a few.
RiGht?
Fuck yeah.
Are you kidding me?
If they knew that they could land on a
planet,
say if they found a planet,
you know,
whatever,
a light year away,
you know,
they figured out how to get somewhere in
a year and on that plan that they knew
there was live primates that were
exactly like chimps.
they're like,
oh,
this is what it is,
man.
These animals,
if you Give them enough time at this
temperature,
this is what you get.
if the temperature's higher,
you get dinosaurs.
If the temperature is lower,
you get woolly mammoths and you know
what I mean?
Like what if it's like a universal thing
in,
in the cosmos said,
all you need is water and carbon and all
the building blocks and the same life
forms exist everywhere.
If we find that out and we show up
someplace and we find monkeys were
stealing them.
Yeah,
for sure.
And we find that we go there,
there's parrots and anaconda is what
this is exactly like the rain forest,
and they're like,
exactly,
exactly.
But pretty sure we'll fucking steal one
of those monkeys.
Let's find out.
So there's the monkeys are the little
monkey community and monkey school
system and teaching each other what
sounds for anaconda.
What's the sound for,
for eagle that comes to steal you from
the trees.
They try to teach and we just go along
and go,
oh,
you're not smart enough for us to care
about your community.
And so getting the cage hooker clink,
shut that fucking box.
Push it into our space.
But.
And for the rest of their lives,
those chimps have to freak out.
Thinking about the time that this thing
came,
this metal disk and stole their mommy.
Go.
Yeah.
Some people wouldn't believe him.
We would do it.
Don't you think of it in a second,
but in a.
Do you think we would do it?
Yeah.
Yeah,
right.
If we were,
we knew,
oh,
they have bass,
large mouth bass on this lake.
We're steAling some of those bass.
They'd be like a guy in Texas,
they would have like a special leG you
have to pay just to catch bass
motherfucker and portraits of mars bass
that can totally be real.
Somebody tried to steal my dog out of my
backyard.
That's just here in America.
Yeah.
so of course we were doing so many
different.
You catch him?
Yeah.
That was a huge.
Um,
my wife said margaret's gone and my
other shepherd wasn't,
which is,
you know,
if you're a person,
it's weird that they're.
Do hooligans always are with each other.
One not going to go.
I'm not going to leave.
So I was in New York,
thought we lost it.
I'm cutting off too.
Sorry.
but I thouGht we lost our dog.
So it's day three
and I'm just beyond bombed.
I'm like,
my doG got out and where I live up in
the hills,
I'm like coyotes to doug.
She's kind of uh,
so uh,
you know,
she's probably dead.
So then before I go perform,
I just go to craigslist just for,
I just type in craig's list.
Then I go found or lost shepherd.
This ad pops up saying free dog and it's
a picture of my dog,
a super friendly,
well trained,
um,
you know,
had a list of all of her things.
And then a phone number.
Oh my god.
So then I called the guy and go,
hey bud,
like I'm excited.
Like,
yes,
you know,
you found my dog.
Thank you.
And the guy goes,
well,
she didn't have a tag on her.
I'm like,
she always has a tag.
She must've got out and then the tay got
got taken off or her collar,
which is in pot like that doesn't happen
unless she hits a picket fence and rips
it off.
So I go,
but you have my dog.
And he goes,
well,
it doesn't have a tag,
so I don't know if it's your dog.
And I go,
it is my dog.
And then I even sent the guy a picture
of her that you would match up and go,
those are my dogs.
And then the guy says,
uh,
well In a dog owner that lets their dog
get out,
probably doesn't deserve to have that
dog.
So now I'm like,
motherfucker,
are you not going to give me my dog?
He goes,
I gave the dog away.
I already,
somebody already called the door thing
and I go,
you had my had my fucking dog,
do we do,
can I have the number to the person that
you gave the dog to?
And he's like,
no.
So now I'm going crazy.
Like,
now I'm like,
motherfucker,
blah blah blah blah.
So then I called my wife,
I go,
I found the person who has a dog but
they're not going to give it to her.
So then I even posted it on my fan page
and there's some cops in,
in this area is like,
if you have his phone number,
we'll,
we can,
we can go to a guy's house and say,
I mean,
that's because somebody said that still,
you know,
he has stolen property so you have a
little bit of recourse.
So,
uh,
I'm uh,
at gotham in New York,
you know,
the door guys that work there,
they're all old tops,
like great,
great guy.
So he goes to one of the guys,
goes put the guy on the phone with me,
get me on the phone because I'm going to
tell him I would hate it.
It's too bad you committed suicide over
the last doc.
It's too bad you decided to like,
he was like,
this is how you talk to that guy.
You go stop being.
So my wife calls him and then he ends up
giving the number two of who has my doG
now to my wife,
right?
So then my wife calls this woman and
this woman says,
well,
I've watched the dog for two days now,
um,
you know,
I've spent a lot of money on food but
boss.
So my wife goes,
this is,
I didn't hear this conversation.
It wasn't happy about this.
She goes,
I'll give you.
I have 150 bucks cash on me.
Can I come anD get my dog and I'll give
you 150 bucks because you were nice
enough to watch the dog for.
So my wife now keep in mind,
now I'm in New York and this is like 11
o'Clock at night,
right?
La time.
So now I'm like,
don't drive to some random person's
house,
you know,
you're crazy.
So she does.
Anyway,
I'm drives an hour and a half away.
So kate,
from where your podcast is that there's
a doG park that's pretty close to here,
right?
Would anybody be hanging out at the dog
park here and then drive home an hour
and a half.
You don't do that in los angeles,
like nothing's making sense.
So then she drives to this person's
house by herself.
Has my other shepherd in the,
in the jeep.
This woman comes out with our doG and
she,
the woman goes,
I still don't know if this is your dog.
And literally as the woman I guess as
you're going to have to prove it,
margaret bam just takes off,
you know,
like lunges for my wife and was just
whimpering and stuff like that.
The woman grabs a hold of margaret's
collar and then my wife has the collar
and then my wife's like,
now I gotta throw it on with this bitch.
Like she goes,
I have to just start punching this older
woman in the face to get her to let go
of my dog because now it's a so then my
other shepherd jumps out of the jeep,
like the the driver's side window was
open and the other shepherd jumps out of
that window because there's now there's
kind of a fight going on and then my
wife has 150 bucks cash.
She throws it like she literally makes
it rain.
She grabs,
she needs an extra hand to grab the
other dog now and the woman let's go of
of my dog and starts like the money was
going to disappear,
starts reaching for the money falling
and my wife just grabbed both of them
and threw them in a car and she said
she.
She took off because she was like,
this is not.
This is not so long story short.
That's crazy.
That dog in the guy.
WHat dude?
I've never.
I've never even had the thought of
actually physically wanting to kill
somebody.
Like you say,
I'll kill that guy,
but you never really like really think
of it.
I'm like,
dude,
this dude came into stole my dog and is
now saying he won't and,
and I have his info now,
but now this guy knows where you live
and uh,
you know where this guy lives?
No,
we don't.
He doesn't know where I live.
I mean he made he Got your dog.
Well that's true if that like,
but I don't know,
how am I,
I have a privacy fence around my
backyard.
So it's pretty dog friendly.
You as a dog,
you can't scale the wall or get out.
So someone had to get in.
I don't have anY proof of any of that,
but something happened.
So you don't know if this lady is sold
or this got sold that lady that dog or
gave that lady that dog.
He said he gave it to her,
but I think a or anywhere.
I think they were running a,
hey,
have your dog give me money.
Some money scam.
Even though that seems like a lot of
don't know.
How would they do that?
Because you contacted them.
They'Re just hoping that you would find
them.
YeAh.
So come on.
that's a ridiculous scam.
They would maybe contact you and say,
hey,
I have your dog,
but anybody's going to run a scam like
that.
They're not going to put it in
craigslist or wherever you found it.
Yeah,
so we found it.
Yes.
I gained craigslist like random.
I just type the city I live in and
shepherd and a picture of her,
she showed up.
That's so crazy.
Right?
Or like I can't figure out like what
happened.
Like none of like you said,
if it's somebody who's just trying to
steal dogs and sell the,
the really shitty at it because there's
a way easier way to do it.
Maybe it's all about that.
The movie lost and found with david
spade.
Seven,
seven psychopaths.
That's what the dude in seven
psychopaths did with the dog.
Well,
I think it could be like,
well,
I eat that.
I have people around me that sometimes
will call and say,
your dogs are barking.
This.
This was a while ago,
there was a problem and then this person
would throw oranges from his side over
into my yard or like eggs and stuff like
that.
And Then he would call and say,
your dogs are back.
they're constantly barking.
And that would go,
yeah dude,
because you're throwing,
you're throwing shit at them and you're
having conversations with them.
Of course they're going to bark at
somebody on the other side of the fence.
So who knows if like a neighbor,
like had somebody.
I don't know.
My,
my ex girlfriend,
crazy shit has happened.
My ex girlfriend had a dog and I think
because it barked all the time,
I think somebody poisoned it by throwing
a piece of food over the side of her
fence and then the dog died or it would
tell me what you think about that.
Speaking of tHat.
All right.
so my dog,
uh,
I would always put like if I was making
peanut butter sandwich or something,
I get like a scoop of peanut butter and
I,
and I get the spoon.
I know you guys had never been to one,
have a spoon at my house.
But I would like turn this boon and the
dogs would lick the peanut butter on the
spoon.
A kind of after all this happened,
I,
I will put out a spoon with peanut
butter on it and show short towards
margaret.
Her ears flip back and she takes off.
She won't even come by me.
Oh wow.
So right.
Because dogs learn something.
So something shady happened.
Like you said.
I have.
No,
I have no.
Well those dogs are really smart to.
Shepherds are very smart.
They're very quick.
Yeah,
they don't.
You don't got to tell him twice.
They usually those are dogs or you have
to be like real active with.
Because they get bored,
you know,
that they can't just lay around like a
bulldog,
like one of those english bulldogs.
Those are fat,
lazy dogs.
They'll just lay around.
Shepherds would be like,
okay,
I gotta get out of this yard.
I got to figure out where it was.
Fucking yard.
They'll climb trees and shit.
You know,
they'll escape there.
Get bored.
Yeah.
Or smartest shit.
That's where the good police dogs,
shepherds and those other ones that look
like shepherds was belgian and ellen was
like,
oh yeah,
matt malamutes.
Malcolm was,
I think they're called the malamute,
two different dogs.
I've never owned shepherd prior to these
two nights and they're great.
I've had like golden retrievers like,
but my shepherd's aren't like,
people are afraid of them because they
look,
you know,
if you see them,
you go,
uh,
that's
there.
That my brother and his wife,
they have rottweilers and I've never
been in it for.
You just have mentally in your head
like,
oh,
rottweilers are rough.
They couldn't be a nicer dog.
Those are good dogs.
Like if you raised right.
I had a buddy of mine who had a really
good one.
It was a sweetheart.
The drunk kids like him,
five-year-old,
he earth.
He's three liaison.
The rottweiler,
like he's watching tv and the dog will
just sit there and I started wrestling
with them a little bit or like tickle
fighting.
The rottweiler came in between us and
just kind of plopped down just to kind
of go,
okay,
we've had enough of the tickle fight.
Dogs are interesting because so much of
a dog's personality is based on the
breeder and how well the breeder takes
care of the parents.
And the generations before,
like I got this dog that's a regency
mast,
if you ever seen my tongue.
Yeah,
his dad was on fear factor and his dad
was so chill.
He was just such a sweet dog.
He's just hanging out.
Like he was just like real calm and like
real sweet.
But then he used them as an attack dog.
Like he had a big dog.
So you like taken out people in those
big attack dog suits and this guy,
he won't even breed dogs if they have
any aggression towards people because
any growlin or barking at eight,
like he'll try and take their food away.
He'll do all kinds of different things
to test them and he'll,
he's always kind to them.
But if they show any sign of aggression
towards people,
he doesn't breed them.
And so because of that he has is like
really calm,
really sweet,
really confident dogs.
And a lot of like dog breeds depend upon
who's raising them.
What qualities are trying to get out of
the dog.
And if they're really strict like this
guy joe was,
then you get like this amazing dog.
Like my dog,
johnny,
he's like the sweetest dog ever had.
He's so friendly.
Like I,
I,
my,
my four year old will bring friends over
and they'll play with him.
I have no fear.
It's just a gentle giant.
Like he.
He's never even.
I've seen dogs bite him and he doesn't
even fight back.
He's like,
hey,
what the fuck man?
Why you whitened me?
No,
he's just a big sweetie.
Just to kind kind dog that I have
visions now because I'm looking at
property in the midwest.
Just for you doing john heffrons exit
strategy.
Trying to fucking prep us.
Yeah.
You're a prepper where I just want to
sit in a lawn chair with one of the,
like those tennis about things.
We go to unc and it shoots the tennis
ball and let my dog do sprints.
So you jusT want to like train them.
I just want to sit there.
I think that would be the greatest.
Just spring day.
Just sit there.
I knew a dude who went through one of
those.
Sun training is some that is.
I try to do it with my,
with margaret,
but that they said she was too friendly,
like kit,
the agitator,
because you need to get a little bit of
it and they're like,
yeah,
she doesn't.
That's fine.
He just wants to.
Yeah.
How old was she when you try to do it to
her?
Whatever.
A year,
year and a half.
Like they say you shake your shake like
a candle to make a lot of noise and some
dogs will take off and their dogs will
go to it like so it all,
you know.
Hm.
LIke whether or not they're aggressive.
Yeah.
Like if there.
But there's levels of that training I've
seen.
Did you see that?
There's a facebook video.
This guy just says a couple of words and
there's a fight like so guys are
fighting.
The guy says some words and then the
shepherd runs to the baby and sits there
and then one,
one of the guys fighting turns to then
go towards the baby.
The shepherd goes,
nope.
And attacks to get like the guys in
suits,
but they're like doing drills and the
train this.
So they're like those.
You ever seen those a dupont registry
magazines.
It's like all like weird rich people.
Shit like watches the cost half a
million bucks.
And rob report.
Robb report.
Exactly.
They always have those pages In there
that are dedicated to these train german
shepherds and you see them sitting there
guarding a crib.
Loyal guardian and like what I do for a
living that.
yeah,
it was a lot of people out there that
are just worried too.
I would totally staring out the windows
was my fucking killers.
Tack dog.
You know what I watched the other day?
A elephant in the living room.
What are you guys doing over there?
Oh the.
Yeah.
The ads are on every one of them.
I used to get that magazine.
The magazine itself was like an alien
because it was just fun to like go
through like what movie?
Oh fuck.
What was I going to say?
Elephant in the room.
Oh,
elephant in the room.
Elephant in the room is a movie about
all these people that keep exotic pets
in their home.
Like lions and shit.
Like this guy had this weird
relationship with this lion and it would
go in the cage with a lion and hug it
and he's like,
this lion,
you know,
kept me alive.
If I didn't have this line,
I would have been dead.
You know,
I had my broke my back in a truck
driving accident.
I was all fucked up on pills and I got
this lion and it's like,
it's so weird.
It's so weird watching this.
It's like,
don't they eventually kill you like a
lion would even though you know you're
friendly.
Anything just have a bad day.
And just sometimes they do.
Sometimes they do,
but I think if you pay attention to all
these motherfuckers that have lines and
how few of them actually wind up killing
them.
I think if you train them correctly and
you were there all the time,
it's probably at least reasonably safe
when they seem to attack is when they
get agitated.
like the siegfried and roy thing.
Yeah.
They're like,
I'm not there were thin.
We're thinking that it might've been
because some lady in the audience had
some crazy hat on and that the tiger
might've seen that hat as like a cobra,
like something,
a peacock,
some fucking crazy animal like remember
in jurassic park when the fucking Wayne
Knight is trying to steal and that thing
shows up in the car with them.
Like maybe that's what the tiGer thought
that hat was like something similar.
Like something alerting him that it was
about to attack will show is talking the
whole time or just as
a performer.
The tigers,
you know what?
Fuck this second show friday they said
that it wasn't even trying to kill him.
It was just dragging them out of there
and that it didn't.
It had no idea like the biting him on
the neck would just crushes vertebrae
because it's just so strong.
It was trying to just get him out of
there.
I don't know if I buy that and I think
he just got sick of working for him.
It could have a guy got killed a couple
of days ago or he got mauled,
went into a line enclosure,
climbed in.
It's like the third guy this year,
there was an indian guy that got killed
by that big white tiger.
Do you remember that?
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
Oh my god.
That was the most ridiculous.
Whenever you guys on hIs knees,
like annoying the shit out of the tiger
by praying.
He's like,
ooh,
he won't stop.
And finally tiger's.
He's like,
hey,
you fucking annoying bitch pam.
He grabs him and just drag them over to
the other side of the enclosure,
like he's a pillow.
Have you seen it?
Know when to watch it.
Put It up on this thing here so we don't
get pulled from youtube.
We have a strategy now for,
what is it showing videos.
Oh yeah.
Well we keep getting pulled from
youtube.
Every time we show videos now we don't
really show them,
so sort of show them over on that side.
So it's not the actual video playing on
our youtuBe channel.
Gotcha.
I get it.
You know,
they're trying to not have anybody steal
a views from them,
but I think it probably in the long run
gets you more views Because people don't
want to see it just on the podcast.
They want to tell their friends about
it.
Did you hear the link?
And then they're gonna go to the actual
length.
But I get it.
I guess they called fair use.
I don't know what Fair use is.
I'm not exactly sure.
It seems debatable.
There's like a debatable definition for
fair use.
Anyway,
this fucking dude gets jacked.
That's what's important.
John fraud.
This guy gets fucking jacked and he's,
for whatever reason,
he thinks it's smart to uh,
to fucking keep praying.
Like the tiger gets like right on top of
him and he just,
he doesn't stay still,
he doesn't play dead.
He just keeps bobbing back and forth and
up and down,
back and forth and up and down.
And eventually the tigers like,
all right,
I seen enough.
Yeah.
Oh we have to sIt through an ad.
It's an indian ad,
but these are americans.
What's going on?
They speak in english.
What state farm is that?
What it is?
I always showing that I don't want to
see this video as disturbing images not
suitable for children de a lady.
this lady all excited to show this.
Look at tHis fucking animal hovering
over that dude.
My god.
That's when it's killing him.
Like this is him dragging them off.
like you can kind of see it unpixelated.
well that you can get a better video,
brian.
You can get a real video.
You don't have to show this one.
There's real videos that show the actual
like thing in front of them like this,
but he's moving around.
But who fall Indiana jumped in.
I think he went to intuit it on his own.
Can find the other one.
You could actually see it because you
see the guy like he's for whatever.
Right?
That's the upper one.
Yeah,
forever.
Whatever reason.
He's like,
he won't stop moving.
Yeah.
The daily motion is going to give you
the real deal.
Daily motion in live leak.
Those are dark websites.
Yeah.
Here it is.
Lively doesn't fuck around.
Look at this.
This guy is just sitting there and
there's this giant beast look scenes
constantly moving and the cat is like,
you're not supposed to be here.
fucker.
Why you moving so much?
Yeah,
I mean it's.
What can you do there?
That feather in front of my cat.
My cat events.
Look at him.
Yeah.
Oh my god.
This is so hard to watch.
You're not getting out because if the
tiger can't get out,
you can't get out.
That thing can jump 14 feet in the air.
It can't get out.
You're fucked.
So you're just going to have to get
eaten.
Son.
This is.
I don't think there's any other way
around it.
What do you do?
Do you get up and go,
hey,
I'm going to go over here real quick.
Can you try to think of the zoo people
will be coming out with.
They're like,
what the fuck they do in India?
That's probably one dude.
He's probably like,
yeah,
cleaned the monkey cage right now.
He's over euros chick like it's a mine
in the tiger cage.
What?
Hold on.
He's got a text.
Text comes in and he's to text her.
Hold on,
I go back.
there's a man at a tiger cage.
What?
This tiger is getting annoyed with this
dude.
I think people were like yelling at him
to like,
hey,
you get the fuck away from here.
Oh shit,
this is the tiger moved in these
dummies.
They're focusing on people's sneakers
because they're not paying attention.
See tHese fuckheads shitty video here.
Here it is.
Oh my god.
it's fucking him up.
So he goes down.
Oh my god.
See that when it like pulled.
Oh,
and here's where it gets dark.
It just grabs him by the neck and just
carries them away.
Look at that.
Look how easy It karen.
Yeah,
right.
And that guy,
and he's like 130 pounds.
Probably 140 character is nothing jumps
over ravine with them.
I mean it's got this enclosure,
it's like a swimming pool type thing and
it just goes right up the side of it.
Like it's nothing.
Oh,
what a way to die.
I mean,
what a dumb idea in a goofy way to die.
But like lions,
there's a guy that made it into a line
and closure and he was trying to convert
the lion to christianity.
whereas yeah,
there's a video of that and alliance
just start fucking him up.
Pull that,
pull that up.
LIon tries to convert man to
christianity.
It's,
it's,
it just fucked this dude up.
It's hilarious.
There's
people in 2014 still want to give it a
try.
Yeah,
just fucking.
I think I can get in there and just this
line needs to be done with jesus.
Poor bastard.
Look at this.
He's out there proselytizing to lions.
Look is waving his hands.
I think this was in China.
Am I correct?
Yeah.
Okay.
This guy,
he's standing there just annoying the
shit out of alliance.
They're not even fucking with them.
Look at that.
Oh my god.
it just finally just sat down and he's
getting a rash.
Like,
listen,
I know you're lashing out,
but it's because you don't have the lord
that lions scratch the shit out of him.
But look,
the lion doesn't want anything to do
with them.
The lich not trying to kill him.
Just this fucking dummy just won't get
ghost.
Yeah,
we get this.
Oh,
you bitch it just bit him.
oh motherfucker not.
Not trying to kill him.
He just doesn't want him.
Does.
Doesn't want him around.
He needs to figure out a way to get the
fuck out of dodge and then the white.
He's so stupid.
He.
Oh shit.
Oh,
it's clawing at.
It bites his leg.
Oh my god.
That has to hurt.
Yeah.
Oh my god.
This guy's lucky.
That lion is like really sweet.
That's a nice light.
They get lost a couple of times.
The line has to attack him.
I mean it's like lot.
I don't remember either.
I don't think he does.
As a matter of fact,
I think he makes it through this,
but the lion actually just doesn't want
him there and he standing there.
May christ compel you.
Oh,
this guy's got a gun out.
Ready to shoot the line.
The case of the lion takes.
He should shoot that guy.
That's what he should do.
You fucking idiot.
by the power of christ.
The lion lies down in front of them.
Jesus made that lie and lie down.
Yeah.
Now the guy's going to get cocky and
walk forward.
Oh,
they're got a tranquilizer dart it.
They should just tranq him shooting him
right in the dick.
Fucking retard.
What kind of a dumb ass.
They got their stretcher ready.
They know this guy's bleeding profusely.
Okay.
they tracked it.
They drank the cat's wow.
They trank the cats for a dumb ass.
look at him.
He's okay at a big ass bite and his leg.
They stitched him up.
What a dummy.
God damn.
people are silly.
Jon [inaudible].
What the fuck is that about?
That his wife was like next to him like,
are you going to beat this guy's ass or
goodness.
Whose wife the the line.
I just pretended that that other line
that was confused,
like,
how do You know?
There's like 10 people around.
how do you know who's married to who?
John half run with magical powers.
Do you have?
My wife called me out on that.
She used to watch the kardashians and
I'd always just go.
It's just making it just it gum.
It makes you dumber than human being
watching.
But the one of the husbands on there,
I don't know enough,
the guy who looks like a psycho white
dude with his slicked back hair.
Do you guys know whatever,
whatever his name is,
but they know who I'm talking about.
He's married to the older sister.
Every time he would see that as a joke,
I will look at my wife and go.
If I ever saw that guy,
I would kick them right in the head.
The first thing I would do that to me so
much.
You have to watch it to see.
He kind of gets under your skin.
It seems like an unreasonable way to
deal with people.
So I would go,
man,
I would just.
I would kick the guy right in the head.
He just seems like a thing.
So we're in calabasas.
This was,
you know,
after me saying this,
every single time I've ever seen the
show,
we're in calabasas at the bookstore.
I'm walking down the aisle with my wife.
He turns into the aisle and starts
walking towards us.
And then the whole time he's walking
towards us.
My wife has gone,
well,
here's your chance.
Here's your,
BIg guys.
He's coming right now and then part of
me was like,
okay,
do I got to kick him in the head just so
I get street cred with my wife or
whatever when we obviously walked by him
and then my wife goes,
I'll talk.
You just all talk.
Yeah,
that game's no fun because.
Because last night we were at the comedy
store and louis ck was playing and we
have the same thing and my girlfriends
is leonardo dicaprio and they fucking
walks by leonardo.
Yeah.
You can't play that year over whatever
It is,
whatever it's called,
they you get one celebrity to hook up
with.
Not if you live in la because you have
chances that you're going to run in.
That's you know.
No way.
If you're a leonardo dicaprio,
you probably can't live anywhere other
than la.
Like leonardo dicaprio tried to move to
Nebraska.
Like people would like.
There'd be like tours.
People would Fly out.
Like that's where leonardo dicaprio is.
We'll go out to his.
He's got a farm up there in Nebraska.
Like I remember there was a thing about
val kilmer,
like val kilmer had a uh,
a place that he put out in a New Mexico.
Yeah,
yeah.
He had some crazy ranch.
I think he still does,
but like he just retired some ranch in
New Mexico and everybody would just be
like walking around the ramps,
like a fucking batman lives in that
place and he was fucking ice from top
gun,
you know?
And yeah,
he lives in this,
this ranch that's like right there.
and everybody would be like,
what the fuck?
It's almost like you want to like go
there just to see if it's real.
Like you'd want to like look over the
hedges,
like what's going on over there.
I can imagine if you're him and you
just,
every time you leave your house to a
bunch of people peering over your
hedges,
staring at you,
you have a.
If you're really famous you have to stay
in la because then that way you get
watered down a little.
LIke it just naturally you.
Well you definitely get watered down
like,
yeah,
sure.
At to the gym that I used to go to,
I'd walk in there at any given time,
the rock would be there,
alec baldwin,
the sweetlife life is zack and cody
kids.
And then every famous porn star.
But it was really weird because you just
see and tHen you know,
you just signed a treadmill next to the
rock and after like week two,
it was just like,
yeah,
you get used to some people.
I watched a guy go up to the rock,
the rock always did you have headphones
on.
And when he's like lifting,
he kinda has this look of,
I'm,
I'm working out,
you know,
it kind of has to.
So uh,
so this guy walks over to him and says,
hey,
could you,
could you help me out?
And you saw him,
he took off his head,
you know,
he was mid workout.
He's like doing squats or something.
Ask somebody.
But the rocks is probably one of the
nicest guys I've ever seen.
Like on a side note,
like I've seen him on flight at 6:00
in the morning tea with his head up
against the window and hat down and
little kids tapping on them and then he
put his head up,
throw on the smile,
signed for the kid and then go back to
sleep for a second to the next kid and
he's never not seen him be cool like
that.
So at the gym he walks over to the guy
and I'm now I'm just like staring at the
guy goes,
I'm going to do these preacher curves.
Can you tell me if I'm doing them right?
Oh girls like the one,
like probably the only weight lifting
technique.
You don't need actual post my like a
squat.
You could go my doing tHis.
Okay.
But like a curl I felt so bad for.
And then mid curl can we be friends?
So what are you doing later?
I mean we need to go.
Let me leave a voice message from my
wife.
Will you go facetime with my kids?
He's hercules.
Kids get very excited to facetime with
hercules' girl's dead man.
That dude who jump on a stairmaster or
whatever,
there was no nobody next to him.
Within seconds there'll be dumb,
dumb,
dumb.
Everybody.
Yeah.
He's a super huge dude.
He's gigantic.
Could you want me to.
I've seen them in different phases of a
pussy magnet almost.
I mean,
it must be like a black hole,
like a singularity of sexual attraction.
He's like six foot three,
right?
Six threeish boarish.
Someone else built like a brick shit
house and he's a movie star goes lower.
Seen those pictures that he would.
Probably not that he posts pictures on
instagram when he's working out.
Yeah.
Like his cheat days are like the
legendary legendary for big,
huge pizzas and never seen anything like
that in your life.
Yeah.
IT's legendary.
What is this car?
That's just the part of the diet is just
like one day a week you can eat.
Like,
I'm just like crazy man.
Yeah.
Some guys do that.
They're super strIct except one day and
um,
one day they just go off your brow.
You know?
Remember when eddie bravo yesterday and
sunday,
I think it was,
and he would just the ice cream,
huge sundaes pizza.
He would be like atkins,
atkins for five days,
six days rather.
Sometimes you'd go five days to do like
two cheat days,
but it would be super strict on those
atkins days,
like all salads and meats and very
little carbohydrate other than like
natural carbs.
So would come from fruits and vegetables
and things like that.
Yeah,
and then the the last day was just
donuts and pizza.
You go off like a rocket and you didn't
give a fuck and he lived for those days
and then they started starting those
days like midnight on thursday,
three days and four.
Then it's like,
I'm on atkins one day a week.
They do it on mondays.
Atkins is weird,
man.
That's not.
Nobody really follows that anymore.
Like people would say that it gives him
bad breath and I guess the.
The idea behind it is if you have no
carbs like that,
your body just starts to living off fats
and you can do it I guess as long as you
like.
Really make sure you have the right
amount of fats.
I tried it for a little while,
man,
and it made me really feel weak,
like I didn't feel good cutting out like
potatoes and all that stuff.
I think cutting it the best I've ever
felt with like an experimental diet.
It was cutting out gluten and I know
that's like a fad thing to say like that
and it's so sad that people don't wanna
admit anymore,
but the reality is this is the simple
reality.
The reality about breads is they break
down and become sugar.
Pasta becomes sugar.
That's the real issue.
I think more so than like gluten
intolerance and a lot of these other
things that people claim.
I think the amount of gluten that we
have in our diet from sandwiches and
breads and pastas and things along those
lines,
the amount is a lot of sugar that goes
into your body and that's just not
healthy.
It's just spikes your levels.
Your insulin gets all out of whack.
It's just not healthy to have a regular
sugar intake of processed wheat,
you know all that shit.
That's like a normal part of the
american diet.
It's just not that good for you,
but you know a little bit every now and
then was no big deal.
It's like if as long as you eat mostly
like healthy foods,
you could fuck around a little bit every
now and then your body's getting all the
nutrients it needs and you just sort of
rewarding it with that other stuff is
the problem is when people have a diet
that's primarily reward and then
occasionally they fuck around with some
lettuce.
You know what I mean?
Like that'S smoothie smoothie today.
Some good fucking people.
Especially if you're working all the
time,
you're tired,
you know,
you're at the office.
I'm just going to grab some jack in the
box the way over.
You can get in that fucking,
you know,
I'm trying to figure out on the road.
This is the,
how do.
I mean I'm,
I'm skinny,
but I'm starting to become skinny fat.
Like do workout big.
Um,
yeah,
do a little bit.
You don't box with anybody anymore.
You're saying stuff that I've kind of
just a workout.
I don't know.
I'm kind of bored with them,
so I'm trying to figure out what my new
thing is.
When you get like a personal trainer and
in those towns,
you know,
you could do that.
find someone at the gym,
they'll put you through like a weight
lift and work out.
That'd be fun.
You'll have forced you to do it.
So I need like a,
like a.
Yeah.
Because my,
my new thing was I'm going to go thing,
I'm going to do pull ups,
dips,
pushups,
and then I'm going to do sprints and
then that's going to be it just in case
I ever get arrested.
Then I've started my prison workouts.
Um,
just because I don't.
Yeah,
I got to figure out something because
I'm at that line,
you know,
when,
when you go.
Okay.
I think everybody at some point,
if you look at them,
they look like they've given up and
sometimes that decision is,
is later in their lives where I think
I'm teetering at that,
at that decision
going,
I might just give up one doughnut that
never work out and just be done.
Um,
what was that book that you gave bill?
Some workout book?
Bodyweight workout book?
Yeah.
It's just um,
her name is like,
it's a weird like della rae,
r I e like if you go visual workouts in
just type that name,
it's called visual workouts.
It's 100 at her book Is like a hundred
body weight.
She's just rushing chick.
But what she does is she has,
she calls the workout like,
like movie titles,
like highlander on batman.
So then batman will be like 40 punches,
40 pushups,
you know,
she has a whole thing and then you have,
do you go through it three times?
Seven times.
So for me it's just like a fun no
brainer.
I can do it in the,
in my hotel room.
I just turn the page and she gives away
the book for free on our website.
You can download the pdfs.
I ordered the book from amazon because I
didn't feel like printing it up on my
printer.
That's so cool.
What's it called again?
Go.
Um,
hold on.
I'm going to look up my,
uh,
visual workouts by nela re already.
Why?
Yeah,
go check out her her website.
I watched.
Okay,
cool.
One video of hers.
She's like just rushing chicken.
She used to be a fighter.
She used to think,
do you know ne ne I l a?
Yeah.
Yeah,
I would say neil,
but neil re work out cards by neil aura.
She has a website.
Any I l o r e y.com.
The book that I l a r e y.com.
So the book that I had,
I,
like I said I just bought it.
She gives it away for free but I didn't
feel like a printing it all up.
Oh that's cool.
Download and print.
I love that.
she's given away for free.
I think.
Here's her thing where she gives like
you'll see some of these workouts that
have 500,000
downloads and then she has a a donate
button and then she goes,
I don't try to sell you anything on here
if you ever feel like donating.
So I think it's a numbers game.
If 500,000
people downloaded her,
her ab challenge,
you know,
in a few of those people go,
you know what,
I'm going to throw her 20 bucks for
giving out.
I bet you she does.
Okay.
Yeah.
Well now maybe she'll get more,
you know,
it sounds cool though.
I liked that last one you circled was
the pillow one.
She has a lot of like weird stuff.
Like I say like throw nice to the pillow
pillow strikes like you're walking a
wall with a pillow pillow.
Lunges.
How weird.
But she does that with like your,
your carry on luggage and then she has
these other workouts where you just put
like four strips of tape on the ground
and you do a bunch of stuff with that.
You do.
So I just,
paige and I pick whatever you.
I flipped the book and I like do that.
Like throw a dart and guts.
Pretty dope.
Here's the love it man.
It's pretty good stuff.
Love it.
And then you can change up the,
you know,
the,
I haven't been able to do one of hers
more than like three times through
because then I,
then I get bored.
But uh,
you know,
he could add more challenges to it and
stuff.
That's interesting.
I like that she's doing it that way,
that she's a releasing them for free
online and ordering,
like having like a paypal button or
something like that.
That's cool.
Yeah.
If you want to give her five bucks for
it.
But she has like 90 day challenges where
she has one of those visuals everyday.
You do some.
So she gives you these crazy.
Yeah.
I don't know what she's doing there.
Oh,
that's the wrong 2000,
250 pushups in seven days.
oh my god.
She don't want her choke you.
It was a fucking tremendous job.
Yes,
she used to do.
I think it keeps kickboxer in jujitsu or
something because she has a lot of
fighting bodyweight exercises,
man,
just yoga.
If you know,
I have a yoga book that I bring with me
some time on the road now.
Also have yoga cards and I just started
using it myself like 10 cards and go
through these 10,
10 different poses for doing plug in 90
count.
I like hold each pose for a 90 count.
We do a like an ipad one.
Oh yeah,
no,
there's a couple.
my wife,
we do yoga every night like we were
stuck.
We started with ddp yoga.
Ddps good that that was my first thing.
I go,
okay,
I'm going to do yoga.
explain ddp do people don't know what
you're talking about.
Ddp is diamond dallas page from
wrestling fame and he had this yoga that
he created.
It was originally called like every guy
yoga because the whole thing is.
It's not like artsy fartsy your momma's
yoga.
Yeah,
exactly that.
Yeah.
And then,
but when you watch him,
he like actually is instructions really
cool.
It's not.
You do like hulk out,
so you do like of this guy.
Then hawk it out and then you just do
and then you stretch the whole and it's.
It's hard.
Oh,
it's definitely a lot of them.
I have to like,
I have to go to a knee and go,
okay,
and then you keep doing it for a couple
of weeks.
You're like,
okay,
now I can hold its.
I think yoga out of.
I mean I'm not an expert at all,
but I think if you stick with yoga
consistently your whole life,
you're going to be like staying,
you know,
at the end where you're not going to
bust the hip when you're like 90.
You know what I mean?
Definitely something that's a lot more
difficult to do than people think it is.
I can't really good word.
I can't do hardly anything.
It's unbelievable how unflexible land.
Well,
yoga iS just,
it's a lot more difficult than people
think it is.
It's like,
it seems like it would be easy to do.
Like all those indian dudes are all
skinny,
you know,
and you look at chicks are all doing it.
You're like,
well this isn't going to be like fucking
running up a mountain.
But yeah,
It is.
It's own way.
My wife's a mom.
Oh she,
I don't know.
I don't want to operate,
but late sixties,
maybe even seventies,
japanese woman.
She can.
She puts her hand like that and they can
go perfectly straight up just holding
like,
that's incredible.
She's
70.
whoa.
Yeah.
As long as you keep using it,
man.
I can fucking stallone.
I mean that's the most ridiculous
example ever of a grampy.
He's like 67,
68 years old,
I think.
At least.
How old is that dude now you always got
to be at least.
I would say 68,
right?
Let's say 68.
Seventy two.
Seventy two,
72 while he's going to be eventually if
you stayed in the law,
but when people like,
oh,
he's going to get off those steroids.
Like what are you talking about?
What's he's to what?
Sixty eight,
68?
Yeah,
he is.
I mean,
it's ridiculous.
The Idea that if somehow or another he
got off of them like what?
He's going to like live 70 years,
got to run.
I'm doing all that stuff.
When I'm don't know.
I think I'm going to get myself a couple
more years and then I figure I can
outrun all the side effects.
Well,
he broke his neck when he was filming
the expendables and he was like 65 years
old.
He fucking fell like they were doing
like some stunt and land on his fucking
neck and snapped his neck.
And he's got like disks that are fused
in his neck.
He liked put up an x ray online.
It showed it.
Here's the crazy shit ever.
It's going to a fused disc in his neck
and he's 67,
68 years old.
What the fuck man?
Like when we were kids,
a 68 year old dude was basically dead.
Right.
You know,
it's like barely hanging on.
And when,
um,
when they come up with,
if you've seen that thing they're doing
with mice that,
that gene doping.
No,
no,
no.
Blood,
just blood.
They're taking the mice have young mice
and introducing it to old mice putting
in an old mouse.
His body and the old mouse starts
literally going back in time like,
yeah.
And they've started,
they've started doing clinical trials
with people and are having positive
results.
Eating babies would make us no,
no need transfusions,
but here's the thing,
there was an episode of a goddamn.
I quote this website,
this podcast all the time,
but it's not like I'm not like their
publicist or anything.
I just really think it's awesOme.
Radiolab.
Radiolab is one of the best podcasts.
Amazing.
So informative and interesting.
It's like the sound effects,
like really well engineered.
IT's like the opposite of like how we do
it.
We just start and you know,
we fuck around,
we talk and then we end it with
radiolab.
Everything's planned out.
It's all really like well edited and
research and they brIng in different
sound effects and different people and
they have anyway,
they had this one on blood and the
reality of like blood donating and then
they sell your blood and a lot of the
blood that you donate doesn't ever go to
patients and a lot of it doesn't go.
Like if you donate blood,
they're actually going to sell your
donated blood to other hospitals for a
profit.
Yeah,
it's crazy.
It's really crazy.
If you.
I'm trying to remember the episode here.
I'll,
I'll said radio lab.
Yeah.
Radio lab episode on blood.
I'll google that real quick.
He always wondered about that because I
used to give plasma like twice a week
just to make money and I always wondered
if this was
sold or just I was donating.
It never really Made sense that I was
getting money for this.
IT's called blood and I think this one
deals with uh,
aids as well because there was a guy who
had hiv and he was doing some art with
his blood and he got labeled a
terrorist.
I think it's one of the same ones,
but um,
it's really interesting.
I think that's the episode they would
like.
What stuff?
I mean,
that's season 12 problems had 12
seasons.
My god,
what steps can be ready for our bodies,
you know,
to go back in time a little by the tIme,
let's say add 20 years from now I'll be
40,
50,
I'll be in only my fixtures,
but I'm hoping by then they'll have
something go.
Yeah,
this is a new.
we figured out how to take your gums
then.
Yeah,
no,
well what they're doing is apparently
they're there,
you know you can take blood out of
people and you can donate it and your
body can produce extra blood.
Like if you take blood out,
your body replenisHes that blood and if
you get a bunch of people to do that and
they sell that blood and say if they're
young you get like a bunch of college
kids to do that to their blood and then
you take this 20 year olds blood and the
the introduced into your body or your
body like literally reverses the aging
process.
You start,
your memory starts working better and
then conversely when you take old blood
and you pour it into a young kid's body,
they start getting sluggish.
That's the thing that they're not doing
that with people but they are doing that
with.
Maybe they are.
Maybe they aren't doing the people
because they did it with mice.
I mean I don't think it would hurt them
necessarily physically,
but it might,
you know,
who knows.
We found out a gave kids like fucking
alzheimer's early or something crazy,
but they're taking old blood with mice
and they're introducing it to the young
mice and it fucks them up for you.
It sounds like a sCary movie where
eventually we start harvesting 20 year
olds,
so it's kinDa like logan's run in the
sense of you can live until you're 20,
But during 20 through 30 or harvest and
maybe some guy doesn't want to be
harvested.
So he hides and runs well.
They're going to be able to Call it a
harvest.
They're going to be able to make
artificial organs if they haven't
already.
They already can make artificial
bladder,
so I know that they're taking skin cells
and they've created an artificial
bladder.
If they make artificial organs,
they're eventually going to move from
that to an artificial Body without a
head.
You know they're going to have your
fucking body,
like an exact version of your body with
no head and they'll Be able to take
stuff from it.
Take lungs.
Yeah.
These with a three d printer.
They just.
Which I'm going to get so bad,
buT I.
I don't know what I would print,
but it's one of those things and you're
like,
man,
it would be.
I saw some kid tHree d printed because I
follow three d printing,
whatever on twitter.
So they always like tweet,
you know,
shut some kid.
Three d printed a laser engraver for 50
bucks.
So the laser engraver was like a couple
thousand dollars.
He printed it on a three d printer,
made it a plastic and then he engraves
metal or whatever for some company that
he just does out of his garage.
But he's like,
that's what I wantEd.
A three d printer.
You can print anything.
I just,
it would just sit there like a
stairmaster,
not be used like I wouldn't know,
but they sell it at a office depot.
They have this thing you put down and
you can put an object and then it takes
a three d picture that's like 2000 bucks
and then a three d printer is,
you know,
it's plastic.
It makes sense.
A plastic.
Yeah.
But now they have all this different
stuff.
You can do it for food now,
like pastas you can create but are
plastic or wood,
like they're coming for the future of
olive garden or restaurants.
You're just,
the whole kitchen is just going to be
printed like you order it.
And scott,
I want to three d print,
anything you,
anything that busts in here?
Dude,
you can just three d print and remake.
I bet it's the future of objects
themselves.
I bet we're not going to log into going
to have store.
So just going to download the plans for
something like on itunes.
There's a,
you don't have to look up the video,
but there's the three d printed a house
and this huge,
this huge thing that just comes in,
like build completely prints a house.
Seeing the nuts.
And then uh,
I saw my wife was looking at a shoe one
where a company,
exactly what you said.
Go,
here's your shoes.
And then you go,
I want purple.
The,
you know,
I'm like,
I need a night shoot because I'm going
on blah blah blah.
And you can,
you get the pair of shoes is printed,
you know,
this is like we're making it all work.
It's a big deal.
But in 10 years from now,
it's going to be like,
remember when we figured out smoke
signals?
John heifer,
we're out of time.
A pleasure.
Always a pleasure.
My dare you.
How dare you get needy.
What,
uh,
your,
your twitter handle is john j,
o h n h e f,
f ron and website is john [inaudible]
dot com.
Facebook slash john hepburn.
Anything pretty much john heparin
fraud.
And where are you performing this
weekend?
I am the at stanhope live in phoenix,
Arizona.
Oh,
that's right.
This weekend.
Yeah.
You got to come down to the fights for a
little bit on saturday and have a 7:30
show.
And I know you have a show friday night.
I'm at the celebrity theater with tony
hinchcliffe.
And uh,
ian edwards.
Oh no,
no.
Yeah,
sorry.
this is already tony hinchcliffe.
And a ra should fear this.
A friday night.
I'm ian edwards and tony hinchcliffe
tonight.
Oh,
tomorrow night.
Tomorrow night at the ice house.
So wednesday at the ice house in
edwards,
20 inch cliff,
saturday or friday is the show at the
celebrity theater in phoenix.
Saturdays that ufc in phoenix.
So come down,
hang out.
Yeah man.
John had fraud.com.
H e f,
f r o n you got any shows coming up?
brian friday ice house.
We're having a benefit show at the
comedy store December 17th.
And all that money that we raised from
it,
it's going to pay for it in a sound
system for the belly room.
Really?
Oh,
that's fantastic.
Organizing this big thing to help
darrious glorious.
All right.
My friends love.
we'll see you soon.
Oh um,
we were supposed to have.
I'm just in.
The viking ran on this week but he might
have to cancel.
He just got back from africa any sick.
So he's like,
I want to take a,
you know,
come back next week.
I'm like,
yes.
Next week.
Very good next week.
And you worked at all right.
Love you guys.
See you soon.
Bye.