Videos, boom. And we're live, uh,
ladies and gentlemen, Charlemagne,
Tha God my man, Andrew Schultz. Yeah. For
being here. Thanks for setting this up.
Thank you for having me sir. My banker.
I've been a fan of yours for a while. You,
I think you're the last great radio host
and you will be the last famous radio
host cause I think radio is a dying thing.
You're the last great one. You're the,
you're the one who made it
famous from radio. Who the
fuck else? Yup. In this era.
I mean, I, yeah, I think radio
was like one of those, uh,
one of those rare lanes way.
It's really not a lot of people who
prosper in it. You know what I mean?
Like especially in the black radio
space. I mean, you've got the,
Tom Joyner is Doug banks to Wendy
Williams, you know, so it's,
it's rare in that lane.
But I think,
I think you've got people that have
established good careers and radio,
but that's a great question. When
was the last one? He's the last one.
Famous from rating on last
Samurai hundred percent.
Gotta give Bobby bones Bobby bones.
That's nice. I don't know who that is.
[inaudible] shots fired.
Shots fired. I know.
Sorry. Bobby knows somebody. Fuck,
I suspect. I'm sure he's great.
He's a nationally syndicated radio host,
but he's on the country states.
He just want to marry. You want to
definitely just start, so, okay. Yeah.
Joe was like, I don't give a shit. I
only know Bobby is, you talk about them.
Really? Yeah. Yeah. He's got two national
New York Times bestselling books season.
That's one of those things though.
It's like Comedians, like you know,
just talking about a comic that
everybody loves and people are like,
I've never heard of them. Like
amongst comics, she began expected,
Bobby has the oldest on the idol now.
Okay. Yeah. And we're around the same age,
so I would have to give it, I would have
to put him in that fight. You and Bob,
you're a gracious man. Yeah. In my
opinion. You're the last Samurai
guys like you. I just want to snatch
you up and bring you over to podcasts.
Like get the fuck out of there.
Get out of that censored boss man,
world interacting with it.
What's he calling you guys?
I know you guys have a podcast together.
The brilliant idiots,
you know Podtrac right?
You know that Short, short,
like we just crack Podtrac the breakfast
club. He was number 20 on Potrero. Okay,
so you put that online as well?
Yeah, we put it out of the pocket.
That's a good cause. I feel like
we're radio. That's what it is.
Like people still listening
to terrestrial radio,
but you have to go where the people are,
so you have to have the podcast,
you have to have the youtube following.
Like you can't wait for people
just to come to radio. Everything.
I wish you could swear though. So that's
the problem they do. That's the thing.
He so they release all the interviews
they do on breakfast club and those things
explode on youtube. They have all the
curse I just found out about, exactly.
That's where most people
globally with watch and listen.
I mean, yeah, right. Yeah.
That's what separates this radio,
this era of radio from other arrows or
radio like I was starting didn't have
youtube. You know what I'm
saying? If I was 30 I had youtube,
wouldn't be no question.
He'd still be the motherfucking guy.
Even though he is the guy.
Right.
But he's still be like Super Super Guy in
this era. Right. He's in that pay wall,
which is very strange to a
serious paywall. That's the
strangest paywalls. Yeah.
Yeah. He took the check and then you
get financial independence. Mac check.
Let's be realistic. He was
already financially independent.
So why do you do it?
You just the numbers that
are thrown at him. Yeah.
That was a different 300 million.
Right?
Well I think that was just
initially you'd have to do,
I think he makes like 100 million
every year or something crazy.
300 was flat and then another hundred
[inaudible] like your kids be in a
straight and like your great, great, great
grandkids being a straight right. Yeah.
But Sears stock and serious as
me is like blockbuster stock.
Hang on to that
messed up match.
Something like that.
Yeah.
I remember when Netflix used to have those
DVDs that you would get like in front
of the fucking [inaudible]. You
have to send them back. He was like,
I'm not sending this back now. I was
so funny. I was home this weekend.
I was in Moncks corner,
South Carolina,
and like there was a black panther DVD
from the library in my mom's house.
I'm like, what? The Fun Library,
Black Panthers in the original Black
Panthers or oh, I was like, Yo,
she was true from back in the day.
That's an original Black Panther.
Like who got the Black Panther DVD that
they checked out from the library and
have not bought it back yet? You didn't
bring it back to the library yet.
Now you don't have to like
what are they willing to do?
Why you the Black Panther from the
library because you wanted it and it was
there and you were at the library.
I'm still trying to understand why you
call it library. What is it? Library?
I don't fucking know. I mean, graduated
guide. It's like a library. Yeah.
It's one of those words, you
know, don't bail him out.
[inaudible] blackberry. Especially
talk variable in Texas to say special,
but everyone,
even like George Bush when
he was president would say
x specially extensionally
yeah.
Yeah.
I think a lot of it has to do with
region cause I still say straight street
strong.
Yeah.
That's or nothing. Screech, screech, crawl
scrumptious say pacifically Oh,
specifically specifically instead of
specifically cause everybody knows then
it's fun. That's the point
of view. It's a little Dick.
It's like, um, dialects.
Like my grandparents were from Sicily
and they would talk and dialects and even
people that knew Italian wouldn't
know what the fuck they were saying.
Like just like people that knew pure
Italian at some weird like pig Latin type
shit. You know. I mean
my mom's Scottish, like,
have you listened to a
real Scottish people talk,
you don't understand what the fuck
they're talking about, that accent.
So the way they rolled their words
together and then they get them drunk.
Well it's impossible. Where you from
Joe? I was born in New Jersey and uh,
I grew up mostly in Boston,
but most really all over the country.
Stubborn sensibilities.
Like before we started the podcast,
she was talking about all the hunting,
hunting.
I didn't get into that until 2012 wow.
Why?
Cause I was thinking about
being a vegetarian. I was like,
I was watching these animal rights
videos, Peta videos, and I was like,
I don't want to participate.
And it's factory farming
shit. It just, it's fucked.
You Watch these
pigs slammed into these cages together
and cows and chickens. I was like,
this is inhumane. It's, it's
insane. Decided to go on a thought,
killing them yourself. I decided one
of two things. Either I was gonna,
I was gonna try hunting and either I was
going to become a vegetarian or I was
going to become a hunter and so I became
a hunter. I did it. I killed a deer.
I ate it. I was like, this is perfect.
I love this call. I'm trying to fix.
Make sense?
I'm trying to forget the thought process
when you saw that it was inhumane for
these animals would be dying. No, no, not
you want to kill him. Factory farming.
Factory farming. And not that
they're, look, every animal dies.
They don't live forever and become angels.
They live in the wild. When you hunt,
you dip your feet into the wild. You
go out there and you, you fair chase,
you'll find them. You track them, you stay
down wind, you get in a good position,
you kill them and then you eat them
and it's a different animal when you're
eating that. Like if I eat an elk steak,
I know it's good that it's delicious.
I know that I was there.
Can I see a picture of this?
I'm still trying to imagine what it is
because I understand dear and understand
Moose.
A giant deer is that those antlers
pipes froze antlers on like an 800 pound
animal. How tall is it? It's huge. They're
big. Like six feet. Oh, taller. Yeah.
Yeah. Elk can mushroom
training. The Moose is crazy.
I saw the first time I saw him moose,
it was like that scene in Jurassic Park
with Jeff Goldbloom looks out the jeep
and sees the dinosaur. It's like you
can't believe how big a MOU says.
I don't think I've seen a moose in prison.
Double and elk.
The double the size of a note. Yeah.
Yeah. We need to go hunting, man.
You want to go? I'm being dead
serious to take you hunting,
camping and hunting where it's one or
the other. But you could do both. Okay.
Well you could camp or you could hunt
rather and then stay in a nice lodge.
That's the move.
But also kind of want to do like the
full outdoor cause sometimes I'll watch
those shows on like nat geo or
something like that and it's,
they're just living off the land and they
got to like make a hunt or make a year,
you know, make it out of snow. Yeah,
don't do that. Don't do that. No,
but what for what for like two days.
Like a cool, you want what you want.
It's like a real tent with a real sleeping
bags and stay warm and you're healthy
and you're not worried about fucking
freezing to death or anything weird like
that.
And make sure you have water filters
so you can drink out of a stream if you
really want to do that.
Yeah. I want to try.
You should try hunting in New
York like nobody's ever done that.
Like hunter rats.
I'm saying.
I'm saying think about all
them big ass rats in New York.
Like nobody's ever done that.
I'm not going to lie.
He'll probably get a lot of
attention for this. Back in the day,
you could go to 120 fifth street and
like Spanish Harlem and you could buy
pigeons.
People were like catching pigeons and
they were selling them and trying to front
like they were exotic pigeons.
Shit, I swear to God. No.
Pigeons were brought over here for food.
That's what squad is.
That's what the fuck is.
Squad squad is like of like a Bougie
restaurant item and it's actually young
pigeons. Really? Yeah. That's
what, that's what squat is. Yeah.
I didn't know that.
All pigeons,
all pigeons you see in the United States
or all brought in from somewhere else
for food and then they released
it become feral.
They like the wild hogs of the bird world.
What a young rats called that are
used for food. It's a good question.
Who uses young rants for food? I
don't know. Yeah, but there's a,
there's a cousin that rats documentary.
What does this is just the dog
that hunt rats in New York, right?
I don't believe that shit.
What do you mean you don't believe it?
That they're really guys sending their
dogs out to go get rats OCR paper.
Because that's halls. I mean,
they're not going to fix it.
There's no way to fix it. But you like
Jack Russell terriers, they fuck rats up.
They're designed to fuck routes up,
but it's gotta be people who live up
north in New York who have the same desire
to hunt. They just, they just go down
south. So why did I go here? Right.
They hunt deer in New York
has a lot of deer. Jersey,
jersey, or got allowed. Yeah.
I live,
I live in Jersey and that's one of the
reasons I loved yard because I'm from
South Carolina,
so I'm used to seeing deers and possums
and just different types of wildlife
running through the streets. I, that's
why I like living in Jersey. Yeah.
The Jersey is an unusual play.
Jersey has more black bears per capita
than any state in the United States.
I don't know if that's a
fact, but I believe you cause
I've seen it myself. Yeah,
they're everywhere. You seen bears
on your property? Not on my property,
but when I used to uh,
stay with my aunt in the Poconos,
the bears used to come in her backyard
cause there was like a scream in the
backyard and they would like come in
and just grab fish out of the screen.
They kill the kid.
One bear killed a kid a couple
years ago from one of the colleges.
What colleges or was it
the one near New Brunswick?
What was it you didn't see in the video?
In Jersey at a walking bed bed.
I would walk on two feet through people's
back yards. They had a bad friend.
Paul was so hell yeah.
Shit happen there.
It is looking at the video, the
bear walking around. Oh yeah,
that's a foot. You know who
believes in bigfoot? Yeah.
You have a believer in the studio
right now who believes in bigfoot.
Do you really? Yeah,
absolutely. 100% believes it,
but you know why I believe in bigfoot?
Because it shit like mousses.
You know what I'm saying?
[inaudible]
you see something?
If you see a fucking
a species like a moon,
God believe. Look at this shit.
Yeah. At some point in life,
somebody was trying to explain that
to somebody else. He's like, man,
get the fuck Outta here right now.
When he's trying to explain it to me,
we look at the size of that. God Damn,
that's insane. Was the legs work?
They'll fuck you up to.
There's a,
those are the rare deer species that
will fucking stuck to death. Yeah.
They used to dealing with wolves.
If they think you're a threat,
they just run up on you
and stomp you to death.
Why don't you believe in bigfoot that?
Well,
I actually did a television show
where I went hunting for them.
You going to do it? I'll
find it. No, no, no. I was,
I did a show called Joe Rogan questions.
Everything.
We spent a whole week in the
Pacific northwest talking
to big foot hunters. Yeah.
We camped out there.
Me and Duncan Trussell went
and interviewed scientists
and interviewed all these
different archeologists,
all these different people that didn't
believe and didn't believe it wasn't real
animal. At one point in time. I don't
think it exists now. I think it existed.
It's just a primate in the fucking woods.
Yeah. Okay. You don't think it exists?
You believe that exists now?
I did up to a certain point,
but I was like in this era
with all the cameras and everything else,
somebody would have caught one. Okay,
that's good. Yeah. I was a little worried.
No, I don't. I don't believe in it now.
I believe it existed at some point,
but I don't believe it exists.
Let me tell you something.
Charlemagne has this amazing
power to manifest shit. Okay,
so I see how it could lend itself.
When you believe something so much,
it becomes real. Right? Right.
I could see how it manifests
itself into things like big foot,
like you believe in things.
I mean Sasquatches wasn't,
it's not a far fetched idea. It's
literally just a primate in the woods.
I'm just saying when you were young and
you believe that you were a teen wolf,
yeah.
That was like, no, no, no.
I did third grade.
He believed that his ears actually
changed shape. No, they did.
I was sitting at the list and I will sit
at the lunch table telling everybody I
was going to turn into this Werewolf at
lunchtime and I was saying this for like
a week straight and we was all sitting
at the table and I was just sitting there
like this going to happen.
It's happening.
And my ears actually went from round
to points into like two seconds.
And when all the kids at the table
saw it in, jumped up and ran.
So they fucked up my concentration. So if
I hadn't kept that concentration going,
I probably would've turned full fledge
where within that moment and maybe
levitated possibly. I've done that
before. Really? Oh yeah. I used to,
I grew up Jehovah witness.
So I used to leave the kingdom hall and
I would walk outside of the kingdom hall
and I would like jump in the air and
be looking down at the kingdom hall.
And not stay up there for awhile
and then I would come down.
But here's the thing, he's not,
he's not doing bits. Right.
He really believes this shit. I'm just
telling you what happened in my life.
If you believe what you believe it,
if you don't,
you don't memories a strange thing.
Ah, you think it's one of those
like you recreate the past
well,
memories of strange thing.
Like you couldn't believe something and
know something to be true when it didn't
actually happen. Mm. You can absolutely
do that. I mean there's what you have.
People have memories in their
head that never happened.
You have memories that people
positioned in your head.
They proven that you can
talk someone into a memory.
You can change someone's memory.
That's why it's particularly
dangerous for kids when you know,
there's a whole case where they were
talking kids into saying that their
teachers molested them and all these
people like lost their careers,
lost their lives, turned out it was all
100% made up. But those kids believed in,
they believed when they were telling
them that they were molested,
they believed it.
Yeah.
That's gone into it.
What is that called when you give
that information to the police?
What is it called when they interrogate
you? Interrogations can be bull shoe.
Yeah, the course you, yeah. Yeah, yeah.
The article I was reading the other day
about why people make false confessions,
why did they just get talked into
believing that they actually,
you scared the devil.
If you a kid,
especially a young kid from the hood and
you like 1516 years old and the police
like, yeah, you went to jail for 20 years.
If you don't tell us what we need to know,
you don't fucking know no better.
They put
you under duress.
They put you in a room,
they sit you across from a position of
authority and this person questions you.
You start, you start, you start saying
things that aren't true. You've seen
beyond scared straight. They tell you,
you gonna get 20 years and get bunched.
Fuck foot.
15 of them show the first five 15 they
let they let you kind of settle in for
the first
fine. Yeah. You know what? Let's
let that bucket nice and tight.
But five year birthday
you might like some elk,
you might go listen,
you might go in under age,
you know there's these criminals got moral
[inaudible] a few but not too come on
up monsters.
When I was young,
I used to have a red tractor trailer.
It was a red plastic trailer with a
farmer on top of it and like of those hard
plastic trailers.
Now farmer used to get off that trailer
in fuck with me and I took it in the
yard one day, put kerosene on it
and set it on fire. And in my mind,
I remember hearing that
farm farmers scream,
my mom even tell you the story of how
I used to always talk about how this
fucking farmer used to come off
of his tractor and fucking me.
And she saw me set it on
fire and I thought I was
crazy until years later I met
Tiffany Haddish and she said
she had experiences with her.
Teddy bears used to come to life and
fuck with her. So I'm just saying,
I'm just saying shit happens.
Is All this happening?
I haven't heard this started happening
at night. When did it happen? Ah,
I don't remember.
I can't remember.
I don't remember like the details of
when it was at night or during the day.
That's why these things are trying
to figure out with Ufo abductions,
you know almost all those
UFO abductions happened.
My people are sleeping and they think
what's happening is your brain is
releasing and dodginess
psychedelic chemicals and
it's forcing you to have these
hallucinations and that you really
do believe you're taking the board,
the CFOs and gone away. But if someone
is watching you with the camera,
nothing actually happens.
Questions, people swear by it.
Have you ever had one of those dreams
where it feels as if someone's holding you
down to the Hag Hag riding you?
I mean that's a term they really
call it a sleep paralysis,
but growing up in South Carolina they
would say to hag was riding you. Okay,
what do we have to take salt is
that you would easily put us,
you need to put a straw broom at your
door or you would take salt and sprinkle
salt at your door. Because when
the Haggins, there's your room,
you got to pick up every criminal assault,
so by the time he picks up
every kernel of thought,
it's fucking date I ag was like these
little old women that they say would come
and ride people in the middle of the
night. I think I've seen them before,
but it's really looks like just the
shadowy figure and it's the same feeling.
You get that feeling like your body is
frozen. They can't, your eyes are open,
but you feel like you're talking,
but nobody here. That's, that's it.
They said that's the Hag, right?
What did they say that is like what?
The scientists,
the blood's not flowing in your body
looks like when you're sitting on the
toilet too long and your
fucking leg legs go. Yeah. Yeah.
I think it's a psychological thing.
[inaudible] your,
your brain is just not
sending signals to your body,
but you want to move and you just
don't move, but I can't knock.
That shit is frightening.
I had that before and I've
had that before and I had a,
when I woke up it was just,
you seen the movie signs? Yeah.
So it was this creature that looked
like he was from the movie signs,
but it was purple and black and it
was standing over me and I couldn't
move. And so I was making noise,
just trying to get it to go away.
And as the sun came up,
it just faded away.
Now that I don't know if
it was a dream or an actual
visit from extra extraterrestrial,
it could be the thing about extra
terrestrials. Well, you know,
I believe in him.
Will you believe in everything?
The reality than toys that can harass
you as a child? There's no evidence.
But the numbers of humans,
I mean the numbers of planets rather
that could support humans are there.
They're pretty well just
what we've documented so
far, it's pretty interesting.
Just what they know about the thousands
of plants to discover this hundreds it
could possibly support human life.
And then there's hundreds
of billions of galaxies.
So the idea that we're the only one,
not only that Neil degrasse
Tyson's explaining this to
me is this is a mind fuck
and a half that the universe is so big
that not only is there another you out
there that has done everything exactly
as you've done to every pause like that.
Pause every pause down to the
second. An infinite number, right?
Yeah. Yeah. You're talking
about, is it called the, uh,
infinite in an infinite universes,
there's this exact conversation happens.
My name look,
people look exactly like that because
infinity implies that that can be a
million variations.
There's one where you get up right now
and you have to take a piss right out of
the room or Charlemagne today.
There you are. Here I'm there.
There's one would you get up and you're
mad that we don't believe you that you
saw big foot or something. You
know, that kind of shit. Yeah. This,
the idea that when you think of
infinity, right, we think about it.
It's being really big. It's not, it's
impossible to put in your head. Yeah.
The infinite,
infinite universes,
like the size of the universe
is 14 billion light years apart.
Infinite numbers of those.
Not only that,
they think that inside every galaxy
is a supermassive black hole.
And inside that black hole,
maybe another universe with hundreds of
billions of galaxies with hundreds of
billions of black holes inside each
one of those hundreds of billions of
galaxies, hundreds of billions of
black holes, that it's fractal.
And that it's impossible
for you to even conceive.
Yeah. I think it's very, so you're
saying just based on the numbers,
there has to be something. The
question is, as you gotta be,
to think that would have only life in
his book was only life in the universe.
I'm just saying like, hmm, whether
or not it's reached us. Well, yeah,
I don't think it's reached us.
And if it has reached us,
it's like they have to find
a way to bend time. Right?
Because time is the biggest issue.
I'm gonna tell you what the problem,
like where earthlings, right? Yeah. And if
you look at how diverse the earth he is,
like there's different
species of shit in the woods,
different pieces of shit in the water,
different species that shouldn't
have jungle, different species.
That shit in the sky.
Why wouldn't the earth be,
I mean the university just as diverse
and is where assuming shortage,
we're assuming we're the smartest
life form in the universe. No, no, no.
I'm not at all. And sure it is all
I'm saying is life has an end, right?
What is the oldest species on the earth
right now with the turtles lived like
200 or some shit like that.
What pool is Morgan Freeman?
The doors on the Goddamn Room. So
let's say it's 200 300 years, right?
Let's say that's the Max.
Now we have 300 years to travel,
millions of light years away to get to
another galaxy to see other planets,
to see if they have some shit
and they have the same for us.
So let's say there is another species,
did somehow found a way to take your,
the consciousness that they have and
put it in a robot that can then last for
thousands of years, then they would
have the opportunity to come here.
But we're limited by time. Right. You
will die before you get somewhere.
Like you can go to Mars,
we can't come back.
I think we're basing that
off our intelligence.
There might be a species in this universe
that can fly to earth the way we fly
to la. But that's what I'm
saying. They would have done
Ben time. Not necessarily what they
could do is fold time or full time,
whatever.
You know what I mean?
Create that wormhole fact where you're
going where instead of it's not linear,
it's whatever.
Send somebody
time like it was in um, event horizon.
They talked about how they did that.
Remember that movie?
Yeah. But, and there was another
one to add. Matthew mcconaughey.
Interstellar. Interstellar. Yeah.
Where they get into like space time,
space time is really interesting,
right? It's like the faster you go,
the less you age. Right? Like,
so somebody on a plane flying over us
into someone here on the earth, right?
So someone's flying around the earth
on a plane versus us sitting on earth,
they will age fractionally less,
right.
So if you just increase their
speed and decrease hours, uh,
when that or keep ours at the
same, they will, let's say not yet
at all compared to us aging like
30 years even crazier. Brian Cox,
I went to see his cosmos
exhibit and that's the fastest,
oh is a physicist from cern,
from the large Hadron collider is a bunch
of differentiate podcasts and shows.
He said that if you were
born and right next to you,
like your mother and you both put on a
watch at the moment you were born and
then you checked that watch 30 years
later, if you have a perfect watch,
it was never out of time.
Your watch would have a different time
than her watch because you have gone
through time differently than she has
fracture fractionally because the amount
of speed, how fast you
travel it. Ew, ew, ew.
Experienced time in a different way.
The Path you take in life,
the different terrain you
travel over the earth,
all those factors play in
to how much time has passed.
Let's say you're locked on the top of
a mountain and she lives at the bottom,
you're actually traveling
at a faster rate, right?
Because it's no different than like let's
say there's a ball on a tether, right?
And you're just swinging it
around in a circle, right?
The ball at the end is actually going
faster than your hand in the middle of
swinging around. Gotcha. Right?
So since you're going fast,
you're actually aging slower and we're
talking about fractions of seconds. Yeah.
But over the course of time,
it proves that everyone experiences
time and a slightly different rate,
which proves Einstein's theory that
if you have to travel very fast in a
spaceship and then come back,
you would look at your brother who was
your age and now he's a hundred years old
and you're only at 30 so I think I figured
it out how we can time travel time,
but I think I figured out,
all right,
so we're trying to create, okay.
And again, I don't know shit,
but this is just me like you know
pontificated logic. This is brilliant.
Lydia chip right here.
Okay,
so we have to do is go faster than the
speed of light in order to time travel.
I don't know how to do that just yet,
but what I think we can do is we're trying
to use like rockets to propel us at a
certain mile per hour to get
close to the speed of light.
Fuck the fuck the rockets.
Why don't we use light as
wind and create a sale?
That harness light and that sale will
naturally take us the same speed or as
close as we possibly could
get to the speed of light.
He did it in a movie called Sunshine.
I'm a fucking genius.
You somebody shipper just
sunshine and didn't tell anyone
I'm shine. How could you see that movie?
I don't even know where the milk is.
Science fiction come on the
show. It's fiction movie.
I'm talking about
Bob Lasar tonight.
That was the guy I was telling you.
I'm wanting to bring you to dinner.
I'm going to as well if you want to gum.
He's the guy who worked at area 51 and uh,
I mean I didn't even know if he's
talking about the test tomorrow. Yeah,
I'm going to bring it
up. Oh, area 51 is real,
but this guy literally worked on what
he says or alien spacecraft. Spacecraft.
That sale on sunshine could be
the next big thing is Caitlyn Bro,
you should work for now and this is
public school education gets you a job at
Trump space for us to do any of the math.
I just want to throw the ideas
out there and I think I got it.
This is a legit space for shirt
from Trump's from Trump tower.
Tim Dillard bought me this. Yo, shout
out to Tim. I love Tim. This is real.
This is what the real fucking
space for us. This is the logo.
I didn't know
how I missed that one cartoon of
the wheels space
for us.
This fucking goofy shit.
[inaudible] you had a friend who
works on alien spacecraft. Oh,
I don't know [inaudible]
on the podcast tomorrow.
He worked at area 51 is he allowed to
talk about that shit when I'll get you is
because he's been talking
about it for decades. Yeah.
And they've tried to discredit him.
There's a very controversial,
a lot of people think he's full of shit,
but the more,
there's a recent documentary by Jeremy
Korbel and the more you look at the
documentary,
he knows too many things.
He knows too many things that that prove
that he absolutely worked at area 51 he
got arrested for bringing people to a
lookout peak to look over where the area
where they would launch these spaceships
and he's got video of these things
flying through the air,
doing all these maneuvers that no
conventional spacecraft could do in 1980
whatever the fuck it was where you got
arrested. They must have some type of uh,
like, like, like a Nda with extra
terrestrials or they don't talk about,
I feel like the US government,
it just,
governments in general throughout the
world have some type of NDA will kill you.
I don't know. Probably is the same one
Leonardo Dicaprio uses on his girlfriends.
He's got the greatest NBA history now.
Holy Shit.
I mean, Shit. No one
gives a fuck about NDA.
So we had pay people and they don't care.
They'll out and talk about it
later. We had Lisa Ann on
a, on a podcast, right?
I just parked the porn star
go playground too. Right.
And Lisa and came on and she was talking
about Ndas and how stupid women are for
a obeying them. And I was like, what
are you talking about? And she's like,
what are they have to lose? They don't
have any money. Exactly. So she's like,
you have a bunch of fucking
heels in your apartment.
You think that Leonardo Dicaprio
is going to take your heels.
You can break any fucking India.
But for whatever reason he gets scared.
You pay a woman to half a million dollars.
Tell her to keep her mouth closed.
She breaks the NDA. An NDA says she
has to pay you back when you exactly.
You mean we don't have money forever.
One money he wrote one is bill O'Reilly.
He had to pay a lady $32 million.
There's no pussy worth that.
I need to see what she looks like.
Can we look at this woman?
I need to see no bail is into some wild,
wild shit.
Can we? There's no picture
of this woman. I don't know.
I need to see $32 million policy on blast,
but I love to,
I would love to see what she looks
like 32 million. He agreed to it.
He agreed to it.
He must've did something.
He didn't want nobody to be even
remotely bills getting packed 100% yet.
It's not even about what actually happened
is about what the person said they
did the you that can ruin your reputation.
She's texting me in 2019 Scott Pick's,
she's got picked, she's got
videos. Something's going to
meals, ask guaranteed DNA.
She's got his shit under her thumbnail,
I guarantee.
And then a guy like bill has to keep
a certain, like, I guess you know,
standard about himself,
right?
You have to look at him a certain way in
order to listen to what he's saying and
what to take his, his information, you
know, correctly, I guess. Seriously. Yeah.
Yeah. So he could lose all
that equity in his audience.
He's out there doing wild shit. He
actually didn't tell him he's gone anyway.
Is it over from bill while he's not
on Fox News anymore, he's podcasts.
He was the number one guy and they
were like not worth it. Yeah man.
Y'All be talking about cancer culture.
Bell really got canceled.
Real came over in a big way and I think
he does do some type of broadcast and
now,
but nobody cares.
Well he let out a book and the book was
Number One New York time best sellers.
Fox history books. Yes. You know, like,
I don't even think he ran into him.
I think he just puts his name on it.
I wonder about a guy like bill though,
because think about it like
you started your own platform.
You know what I'm saying?
And people really care about your voice.
Did people ever really care about bill's
voice? The thing, check it. Right.
So it's like sometimes you
become a mouthpiece for a
network or foreign ideology
they believe in and
this is the difference.
This is how you find out if people
really fuck with you the second you leave
that network.
It's like when people leave ESPN and you
never hear about them again. It's like,
Oh,
you thought you were bigger than ESPN.
You thought you were
bigger than the sports.
They just want you to say
strike ball. That's it. Yeah,
so I think we learned that bill really
didn't have all that cachet that we
thought we hit. Yeah. That's why
I like ESPN is a good analogy.
That's why you got to get people
like skip Bayless props. Yeah.
You got to get your mail hill prop so
they can go other places and people still
care about what they have to say.
Even if it's just in tweets. Right.
I don't even know what Bill
O'reilly's Twitter handle is.
I imagine something around it
like below where I'm sure it is,
but you know what I mean? I see
him, he's never known for like, Oh,
Bill O'reilly said this on social
media when the last time you heard bill
O'Reilly say something, he might
not even be, I made some news. Yeah.
He might not even be own.
It's tough bro. Yeah,
he's podcasting from his like apartment
or something like that. Dude is like,
it's no background. Nothing
really. Yeah, it's bad.
He's not even wearing like
suits. Skylar, NASA wealthy shirt
below Rogan.
Well we gotta look him up.
We got to see the girl,
he fucking him and see how they're
living right at the top. Guys like that.
They say we'll just lay low for a couple
of years and then someone will scoop
you up again now,
which is only right
one fox and Fox lets you go.
Yeah. If you're one of those guys,
those neo-con guys like you don't
really have any place else to go. Hey,
too old to really understand the
landscape of like how to navigate this new
Internet space cause you've got
plenty of conservative voices.
We don't have those big platforms right
to Candice on Tommy Lauren's bitch bro.
I don't even look at them. Well no makeup.
He really look at the, on the shirt.
He's wearing a nurse's outfit
underneath that fun pants on for sure.
Guarantee that aura is based
for a shirt for real under the
what size is that button up? Shirt
did that. You'd take his wardrobe.
He's got old fat gut now. It's been
drinking. No, this is not good.
Those are the news. Watch
the film fold. No Spin News.
Nobody low riley.com now we
need to get some new shorts.
81,000 views on whatever video that is.
What is what is on Twitter?
There are no charges.
You are presumed innocent in this country.
This is not what the left wants.
What is this about? Was he renting
them out as April 19th well,
maybe we turn your report. Scroll down.
How many people are watching that?
How many people have him on Twitter?
How many
Oh, so you may million followers. He
has and that video had 581,000 views.
10 you look at them right there
in that video right now. Go down.
Now scroll down. Do you think he's doing
the orange thing to reflect triangle?
100% he's bringing them in. We'll look
at that. That's 100% the orange thing.
He looks like turmeric.
Yeah,
but he don't look anything like it looks
in real life. That's like an Instagram.
Whoa.
[inaudible] come on Bro.
If you met him at a restaurant, you'd
be like, wait, okay, wait a minute.
Not Update your picture son.
You had to pay that woman $32 million.
Fucking disappointed. Just it keeps
getting more orange. Go down raw.
That's [inaudible].
People are watching video watching it.
He's got 500,000 views. Yeah, definitely
watching it. But now he's in a vacuum.
But it's those crazy old white
people that live in Kansas. Yeah,
but they don't have Twitter. Hey man, I
went in when, you know what I'm saying?
If you got 580,000 people that can
watch it when you put up a video and you
could still get paid for it.
I'm cool with that. It's true.
You know what I'm saying?
I think we put too much emphasis
on like whatever mainstream it is.
There's no such thing as mainstream
cause there's not just one scream anymore
that's over. That's why.
And shouts at Brennan Shab.
That's why we wanted you guys to connect
because I feel like you guys represent
the most. I think you will are both the
most influential people in media. Right?
And you represent, put that
kind of pressure on me. Well,
I think that evil on me,
Ricky, Bobby, I think it's important. No,
because I think you guys represent,
and I think the illusion
was before I went on,
before I went on here for the first time,
the illusion was that these things
operated in separate spheres, right?
That there are these different vacuums,
like the Charlemagne world, right?
And then the Rogan world.
And then I went on,
I found all these people that
knew me from our podcast.
They also listened to yours, right? So
it turned out in that moment I was like,
Oh shit. It's not as fractured as people
thing now because everybody's aware.
People will always been hitting
me for years. Like, yeah,
you got to go on Joe Rogan.
You've got to go on Joe Rogan,
or you've got to go on Joe Rogan.
So there's clearly that the
worlds collide connected,
especially this internet
wave that we're on right now,
the Internet we have people are
craving this type of information.
They're craving the type of interviews
you guys are doing and talking to the
people you guys are talking to.
Right, and I don't know, for me,
this is really cool just to see people
like the fact that everybody could do
everybody show.
It's not like,
like Jimmy Kimmel never does psych the
Seth Meyer show, but you know what I mean?
It's like everything is not, that
world is very disconnected. Yeah.
Whereas this world, the Internet world
is like for the comics and podcasts,
it's like there's no competition.
Everybody helps everybody.
Everybody supports everybody.
I mean that's one thing I've
always noticed about your platform.
Like you've always bought on up and coming
Comedians who just needed that extra
push to for people to know who the fuck
they are. You know what I'm saying?
This is important.
That's why you have ms paddling yesterday.
[inaudible]
genuinely funny.
[inaudible] is insane.
Like you can only take a story that sad
in that tragic and turn it into a sitcom.
She was talking,
she was talking yesterday about her ex
husband who shot her in the [inaudible]
her in the head, shot her in the titty
shot in the back of the head, shot in the,
he got her pregnant.
It was fucking her when she was 12 got
her pregnant when she was 14 with two
kids by the time she was 16 she had an
abortion when she was 16 with with his
third kid. She called him up to
try to get him to apologize to her.
He wouldn't apologize to her.
So she forgave him and she said it
released like this huge weight off of her
shoulder.
She was talking about it like you can't
believe her story she's laughing about.
Of course not. Yeah, I'm not. I'm the, I
got, yeah, def whole forgiveness thing.
We talk about that all the time.
I'm not with that whole like I forgive
you and it makes me feel better.
I'm fine not fucking with you.
I'm fine saying, fuck this guy.
Fuck this person. Like, I don't care.
Like why I have to give you when
I a manual movie just came out,
you know,
uh,
the shooting that happened in Charleston,
South Carolina and like all of the
family members for gave Dylan roof.
And I'm like, there's one dude in there
that's like, fuck him. He killed my mom.
I'm like, yes, that's PR.
That's a perfectly fine emotion.
You go talk to your therapist about it,
you allow yourself to feel like, yes,
fuck him.
Why do we feel like we got to forgive
and in a way that comes off our shoulders
for her, it was like she was carrying
around her whole life, you know?
I think for her it just helped her and
she knew he was a piece of shit when she
was talking to him.
She said to him like,
you are fucking me when I was 12 years
old. And he literally said this to her,
your mind, your body wasn't
12. That's what he said to
her. And she was just like,
so she decided after that like,
I'm not going to invest my energy in this
cause I'm gonna let it go. Let it go.
So she just doesn't fuck with him.
Doesn't talk with them and she doesn't,
she doesn't carry around the hate.
That was a, it was poisoning her.
Yeah. I get it. And I understand
the power of forgiveness.
There's a reason why it exists. Right.
There's a reason why it's, you know,
it's still here for thousands
of years. This idea of, hey,
let's forgive so that we could feel
better. Right. I think, I think,
I think usually things get
weeded out if they don't work
well. It's hard to forgive someone that
doesn't feel bad about what they did.
It's one thing if you like,
man, I fucked up. I'm sorry.
Please forgive me. I get it.
You're a person. Human beings
make mistakes. I forgive you.
But if someone is like you were, you
weren't, you weren't 12 with your mind,
your body, and he's talking about
fucking you when you were 12 years old.
Like I have an 11 year old daughter.
The idea of I'm a grown man,
fucking her violin.
Yeah. Yeah. You're not
gonna forgive him. You know,
you might fuck him up and then after you
fuck him up, he'd be like, you know what?
It's all good.
Well, no, I'm saying you put a fucking
hour on his fucking gun. That's it.
So maybe forgiveness is misconstrued.
Maybe you're not actually forgiving the
person and letting them offer what they
did, but you may be just re removing
them from your consciousness.
People forgive when
they not gonna do shit.
[inaudible] realize I'm not
going to slap the shit out there.
Punches you in the face.
You're like,
I forgot to you go [inaudible] I'm
attaching myself to Jesus because I can't
carry this no more. [inaudible]
I don't know. We do.
We don't know. We do. Sometimes we make
mistakes. We all make mistakes out here.
And when somebody who gets punched in
the face and be like, Yo, you got it.
You got Sam [inaudible] forgive me.
I'm a Christian.
You're fighting. You might attach
me to the worst part, my state.
By the way,
that's probably when I would get to that
point of forgiveness when you want to
do something to somebody so bad.
But when you get the opportunity you
don't and you realize it's not that
important to you, then at that moment I
might be like, you know what, God bless.
I wish them the best.
When you guys have like surpassed people
in your career that were pieces of shit
to you as you were coming up,
did,
did the anger that you had towards
him totally leave your body? No,
absolutely not. Hold onto
that. She books about it.
Yeah, totally. Like Jordan at the press
conference, I need you. And by the way,
God bless
you with the facts are the
facts. You did fire me. Right.
You know Boogie d from an it
firm in Philly going [inaudible]
you did fire me for no fucking reason.
You did that happen.
You're listening what you're doing
right now. How are you feeling?
He goes over, he does radio in
Saint Louis. He does. Yeah. Yeah.
Cause they told him that if he,
um,
if he fired me and whatever
he bought in didn't work,
they were going to send him back to
Saint Louis cause he had moved from Saint
Louis to do be the PD in Philly.
And so he fired me.
What he bought in didn't work right.
And they kept their word
and they sent it back.
And Saint Louis Garbage is probably
the best thing for them though.
But everything worked out for everybody.
He's living a great life in Saint Louis.
I'm living a great life.
Oh life. Have you seen
that? Uh, uh, Jordan, uh,
what does it get into [inaudible]
what was it? A training.
He wouldn't stop talking about journalists
Brown cause they remember every
single thing and that was his,
he's Bernard Hopkins.
Remember we were putting on happens a
fighter. He needed to be the villain.
He needed to be the heel for the
motivation. Y'All don't have people that
shitting on y'all and like,
you know,
when I surpass them it
goes away and not for me.
And when I start passing it goes
away. It's weird. It's like bullying.
I'm not saying it goes away,
but I have to remind you to remind you
because you told me I wasn't going to
make it.
I'll tell you this.
When I was starting out as a comic and I
was, you know it was rough in New York,
motherfuckers are just dickheads.
Teacher used to carry a,
a list of people who are
pieces of shit in my wallet.
All the people I was going to say fuck
you to when I passed him and as I would
start to pass them, I felt
zero, I felt was your anger.
I almost start to feel bad. I go,
Shit, you're still in the same place.
That's why you were addicted me.
Cause I was all you had to be a dick to
well that's the type of person that is a
dick to someone who's coming up.
The person who is your fee.
This famine mentality. Yes. She
think there's not enough. Yes.
So you try to keep people
away, get away, get away.
Whereas the people that don't have
famine mentality like, come on, come on,
come on. Let's do it. Plenty
for everybody, for everybody.
Like if you like I'm been five, four times
from radio, you know what I'm saying?
So I'm not angry at the
people that fired me,
but the people who told me things like,
like there was a guy named Dj Cath
and Sean's the sideline who told me I
wouldn't be my first time I got fired.
He told me I would never work in
radio again cause I was an asshole.
And then you know, Boogie Dee told me,
this is why you'll never make it in radio.
So those two individuals
just need to be reminded.
So people need to know that they may
[inaudible] you like to know the person
that cut Michael Jordan from the
basketball team. He had eyes glow.
Wouldn't you like to know the
person that didn't hire Oprah?
The news cast the back and they would
you like to know if people just want to
know these people. By the way,
I've had other executives in radio,
you know like [inaudible],
my God dark winters doc when it's
told me that one person in particular,
he would never hire because they fired
me and couldn't give him a reason why.
When he asked him why,
he was like, I just did. I just, I didn't,
they didn't like what he was doing and
he was like, I never hired that person.
So that's why certain
people need to be told,
being reminded about the decisions.
They made it like a cycle.
Know Francis
also that you get hired for these jobs
and you can get fired by these assholes
and there's always that weird power
play between producers and executives.
That happens with television shows and
networks and it happens with radio.
It happens. This, this a power play.
Yeah. The thing about comedies, it's like,
you know, you just work at a different
club. There's no real, the only,
I mean there's a little weird struggle
between you and the other comedians,
but there's no where real struggle between
you and a club. When you go in there,
you sell out,
you kill and you're friendly to everybody.
They don't give a fuck 100% thank you.
Here's your money
bro. They lash fucking care. And it
doesn't matter how much of a diva you are.
Everybody knows this story in comedy.
Eddie Griffin, you know Eddie Griffin,
writer anywhere has the best
rider in comedy. He has a writer.
Oh did he give me writer?
Oh he's had it forever.
Oh, so he had a ride. A ride.
No rider mean like the thing,
it's all about me
pronounce this shit wrong.
[inaudible] go man.
And he's great. So, but
apparently his his rider,
which means like the shit
that's in the green room. Yeah.
Any needs a brand new pair of
air force ones for every show.
A lot of people do that. What? Yeah. Yeah.
A lot of people have like sneaker riders.
Wait a minute.
Yeah,
fucking up. Cause I haven't
asked for anything but water.
You would think sneakers are the most
important thing in standup, right?
Like you need to fucking shoot
when you're on that page. Hold on.
There are more than just Eddie
has some guys have it where they
want a fresh pair size eleven's
whatever. They were right there. So they,
they get to the plate,
they number one to wear them at all
until right when they get on stage.
That's it.
Yeah.
What's in your either I just
was like Jack Daniels wine meet,
um, water, simple sugar free,
red bull kind of meat. You're
not specific with me? No.
Like, like meat plates, like
roast beef and shit like that too,
just so I don't eat garbage, you
know, stuff like that. Nothing. Nuts.
Macadamia nuts and pistachios.
Normal Shit. Red M and m's,
Kelly Green ones pick out
the green ones. They, I mean,
that is what you're saying about standup
is the beauty of independence though,
right? Yeah. That's why.
That's why everybody who gives me to
run through the standup stage afterwards
because the comedy clubs still accepted.
Did you see that tweet?
I thought he was, uh,
I forget what word or something
like that and he was like, oh, Jay,
we'll be doing stand up in three
months, dude. Do you watch those?
No. Why do you, why do we it? She love it.
I love that term Twitter world.
There's a lot of bs out there.
Now there's me off that.
He does videos on Twitter.
That shit to Instagram doesn't know.
He thought he thinks Twitter is bad.
Thanks.
He's holding his reading glasses in
his hand. I mean he's going blind.
He's 71 old.
He
just see the, the, the DME sent
that dude amazing with all the,
all the knife emojis. What'd y'all do you
understand that with strategic, right?
He sent that on Monday.
Monday was the 25th anniversary
of the fucking Bronco Chase.
So you think that he didn't just want
to be in the news like that was a,
that was a strategic move.
I don't think he's that smart.
I think what's going on is he reacting
to someone fucking with him and he
doesn't, he doesn't know
how to just let shit slide.
So somebody makes a parody video or he's
doing his Twitter hello Twitter world
and then someone's got hell please
background. That's a great deal
to me. He gets mad and new DMS.
That person who made that video?
I'm going to cut you.
I don't think they said I'm going
to cut. Yeah. Yeah. Strategic Man.
I think he knew it was
the 25th anniversary.
The Bronco Chase and old ojs only
relevant is the fact that he got away with
murder,
so he has to remind us of that fact all
the time in order for us to give a fuck.
Did you ever see the videos
he did when he was doing rap?
When he's dressing up like King in Miami?
Yeah. He dressed up like a rapper. Yeah.
You said no yet Jamie. We
can't, we can't play it. Right.
You get pulled off of youtube real quick.
That stuff was faked
that DM stuff at the end.
Oh Wow. Yes. I listened to Jim
and Sam yesterday actually like
rub it down instantly. He made an
a fake account with like it though.
It was the real Oj. He just
made the l a capital. I
Ah,
[inaudible] gave him
he day for no fucking reason.
God Damn Lucky your I'm and I'm back.
I'm glad.
I'm glad he's not that stupid.
Right donkey today. The second one,
I'd go in the breakfast club.
I get somebody to the credit they
deserve for being stupid. I'm like, yeah,
you can't be that stupid, that thirsty
for attention Oj. So, so it's kind of,
it's kind of a relief that he's not
that thirsty. This is Oj when he
was doing rap music, all right,
well no we can't and now he is.
He can't play the music.
But he had girls out there dancing around
their underwear and the Oj was rapping
to me.
Have like a crown on or something.
There he is dressed up in like
white face and all sorts of things.
There's naked girls in it.
Oh God.
You don't think Oj man riding a wave of
killing these two people for too long,
Bro. Crazy bitches will
still fucking guarantees.
I don't understand this, this,
this part of women at all.
Like the women that like meet people
in jail and then they're like getting
married to them in jail.
Like what is this about?
It's thinking about that Jill Dick,
when they come home and jail,
those guys never get to
give them that jail Dick.
They're in jail forever and then get your
conjugal visits and they still want to
marry him. But why are attracted
to killers? So they want killers.
They want killers in specifically they
want killers that kill women. What? Yeah,
that's a thing with some women
with really fucked up women. They,
they're attracted to men who kill women.
God Damn happened. The girl just wanting
to get choked. No. Why? Why? Why go?
Why you got to go to that extreme? Spanky
that's all I'm going to just ranking.
Do you think all the choking
they know and like,
you know how like some girls have like
rape fantasies and shit like that.
Do you think that's all because
men have just become such pussies,
they want to see if they have
the ability to even do it?
No. I think some girls have this primal
need to know that you can kill them.
But what don't they know that this
turns him on? Turn Your Daddy,
right? Yeah. Protect them. It's
a tech kill them. Yeah, for sure.
But they want to know you could kill them.
Not that you're going to kill
them or kill someone else.
Trying to get them that hand
on your neck choking you.
They want to be like close to the door
of you doing something viable to them
while you're fucking them. So it feels
good. Why you got control over their life?
You really have like you're
holding their natural. Yes.
So why do we up too
dudes that like jerk off with like
a belt on her neck and choke them.
We call them Weirdos. Women.
Yeah. But that's different. Does,
that's on our erotic is
fix the [inaudible] it is.
But I think the choking is, you're
doing it. A man is doing it to you.
It's not just that you're running out of
oxygen because someone is squeezing the
blood out of your brain.
Right.
But it's also that someone's doing
it to you while you're while there.
Do you guys go for the whole choke?
Because what I do is I like put my hand
there and then I kinda just tense my
forearm. But I don't really squeeze
the fingers cause I want, you know,
cause it's way to really show like
that she won't let me do that.
She wants the whole choke. No, she doesn't
like that. She doesn't like that. Yeah,
because she knows you could do it.
Well it's not just that,
it's like she just did. You took people
out regularly. She knows you're capable,
but the kind of girl that wants
you to children like that,
I think you should leave that one alone.
Dude. My wife liked the load shogun.
I mean we've got, we've got no did all
of that stuff and kind of like subsided,
but she used to like a lot of choking.
You know we've been together 22
years though. Yeah. You want to play,
you have a John Doe she likes,
she's nice.
Did I do?
It's enough for us.
It's happening to you. Some
girls love it, man love it.
But I think it's really because
they see men as pathetic.
Now they see men as babies and the more
pathetic and like cocked up a guy is
there like, okay, choke me,
slap me around, show me that
you have some testosterone,
show me you have some sort of frame
gotta go give. Oh Jason Placido. Mike.
That's right. That's right.
They're asking. Oh, take the token.
Richard Ramirez used to have
girls visiting him Manson
that was married when he
died. [inaudible] Manson had charm.
He must have had something. No,
he must've had some, I've had fame.
Fame has always been in attraction.
People are famous in the beginning when
he was getting people to do all that
wild shit, man in Manson, right? Well he
wasn't famous. Buddy was a cult leader,
so, right. So he was the leader of
a small group. So he was infamous.
Infamous amongst that group of people.
But you got to at least turn a couple
of people to turn it into a cult.
Like eventually it becomes part of them.
But if you look at social media,
you realize that ain't really shit
right and ain't really shit to have a
following. You know what I'm saying? 500
followers on social media is pathetic.
Right, but 500 in real life. Yo, you
champion a man, Jim Jones. He's like,
especially in 67 yeah man,
you get 10 people,
you get 10 people to kill herself is 67
man.
Some people can't get 10 people to
accommodate you. That's what I'm saying.
That's a different kind
of captive audience. Yeah.
You would have met and know like you got
a fax them like there's no organization.
Everything has to happen in real
life. Yeah. Peach, like that's wheel.
He must have the speech when he made
everybody drink the Koolaid, bro.
Let me tell you something about
some he that must've been,
they know they were drinking. That
wasn't even cooler. You know? Cool.
I took a bad rap.
It was some like cheap Costco brand,
which koolaid existed even back
then I think who laid existed,
so he went with the generic to
me was some bullshit clerks.
It's like they didn't have enough
money for all Koolaid. Hey,
whatever the fuck they drink, they serving
it in the Dominican Republic. Every
cocktail in sandals,
performance is happening in the Dominican.
All these people are dying. They should
try to get that big PAPI. No, no, no, no.
This is a dye that resorts,
that was an assassination attempt hold.
People are dying at these resorts there.
They're listening to all these
Americans that are being poisoned.
One lady got beaten to death and raped.
She didn't get beaten to death but like
beaten half to death. She survived,
but like her whole head was just big
swollen, massive blood and injuries.
Everyday at the worked at this resort,
she saw him where at least
he was wearing an outfit,
clubbed her over the head and did all
kinds of crazy shit to her and left her
for dead.
I read a story today.
It was a group of high school kids who
went to the Dr of celebrating graduation
or whatever.
All of them ended up in the hospital and
nobody knows why this shit is happening.
Nine people have died at these
resorts and nobody knows what.
A lot of them are dying from
pulmonary edema and heart failure.
It's like some blood issue
and the drinking things from
the Minibar, the Minibar,
you know,
we'll do a walk around the yard a minute.
What is the number of buildable puts?
The number of people if tied over
then now it's like seven nine, nine,
nine nine and it's happening in
the resorts. The safe spots. Yeah,
it's happening in the
resorts. Fuck the dog off of.
We got to go to Dr. What?
What?
That's hunting right there. Let's
get into it. This is, this is,
let's get to the bottom of it. Do you
want really want to do some nature shit,
Joe,
you want to go do some major shit?
Let's go hunt some rapists in the
Dr. I wonder what's happening.
I don't think it's just right back and
got his right as people die from drinking.
If they started drinking at these mini
bars and drink it at these bars and like
they've been testing the alcohol and
it's like fake alcohol or some shit like
that. I don't know what the fuck is going
on. I just know nine people lived. Died.
Yeah. I'm not gone. Nah. Yeah, I'm
not going. Yeah, you can't take it.
That's all it takes.
It takes us nine people going,
Oh fuck up your whole tourist economy,
you would think.
But we live in this era where
people are like, Oh shit,
let's go over there and see
if we can survive the DVR.
Like it's become like a fucking
game almost. Yeah. Yeah.
Well this one, anybody dies of a cocaine
overdose. Everybody wants to shit.
[inaudible] right where you want the good
shit. You know what the shit they, no,
never ever done it. You ever do coke? I
fixed enough cold coins. I smoked in it,
a blunt with some weed. Okay. Back
in the day. But I fixed nifty,
like it was like the lines are
on the table and I just wanted
to make the people I was around feel
comfortable almost like on some training
day shit. I don't want them to think
I was like gone to a couple of copies.
So some mother fucking, you just do like
this. Yeah. And you knock it off. Yeah.
I just get a little on your face and
you just go, whoa. Everybody's high,
but it's not like they really do.
Black does say Wu after doing coke too.
I don't know.
I did [inaudible] ric flair movie.
I saw it. He let out a Goddamn
ric flair. Woo. I've had that
t that Mata de cocoa tea tea
made out of cocoa leaves.
Yeah, those, yeah, the
apparently the leaves,
if you just chew them are actually good
for you and they have the phytonutrients.
It's like cop, it's like a cup of coffee.
Okay. It's like, but it's healthy.
It's actually good for you. Right though.
Those high, those high altitude herders,
they put a big wad of
that shit in their mouth.
They chew on it and then it releases
into their bloodstream and it's actually
healthy. It's not bad for you. It's when
they process it and turn it into cocaine.
That is bad. That's when it gets, what
I've had is coca leaves in a tea form,
so you just take the leaves and it's like
you're in a tea bag and you drink the
tea. It just makes you kind of
like hyper and he talked to me.
I'm not gonna lie. When I smoked that
cocaine with that weed by accident,
that was the best high I've ever
had in my mother. Really? Yes.
I used to always say I would do it again
by accident if it was all by accident
on purpose. What? I think I'm too old
for that shit now, but back then my God,
I remember that high
like it was yesterday.
He said if you just feel like very alive,
like you feel aware,
like everything just seems bright.
Even when it's dark out and it's just
like you feel like you're actually on top
of something. It's just like you just feel
mad hypo. But when you crash you crash.
Came over when he crashes.
Tried Molly.
Yeah. Want to try them DMA and Dma yet?
Yeah, same shit. It was once though.
You like it or no,
I love the feeling when I was on it,
I did not like the next
day I couldn't read.
I was trying to read a magazine and I
couldn't read. I was like, I just can't,
I couldn't follow it. Yeah. My
brain was so dried out to shut down.
Just it was just debt. And then I've been
on stage that night and ate shit. Yeah.
Cause the synapses are firing
up. I was slow and sloppy.
My, my delivery was, yeah,
all fucked up. Cause when you say shit,
I thought literally I was like, Oh,
I can't wait to hear this story.
I was like,
you started reaching in your fucking pants
and you pull it out of my mind, dude.
So I've been going to burning man last
few years. Right. Real and uh, yeah.
Got, get the hippie pussy bro. Dude, it's
not even really like for me at least.
I haven't even really been fucking
there. No, no duty. You don't,
you're not showering, you're all fucking
hopped up on drugs and check. Yeah.
I think like the fuck communities exist,
but I don't want to sell it. It's,
it's weird to like sell it,
but it's a really cool experience.
You would probably really
love it. But, um, and I tried
Molly and it was, you know,
people say like when you
try drugs it gives you, um,
this heightened version of reality that
you can't come to naturally. Right.
And then you have a new
perspective because of it.
Some people say that about like acid or
mushrooms at these types of things. Um, it
was weird used for the
first time in my life,
I felt past emotionally fill full.
It was like excess. Does
that make sense? You don't,
you kill on stage and you walk off and
you just want to like help people because
you filled up the void and then you
have a little extra, right? Yeah.
So Molly put me there and I was like,
oh,
this is how people who
feel no void operate.
Like I was just calling my parents,
I was calling my best friends and tell
him I love him and I'm gonna take care of
your kids if anything happens.
Like w what the flow. Yeah.
Maybe they gave you the courage to
do things you want to do before,
whatever reason you choose not
to. Right. Because you know,
before I'm busy trying to fill the void,
right,
be it through laughs or through content,
whatever we're doing.
And here I had the excess and it was an
interesting experience to make me okay,
I can probably hit this maybe without
the drug, I can do things in my life.
Exercise or gratitude.
Gratitude 100% that's the ultra hundred
percent Dr Wayne w dies said that you
won't find your true purpose. Your true
purpose in life is service to others.
So I think most people that are public
servants and like give their lives to
other people, like I think that's
the ultimate high, but it's so crazy.
It's like you don't get to
notice that until you're there.
Like it's so easy to sell.
If you tell people, hey,
you should be grateful and
then you'll feel better.
But if they're not able to feel
the sensation of gratitude,
you're explaining to them.
You're explaining Chinese to someone
who doesn't even know what the fuck the
languages. Yeah. It's like we're,
we're all in this like unique situation
where we've probably experienced that
and we probably, you know, it tried
to find ways to give back, et cetera.
And then we felt really good because of
it, where like, I should keep doing this,
this,
this is a really good feeling thought.
But imagine someone who's like
barely surviving. They don't, yeah,
but they still have something to give.
They just don't realize it.
Like you might have $10 in your
bank account, but guess what?
It's a homeless person on the street that
has zero. Right? You give him a dollar,
you might feel great, and
then we take that dollar and
he's so appreciative. Like,
thank you. Thank you. Like that'll
make you immediately feel better. Yeah.
Really just helping people without any,
you know, you'd have no alter your motive.
It's a great feeling. It's addictive.
I thought about that with Karma, right?
Like we always look at Carmen,
we think that calm is what you put out
is what you're supposed to get back.
No calm is just an action and you're
supposed to do those things just because
it's the right thing to do,
period.
Like also Karma involves you feeling
the way you feel about yourself because
when you do shitty things,
you feel you have a bad self image.
So you live in your Karma that
people don't get. It's not like,
here's a dollar for a homeless guy.
Five minutes later I should get $10
it's not an investment Karma, right?
It's I feel better when I'm acting right.
It's simple as that.
You can't run from yourself. You
do. You go to sleep every night,
you look in the mirror like,
and when you jack off,
you know what you're thinking about
your Jackson. I'm like, you know you,
and I think a lot of people
don't understand that
concept. Like once you like,
I can't do people dirty because
I know I did somebody do it.
I can't do something. I'll
carry that. Cause I know I
did something foul. You know?
And even when somebody
does something to me, I've,
I've got to go through my
files and my mind like,
did I do something
fucked up to this person?
Did I do something to cause them to
run yet this, wait, no, I didn't.
That's their problem and that's
the competitive advantage
of sociopath's is they
don't carry the negative Karma. Sure.
Right. They have the interaction. We,
the three of us would walk
around afterwards like, man,
I shouldn't have fucking done that.
What the fuck was wrong with me?
I feel like a piece of shit. They
just go, no. All right, that happened.
I don't believe that. No. That's why
they, if they're effective in business,
that's why they're effective in politics.
That's why you see these
personality types succeed. No,
with the ability to just destroy
thousands of lives, you would just say,
but I think eventually it
catches up to all of them.
I don't think it does emotional
just suppressing shit so much,
but eventually I think that just,
I think that should just explode in them
and causing them to go crazy if they
don't fucking get killed.
There are people though that
don't experience any emotions
the way we experience.
No empathy. Yeah. There's,
there's, they're broken.
There's something wrong with the synapses.
Yeah. Stuff like that for a long time.
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah. When I,
when I started going to therapy is when
I started like piecing things together,
but I,
I,
I made myself cold just because
of how to protect yourself. Yeah.
And how I felt like the world and
the business was treating me. Yeah.
At a certain point.
Yeah.
I mean I was purposely making myself code
and I thought that was the way that I
had to beat you fucking around and read
books like the 48 laws of power when
you're young and you know,
you study all of these people who got
to a certain point and they all had like
this, this, this, this, this coldness
about them. Like this ruthlessness.
Like I'll step on anybody to
get to where I need to be,
but then you realize these motherfuckers
up miserable. That's the theme saying,
Dude. So you're on the island,
right? Lanai. Yeah. Right.
And were you hanging out with
any gallon folks? All. Yeah.
So there's this a comic and
little Duvall. He's, he's,
I really think he's one of the people
who understands life better than anybody
on this planet. My guy and good breeze.
Yeah. He's a good buddy of ours. He's,
he's fucking and brilliant.
And um, he says, he goes,
dude, for the smile bitch song.
[inaudible] you go,
okay Joe,
when I'm telling you stop vendor comes
out to that song easy man, let's talk.
We were on is pious last time we were
talking about how is he was going to do it
man. Yeah. But um,
he's one of these guys, I promise you,
his understanding of life is unparalleled,
unparalleled to anybody I've ever seen.
And you see a song like smile bitch,
and we see it maybe on surface value,
but everything he does has a purpose
and he's aware of the purpose, right?
He's aware of the energy puts out in
the ecosystem and how it affects the
ecosystem. And he was telling me
how he likes to go to the islands.
I visit him and Bahamas and he likes
to be in the moms. And I was like, why?
Why do you like to be here?
He goes, because people
understand what life is. Here.
I go, what are you talking about? He goes,
they don't get caught up in the bullshit
that we caught it get caught up in the
states. Right? And like in the states,
everybody here thinks they're going
to be a millionaire. Everybody. Yes,
we have a lottery or reality show,
some viral video,
and you'd go to the island and they
understand that they're gonna live and die
there. And then they
start to realize, hey,
I got to just maximize happiness in life
to try and get some chicken tenders on
the island. When we were in
Bahamas, it takes 50 50 minutes,
an hour for fucking five chicken tenders.
I'm like,
why the fuck is it taking so
long? And he looks at me. He goes,
why should they hurry? It's philosophy.
The purpose is real Buddhist.
Like it's a lot of it is a lie. He
doesn't know. He doesn't know that.
But his philosophy is like he's,
he's aware of it.
He don't even know what you call my nephew
who was Buddhist. He'd be like, Hey,
I didn't go to school. No Buddha. No.
He thinks he knows instinctively.
He no formal education comes from nothing
and the way that he's found a way to
understand humanity. It says competitive
advantage in the industry is in.
He just truly understands. It's fast.
We've complicated this shit dude.
We had that like capitalism
is complicated things,
you know the cultures that we strive
to be a part of of complicated things.
The truth of the matter is life
is about treating people good,
being a public servant and dying.
That's how I,
the crazy thing he goes, he goes, I love,
I love it and this is what's hard to
understand because I love hanging out with
old people. I'm like, why? He goes,
because they understand life
like what do you mean? He goes,
you eventually get to a certain point
where you realize you're going to die and
all these things that you want to
accomplish that you thought you had to
accomplish and all this shit that you
thought you had to get done in order to
value yourself as is meaningless. It was
just distraction. Until we get there.
Yeah. That's the concept. I could
you not believe hard to swallow too,
cause you have to let go of Ego, right?
You have to go, you have to go, okay,
I'm okay as I am and I'm okay having a
quick conversation with somebody or a
good interaction today or just fucking
sitting on the beach and looking at the
stars. Right. These are cool things.
That's just as valuable as
having a youtube clip hit
a million or something like
that. These, these things aren't
any different in the grand scheme.
A grand scope of things, right? Yeah. I
believe in the law of attraction, right?
Your thoughts become things.
So that's why it's hard for me
to grasp the concept of, okay,
when are you going to die?
Because in my mind I want to die when
I'm 90 or 100 years old. But you know,
you read certain things and you're
like, no, you have to embrace it.
You have to tell yourself
every day you're going to die.
Cause then you'll live your life
like every day is your laugh.
I that's a hard concept. You know CT
Fletcher, I've heard that name. So
he had a heart transplant last year and
he came on the podcast a year after his
heart transplant.
And you've never seen a guy more than
loving and open and friendly and thankful
and tells everybody loves him and he's
hugging everybody and just genuinely
grateful because he was at death's
door like legitimately on death's door.
His heart was failing him.
His father,
his heart had failed him
is his brothers is like,
he's got congenital heart disease in his
family and he knew that his heart was
going.
He had had heart attacks,
he'd had surgery and they transplanted
his fucking heart and they put a woman's
heart inside from two. Wow. Also fucked
with him. That's why his lines. Wow. No,
but I mean it's just like just that's
one. The one that fit, you know,
there was like this is matches you and
we're ready to do it. Bam. So now here,
here he is a year later,
but that guy has like this renewed lease
on life and he just, he glows like a,
like a, like a religious
figures. He got close.
Tell concept for a movie like somebody
who was a male chauvinist all his life
and shitting on women and then had to get
a woman's heart as a whole. [inaudible]
move yourself. Put Nail Polish. I'm
jealous for no reason. Wow.
Yeah. Interesting. Crazy. Yeah,
it is interesting. It's like that's why
now we're getting to the fuck up thing,
right? Like this idea of there is no
good and bad things just are et cetera.
Right. But like, but there's good and bad
and how the, the energy that you put out,
how it affects people.
If you do a bad thing and it
hurts a bunch of people's lives,
that's you're really,
you're changing how those people are
going to interact with all the people they
experience as well.
You fuck up the ecosystem.
There's a ripple effect
with the ecosystem. Right?
But like let's say you look
at like you were early,
we were talking about like bears,
right?
Or maybe I was watching a clip
of your show, but you're talking,
I think it was who you and
Duncan and you're like,
bears really just attract baby animals.
That's what they eat. They eat baby deer,
whatever they can, but the, the most,
most of the baby deer, that dog and Eaton,
they just, they're like animal pedophiles.
They're just killing fucking kids,
right? That's what they do, right?
That's what they fucking do. Coca Cola,
Coca Cola sponsor is an animal
pedophile, just eating baby seals. Right?
So that in our culture
would be a piece of shit.
What if there was a group of people
that just killed kits? Right?
We would call them pieces of shit.
That would be a bad thing. Right?
But that's just, you've
acknowledged within the, you know,
the ecosystem of that with those
animals, it's necessary, right?
The bears need to,
how do we know though?
How do we know there's not fucking
groups of animal rights activists,
animals in the woods saying
he's fucking man video.
We don't know what these
animals are really talking
about and really discussing,
you know the shark fin soup, Yo
Charlotte, you know what? Shark fin soup.
So they cut,
they just cut the fins off the shark and
then they'd let the sharks sink to the
bottom of the ocean and die and die.
Right. It just sing to them. I can't swim.
It just sinks to the bottom and there
was somebody tweeting about how horrible
it is. But I bet there's a bunch of fish
that are pulling up on that shark. Like,
Oh look what we got here.
You know what I mean?
Right. So say you've been there,
don't just stay there when they see,
you know they get the fuck on and hit
them and fucking humans with them guns
again, like I think animals are way
smarter than we give them credit for.
Well they have instincts. I think they
got a little more than, than things. Some,
some do, some animals are smart.
You know what's interesting?
Moose are some of the dumbest,
the dumb as fuck,
but because why so big? Cause who's
gonna take them out? There's so big.
All they have to do is stomp, stomp
wolves. That's all they have to do.
Wools try to come after him and then
they just came off. If I was a moose,
I'd beat them too though. Cause I'll
be looking at y'all like y'all dumb.
Y'All really out here with us. Yeah.
And I just, motherfuckers got the,
you don't have the nerve
to try me shooting at them
more than you're like fuck
he shot. It's like from game of Thrones.
What that, what's that guy's name?
Thorn and [inaudible]. No, his Iq,
but I can't imagine. It's incredible.
You think six, nine, 300 pounds.
You've got to figure shit out.
It might not have to, but some dudes
choose to this giant dudes that are
smart as fuck. Small Cox. That's what
level people would like to think.
That's what I have to think. You have
to make yourself feel better. Maybe six,
900 hammer. Always say that about
Shaq. Someone saying that about, oh,
he's got a little Dick. Uh, compared
to who or no, I ran, I ran, I ran.
I would compared to a bear
current stuff is book current stuff
and said she had sexual relations with
superhead. She said it's not
little, it's just regular.
So it's like his dick
probably look big on me
when on shack,
right?
Like nine inches ain't really big for you.
Shag Chris Rock joke about
the background and he's like,
I don't have a big Dick but I've got a
small background or something like that
so it looks like he's so skinny. That
is Dick. Oh, got you. Got You. Got You.
Got You got to check.
Needs to come through at the time Warner
remote check the 15 inches on his dick.
Yeah, that should be
set. That boring company.
What does that call Joe the barn
complaining. A lot of flame thrower that,
that's what shocked me.
Ain't got to disappoint a woman.
I guess what I'm saying it's like,
like with CT Fletcher,
right?
He needed to see death in order to like
have this amazing revelation about life
and maybe the fucked up things
that happened in the world. Right?
Maybe if there is some sort
of designed to all this,
maybe the fucked up things that happened
in the world allow us to have a little
bit of empathy and joy
for being able to be here.
But you got to give a fuck
about life first of all,
because I can think about all
the near death experiences I had,
whether it was somebody pulling a
gun on me, whether it was, you know,
me being drunk as shit and wrecking my
mom's White Lumina Caravan and literally
the only reason I survived because I
didn't have a seatbelt on it because I was
so drunk at the impact didn't kill me.
I didn't think about stuff like that until
decades later when it happened in the
moment. It was just like, all
right, whatever. I got into a wreck.
Oh I got a gun pulled on me.
But when you're old and you know,
I've got three daughters and I look at
my wife and I looked at people that love
and care about me and I really
appreciate and value life.
Now I started thinking back on that shit
like what the fuck was I think like I
didn't give a shit about life back then,
but I can get an anxiety attack thinking
about those past moments because those
past moments would have caused so
much not to happen if I died. Yeah.
So you've got to care,
you got to care and you have
to have something to care for.
And that's one of the things that
really changes when you have children.
Oh absolutely. Just change.
Chappelle said the best thing to me,
he said not only did it change
how much I love, he goes,
it changed my capacity for love.
It teaches you how to love.
Yeah.
You might not even know what real love
is until you have children and you
realize like, man, this is like my heart
walking around outside my body. Yeah.
And you feel a different level of love
with different level of empathy. Like,
like I remember my,
my daughter had attracted me like two
or three years ago and she was learning
the long jump and you know,
it was like the first time she ever
did the long jump. So it was literally,
it wasn't even a meet with like practice,
right?
And so she goes and do the jump and I
just, I go, oh my God, that was horrible.
And she just burst out into tears.
And I'm like,
well what the fuck did I just do? What
did I say? My wife was like, Yo, what's,
what's your, what's your problem? And
then other parents would come in like, oh,
it'll be fine. You did perfectly. I
said the fuck up. She didn't do good,
but I didn't understand that my
word meant everything though.
Her like everything.
So I just took all her confidence out of
her and just that one snap of a finger
like fails and that shit, even thinking
about that shit now hurts my heart,
but I've never made that mistake again.
Now I'm the father of that,
that that overly tells
her how great she is.
And I know how to explain to her if she
does something that I necessarily don't
think it's great.
I know how to explain it to her in a way
where she can do better and she's very
receptive to that changes who you are.
You how many kids?
Three daughters too. Oh, you
as a whole in the past life.
Let me see. Go wrong. I'm telling you this
is Carol. You versus meeting right now.
I swear to [inaudible] girls.
[inaudible] I know,
I know for my whole,
when I see
about how much it changed,
the way I feel about life is
that when my daughter was little,
there was two bananas and a one of them
was brown and fucked up and old and one
of them was perfect.
And I looked at those who bananas
and I know my daughter loves bananas,
so she'd probably want that Nice
Banana, I'm sorry, eight that fucked up.
And so while sitting there eating
this mushy mashed potato texture,
banana, I was thinking about this
and not another person in this world.
I would do that for because I love my
wife. My wife is an amazing person,
but it was just me and my
wife. I'd be like, Ooh,
I guess that bitch is getting the shit.
You had asked her three times.
You show baby sure you set it on.
The [inaudible] is perfect.
He just asked the wife three times.
They get it from the start.
You would literally, I'd jump in front
of a bus for her. It's a different thing.
So like this,
people say I would die for you don't
mean it most of the time unless they're a
Serb soldier who's wanting to
dive in a fucking grenade. Yes.
But if I could die and I knew that
my kids would be happy and healthy,
but if I lived, they would die. I would.
Dot. I flew out. I flew out.
Uh, I flew out here. I left.
I left New York five 30 this morning
simply because I was supposed to fly out
last night, but my daughter had
attract dinner, which I forgot about,
and it was literally like attract dinner.
It's in a fucking gym and they're serving
chicken tenders and Lasagna and pizza
and listen to the old town rolled Tinder
different times. Everybody gets
to participate. Participation,
trophy talk, please go
11 places. I'm like,
ah,
but I stayed just to be there.
I changed my flight and everything just
to fly out this morning because I needed
to be there for that track.
Then that's dope.
You don't do that for people that
you don't absolutely love and adore.
So here's a question.
You both have these kids and you need to
balance loving them so much and telling
them to the most amazing people in the
entire world and not making them horrible
human beings.
Well more than that,
and making them weak
and not making weak.
You have to give them a diversity or
they'll never know what to do with.
I think sports is the key.
The key to that make them do not
know that it's difficult. Well,
I know what you're saying
about participation trophies,
but get them involved in something
competitive where they have to struggle so
they'll learn what it's like to lose,
to learn what,
what life is like in a kind of controlled
environment and then you can still
nurture them and love them.
The difference between people
who participate in sports
and people don't as you
learned what losing is.
Yeah.
Some people never learn what losing
is and they just are terrified of it.
But they're not teaching these kids how
to lose no more. Some in schools, schools,
but I mean like competitive things like
get your kids involved in martial arts,
get your kids involved in these
things that are just, it's very clear.
The binary one or zero. Either you win or
you lose. Those are important. You learn,
you learn. Like what struggle is if
you have a race riot, attract mates.
Perfect example. Someone fucking want
and someone did not win. That's it.
You know like who? Oh you got to
cross the line and I'm second. Fuck,
I gotta be first.
How the fuck can I be first?
I've got to figure out how to run
fast. That's it. Will you guys ever,
will you guys ever be
openly disappointed in them?
Will you show them that they let you down?
The only time I'm that way with my kids,
when they're mean to each other,
I tell them I go, this is unnecessary. I
know while while you're feeling this way,
I know why you're mad at each other.
Be can't be shitty to your sister.
You can't do that.
It's a bad thing.
You've got to learn how to take a deep
breath and think about the consequences
of what you're saying and every time you
do do something Shitty, learn from it.
Yeah. You know it's a learning
experience. I think for me,
I'm just like that when I, when I think
that there'd be an ungrateful, okay,
am I going, oh my oldest daughter
is 10 my second oldest is three,
but so she doesn't really understand.
The concept behind the
daughter is nine months old,
but my 10 year old is had lived a very
privileged life and sometimes you see
that Bougie shit come out.
And like I'm saying like,
like little things like,
like I love this island called Angola,
you know what I mean? And we vacation
like two, three times a year.
Like these long, 10 day vacations,
just like ugh man. Quilla cane. Oh,
you know, we was on the Isle
of, uh, we was on green,
we was in Grenada and her and my niece
because my niece comes with me all the
time and they're just talking like,
the food is so much better and
cooler than here. I'm like, Yo,
no,
the fuck I was doing when I was
[inaudible] toys on fire and my thanks
[inaudible] road in Moncks corner,
South Carolina,
single wide.
Fucking try to like that.
The only thing that pisses me
off to his lack of gratitude,
but that's perspective issue though.
They'll never there.
They're wealthy.
They'll never gonna understand
what it's like to be surprised.
You instilled that in us. Impossible.
You know, there's gotta be ways Ms Man,
all of my favorite people
have fucked up childhood,
but I don't want my kids to have a child.
You're not supposed to.
My mom,
my mom told me we're here to
make our children's lives better.
Like my mom actually showed me like
my great great grandfather's taxes.
He had to pay one year and
that she was like a quarter.
What I'm saying like it was just something
to light but back then was a lot of
money.
So she was just saying that to me.
Just tell me that every generation is
supposed to be better cause I got this
thing sometimes where I feel guilty
about doing so well cause I don't have no
fucking skill set. Like I didn't go
to college. You know what I'm saying?
Like I'm not, I don't feel special. Like
why am I in the position that I'm in?
My mother was a school
teacher with 30 plus years.
Most she ever made was $30,000 a year.
So I can line up.
I get that for a fucking appearance.
So it's like that shit will
make you feel bad sometimes.
Like you'll feel a sense of guilt. So
she was just showing me that to say, Hey,
every generation is supposed to be
better than the next generation.
So our kids are supposed to
be way better than us. Yeah,
but don't you want to
prepare them for that life?
Like you look at any one of these
movies or even stories about, uh,
a king that took power and
then the son that he has,
Sonny has only some spoiled little
bitch who ruins the kingdom.
Well, that's the thing. Find me a
great man as a son of a great man,
find me a man who's the son of a
great man who's the son of a great man
because I'm great man. Always has
these weak little sons. And it's like,
how do you like maybe you do need
to create adversity for your kid.
Maybe you do need to
be a Dick a little bit,
and maybe it's selfish to be sweet to
your kid all the time because you're not
preparing them for the
world when you're not there.
I think you've prepared them for the world
when you let them find their own way.
Meaning like you got to cut the
cord. Yeah. I don't want my,
I don't want my daughter to get into
media, you know, if they choose to. Cool.
You know, my daughter likes the right
now, so she wants to be an author. Fine.
I'm not loving. I'm not really an
author. I wrote a couple of books,
you know what I'm saying?
When it goes rider,
right.
I think I'm not really an audit.
That's all I want. I want them.
I want them to find their own way.
When they find their own
wait,
then that gives them that integrity in
that purpose and everything else that
they're looking for them. I think
when you hand them things, yeah,
that's when the Eagle,
all that other shit I have to work for.
What I see in the communities that I live
in is I always like the rich kids that
have nannies that take them everywhere
and they don't see their parents very
much because the parents work all the
time and their parents vacation without
the kids. They like to go places
without the kids all the time.
You see a lot of that.
Those kids are getting fucked up
and you see them as they get older,
they're more and more vacant, more and
more weird. More and more detached. Yes.
You know,
but the kids that around the family all
the time and they do things with the
family, then they get a
richer experience. It's,
it's neglect and it's the parents that
are like super driven and they're never
home.
They're working 16 hours a day and that's
why they live in this fucking giant
mansion and drive around in a Bentley.
Like though those kids get fucked up
and they wound up getting on drugs and
empty and looking for
something to fill them up.
Imagine your parents sent you to
boarding school. I have a buddy of mine,
30 minus Brian County is a,
his parents sent him to fucking boarding
school in the United States and they
didn't even live in the United States.
They send him to another country. Jesus,
where's Brian from? I love Brian.
Brian is from all over the world.
His Dad was a banker and international
banker air quotes and uh,
traveled everywhere and was involved in
some weird foreign shit weapon deals.
We can talk later.
But he was involved in some weird
weird shit and then sent his,
was fucking 13 years old.
Set Him to the United States to go to
boarding school and Brian to this day,
still a little shell shocked cause of it
dude. And at your parents send you away.
You feel like when you're 13 it's,
yeah.
Imagine if he was at that boarding school
and got fucking molested or something.
You would really hate life each
parents molested. No, I'm just saying,
let's just say listen somebody
that's funny. That hasn't been, yeah,
you got to get that funny diddled in.
Something fucked up happened. Yeah.
If you're fucked up, if you're funny,
something fucked up. Some, some pain,
some struggles. You have to
learn it, you have to learn it.
Why would you need funny? It's like, it's,
it's why it's so rare to see
people always say this about women,
but like even attractive dudes.
Like have you ever seen like a male model?
That was funny. I was to say about
girls carrot top, unless you fat,
your stories suck. Real talk. It's
true. Unless you have to earn pussy,
like lesbians are hilarious.
[inaudible]
right fucking to talk to Tiffany Haddish.
Yes. Tragic is, fuck. Sorry. Yes.
She's not fat. No, no, she's not. But
she had that tragedy. The tragedy. Yeah.
Yeah. That does. The tragedy is the, that
y'all say being a fat is a tragedy. Yes.
Oh, for Shit. That's why miss
pat is hilarious because she's,
that's why.
That's why you would never want
your kid to become Miss Pat,
but you love Miss Pat.
He's not miss you.
Let me spread only because like that's
when you go through that kind of trauma.
When you come out on the other side,
you're really unstoppable. Yeah.
Especially when you deal
with what's going on in here,
which is the toughest part, right?
Yeah. I think that's what comedy does.
Comedy is therapy for a lot of people,
a hundred percent therapy for a lot of
people. It gives you an escape. Well,
that's why she was able to accept what
that guy did to her and forgive him
because she just, she's passed it.
Yeah, she's on the other side. Yeah.
She's gotten through on the other side
and it forces you to deal with the
reality of the world.
Like I think comics better than most
people deal with the reality of the world
and often it's because we went through
some kind of real shit, right? So we go,
Oh yeah, these things happen so I
can let my mind even operate in it.
When you exist in like a really privileged
life, emotionally and even mentally,
when you exist in that space,
you don't want to imagine that
there are people starving.
You don't want to imagine there are
people hungry or that their parents are
abusing their kids. You don't even want
to go there because you don't have to.
When you grew up in it, you're like, yeah,
that's what the life is. Where's the fun?
My Dad could hit me for shit.
My mom, when you travel,
you can appreciate where you're going.
Is your daughter's like again,
he'll go again. I went to
South Africa in December. Um,
it was like the hundred view of Mandela.
It had been his hundredth
birthday or something like
that and I took my daughter,
my
10 year old daughter.
So like a few months later she had a
project in school where she had to do a
project about Nelson Mandela in South
Africa and so she had printed this picture
of the Nelson Mandela statute and from
Mandela Square and had it as the cover
and I'm like, where's the picture of you
next to the statue? And she was like,
I don't want to use that.
What the fuck do you mean you don't want
to use the picture of you standing next
to the actual statue in
a Nelson Mandela Square?
That's the point of these
experiences because you're
able to do things like that.
I had to explain that to her.
You have to teach her how to flex,
teach a class on how to
start, Bro. You got a kid now,
but think about how normal that
moment seem to her as she was.
Don't even need to use this as a cover
for my book. I think she's embarrassed.
You don't think she didn't want the
other kids to be like Kansas rich private
school in Jersey. All these kids are doing
well or not the kids, but the parents,
all the parents are doing
well. Like, yeah, like what
did I, I yo would you guys,
you guys got, you guys got
some money and you've got kids.
What'd you guys pay to get
your kid into a good school?
Cool.
Oh,
like that lady didn't know no fucking
chance actually earn that shit. Yeah.
You got to earn that shit.
You can't do that.
Cause they're not going to enjoy
it and they're not going to do,
they're not going to work hard.
Yeah.
Some of those people paid a half a
million dollars. Right. To get up,
get a Shitty, shitty kid into some
schools that they didn't deserve.
Yeah. And the kid's not going to have
no passion for what they know in,
you know what I'm saying?
They just dare like they gotta fuck.
It's just like having a regular
piece of paper like I want,
I want my kids to do things
that they really want to do.
That's how you change the world.
You change the world when you're doing
things that you, that you want to do.
Yeah. What's funny, I thought,
isn't it those kids that went to the
school like did fine at them. So yeah,
so school's just a big fucking hustle.
It's like if they didn't
earn it based on grades,
they should feel right the
fuck out of the school.
It's becoming a hustle just because
of the way the world is working.
Jane went to school for audio engineering,
not a Goddamn thing he learned in
school he could use today. Really?
Yeah. Yeah. I mean for the
most part I got the touch.
Some stuff I could never
have touched before.
No.
[inaudible] at that time it was,
it's like 2005 maybe youtube didn't
exist and there wasn't the plethora of
knowledge out there that 12 year olds
are teaching you how to record audio now.
Whereas I had to learn from the guy
that was recording mnm and Jay z and all
these guys, doctor tray. Right.
Like they can't really do much with that
job either, besides teach it now either.
So
that's why I like the go back to Joel's
point when he said I'm the last and
radio to reason.
I'm probably the last thing radio is
because I'm the guy that steering people
away from radio when she's come up to
me and I'm like y'all want to get in the
radio? I'm like full what? You can
start a fucking podcast and like,
you know what I'm saying? Like it's
all type of different ways to be heard.
You can go on youtube and if
you want to be a VJ on TV,
you can start doing your
own video countdown's on
Youtube. Like why you need TV
or radio to do middle man gone. Yeah.
We didn't have any of that growing up.
I had to be on the radio. You had
to be on radio, you had to be on TV.
We didn't have that shit
growing up.
Now I'm even experiencing
that with commentary for
the UFC because I love doing
commentary for the UFC. Be Known. I love
even better. I do these fight companions.
Yes. When you want to get
in here we get hammered.
He start smoking weed and talking shit
and we watched the fights on the screen.
We have the best time.
It's way more fun than being there live.
Do you think that's the future
of all live events? Right.
So you could watch the NBA finals
and instead of listening to the guys,
you know Marv Albert or whoever do it,
you could choose your guys that
you watch the commentary with. Oh,
so fight companion for basketball.
Football.
Well Dana Hart was doing
that with Snoop Dogg. He had,
he had a the Tuesday night contender
series and snoop Dogg and Uriah Faber.
We're doing commentary and snoop would
just have a constant blunt lit and he was
drinking tankaray and getting
hammered hot and talking crazy shit.
That was an option for the commentary.
You should listen assumption snoop cast,
it should be right.
It should be every single one like got
tired of doing it though. Stop doing it.
He'll snoop is thought to be
around Dana White. Ah, it's bright.
I think he just got tired of
having to be there every Tuesday.
Well that's a beautiful thing.
Like we showed you the, excuse me,
the NBA did this during
the finals this year.
They tried an alternative stream
using the ESPN APP. Right.
So the thing about this as you're doing it
with ESPN guys, right? Correct. Correct.
So it's like what would be great is do
it with like the funniest commentary guys
that you like in your life.
Hear them too.
Just the reason why people
tune into your thing. Right.
I'd guarantee they'd probably mute the
TV. Right? The people who are watching,
they listen to both.
I think that's what people probably do.
So they never let the good commentators
commentate anything like Todd Bockley,
kidneys, movers, shacks.
You'd be actually commentating dorm
the NBA and it would be incredible.
It would be incredible for them talking
shit to each other. Matter of fact,
put them on a little screen in the
bottom so we can actually look at them
visually what they're doing.
I Dunno, I just think of that
UFC, they have the best guys doing like
Daniel Cormier. He does it and he's great.
Dominick Cruz, Paul Felder, you
know, they have good fighters. Uh,
Michael Bisping that do commentary
now. Columbia is the best though. Yeah,
he's great. He's hilarious. Yeah.
And you used to fight fuck gaze.
The heavyweight champion.
He comments.
He's the light heavyweight champion and
then the, he vacated his title and the,
he's the heavyweight champion.
Yeah, he does commentary.
We do it all the time together. Wow.
Together. Cause you guys get fucking,
we're also good friends so we're always
talking shit and we're laughing about
things like whether it's a judge who's
a nice lady but a terrible judge Europe.
But this is like when, when
Rose Nama, une is one the title,
he starts screaming out thug row.
Yeah.
It's not like you guys turn
into fans. Yeah. Well we are.
I mean neither one of us
are real professionals,
but we do it for a living and it's weird.
That's my worst nightmare.
Like to be out somewhere and fucking
get into a argument with an MMA fighter.
You don't realize that name if me
no, don't say, oh she's terminates.
Propel show where he got folded
when keeping it real goes
wrong. When the got to hold
him up. [inaudible] girl.
I'm telling you. Got To chop.
Forgive you bro. [inaudible] or other
signs other than ears. Here's a good one.
But, but the thing is you
can wear at your cards.
I don't have any cauliflower ear.
I have a little bit on this year,
but I wear ear guards.
Get changes the way you hear things.
You don't want that cauliflower ear the
case your stick out already too much. Oh,
they would stick out like a bat. Yeah,
you'd have a big old knots and cancer.
There's no other signs of, of what? Of
a guy could be an MMA. No, not really.
Like hands. What about knuckles? No, I
mean you can tell and not tell. You know?
It's not. You don't know. See, that's the
way it's gotta be nice to people. Be Nice.
Nice. Are you going to find yourself
in one of those? You got it, Bro.
Fucking Andy Ruiz,
the new high champion.
[inaudible]
you look at his body, he would think no
fucking way. And you look at Anthony.
Joshua was sculpted out of marble.
Ben Thought he was trashed, Bro. Yeah.
It been saying we've Saint Anthony's
hospital was not that guy. Never.
He never had it. Never. He is
literally Ivan Drago. Literally,
he's the UK. Ivan Drago. He
looks the part, ladies love him.
He never had that skill in the ring.
I told him that when he came on breakfast
club. I don't think that's true.
He got dropped by Klitschko and
he came back to knock them out.
Let's go with [inaudible]. She was a
old ass man dude. And he's Ukrainian.
He's got Chernobyl and them and shit.
He was seminar.
That's nuclear poisoning and shit.
He was very old.
He was trying to win an election
for like this, you know, crazy.
Because she's got a lot of
things going on in his life.
The real fight is to Deontay wilder Tyson.
Fewer to,
how about this tight security
closest thing we've, we've had, uh,
in the heavyweight division to Ali. I'm
not going to say, I said after that,
I said a couple of fights.
I think he is the head movement.
The foot movement at his size and weight.
I leave was doing that 212 pounds.
His head moves. That last fight was
very Ali, like on an amazing deal,
but Ali did that with George Foreman.
You see there's a difference.
The guy that he was fighting like
that Guy Deontae Deontae he did it,
but he also got dropped
and almost murdered.
He died every time I look at 12th round
when Deontae connected and then walked
back,
went like that game over and the fact
that he just rose up and then outboxed him
for the rest of the round when I
was over all those years of therapy.
That's all those years of
therapy and meditation.
When did he say he hit
him and knocked him out?
He was in that place of stillness.
Oh, he knows how to come up.
Absolutely chaos. It was chaos are
weird, man. It's like sometimes the,
the a punch does not look like much
and it drops you and puts you away and
sometimes you get fucking flat line like
right there and it looks like you're
over watched. I was amazed at
the ref and gave him a cal,
thought it was going to call him out.
I thought,
I thought the ref was going to
wave their hands. Meanwhile,
this motherfucker rises up
and doesn't even look wobbly.
Unbelievable. By the way,
Anthony,
Joshua can't beat Tyson fury.
He can't beat Deontae while I know
he can't beat Louis Ortiz. Well,
well I don't have, Louis is all too,
here's a good 90 years old. The word is,
and I get this from a reliable sources
inside the fight community. Yeah.
That Anthony Joshua got dropped in
training camp right before the fight. Bad.
Yeah. From Philly. Right. I
don't know who, but bad to
the point where he was chaos.
Yeah,
essentially.
And that's why his dad went after
the promoter after the fight was,
you see his dad's screaming
at the provider in the ring.
Apparently he was just not, he's
not prepared to fight. And he had,
he was looking bad in the locker
room that they were worried about.
So we'll totally get a panic attack.
Yeah. That's what I heard too.
He had a panic attack before
to fight and if you remember,
we know it took him a
while to come to the ring.
Like they even played dance music and
everything, but he never came out.
And I was told that when,
if you notice when he was walking out,
he was rubbing his back and
they were rubbing his head.
I already had a panic attack,
fainting attack.
If you've been Kao like within a week,
you,
it takes months to get your
shit back together again.
The whole world is like shaky
to you. Well, equilibrium's off.
So he was in there and then when he
dropped him, he was like, Jesus Christ,
can I go get him? No, no. When he
dropped me or whatever, he's like, good,
we've got it.
Let's get this motherfucker out here.
And then he went right
at them and then boom,
he got clipped and then it was over.
There's a, uh, there was a, the biggest,
what is it? The biggest upside
heavyweight history is typing, right?
Guess who got dropped and
training camp. Tyson did, did he,
I'm strapped and trends, right? I
forget the guy's name who dropped him,
but his sparring partner track them
and training camp. There's video of it.
This video, the Human
Kao. Let me took a knee,
but still it's like got dropped your
body shut down for a second and it takes
time to recover from that shit and that
dimension in the night before he was
fucking a bunch of Japanese women would
Bobbi Brown in the hotel room and doing
drugs by the fives five at a time.
Take a toll out.
Yeah. They'll take a toll. Bobby Bobby
said, Mike told him, I'll be right back.
Bobby was like, don't you got to fight
tonight? And he's like, yeah, yeah,
I'll be right back. I'm going knock
the guy out and I'll be right back.
And he still got up and he
still dropped buster Douglas.
That's even crazier because you have a
watch the 30 for 30 about Buster Douglas.
No,
they had the 30 for 30 in me.
I didn't realize how much
he dominated Mike Tyson,
like round four round. He was
punishing Mike Tyson. Yep.
I remember that when I was just a,
Douglas is like one of the most talented
guys that just didn't have the kind of
drive and discipline that you needed to
be a champion. But when his mom died,
mom or dad is mom.
That's what gave him all the drop dead.
He was hooking off the jab on
Tyson popp like in a beautiful way.
His skill was incredible and wasn't
afraid. It was a world beater.
He was a world beater in that fund. We
needed the motivation. No, totally feel.
Fucked him up after that and
yeah, basically done. No, he
didn't. He was done. Yeah,
but he's a, he's infamous.
He beat Mike Tyson when it,
when it meant something to beat Mike.
I found out about it after the fact.
I didn't watch the fight live. I had
a Gig that night, not in real time.
And then I watched it later and I still
was waiting for Tyson to get up and beat
him. I didn't believe him,
believe it. I remember,
I remember watching that
fight and in my mind,
I guess I wasn't really paying attention.
I was just like,
this is longer than most
Tyson fights always so low.
You can have a dinner
reservation on a Tyson. I'm like,
and then when you finally got
knocked down, I'm like, Oh shit.
Mike just laws doesn't
mean you've got to think.
Not only did we grow
watching Mike Fuck people up,
we grew up trying to beat him
on my Titan Punch. As you say,
that shit was impossible.
So it's this like dad,
that was an unbelievable moment.
I didn't feel like that we were weeding
Joshua though.
Well there's certain times of people lose.
You can't believe they lost.
Like for me it was Roy Jones when
Tarver knocks him out. I was just like,
what on fucking White Jones?
They stopped to this day, man.
Unreal. If you watched in the second
round. It's really interesting thing.
It happens.
They both,
they both throw hooks and
Tarver just gets there. Yeah.
And we'll Tarver was
actually a south pole rights.
I think it's his is kind
of like a looping left,
but they exchange and Tarver
just hits first. Roy timed
it and this, what happens?
I think when fighters get a little bit
older they lose a fraction of a second
and that fraction of a second
earlier and Royce career,
he's checking them and then he's
moving out of the way. Well,
I think the real there is is fine. Do you
see it? Oh look at them. Exchange ready.
It's an yep. Boom. At one point
it changes everything. Well,
you know what Tarver coach said that
Tarver beat him in basketball. Yes.
And then when he saw that he beat him in
bed, the bed or after, who was his coach?
Mcgurk is buddy. Yeah. I
think find that's true.
Did we had, we had Roy on a,
on a on flavor and two and
a, I asked him, I was like,
were you ever worried about like
getting knocked out in like a, you know,
losing something, leaving something in
the ring and he takes a second. He goes,
I'll be honest with you,
man.
I didn't come in the rain
with much sense to begin with.
So I wasn't really worried about losing it
straight up. I've got a crazy
competitive nature to Roy last,
was it last year?
Last year Roy was hitting me because he
really wanted to fight Michael B. Jordan.
Yeah.
Would be Jordan say that he thinks
we were talking about
on the podcasts like,
no, I really want to
fight him. Road was like,
y'all got the sponsors
that can put them money up.
I think it was like $30 million.
I made the call for him
and Michael was like, Nah.
He was like, Nah, we good on that. Like,
Yo Roy would fuck Michael B. Jordan. Oh,
don't let creed fool you. Don't let
fucking kill mom game black pants.
You still run up on one of
them old boxes right now.
Muscle memory will get you not them.
Right.
And some would even be close.
So horrific.
And isn't that what happens
is like some guys start,
they start fight fighting
or they start to an MNA,
they start doing a little
Brazilian Jujitsu or some
shit like that. Right? Yeah.
And they put a couple of jokes in it,
like a safe controlled environment and
you get that like delusional. Yeah.
Confidence.
And that's why sparring so important.
Do you remember the first time you guys
sparked? Sure. I'm not the first time.
Well you were doing since
you're a kid, right? Yeah. Okay.
I mean the first time I started
before I went in the ring I was like,
oh I got this. It's just combos,
whatever. I almost fucking frightened.
Frightened when the we're coming back.
Yeah. I was just a shell. I just stopped.
Yeah. Miss bought since the last time I
was born. I swabbed with Shawn Porter.
Really? Yeah. This was nuts.
He was actually throwing
punches. Yeah. Cause I was mad.
But this shit don't mean nothing.
He was dodging.
I'm surprised he didn't knock your
ass. Hell Bro. And this is one of the,
there's this guy's head
movement is impeccable them.
I mean people have tried to tack them
on the street and they missed it every
single time. Cho, Cho, Cho.
It's unfucking real cute is what
do you got here? Here it is. This,
you guys far look at him going forward.
This is a PR move that's got a
PR move I was trying to show.
I know you're sweating.
Mm Nah.
That shit is in Brooklyn.
And you gotta be focused cause
there's people yelling in there.
You're showing me and got on,
make up.
[inaudible]
can I get a drop from the army? You
lefthanded? No, I'm right handed.
I'm just trying to throw him
off a little bit. Really? Yeah.
He did that on purpose, man.
He'll know what he's doing.
I don't know what the fuck
[inaudible] bouncing word his mind.
Do you know movement.
Do you train in boxing or are we
just doing this for a goof? Nah,
I just wanted to go in there and I was
like, fuck it. This is Shawn Porter.
I'm a boxing fan. I'm like, you
know what's the worst can happen?
You get knocked the fuck out. Worst can
happen. Is these mean? Yeah, you're right.
That could be terrible. I'm just sitting
there flat footed. Yeah. He's now,
we not even really and we
went three rounds. Wow.
That was about to die at the end of
the three rounds bolted a few times.
That's why I haven't spots.
It's like stay in my fucking lame.
You know what I mean?
I hit the punching bag callins bars all
the time and I'm like, Bro, doing? Yeah,
Brian on that pry can DJ count?
Oh no one person is not doing any cardio.
It's Dj Cally
Ruiz, one cal getting out of
a car with a gun hanging out.
It's like all the big guys.
The day after the release was the title
Kaolin Kaolin Kaolin been working out on
snapchat for a whole year and
didn't lose her motherfucking pants.
This guy and got a weight watchers deal.
God left the marriage,
didn't really steal a weight watchers.
I mean we are just watching this weight,
this plus size models,
right?
And they're doing that now like Nike and
the Nike store has like a big mannequin,
like a fat mannequin, but they don't,
they don't have plus size models from men.
Chill. There's nothing that
enrages me more than fat models.
There is nothing that enrages
me more than fat for. Okay,
let me just say something. As
a comic, we want attention.
We don't feel like we deserve it.
So we make you laugh.
So there's an even exchange. I get my
attention. You get some joy. Okay, actor,
they want attention and I'm
willing to write the script,
but they'll memorize some lines.
So do a little bit of effort to
get the attention. A regular model.
It least she's willing to lose
weight so that she can be looked at,
but these fat bitches are just like,
look at me.
Stop using the word bitches in 2019
what the fuck that's, that's a,
that's the plus sized model
mannequin.
This is the all
dentist rage.
You guys.
The only thing I don't like about
that in Rachel that they're like,
just stare at me. I'm going to eat bread
all day, but you should stare at me.
The only thing that
bothered me about that,
that's out of context because that's the
oversize mannequin in workout clothes.
Right? Right. She's going to
lose the weight. Now she's
trying to lose weight. Okay,
so I need needed some context.
This is workout gear.
So overweight women who want to go
lose weight. Cool. Other than that,
why are you wearing workout gear?
Because she's trying to lose weight.
That's the only reason you'd be
wearing it. She, she even bigger,
if she didn't work out,
she like Allen.
Cal didn't Jay,
Jay,
you gotta have a Dj Khaled
level of annoyance to succeed
in life though, do you?
Yes you do.
Oh, wait, you do? You do so much.
It's so much in your fucking shirt.
He's the no way. You didn't know
you could button your shirt.
He's the epitome of not being
afraid to ask for things,
but it looks like French toast.
Jesus. Every time I look at him,
it's French toast and he has no,
Oh cal it minus the butter
and the maple syrup. It
says the lost 15 kilograms. What does
that 34 pounds? Yeah. Yeah. There you go.
Lost 34 pounds. Listen, congratulates.
You can see his dick now. Congratulations.
Slimmer on the ride. He does
look a little slimmer. Oh, okay.
Maybe it's a little bit rose Christ's.
I don't even know what that is. Our,
we watch her. I respect that
cal came from radio. Oh Dude.
Cal came from Radio College, used
to do 12 midnight to 2:00 AM, uh,
on weekends at w Edr and Miami,
if I'm not mistaken.
He used to do Friday and Saturday night
and then that was like 15 years ago.
Right. So radio is a lot like comedy
in a way. Right. And not like this,
like a sort of a
fellowship of radio people.
You respect people who
did it. Yeah. It's so,
it's so few and far between that actually,
I guess make it so to speak that
you know who those players are.
You know what I'm saying?
So yeah, in a way. Yeah.
And there's so few like national ones,
like who's like nationally
known radio guys, Elvis Duran,
there's maybe a dozen. Um,
you, Elvis, Bobby, Tom,
us. Tom Is retiring this year. What about
Steve? Is Steve National TV national?
Obviously those,
and I respect Steve and I respect Ryan
Seacrest and I don't really count those
guys cause they didn't start in radio.
They in grassroots cause didn't start
in radio, wasn't he on own radio guy?
Dan have no, a radio guy a lot. I did
his radio show in the nineties. Okay.
So he might've, he might've been
none. He doesn't tell him on the show.
He doesn't radio five
jobs from American idol.
He does radio day. Yeah,
it does it in the morning.
And he does that secretary radio.
What do you like it like, hey,
you're the one who won,
you know, come on be thing like that kind
of shit. Why don't we run is never off.
No, we work for the same company. I heard,
I've seen Ryan walked out the bathroom
like he's walking on stage to introduce
the next guest on American idol.
Like he's always on.
Like how is a perfect example
where like you're gay?
Rumors trumped tear me to rumors.
What happened?
Remember when he called the me too and
like a girl said that he meets who'd or
whatever and then a girl who worked
with right, something like that.
And then everybody was like the gay guy.
Okay,
sure. He's, he's not
okay. What is he know?
What is he, what do you call it? I
don't know. Ryan is one of those people.
He is a handsome, those fucking teeth.
But you don't think about sex with him.
So what is he right out with a letter.
So what? ASEXUAL sexual, sexual. Oh,
that's the old, it's a
positive. Positive. Is Oh,
closet to he's, oh, he's like, oh,
you don't fuck dudes or chicks.
Okay. I see what it is. Yeah.
He's always on. I've, I've, uh,
can you imagine him choking the
girl? No, no. Absolutely not.
I can imagine she's beating him to death.
[inaudible] down in the
middle of Bolivia, right.
Is One of those people that when you hear
something about him, you'd be like, Nah,
not right.
You know what I'm saying?
Like you have that kind of personality
was actually worked in a lot of people's
favorite. Yeah. What's
great for top 40 radio?
It's great for secretaries that call
in. Yes. You're the seven color.
Congratulations. What'd you think
about the finals of game of Thrones?
That kind of
shit that some people thrive in that,
that frequency so good at being like
authentic in the most inauthentic
situations.
Explain like,
like hosting a show is why like America's
got talent, all that kind of stuff.
When you've got to be like really excited
about somebody like juggling deldot's
or some shit that's really inauthentic,
but he kind of comes across as believable,
like sincere that matter,
meaning like this.
His reactions and knows moments matter.
I just [inaudible] care that no one cares.
Chief man, that's a pretty man.
He's America's host. He is, yeah.
He's America's holes man. He said host
some den in that slot, that's for sure.
Big.
The Rowan's say what did put him on Clark?
Does he do the New Year's countdown now?
I've got a lot of jobs, man. Listen,
they was [inaudible] they was probably
in Dick's Kopeks cops up for like 10
years before they finally say,
Ryan, just do it yourself.
Right when he had a stroke and he was
still do it. Not that your dick been dead,
Bro. Wait, he had a stroke. He was doing
out the side of his mouth, like to phase.
He was struggling.
He was definitely struggling to talk.
I said it was so they kept them bad. Yeah,
like they, and it went from he would it,
but then it was just like they would
pop in on him and like some studio and
he'd be like sitting there struggling and
talking. I'm like, why do they keep
willing Dick Clark out for New Year's Eve?
Like you're actually depressing
people before the ball drops. Oh,
and then they had Kathy
Griffin and Anderson Cooper.
That was a great combination.
It annoys me. No Man can
shut up. I love Kathy Griffin. She
enrages me. Just like the fat model,
Kathy, because Kathy don't give a shit. I
like Kathy would the same reason I like,
I used to like join rooms. I mean,
I say used to because she's dead,
but I mean like, oh no. John Legend,
they both didn't give a shit.
They will cut from the same cloth.
I don't know if they're cut from
the same cloth. So man, I think so.
I used to love Anderson
and Kathy Griffin together.
You've never heard anybody say that
you're guilty pleasures.
Anderson Cooper and cat.
Look at that chemistry.
You breakfast club. Now I'm saying she
cut. She cut Trump's fucking head off.
That was, that was a strange
thing that would change.
What was strange about it is the fact
that she didn't think she was going to
suffer any consequences from that.
I think people forget that Donald Trump,
even though he is the ex
executive producer of celebrity
apprentice and he was a
reality star, he's the president
of the United States of America.
It's rules about threatening
heads of state. Yeah.
That you just can't do things like that.
But it's hard.
It's almost like a fucking flavor
flavor became president. Right.
And it would be hard for you to look at
him as anything other than flavor flavor,
but you better respect his position
before those God damn minutes suits come
knock on your fucking door
at flavor becomes president.
Well Donald's the first guy who was
famous like other than Ronald Reagan,
I guess Ronald Reagan was famous as an
actor, apparently. Really famous, famous.
I don't think he was famous,
famous.
He was in big movies and then to the
governor of California. You know,
it's a weird one,
right?
I mean just having a famous person in a
popularity contest is strange cause you
got a built in advantage.
That's how all of them are going
to visit popularity contracts.
Not all of them are going to be
moving forward. Someone could say.
Some people might say Obama was
the first celebrity president.
He became a celebrity though.
I don't think he was one
before now. No, absolutely.
I think there was some, Nah, not
Trump is on a different level.
Domino's commercials, Bro. He has Trump
had rap songs named after him like,
hey Caroline. Yeah, an
airline. I'm fucking hotel.
I'd show him is on buildings all
across the world. Giant Trump letters.
He was a brand troubles.
He might not have been the first thought.
Trump was the first brand
to run for president.
Reagan might've been the first star.
Trump was the first brand,
but he was definitely a
bigger star than Reagan.
I think easily it's
Megan is before our time.
It's hard to understand what it
was like when he was a movie star,
but I don't call it,
it's called Betty White and after
it's up to how big is still alive?
She's still alive. Still kicking,
checking. Do we have to like,
do you have these people's Joe?
I don't have her number. Okay.
Was anybody in a while? You become
famous. You get on a Rolodex like here,
here's a list of all these
famous Keanu Reeves, Betty White,
some famous people where I
texted him and I call him.
I'm just like this so strange.
[inaudible] feel like that. Mm.
Steven Tyler's a weird one from Aerosmith
and text each other and I'm like, Huh,
okay. All right. That's the most
surreal feeling that while it was weird,
I never get youth today. No.
It's humbling though. Yeah,
but that's why I always say
I don't, I don't do shit. I
got no wait. I talk. Right.
I know people who have real talent
actually looked up to growing up that
people like about you is that you
recognize that in yourself.
Yeah. You know that you're not,
you're not oblivious to that.
You're not delusional. I mean,
I kind of wanted the room to be
like, well, no, you are talents.
[inaudible] you weren't fucking normal.
[inaudible] just double
down on [inaudible]
let's change it. Came up a little
bit like that in that regard.
For
people listening, they want to
know that, you know, you know the,
you can't play musical instruments
sing or do something crazy.
They want to feel like reflected like
often, often at times I think they had a,
your audience resonates to you like that.
It's like you are asking a lot of times
the questions that they would love to
ask people. When I,
when I listened to you,
I hear somebody who is still a fan
and that's how I, that's how I feel.
Like I'm curious, I'm curious. I
have a curiosity about things and,
and I'm not afraid to, I don't, I don't
know shit I don't have, yeah, I don't,
I just got some experiences. I'm not
an expert at nothing. Everybody did.
I sit across from is way smarter
than me and I'm fine with that.
Let's have a conversation I want to learn.
That's good. That's no, that's what,
that's probably why you're successful is
the way to thing where people be like,
oh,
I can't believe you would say.
You would ask you Elizabeth Warren
about her native American ancestors.
Did you see that? What do
you call the original, well,
Rachel's by now too, but did you see
the interview with him and, and uh,
Elizabeth Warren? Yes. He calls her out
on the native American Shit. But you know,
here's the weird thing about her.
It's like I don't necessarily think she
told the truth in that interview and I
don't know how she did away with it when
she said that the Boston Globe did an
investigation.
They said that she didn't it,
she didn't in any way profit off
of that or have an advantage.
She got hired for apart from Harvard and
she wrote native American on a resume.
Like they hired her based on her at this
city. Yeah. Yeah. She's a liar. Yeah.
That's a lie.
Which is fine cause I don't have no
problem with my politicians lying.
They do it all the time.
But I want you to acknowledge your
lie and hold yourself accountable.
Like none of this shit is disqualified.
It's not the eighties anymore.
It's not the 90s where shit like that
ruins you. Just be honest. Like, look,
I'm American. I've cheated
before. I've taken shortcuts.
I fucking used to put the cheat code in
Mike Tyson all the time just to get Mike
Tyson, give everybody else.
That's what we're based on.
So if she did that at some point in her
life, was it a horrible thing to do?
Absolutely. Does it make it a title for
her? Make her a terrible person for ever?
No, I buy what you saying though that
she was told that she was native American
because many people were and then they
find out when they get a DNA test at this
time.
Didn't happen to you,
didn't have to you? Well it hasn't
been disproven yet, but yeah.
What are you native American?
Yeah.
It was like growing up around
the time I was going to college.
My it guy that works with
my dad found out that he,
he like filed the paperwork to,
to his college 10 years after the
fact and got a bunch of money back.
And so my dad's like, well,
we're native American.
That's what we've been told our whole
time. So we're trying to prove it right.
Birth certificates and whatnot.
And it's really hard to,
because they didn't keep a lot
of information back then. Right.
So I put it on an application,
got into Ohio state that way,
caught them and it was real weird when
I was in like the minority, uh, hauling.
There's like on the orientation day,
they was like,
they gave me a letter to
say show, but this, uh, like
you pulled out me and Elizabeth,
you got your photo.
That's exactly what might have, I didn't
take a position from a hardworking,
exactly.
Cherokee kid did it in good faith.
I did. I had no idea. And
it was the first time,
just like when I sit him application
and it was like, what's your race?
I was like,
I just found out I'm native American I
guess so I'm going to put that and no one
checked. No one asked. That's hilarious
that people notice it. Yeah. I,
I didn't know I was doing anything wrong.
The w the wild thing about that is like,
that that conversation was like,
people would ask me why I said that.
I'm like,
I'm just too dumb to know that that wasn't
a question I wasn't supposed to ask.
If you were supposed to ask
that [inaudible] having a
conversation. Yeah, I did.
You're not as ridiculous. That's a huge
thing. We need to find out how she reacts.
The fact that she told a lie cause
the rest of her life is her family.
Did that fuck up the whole lineage.
Ditto.
Family Start Tearing Shit down
off the wall like, oh my God,
we're not native American.
How many dream catchers were in the
garbage that we can talk some saying holy
shit,
just feather sticking out a hefty bags.
Once she learns that the whole family
have to realize that we're not native
American.
I had to fuck up some family reunions
or had to fuck up some tradition too.
Oh my Lord. There's a lot of people who
were shaking their head after that one.
She actually got the DNA test.
Okay.
Can we talk about how fucked up
Ticketmaster is real quick? Yeah.
You went through and talked
about the dealing Maltitol.
I just figured out it just put
my mind to get on this thing.
There's a text he sent me. Oh
my God. Model Ticketmaster.
We're going to take them all down.
Okay, so take a master. You know what?
The place where you buy tickets. I had
no clue about this ticket master thing.
I'm just starting to do some
theaters and shit on the tour.
So I'm starting to look at
like what they charge to do.
Like the processing and
servicing, right? You buy,
it's like a 30 or $40 ticket. I
looked at yours, 40 odd tickets.
$16 in servicing for a service charge.
Yeah.
Is it per ticket? Personal
fucking tickets. We got it.
They got to pay 40% don't they gotta pay
for Shit in a venue? Like no you don't.
That's the venue cost
that you also got to pay.
It's just a process that ticket and if
you want to pick it up and we'll call
another $3 it's unfathomable, right?
So I'm starting to think I'm going,
okay.
So for the first time in my life I'm like,
okay,
I'm selling some tickets and everything's
good and I'm just getting a piece of
the door so I'm happy. Right. And my
boy who's like this genius fucking kid,
Oj Nigerian, all these
Nigerians are geniuses. And
he comes up to me. He's like,
okay, but what about the
processing fee for Ticketmaster?
How much are you getting off of
that? And I go, what is like,
what percentage are you getting off
of that? I go, nothing. He goes, wait,
but you're bringing all the tickets sales.
Why aren't you getting a piece of it's
40% of your ticket price? And I'm like,
well I don't know.
And he goes,
and what about the data from the tickets
being sold? Are you getting that? I go,
no. He goes, hold on. So they're fucking
you and getting paid to fuck you.
I go, what do you mean? He
goes, the game is data. Now,
any businesses successful right now
was all about data acquisition, right?
Any business and data is not how
many followers we have on Instagram.
Because they could take your
account away in a second.
How many subs that you get on Youtube?
Cause they could throttle your search.
We can see that happen all the time.
It's direct connect to fan. Right?
And what Ticketmaster has done
is they're your ticketing site.
They get your email, they get your
data set, they get all your fans,
they know exactly who your fans are.
May email them and tell them when you're
coming into town or when somebody else,
they might like this like you.
Exactly,
and then they're getting paid
an absorbent amount of money.
They're fucking over the fans on it.
So I'm like,
I'm talking to him and he's like,
Yo,
we've got to just create
another one of these.
We've got to create another system
that gives all that data to the comic.
Why is the middle man even there?
We could create a way cheaper ticketing
service that gives every one of those
emails to a comic and it's like comics
used to do back in the days by putting a
comment cards on the tables and
you collect them afterwards.
You can have an email list for every
time you go to Idaho and email lists for
every time you go to New Jersey and email
lists for all these different prices
the most authors do. And Kevin Hart,
Kevin Hart, Kevin Hart came up,
Kevin Hall was going into all of
these comedy clubs and he was getting
everybody's mother fucking email.
And people wonder why whenever Kevin
would launch on these social media sites,
he'd get all of these crazy followers
immediately is because of that road work
you put in in those comedy clubs and
everybody's, you know, before anybody,
I think Louie CK did that as well.
We had this massive email and that you
have direct connection with your fans and
that's what your fans want.
Your fans don't want ticket master telling
them that led Zeppelin's come through.
They want to know enrollments
come through. What do you know?
Pearl jam tried to fight them back
in the day. And what they have,
they have exclusive deals with certain
venues. They are top to bottom, they own,
they own live nation and
live nation owns a venue.
So that complete vertically integrated.
So if you want to plant the garden or
whatever the fuck it is, right? So you go,
we're going to process your tickets.
The only way you do is perform here.
So you do it with our promotion company,
which is alive the nation. And um,
you're going to have to use our
ticket processings fee and our venue,
they actually own the venues now.
But here's the thing,
there's a handful of you guys to
get to play those venues. Now,
I think with podcasts
now shows are 300 people.
There's going to be thousands of comics
that have 300 fans and the venue where
we perform, it's not imperative
that it's this specific one.
It can be a comedy club. It could be a
hall, it could be some conference center.
It could be anything.
It could be Airbnb,
but aren't you only know in Ticketmaster
and when you're doing these big ass
venues, well, sometimes now that
they're nation, they own some certain
clubs. I work with live nation. So now
I make sure all your shit is that up.
Yeah. Really? Yeah.
Why not just do the podcast live
every fucking where different man,
it's not the same.
Yeah.
I like podcasts like this where
it's just people talking you,
you do it differently when
you're playing for an audience.
He's performed for them.
And it becomes this weird days an issue.
It just is not. Um, it's not the
same. It's not a real conversation.
Like I think the intimacy of podcast,
one of the things that people like about
as they listen in their ear, right?
They've got to leave your plug. It's like
you're talking to them. They're like,
you're right there. When you're doing
it live, it becomes a different thing.
There's reaction reactions, a bad
thing, but it's different thing.
But standup is way better way.
It's just way more fun.
I'm saying is what are we doing with
this, right? It's like you should,
you should have a direct
connect to all your fans.
I should have a direct connect to all
my fans. Right? We should be able to,
even the venue should have
that as well. Why? Why do we,
why are we giving away all the data
to a company that's really not,
I know my agent's going to call me right
after. This thing's going to be like,
why the fuck we have to shut the fuck up?
So you want their email,
do you want your audience with emails?
Basically.
And that's what the audience wants and
I don't want my audience to get charged
16 bucks every time they buy a ticket.
Where does that money go?
It costs $16 to process a ticket,
40% of the ticket price.
Why not just create an email
and when you're at these venues,
just put it up on the
jumbotron and be like, Yo,
email me after the email me after
the show. I mean that's, yeah,
that's one more step.
Or we could just create the ticket process
and the charters. I'm way letter left.
Excuse me,
and Andy already starts aggregating the
emails and then if you want to get real
crazy with it, you have a boy of yours
that like let's say my buddy Aakash right.
I do the podcast with. It's like, Hey, I
caught you. You were about to go on tour.
Yeah,
why don't you just use my dataset man.
They're going to know you from doing
the podcast with me. Maybe you can,
they'll want to see you.
It's like we get to empower
each other through that shit.
Am I making sense or no?
It makes sense to think
specifically about data,
about the email list and about they get
that if you show up in these different
places, they get the email address because
that's how people get their tickets.
But you get that, that you get the option
of saying like, cause they'll ask you,
they'll say,
can Ticketmaster reply to you all?
Can ticket master's send you the
latest updates and news and events?
You can click no. Yeah and I could
go all the time. Let's take a master.
But you would click yes.
If it was us and there was somebody who
are invested in going to see you just
don't want to take a master
promoting random events.
Depends what you're sending me.
You click no Ticketmaster's still gets
your email address and might sell it.
Absolutely.
Yeah.
Even if you just click no like you do
you want updates from Ticketmaster.
You're not saying is it okay if this
company just starts selling my email
address because that's what
they do. That's what they
do. Yeah. Rodi own us anyway,
but they don't have to.
I'm saying now,
like everybody that's coming out to your
shows is coming out from this podcast.
They're not coming up cause
the Ticketmaster and if
you use a different email
service or ticketing service,
they would come out with that one.
There was a Sam Harris' podcast
where he talked about this,
where they had on this expert and
they were discussing how data is. It's
like a commodity that no
one knew was a commodity.
And we signed off on it
before we realized it.
And these people that don't provide any
service or getting that data and it's
worth billions and billions of dollars,
which is essentially what Facebook is.
It's Facebook,
but it's also shaping the
way we communicate with each
other because the things
that attract people there are conflict,
right?
So things that get you to
engage our conflict, right?
So that's the stuff that shows up
in your email or your Facebook feed.
They find out what's going to know you.
Yep.
And that's the shit that they show people.
Click on Oj has 800,000 followers
in two fucking date overnight,
instantly on Twitter, which nobody
grows on Twitter anymore. No,
but at least we're trying at least
Twitter. At least. At least Facebook,
they're not charging. Right. My
issue, if Ticketmaster was like, hey,
here's a free service, we just want to get
your data. I bet. All right, boom. Cool.
If Facebook is,
you want to charge me,
you gonna fuck me in my ass and make me
pay you. I think Facebook gets you all.
Did they just not charted ads? Yeah,
and also like think about it there.
They've stolen a lot of that data
from people. Yeah, a lot of ways.
So that is a charge because you signed
up with something but you didn't know you
were signing up for that. I didn't
know I was giving you all it is. Right.
What's weird
to me,
man is fucking,
when you're talking about something and
then those ads show up in your Google
feed, Bro, we were just
talking about coolers, Bro.
And I looked at my Google newsfeed
and there's ads for coolers. I'm like,
how does my phone, no, I was talking about
cool. That's why I say date long
as you know. What else is crazy.
When you get in your car and you look
down at your phone and it says 32 minutes
to where ever the fuck you're going.
That shit happens to me all the time.
Knows what you're going to go and
that was where you look at your phone.
It'll be like 32 minutes to whatever gym.
I go to a now, I used to tell me
40 minutes to work in the morning.
Now it says 40 minutes to Starbucks Brown.
I'm like,
I drink Starbucks every morning and
there's a Starbucks by my job in the
building,
but that's the way it tells me I'm going.
I'm going every morning I watch
one video of Robbie Williams,
you know that like English singer.
It was a youtube video with him
and Tyson fury. I just clicked.
It was two minutes long. Every other ad
on Instagram is Robbie Williams life,
so it's not good. The targeting
isn't perfect. I'm not
going to buy those tickets,
but my point is it's scary.
One Youtube video and then a
completely different platform. Yeah,
and this is all within the last decade.
They figured out how to do this. Yeah.
Even if we unplug was still plugged in.
If we were all to delete everything
that we have on social media. Right.
And I ain't got us already,
Bro.
That's why I don't like all that snapchat
shit with their face filters and all
that. And you can see what they
did to him. What'd they do to you?
What they're doing, the
shit where they are. Yeah. I
think this was nuts.
He made a,
a complete deep fake with they take,
they basically took all the recordings
of me talking and it's made me say words
that I've never said before and I was,
it talked about me sponsoring a hockey
team made of entirely of chimpanzees and
a bunch of other crazy shit that I
might actually say, but it said it.
I've never said those things.
Okay.
So they use my voice with
artificial intelligence.
They've all the sounds that my mouth
winks and they use it with all the right
inflections and they create the sentences
and the Pharaoh is out of a job.
They just passed the legislation
about that, about deep faith,
congresswoman from Brooklyn,
I can't remember her name,
she just passed the
legislation about defects.
They also did video of the Mona Lisa
talking, bro. They got the Mona Lisa.
They took the painting of the Monalisa
and start and now she's like opening her
mouth and saying things they
can do with Abraham Lincoln.
And how can you believe anything
you hear on social media anymore?
It's going to be in a few years.
You're not going to be able to.
No Man. You don't know
what's true, what's not true,
and nobody cares about the truth and
the life more in a table that's better.
Maybe now we could say fucked up shit
like, Bro, what are you talking about?
Definitely deep. Thanks. Well it's,
you're already getting
porn with actresses.
They're taking actresses face and putting
them on porn stars and you can't tell,
whoa, wait a, yeah. Oh, you
could fuck everyone. Yeah.
And now they're going to be able
to do that with virtual reality.
So you're going an ar porn. Yeah,
they have that. Yeah. Vr Porn.
And they put something on your Dick so it
feels like, yeah, they could put a logo,
one of them little things
that jerks you off.
Eh?
[inaudible] got the same,
it's not the same old school.
You like your Paul just started fucking
listen to the audible books too because
I'm old school.
I like flipping the page and get a book.
I just started listening to audible only
because of time purposes and it's like,
it's like listening to the long form
podcast. I'm like, you know what? Fuck it.
I'm still getting the information
and I feel like at this age I retain
information more by hearing it.
Right.
So I'm not bought that gold start
fucking virtual reality pussy.
Here's the shit that's not porn.
But it could be interesting.
Have you seen the one about the
basketball games? What? Okay,
so they put a few cameras so you
can sit front row. But in Vr, Ooh,
I don't think I would mind that.
That's the best you're looking around.
You're seeing all the people that are
actually there and your front row at the
game. Oh, last month I went to,
um, I could use the bathroom
cause I went to Disney,
I went to Disney and I went
to that fucking, that Avatar,
avatar flights of passage.
Right, right. It's Weiss. Yeah,
me too. That shit was incredible.
And you know, I got anxiety, right.
So I'm on it and I'm like,
Holy Shit.
Until you just remember I'm not even
moving. Right. And then it's just like,
it settles everything for you and then
you can just enjoy the actual experience.
And that helped me.
I was telling my therapist about it,
cause that helps me when I, when I'm
dealing with my anxiety because it's like,
you know,
breathing exercises,
things that get you back to center even
though you're falling and you can feel
to the dragon breathing on you.
It's just like when you realize
you're really not moving,
it just brings you right back to center,
then you're okay, then you're fine.
You can't do that on a rollercoaster.
No, really, yes, it's real.
But if they have a roller
coaster with virtual reality,
like if you're wearing virtual reality
goggles and they put you on a roller
coaster.
Yeah, but I can enjoy, I can
enjoy the, what do you mean?
Like they put these goggles on and then
while you're on this roller coaster,
you're experiencing things
that aren't really there,
but you're explaining like you,
you like going through
wormholes and you're traveling,
you're seeing things happening and I'm
a heart attack. Have a panic attack.
That's not,
that's not something I want to experience.
I'm glad you talk about anxiety.
I'm glad you're talking about the way you
do because I think you've opened it up
for a lot of people.
I think [inaudible] get,
you've made it a subject
that's okay to talk about.
For someone like you who
would like a cool guy.
It was a smart dude who is successful
and talks openly about anxiety and about
how it's affected you.
That's, I think that's a,
you're doing a very big service for that.
I didn't even know what the anxiety was
until 2010 because growing up in the
environment that I grew up in, I just
thought all those feelings were normal.
I thought all those feelings
of paranoia or you know,
being anxious all the time like you know,
and I used to smoke weed so you know
when you smoke weed and you have a panic
attack, you just blame
it on the weed. Know.
I remember driving the Burger King
one time with two of my home boys.
One of them is dead now.
His name is Darell rest in peace.
My Man Zeke and I was high as hell and
my steering wheel needed like steering
fluid.
So it was shaking so it was shaking my
legs and I'm bugging out just driving the
burger king, a two mile ride. I'm
like, Yo, one of y'all got to drive.
We're all gonna die right now.
Take the wheel right now.
I'm going to crash this motherfucker.
Call them tripping the fuck out.
And they looking at me like, Yo, don't
let this motherfuckers smoke no more.
But I had nothing to do with the weed.
It was, we'd probably accentuate. It.
Definitely did. Because
when I, after, you know,
when I found out what anxiety was in
2010 and I didn't start going to get,
you know, going to therapy until like two
years ago, because back in 2010 when I,
when I got diagnosed with my
first panic attack that somebody,
the doctor was saying,
Hey,
this is a panic attack because I had just
gotten fired from radio for the fourth
motherfucking time and I was back at
home living with my mom and like 31 years
old with a two year old daughter and you
know, collecting unemployment checks.
So when I'm having this panic attack and
I go to the doctor and he's like, Yo,
your heart is fine. You've got a
perfectly fine hardening, you're healthy,
you got an athlete's heart. He was like,
Yo, are you stressed about anything?
I'm like, fuck yeah. You know,
so in my mind, all I gotta
do is get me another job,
get back in position and
everything will be okay.
But when you get back in position and
you know you've made more money than
you've ever made in your life,
and you've got books that are selling
in TV shows and all of this other shit,
you still having no same panic
attacks. She's like, well,
what the fuck is going on? I'm sure
that's it. That's exactly what it is.
You think you're going to lose everything.
It's also you experienced
pressure that uh,
most people never experience because
you experienced pressure at this,
this public scale.
It's not just pressure,
it's pressure with people's eyes on you
and expectations and criticisms and all
these different things that the average
person is not gonna experience that from
millions of people. And you do.
And it's just like it's always on.
And if you're one of those crazy
fucks that reads comments, good
Lord have mercy. God love. That
was my problem with you. At first.
I used to enjoy it because I was the guy
who came up on Youtube looking at all
these worlds thought hip hop conspiracy
theories about people and you'd be like,
oh my God, it's motherfuck
sacrifices hamsters. And
that's how he got successful.
You know what I'm saying?
I know you take all that shit is cool
until you get old and then you start
seeing things about you and you laugh
at it at first until you realize like I
not even really starting
to say some wild shit.
What was the craziest one that you
heard about you? I mean for me,
you know what it is when they tried to
meet to, to fuck over the last year,
try to get him Outta here. You know
that that was, that was the most,
that was the wildest one to me
cause I was always the person,
I say live your truth so nobody
can use your truth against you.
So it's not like they bought up anything
that I hadn't spoken about numerous
times before or written about in my books.
They just decide to attack, oh my God,
targets. Oh man, it can happen. It can it.
So that for me, that was like,
I, this is going too far,
but it then it's like you really
can't do anything about it.
That's the other thing. Like there's
no, there's no way to fight it.
Once the toothpaste is out of the tube,
there's no way to put the
toothpaste back in the tube.
So the only thing you could do is just
either let it consume you and, and, and,
and probably ruin you just
because you took it all in. Oh,
you just keep it to fuck moving like you,
you how you have to be confident enough
to know what's the truth and what's not
the truth.
And so now you don't read
any comments anymore.
I don't go on Twitter at all. What
is too toxic? That shit like yeah,
we were in verbally abusive relationships
with our fucking smart phones.
Yeah, I agree. Yeah, it's not, it's
definitely not healthy. You know,
we were talking about it yesterday,
me and Duncan Trussell,
we were saying that it's like your diet,
like your diet,
if you take in junk food all the time,
eat a bunch of shitty things that are
unhealthy. It's not good for your body.
What your mental diet,
it's important to.
And if you're always taking in
these toxic arguments and yeah,
I mean half a Twitter is just people
screaming at each other and just yelling
and insulting each other and trying to
find ways in this person's being shitty
or wrong or negative and it's
like that's not real life.
The real life that we experienced that
were designed experiences like this,
people interacting with
each other reasonably.
It's one of the reasons why I
think people like podcasts so much,
especially good podcasts where people
have real conversations is because you go,
oh, okay, this is, this is, this
is v resonates with me. Yeah.
Whereas Twitter does
not resonate with you.
Twitter just gets you anxious and gets
you upset and conversations where people
actually being nice to each
other in person. Look, I
don't do podcast over Skype.
I don't like it. I don't. I want to see
you. I want you to be in the room with it.
I want everyone to know we're going
to be okay. You know when you,
when you have these conversations
and people listen to them,
like just one on one like
this or two on one to this,
this kind of what we're doing now.
This makes sense to people.
That's one of the reasons when I,
when I'm out and about and you know,
like if I'm at the airport and somebody
comes up to me and talks to me,
I speak to them.
Yeah.
Because I feel like that interaction
was supposed to happen. Right? Yes.
You know what I mean?
Normal Twitter, Instagram,
I ain't supposed to be talking
to you on this shit. Yeah.
With a Vegan you are not supposed to be
human beings are not wired to be that
wired. No. Everybody should not have
that kind of access to, you know,
so it's just like we got us,
we've got to take back to them that see
the facade fall apart when you respond
to one of their tweets,
like someone would be like fuck you,
Charlemagne you a shit and then
you can be like, why in the bag?
I'm just playing bro. I'm a fan. I
didn't really know what to say though,
is that they're just trying to get a read.
They just, one reaction I, in my mind,
if people, if you like
somebody, right, you see him,
you're going to go up to
them and speak to them.
I just try to gauge things on how
I would do it. Right. For example,
I was on a plane with Steve Nash this
morning. Okay. Steve Nash. I'm like, why?
He's like, Oh shit, where's my boy?
He's like, Oh shit. That's Steve Nash.
And I'm like, Oh shit. That
Steve. I didn't speak to
Steve. Did you say hello? No.
Nothing. No. Okay. I didn't feel, I
didn't feel it. Even I respect them. No,
he's a great player and
I feel John Stockton,
that's a little like [inaudible]
have to say hi to say what?
There's some people you have to say hi
to Rachel Dolezal [inaudible] Seattle.
Absolutely. Where was she? Was I started
with a, I think she had at least one kid.
Maybe another one. She was just at
the airport. Where? Online? No Tsa.
Precheck sexual. Now she's bought. Yes.
She bisexual biracial shoes. Oh, no shit.
Not biracial.
Transracial she is black.
She's got both transracial I know,
but what I'm saying is she's bye.
So she's straight and gay with the
thing, but I said hello. Said what's up?
Amazing forehead. One of the best
port has you'll ever see in a game.
I want to ignore her.
That's what I would have known her.
You want to got the Selfie?
No,
I saw Jessie Smollett took a picture of,
oh my goodness.
In Lafayette Bakery. What do you think's
going to happen with him? Nothing.
Nothing. It's amazing. Nothing
legally. It's amazing legal.
I think Chicago was coming after him.
Now you think so now didn't they say
that they were going to get them for the
money? For the money that they spent?
There's no such thing as cancer coaching.
No more cancer coach was absolute
bullshit. Ooh. O J Simpson proved that.
Ooh. You know what I'm saying? Like,
Hey, when bill Cobb, he comes home,
he'll be on the road doing motherfucking
standup or Kelly's still out here
selling shows like Charlie
Sheen is still out here.
Flourishing like it's
really sheen duct it all.
Wait a minute.
Not all he did get.
That ain't [inaudible]
blue man.
And what is HIV?
Some say the greatest endorsement deal.
Magic Johnson ever sign.
I'm saying we're not going to act
like his career and it looks great.
Take this age. You're going to get some
movie theater though. I was in my head
car the day they announced on the radio
that Magic Johnson had HIV and I was
shitting my pants. I was like, oh my God,
this is like the beginning of a Zombie
movie. We're all going to get it.
If Magic Johnson with all his money
and all his fame, if he's got it,
I'm going to get it. We're all
gonna get it. I was terrified.
I remember in my car driving
and then hear it on the radio.
Holy Shit. Holy. This is insane.
30 years later he looks great.
He looks amazing. It's great.
He's on TV telling us why he
left the motherfucking Lakers.
The Lakers not once did somebody say Yo,
you know magic got HIV.
This is how you shut it. Let you did
that. That's all I was thinking about.
Every time he, cause he looks incredible.
He does look incredible. Incredible. Yeah.
It's not even positive and tests anymore.
Wait, what? Yeah, I heard that. Yeah.
If you give them a test for HIV comes
up negative because apparently these
protease inhibitors and all these
different things that they take to to the
different medications, you don't even
test positive for HIV anymore. By the way,
Dan, listen, it was just,
it was this older white dude and I
forgot what TV show I was on the set up,
but he was explaining to me the whole
situation with magic and he was like the
reason that they chose magic with,
because they want it to
erase a lot of these stigmas.
People thought that HIV and AIDS was
a gay disease and he needed like a,
an Alpha male.
I guess to have it,
to kind of erase that stigma and to let
people know that you can live with it
like HIV. They gave it to him.
Well this is what he told her
nuts by the way,
is it [inaudible] I'm telling
you what somebody told me.
They said to me was magic had got
caught up in some type of scandal and
[inaudible] right? Yeah. And we'll
put in before the scandal came out,
just because the person that he was with
was like some allegedly some big wigs
child or something like that.
And so this,
they said this is what you're
going to do so we don't ruin you.
I'm just now on this show before you
take this in, he believes in Sasquatch.
[inaudible] believe Sasquatch was real.
That just started right now on this
podcast. If I asked him yesterday,
he did 100% there. I'm not saying
I believe that magic theory,
I'm just repeating what I was told that
that is a common rumor that's out there.
I've heard that. I've heard that rumor.
It's guy, he doesn't actually have it.
But then it was either that or,
but we just got done saying how you read
rumors about you that are ridiculous
and go, what the fuck? And then you
realize, oh this is what happens.
People just make shit up.
And then people repeat the shit that
people make up cause he can't fathom that
he beat aids. Bro Aids was bodying people
back in the day like shooting mercury.
Freddie gone? Yeah. Who
else? He's he. He's he,
he my downstairs neighbor.
Downstairs neighbor? No, no.
I had it downstairs neighbor who had aids.
[inaudible] I learned
about it really young.
That's
definitely Andrew with his thirties
I'm like either he was just out
looking at him. Yo Book Charlie Sheen
for 350 bucks. Book them where I came.
Yeah.
Oh on cameo,
cameo sunglasses on like what is
happening here? What is, what is he doing?
Yeah, it is strange stuff. Just
showing you what is that too?
He aged very quickly.
It's like,
see he seemed to be fine when he was
doing two and a half men when he stopped
doing that show. He aged like a
hundred years old. He had HIV.
We don't know how it's affecting her
too. I forgot. I forgot. Everybody has,
everybody's not magic Johnson here.
Okay. Come. Same Magic. That's why
that,
by the way,
that is why I say magic is like the
greatest NBA player of all time.
Why? Because of that, he
played 13 seasons in the NBA,
went to nine NBA finals, won
five of them. One in college,
came in one his rookie year and went
one on one with HIV and fucking one
destroyed. He destroyed the
stigma of HIV. Definitely did.
Anybody that catches HIV right now,
the first thing you're going to say
to yourself is give me a magic style.
I can live through anything of magic.
Made it real time.
You know what I'm saying?
30 years later he's okay.
What did the death sentence anymore
and by the way, what's worse?
Herpes all over your Dick for life.
Not that it comes back and forth,
but it's always there. The open
blisters forever, forever or having HIV,
definitely the herpes,
it's worse because the HIV,
they could basically cure it
pees on your dick forever.
Meaning those boosters don't go away.
You can't even fuck, it'll hurt. No,
let's just go away.
Nobody's saying that you get it do today.
Yeah. Breaks. He said,
I'm saying this specific type of like
real hardcore herpes, they never go away.
They're just always, they have one
that doesn't go away hypothetically,
which is herpes.
You ever see the Damon Wayans bit about
magic when magic came back to the MBA?
No, no. Nobody wanted to block
him, but second Dennis Rodman,
Dennis Rodman was like,
fuck y'all.
Spit in your mouth and
accelerate your symptoms.
[inaudible] enough credit.
David's a goat man.
He's one of the greatest of all times.
I don't give them enough credit.
We had to actually delete a Damon Wayans
joke from the breakfast club. Well,
because it used to play like, you
know, you have stuff that plays,
has the loop and he had to delete it.
Wants to meet two times up. Eric Cain,
can you say it? I mean, I'll say dammit.
Damon Wayans Damon Wayans.
It was on the breakfast club and he was
talking about the bill copy situation.
He just goes, Yo man, have you seen
the women that are accusing bill Cosby?
They're all on [inaudible]
Damon Wayans that day I was like, you
know what I mean? For the authentic.
Always have. She doesn't
give a fuck man, but we do.
So that's why we took this shit.
Taking the heat for somebody else's words.
Dennis Rodman's said,
I'll spit in your mouth and
accelerate your symptoms,
bro. I think about when call him
alone. Think about calling alone.
Everybody right now call Malone
would get so much flack for this,
but in the 90s what he said made sense.
Oh, none of us really knew what HIV aids.
What? Do you remember what he
said? Oh, about? I was like,
I'm not playing basketball with him.
Like what if I hit him and he starts
bleeding and he gives me like, but that
was what a lot of people were thinking.
Sure.
How could you be mad at him
for not knowing? For being
ignorant about mosquitoes?
Remember that? Yes, I do. What about
mosquito? That's, I mean, yeah,
that's reasonable though, right? I think
what works with Ebola and other shit,
they can give you birthday
or some shit or malaria.
Why can't they give you some HIV? We used
to be. We used to be, as somebody said,
you can't get it in your mouth.
I thought this was propaganda,
but like you can't get it in your mouth
when someone comes in your mouth. Yeah,
you can't get it back and tell you that.
Free tickets to the movie theater for
life. What are you talking to that show?
If you got HIV aids, like
look, you can't get it.
You can't just come in your mouth.
It's calling your mouth. Don't worry
bro. Oh my God. Did you just put it up?
All the mosquitoes are carriers
or yellow fever, dengue fever,
Japanese encephalitis and
sinful itis encephalitis.
There's no evidence of
mosquitoes can transmit HIV.
Studies with HIV have shown clearly
the virus disappears the mosquito after
about one to two days. But what if that
shit bites you and invites you right bro?
Look at that last line.
I've never heard it described like that.
The time required for them to
scuttle the digest, the blood meal.
Oh Jesus Christ. You don't even talk about
vampires is like that. The blood meal.
So that means if they get someone who's
got HIV and then they get to you within
one to two days, doesn't that
seem like it would get you bro?
That's all I'm saying. It's,
it's a reasonable thing to ask.
These are reasonable things to do.
I have to worry about shit like that.
I'm married. Well, the real
fear is pandemic diseases.
I'm out the gate. Yeah, yeah,
yeah, but that's his fucking, we're
talking about. You're on the beach and,
and some dude with Charlie Sheen's next
to you spitting in your mouth. Yeah.
Just from Tiger Blood
Hashtag Tiger Blood Hashtag
oh Charlie had a moment.
You had a moment. Moment.
HIV cases moment count was the thing.
The only thing we could have handled
similar thing like [inaudible] the hell
there. That winning shit don't sound
too, I don't believe you ready Bro.
Yeah,
he was wild.
Do you know why don't match the
difference between magic and Charlie?
I don't think Charlie was ever recruited
anybody because people,
yeah, like we wanted,
we wanted to be magic at
some point in our lives.
Everybody wanted to be Magic Johnson,
his live show showing stand up in
2011 was when he was on that thing.
But that's crazy.
What fixed that those Russell Peters
fixed that Russell Peters fixed it because
he went with him.
So what happened was Charlie was trying
to do it by himself and really didn't
have anything to say.
And people get bored after a while.
They would boo him and like he was
like, Oh fuck you, I have your money.
And he's like a bunch of dumb shit cause
he tried to do this live tour but he
didn't plan it out. So then we did as
you brought Russell Peters with them.
So Russell, who's the best
at work in the craft, right?
He could just make something
out of nothing. Right.
So Russell got Tim to talk
and then Russell would start
talking shit and making
fun and someone would say southern
Russell incorporate that and Russell are
treated like a comedy show and turned it
into something that was actually good.
I have a bunch of people go see him live.
He should Russell's there.
So it's going to be good
cause Russell's though, right?
Russell's going to handle
it and turn it into funny.
So I want you to just do the
podcast. Yeah, yeah. Hi Cass.
Back then nobody cared about podcast
early. Have some stories though, Dude.
Oh yeah, those cracked stories and the
workers if you willing to tell him though.
Oh he's telling he was all that
had already got aids. What's worst?
Do you remember when he was on television?
He was talking about just smoking rocks
and just all this and the people are
like, what? Like what you're saying,
but did that excite people in 2019
like we've seen all the crackheads? No.
Back then it was the right window of time
and it was like him coming through and
just being unapologetic about doing drugs
and you don't pay hookers to fuck you.
You pay him to leave if you're kind
of shit that he was saying it was
unapologetic and that's why it resonated.
And that's also why no one could get
him with like a me too thing. It's like,
what are you going to say? Of course he,
he'll tell you what he did. First of all,
no woman is going to say they slept
with [inaudible] for sure. Yeah.
Maybe he did that too.
Oh,
[inaudible] you about to catch that?
Me Too. You just got, I got heat and
those girls get quite here real quick.
Holy Shit. That's what you
found a way around the system.
Oh, my show. What did, that's
what Leo says. Every time a
girl leaves the house. Oh,
by the way,
positive. Oh my Jesus. Really
nice to them. They like them.
They don't want to fucking throw him
under the bus. So some guys are like,
the Leo would like that. Drake, I don't
know about Drake. Derek Jeter. Oh,
Derek Jeter was given a gift bags,
baby. You know what I'm saying?
Can you imagine the number that came out?
He was getting signed baseballs. Yeah.
Think about how many guys have gotten a
signed baseball from their girlfriend as
a gift.
Think about what was going through
their head when they read the post that
moment. And there's this sign, Derek Jeter
baseball one. They're fucking Nantel.
Oh Dude.
Yeah.
And your girls like no other girls
might have, but he was just nice to me.
He's a gentleman, but what you've
got to earn that gift back, Joe. Joe,
Joe saying is very true though.
That's why I always like when I see dudes
still treating women like shit in 2019
like, yeah, fucking them and kicking
them out the room. Oh my God. No,
I'm not answering the phone for
after, but I'm like, you're wiling.
You should be treating her with the
utmost respect and being extremely nice
because you just never know. Uber, Uber,
she's your friend. She's your friend.
She, she should be. She
should be your friend.
Like I don't understand why guys,
like I said at the time said,
why are y'all still calling women bitches?
Some of them are bitches bitches
out like it in a positive way.
Like check this bad bitch
out. Yes, that's okay.
But some of them are just
old school bits of stuff.
There's some bitches where it's
like you're in a derogatory way.
Like you could say it in a positive way.
You're laughing about it or you could
say it in a derogatory way. Yeah.
Sometimes I'll say it in a derogatory way
as a man. Cause I mean it because man,
it's 2019 no. What about Twat?
I've never used that ever.
What about content now?
I've never used car.
He got in trouble for using the word cunt.
I didn't trouble me in trouble.
You get, but you got
outraged. He's, yeah, he's,
he's not a match. I want to
ask you this, first of all,
I think what you're doing with
youtube is genius. It's brilliant.
You're the first comic to
really capitalize on using
you to, you know, Netflix.
They want to give you a special like,
fuck, I don't need you. Let me do this.
It'll get more views. And it
has, and it's been amazing.
It's been beautiful to watch.
But are you experienced because
of the popularity increased?
Are you experiencing some push back on
some of your material because you go hard
bro? The weirdest thing? No, it's like
we've curated an expectation for it.
Mm. So the people that are
going there are waiting for it.
It's not people who like got free
tickets from the funny bones website. No.
What you do, they're there for
things that they didn't watch.
You talk about eating ass either ass.
Yeah, I was just talking about this on,
on a pod on the part of the other day,
but like we were just
talking about privilege.
You have to be to eat at no serious
sign because think about all these third
world countries where they can't even
eat food, but we're so full in America.
Look, you can't have a fucking
cocktail or without almost dying.
You think they're eating ass in America.
We're so full.
We got so many choices that we choose
to eat ass we want to do for fun.
But Bro, I'm telling you they're
not. It's pretty, pretty amazing.
They're all leaning into it and I think
that people have had enough with the PC
shit. So they really like to see
the fact that this is out there.
And I mean we're posting, you know, I'll
tell you one thing, the Joe Rogan effect,
we used to do a million views a week
on my youtube channel. I came on here,
2 million now.
Wow. Wow. Doubled. That's crazy. We'll
see what happens now. I mean, we'll see.
I mean it was nuts. Charlemagne effect
in there. Well we do a pocket. I mean,
but the channel exists because of the
Charlotte made effect by Shayle exists
because we were putting the
brilliant idiots, fat videos,
idiots videos out every week on
the channel. Like without him,
that channel doesn't exist.
I mean like you two guys,
I swear to God,
I have the biggest influence on the
market and it's like he gave me this
opportunity to have all these people
view and I was able to put the stuff out
and luckily they liked it.
But the same thing happened here.
We just doubled up again.
I mean
it's crazy that it's all dependent
upon generosity and being a fan.
Cause that's what I do. I mean, when I'm
talking to a scientist or talking to you,
yeah, I'm a fan, I'm
interested. I'm curious.
And it's not like you're putting
on some fuck shit. Right. You know,
say like Andrew's funny, he's
been funny. Exactly. Years.
So now everybody else is actually
realizing what we all knew already. Yeah.
And the limitations of like
those platforms putting
you on like Netflix or HBO
or something like that, that
doesn't exist anymore. It's not you
in your whole game and
you know that you go,
you go get no systems and they teach
you I just to shoot three pointers. Yup.
You know what I'm saying?
Instead of like fucking
cultivating your your whole game.
That's why, you know, really
needed, I love rainy days.
I try not to promote brewing needs.
I know this sounds crazy, right?
This is interesting. And the reason
I do it because I love our audience.
I love that group of people who
come to listen to us every week.
They know that we just out here saying
some wild shit, not even on purpose,
just because we're,
we're,
we're trying to get ideas out and
we're just talking through things.
It's when you bring those outsiders in,
who here you don't know
any context than nothing.
Take that little piece out of context.
Give it to the rest of the world.
Now the rest of the world is outraged.
We can ask God to come over here any
fucking way. Right. You know what?
We want to be wild.
We want to place
is where do you think that's going?
Like what is outrage?
Culture reached full outrage.
It's coming back. We turned it
around. I agree. [inaudible] around.
You know what's made me think about that?
Two situations in the past two weeks,
I can't remember the first one,
but the whoopie Goldberg one
from yesterday with Bella
Thorne. I didn't hear it.
Bella Thorne, uh, she took
some nude pictures. Somebody
was going to expose him.
So she just shared them herself first.
I think somebody hacked her out.
Acthar clouds cloud.
They're trying to say, hey,
we're going to put this out unless you
give us money or some shit. She's like,
fuck it. I'm gonna put my own shit
on Twitter. Yeah. So Whoopi Goldberg,
it's on the frame of juggernauts.
I didn't even see it. Lovely.
We'll be getting on the
view at whip. He goes, look,
it's 2019 when you take pictures,
they go up to the cloud.
Hackers can hack you, so don't
take pictures. She was like,
it's just common sense like it's not,
it's not worth it.
Just don't take the pictures. Hey.
I was like, oh, your victim shaming,
but I thought that I thought that
was what the outrage was going to be.
It wasn't. They was like, Oh shit, we'll
be, you're talking to super common sense.
Now. Bella came out and said
she was being victim shame,
but the general public
on social media was like,
so y'all are mad at whipped before talking
common sense and I was like, Oh shit.
You can't say it's victim shaming if she's
correct because we are moving into an
era where all information is going
to be available to everybody.
I think that's going to be a thing
that we're going to have to overcome.
The privacy is going out the window,
John. It's not going to exist anymore.
Like what?
Our expectations of privacy are so much
different than people that lived in our
parents' age. Well, our kids,
it's going to be even less and
then their kids nonexistent.
They didn't even know FDR was crippled.
That's right. FDL was crippled. Yeah.
See?
Yeah.
They didn't know. He would literally
hold himself up at the podium.
I think he got polio or some shit.
Right. So he was a paraplegic. Right.
And but the press respected his role as
president and they respected his privacy.
I mean he had side bitches,
he had all this shit going on and he
would just stand up at the podium holding
himself up. Whenever you're talking
to everything else besides that,
they kind of roll them around with the
people didn't know because there wasn't
this access. Oh I want us to get
back in line to each other all day.
Talk to me cause I cause think about it,
it used to be a time where you didn't
know what somebody's religion was.
You didn't know what somebody's political
views were like you didn't like,
nobody knew. Like you just went, you
presented and you went the fuck home.
I think we need to get back to that.
Well I think it's too much
motherfucking.
So every call trooper get back in the
closet and not just with your gay should
just whatever the bullshit meter everybody
to just get back to bullshit and each
other. Cause. Guess what?
Remember I used to say you don't want
the truth because you can't handle the
truth that this era,
the world cannot handle the truth.
That's why you wanna tell us about Ufos.
What,
what do you think is happening with you?
Fos they won't tell us that you FO's
exists because if they told us that you
oppose exists,
motherfuckers would probably go crazy
when the reality is we really probably
need to know you. Fo's it just cause it
would humble the fuck out of everyone.
Well that's the only time we get a
roar, right? Like in every movie, right?
The only time Russia and China and America
get on a conference call is when they
had the movies.
Aliens are coming up the movies.
Ronald Reagan said that in his speech in
the eighties Ronald Reagan told him to
Kel Gorbachev, why the fuck are we
beefin cause one day we might be,
we might have an extra terrestrial threat
and then we got to come together and
everybody was like, what
the fuck is Ronald Reagan
talking about? Click quickly.
We would put aside our differences.
We were three phase faced within a threat
from an alien world and everybody was
like, what does he know?
Oh, I would respect
no tonight show.
We go find out 10 nights.
By the way,
I would respect you have prejudice.
If aliens came and you still had held
onto whatever the fuck you [inaudible] was
still racist, you will still
homophobic, transphobic,
got the aliens came. I'd be like, shit,
that's not a girl. That's a fucking dude
in a dress. Can't get pregnant. Hold on.
[inaudible] oh my God, I respect
the fuck out of there. I'd be like,
okay, I'll tell you no. It's
true though. You know it's real.
As long as it's real. I really
don't have no choice but to respect
Joe, I think you're right. I think we're
getting to the end of outrage culture.
I think she was almost over. We had,
we put on a clip this last week,
there was this kid in the front row
in a wheelchair heckling me, saw that.
That was hilarious and we went back and
forth and initially I put it out like,
oh fuck. What's going to happen? Am
I going to have these like, you know,
people rolling up to my shows and
like fucking pussies that really,
well he was also a special kid. He had
something, you know people have it,
you are river around people and
they just have a fucking, like,
they have a cold like you know
who has it? Ari, Ari, Ari Shaffir.
He has this fucking, I don't know,
there's something I just want him around.
I just like them. I just kind of want
him to tell me his opinions on shit.
I was ask him Janklow Talker,
but he's just, he's like,
do you feel about carpets?
And he'll just fucking tell you. They'll
be like, eh, whatever. So it was like,
he just had this thing needs such positive
energy and I'm making fun of the guy
from fucking being in a wheelchair and
he's making fun of me for having a shitty
up body. And like literally I go to
him, I was like, I said, you don't,
are you upper body is pretty good.
And he goes, what's your excuse?
Like cool.
And we have this moment and no
backlash. There's a thing. It was cool.
Backlash shouldn't matter except for
the guy in the wheelchair, right.
If everybody else is like, oh, why
the fuck are you picking on him?
If the guy in the wheelchair don't care
and the guy in the wheelchair is going
back and forth, why the fuck are you
jumping in ever? People that have it,
never always.
Parents of people have things
like when there was this person had
a seizure in, in one of my videos,
everybody who had
seizures was cool with it.
It was always a parent of a kid
who had a seizure, who was like,
my son suffers from, how dare
you? What a clip up like that.
So it's always a fence on behalf of cause
I really think that people who suffer
for things,
they've went through way harder things
in a joke and they actually like that
they're being spoken to as a
regular person in the audience,
not babies like every other part of their
life. When can I get the door for you?
Can I get, it's like they all
right for the first time I'm in it.
I don't, I don't, I don't, I don't
pose, I won't post or like make jokes.
I talk shit about something
that I wouldn't want to
happen to me or somebody I
loved though. Right. You know what
I'm saying? Like I can handle,
you know what I'm saying?
Like HIV aids.
I don't want it
[inaudible] I wouldn't trip
if I got it. I wouldn't trip to orders.
I mean not what we used to think it was.
So it's a different thing. Yeah. Do
you know what bug catchers are? Yeah.
What's a book around fucking
people who have those?
Did he try to get it? Yeah. There's
a bunch of guys in the gay community.
We're trying to get HR. Yeah.
That's fun catching crow. Hold on.
Self low.
The people that wanted to get HIV,
and this is back in the day
where it was a death sentence,
there was a lot of guys who were doing
that hold on. Their goal. Their goal.
Yeah.
They would try,
they would put out ads on craigslist
looking for HIV positive guys to give me
the bug.
This is why colts happened because people
need to be part of something there.
It's like in them,
some people are just broken.
Exactly. Cause I heard about that 20
years ago and I thought that was crazy.
But now that I'm thinking about it,
I'm like, what was their life like?
I need to know what their life is
like if they had something to lose,
if they was actually successful,
would they be doing that?
I need to know what kind of people were
out there trying to catch dis book.
This every,
every step in the spectrum
of crazy you think about it.
And there's a whole fucking category
of people that are doing that.
So bug catching was one of them.
Like it was a big thing where guys were
like actively going out and trying and
guys who had HIV,
we're trying to go give it to people.
Yeah. That's why, uh,
I did thing would calm,
I don't even necessarily believe in common
anymore because every day of our life
we're trying to avoid crazy.
Right? Yeah. But you can't,
you know what I'm saying?
When a guy comes in with a gun and he
shoots up a motherfucking school. Yeah.
Like what are we supposed to do?
We didn't do anything to cause that,
but he's got something going on with
his life that caused him to snap and it
affected us.
Like if you're walking down the street
and you know a guy's just angry about
something, he bumps into you and
you're like, oh, excuse me. He's like,
why the fuck you mean it's choose
me and he's ready to fight.
I don't got nothing to do with you.
I've got everything to do with him.
So you really can't avoid
this crazy that exists.
I had a conversation with someone they
were talking about like everything in
your life you have manifested
and created. I go, okay,
explain babies who get shot and
drive bys. Shut the fuck up. Yeah.
There's random things that happen.
Kids get leukemia. What would they do?
Something bad. Come on, I
use it, but bigger than you.
That's the thing that people hate to.
Yeah.
We are a very small part of this
big fucking ego system, right?
We really think that everything
in our life is that important.
That it could affect the world.
Get the fuck out of here.
Sometimes random factors, cause you
know, you think about the secret,
like the law of attraction,
your thoughts become things.
I think that thing that we forget
about that is not only do our,
it's not just our thoughts, our
actions. You know what I'm saying?
It's not like you're just sitting around.
You didn't think,
you didn't sit around and
think about doing this. Yeah.
We actually put us on fucking work.
That's the difference between the secret
in reality is that people think that
you think things into existence, but know
when you're successful and people say,
what did you do while I thought this a
new existence, show me how you did that.
Well,
I got up every morning at 6:00 AM and
I fucking hustle to the gym and then I
wrote jokes all day. Like, here you go.
Listen Bitch, you put it in the work.
Yeah. Yeah. And put in
the work. It's like,
it's like literally if
somebody said to you, Hey,
one day you're going to win the
lottery so you can sit at home. Right.
Thank all day waiting to win the lottery.
You get up and go to the fucking
store and buy a powerball ticket.
I think Chappelle had that joke.
He's like,
you don't think they're starving kids
in Africa thinking about food, right?
They don't get drew out a nice roast
beef sandwich. Any common exactly that,
don't get me wrong.
There's plenty of things that I've
thought about that I've manifested,
but like you said, I took the steps to
go put in the work. Like there's focus,
there's a process discipline.
I've got this theory called
putting the weed in the bag,
you know what I'm saying?
And they came from the movie belly because
nod and Dmx was sitting at this table
with these two young kids and they were
bagging up the weed and all the kids was
like, y'all want to go
thank you money with y'all.
I want to go out there and get
money at Dmx is like, what are the,
we in the back first didn't
go out there and get money.
You have to go through the process
so we can start with a thought. Yeah,
but you still gotta execute.
Put some fucking work in.
All right.
I remember I was talking to this girl,
she was a friend of a friend of
mine and she was telling me how, um,
I found the secret and my life is
going to be amazing now and I'm gonna,
I'm going to get married and I'm going
to meet the right man. Never ever.
It was like, okay. And then I ran into,
like a year later she came to one of
my comedy shows and I'm a, I'm like,
how's everything going? She was like, I
don't get it. I've been using the seat.
Good. But I, life is a
mess. My father's in jail.
She was a sweetheart of a person,
but she really believed that
her life was going to transform.
I'll never forget the juxtaposition
of those two conversations.
That's why that's why the
position that we're in in media,
you have to be very responsible
with these positioning. Yeah.
Malcolm X and Malcolm x at the person
who controls the media controls the minds
of the masses. So you have
to be very, very responsible.
What do you remember when you used to
get a lot of flack for putting on just
different voices that people
didn't agree with? Yeah.
Like why are you giving these people
a platform platform? I'm like, Yo,
everybody deserves to
be heard. Yeah, I guess
man, I'm not everybody but I just, I want
to know how people think too. I want to,
uh,
even if I don't agree with it,
especially if people you don't want to
go with that conversation isn't a co sign
and I think that's what we owe.
We often mistake
in this day and age two was especially
on the left that so many people are
talking about d platforming.
You want a d platform
people, I don't like to know. I don't
like that. Like you might get either.
I saw people getting mad at Lavar ball
this week, you know what I'm saying?
Because of the comments he made the
Molly on ESPN, which I didn't, I didn't.
He just was like, she was like, Hey,
let's shift gears and you said you
can shift gears with me anytime.
[inaudible] he said it just like that.
You can still be in the meeting.
He didn't say, he didn't whisper that
you could shift good placeholder.
If she had said, hey, let's switch it up.
He would say, hey, you switch it on me.
But every people was like, oh, they need
to stop putting them on ESPN. I'm like,
wait a minute,
Huh?
Literally just last year y'all was saying
he was the drunk uncle at the picnic
and you love him or hate him.
He's good entertainment but that now
because he said that you want to take them
off and I'm like, we got to stop
doing that because guess what?
Every single one of us is going to
say something that is going to offend
somebody at some point. Now that doesn't
mean that we shouldn't have a platform.
I'm not calling nobody to get killed,
but also makes things fun.
When people say stupid shit sometimes.
You know when Steven Smith
was going off about Andrew,
he's winning the title looks like Butter
Bean. This is a disgrace. There was mad.
I'm like, the guy is speaking the way
he would speak if you are around him.
You gotta appreciate that. Unless you
want everybody to be Ryan Seacrest,
you should fucking appreciate not
there's anything wrong Ryan Seacrest,
but you should appreciate someone who
just giving you what they really think.
Yes we do. That's why he's so
popular. We pretend to hate it,
but the reality is we're going to keep
listening. The second one gets a result.
So pay attention. A lot of
people like, ah, all right,
that's the America feeds off of that.
She, that's why Donald Trump is president.
That's why the Kardashians are
still viable. I caught that.
She's the first family drama.
Every year.
Every year they find a new piece of
trauma. Once shit gets calm and cool,
the show ends. So they need
a new piece of drama. Oh,
who you got cheated on this year? Who's
going to have a baby? You're gonna,
you gonna get a baby. But
whatever it is every year, hey,
you're going to chop your dick off.
But you respect her for with Kim,
she is getting people out of jail going
forward. I can go back before that.
I respect the Kardashians
because if we really,
really pay attention to the Kardashian's
over the past 10 years, first of all,
you got to put them up there with some
of the greatest dynasties of all time.
This is Lakers. This is patriots. This
is fucking, they've made billions. Yes.
Billions with a B.
So many,
so many social conversations have
started because of the car dashes.
You're talking about interracial
relationships. You're talking about, uh,
the transgender thing. You're talking
about drug use and mental health.
With Kanye plastic surgery,
they did change the shape of
American women. They changed,
they changed asses. They made that
whole fat relocation thing popular.
They suck it out of your waist,
turn your,
wasting this little thing and turn
your ass into this ridiculous platform.
But Real Kim. Kim learned that from black
women though because people forget Kim.
But that's a bile. The when, when the,
when you would look at someone who really
has it. It's different. Absolutely.
You will see a woman who
has a big ass naturally.
It looks like it belongs on hers.
It's a different thing. Yeah.
They thick legs. They're there.
They're fucking genetically superior.
Built like a Turkey. Built sexy.
Yeah. Kim. Kim is inspiration.
People don't rip from Jim and Kim
came up in the black circuit. Right.
She did king magazine and smooth.
That's right. That's right.
You know what I'm saying?
Wendy Williams radio show earlier.
That's what I'm better. I met her when
I was going to read it with Whitney.
He knew her before she
was ever on anything.
When she was [inaudible] who's assistant?
Some of the system was Paris Hilton.
She's the organizer to organize
closets for Paris Hill.
I got a old picture like me and
Kim from like 2006 different,
what I will say,
she always had that vision.
She used to always say, I'm going to do
what Paris is doing times a hundred wow.
She motherfucking did it.
The secrets she used.
The secret secret is black deck.
That's the secret smoke a black cock.
It's amazing that that kicked her off
because it used to be the kiss of death.
If a girl did porn,
that was the hand Lisa and she
was the one to break that down.
Well what's it to her,
Jenna Jamison.
I think Jenna Jameson was the first one
to become actually popular outside of
porn.
Oh,
I thought you meant like the first person
to break like the racial barrier and
pull pulling on purpose. She was
the first to break the racial part,
but I mean doing porn
periods where you can be,
where you could be a celeb outside
and you talk about radio. Uh,
it's not too many people that came up off
celebrity sex tapes as long as few and
far between that really popped off.
Who made it off the sex?
Do you remember when girls were showing
him [inaudible] they were showing their
pussy on purpose.
You remember [inaudible] camera
just happened to be down with that.
Pussy is, yeah. Fuck.
Did you not know that camera was
down near your pussy up? Yeah.
That's a lot of confidence to put climbing
out of the car is showing their pussy.
Not a lot of trainers chill. What is
happening you not a lot of witch fingers.
That's all the more reason you
got to say Kim k Bro. Sat grow.
That was happening on a cause and you
could see her vagina and was doing sex
tapes is out here getting prison as free
is doing that. I don't give a fuck. Yeah.
I don't give a fuck if she's best
friends with Donald Trump. I don't care.
That's my thing.
Right?
If you care about prison reform to care
about criminal justice reform, yes.
You should be happy that these people
are getting out. Yeah. Worried about, oh,
she's doing it in the White House with
Donald Trump. Who gives a shit. You,
you think the guy who just
did 15 years for nothing,
nothing cares what president let him out.
She doesn't have to do this.
She could just be buying cars
and getting her nails done.
She's choosing to spend her time to get
these people that are unjustly accused
and convicted and get them released
and that and Trump like him or not,
and he's listening to her and he's
helping her at that. But you know why?
Because he's a celebrity.
He understands the and go.
So you keep sending all these politicians
to talk to a celebrity. That shit,
that shit goes over his head.
You've got to send another celebrity to
get in his ear because he understands
that type of lane.
He just understands that their power,
he understands where they're reaches.
He knows the Kim k doing something is
way more valuable than some random,
you know, democratic congress
person. Are you seeing that much now?
You look at Capitol Hill
the past few weeks, you see you're not,
I was there meeting Bti in David Gross,
what they're talking about
opportunities on legislation.
I was there with Taraji talking about
bringing social emotional learning in
schools. In therapy. You
had a a tiny, he see Colton.
Danny Glover was dead this week talking
about HR 40 you had John Stewart.
They're talking about the victims of
nine 11 now be compensated by the way,
to nine 11 shit. I didn't even
know that was going on, Bro.
If Jon Stewart hadn't had done that,
that I would've never even known that
was going on and that is fucked up.
And it was a simple statement. The
people you said you would never forget,
you forgot, whoo, that's not going to
win. Nobody's, hey, anybody can get that.
You can be with no teeth sitting in
fucking South Carolina in a trailer park.
You understand it.
You understand that link.
It doesn't have to do that. Let's do that
because he needs to. It's in him. Yeah.
It gives you a different sense of purpose.
Yeah.
Like that's what really means something.
When you talk to me about talking
about anxiety and mental health,
like the past couple of years, I feel
like I've been walking in my purpose,
you know?
Because I truly feel like if we can get
more people to deal with their mental
health issues,
you'll reduce so much of the
other bullshit we complaining
about in in America,
the violence,
the gun shootings.
Because when you've got a bunch of people
who have never dealt with that trauma,
never dealt with their pain and
their hurt, hurt people, hurt people,
and all we do is go around
redistributing that pain. The others,
you think murderers and rapists do that.
She could just put the thrill of it. No,
they are broken, damaged people so they
go and break in damage other people.
So if you can get people to deal
with their mental health issues, man,
that's the foundation of it all.
To me that's the real secret.
Getting to the root of that shit.
Yeah.
There is a thing about about purpose
that like what happens I think when,
when some people reach
financial independence and
I mean like fuck you money
meaning like you don't have
to work anymore, your family
good. Everything is good.
Yeah.
You have some people go,
well I'm going to get even more money
and I'm going to become a billionaire and
a trillion or whatever
and then some people go,
I'm going to live life
instead of survive it.
Or if you're working every
week so you can get a paycheck.
There's absolutely nothing wrong with
that. That's a majority of people are.
But you are surviving. Yes. That, that,
that job is no different than being out
there in the forest trying to find some
foods you can eat. We have some
shelter, you get financial dependence,
you have the opportunity to truly do
whatever you want every single day with
your life. Yes. And some people
go, you know what I want to do.
I want to go to fucking DC and help out
with these causes or I want to put on a
whole comedy community.
You know what I mean?
And like you really put it on your back.
I want to help other people out.
I want to have these conversations
and just talk shit about, you know,
fucking magic having HIV,
whatever it is.
We're actually choosing to
do the things that we enjoy.
Cause you realize it was important.
Like even when you're talking
about something like that,
but it's only when
these known legislation,
I feel like that goes hand in hand with
mental health because the environment is
so important. So if you can, you know,
get into these, these, these, these,
these communities,
these points just in franchise areas and
you can start putting things in these
communities that people actually need.
Like in the hood,
you replaced the liquor stores and
the fucking chicken spots in the check
cashing places with juice bars and
mental health spas and wellness centers,
things that people actually need.
Now you're creating an environment where
people can thrive in instead of just
trying to fucking survive in.
Yeah. You know what I'm saying?
You can't properly deal with your mental
health if you're trying to survive
every fucking day.
Well I think what you're doing is very
important as you're bringing up that
conversation.
That conversation wasn't taking place
before the mental health conversation
about anxiety amongst cool, successful
people. It just wasn't happening. Yeah.
Everybody was pretending everybody
was there. They're hiding from it.
You can use secrets like you've got,
you've got the float tank in
your fucking compound. Yeah.
Are you telling people about
that? Oh yeah. Okay. I'm the,
one of the reasons why that thing became
popular again. I got one in 2002 wow.
Yeah. I didn't do it for the first
time like three weeks ago. Yeah, man.
If you go to some float places,
they'll ask you how he found out about it.
It's like,
did you find out from the Internet,
Yelp and then they'll say Joe Rogan.
That's why one of the,
cause I talk about it so much as videos
of me. I gave one away. I gave one. No,
I had bought a new one and I said
I'm going to give one away to,
and I just got random emails and I picked
one of them had it sent to this guy's
house,
had it set up.
I just cause I want people to
know about what these things are.
Never felt stillness like I felt inside
the float tank. Yeah, it's amazing.
It's like, you know, at first you're like,
okay, they want you to get butt naked.
You don't know if they and you,
you know what the fuck's going on.
You know what I'm saying?
And then they're like, no,
that's complete a lot of confidence
in your cock. I wasn't even swinging.
And I'm a, I'm a, I'm a grower, not a
short, my shit is like swinging that.
Actually I was trying to think it
was all church say bro, I can't,
I actually would try to make it a little
chubby just in case you can't trust
these people. I don't know.
Trust. How do I go, Oh fuck,
I might be recording me in this shit.
So the lights went off and it's
like when you first get in,
it's allowing yourself to relax because
at first year fighting it a little bit,
you got your head up, you're
like, I don't know if I'm a drown,
but when you finally just relax,
you don't,
you don't even know what
the fucking I went. Right.
And I've never experienced the level
of students like that. It was point,
it was period where I thought I was
actually, I'm like, am I alive right now?
Right. Because your eyes are open, but
it's totally dark. It's totally dark.
So you don't know if you're really sleep,
you don't fill the water,
you don't feel the water. You don't know
if you're in and out of consciousness.
It's, it's, it's wild.
Everybody should do floods.
Yeah,
I agree.
What is the hardest part
about having influence?
That's a nice pregnant pause. I was
dope. Right? Yeah. And then the clap.
Who's going like [inaudible] the cameras.
Cameras switch.
Well timed.
Yeah. I Dunno. What's the hardest,
I don't think about it that way.
The thing you're very,
there's very,
there's very few people that you have
the opportunity to have the kind of
influence that you or I have or
you, it's a, it's, it's very,
very strange. I think you gotta
realize what harm you can do.
You gotta be careful when the,
the kinds of things you say are the
kind of things you promote, you know,
the kind of things that you
sign off on or agree to.
And I think there's also a responsibility
to tell people about cool shit.
I tell people about things
that have benefited you to
help help people about how
you've
overcome your own personal mistakes. I
think all those things are very important.
Yeah.
I never,
I never even thought about having
influence until like the past three,
four years because you know, I'm just
out here doing my thing. Just doing it.
When you read,
when you realize you are having influence
and a lot of that influence could be
negative. Yeah. That's when
you realize like, Oh shit,
let me make sure I'm doing the
right things with these platforms.
You know what I mean?
Let me make sure I'm bringing on the
right voices that people can learn from.
Let me make sure I'm telling people about
the things in my life that are making
me a better person.
So for me it's like the best compliment
I get nowadays when people say, man,
you really grown like you've, you've
really evolved. Like it's visible.
People can see it.
Yeah.
That right there lets me know I'm
putting out the right energy into the
ecosystem.
It also people become inspired
to seek that same kind of path.
When someone in the public eye,
like yourself and they see you grow and
expand and change your views on things.
It also inspires other people to open
up themselves and change their own
perspective and enhance their
own way of looking at the world.
I can admit when I'm wrong, y'all said,
I've said a lot of fucked up wild shit.
You're going to live on the air,
you're not reading a script right now.
You're free balling.
It's going to happen.
And I think the worst thing that can
happen too is like for me, you know,
breakfast club has only been
going on for nine years.
So I never had experienced this
level of attention. And you know,
you start reading things
about yourself in the media,
like you read real articles and be like,
oh the hip hop Howard Stern.
And I'm like, oh, so I gotta be like,
how would so I gotta give him more of
that shit. So what Howard though? Right?
Cause I'm giving them a little
bit of nineties I was like, what?
How would do yo fuck no. So it's just
like you can get caught up in that,
you know, you could get caught up in
what people's expectations of you are.
You change who you're,
you know,
a lot of people say that
happens to a certain comedians,
so they become their character.
Dice. I was going to bring up,
his name is Andrew Silverstein. Yeah. Dot.
The dice man character that he
would do in his bit. He would do,
he was doing a routine where
he would be John Travolta.
He would do a Sylvester strong and then
he would do this character called the
dice man. And that part was so funny
and so good. It took over his whole act.
I went toe to toe with dice
one time. Toe to toe. Yeah,
on Wendy Williams show back in the
day when I was Wendy's a sidekick.
And you the Wendy VH one.
Wendy had a show on VH one and Andrew
dice clay had a show on VH one so they
bought him on to promote it and
like we just ended up going,
but I don't know why the fuck me
ended up going to happen. Yes.
And and like VH one edited it to make it
look like he like kind of fucked me up.
But they kept a couple of mine mining.
He was really upset. Like I called him,
I said, you're like a fat Fonzie. Fuck
fucking loved it.
He was like,
fuck are you fucking one is basketball
fucking living? And I'm like, Oh shit,
it's on and got his shoes on. I'm
like, you fucking laugh at that.
I thought it was funny.
I want to be able to laugh
at that. If I looked like a
fat Fonzie be like, Oh shit,
you'd have to go. I was on, as I told you,
he going to discontinue terminate a model.
You remember
did that.
But what you said is real cause I'd
never want to become a character,
chill my say.
Yeah.
And I feel like it was a certain point
in my life where I was becoming a
character of myself and it's like,
well that's not real.
Like you can't claim claim to be a real
person and be out here pretending to be
real. You either really you not. Yeah.
And what's real is yo being
honest about going to a therapist,
what's real as being honest about your
mental health issues was really talking
about being a father.
Like real shit.
Like you can't always be trying
to be cool. It's not cool.
That's fake only existed when there was
like some sort of, uh, you're, you're,
you're projecting something.
You're putting something out
there in these small bits.
When you're doing what you do,
when you're talking for hours and
hours on gotta be you gotta be you,
you at the end of the day,
it's going to come out.
And then people with the longest careers,
I feel like are the people
who evolve born time. Boom.
You could see the guys
who have real growth,
like how it started in the beginning
when we really think about Howard,
like chicks were queesland on speakers.
That was a normal thing in the
Howard stern radio show is come in.
Who has the loudest Queef on the speaker?
They're lucky.
The Tiffany Haddish
wasn't around back then.
That's cause he, cause it would
be over six that Microsoft Pussy,
she makes a canon sound.
It doesn't even make sense.
She's like large had midgets into
the fucking atmosphere. Yeah.
She used to do that all the time.
She would quantify what she's shameless.
That lady
give a fuck.
[inaudible] guys to fucker like on comedy.
Oh y'all. Well there's not allowed. I'm
kind of an elitist approach to comedy.
It's quite interesting. He likes and
he likes bars. He says he likes jokes.
He doesn't like school.
Fucking still fucking,
if it's the right bit can be funny,
but it has to be the right.
It has to be a real comic with a
real reason to fuck that stool.
There has to be something to it. I'm
trying to think of Eddie. Fuck this tool.
I'm asking. Nobody fucking knows stole
Bro. See, I like Eddie. I like Richard.
I like Chris Rock. Bless
you. I like Chapelle. You
know what I'm saying? I like,
I like those guys that actually don't say,
just say something like have
something in perhaps something to say.
Louis C K has something
to say like I want,
I like people that have something to
say. All that stool fucking is, hey,
I want to get him on stage. I think
he could do it. Oh, you never go down.
I would not. I would never
disrespect the craft like that.
Well you wouldn't have to disrespect it.
You would just have to want to do it and
then try it. Yeah. I don't want to do it.
I tried to do it for fun.
I don't want to do,
you don't want to do it if you
don't want to do it, don't do it,
but you could do it. I tried one weekend
and my first job was like, you know what?
I'm going to sit down cause I don't
want anybody to ever say Charlene's up.
You're trying to do.
Stand up.
If you don't try it. Okay. Maybe don't
try and listen. It's not for everybody.
[inaudible]
my bad. Maybe I don't have an eye
for talent. We just did three hours.
That's how we do it. Let's
bring it home. Uh, Hey Andrew,
thank you for setting this up
and bring it to a shop to me.
Shout out to Brendan Schaub.
Um,
I really do appreciate what
you do for comics though,
cause I got seen what you do for Andrew
and Jessie Mae Paluso and ms Pat Dyno
Riley. He's people I really fuck with,
so thank you for that man. My pleasure.
It's for me, it's a, I'm, I'm honored that
I have the platform to be able to help.
All right. Bye. Bye.
Okay.