Donta.
Uh,
and we're back.
What's up buddy
tan really and joined the southern
California weather,
sir,
my biggest problem everyday is to decide
which beach between La and San Diego to
hit.
Would you bragging,
bragging about your lacks problems?
My privileged life,
you're brown privilege,
like Brown privilege.
It's like a bronze.
It's a very bronze shine.
In a few days it'll settle in and that's
when the true glory of God comes up.
Ah,
I bet your,
your vitamin D levels are at an all time
high.
I need to take them in for the Montreal
winters.
Right.
Do you supplement and when you were in
the winter in Montreal,
you don't died a hundred percent vitamin
D's.
It's a critical factor or I'd just come
back to do your show in the winter and
then that's how I got myself.
I don't think that's enough.
I need that vitamin D,
that's a big thing with the,
apparently with people that live in
Seattle in the winter is taking vitamin
D and even sun tanning beds.
People don't realize it's sun tanning
beds,
although it's kind of counterintuitive.
You think they're really bad for you?
It's actually not that bad for you.
As long as you don't burn yourself.
It's actually good.
I did a study a while,
a paper,
I wrote it.
This was a theoretical paper with a
dermatologist a few years ago where we
looked at some evolutionary explanations
for the epidemiology of suntanning.
So if I were to ask her,
not without you knowing anything about
it or not much about evolutionary
theory,
who do you,
what's the typical demographic of the
sort of obsessive Santana [inaudible]
what?
Well women,
young,
bright,
single.
And they usually tend to discount the
future consequences for the immediate
benefits.
Right?
Right.
So the smoking cigarettes,
they probably smoke.
Exactly.
So it doesn't matter whether I'll get my
window when I'm 73 I'm going tonight to
the Party and Tony might be there and
I'd like to,
and so we,
so,
so with this,
this dermatologist friend of mine had
written to me,
he was doing his fellowship and he said,
look,
I've got,
as part of my research requirements,
I'd have to write a paper,
can I,
you know,
you're the big researcher.
Can I do a paper with you?
I said,
but you're a dermatologist.
What can we talk about?
And then I thought,
well,
let's do the evolutionary roots of
suntanning and there.
And that's how that paper came to be is
how was that evolutionary though?
What's evolutionary about white girls
that don't think about the future?
Well,
no,
it's,
are there particular ways that we can
predict the demographics of people who
do certain behaviors?
So for example,
pathological gambling.
Who Do you think is likely to succumb to
that affliction?
Pathological gambling.
I would say,
uh,
men are with men,
adult men in their thirties.
Low status,
low status on average.
Okay.
And the reason is because it's,
it's,
it's one of a multitude of strategies to
acquire resources,
right?
It's the same reason that men,
rob banks,
not women.
And so you could,
okay,
let's do another one.
Eating disorders.
Who Do you think it's,
it comes to eating disorders?
More anorexia Nervosa in particular.
Okay.
Women limit.
Now typically the social science
explanation is old,
just due to exposure to media images,
right at that turns out to be a
laughably false premise.
Why is it laughable?
So here we go.
Here's the evolutionary angle.
Okay.
Hippocrates,
founder of modern medicine 2000 plus
years ago had documented the exact same
epidemiology of eating disorder
disorders in women.
So it certainly can't be because of
media,
right?
So there,
there must be something biological that
explains the sex specificity of these
different,
uh,
you know,
dark side consumption.
And so the evolutionary perspective is
to then look at to the extent that these
human universals manifest themselves in
exactly the same way across time and
place.
What might be some of these biological
drivers,
compulsive buying almost exclusively
women,
90% women,
uh,
pornographic addictions,
almost exclusively male.
And let's just stick with this one.
Let's just stick with this one.
The anorexia Nervosa.
First of all,
when you're talking about hippocrates,
you're talking about one lone
individual,
so completely anecdotal piece of
evidence and he said that women were
throwing up at a status symbol back then
for women to be overweight.
So it actually,
it's,
it's a good question.
Uh,
eating disorders are much more likely to
occur in cultures of plenty,
right?
Precisely.
Because the argument is that you can
shut off your reproductive window today
because when,
what happens when you,
so here's the evolutionary angle.
When you,
when you suffer from eating disorder,
the first thing that happens
physiologically is you get what's called
[inaudible] Arabia.
Primary Laminaria is where you haven't
had your mentees yet and now they don't
come out.
They don't,
there's no onsite and recycle.
Yeah.
Did you say menzies?
Your mentees?
Yeah.
Is that,
is that like the technical term for it?
It's the,
it's the fancy term for it.
Yeah.
MNCS,
everyone said it sounds like something a
little kid would call it mommy,
I didn't get my mentees.
Well,
uh,
now secondary amenorrhea is where you
already had your menstrual cycle and
then it's shut off once you become,
once you have anorexia Nervosa.
Okay.
Well what happens when you have an
erection when you have avenue area is
that you,
you know,
your,
your reproductive potential shut off.
Right?
And so what evolutionary scientists have
found is that it turns out that when
women suffer from Anorexia Nervosa,
there is some environmental trigger that
they're being exposed to Co.
Rightly so or wrongly so that they think
they should shut off their mentees.
They reproductive potential for a better
future.
You can see what I'm saying.
Whoa.
So,
and,
and let me,
let me give you the background to this.
There's a model called the reproductive
suppression model,
found an other mammalian species that's
say a cow.
Okay.
So if you take a cow,
what would be the biggest environmental
threat that it faces other than
predators?
What would you think about tainted water
or food or just how much food she can
have?
Right.
Cause she had access to enough calories
to sustain her gestational period.
Right.
Well it turns out that in in Mammalian
species,
a wide range of movie alien species.
Somehow there was a mechanism in
evolutionary mechanism that either
causes the females of the species to
either shut off they reproductive window
or if they're already pregnant.
And then there's an environmental input
that says,
Hey,
this is not looking good.
What do you think happens to their body?
What did they do with the video board?
The fetus,
they abort the fetus.
And now postnatally you have
infanticide.
So in this case you have the child,
but you realize for whatever
environmental reason that it's not going
to be fruitful to raise that child and
you buy where you fall.
You see it in human cultures where
typically the one who was killed as the
last born as you would expect because
the other children now you've invested
quite a bit in them.
And so if you're going to get rid of
some of your genetic package,
you get rid of the one that you've
invested Leeson.
So all of these mechanisms that are part
of something called the reproductive
suppression model,
the idea is that eating disorders is a
special instanciation of that because
what the eating disorder is doing,
it's shutting off your reproductive
potential because you're getting
amenorrhea,
right?
But is that absolutely connected to why
women get anorexic?
Because it could easily be just a side
effect of them wanting to be
ridiculously skinny like it.
Like I would understand with a cow,
with something that's living in a very
wild life,
a wild world,
you know,
this animal out there just eating grass
and when resources are depleted,
like nature kicks in.
But,
but there's no conscious decision making
process when a woman is deciding to be
anorexic.
At least there's some form of decision
making process that wants her to lean
towards a slimmer physique.
So that speaks to a very interesting
distinction.
And so bear with me as I set it up.
Okay.
There's something in evolutionary theory
known as proximate versus ultimate
explanations,
proximity.
And actually that speaks to the article
that I had sent you.
That's one of the points that I
discussed in that article.
Proximate explanations and science.
Explain the how and the what of
something much of science operates at
the approximate level.
If you want to explain what diabetes is
exactly,
physiologically speaking,
you'll explain it at the approximate
level.
The ultimate explanation is the
Darwinian why,
why would something have evolved to be
of that form?
So let's discuss it in relation to
something related to eating disorders.
Pregnancies taken us,
right?
So pregnancy sickness is a phenomenon
that women experience around the world.
That's a universal phenomenon found in
all cultures.
Uh,
approximate explanation might be,
or approximately exploration might be,
how do shifts in a woman's,
uh,
estrogen levels affect the severity of
her symptoms?
That's approximate question.
The ultimate question is why have women
evolved that physiological response
before I give the answer?
Can you guess what that might be?
Why do they develop that ultimate
response?
So why is it that women experience Prek?
The,
I call it pregnancy sickness,
but I mean the typical colloquial term
is morning sickness,
but some women don't experience it in
the morning.
I have no idea why.
Tell me why you ready.
Yeah.
So pregnancy sickness happens during the
first trimester of gestation during a
period called organogenesis.
This is when the fetus is developing its
main organs during that particular
period.
It's particularly important that the
women not be exposed to food pathogens
teratogens that might harm the
developmental pathway of the fetus is
organs.
Therefore,
all of the mechanisms that she
experiences attraction to certain foods,
pickles,
up,
repulsion from other foods.
Uh,
the feeling of feeling,
uh,
you know,
being nauseous,
the throwing up,
all of those built in mechanisms are
evolved mechanisms that are meant to
protect possibly the fetus from being
exposed to teratogens and it's perfectly
timed so that once organogenesis ends,
that's when the pregnancy sips symptoms.
And so the difference between proximate
and ultimate,
it's not that one is a better
explanation than the other is that you
need both levels of explanations to
perfectly understand something.
Well that makes total sense,
but it doesn't necessarily apply to why
women become anorexic because the desire
to be slim,
to look very thin in public is very
strong because of social media or media
rather.
Uh,
the depictions of women,
they're always almost impossibly slam.
And then on top of that,
they also had photoshop to it.
Right.
So in the,
in the,
the evolutionary explanation to the
eating disorder story is there is
something in the environment that the
woman in question is thinking is a
threat to her.
Could you think the same thing as the
cow felt for the lack of calories?
Can you think in the human context?
What might be such a threat?
Do you see what I'm saying?
So what?
I don't know.
What would be such a salt,
for example,
if you feel rightly or wrongly,
right?
It doesn't.
It doesn't matter whether they
objectively it's true or not.
Whatever she feels is what the reality
is,
right?
If she feels that there isn't going to
be sufficient either can support,
extended,
can support when she raises the child or
the most likely thing is partner
support.
If she feels that there isn't likely to
be a good partner who's going to support
her since we are by parental species,
then she engages at and shutting down
her reproductive window.
Hence what you said is true at the
proximate level,
right?
Her thinking can become this disordered
so that she actually looks at herself in
the mirror even though she's only 70
pounds and she still thinks that she's
fat,
but that's approximate explanation.
But the explanation that I've given you
is the ultimate Darwinian white.
Together they make a full,
complete explanation of the phenomenon.
So it doesn't occur in people that have
very healthy relationships with a spouse
or it occurs much more rarely.
Much more rare.
Exactly.
So the research shows,
the evolutionary research shows that the
environmental threats equivalent to
lacking of grazing area for the cow is
lack of extended,
can support or made support to the
woman.
Does that makes sense?
That makes sense.
Because it is primarily single women,
right?
That they'd have anorexia and that's
why,
by the way,
you see it in cultures of plenti rather
than an Ethiopia because you would
expect that the woman who shuts off her
reproductive potential today,
it's because she's hoping that in some
future state things will be better for
her to get back on the reproductive
train.
When you're in Ethiopia.
I don't have a chance to shut off my
reproductive potential.
I need to get the food tomorrow,
I'm going to die.
Right.
Wow.
Interesting.
But that still doesn't cover is
hippocrates.
Hippocrates is just one guy who,
right.
Who had a sufficient database at the
time to,
uh,
describe the findings in very similar
farms to the current ones.
What I'm saying basically is that if
it's were that it's due to media images
then well he didn't have media and it
just at that time.
Right.
I mean so how would it be that an
ancient Greece,
it is also the case that is only women
who experienced an erection or votes.
What did he describe?
What was he talking about?
I mean the specifics,
I don't know.
So I haven't read the,
the original,
it's kind of managing,
I don't know.
I mean cause I'm just aren't like
ancient depictions of women.
Like it's desirable for them to be
overweight.
Right.
It depends on the culture.
I mean the usual universal that we
typically talk of in terms of body types
is that it'd be an hourglass figure,
which actually is going to speak to the
second point.
That other paper that I send you,
so an evolutionary theory.
What we do typically is we build what
are called neurological networks of
cumulative evidence.
In other words,
when you're trying to make an
evolutionary argument,
it's you don't just come up with a post
hoc story as some people who don't
understand evolutionary theory like to
say that,
oh,
we just concoct these post hoc
speculative evolutionary stories.
As a matter of fact,
the evidentiary threshold that
evolutionists typically seek to achieve
is actually very high.
So let's take the hourglass figure for
example.
Okay,
so what is some data that would convince
people that men have evolved the pension
for the hourglass figure?
So let's go through some of these.
You Ready?
Okay.
What is some data?
Yeah.
So in other words,
if I wanted to convince you
unequivocally of the adaptive argument,
the evolutionary argument as to why men
might prefer the hourglass figure so
that they should have bigger hips,
it would make it easier for her to breed
larger fat deposits in the breasts in
the ass.
It makes it healthier.
She has fat storing for she's,
she'll have healthy offspring.
Okay,
so let me jump in.
So if you had medical and reproductive
data that shows that women who have that
particular body type are more likely to
conceive,
then that would be one check and we have
it.
Yeah.
Then we might look for human universals
of that preference.
In other words,
we don't simply use data from Ucla
undergrads to tell us what types of body
types would prefer.
We go to the animal,
more tribe in the Amazon and ask them
what type of body types they prefer and
so on.
So if you then demonstrate the
universality of that preference,
that's another check.
Now we could look at art data.
You,
you pointed to some of the depictions so
we can ask Ruben.
We can look at data from ancient Greece,
from ancient Egypt,
the pharaohs and so on from Africa,
from India,
and we could take the statues from those
cultures spanning several thousand years
and do a content analysis of the statues
and show that they,
they come very close to that hourglass
figure we could take,
if that's not enough data,
this one's going to clinch it for you.
But there's many others that I could
give you.
You could take congenitally blind men,
these are men who have never had the
gift of sight.
And you could show haptically through
touch that they prefer women that have
the hourglass figure,
which,
which immediately negates the
possibility that it's due to the fact
that they were taught those preferences
through the media.
And so you systematically collect data
from multiple converging lines of
evidence where that that data becomes
overwhelming,
it becomes unassailable.
And that's how you built an adaptive
argument.
So contrary to all the guys who say,
oh,
evolution has just come up with these
cute post-hoc stories,
we're actually profoundly more
meticulous and a situation.
And the data that we collect well is
that really been established that so
many men prefer soft,
mushy,
hourglass type figures is deposed too
hard bodied women?
How many women are you letting these
blind guys grope?
It's like,
are they getting a real study sample to
choose from or like how's that?
I like it.
Good.
We got it.
Well,
the p the,
the particular data with the congenital
blind men,
I think they only had maybe two or three
mannequins.
Mannequins.
Wait a minute.
Okay.
So you're letting them feel up
mannequins.
So all the day that I gave you is not
enough.
Now you're going to attack me mannequin
style.
He got it.
Okay.
How about,
can't you bring up strippers?
I mean,
how do you,
why do you have to have a mannequin?
Well,
because probably it might be difficult
to have the,
uh,
ethics approval board of universities
have young,
a young blind men or maybe they're not
young feel off a bunch of women.
Yes.
The ethics board doesn't like science
because you can't just judge what a guy
likes and women by you letting them
touch a doll,
that's ridiculous.
But let's shit science.
Okay,
well isn't that look every,
every study has some methodological
constraints,
right?
That one's easy to fix by having real
women being fest.
I'm sure a lot of women would sign up
for that.
Okay,
well maybe.
Maybe.
Why didn't they try that?
That seems so that you can tell by the
way that I'm not misspeaking.
I hope that they did use mannequins and
let's find out what's the name of the
study at Jimmy.
We'll look at the 2010 he just do
congenital blind men and waist to hip
ratios and it'll come up.
It'll come up on the Jamie Board of
truth,
the Jamie Bode of truth,
Aka the Internet,
by the way.
You could,
you could take Fmr,
righ,
right?
Brain imaging studies of men that are
exposed to women of different waist to
hip ratios and their pleasure centers in
their brain light up more when exposed
to women that have that hourglass
figure.
So again,
the data is unassailable because it
comes from multitude of countries,
multitude of time periods using
different methods.
I'm not denying that men enjoy that.
What I'm saying is that that Saturday
was study.
Yeah.
By using hourglass figures on the
mannequins.
So let me,
let me build on that.
I,
I in one of my papers,
I looked at sex dolls,
right?
Sex Doll,
convenient money.
I have to look at sex dolls for a paper,
right?
Uh,
so anyways,
in that paper I just went to,
I can't remember the company's name.
It's,
it's a real dog.
Probably one of those,
was it a like a realistic one?
I mean,
I didn't get them at home and measured
them.
They don't mean one that looks like that
person looks like a person and they
advertise their measurements.
Okay.
And as you would expect,
the average waist to hip,
their hair color changes in their skin
color changes.
But the average waist to hip ratio was
close to that 0.7.
And so here what you're demonstrating is
that marketers,
right,
these guys that are producing these
products are producing products that are
aligned with our evolve preferences.
If they didn't do that,
if they produced a sex dolls that look
like east German female slash male
swimmers,
it's not going to work.
Well.
It's not going to say,
how dare you.
Those are women,
I think.
How are we going to get into the
intersex debate from the Olympics?
Is that what we're doing?
Um,
well the Olympics is a fascinating place
to jump off with that,
but no.
Um,
so I think,
okay.
The atomy anatomy of desire,
uh,
the two mannequins stood side by side,
blah,
blah.
Cargo van mobile vans.
Yeah.
Okay.
Mannequins.
Yeah,
it's just two mannequins.
It's a shit study.
They could have easily gotten strippers
published in one of the top science
journals,
but okay,
well I'm still still publish it all day.
It's,
I'm fucking mannequin.
Why would they,
you can get real women.
All right.
I'll speak to them.
The only the way that it would be rude.
Well,
even the woman who was like not chosen,
well you don't know.
I mean,
some,
some guys might be like in petite,
slim,
slender model type.
Well,
that's what's interesting to me is that
men aren't really attracted to that
model shape.
No.
Yeah.
It's weird cause women oftentimes think
that men are,
because they see these models in these
magazines and I think that does lean
towards the desire for some women to get
into that anorexic state because he's
sort of get this body dysmorphia thing
going on by looking at these,
uh,
almost a completely unrealistic to
pictures.
I mean,
I know people were actually built like
that,
but they're extremely rare.
Right?
It's like knowing someone who's built
like a professional basketball player,
they absolutely exist.
But boy,
good luck finding one on a random day,
finding some seven foot tall super
athlete.
Right?
Yeah.
No,
I agree.
Uh,
there's all sorts of differences between
what images that you see sometimes and
what people truly prefer.
I think it's really strange how women
always say want to paint it as women
being victimized by these unrealistic
body images.
But you never hear the same from men
when it comes to body builders,
right?
When men see a guy who's just giant
muscles that had big six pack and just
looks like a stud.
Men never feel like they're being
victimized by these unrealistic body on,
right?
I mean most of the guys that you see as
leading men on average tend to be taller
than the norm.
Right?
So I'm being victimized cause I'm a
shorter guy as if you don't,
if you forgive me for saying as you are,
right.
So how come we don't complain about,
you know,
short guys and he'd love as well?
Or how about social status?
Right?
Typically you see the six,
the depiction say in romance novels.
I've given this example on previous
occasions.
I'm not sure if I did on your show,
but if you,
if you studied the archetype of
masculinity in a romance novel,
they'll look,
fabio,
it's long hair.
It's exact same guy,
right?
He's tall,
he's account and he's a neurosurgeon.
He's rough.
He's reckless in terms of his risk
taking.
He can only be tamed by the love of this
one woman.
He wrestles alligators on his chest,
uh,
on a six pack,
right?
He's usually not a pear shape.
How many of these books you've read and
Man,
I'm reading them every single day.
I just read one before I came here.
It looks so deep.
But the reality is that that you know
the product works because there is a
commonality to what women fantasize
about,
right?
And whether she's Romanian or Nigerian
or Japanese,
she likely prefers a high status tall
alpha male to a nasal pear shaped a
wimp.
And,
and so that's how you describe yourself.
How rude I am.
I am the walking Alpha male side.
I could call you son cause you're a bit
younger than me.
We slightly plus I've got gray hair so
maybe I can get away with that
appellation.
But no look up products that work well
are typically those that are congruent
with our human nature.
Right?
And those that are not will typically
fail.
I've always wondered why women claim
victim status when they're,
they're being compared to unrealistic
body images,
but men don't because I think that just
kind of relates to social justice
warriors.
I've proposed the theory of Munchhausen
Syndrome.
Have you heard me talk about this?
I don't know what it is.
Yeah,
so Munchhausen's syndrome for those,
for the viewers who don't know is this,
you know,
you get sympathy and attention by being
victim and so you feign an illness to
get attention.
Munchhausen Syndrome by proxy is when
you hurt someone else was in your care,
typically an elderly person or a pet or
typically your biological child because
that will garn you garner you empathy
points at well,
so then to answer your question,
why do women do that?
Because some women ultimately I trapped
and they sort of big Munchhausen a love
fest where I need to constantly get
reaffirmation and empathy by being the
victim.
To the extent that Western women,
you know,
have been liberated from all of the
typical problems that we see in other
parts of the world.
I've got to look for a new victim
narrative and boom,
that's a good one.
Well,
isn't it also though that it is an
unrealistic body shape and that they do
feel it completely.
It's like a completely impossible task
for a lot of women who were built like
normal people.
Have you seen the body shapes of a male
superheroes and toys?
Yeah,
like Mason,
they let me shoot.
That's right.
They look at you.
So what about the rest of us that don't
look like you?
How come we don't go into a fetal
position?
I'm asking why did,
why is Munchhausen Syndrome more
apparent in women than it is in men?
Incidentally in the true form of much
housing,
in terms of harming a child,
it's usually always the biological
mother.
So you're exactly right.
So it's just a manifestation of that
phenomenon in a new context.
So you're exactly right.
That's interesting.
But I wouldn't have phrased it that way.
I would phrase it more of a term of
frustration then some sort of a
psychological disorder.
I would think that women are just
frustrated with this seat.
One of the differences being that if a
woman is large boned or la,
you know,
she has a wide waist or something like
that,
there's very little she can do to try to
achieve that model shape.
Whereas if a man,
uh,
is slight,
he can lift weights and you know,
eat a lot of food and go get a personal
trainer and do a lot of squats and dead
lifts and build his body up,
right?
Like a man can make his body look more
masculine.
It's very difficult outside of surgery
for a woman to change the shape of her
body.
She can get in shape and if she's
overweight she can diminish that.
She can lose some fat.
She can,
you know,
put some meat on her butt and her legs
and,
but she can't like grow breasts,
you know,
she can't,
she can't do anything that would make
her appear more outwardly feminine.
You know what I'm saying?
By the way,
that exactly speaks to some of the
antipathy that people feel towards
evolutionary psychology.
I mean,
you hit the,
the nail the nail on the head yet
because there is wrongly saw,
there's this idea that evolutionary
theories sort of biological determinism,
right?
If people prefer facially symmetric
faces,
and if my face is not facially
symmetric,
then I'm doomed to a life of twiddling
my thumbs and the life of celibacy.
Right.
And that's why there's this narrative
that became famous with Naomi Wolf.
I don't know what,
do you know who that is?
He,
she wrote a book that sold,
I don't know how many millions of copies
called the beauty myth,
which I actually critique.
And my first book I talked about the
myth about the beauty myth and the
beauty myth.
Basically she,
she provides it this liberatory argument
against these beauty standards.
And here's her argument,
which I will sort of summarize very
quickly.
She basically says,
look,
women are now winning in every facet of
life.
And the only place that men can still
cause harm to women that they could
still dominate women.
And this is going to speak to one of the
points that you raised is by creating
this false
narrative about the types of women that
men prefer.
And by pushing this narrative,
it makes women feel insecure about
themselves.
Whoa,
hold on.
That's so her proposal is that the only
reason that this exists is because men
are trying to harm women.
It's a conspiratorial theory.
That's hilarious.
She must be a lot of fun to hang out
with.
She's not,
she's still alive.
She's alive.
Yeah.
She's,
yeah.
She's reasonably young and still very
productive.
Uh,
but you know,
again,
it's,
it's a,
it's a message that sells because if I
am a unattractive,
if genetically speaking,
uh,
I don't score well on some of these
universal metrics of beauty,
I would much rather hear a story that
basically says,
oh,
it's all due to arbitrary construction
of beauty standards.
It's not,
there's nothing innate about these.
Right.
I think there's a lot of women that are
very intelligent that run into asshole
men so many times that they developed
this distorted perception of what a man
is.
And so they can formulate this theory
and feel justified in doing so.
Is it just ran into so many weak bitches
out there that they start thinking that
all men are trying to harm them.
Right.
And all men are trying to hurt their
feelings.
Right.
And that this,
this theory is valid in her eyes because
it's based on the anecdotal evidence
that she's acquired through her whole
life of running it.
I mean,
obviously she's very intelligent.
She's writing books.
She's probably far more intelligent than
most of the men she's coming in contact
with.
And so she's formulated this theory
based on her own personal evidence,
protect her own ego or you're saying,
yeah,
but there's direct,
there's a direct connection.
Like as a man,
there is a huge difference in how you,
uh,
you react how your body feels when
you're around a classically attractive
woman.
Like let's classkick attractive like
Sofia wren in her prime,
like when you're around it,
you'd just go,
Jesus,
like your hands would get sweaty,
your heart would start beating it start
freaking out.
It is 100% natural and there's,
there's no like,
uh,
oh I want to enforce this because it
will make other women feel like shit
like that.
That is not it.
There is a real genetic propensity and
it doesn't it seem as though that should
be so trivially the now to accept,
right?
I mean it's,
but it's not for someone who's an
empowered woman who doesn't see any way
of achieving the right.
So if you don't,
it's like a man could do steroids and
live weights and become a giant body
builder type dude if that's what he was
really into.
And you could achieve that through time
and effort,
but it can be done.
But for a woman to look like one of
those women,
it's impossible.
If you are not built like that,
you are not built like that.
And that's how it goes.
So I'll tell you a quick story that I
discussed in one of my other books.
It was a documentary that I had watched
on speed dating.
I think it was where there was a,
you know,
profoundly overweight woman,
I don't know,
500 pounds.
It was basically arguing that,
you know,
it's unfair that all these men at this
speed dating event are not paying closer
attention to her.
Okay,
that's fair.
It's unfair because they're,
they've been taught,
they've to internalize all these
arbitrary sexist standards of beauty.
So she was really sorry.
Yeah,
yeah.
Now,
but listen to this.
So on the one hand if you're unattracted
to an overly overtly overweight woman,
then you are a fattest.
But on the other hand doesn't,
this is the other side of the coin.
If you prefer very overweight women,
then there's the narrative that you are
fetishizing our,
you know,
access meat.
So if you prefer an overweight woman,
you're a bad guy.
And if you this slight overweight women,
you're a fat that.
So there's no state of the world where
someone won't accuse you of being an
asshole.
That's,
that's the world we live in.
Well isn't that just the world of just
so many different people with varied
opinions that are trying to justify
their own physical condition?
Sure.
We,
and that's really what it means.
Have Fragile Egos.
Well there's a new study that they put
out recently about the,
the myth of healthy obesity because I've
ever seen that read many times.
Or I've read that rather many times
where people are trying to justify their
own obesity by saying that there's this
distorted perception of whether or not
people are healthy because they are
thin.
And then in fact there are some
diseases.
And this is kind of true.
It's some sort of a weird contradiction.
There's some sort of diseases where
people actually do better if they
recover because they're overweight.
But the reason for that is not because
being overweight is healthy.
The reason for that is there's a lot of
diseases where you don't take in any
nutrients while you're sick and so your
body goes into a state of ketosis where
it starts burning fat and you're better
off using that fat for fuel if you are
overweight than if you are a very lean
person was no fat to burn.
Then your body starts burning off a
tissue muscle tissue,
which is much less healthy for you and
much more dangerous.
Incidentally,
what you said,
uh,
there's I think now a movement to start
fattest studies at universities.
You know how you have women's studies
and peace studies.
So fat to studies in the heart of is
exactly what you led off with,
which is the idea that there's this kind
of medical conspiracy that's pushing a
false narrative that basically says
being overweight as a bad thing,
when in reality there is no such
evidence.
You know,
there's evidence of,
no,
sorry folks,
pull up that study.
It's a,
it's,
it's really kind of interesting because
it's so black and white.
There's just really no arguing about it.
Fuck it.
It's not good to overeat.
It's just not,
it's not good to tax your body,
you know,
having a little bit of fat.
It's not that bad.
Studies suggest healthy obesity might
just be a meth.
Um,
suggested vigorous health interventions
may be necessary for all obese
individuals.
Yeah,
that's a fact.
There you go.
But everybody knows that.
You know,
that that's why you see that fat woman
and people get repulsed.
It's not because they're mean.
It's because it's not because they're
taught to think that that's not an
objective standard of beauty.
It's just you see someone fat and you
go,
Oh,
this is a mess.
It's a mess.
This is someone who's must be
emotionally fragile because they're
there.
They're throwing food down their face.
They clearly have an addiction to sugar
or too simple carbs.
I mean,
they're,
they're definitely trying to make up for
something.
You know,
there's this,
this idea that people are just naturally
more fat.
Well,
that's not true because if you look at
their diet,
it's almost always in support of
maintaining a giant body.
I mean,
that's this idea that some people can,
well,
there are people that have hummingbird
type metabolisms and they can eat ding
dongs all day and still weigh 90 pounds.
Yeah,
that's a freak there.
There's a rare,
you know,
my sister was like that.
My sister's tiny.
Her nickname's peewee,
that's what I call her.
But when we were kids,
she was always,
uh,
she always weighed like a hundred
pounds.
She could fuck it,
eat anything.
She could trank she could have a steak,
she could eat ice cream,
90 pounds.
I mean,
that's just what she weighed.
Or,
you know,
maybe I'm exaggerating,
she might weigh 105,
but you know what I'm saying?
Like she just had that crazy metabolism.
It's just the way it is now.
But that's super unusual,
right?
For most people.
And you overeat.
I've posted a few photos on social media
of yourself,
myself at 1985.
Actually,
that was the first time that I've come
to California to visit my brother.
And your soccer players Subtler,
uh,
four or 5% body fat.
And of course I said you really get it
checked.
I did get a check.
Yeah.
But Calipers,
right?
Pri Calipers and the electric
conductivity tests.
Yeah,
the electric thing sucks.
I've done that electric thing before.
It was an in real ways submerging,
submerging the electric thing.
Apparently if you're dehydrated it can
be off.
There's a lot of like very fat cause
it's,
it,
a lot of it is,
I might be using a bad one,
but the one of them using was a one in a
doctor's office,
but he was even explaining to me that it
can easily be off if you,
uh,
have,
um,
if you're dehydrated and there's very
various factors,
whatever the number was,
was very low.
And this was 85,
so this is almost 30,
well more than 30 years ago.
And until up til about my early
twenties,
22,
23,
24,
I was always grossly underweight.
The day that I stopped being a serious
athlete,
it just snuck up on me.
Every single,
it's a coincidence.
That's all that is.
You think so?
No.
Okay.
Of course,
I didn't pick up on the sarcasm.
You know,
it's,
it's very insane.
This is society's standards that they're
enforcing.
I knew God,
exactly.
Venture of these assholes.
What it is,
is a bench of men who want you to feel
bad.
Right?
Right.
Yeah.
So they,
uh,
they let you eat.
There you go.
Yeah,
man.
Just fucking run every day.
You'll lose a ton of weight.
Well,
not,
that's not enough because I actually,
believe it or not,
I trained a lot.
The only way I lose weight as if I'm
very,
very careful about what I eat.
Well,
she thought that I never lose weight.
But you're a smart guy.
Why do you allow yourself to get
overweight?
Oh boy.
We're going to get into this now.
I mean,
this is a subject,
right?
Yeah.
Okay.
Uh,
I mean,
I don't think it's related to your
intelligence because,
well,
it must be,
right.
Well,
let me give you an issue.
No,
no.
We'll,
we'll just so quick to dismiss,
but it is an issue,
right?
You walked into a physician's office
when I had severe bronchitis.
He's,
he was I think a pulmonologist.
He was chain smoking in his office.
Now is that because he was an idiot who
didn't understand the yes.
Yeah.
He's an idiot if he's changed,
but it's an idea.
It's not correlated to his Iq.
Right.
It's just,
it's correlated to his objective
assessment of what is intelligent to do
with your meat vehicle.
This guy is stupid.
If he smoked cigarettes,
that is a stupid thing to do.
It doesn't mean that he can't be
intelligent in other areas of his life,
but he's most certainly shutting down or
ignoring some really clear information
that we have been given for the past,
you know,
50 plus years.
Well,
I think actually what you're,
what are you talking about speaks to a
point that I reason some of my writings,
the idea of whether we make choices
simply because we don't have the right
information to make better choices.
That's usually the typical argument that
public policy makers use.
So that basically say,
Oh,
if you're,
if you're engaging in,
uh,
on,
you know,
uh,
risky sexual behavior,
or if you're engaging in a sedentary
lifestyle,
it's because you don't know any better.
So let's set up public service
announcements that teach you a better,
and then hopefully people will act
better and that doesn't actually work so
on.
So the issue is not so much that people,
you know,
it's not as though I don't know that
being overweight is a bad thing.
And now that you've taught me better,
I will now change my behavior.
The problem stems from the fact that
there are these Darwinian pools that
make it difficult for us to extricate
ourselves quite.
Whether it be,
whether you're addicted to drugs because
it tickles your pleasure center in your
brain,
or whether it be because you addicted to
sex,
or whether you're addicted to a bit more
food than you should be eating.
Those are the Darwinian pools,
uh,
Poles that make it difficult for us to
do the optimal decision.
It's not because we're too dumb to know
better or we don't have the right
information.
But you,
William,
you're,
you're talking about food now,
not the cigarettes that this doctor was
smoking,
that you were using it as an example.
That's not the best one because there's
no Darwinian pool towards smoking
satellites.
Forget,
forget the,
the nicotine example of what I just
said.
In general,
when we make poor decisions that lead to
deleterious health outcomes,
it's not because we don't know any
better.
So let's go back to this suntanning
example.
Women know more about the deleterious
effects of sun exposure than men do yet
they do with more.
If it were only a question of,
you know,
it's because I don't know any better
than,
we wouldn't expect women to be doing it
more.
So it's not a question of not having the
right information.
It's whether ultimately you have the
control to not succumb to these polls.
I mean,
we've got the seven deadly sins since,
you know,
since for thousands of years precisely
because very smart people understood
that these are some traps that we all
succumb to,
whether it be greed or lust or gluttony.
And my case,
I've never smoked.
I've never drank.
But very,
I mean,
an elite.
My problem is I guess gluttony.
I'm a gluttonous.
Right?
But when you say have the control,
like what,
but what steps have you ever taken to
acquire the control?
I mean,
do you practice mindfulness?
Do you meditate?
Do you write down your goals?
Do you write down like what you eat and
what your cow,
you,
have you ever gone to a doctor and found
out what your calorie consumption should
be?
Have you ever tried to alter your diet
and maybe go on a fat burning diet
instead of on a carbohydrate burning
diet?
Not the mindfulness,
but all the other stuff that you've done
in a fat burning diet instead of
carbohydrates.
Absolutely.
So what have you done for them?
And when I do it [inaudible] you'll see
me in three months,
I'll be 35 pounds lighter and you won't
believe in what have you done?
Like what pro?
So I just do a heavy protein dive,
minimal carbs with a lot of vegetables,
so upbeat,
you know,
six ounce steak,
with Broccoli and whatever,
something like that with the tomato
juice.
Uh,
and that I'll,
I'll loose kind of like the,
uh,
well not the Atkins in the sense that
you'd eat as much fat as you want,
but it's really a lot of protein and a
lot of vegetables.
Well,
honestly the Atkins is when you're
saying eat as much fat as you want
there.
That is actually the trend.
The trend is towards a,
a ketogenic diet when he talking about
getting your body to burn fat,
a lot of athletes are getting involved
in getting on fat burning diets.
And I actually switched my own diet to
that where,
I mean,
it didn't really have a problem being
overweight,
but I was definitely heavier and I had
more body fat than I have now.
And what I did was I switched over to
this.
Uh,
this is a guy named Mark Sisson who was
on my podcast before.
Um,
and he wrote this book called the primal
blueprint.
And,
uh,
it's the idea behind it is that you're,
when you're eating a lot of simple carbs
and a lot of pastas and breads,
you're getting insulin spikes,
your body's processing all that sugar
and your body stores it and your body
starts burning sugar.
Whereas if you can get your body to a
ketogenic state,
meaning your body burns fats and uses
that for fuel rather than carbohydrates,
you don't really want high protein.
You want,
um,
uh,
minimal protein.
You want what you're supposed to have,
which is like,
you know,
six ounce steak is fine,
but what you really want is a bunch of
healthy fats like coconut oil,
Avocados.
I eat a lot of Avocados.
Salmon is excellent,
excellent.
But also because excellent because it
supplies you with Omega six isn't threes
the essential fatty acids,
which are really important for brain
function.
But people this,
this idea,
this is also a big fucking problem that
people have.
We've been lied to about fats,
about the danger of saturated fats and
the danger of cholesterol.
Dietary cholesterol barely moves the
needle on blood lipids.
It's not dietary cholesterol.
It's a problem.
It's sedentary lifestyle.
It's overeating.
It's a consumption of excess carbs is a
bunch of factors that cause people to be
fat and it's not necessarily saturated
fats or or um,
or cholesterol.
In fact,
saturated fats and cholesterol,
that's the substrate for building
testosterone.
Like when,
when I went on this diet of,
uh,
having my body burn fat and not just me,
but a ton of my friends,
my friend Denny,
um,
uh,
who was a,
a an elite athlete is a Brazilian
Jujitsu world champion.
Um,
my friend John Rollo who's a MMA
fighter,
Brazilian Jujitsu,
black belt,
these guys have all reported jai and me
included gigantic spikes in their
testosterone production.
And it's because that is the building
blocks for testosterone.
So when you're eating these low fat
diets and these,
uh,
these like minimalistic diets to try to
get your body to be more healthy,
you're dropping your body sex hormone
production.
Well,
we'll have to ask my wife if she has any
complaints of that department.
But,
uh,
Oh God,
fuck.
Honestly,
uh,
the only problem I have is when I walk,
when I walk away from those types of
dyes,
that is where the problem arises.
Of course.
Yeah.
But I bet that if you walked away from
what had,
whenever you're on that diet,
when you get off it,
the things this integrate very quickly.
If you don't descend it,
well,
I'm,
but I guess for me they do.
I mean,
I could,
I could put on seven pounds in two weeks
by simply eating.
Normally once I'm away from that side is
normal.
Then if you're putting that much weight,
seven pounds in two weeks is 14 pounds
in a month.
I mean,
that means 28 pounds in two months.
Some liberty,
that's not normal.
Okay.
That's a crazy amount of weight to put
on.
If I saw you two months later and you
put it on 28 pounds,
I'm like,
what the fuck are you doing?
No,
I'd have to grab you by the hand and sit
down with you and go,
come on,
man.
I don't want you to die.
I,
I'm already thinking about all the
comments that are going to be at the
blind.
Oh boy.
Well I'm,
I mean I'm just saying this cause I'm
your friend.
I want to get your copy of this book.
Okay.
That I would love you to try to do it,
but it's not hard to just eat til you're
satisfied and not eat until you're full.
That's a big factor.
That alone is probably 20% of everyone's
meal.
A lot of people eat and then they keep
going.
I love to do that.
That's fucking awesome.
I love to eat a giant bowl of pasta and
eat a big steak,
but I also work out like a terrorist.
I do that.
I work out almost every day.
I kind of work out hard,
so I keep my body fat down because of
that.
So even if my diet has shit,
I still keep my body fat down because of
tremendous working out.
But then when I adjust my diet as well,
I saw a big difference in my energy
levels and my cognitive function and a,
and a big difference in just overall
wellness.
Right.
You know,
I just don't,
I mean I'm an extremist when it comes to
physical performance because obviously
I've been around it my whole life and
I'm in the martial arts world and I'm,
I'm trying to get my body to do certain
things that are very unusual.
But I just think that people are not
designed to eat big plates of Pasta or
bread or all these sugars that everybody
downs in the form of corn syrup drinks.
It's just not good for you.
Have you seen the uh,
documentary sugar
or something?
I can't remember what the sugar,
that sugar movie.
Yeah,
it was crazy.
Festival is a watch with my kids and
then we went to the supermarket was
hilarious cause they're,
they're grabbing things,
going sugar in this,
they were like grabbing things off the
shelf,
finding how many grams of sugar per
serving or,
and everything.
So let us,
maybe I'll say this,
you know,
if you say something publicly,
then you have to kind of add to it.
Say it.
So let,
here's,
here's what should I look at the camera
here?
Uh,
next time I'm on your show,
I should hopefully be visibly thinner.
Yeah.
Which you're going to do is you're going
to wait until two weeks before the show
and then you're going to stop your
period and you're going to do,
I'm going to go anorexia,
Anorexia and stop your reproductive
system.
Very nice.
Yeah.
I mean it's just people should be more
healthy and the body is designed,
I mean this is this whole trend for like
Paleo Diet,
Paleo diets and Paleolithic Diet.
That's not an accurate term.
It's a,
it's an,
it's a good way to eat,
but it's not an accurate evolutionary
term because in the Para Paleolithic
era,
people ate a lot of grains.
They whatever the fuck they could,
they bugs.
They were hungry,
you know,
and they worked hard to acquire it off.
Yes,
exactly.
That's a big point.
When they needed those calories in
grains,
like,
look,
if you're out hiking every day,
you talk to people that are like
mountain climbers and hikers,
like they're eating massive amounts of
calories.
I have friends that go on these gigantic
mountain trips and they literally cannot
consume enough because they pack all
their food.
Um,
and my friend Jason just got back from
this a big trip that he was taking to
the Yukon and he's going up and doing
all this mountain climbing.
They climbed a,
they went a hundred miles in eight days
up in the mountains,
like at 10,000 feet altitude.
So it's,
it's this incredibly grueling experience
because there's very little air and
you're constantly doing squats cause
you're constantly lifting your body up.
You're going up hill and they were
eating two pounds of food a day.
That's all you could take.
So you have to eat the most calorie
dense two pounds of food that you could
carry because you know,
for this trip,
you know,
you're only carrying a certain amount of
food cause you have to have your
sleeping bag on your back,
your tent,
all that jazz.
And he'd come out of there,
you're 15 pounds lighter right here.
And you know,
you just had this incredible,
I mean it's like,
it's,
it's like running a marathon every day
almost.
Are you familiar with the field of
evolutionary medicine?
Does that ring a bell?
What way?
So evolutionary medicine is basically,
actually I had one of the pioneers of
the field on my show.
His name is Randy Nessa.
He's a physician by training.
So evolutionary medicine is basically
trying to infuse within medicine
evolutionary ideas.
Uh,
typically most physicians are trained in
the proximate world,
right?
We were talking about proximate and
ultimate about how to deal with the how
and what other disease without ever
asking the ultimate wide Darwinian why.
So as relating to something that we
talking about now,
if you look at the top killers around
the world,
you know,
colon cancer and diabetes and heart
disease and high blood pressure,
they're all related.
As evolutionary folks argue to that,
what's called the mismatch hypothesis.
The idea being that those things that
were adaptive to us in an environment of
scarcity become grossly maladaptive and
an environment of plenty like we have
today.
That makes sense.
And so basically what you're having,
I mean,
my gustatory preferences don't change.
So my desire to eat the fatty foods
remains.
But what has changed is the fact that I
used,
I had to do 20,000 calories of
expenditure to punt it down then and now
I could go to the grocery store and get
it.
There is no caloric uncertainty in local
a scarcity.
And so if you look at hunter gatherer
societies that most closely mimic,
you know,
our evolutionary past,
they don't have all those diseases.
So once they clear the early childhood
mortality threats than they actually
live quite long lifespans precisely
because they don't suffer from,
I think they're the nine top killers.
So that's a way of taking some of this
stuff that you're very interested in and
infusing it with a bit more of an
evolutionary twist.
So that totally makes sense that people
would have to expand massive amount of
cowers to track down food.
Because that was at one point in time
what we did all day with our day,
whether it's hunting or gathering or or
farming.
We were constantly working to try to
acquire food.
That was it.
Now that food is so easy,
we still have the same genes.
Right?
Exactly.
Right.
Yeah.
So look natural selection,
right?
That the mechanism of how species
evolve,
traits that they have.
I mean it all,
when I teaching my students,
I start off by colloquially saying,
look,
most animals,
including humans throughout their
history had faced,
you know,
either you don't want to become somebody
else's dinner and you want to get enough
for dinner for yourself.
Those are the sort of the two big that
the problems.
And then you just add to that sexual
selection,
which is it's not enough to simply
survive.
Then you have to mate.
And so then you had want to get the
right mannequin that I tear you go.
So that's basically natural and sexual
selection and in one sentence,
right,
don't become somebody dinner,
get enough dinner and then get a mate.
And there's your evolutionary is how
much,
if at all,
do you pay attention to your gut health?
Do you,
do you eat probiotics?
Ooh,
see that's crazy.
Is that right?
Oh my God.
Probiotics are one of the most important
aspects of healthy bodies like your gut
health can infect or can affect rather
your mood.
It can affect cognitive function,
can affect your personality.
There's all these studies being done now
on probiotics and of gut health and
bacteria content and Gut Candida.
If you have a high level of candy to
which a lot of people do eat a lot of
sugar and simple carbs,
it be,
it developed.
You developed this intense craving and
hunger for sugar and simple carbs.
When you adjust your gut bacteria,
when you start taking in healthy
probiotics in the form of Keifer.
Um,
I like Kombucha.
I like Kimchi.
I like fermented cabbage and sauerkrauts
and natural sauerkrauts and things along
those lines.
Um,
I,
I drank a of different kinds
of them and take a bunch of different
kinds of them every day along with this
thing called the,
on it total gut health,
which is a packet that I take with every
meal.
It's a massive factor because what's in
your gut,
like your gut flora is incredibly
important for your overall health and
for supporting your immune system.
So has that become sort of part of the
daily,
not daily,
the yearly,
a health checkup that people do?
It depends on what doctor you're talking
to.
You see,
because most doctors spend very little
time studying nutrition,
right?
When you go to medical school and you
get a degree,
you,
I mean the amount of hours that you
spend studying nutrition are so small
end by the time you're out there
practicing.
This is a field that's constantly
evolving and changing and growing and
this,
this 10 toward this,
I'm leaning towards probiotics as a a
health supplement.
It's fairly recent in terms of like
mainstream exposure,
but incredibly important.
It makes a big fee.
First of all,
I hardly ever get sick and it's a big
factor cause I,
I travel constantly.
You're shaking hands,
shaking,
hands,
icons.
I'm constantly flying on planes and I
hardly ever get sick and if I do I can
point to some pretty obvious factors.
Like I didn't get any sleep.
My kids are going to school again.
They were around other people that are
sick.
They're sitting in my lap,
Kop it in my face.
It's normal stuff.
And even then I bounced back very
quickly and I attribute that to
probiotics.
I think it's really important to take in
healthy cultures.
Have you,
are you feeling,
here's another example from evolutionary
medicine that relates to children's
since you mentioned children.
Uh,
you probably have heard of the studies
that show that if you grow up in an
environment that doesn't have any
natural,
uh,
allergens,
you at an increased risk of developing
respiratory illnesses like asthma.
That makes sense sic because it doesn't
trigger your immune system to have the
types of responses that you typically
would have encountered.
So if you have a mother or a father or
both parents who are incredibly lcd
about having a perfectly sterile and
spotless home,
prepare for the onset of asthma,
that's another example of it's asthma,
but not necessarily allergies.
My,
my,
one of my daughters is allergic to cats.
We've had cats her whole life.
We've also had dogs her whole life.
She's been around in these animals her
whole life,
but she's allergic to them.
What,
what are the manifestations of,
she starts sneezing or eyes get puffy.
The cat can't sleep in the bed with her.
If the cat does,
she'll,
she starts sneezing and she can't help.
But it's soon.
It's because my wife's allergic.
It's just genetics.
Okay.
Yeah.
She's also solar g to horses that we
were in Italy and we were riding on one
of those horse carriages and she wasn't
even on the horse or touching the horse
just but being behind the horse on a
horse carriage,
she starts sneezing and coughing and we
had to get off the,
uh,
off the carriage.
You know,
it fits the saliva,
the horse or the standard.
The dander.
Yeah.
I'm sure she's allergic to saliva too,
but I'm just not swapping spit with a
horse and grow.
Settle down.
Gotcha.
All right.
What's next on the docket?
Now that you've convinced me that I eat
to lose weight as well.
I'm not saying that you need to lose
weight,
but I'm saying you're a healthy,
you're a smart guy.
You think about it very good life.
You're very handsome,
you bronze,
you're shiny.
You're thinking in these terms of like
looking at the big picture,
but yet there you've got this blind spot
and his blind spot is because you have
this indulgence for food and you look
forward to it.
It becomes your reward at the end of the
day and you sit down,
did you indulge?
And then you,
you say,
Hey,
I've worked hard for this and I can
enjoy it and now I'm married,
I've got kids I don't need to look
beautiful.
And you want to hear something that says
we're getting personal in California,
when we lived in California,
I actually naturally lost a lot of
weight without having to worry about
anything.
I was a lot more active.
I ate less.
And what about you?
We've talked about a reward when you're
in the dark cold winters of Montreal and
the only reward delivery system is for
us to be foodies,
then that's the problem.
Right.
And we often talk about that.
My wife and I because we eat at Joe beef
and Montreal,
uh,
that he's your friend,
right?
Yeah.
If you eat in there,
I have not.
Good Lord.
You are in the same town as the greatest
restaurant on the planet earth.
We're supposed to go there together.
I think when can go back,
something happened.
Yeah,
we will.
Next time.
Next time I'm there.
I'll take you.
Hopefully I'll be in California.
Going to have to,
yeah,
hopefully.
But if you are there,
you're going to have to indulge.
Yeah.
That's one of those places we've got to
get off the ducks.
Yeah.
Well it's,
it's okay to have a cheat day.
Yeah,
you're right.
But you know,
um,
I think a lot of people have those blind
spots and even intelligent.
Pete,
what's yours?
Ooh,
booze.
Yesterday we got fucked up.
Me and Hannibal burress to the podcast.
We've got a little too hammered.
That's one of those things where I enjoy
it while it's happening,
but like I worked out today and my head
was kind of throbbing.
I was like,
this is so stupid.
And then I don't do it every day,
but I do it maybe once a week or once
every two weeks or something like that.
It's just,
I know objectively that it's not healthy
so that you enjoy the taste or the
effects after your drinks.
Enjoy having drinks with friends and
getting stupid laughing,
you know?
Um,
that,
I just know it's not healthy.
It's just,
there's nothing healthy about booze.
Right.
There's nothing wrong.
And actually there is some,
some studies that suggest that,
uh,
it's a actually pretty healthy to have a
glass of wine or two with a meal and you
know,
you're getting Rivera trawl.
And also there's some studies that uh,
or,
or some,
uh,
some indications at 0.2 people developed
for a long time drinking wine because
they couldn't drink still water because
they would get traveler's disease where
if they found water would have pathogens
in it and they would wind up getting
sick.
So they drank wine for that purpose
because he can carry it around with you
and it's not going to go bad.
But um,
but getting drunk like we were drinking
whiskey,
drink jamison or something like that,
I'm out on the rocks.
It felt great,
were hammered and laughing.
But God damn it,
it's so bad for your body.
So if there's,
if there's an indulgence that I take
part in that's not good.
It's the occasional getting fucked up.
Gotcha.
Yeah,
it's not good,
but I don't have a lot of those.
I mean,
I'm pretty good at not having a lot of
those,
those things in my life,
but it's easy to do that.
It's easy to trip yourself up because
there's a natural tendency towards
distraction.
You know,
the pressure of a attempting to be
successful at something.
The pressure of whether it's competition
or whether it's uh,
just this yearning for achievement.
We look for a release,
you know,
from that pressure.
And that's what a lot of people do.
They go to cigarettes,
so they go to booze or they go to food
or whatever it is.
Yeah.
I've never smoked a single cigarette in
my entire life.
Good one puff good.
I did when I was like 15.
I smoked a cigarette with my sister.
She kept going.
I quit.
I was like,
fuck,
this is so stupid.
Is that,
I think that if you hit 19 and you
haven't started,
you almost have zero chance of starting.
Oh,
I know.
People have started in their thirties
due to start study was fucking 40 years
old.
He started smoking cigarettes,
smoking.
What are you doing man?
So weird.
But again,
I think it's a sabotage thing where
people just go,
fuck it.
We don't care.
And by doing that,
it's almost like they can,
um,
by saying,
fuck it,
I don't care about my health.
They could say,
fuck it.
I don't care about my student loans.
Fuck it.
I don't care about my wife leaving me.
I don't care about my mortgage.
Fuck it.
I don't care about losing my job.
It's like this,
this sort of like denial of reality by
indulging in something that's not
healthy.
It reminded me of a irrational position
that one of my former students took to
justify him smoking.
And so if you,
I don't know if you'd do this in the
United States,
but in Canada,
Health Canada,
uh,
has this program where they put very
vivid images on cigarette packets.
You have the same thing here,
right?
They used to,
well,
not that they don't have images,
but they have the sayings.
Okay.
But in Canada with these images,
I should even say they used to,
they still do.
There's still like,
so you know what he would do,
what to show you how irrational human
beings are.
So he would,
let's say ask for whatever the brand was
marble roll.
Now he would receive one and look at it.
If the warning message was one that
would be relevant to him,
he'd ask for another one until he
received got low birth weight.
He got low or you don't,
don't drink while pregnant.
It doesn't apply to me.
And since I looked at,
I said he was serious.
But you obviously know Bill Hicks bit,
by the way.
What does that,
what does Bill Hicks,
who's one of the greatest comics hour?
There was a bit that he had on exactly
that point.
Said just,
just pick one that doesn't apply.
Low birth weight.
Good.
Oh,
there you go.
Maybe he got it from him.
But it shows you how,
even though we often have our fully
cognizant objectively about some truth,
uh,
our ability to engage in self deception
is limitless.
Right?
Well,
it is for some folks.
And I think,
uh,
again,
that goes back to mindfulness.
It goes back to meditation.
It goes back to reflection.
Most people live their lives in a
constant state of momentum.
The momentum of the past constantly
propelling themselves forward,
and they're always adjusting and trying
to make up for all the mistakes that
their past is made.
They don't live their life in a state
of,
in the now they lived their life in a
state of,
fuck.
Why did I do that?
Now I gotta do this.
You know what I,
you know what I used to come to and I
think,
let me let me know if you feel it too,
because you have young children.
I'm obsessed about first,
for example,
this is the first time that my daughter
did this and they'll never be another
first.
I'm always panicking about them growing
up.
Really?
Yeah.
I want to sort of weird,
just it,
there's a purity,
you know,
look,
we live in a world where we're exposed
because we're in the public eye.
We're exposed to a lot of negativity.
Even though we're exposed to a 100 fold
more positivity,
you know,
it's a,
it's a rough ride out there.
And then my solace is coming home to the
purity and innocence of my children.
And then the reality is that you can't
bottle up that innocence and that purity
forever.
And so I,
so speaking of the here and now,
rather than oftentimes just enjoying the
moment,
I'm always worried that,
you know,
in five years she,
she's going to be a prepubescent girl
and then there's going to be a bunch of,
take this young boys that are gonna come
around.
So that's something that truly bothers
me.
Does it doesn't affect you?
I mean,
I,
I don't dwell on it honestly.
I mean,
I just try to enjoy every moment I can
with them and try and enjoy all the
different stage of their life.
Right.
But,
uh,
you know,
I,
I remember what they were like when they
were babies,
when they could barely talk.
And I,
it was,
I was thinking I could never love
something.
It's a lot,
much as I love them,
but now I think when I talked to them,
I love them even more because now I get
to have little conversations with
people.
You know,
when you have like a deep conversation
with an eight year old,
it's pretty intense and it's one of your
child and your daughter.
It's pretty intense,
isn't it?
Humbling when they ask you things that
clearly demonstrates out,
you know,
little about so many things because they
often will ask you the questions that
are profound and deep.
Why is lightning in that particular
form?
And you try to concoct some story while
being truthful and then oftentimes they
stump you.
Right?
Uh,
all right.
Just go to Google man.
Well it's got a heart to go to Google
while you're driving and having a
conversation about some,
some observation of that just made,
but it just shows you again the,
the,
the purity of the child and sort of
looking at the world and hitting you
with questions that you frankly can't
answer.
Well I always like to say that I can't
answer it.
I think it's important to let kids know
that you don't know everything.
Right.
You know,
cause I think children automatically
look towards adults as being some sort
of superior form of a child.
You know,
like the,
well,
I don't know anything,
but I'm a little kid,
but my dad will know.
And then you know,
if you let them know like,
Hey,
there's just way too much information
for everyone to know.
But what's important is you're honest
about what you do now.
Yes.
And we were very fortunate that we have
this thing called the Internet so we can
find out what it is that we're trying to
give them the answer for.
And incidentally,
I do that with my one.
They ask a question and let's see.
I don't know the answer.
I'm very open.
I said,
you know what?
I think you've gone with this one.
Yeah,
good for you.
Why don't you send me an email,
remind me.
And I'll look into it.
And,
and I do it just naturally,
but oftentimes they'll write back to me
and say,
you know why that was so refreshing?
But you know,
you are humble enough to not pretend
that you know everything about every
single thing.
You know,
I,
yeah,
I love that.
And it's so frustrating when you're
talking to someone who was really smart,
who don't,
doesn't want to admit that they don't
know something or wants to deny
something's true when they haven't
researched it.
It's very frustrating.
I have a friend who's a brilliant guy
who does that.
He just,
you'll bring something up and he's like,
that's not true.
And you're like,
oh Jesus fucking Christ.
We just google it.
Right?
And I've done it with him over and over
and over again.
I had to have a conversation with them.
I said,
listen man,
if I tell you something,
it's true.
It's,
I'm not making it up.
And if I'm wrong,
it's a,
it's an honest mistake.
But if you just google it,
then you'll know.
But you're,
you're saying it's not true and you've
never even looked at it.
But here we are in 2016 give a fucking,
you have a device in your pocket.
We can get the answer to virtually
anything at anytime.
Oh,
shit is out the window.
So what's the psychological trait?
Ego.
He's a very smart guy and he wants to be
the smartest guy in the room all the
time.
And so it just gets really frustrating,
especially if we're somewhere with,
there's no Internet service.
You're like,
we're going to get to Internet service
motherfucker,
and then you're gonna apologize.
It's,
it's,
it's this thing that people do where
they,
uh,
when you're having a conversation with
someone,
they're not just talking to you.
They're engaged in a contest.
Yes.
Oh yeah.
Men Do that.
All that.
I have several of those in my own,
uh,
and not nuclear family,
but my family of procreation,
so might brutal and say who but brutal.
Right?
And,
and here's another thing that you'd
never admit that you're wrong,
right,
because admitting that you're wrong
makes you lose face.
And that's such a detrimental dynamic to
have.
Right?
I mean,
you know,
I might come home at night and,
um,
I've had a tough day and I might respond
curtly to my dog.
I actually,
we'll go back and then hug my dog
because I have enough self awareness to
realize that I didn't give her enough
attention.
Right.
So I have enough humility to nevermind,
you know,
another human.
My dog is just as important to me and if
I responded curtly I will sort of
apologize to her yet I haven't got
family members.
Uh,
again,
this is not my family of my wife or
kids,
but the family that I was born into that
have never apologized about anything
because they come from a cultural
landscape where to apologize to your
child,
to somebody younger is to lose face at
parent is always right.
And I mean that might work when you're
too,
but when you're both now adults,
I think you sort of have to get out of
that and realize that we all make
mistakes and we all have to own up to
them.
We all have to apologize,
honesty when we make a mistake.
And yet some people it's super unhealthy
and it's unhealthy for the person who
doesn't admit they make the mistake too
because then it puts you in this
position of being in denial of what you
know to be the truth,
right?
You're going to run around pretending
that you were right all when you know in
your head that you were wrong.
So it diminishes your own personal
opinions about yourself,
right?
You're not sorry.
Ready on this exact point.
Okay.
So I'm having a chat with a family
member,
an older family member of mine for my
family as the problem person.
This is,
this is one of the key problem for
people in with my family.
And we,
uh,
he says something to the effect of,
Oh,
you know,
those ancient Greeks,
uh,
those Christians were really,
antisemetic where I come up with these
details.
I said,
oh,
well,
you know,
I'm,
I'm sorry,
I don't mean to correct you,
but,
uh,
those ancient Greeks were not Christian.
As a matter of fact,
the way we mark that eras,
we say bce before common era or BC
before Christ.
So by definition,
those guys were marked as not being
Christian.
So when he's now faced with sort of
historical evidence that suggested he
was wrong,
what do you think he does?
It's,
it's so grotesque that I'm not even sure
you can guess what he did.
I don't want to guess.
So he basically says no,
that's right.
That's what I said.
I said that they weren't Christian and
you said that they were Christian,
so he looks at you in the face.
That's,
that's called,
if I,
if you don't mind me saying on air,
that's mind fucking right.
He looks at you in the face.
He knows that,
you know,
but he has enough in Arabic.
You say what?
Ha it's the,
it's this kind of pathological pride.
Right.
Fuck you.
I'm going to look at you.
Right.
So rather than saying,
Oh gee,
I didn't know that.
Thanks for correcting me.
He flips what our original points of
disagreement was
there.
You can talk to that dude.
You've got to cut that guy loose.
Well,
maybe I have,
oh,
maybe have molly can I said that.
Yeah,
that's a,
that's an unfortunate characteristic in
men.
Uh,
I guess it probably exists in women too,
but I see it more in men,
uh,
that they will,
they'll always want to be right,
right.
You know,
but it doesn't make you better to have
information that someone doesn't have.
Like I like when someone can tell me
something that I don't know.
Sure.
It's interesting.
I suspect that one of the reasons why
your podcast is so successful is because
you exhibit that generosity.
If you came to the,
to every discussion thinking that there
is nothing that the other person could
bring to the table,
you're not going to have a show that's
going to last long though.
Well that's also,
it's impossible says we're not talking
about like the 1950s when people at this
narrow view of the world,
it was defined by their own environment,
right?
We're talking about this broad place now
where you can just access all sorts of
data.
And one of the beautiful things about
the podcast is by sitting down with
people like you or all the other awesome
guests I get to sit down with,
I get to experience the wisdom and the
information of someone who's lived a
completely different life than me.
And I just find that really fascinating.
And I just think that that arrogance
that someone would display by doing what
that guy did to you and switching around
your,
your points.
And just that's just a child that's like
a developmental dead end that this
person went down still.
So unhealthy.
I hear you.
But so common,
right?
So common.
Yeah.
What's next?
What do want to talk about?
I want to talk about your paper that you
brought up.
Oh yeah,
sure.
So this is a paper that uh,
I was invited to write and one of the
leading journals in the field general
marketing research,
uh,
where I was asked to talk about the
methods of evolutionary psychology,
how evolutionary psychologists conduct
research.
And it was specifically to address some
of the common canards that we hear from
the tractors of evolution psychology.
Oh,
it's all a bunch of post hoc
storytelling and so on.
And so the paper basically looks at
three points,
two of which we've already sort of
covered.
One is the distinction between proximate
and ultimate explanations.
And again,
that's a very important point to make
because it basically argues that you'll
never have a full explanation of any
phenomenon involving biological agents
if you don't study the phenomenon at
both the proximate and ultimate level,
approximately how,
what ultimate is the Darwinian wise.
That's one we've already covered that
one.
The second method of evolution
psychology is the building of these
networks of cumulative evidence.
Like the one I gave you with the waist
to hip ratio.
Uh,
maybe I'll give you another one as an
example of this mechanism.
So for example,
if I want to argue that toy preferences
have sex specificity,
that is innate,
right?
So it's not that cause typically in the
social sciences we,
we hear that what makes little boys,
little boys and little girls,
little girls,
is that boys are taught to play rough
with the GI.
Joe Girls are taught to play gentle with
the pink thought.
But that's dismissed.
I mean,
you,
you hear that,
but it's a very fringe in the social
sciences.
It isn't,
it,
it's,
it's still up there.
Well,
it's only because of liberal colleges.
It's not because of a,
it's,
it's not people that are objectively
intelligent that are recognizing us,
but certainly in terms of the university
landscape that is the dominant,
uh,
navigate.
What are they uses evidence to point
that men are taught to that because
they've proven that children absolutely
gravitate just based on gender gravitate
towards certain types of tasks and toys.
So that's what I'm going to do next is
I'm going to demonstrate how
evolutionary psychologists build these
numb logical networks of keen wealth of
evidence.
So if I want it to prove that that
premise that you argued is dismissed is
truly laughable,
how would I go about them?
And so that's one of the things that I
did in the paper.
So we could look at children who are in
the pre socialization stage of their
cognitive development,
meaning that by definition they're too
young to have been socialized and we
could do studies on them to see what is
it that the,
that that they,
you know,
approach first or what is it that they
gaze at longer.
And we see that there is a sex
specificity in such young children.
So already it demonstrates that it's
probably not due to socialization.
So that's evidence line number one.
We could take other species vervet
monkeys and rhesus monkeys.
And now there's some research
with chimps showing that they exhibit
the same sex specificity.
Would these types of toys as human
infants do?
They done number two,
we could take data from a clinical
population.
So there's a this order known as
congenital adrenal hyperplasia,
which is an endocrinological problem
that masculinized as little girls that
masculinized his little girls,
both in their morphology but also in
their behaviors.
So if you take little girls who suffer
from this disorder,
what do you think happens in their toy
preferences?
They become more like those of little
boys.
We could take a depictions on funerary
monuments,
uh,
you know,
these big mausoleums of that people,
uh,
from ancient Greece.
And you look at depictions of little
boys and little girls and you'll see
that the little boys are depicted with
the typical toys,
you know,
with a ball,
with a,
something with a wheel thing.
Little girls are depicted with dolls.
You could do the studies across a wide
range of cultures that are very
different from western cultures.
The phenomenon manifests itself again.
And so what you do,
again in evolutionary theory is you
build this normal,
normal logical network of cumulative
evidence coming from completely
different data sets that then makes it
unassailable to argue against it.
So that's the second method of evolution
psychology.
The third one I argue is a evolutionary
psychology operates on what are,
what are called consilience trees of
knowledge.
Consilience is a term that had sort of
lost its way.
It basically refers to unity of
knowledge.
So if you say for example,
physics is more conciliatory than
sociology,
it's because physics has these organize
knowledge trees that sociology doesn't,
okay,
so what is a typical tree of knowledge
and evolutionary theory?
So you could start with something like
sexual selection.
Sexual selection is basically the idea
that how do,
how does a peacock evolve?
It's a big tail.
So,
so how do animals evolve their traits to
give them reproductive advantage?
That's been established from the time of
Darwin through a million different
species.
So now that leads to down the tree to
another theory.
It's called the mid level theory called
parental investment theory.
Parental investment theory basically
says that if you want to know about sex
differences within a species,
look at the minimal,
I would look at Dory parental investment
that each sex has to have in that
species.
So in most species it's the female that
has more parental investment.
So typically they're smaller.
It's the males who fight for access to
females.
Females are more careful about the May
choices they make.
But you also have sex role reversal
species where it's as the males who have
greater parental investment.
What do you think happens to the sex
differences there?
Exactly reversed,
right?
So that has been also established.
So now we go down.
Parental investment theory leads to
another theory that basically says that
in the human context females will make
more judicious may choices than men.
In other words,
women are more careful and the types of
make choices that they must make
precisely because they have greater
costs if they make a wrong may think
choice,
which leads to a study that I did.
Looking at how much information the men
and women look at before they either
reject mates or choose mates.
And what do you think the results shows
when it comes to rejecting mates?
Women need less convincing.
In other words,
they,
they acquire less information before
they decide all these mates are losers.
On the other hand,
when it comes to choosing a mate,
women look at more information prior to
choosing.
So what I've shown you here is how you
start with a general principle and work
down a tree to a specific hypothesis.
That's called a tree of knowledge of
evolutionary theory.
That's what the method of evolutionary
psychology is.
So contrary to what typical the
tractors,
there'll be some buffoon,
some customer data on your,
uh,
at the bottom of your comments section
that says,
but evolutionary sciences,
that's not a real solid mckinnis
toronto.
Right?
Okay.
So that's hilarious.
Yeah,
you liked that,
huh?
That's the turn out of that is good.
Uh,
singers and other balls chopped off.
I usually call him the Castrati brigade
and of course in the singular form,
that's gus throttle,
right?
So it's a guy who walks around without
testes,
but a very inflated ego who then tells
you,
you know,
despite the fact that you've spent 20
plus years studying something,
he knows more than you.
All of you evolutionary scientists are
full in order.
Well,
it's,
it's interesting to me that there would
be people that would be involved in
universities that would debate this sort
of very objective research.
Right?
Right.
I mean,
especially when it comes to gender and
obviously there's variables,
but when it comes to the,
the gravitating towards certain types of
toys and tasks and,
and then it also pertains to career
choices as well.
Like there's this big push to get women
involved in stem and women involved in
technology and other th there's
discrimination.
Women in tech,
well,
no,
w women don't gravitate towards those
particular jobs.
They don't want to do them.
Some do.
And the ones that do,
they cry sexism because there's so few
of them.
Well,
there's just no,
it's just not something that they
naturally gravitate towards.
Overwhelming.
Well,
that's what,
I don't know if you remember the,
the whole debacle with Larry Summers,
who was the president of Harvard
University who then became,
I don't know if he was in the Obama
administration,
but here's this guy who was president of
Harvard University.
He was giving a speech,
probably Jamie can pull it up if he has
time.
Uh,
and he was basically giving a talk where
he hinted to exactly what you said.
He said that he didn't say,
Oh,
you know,
women don't have the capacity to get
into these fields.
Right.
I think he hinted to exactly what your
sensitive then they might not like it as
much.
Despite these very aggressive programs
that we've instituted to try to attract
women,
maybe they're not drunk,
just hinting at that led him to
eventually stepping down as president of
Harvard.
It's a real problem in colleges and
universities today with that,
with this denial of reality to her to
help other people's feelings,
where to make other,
but to placate other people's feelings.
And it's also this repeating that even
Obama has been involved in repeating
this myth that women working the same
job make 77 cents for every dollar that
a man makes.
That's not true.
I don't know if you've ever researched
that or gone into that.
So I know,
I know from two sources,
the only two sources that I've sort of
paid attention to that have addressed
this.
I think as Milo Yiannopoulos,
who's sort of been one of the big
champions to try to dismantle that
narrative.
Well it's just,
it's been dismantled by sociologists,
has been dismantled.
Dena hoff summers.
Yeah.
Did it so,
so,
yeah.
Yeah,
I think you're exactly right.
Well,
the,
the data is wrong.
I mean it's,
it's totally misinterpreted.
The real data is when you look at the
overall wealth,
like what men make versus what women
make.
Men make more money,
but they also work more hours.
They also choose different jobs.
They also are at a higher risk to die on
the job.
There's all of these different factors.
The misconception is that a man and a
woman working side by side doing the
same job that the woman is making 77
cents to the man's dollar.
That is not true.
Exactly right.
And that's the problem with this thing.
And even fucking Obama,
he,
he parroted that and Sarah Silverman did
it recently,
one of those,
Hillary Clinton's speech is talking
about how women make less than men.
It's not true.
Right?
But it's one of those things that if you
tell people they don't believe you,
like you have to,
you have to send them studies and then
they read it and you're like,
we have this myth has been perpetrated
so pervasively.
It's so common that people parrot it and
no one questions it.
The fucking president parrots it on
television like intellectually that is
so incredibly dishonest for him to do
that.
If he is aware of the actual stats and
he says that just because he knows
that's what people want to hear.
Like,
oh,
Obama does care.
He is,
he's caring and sympathetic and he's not
a pig.
I mean,
similar narrative has been proposed and
you could probably could fill in the
details regarding the,
I don't know what the number is.
You know,
one in five women on university campuses
will experience a sexual assault.
That is a ridiculous stat that is,
I don't know that that's not the ice did
define sexual assault.
If it's a guy making an an an unwanted
grope,
you know that a guy moves in for a kiss
when he doesn't,
I mean,
I think you're dealing with a lot of
awkward kids.
They're drunk and they do stupid shit
and some of it easily could be sexual
assault or sexual,
you know,
in propriety.
I,
I don't,
I don't necessarily think that that
number's off so that I think rape is
much more,
much more complicated.
I mean that then I think you're talking
about something way,
way more.
I'm way less common,
but way more disturbing.
And uh,
I think the,
the real re the real statistics about
how many women get raped or I'm way
different than what is being proposed.
The problem is you start talking about
things like an unwanted grope or someone
slapping someone in the ass that that
all gets factored in.
Then they start factoring in things like
having sex while intoxicated and that
becomes sexual assault.
But conveniently only for the man to be
the one who's the sexual assault or like
if a woman is sober in the man is drunk,
no one has ever accusing the woman of
being a rapist by having sex with a
drunk man.
Right.
Have we talked,
uh,
speaking of very private,
I'm not sure if we've discussed it on
the show,
that'd be discussed,
the rape by fraud story of this show.
Yes,
we have.
Well there's also the new laws that are
being passed rate by fraud,
which is a fascinating,
like if a guy says he's a prince and you
know,
I'm going to take you to my council,
you will live in luxury forever.
Right.
But he's really not a prince.
That guy can get charged with rape.
What are your thoughts on that?
Well,
the guy's a piece of shit.
So Amal be arrested as a rapist?
Well,
no,
but he is definitely a liar.
It's,
it's,
it's really tricky.
It's like what is he doing exactly?
Uh,
he's being a liar.
He's telling a story that's not true.
And because of that,
of girls having sex with him,
he's immortal.
He's unethical.
It's reprehensible behavior.
He's not criminal.
Criminal.
Because if that were criminal,
as I think I might've mentioned on your
show before,
95% of people who are engaged in online
dating are rapists.
Well,
yeah,
that's,
that's true.
And also a lot of guys will lie to
themselves,
the raping themselves,
you know,
pretending they really loved that one.
When I tell it now,
musterbation is raping yourself even
mean masturbation.
I mean,
having sex with someone,
you don't really,
you're not really attracted.
You just horny as fuck and you convince
yourself this is the right girl.
And then as soon as your orgasm,
you're like,
I gotta get the Fuck Outta here.
I just wrote myself.
Um,
I think,
um,
there's something immoral about it.
There's something unethical about it,
but it,
it becomes very tricky when you try to
decide whether or not that's a crime.
Right?
Or you want to prosecute someone for
rape,
for doing something like that.
Also,
it's weird because presumably the woman
had sex with that man,
uh,
voluntarily and enjoyed it and then
decided she didn't enjoy it when she
realized that guy was crazy or a liar.
Isn't that just like a lesson?
Like isn't that just a life lesson and
now you're going to go and be way more
picky with who you decide to have sex
with?
Well,
I mean,
think of it this way.
again,
let's link it back to evolutionary
theory,
not just in the human context,
but across the animal kingdom.
There's endless manifestations of the
set of signaling,
right?
Sure.
Animals including engage in deceptive
signaling,
right?
I mean,
he's an example that doesn't relate to
me thing.
Uh,
apple somatic colorings,
which is basically warning colors,
right?
So you have a species of say,
Amazonian frog that has very vivid
colors.
Why?
Why would it be vivid?
Well,
because it is advertising to everybody.
Hey,
don't approach me.
I'm very venomous.
Right?
Well then there'll be another species of
frog that piggybacks on that coloring.
That actually itself is not at all
venomous but yet because it is a Serp,
this signal now nobody will attack it,
right?
Oh boy.
What a,
what
a fraud.
What it right.
So,
so the idea,
and again I don't want to receive
comments now that I support lying and so
it is reprehensible.
It is unethical,
it is immoral.
I don't do the behavior of course,
but it's part of life.
People lie to one another.
People lie to themselves.
I think I might've mentioned on this
show before and even if I have,
it's,
it's worth repeating.
Uh,
there's a gentleman,
a very famous biologist by the name of
Robert trevors.
We've talked about the evolutionary
roots of self deception,
right?
Why is it that we deceive ourselves?
And then the argument there is that the
reason why I have to first believe in
the lie before selling it to you is
because when I lie,
I actually have these micro expressions
that serve as tale tale signs of my
line.
If I could suppress these so that when
you're trying to look at my face to see
if there are any signatures of deception
on my face,
you won't read them because I've already
lied to myself.
And so they are even clear evolutionary
adaptive reasons for why we lie to
ourselves,
nevermind lying to others.
So lying and deception is part of the
large repertoire of human behaviors.
And to call somebody a rapist for
engaging in that represents that we'd
behavior it does nobody any good.
Hmm.
That's interesting.
Now deception also has to be defined
like lying and rape by deception.
Like at what level are we still calling
it rape by deception?
Like if a guy has a fake rolex on,
right?
Like,
and he's advertising that he's wealthy
when in fact he's not,
I mean,
when a guy pretends he's making $100,000
a year,
but it really makes 45 let's make it
less fun.
Let's make it more fuzzy.
Okay.
How about if I am actually a very,
uh,
apathetic guy who can't get out of bed
till 11 o'clock in the morning,
but yet I convince whomever I'm going
out with that I have this infinite
bottled up ambition.
So not even faking the Rolex watch,
this is not a tangible thing.
I'm just sending her cues that I'm going
places that all great ideas.
I've got a lot of entrepreneurial spunk
and my workout every day.
I worked with drink wheat grass.
I'm super healthy or meditate and soda
my rapist.
Yeah,
that's a good question.
Like who are you?
You know,
I always tell guys,
you should aspire to be the man you
pretend to be when you're trying to get
laid.
Like if you could just do they just be
that guy all the time.
Like you don't really,
it's the best way to go.
Right?
Uh,
but yeah,
that is a,
that's interesting.
Like that is deceptive,
right?
If he's pretending to have all this
really,
uh,
admirable behavior,
one on one fakes orgasm and makes you
think that you're a great lover and you
have sex with her,
she's alive.
She raped me.
So then I had sex with her.
It was under the misconception that I
was a great love of the first time when
she faked an orgasm.
So she's raping me that second time.
Now when you were talking about
evolutionary psychology,
receiving a lot of criticism,
what,
what is it?
What is this?
You and you,
you sort of glossed over it real quickly
to make your point.
Like where's the,
where's the vast majority of this coming
from?
Yeah,
that's a great question.
So it comes from
different camps for different reasons,
right?
So you,
so let's start,
let's kind of break them up.
Okay.
So we can go to the religious folks,
right?
I mean that's obvious though,
isn't it obvious that they would be the
track?
Obviously they're not going to look at
things realistically because they have
this,
that blind spot.
Let's talk about like professors,
right?
So then the professors typically will be
one of,
against several types.
They'll be the social constructivists.
Those are the guys who believe that
everything's due to social construction.
That what makes us human is that we
transcend our biology,
right?
It's an argument for that though,
isn't it?
Well,
we don't transcend our bile.
We were not strictly biological animals
would biological and cultural,
but we certainly can't negate our
biology,
right?
What they're basically arguing is that
what differentiates us from all other
life forms is that we transcend our
biology,
right?
So,
so they're perfectly fine if you use an
evolutionary explanation to explain the
behavior of the mating behavior of the
salamander,
but don't apply that exact same
phenomenon.
What are the flies to humans,
right?
Because somehow we have,
uh,
you know,
consciousness and we have higher order
thinking and we're called church
culture.
And that's what makes us human,
right?
Uh,
there are guys who,
for example,
professors who believed that evolution
stops at the neck,
so,
so they're perfectly happy with a,
you offering an evolutionary explanation
for why we fingernails where we evolve
opposable thumbs.
That's fine.
Why we've evolved the particular,
uh,
pancreas that we have,
but don't apply it to anything above the
neck,
not dumbo.
How behavior patterns or cultural
personhood,
who you are as a human being.
Right?
Right.
Uh,
there are some guys who,
uh,
don't have any ideological reasons for
hating evolution psychology,
but because they don't know much about
evolution psychology,
they typically will argue,
oh,
evolution has come up with all these
fanciful post hoc stories.
And in a sense,
the article that I wrote that I
discussed on your show today seeks to
address that.
Then contrary to what people think,
the,
the standard of evidence that
evolutionary scientists typically seek
to meet prior to accepting an
explanation is actually much,
much higher than other sciences by the
very nature of the epistemology of the
field,
by the very nature of how knowledge is
created and generated an evolutionary
theory.
So for all sorts of reasons,
reasons,
none of which is valid,
there's a long queue of frankly buffoons
who despise evolutionary theory.
Now the reality is that they're going to
lose this battle,
right?
There will be a day when it will become
by now to argue that humans are driven
by evolutionary imperatives.
And I already see it from my own
scientific career.
If I look at the antipathy that I felt
that I faced 15 years ago versus today,
it's very,
very different.
Right?
The antipathy that I felt from sometimes
the same person,
I could still have emails from somebody
who wrote me 10 years ago thinking that
my work was full of Shit,
who's now inviting me to his university
with all sorts of deference.
And so that's the nature of science,
right?
It's auto corrective.
And the reality is the cat's out of the
bag.
We,
everything's evolutionary,
right?
I mean,
we,
by the way,
we could talk about the range of fields
where evolution has made its way in
fields where you wouldn't typically
think.
So is that something that interests you
that we can talk about that,
but I want to keep going down this road
for a little bit.
Sure.
I find it very fascinating when people
oppose things that seem pretty obvious,
right?
And not only that,
or unwilling to take into account that
it might not be a case of either or,
but it might be a case of there's a,
uh,
a bunch of combining factors and that
evolution must certainly continue to
play.
It's the idea that we've completely
transcended evolution with culture and
thinking and logic and language.
It's insane.
It doesn't make any sense.
I don't know,
forgive me if I've mentioned this on the
show before,
but again,
it's,
if I have it's worth repeating.
Uh,
I always talk about the interaction test
framework.
Interaction basically means everything's
interaction.
Most things aren't traction between our
genes and our environment.
Right?
Right.
As a matter of fact,
genes get turned on or off as a function
of environmental input,
which is fascinating.
Exactly.
Evolution happens within an environment.
So by its very nature,
evolution itself recognizes the
importance of the environment,
right?
So any,
any,
anybody who is,
uh,
who exhibits hatred or rejection of
biology using those types of arguments,
it's simply advertising and they know
very little about biology.
The reality is it's an interaction.
And the example I like to give,
the metaphor I give is the cake
metaphor.
If you take the separate ingredients of
a cake,
here's the sugar,
here's the exit as the baking soda,
whatever,
whatever the parts are,
the butter,
they're separate at first.
Now you bake the cake.
If I then ask you when you have the
final kick in front of you,
point to the sugar or point to the eggs,
you can't.
It's an inextricable mix.
Them both.
And that's a very good point.
That's what we are.
We are in an inextricable mix of our
genes and our unique environments and
our unique talents and our unique
personhoods.
The problem with much of the social
sciences has been,
and they're losing now by the day,
has been that they've completely
rejected biology as an any way relevant
and explaining anything,
mating criminality,
a political choice.
For example,
there's a field called evolutionary
politics or bio politics,
which tries to infuse evolutionary
theory within political science.
Well,
no kidding.
I mean what?
What happens when we were making
political choices?
Suddenly our biology,
she's just a matter.
So evolutionary theory is relevant
anywhere that you're studying biological
agents.
So what is the argument against this and
what and why?
How has someone got into a university
level teaching this kind of bullshit?
Right?
So it comes from several sources.
Uh,
so maybe we could sort of point to a few
of you ever debated anyone about this.
Uh,
and I mean I have in various forms,
not necessarily in a public one on one
like this,
but I would like to see that,
hook it up,
make it happen.
I would like to find somebody who
opposes,
you have read their stuff online and
it's infuriating.
It's unopposed.
Like someone who writes a ridiculous
blog and you know,
you,
you know right away what the motivation
is.
Someone who is distorting reality to fit
their own ridiculous view of the world.
I mean,
I've debated them and typically one of
two ways,
either through the review process where
usually they're anonymous and oftentimes
I'm in on this.
So what,
in a double blind review process,
I don't know who they are,
they don't know who I am,
and then we're engaging in the debate,
right?
And oftentimes the paper gets rejected
because they're the reviewer,
they're the editor,
and then they have the final say.
So in that context of the Beta,
or I've debated publicly,
typically when I go after somebody on
twitter who is espousing these kinds of
stupidities,
but I've never done it publicly in this
way.
Have you had a paper,
a rejected that was logical and
objective and made a lot of sense?
Tons of times really.
And what like give me an example one.
So the paper when I was talking to you
about the,
the tree of knowledge going down the
tree sexual selection plan.
So that,
so I had a paper where I had looked at
how much information do men and women
look at before they either reject a mate
or choose a mate,
which I mentioned earlier,
right?
That paper originally I had sent it to a
top journal and consumer psychology and
to kind of just summarize the,
the thing,
the,
the position,
it was,
well this is all biology.
What does this have to do with
psychology?
So these very esteemed psychologist
somehow thought that biology existed in
a separate realm to psychology in a
vacuum.
You're brain exists in this other
parallel.
His influence,
the body has no influence in the brain
at all.
Exactly.
The other thing that they were upset
about,
cause they were talking about,
well why is this person who was an
otherwise be very patronizing was an
otherwise clearly a bright behavioral
scientists talking about sex differences
when we should be looking at things that
make us similar to one another.
Well,
when you're talking about sex
differences in mating behavior,
your study sex differences,
right?
I mean it's a fundamental defining
quality of humans that they are sexually
dimorphic.
They are innate differences between men
and women.
So he are people who did not want to
accept that they were sex differences
between men and women.
And they didn't want to accept that
biology has something important to say
about psychology.
Right now.
If I speak to neuroscientists,
if I speak to bio psychologists,
they would listen to my stuff and say,
well yeah,
no kidding.
So,
so in a sense I've existed in a
fractured life in my academic life.
If I am navigating amongst my natural
science colleagues,
then they're all like,
Oh yeah,
I love your stuff.
You know,
I love you.
If I navigate amongst my social science
friends,
while they're
less loving and less receptive,
but they're coming around.
So I think the problem stems from the
empty slate premise,
the idea that we are born with empty
minds that are only subsequently failed
by a wide range by a cascading number
of,
that's a nonsensical isn't it?
It is.
But it also,
I have a problem with someone saying,
why are you looking at this instead of
looking at that?
Right.
Well looking at this,
it just because you're looking at
something,
it doesn't make it so that you can't
understand why we were all similar in
many ways,
but the denial of these preferences of
these genetic preferences of these
evolutionary tendencies,
that's not scientific at all like that.
That is,
that's really preposterous.
And the fact that that's being taught to
kids and that they go leave these
institutions with these thoughts in
their head that are based on a bunch of
people that have never even existed in
the outside world.
That's what's fucked up about schools
and a lot of ways chair is there going
from learning by these people to
becoming one of these people teaching in
these schools and never existing,
uh,
John gigantic percentage never existing
outside of academia.
Absolutely.
So to speak,
to your point about if I ever faced this
type of antipathy and so on,
I gave two talks.
One of my first book came out at a
university in the psychology department
and in the business school they were
back to back to on two separate days.
So this was a talk on my book.
How do you Darwin eyes,
the field of consumer behavior.
I gave it in the psychology department
first,
which is made up of a lot of people who
have background in neurosciences,
in biology and they all listened and
said,
yeah,
beautiful.
No kidding.
I mean,
of course,
to study our consumer Tory nature,
we have to understand the biological
impulses that drive us.
Great.
Exact same talk the next day in the
business school.
This is one of the top universities in
the world.
I couldn't get through a single
sentence.
Why?
Because of the amount of hostility that
I faced in the business school,
the business school.
Why Business?
So I think so.
This is a very interesting question.
So I think business practitioners,
in other words,
business people,
not business academics actually loved by
work or historically he loved my work
because they're not vested in a
particular paradigm.
All they care ideology,
they care about results.
What works right or earns the money.
Exactly.
You're going to tell me what are the
evolutionary triggers for me to develop
a more effective advertising campaign.
I'm in,
I'm in talk to me professor side.
I don't give a shit about your
paradigmatic fights in academia,
but yes,
by the act,
but the academics who've been vested in
social constructivism or an cultural
relativism,
every culture is relative.
There are no human universals.
There is no shared human nature.
There is no shared biological heritage.
Then I come in on my biology train and
I'm dangerous.
We've got to shut this guy down.
Now the reality is if you're
sufficiently confident about what you're
doing,
you ride out that storm.
And Luckily
for me,
you know,
now 20 years into the game,
uh,
more people are coming to seeing things
in the way that I'm saying him.
But it's taken a lot of dog fighting to
convince people,
uh,
of,
of the veracity of what I'm saying.
So when you were giving these speeches
and you're being interrupted,
yeah.
Like what are they saying?
No example.
Okay,
I'll get the first one.
How do you explain homosexuality?
Right?
Because their first instinct,
no pun intended,
instincts as an evolutionary
term,
uh,
they,
they want to show that if everything is
evolutionary,
if everything is adaptive,
then how could you explain something
like homosexuality,
which by definition is Darwinian,
could the socket that end?
Right?
Well,
then I say,
well,
there are some evolutionary theories
that try to explain homosexuality,
but that's not really the focus of my
talk tonight.
Can I just go on?
And he explained suicide.
Here's the other.
Now,
if we are these adaptive creatures that,
that have this survival instinct,
how do you explain the fact that there
is an epidemiology of suicide?
Why would somebody to take their own
life?
So,
uh,
if I started,
it's pretty easy to describe.
I don't think I'd have a problem with
no,
but then imagine if this goes on for
every syllable that I authored,
right?
So these are students that are
interrupting all these up,
but he's a professor professors,
as a matter of fact.
That's so rude.
Yeah.
So two points I'll make the,
the more senior,
the person in the room,
the more hostile they were really.
So the doctoral students who took me out
to lunch after,
we're all like,
Oh man,
I love your stuff.
Professors up.
Now why?
Again,
anecdotally we can understand why
because the more senior professors are
vested in their paradigms,
therefore their brains are closed to any
ideas that might challenge the status
quo.
The doctoral student who still surfing,
who's surfing at the buffet of ideas is
open to the idea.
Oh yeah.
Biology seems to make sense.
The second thing that I'll point when
you said it's very rude.
I actually got upset and I'll just try
to stay with the Corum and politeness,
but as we were leaving,
I took a couple of those senior folks
and I said,
you know,
what is the point of inviting me here
and wasting your money and our
respective time by not giving me a
chance to get through my talk?
Would it make more sense to give me the
forum?
And then at the end of the day,
if you decide that it's not worthwhile,
you throw it in the garbage,
but at least you've given,
you've given me the opportunity to share
my ideas with you.
Oh No,
no professor side you mis mistook are
interruptions is because we were so
engaged.
I said,
well,
it can't be really engaged when you're
not allowing me to finish the syllable.
Well,
not only that,
it's really simple to take notes and
then at the end of it ask me questions.
Right.
I mean,
why did they feel like they have the
right to interrupt your speech?
That's a great question.
I usually ask people to hold off their
questions till the q and a period,
but I don't know why,
but especially in business schools and
it's certainly in some of the top
business schools,
there's this culture of very sort of
Alpha maleness where you hammer at the
person you,
you because you,
you're trying to one up them up and it's
very,
there's a great story on Richard.
Do you know who Richard Feinman is?
Yes.
The Great Nobel Prize winning
physicists.
I think I read it in his book.
Uh,
surely.
You must be joking,
Mister Feynman.
Uh,
so I hope I don't watch the story,
but the story goes something like this.
He's giving his sort of pre final
dissertation talk is sort of
departmental talk.
He's still a doctoral student at
Princeton and fun of the WHO's who of
leading physicists throughout.
I mean,
Einstein is there and everybody's there
and as he's giving his talk as a young
doctoral student,
there is this one professor who's
interrupting him and the way that those
folks were interrupting me at that
school and from the corner somewhere,
apparently Albert Einstein says,
don't you think we owe the young men the
respect to let him finish speaking?
And then I'm sure at the end of his talk
you'll have plenty of opportunities to
answer us.
And then after that nobody said
anything.
So I think it's part of that baboons
sort of gorilla thing.
I'm going to show you that I'm the
smartest guy in the room.
So you're typically see it from not the
truly elite,
the truly elite don't have to do this,
but the guys just below want to show
that they're the toughest guys in the
prison yard and therefore they interrupt
you,
they harass you,
they heckle,
you know,
it's so on the same type of people that
would go after you with like a hate
blog.
Exactly.
Professors that are just fringe
intellectuals that just really aren't
that really that smart,
but they've achieved this notoriety.
And a a status because of the fact
they're teaching at some school.
Can I mention one such got,
sure.
A grand buffoon,
peas,
Ed Meyers.
Do you know that?
Yeah,
I know that is one of the most execrable
creatures that has ever walked academia.
I don't know him personally well,
but he's the exact type of guy who
exhibits those types of behaviors.
He has an incredibly successful science
blog hat off hat tip to him for having
that forum,
but all he does all day is attack fellow
scientists an extra ordinarily,
you know,
poisonous manners.
It's never respectful.
Certainly evolutionary psychologists,
we're all lobotomized idiots who are
faking science.
He's the real scientists.
All of us are just idiots who couldn't,
you know,
are borderline illiterates.
And the reality is the last time that he
ever published something was probably
around the period of the renaissance and
yet he feels perfectly comfortable
criticizing folks who are infinitely
more productive than him.
And I only call him out,
not,
I don't know him,
but I just despise this type of
bullying.
This is kind of arrogance when they are
incredibly honest,
hardworking scientists that in their
best way are trying to understand the
world.
But here's this guy who's got a huge
soapbox.
I mean,
I think over a hundred million views and
visitors on his side.
So he's got a big platform.
He's just denigrating everybody.
There's a lot of,
um,
there's the slot out action in that.
Like there's,
there's a lot of eyes.
If you,
if you're one of those people that
writes a hate blog,
you can get a lot of attention doing
that.
And some people become very addicted to
attention and if you notice,
they start repeating those patterns and
blogging constantly over and over again.
And then also what he also does is
anybody who opposes him,
he deletes them from the comments,
even if they're,
even if they're respectful,
if you,
you're an idiot,
you don't know what you're talking about
and gets rid of any,
I became aware of him because that whole
Michael Shermer debacle.
Yes.
The rape thing,
right?
Yeah.
Well,
he accused Michael Shermer of rape
because he had sex with a woman a
consensually while they were both
intoxicated at a conference.
I think.
Yeah,
see,
oh,
that's how you got to know him.
Like,
yeah,
well that's how I heard of them.
Right.
You know,
and just,
and it was the way it was done was so
reckless and so uninformed.
Like you don't know what happened unless
he were there.
And also there's photos of Michael
Shermer and the girl's smiling weeks
after this incident.
It was all,
it's all very sorted and its ugliness,
right?
It's just to understand what he gets out
of this sort of frivolous,
diabolical ugliness.
It's a tension.
It's a tension maybe.
Yeah.
It gets attention.
And you know,
he is the Grand Poobah of the retarded
social justice warriors.
Very true.
That's a,
there's a lot of people like that out
there.
And there's,
again,
there's a lot of attention in doing
something like that.
Um,
you know,
and if,
unfortunately it negates some really
good points that they might have,
might have about a bunch of different
issues because you have to look at it
through the lens of this really poisoned
his person.
Exactly right.
You know,
I,
the first I had heard of him,
uh,
was there was an incident that happened
on psychology today with a gentleman by
the name of Satoshi Kanazawa.
Are you familiar with him?
No.
So [inaudible] is a professor,
an evolutionary psychologist at the
London School of Economics.
It's a very,
very prestigious school in London,
England,
uh,
who was a very popular blogger at cycle
at psychology today.
But he had a very sort of bombastic
style of writing that sort of drew a lot
of attention because of the way he
phrased things.
And,
but,
but I guess he thought that he was so
popular that he was sort of untouchable.
And at one point he wrote a blog article
summarizing somebody else's work,
looking at racial differences in
attractiveness.
So for example,
who's most attractive white women or
black women,
white men or black men?
And one of the results from that
Dataset,
this wasn't his own study,
he was summarizing somebody else's
water,
was that black women had been rated as
less attractive than white women.
And he gave some,
I guess,
speculative reasons as to why that might
be.
So that caused a huge,
you know,
fewer.
Uh,
he's a racist,
but he's Japanese by the way.
Uh,
he's a racist.
He hates blacks.
He hates this.
He was,
he,
they tried to get him out of a
psychologist today.
They eventually kicked him out.
They tried to revoke,
they started a petition to try to revoke
his tenure at London School of
Economics.
But I'll mention two points.
Number one,
uh,
bees at meyers takes this example and
says,
look,
here's what evolution psychology is.
Here's this racist who happens to be an
evolution psychologist.
All evolution psychologists are racist.
Well,
I mean,
that's what racism usually is,
right?
Give me a generalization.
I know a friend who is Jewish and who
was caught cheating on his taxes,
that that shows you Jews cheat when it
comes to money because they're always
looking to make the most money.
That's what happens with those jobs,
right?
So he doesn't see the irony of that.
So then I wrote an article,
which I frankly,
if you don't want me to say,
it took a lot of courage where I,
and you could probably pull it up while
you could pull it up if you wanted,
where I basically argued that to purge a
blogger would set a very dangerous
precedent,
right?
If you disagree with whatever Satoshi
Kanazawa saying,
let his words come back to haunt him,
right?
His words will be there.
If the are truly racist,
if he is espousing racial theories that
are pure quackery,
that will be the biggest punishment he
could suffer.
But to remove him from the discourse,
the public arena of ideas sets a very
dangerous precedent precedent.
Now,
guess what happened?
A lot of my academic colleagues wrote to
me privately said,
my God,
thank you for having the courage to
write that article.
That's exactly what I thought.
But I didn't want to write the article
because then people might think that I'm
supporting Satoshi.
So it shows you that why would this of
people,
to me it seemed very natural to write
that article.
I don't give a shit.
I mean I know what's right and I'm going
to support that principle,
which is you don't ban people based on
ideas that they write.
Let their ideas come back to haunt them
if they are bad ideas.
Not only that,
right.
Why is it okay to say that it,
there's a,
there's an evolutionary desire for women
to breed with an Alpha male,
like one of these romance novel guys.
Right.
Why is it okay to say that women are
more inclined to favor taller men with
broader shoulders and longer or whatever
the fuck it is or why is it okay to say
that women are less attractive to obese
short men?
Why is it okay to say that women or or
that men would be less attractive to
obese women,
which is a fact,
but as soon as you involve race,
that's it.
Then you're not allowed to look at the
actual statistics.
You're not allowed to look at the real
numbers.
Have you noticed by the way,
that the a hundred meters was very
racist this year wasn't racist.
How so?
Black people,
one,
there were no Lebanese Jews who are
overweight that we're in the final,
ah,
there was no proper representation of
the rich tapestry of humanity.
Why were they all black?
That was,
that was clearly racist.
We're talking about an athletic event.
We're not talking about sex,
right?
It's,
it's,
it's all sorted
in many ways.
Um,
you could make the argument that there
are women that are far more beautiful
than any of that are black,
that are far more beautiful than any
white woman that,
you know,
I mean,
there's a broad range of attractiveness
and all sorts of different,
um,
uh,
different races and creeds and different
parts of the world and is also be
different.
People have different things that
they're attracted to.
Sure.
Like some people are attracted to short
Asian women.
Some people are attracted to tall women
from Norway.
You know,
there's a lot of variety in what people,
personal preference.
Sure.
But when you're just looking at sheer
numbers and which is,
I'm sure he wasn't saying black women
are completely unattractive.
Absolutely not.
That's in fact,
I think in the same study,
if I'm not mistaken,
he pointed to the fact that black men
had been at scored as more attractive.
So the result that demonstrates a
finding that is racially acceptable is
gleaned over the one that is
unacceptable then makes him a Kkk Nazi.
He supposed to do what he's supposed to
ignore the statistics.
Exactly.
Incidentally,
the,
the king on this issue as a gentleman by
the name of Phillip Rushton,
who's now passed away a few years ago,
who was a Canadian psychologist who
spent his career studying racial
differences specifically,
he studied,
uh,
differences in Iq.
And I actually had a personal anecdote
with him because early on in my career,
uh,
I think two years into my original
professorship,
I think it was [inaudible] 96 I was
giving a talk at a conference and this
hall had maybe 50 a hundred people.
And I hadn't looked at who were the
other speakers in my session,
but I noticed that people were very,
seemed there's a lot of poison in the
air and it turned out I should have
maybe checked before going into the
hall,
that the gentleman who was speaking
immediately before me was this gentleman
Phillip Rushton and he's going to talk
about,
um,
a cranial capacity postmortal carrying
capacity of black men,
black women,
white men,
white women.
And then he would show some racial
differences.
We forget everybody riled up.
And this was probably the only time ever
where I was about to give a talk where I
was genuinely terrified because I
thought that I would just get lynched by
proxy because I'm,
I'm the next guy in line and they just
going to kill me just because I was next
on the same stage as him.
The good news for me is that after he
finished his stock,
so the room,
let's say I had 1500 people,
he finishes a stock.
I'm getting ready to go up about 425 out
of the 1500 leave to follow him.
And his new yelled at him to yell at him
to kill her.
And there's maybe like 75 people in the,
in a room of,
and I was actually very happy that there
were so few.
So few people that had stayed at my talk
undeniable physical differences in human
beings to,
to somehow or another say that bringing
those up is racist,
is really strange.
Like there's just some undeniable
physical differences in bone structure,
bone density.
There's just some thing,
like for instance,
uh,
African American women,
tend to have a higher bone density and
similar bone density to a Caucasian men,
which is very rare.
Like in women,
it's not the same like African American
women have denser bones,
uh,
per capita.
You know,
normally rather you've got on average,
just in general,
you know,
who and who knows what the origin of
that.
I mean,
you could go into that from an
evolutionary standpoint and try to
figure out what part of the world they
come from,
what you know,
what their ancestors did,
what would have been the selection
pressures that would have resulted in
this indication that they're fascinating
conversation.
Exactly what Phillip Rushton,
you still have new,
he used to argue,
look,
I'm not a racist,
I don't have an agenda.
I follow an interesting line of
questions.
Yes.
And here's the data.
Now I've asked people who were friends
with him privately,
so,
so what is the deal on the gentleman?
Is he racist?
Is he not?
And I've never been told by anybody that
he was a racist.
But here's where I'm confused.
If you're showing actual skulls and
you're actually measuring cranial
capacity,
are you not allowed to do that?
Are you not allowed to look at the
differences between Asian people and the
Norwegian people?
Or are people from Antarctica versus how
you not allowed to do that?
Because it seems kind of crazy if you're
not allowed to.
So that's part of,
there's a great paper that was published
I think in 2005 or 2006 either in
science or nature.
I love the title of the paper.
I think it's forbidden knowledge and
it's specifically sort of breaks down
the types of research questions that if
you want to have a viable career as a
scientist,
you should stay away from.
And I think pretty much on top of that
list is studying racial differences,
especially racial differences that might
eventually point to a finding that is
politically incorrect.
Right?
That's an excellent way for you to
become the pariah of academia,
if not more generally the public.
And so,
yeah,
it's growth.
I actually did a sad truth clip on my
youtube channel where I talked about,
you know,
facts are not racist,
right?
I mean w [inaudible] and boolean logic
and mathematical logic.
You'd take a statement and it's either
true or false,
it has a binary value one or zero,
right?
I mean,
that's how we create circuitry,
architectural circuitry of a computer,
right?
It has a truth value.
Yes.
No.
Right?
So the idea that a statement is racist
scientifically,
no,
it's either false or not false or
provisionally true.
Uh,
but apparently the argument from the
other camp is the mere fact that you
asked these questions suggest that there
must be a reason that is nefarious for
you to ask these questions.
What is the value in asking that
question?
So they sort of infer a nefarious motive
to you going down that alley.
Yeah,
but you can't do that.
And because it's an appeal to ignorance,
you,
you're,
you're saying that let's all,
let's all feign
ignorance and not look at the actual
facts of just the physical bodies of
human beings and that they vary based on
climate based on,
you know,
what,
what area of the world,
what the people were up to that were
living there for generation after
generation that led to the genetics
expressing themselves and the way they
do in 2016 it's,
it's crazy,
but it's weird.
It's weird.
And it's,
it's almost like in response to what
they believe to be illogical criticism.
That's inevitable.
It's like this illogical criticism is
inevitable.
So hedge your bets early and say there's
no difference between the sexes.
There's no difference between the races.
I don't want to get in any arguments.
I want tenure.
I want just to want to keep promoting
ignorance at an institution of learning
Zap,
which is bananas.
Is it that the,
that's how you remember already were
asking me.
So who are some of these,
the tractors of evolutionary psychology?
So what you just mentioned kind of can
bring us back to that point.
Some of the early proponents of sort of
this anti evolutionary position came
from anthropologists who saw the
potential for biology being misused or
Darwinian theory to be misused,
right?
So the Nazis can,
can,
can refer to,
you know,
Darwinian theory.
There's a,
there's a struggle between the races and
we are the areas the Jews lost.
So what's wrong with getting rid of
them?
That's Darwinian.
Of course,
it has nothing to do with Darwinian
theory,
but I the assert the theory for my
nefarious pursuits.
A British class elitists said,
hey,
there's a struggle between the uh,
classes.
We are the upper class.
Who cares if the lower class are
eliminated?
If we don't fund them,
if we don't give them healthcare,
if we don't educate them,
that's natural selection.
You Genesis said the same thing.
You know what's wrong if we sterilize,
uh,
people who are dull,
you know,
mentally deficient people who are maybe
a bit too dark,
people who are homosexual,
hey that's cleaning out the gene pool.
Hey that's Darwinian,
right?
So some anthropologists thought,
well,
you know,
there is going to be misuse of biology.
So let's now create a new world view
built on bullshit.
So the edifice is built on bullshit
after bullshit,
but at least there won't be an
opportunity for people to otherwise
misuse biology.
And so how do they express that?
They created a narrative that basically
says that cultural relativism is what?
The fines,
humanity.
Every culture is unique.
Every culture is different.
There is no such thing as human
universals.
Cause that would necessitate biological
commonalities which we don't accept.
And so therefore for a hundred years,
anthropology departments have been built
on an edifice of pure bullshit,
at least the cultural anthropologists.
The Bio anthropologists recognize
biology.
But the cultural anthropologists are
driven by a premise of cultural
relativism,
which incidentally on our common friend
Sam Harris,
it tells a great story about moral
relativism.
And I hope I don't watch the story,
but apparently he was at a conference
somewhere where he had a chance to speak
to the bioethicist who is sitting on the
president's commission on bioethics.
And she apparently is a sort of moral
relativist stipe.
And he asks her,
are you sure that there are no universal
moral truths?
I mean,
are you not able to pronounce a position
on whether if there were a culture where
people were told that every fourth child
has to have his eyes gouged so that he
can walk towards the light without eyes,
would you support?
Well,
who am I to judge?
So this bio ethicists was unable to pass
a moral judgment as to whether if you
had a religious narrative that says that
every fourth child should have his eyes
gouged out,
she couldn't pronounce the position.
And the reason why she couldn't,
she because she is shackled,
she's intellectually shackled by the
narrative of cultural relativism.
Who are we to judge other culture.
It's the lack of criticism for things
like female genital mutilation in the
Islam and that's why the ca strata and
chief Justin true though.
That's why when he was not before he was
prime minister,
when he was a minister in parliament,
he got very upset when somebody referred
to child bride honor,
killing,
genital mutilation,
throwing acid in their faces when they
refuse marriage,
whatever.
Uh,
somebody referred to these practices as
barbaric and there is no place for the
Mccain society.
He didn't get upset by those practices.
He got upset by the other politician
referring to them as barbera.
Is that true?
That is true.
Look it up.
Then he later came out and you know,
hedged and so on.
Of course after criticism of course,
but he's responding to that standard
social justice warrior sort of creed.
He is the king and we've talked about
this I think last time on the show
briefly.
He is the king of the social justice
warriors.
He is taking down Canada to meet where
Sweden and the rest of the European hell
holes are not becoming as fast as he
can.
Well,
what is his motivation?
I think he's,
I don't,
I don't think it's because he's an evil
guy who you know has nefarious ulterior
motives.
I think he is simply profoundly
misguided because of all the bullshit
that you and I have talked about through
the years.
He comes from a environment of social
justice warriors.
His Dad was the architect.
Pure true though was the architect of
multiculturalism and Canada.
Now,
multiculturalism,
as we may or may not have discussed on
the show before,
has two different meanings.
We could talk about multiculturalism.
As you know,
there are many cultures in Orange County
that's multicultural but
multiculturalism as a political
philosophy,
as the idea that when people come to
your land you don't ask them to
assimilate.
You rejoice in the fact that everybody
has their unique,
distinct cultures where they can express
themselves in any way that they can.
Well,
of course in some cases that's fine.
When it comes to cuisine,
it's not fine when it comes to let's cut
off some cliteracy his right,
I don't where
it's not fine when it comes to genocidal
hatred of the Jews honor killings and on
it.
But from his perspective,
he is simply shackled by his inability
to have a clear moral compass that says
this is right,
this is wrong.
Because all he sees as the parasites in
his brain that says,
who am I to judge?
Well judge Asshole,
they are thumb some things that are
right and some things that are wrong.
And when we're talking about things like
people,
uh,
objecting to the analysis of cranial
capacity of different people,
I could see why some people would be
uncomfortable with that because I could
see how some people would perceive that
as being some sort of a justification
for racism.
And so there was stand,
but as a person who is not racist,
I'm not racist.
I don't think you are either.
We,
when we're discussing this,
it becomes a matter of just being a very
curious biological trait,
right?
And it doesn't make someone superior or
inferior.
It makes someone different.
And it's fascinating to me because I'm
looking at the human evolution of the
species as being this massive complex
algorithm that's been going on since the
beginning of single celled organisms
branching off into multicell organism.
So there's has been this process of
change and what has made this process so
that people that live in Iceland are so
big.
You know,
you look at those men that when those
strong man competitions,
how many of them are from fucking
Iceland?
It's crazy.
Like what is that?
What it was it viking genetics.
Okay,
well what,
tell me what happened.
Why are their bones so big?
Why they're so tall?
Like what is it?
What is it about certain people in
Africa?
Marathon runners are always from east
Africa.
Yeah.
Was it West Africa?
No,
east Africa.
Which ones is West Africa?
Africa as the sprinters.
That's funny,
isn't it?
Their muscles structures are very
different.
Right?
Slow twitch versus the longer,
so the east African soul,
Ethiopians and Eritreans and so on,
Kenyans have these elevated bodies that
are just built for a long distance.
The other guys are packed muscles.
Right?
Uh,
that's why you get those differences
that is not viewed as racist because
ultimately you're talking about success.
Success,
right?
On the other hand,
if you talk about race a as somehow less
good at something than race be and where
race a scores high on the victimology
Olympics,
forgive the pun and you're screwed,
you,
that there was a fantastic radiolab
podcast that dealt with,
uh,
people from one particular part of the
world that were amazing at running.
And uh,
they were talking about their ability to
endure pain because of the rituals that
they were.
Uh,
they had to endure the rites of passage
as Madison there,
their circumcision done with like sharp
sticks and having to crawl naked through
thorn bushes and,
and like really dark,
dark shit that they had to do.
And it was interesting because one guy
who had gone through that and became
this unbelievably successful runner and
just had this unbelievable ability to
shut off the pain signal,
like to ignore it,
but he was also talking about who we
wouldn't want his son to go through that
same process and that he believes that
the benefits are not worth it.
And that remember what culture that was.
Um,
I do not,
uh,
Jamie could probably pull that up.
He's probably looking it up right now,
but it was a,
an unfortunately,
he's like,
I listen to like five podcasts a day,
so probably a fucking million podcasts
ago.
What is it going Kenyan runners?
There's a Kenyan,
but it's a particular part of Kenya
is a very small population of people by
the way,
that engage in this like really brutal
ritual of manhood,
a rite of passage.
It's really,
um,
it's,
it is fascinating how the,
is this it right here?
Okay.
Yes.
Collagen,
Collagen people pursue,
pursue,
produced an astonishing number of great
long distance runners.
Subpopulation of Kenyans.
Yeah.
Those,
that practice,
those rites of passage.
Yeah.
So it's not just biology with them,
but it's also this unbelievable ability
to,
to die.
And it's called the,
the actual episodes called cut and run
because it's about circumcision,
about what they're forced to do while
they have a stick poking through their
dick.
It's really hardcore.
And that this ability to shut off pain
and ability to endure is a,
a,
a key factor in their ability to succeed
in running that it's a mental toughness
thing as well.
Like they've maybe perhaps turned on
this aspect of their brain and he's
like,
yeah.
And have you,
have you heard of this other rite of
passage?
I,
I talk about this one of my books that
with the bull ants?
Yes.
Yeah.
I know a guy who's been bitten by one.
My friend Steve,
my friend Steve was in Bolivia.
He was there filming his show called
meat eater and he went down there and
uh,
he got a bullet ant bite in his foot and
he said it was so unbelievably scores
the high.
So there's a paint quotient,
whatever.
I don't know the exact metric,
but apparently the bullet ant scores the
highest on that.
Yeah.
And so this particular peoples in their
rite of passage,
uh,
you could probably pull,
they take a glove,
they take gloves,
they said date the,
the ants.
When the ants wake up,
they start stinging the hands that are
in those gloves.
So they are multiple of these bites,
dozens all over the globe,
all over the glove.
And they have to do that ritual I think
if I'm not mistaken 20 times before they
are accepted as man or someone who could
take a fucking been there you go there
you,
Jesus Christ,
the amount of pain that you would endure
it by doing that.
It's just the,
there was a guy from Australia that did
it for a,
some sort of a television special and
one of going to the hospital.
But uh,
you,
you see the pain in his face while he's
doing it credible.
They say it's like getting your hand
slammed in a car door 24 hours a day.
Incredible.
Yeah.
And it lasts a long time.
It lasts for hours.
What was interesting is my friend Steve,
he got stung
by this bullet and he says,
unbelievably painful for about an hour
or two hours.
Like where you just like,
you can't believe how much pain you're
in during.
And then he said after that he could
remember which ankle got stung.
No,
just goes away.
It goes away.
And then he's just walking through the
woods with these people.
The,
um,
I'm trying to remember the name of the
people in Amazon via,
yes.
We'll try to remember the name of these
people that he was.
Um,
I don't remember.
Anyways,
speaking of bullets,
can I tell you another story short on
this vacation?
So I have a FBI special agent friend
here in southern California,
and so I know Fred,
Fred.
Oh,
you've met him.
That's true.
That's right.
So,
uh,
so his last name now I won't,
I won't.
Actually,
we'd met Fred and I met another
gentleman who is a CIA operative and we
went out that conversation should young.
Oh boy.
Uh,
maybe I'll give a little few hence
later.
But anyways,
he took me out to a,
cause we've talked about bullets.
I asked him if we could go to a shooting
range and he said,
sure,
let's do it.
So he brought his whole arsenal of FBI
stuff and he had another friend with him
who was a security type guy.
And so I went shooting for the first
time ever.
Even though I've never shot a gun
before.
No.
Even though I've grown up in the
Lebanese civil war and I had held the,
I think it was a question Kalashnikov.
Uh,
I'd never fired a gun.
Wow.
It was something that's interesting.
Yeah.
I guess you shoot your hunt,
correct?
Yeah.
But you hunt with a bow and Arrow,
correct.
Hunt with a rifle you've had.
Okay.
Yeah.
All these animals you see around your
shot with a rifle,
the rifle,
that one,
the one outside with the shot that with
a rifle too.
Right.
So I've shot things with both bone
marrow and rifle.
So when was the first time that you ever
shot?
Four years ago.
Well,
no,
not just guns.
Yeah,
long time ago.
A long time ago.
Yeah.
It was unbelievable.
It was really,
I mean it's a lot more,
he told me actually,
he said,
look,
I'll,
I'll book the range for two hours and
either you'll be the type of guy who go
there and we'll use the two hours or
you'll shoot once and you'll say,
this is not for me.
I don't like it and we'll leave.
Cause I was asking him what should my
wife gets come back to pick me up at?
Well I turned out that I stayed for the
full two hours,
but I can understand sort of the,
the response that people might have
where,
because the,
it's a lot more powerful than you think.
Right?
I mean,
you could speak to this probably better
than I can.
Uh,
I shot also the submachine gun,
the FBI something.
I found that a lot easier because it's
kind of recoil recoil,
but the guns and I think that would have
different calibers.
2145.
I don't remember the exact numbers.
Uh,
wow.
There,
that's why I have some really powerful
rifles that were even different.
I'm sure that anything you shot,
I have some hunting rifles,
like a 300 win mag that is like getting
punched in the shoulder.
Every time you,
you,
you shoot it because it's designed to
shoot Moose and elk and big giant
animals.
It's a heavy
fee,
really strong,
powerful round and a,
yeah,
the vulnerability that you feel when
that trigger goes off and you hear that
boom.
And I'm sure you're wearing your head
gear,
your guards,
which you really have to,
it's so important.
There's so many people out there that
hunt and shoot without ear protection
and they wind up having tendonitis or
tinnitus and yeah,
all sorts of issues with their hearing.
It's so bad for you.
Well,
what he,
what was interesting is when before we
went and he gave me maybe a 10 15 minute
safety mini lecture,
the main one that he gave,
I mean this is of course live,
this is not,
these are live bullets.
I mean are lethal.
And he said,
the number one thing you do is when you,
the gun,
the gun barrel always points to,
because what happens is he said,
you know,
people pick it up and start doing yeah,
yeah.
Gesture with it.
And so and so to sort of make sure that
I wouldn't commit such an error.
I said,
here's what we're going to institute as
I do every action.
I am verbally going to describe it.
Ah,
that's smart.
And that really sort of soften us.
Why should that the fear?
Because then he's listening.
Okay,
I'm not cut.
For example,
he told me after you shoot,
take your finger out of the trigger.
It's a trigger discipline.
Exactly.
So then I would speak it and by speaking
it,
it sort of gave me the discipline to
never make an error.
But anyways,
it was a very smart,
they should actually teach people to
think.
So yeah,
I think that your method is probably
something that people should adopt as
very intelligent.
You know where it comes from,
actually it comes from some of my
research.
There's,
there's a,
there's a methodology called verbal
protocols.
So what when you're doing research,
you could either ask people to fill out
something.
So that's where you're only interested
in the output,
right?
Please watch this stimulus and tell me
on a scale what you think,
right?
Or sometimes I'm interested in the
process that you're going through as
you're doing something.
So in that case,
I will have a recorder and I will ask
for your verbal protocols.
Verbalize what you're doing as you're
doing it.
What that does is it basically yields
very rich data,
but that,
that is a real bitch to analyze because
you're not analyzing numbers on a scale
of one to seven,
you're not agonizing,
uh,
spikes of testosterone.
You actually have to go through these
huge transcripts of verbalizations.
You know what it also does,
it forces you to exist in the conscious
mind versus the reactive mind.
You are consciously engaging in a
process.
So like there's a,
there's a thing called target panic that
many,
uh,
archer's a face and a,
it's a huge issue because of nerves,
especially people that aren't used to
um,
performing under nerves.
They go into this really almost like a
tunnel vision sort of estate and they
start panicking and they just want to
shoot the shot as quick as possible.
And so they make a lot of errors that
make a lot of,
cause.
There's a lot of things involved in
shooting a bow and Arrow correctly,
bowen arrows.
It's so,
it takes so much more disciplined than
it does to shoot a rifle because of the
rifle.
Essentially what you have to do is have
your face in the proper position,
put your finger on the trigger and
squeeze.
So the shot goes off almost as a
surprise.
And if as long as you're looking through
the,
um,
the scope correctly,
you have your,
your rifle centered in or you have a,
your rifle,
um,
cited incorrectly,
it should hit where you want to aim it.
If the rifle was accurate with a bow and
Arrow,
there's so many different anchor points.
The,
you have to have the string touching the
tip of your nose.
You have to have your hand the exact
same place every time.
You have to have practice countless
times.
You have to make sure that you're
holding your shoulder,
your front shoulder,
and the right position in your hand has
to be holding the bone,
a very specific position where you're
not talking the bowl left and right.
And so when you go through your shot
process,
you go through these,
this checkpoint in your mind,
very like I tell when I do it by myself,
I say it,
I say,
okay,
and the right position,
front shoulder position,
and say it in your mind.
Say it out loud.
Okay.
I say it out loud.
And then when I go through it in a,
in a hunting scenario where obviously
you have to keep your mouth shut,
I go through that same checklist in my
mind and that sort of in many ways
prevents a lot of the panic because um,
that sort of panic exists in the
conscious mind.
You Start Thinking,
oh my God,
here we go.
Oh my God,
I can't believe it's happening.
Don't fuck this up.
Ah,
you fuck it up.
And it's because of this reaction to the
overwhelming,
unusual stimulation of the event,
of the panic sets in.
And you succumb to that unusual
pressure.
Yeah.
So the portal causes,
I'm talking about the income of two
varieties is what's called concurrent
protocols or retro spective protocols.
Concurrent protocols is where you
verbalize as you're doing the task,
the,
the benefit of that is that it's,
it's live,
it's,
it's top of mind,
right?
The downside is that sometimes by asking
a participant to verbalize,
it actually changes their cognitive
process.
Sure.
So then you might go to retrospective
protocol,
which is now tell me in details how you
did the thing.
And now the benefit there is that you
don't have that,
uh,
that,
interference.
But the downside of course,
is that you have memory loss.
You don't remember the specifics.
Or you also have people who fill in
stuff.
That's bullshit,
right?
Oh,
now the guy wants me to justify how I
went and did it.
Now let me just fill in stuff.
But that's not really what I did.
So as is true in most of these
methodological choices,
when you're making these scientific
decisions,
there is no absolute optimal strategy.
There's always pros and cons to any
methodology you use.
Yeah,
and I think there's also something that
happens to people when they do something
so many times where it becomes a
subconscious action.
Right?
And then when you ask him to verbalize
what the steps are,
oftentimes they don't know because
they've programmed it into their mind
like electricity.
If I asked you to describe in exact
detail what is the process that you tie
your shoes with?
Right?
Like which hand goes first,
which finger goes under,
where you'd be like,
um,
how do I do it?
Okay,
I take the,
but when you tie your shoes,
you just go,
Bro,
whoops.
Caught it.
Right.
You know,
you just go through this storm standard
process.
If that happens with martial artists a
lot,
there's a lot of martial artists that
have certain techniques that they've
gotten down to a science.
But then when you ask them to teach it,
you say,
okay,
what are you doing first?
Are you doing this first shot?
And they go,
Huh,
um,
I'm not sure.
And they literally don't know.
I've,
I've talked to that with certain archers
to certain artists.
I've asked them,
are you looking at the,
the site first or are you looking at the
target first?
We know when you released the Arrow,
are you looking at the target or the
site?
They don't know.
You don't know where it falls into this
sort of subconscious state where they've
made repetition.
So they've,
they've repeated the process so many
times they've made this repetition
cemented in their subconscious where
they could just just sort of go into
this Zombie state.
You know,
it's funny,
I,
I felt that recently trying to play
pickup soccer.
Ah,
it's going to speak to that authenticity
and exactly how you're saying.
So when I was a young guy,
young player who can,
you know,
accelerate past players as if it's
nothing,
it's a natural thing.
I don't think about it.
My Body reacts and if you asked me to
tell you how I shifted left and right,
I couldn't tell you now is a much older
and much heavier.
Those moves that I tried to do,
I no longer had the automatic ability.
So actually my brain was trying to
think,
oh,
I better turn right,
but be careful because my knee is a bit
weak.
And so I actually felt the difference
and the automaticity response,
Ah,
if only by virtue of being much older
and much heavier.
Right?
So there you go.
20 years ago I could have probably not
been able to tell you how I did this
today.
I could tell you how I did it because it
was a slow as a turtle.
Ah,
that's funny.
Well,
that exists in a,
in fighting for sure.
You drill these moments over and over
into your mind so that when you're
fighting,
they actually just come out
subconsciously or they come out without
conscious thought because you don't
really have the time to say,
okay,
I'm going to slip this right hand and
throw the left to the body.
The,
the,
the right high kick.
It has to sort of be an automatic
response,
right?
So you have to be able to go into this
zen state,
which is fine in these big movements.
He's explosive movements like a martial
arts thing.
But in terms of like an archery thing,
you don't want fast,
big twitching,
explosive movements to come out
automatically.
What you want is a very controlled
process.
Will you maintain very strict form and
you stay calm.
And so when that sort of a process going
over this conscious shot making process
is probably better for you.
Right.
Cool.
Are you still fighting?
No.
That's really not good for,
you know what I mean?
Even as a spotter,
Jujitsu only,
you know,
that's,
and I haven't done that in over a year.
Okay.
But it's just because of a back injury
that I've been dealing with,
but it's pretty much gone now.
But sparring as far as like kickboxing,
sparring,
I gave that up many,
many years ago.
It's just even sparring for fun.
Even just a,
even you have to like really be sure of
the person you're doing it with because
every single time you get tagged,
if you looked at your body or your brain
rather as um,
uh,
a punch card,
like say you have a hundred holes to
punch and once you punch through those
hundred holes,
you're fucked.
Right.
And you might get away with a couple of
holes.
You might get away with three or four or
five or 10 or 20.
This is the whole nfl.
Yeah,
it had been 100%,
100% and,
but it pertains to a lot of things.
And even soccer players would the head,
the heading,
which is insane,
you would never meet.
Imagine like for years,
for decades,
rather,
we had no idea that heading a ball could
have detrimental effects.
But now we're finding out that certain
soccer players who consistently headed
the ball over a long career develop all
sorts of cognitive issues with memory,
impulsiveness,
all the same sort of symptoms that I
find from fighters.
Incredible.
It's amazing because it's not a
concussion thing.
It's a sub concussive trauma thing where
you're constantly engaging that
connective tissue inside your brain to
try to stabilize the brain.
Is it swashes around inside your skull
and it starts failing and then the,
the damage of your brain moving around
inside of there starts accumulating.
Speaking of soccer and your mma stuff,
I'm triggered by,
and you're going to be interest Konan
Konan Mcgregor,
connor,
connor.
What happened?
I'm going to get a thousand.
He,
I was trying to be impressive.
Wait for the [inaudible] being nice to
me.
They're not going to be made,
but it's going to be all whatever colon
man,
conor,
conor Mcgregor,
I'm triggered by him.
Triggered because,
oh,
he's a friend of the nemesis of my top
man.
He's a friend of Ronaldo.
Oh,
the soccer players channel.
Rinaldo apparently is their buddy buddy,
Cristiano Ronaldo and Lionel Messi had
been trust that you now know who he is.
I also know that he's a tax cheat.
Motherfuckers going to jail isn't,
ain't no,
he's not going to jail.
No.
I think Jamie says he's going to,
the pokey says is going to get banked.
So Dude's going to bang them.
There is.
Wow.
By the way,
I will gentleman's in great shape.
I will ask you to look at it.
Can you put it up again?
I'm going to show you in 1985 pictures
of me with more defined.
I will show you photos.
Egos,
so showcase.
How dare you.
Godfather.
It doesn't matter.
By the way,
you live in the present right now.
You've got a one pass.
Gloria,
you had a barrel.
Let it go.
The six pack is gone.
You we get it back
though.
That's what we should do.
The Dad sad six pack project.
Yeah,
and you sort of fill me as I go through
the transformation.
I'm not going to do it.
You're going to do it on your own.
I'm busy,
Bro.
How dare you.
I'm reaching out.
Infection.
This is how you treat me.
I'm going to get you a copy of the book.
I'm gonna get you a copy of the primal
blueprint.
Yeah,
I can't.
I can't hold your hand,
man.
If you're a grown man,
you're older than me.
He called me son.
Remember you're,
you're not 50 yet.
Oh yeah.
No,
49 just turned.
Oh yeah,
that's right.
Happy Birthday.
The slide is real.
I'm 51 so I'm already,
I'm on the downside.
So when it makes it even more difficult
to lose weight,
you're more set in your ways.
Your hormone system starts Sulu and
does your metabolism slowing down?
We've got to ramp it up,
buddy.
I do.
You got to start off your day with
exercise too.
So are you,
are you currently at the same weight as
you would have been 20 years ago or no,
I'm heavier but more muscle because I've
been lifting weights with the last,
when I got into Jujitsu like really
heavily,
which was about 2000 right around the
year 2000 I started training in 96 but I
got really into it around 2000 so over
the last 16 plus years I've been lifting
way more weights,
like are really good in the lifting
weights because I realized how
significant it is a factor and also to
protect your joints.
That's a big factor too.
Just the,
the ability to uh,
defend yourself better.
You know,
I,
I do a lot of long endurance,
you know,
an hour cardio,
but I've always been terrible a lot of
ways.
How often do you do self tape?
I've been here for a month in
California,
so 30 days.
I probably did have 24 days.
Wow.
Yeah.
That's amazing.
What do you do afterwards?
Just so I'll usually do,
uh,
an hour,
either treadmill or bike or a
combination,
sometimes elliptical.
So these three are usually,
what time do you do it?
Do you do in the morning and going,
oh,
that's good.
In the morning,
but not very early.
Maybe say.
And you do an hour.
I do an hour.
That's a lot,
man.
That's really good.
It's cause I was coming on your show.
Uh,
but uh,
I usually do about an hour and now here
in California I've tried to incorporate
weight training usually back home.
I don't as I understand that I need to
do it more so.
Well I would say that weight training
definitely makes your body burn more
calories,
that's for sure.
And two for two reasons.
One,
because when you put on more muscle,
your body has more requirements for for
calories,
so it's easier for your body to burn
more fuel if you have more muscle.
The act of lifting weights is very
strenuous,
burns a lot of calories and a it also,
it's just,
it's just really good for your endocrine
system when you start lifting weights,
especially if you do things like
deadlifts or squats.
I can't do any of that stuff cause I
have three herniated disks in my back.
You do,
so I'll try with your back.
What's going not actually about 2005 we
were moving from one house to another.
I've got a huge library books and I'm
going to say this will become evident in
a second.
As you know,
book boxes are deceptive and that they
look like
they're small volume but they are
extremely heavy.
I went to pick one up and I did the
wrong emotion.
I felt my back and then after that it
would just flare up maybe once a year
and about four years ago I went down to
bend down and then I was basically
immobilized for what part of your back?
It's the left side through your lower
back.
Back there.
Three herniated this.
So I went to see a physiatrist and
here's his advice.
Never bend again.
Well those people are dipshits.
There's so many doctors.
It'll tell you don't do this and don't
do that.
I went to a doctor in 2002 because I had
a torn meniscus,
just a torn meniscus,
really simple injury for someone as a
martial artist and uh,
they told me to stop doing martial arts.
They literally told me,
you're going to be a cripple if you
start.
You don't stop doing martial arts.
I'm like,
yeah,
okay.
What the fuck?
Kind of stupid advices that I'm like,
just scope this God damn thing and let
me get outta here.
Right.
I got back on [inaudible] and
glucosamine.
I ate a lot of fish oil and I've had no
problem with that knee since then.
Like they scoped out a chunk of
Meniscus,
which is really common with people that
have extreme athletic pursuits,
whether it's soccer,
soccer,
La guys are cheering,
you know,
martial arts.
It's a big,
it's,
it's normal thing that they do.
But to have this asshole tell me to stop
doing martial arts,
I'm going to be cripple.
I've just,
I just wanted to just say,
look,
you're a fucking asshole.
Like you really have no,
no qualifications to be saying this.
Like this is foolish.
You're fixed injuries.
You can't tell me that if I don't listen
to your stupid lazy advice.
It's just such a dumb thing to say to
people be,
especially when you're talking about a
meniscus injury,
you're not talking about a severe spinal
injury where someone could become
paralyzed if they continue the same
thing that they're doing.
Now you're talking about a meniscus
tear,
right?
It's really simple.
Not only that,
they have artificial meniscus now,
now they do stem cells that actually
regenerate meniscus.
By the way,
stem cell research is another one that
those forbidden knowledge,
uh,
topics because of,
well it was way more now because they
found so many different methods of
acquiring stem cells.
But yeah,
but during the Bush administration,
I was hugely problematic and that's one
of the reasons why Europe got so far
ahead of America.
It's true.
And there's a lot of,
uh,
people that go to get certain
treatments.
They got,
they,
they had to go to other countries.
Fortunately now there's a lot of stem
cell doctors and specialists that are in
United States that are having incredible
success with injuries.
And a lot of mixed martial artists do it
right.
Um,
Demetrius mighty mouse Johnson is the
best pound for pound fighter in the
world.
Just had some stem cells shot into his
knee.
Um,
so it's,
this is a really common thing that
you're,
you,
you deal with some doctors who aren't
athletes,
don't work with athletes and then they
tell you things like,
don't ever lift something again.
That is crazy.
That is a crazy piece of conceivable.
100%.
Yes.
I'm going to show you a machine.
When we get off today,
we'll,
I'll show you in a couple of minutes
because we're gonna end soon where
there's a machine that I have in the
back called the reverse hyper and it was
created by this guy.
I've talked about this so many times,
people like not again,
but it's created by this guy named Louie
Simmons.
And Louie Simmons is this guy who runs
this very famous powerlifting gym called
Westside Barbell.
And he had a bulging disc himself and
his doctors are telling them they're
going to have to fuse your disc and you
know you're going to have to have an
operation.
He was like,
what?
And he couldn't,
as a person who is an expert in
physiology and a person who is an expert
in a,
in exercise and,
and teaching people how to get strong,
he couldn't understand why if an injury,
a compression of the disc,
cause the disc to herniate,
why couldn't a decompression of the disk
cause it to reset or to heal?
So he developed this machine that does
exactly that.
It's called the reverse hyper.
And I have one of these in the back.
So you see when he's lifting the weights
up,
it's strengthening the back.
When the weights go down,
it's actually pulling the back apart.
It's slowly decompressing the back in an
active form.
But has there been,
have there been any studies that show
that if you use this,
your herniated disc
he himself has done,
I mean no peer reviewed studies,
but athletes have used this time and
time again along with decompression.
Spinal decompression is also really
important.
Spinal decompression meaning like
hanging from your ankles,
hanging from your waist.
I have a couple of different devices in
the back that I can show you that allow
you to relax your back and yoga is also
critical.
Yoga is huge because there's a bunch of
positions in yoga where you are actively
decompressing your back.
There's one where you reach back,
you grab yourself behind the heels,
you straighten your legs out and you
literally are pulling with your arms and
you feel your back all like pop,
pop,
pop.
You're releasing tension and pressure
and you're actively stretching your
back.
So I'm walking out of here invigorated
by our chat and filled with hope and
optimism about diet,
exercise size.
You know,
me,
nothing my friend.
But I,
it's,
it's really important for people to work
on their core and their spine and
there's so many people that don't.
I have a friend of mine was just big,
strong,
powerful guy and uh,
you know,
he played football and he's done a bunch
of different things but he's never done
any like real significant core work.
And I started showing him some different
exercises like windmills and things
along those lines and he was stunned at
how weak his lower back is because so
many people don't work those muscles.
And those muscles are critical for
athletic performance,
for your ability to move and to protect
your spine from injury.
There's a lot of injuries that you can
avoid by just being strong in your core
and your column,
your spinal column and d developing
strength around the,
you know,
that whole really super sensitive and
delicate area of your back.
But decompression is real.
Um,
there's a bunch of machines that doctors
have,
and when I hurt my neck,
uh,
one of the things that I did is went to
this doctor that would,
they would have this machine.
It kind of straps you in.
It just gives you this gentle poles and
it's sort of like,
what about the upside down world?
I have the one of those two.
Yeah,
those are good.
Those are good.
But you have to learn how to really
relax your back.
A lot of people,
when they hang by their angles,
they tend to up and it sort of defeats
the purpose,
right?
You have to learn it,
you have to learn it.
And it feels weird.
Like you could feel yourself pulling
apart,
right?
But you have to relax that.
You have to allow that to happen and you
have to do it really consistently.
It has to be something you do all the
time.
It can't be something you do like once
every now and again,
like,
oh,
I'm stretching my back out because it's
going to go right back.
And also posture is significant.
It's a really important part of
[inaudible].
Good.
Yeah.
I mean,
that's why these chairs that we're
sitting in,
we're sitting in these,
um,
Ergo depot chairs and these chairs are
designed to make you sit at a good
posture.
So if you sit like this,
you'll sit with your spine in a,
in a good position,
normal chairs.
A lot of times you're back gets rounded
and you sit into them and he'd sink and
then you developed this pain like right
around your mid back or maybe perhaps
your lower back depending on the,
you know,
whatever ailments you've got these
chairs,
I sit in these fucking things for hours.
I don't have any problem.
And I think they're actually in some way
beneficial because they force a good
posture that actually,
it's actually like a static exercise.
They think about the standing a working
desk.
It's better than sitting sometimes,
you know?
Right.
But I think,
um,
these things are great.
Like,
because these things force your spinal
column to be in this correct position.
But I think the standing ones,
a lot of people have a lot of success
with that.
They also,
a lot of people have success with those
exercise balls.
You ever sit on one of those exercise
balls,
they force you to kind of exercise.
Like as you're sitting there,
you,
you have to kind of be adjust in a
posture.
Yeah.
There's also a lot of those standing
desks,
they develop these a standing surfaces
that are,
there are a surface that's very varied.
So instead of standing on this absolute
flat static,
um,
sort of a floor while you're in the same
position all the time,
instead,
it's this dynamic surface where it has
all these humps to it and you move
around on it lot like,
so you'll,
you'll like lean on the left leg,
you'll lean on the right leg if you're
seeing those things.
See if you can find one of those.
Those,
uh,
surface is standing surfaces,
for a standing chairs.
It's really interesting.
I had a complete rupture,
my achilles tendon when I was a soccer
player.
And one of the things that I had to do
in 14 months of Rehab is to stand on one
of those boards with a ball.
And you had to because just to relearn
how to move in and to adjust.
It's not,
you have to have a repaired surgically.
That's a big one.
Right.
That was,
that was finished after that.
I have one of those,
um,
in my knee,
I have a,
an Achilles tendon from a cadaver in my
knee.
Yeah.
I want to,
when you get acl surgery,
instead of replacing your acl with a
cadaver acl,
which is significantly weaker,
they take this,
the acl tendon or,
and replace it with Achilles,
which is way bigger and way stronger and
it makes your Achilles' tent where it
makes your acl rather 150% stronger than
a,
a regular one.
She goes,
I don't know if you're aware of how it
works with cadavers,
but when they replace a ligament,
what it does is essentially a acts as a
scaffolding and your body [inaudible]
this cadaver ligament around your own
cells.
So instead of it being normal size,
it becomes this fat cord that really
keeps your,
cause.
I've had both my knees blowout to acl
reconstructions.
One in each knee.
No,
that's not it.
There's other ones.
That's just the chair.
This guy's on.
It's a standing desk surface,
uh,
standing surface,
pull up,
standing surface for,
uh,
for standing desk or surface for
standing desk.
Standing desk surface for standing on.
Hmm.
I don't know.
Uh,
I bet ergo depot has it.
Well,
there's a bunch of those,
um,
different kinds of standing desks,
but moving surface for standing desk.
I don't know.
Just don't show me this way.
You're going to go fucking crazy.
But um,
I don't know.
I don't even know if it's good.
I just saw that someone developed.
So when I had my,
a ruptured Achilles tendon,
I'm the trip.
Have you ever heard somebody describe
what happens?
You actually feel as if somebody hits
you with a sledgehammer on your Achilles
tendon.
When it pops,
it feels like you were hit and you,
I mean,
you drop,
like somebody shot you after the fact.
So I had the surgery.
This was,
I was a student,
a graduate student at the time at
Cornell.
I went back to Montreal to have the
surgery.
When I,
when I went back to Cornell,
I asked my fellow soccer players what
happened,
who was the guy who tackled me,
uh,
that had hit me.
And then somebody,
nobody hits you.
You just dropped by herself.
And then I had done,
you know,
I found out that that's what everybody
feels like an explosion.
It's an explosion.
But the way your body feels it,
it's as if there was an impact.
Someone just clobbered the back of my
leg.
Nobody was around.
I just dropped.
That totally makes sense.
It's amazing how fragile we are.
It's incredible.
People are so,
it was like the human body that's
similar.
That's one of them.
That's a,
that's a standing board.
This one is a surface is a surface you
stand on and it's just an uneven surface
that has many different layers to it and
many different,
um,
so now it's Sunday at either whatever,
there's a bunch of them I'm sure.
But you know,
there's all these different solutions
that people try to come up with for the
real problem,
which is not sitting in the proper
posture at a,
at a chair.
And I sit in this desk doing these
podcasts for like yesterday I did nine
hours.
Wow.
Yeah.
And when I'm doing that,
I'm just sitting like this and my back
doesn't hurt it.
She didn't feel that your mental acuity
is as strong going into podcast number
three as it was in number one or yeah,
it's only nine hours.
It's not that big a deal as long as
you're eating food.
And I asked this is because,
you know,
earlier in my teaching career,
I could do back to back lectures,
each one being three hours and it was no
problem.
Now I can't do it,
not because of mental acuity problems,
but because when I send me back back
starts hurting by about hour for,
I can't do it.
Well let's wrap this up and I'm gonna,
I'm gonna show you all this stuff,
equipment,
because you should really invest in this
stuff.
So it'll make a big difference in your,
your,
the health of your back.
Because it's one thing we really didn't,
they just don't,
they don't look into enough.
And the only time they look into it is
when they're already injured.
Right.
And,
uh,
I really wish people would pay way more
attention.
And I wish I had known this before I got
injured.
I got injured from martial arts because
just the nature of Jujitsu and
wrestling.
There's a lot of people that I get in.
I know a lot of guys that have had disc
replacements and all sorts of fusions
and stuff and it's just the brutal
nature of,
of the sport.
But,
um,
the,
I think some of that at least can be
prevented with proper maintenance and
proper spine health.
Okay.
Decompression stretching.
I look forward to do yoga at all.
I don't,
you should do it.
I,
you know,
I do stretching,
but I do it in exactly the way that you
said I shouldn't,
which is very sporadic and yeah,
don't do that.
He got,
it's kind of a daily thing,
man.
It's gotta be one of those things like
brushing your teeth,
right?
You write down,
you do it,
you get it out of the way.
Just force yourself.
To me,
there's certain things that I just can't
go through a week without doing,
you know?
And I don't allow myself because I know
that there's just,
it's easy to just fuck off and not do it
right.
It's easy to just be lazy,
but when you do that,
you,
you do your body a disservice.
You quick final anecdote before we end,
I know we have to end just to point to
your incredible reach.
So I'm,
you know,
I'm recognized on the street reasonably
off.
We usually,
it's because of the visual.
Beautiful.
Beautiful,
right?
This is what happened about two weeks
ago.
I think I might've even tattooed you on
twitter about it,
but you're probably going to read it.
I'm being served by a waiter slash bus
boy at a place in,
uh,
Venice beach.
And the gentleman comes up to me and
says,
excuse me,
are you?
I said,
yes.
He goes,
Oh,
I recognized you by your voice because I
listened to Joe Rogan's podcast.
So this is the first time that I was
recognized auditorily,
not visually.
That's a pretty astute listener.
That's a guy who really listens to Joe
Rogan.
But I mean,
I,
I say that story simply to point to
apparently how infinite you'll reaches.
That's pretty crazy.
Or I have a very unique,
very sexy,
and they definitely have that.
You definitely have that.
But I also think that guy is probably
pretty exceptional in his ability to
pick up voice has amazing.
Yeah.
Because your voice is,
it's,
uh,
it's distinctive,
but not so much.
Right.
Exactly.
Yeah.
Well,
listen,
man,
it's always a pleasure having you and
somewhat have an open invitation.
Of course.
Anytime you're in town,
and I really do hope you wind up moving
here.
Thank you buddy.
Fuck those winters up there,
buddy.
Love you,
man.
I love you too,
brother.
Thank you.
All right folks.
We'll be back at five o'clock and about
40 minutes with Josh apps.
See?
Yeah,
yeah.