Have you had him on wheeler?
Oh No.
Are we don't had about punchdrunk.
You can't tell everybody.
A lot of people that don't get mad when
they find him in the middle.
He goes,
this ben talking.
He might be going crazy,
but I know that guy.
Yeah,
I know both of them.
The different dudes
podcast is wheeler,
like he's different than when he came on
the podcast as the other fella.
He's been doing these promos where he
does voice over like a famous person,
so it's like garth brooks talking talks
over.
He's like,
Hey,
it's me.
Got Me my private jet.
I hate regular people like this.
I love with my instagram.
Tommy,
you showed me the video.
He.
Garth brooks here.
I won't tell you about my new favorite
records.
Hold whole.
We'll buy.
We'll walk the junior.
I love blacks in here on my private jet.
I don't fly commercial anymore.
There's always a bunch of dumb crackers.
Who will want my autograph thing?
Little place with them.
I liked being by myself and got enough
dick to go round and have a look at my
dick.
So I'll see you guys later.
I'm Clark books on set.
Looking at the bottom,
it says it's been retweeted by Garth
Brooks.
No photoshop him.
Re tweeting from Garcia.
Fake Shit with his face was like,
this is a call to garth brooks.
This is,
this is a call to find out how cool you
are.
You should retweet,
retweet that shit out on instagram.
Garth.
That shit's hilarious.
And garth Brooks Fan.
I don't give a fuck what anybody says,
but that uh,
friends in low places with that comes
on.
You don't get excited.
No Man.
It's all right.
It's fine.
Bar Jam.
I listened to a country boy can survive.
I'll get fired up for that.
Complete books.
I'm making a point about that song.
That's a killer song.
Fuck yeah,
it is like riding a horse.
Riding Cowboy.
I want to fucking be in a pickup to
drink beer.
I want to have a dip in.
I want to shoot somebody.
Hank Williams Jr.
Motherfucker.
Yeah.
That song is fantastic.
That's w.
That was Matt hughes walkout song.
Yeah,
that's right.
Yeah.
I had a fight for that country board
cancer by a great song.
That's a great walkout song too.
That might be the best walkout town song
ever.
Oh no,
it's raining men.
Me if I ever.
But you know what?
Making girls might be the best when it
comes out to nikki.
That might be the best know.
That's fucking because that one's not
taken seriously.
LegitimatelY hilarious that he comes out
to that and he's a beautiful man.
Did he wear weird shiT?
Like different colors,
like pink stuff,
like as a,
making a,
someone did write,
but I went to a fight once where some
dude came out like in a,
in a tutu or some shit and yeah,
some.
So he was wearing like something girly
and everybody was like,
he better with shit.
Something like,
I don't know,
like a skirt or something.
And they walked up and down the aisle,
whatever.
Well there was one dude who fought in k,
one who was a famous crossdresser in
Japan and it was a bad motherfucker.
He wasn't like necessarily a constant
cross dresser,
but occasionally he would dress up like
a school girl.
Yeah,
iT was cool.
What is this?
He,
this dude beat the fuck out of some
people who like underestimated him
dressed up like a school girl sees me to
find that story.
I remember it was ballsy was Japan.
They go crazy.
He did some weird shit.
Were dressed up like a female and I'm a
character or something.
I can't really remember entirely how the
story went down,
but I remember he could fight and it was
super confusing for people because he
was knocking dudes dead and you know,
in the part time we dress up like a
school girl fight girl outfit.
JusT do that.
I'm like,
come out with pigtails and shit.
Fuck soMebody's world up and then lick
your lollipop on tHe way out.
The fucking brutus the barber beefcake
shoW.
That would be some next level mind game
shit like your past all the aggreSsion.
That's nonsense.
I'm trying to.
I'm a girl.
I'm gonna fuck You up,
but I'm going to pretend I'm a girl up
until the moment I fuck you up.
Yeah,
that's,
that's the polar opposite of what other
dudes go.
If you could pull that off,
you'd be so relaxed in a fight.
If You could figure out how to act like
a girl in front of a dude was ready to
beat the fuck out of the closet.
Queeny gay In the ufc,
but it was super well trained.
That'd be awesome.
That will be best to totally post fight
interviews would be amazing.
Amazing.
Yeah.
It's completely biased there that it's
completely possible.
Yeah.
Completely putting a call out to the
universe right now.
We just gotta you just gotta get a super
clean.
Know some like queen who's built like
check Congo.
fuck people up.
Smash people and get them a.
This is the japanese guy.
Yeah.
Umbrella.
Ufc 94.
Oh no,
no.
This is a.
Isn't this?
Oh no.
Just the one you saw tom.
No,
no,
no.
Yeah,
yeah.
This is the.
A ufc fight where he came and translated
girl.
Yeah.
Did a choreographed.
Great.
Just the one you're thinking of.
Are you thinking about the japanese?
The japanese one,
but this one I remember now.
He did a choreographed dance.
I forgot about this.
Jamie.
This is a strong pole.
Strong selection was good,
right?
Dude,
I don't remember this at all.
Did he win this fight?
I hope so.
I don't remember who gono fought weight.
Well,
if you just go further fan video.
Oh,
it's a family day.
hockey hero.
gono.
Yeah.
He was like,
uh,
and I think he was in judo.
He was definitely a japanese star.
You a lot of those guys,
by the time they came to the United
States,
they already had been in so many words.
They just weren't the same anymore.
Like,
go me,
go.
Me wasn'T the same anymore.
Saccharide wasn't the same anymore.
Yeah.
Look at this.
Oh my god.
So good move,
man.
Yeah,
too good move.
I'd like to be one of the side bitches.
Yeah,
I think there were about trying to.
Oh yeah.
Probably his fight team or something
probably.
Oh
yeah,
that's what I was saying at the time of
that fight a goal.
No,
let's go.
no,
no.
I like to relax.
He's biting over here.
Oh yeah,
I know that guy.
It's like,
what?
It's probably seriously a good idea.
It man.
You got to take your dress off,
take your heels off.
He foughT john fitch.
I don't.
I do not think he won.
I think he got beat down super long
winning streak right around the.
Yup.
I think that was before john gsp for the
title.
I think he tied the record for most wins
and they had to give him a title shot
and like,
oh,
we got.
That's ridiculous.
He's happy when he's fighting on that
card.
Is it john fitch came across this other
entrance.
Oh,
did a wonder what year this was?
Trying to remember when the ufc brought
back 155 pound title because for a long
time 1:17
was the lightest weight you could fly.
You got to give the student credit for
his entrance is a lot of thought put
into this.
He obviously does a lot of work behind
me and miller had a great one and once
he had like a bunch of dancers behind
him and shit.
He had a whole choreographed entrance
when he fought in pride.
Yeah,
I liked that,
but he always had ridiculous entrances.
I dunno.
What was that with his ski mask and what
was that?
Anybody stealing money?
Anybody who ever questioned whether or
not mayhem was a good fighter because
you know,
may have had some hard times and getting
a little nutty lately.
Yeah.
But if yOu go back to one mayhem fought
sakharov No,
not soccer.
Soccer.
Raba in pride.
Dude.
He smashed sakharova.
Smashed it,
went right through them and submitted
them.
Really?
Woo.
Yeah,
pull it up jimmy.
See if you can find it.
It's a this qualification mayhem in the
ufc or what?
Pride and pride.
Did he lose one by disqualification?
Boy,
I don't remember that diddy.
I don't know.
I didn't see it.
It was like on this road,
this is his dream and oh,
this was dream.
This wasn't the pride.
That's great.
Schoolgirl outfit.
Come on.
How do you not love this?
It's awesoMe.
No ma'am.
He's had some tough tImes,
but he's always been cool to me.
I like that guy.
I see him.
He comes out to my shows when I do
urban.
He's a good man.
He's a great guy.
I mean,
he's got some problems and you know,
he was always,
he was always a extraordinarily nutty
dude.
You know,
he did the mtv show for awhIle,
by the way.
I ended up binge watching that one day
and watching dudes.
Fuck,
I don't know how to fight.
You know what?
I remember one time when we were in
Australia for fights years ago,
a rampage was there and I guess those
two are good friends.
So I was going from like different areas
in like this mini group with rampage
patient.
Every time somebody wanted a picture
with him,
they put their arm around his shoulder
at any time he would throw their arm
off,
get your fucking arm off and were like,
okay.
Then they'd Be like scared for their
picture.
Like,
huh?
Like that.
So get your fucking horrible.
That was rapid.
It was rampant.
People pinch my nipples and pictures
with me pages and so I'm sitting like,
so
witnessed that like 10 times.
And then we moved to some bar somewhere
and it's a,
you know,
there's like,
I don't know if it's like roped off
people over here.
There's a lot of people in the place,
but it's like a small group like this
and brand pages here and mayhem comes up
and I don't know that they know each.
I don't know the relationship and he
immediately grabs him by the throat
like,
I'm gonna fucking kill you.
But the for the,
for a split second,
I saw all this just split like violence
come into random eyes.
Like he was about to fucking murder
someone and then I saw it disappear.
He saw him.
He was like crazy as well,
but like for a quick second,
he turned like just to break them in
half and I was like,
that was more terrifying than any fight
I'd
seen.
Rampage is a beast.
Yeah,
shoulders.
That head is too.
He hits so hard.
Rampage had some epic fights in prior to
before we ever even came to the ufc.
He has the all time,
greatest slam knockout of all time,
greatest in the triangle and the
triangle smashes them down to the
ground.
What the fuck was the guy's name?
But he fought very good.
A raMpage was in a triangle.
Ricardo arona stood up.
He still had his legs around him.
He just picked him up and then.
Yeah,
this is like,
yeah,
this is the dude went for the triangle,
but he was elevated and like watch,
go find the video.
In the video he went for the triangle
and rampage elevated like he lifted him
up and the dude held onto the triangle,
which you just can't do.
You gotta you gotta let it go at this
point.
See what he's up like that you gotta let
go of the slam.
Greatest slam kale ever in the history
of sport.
And he had him look at this.
It's like a pillow glam to it looks like
he headbutted his face.
He did and he actually got his eyebrow
cut.
I mean this dude was dead on the way
down.
Watch.
Let go right there.
Yeah.
I mean he just got fucking k.
Oh,
did,
did.
They did.
This is the worst time I've ever seen in
my life at all.
My years of watching fights.
Yeah.
I've never seen.
Never seen anything more brutal,
man.
I would love to see him do that.
The bird,
like just.
I'm just to see it just to say it.
Yeah.
I can't take that kind of impact,
man.
No,
no,
no.
I was never the same.
no more tickets.
Man was never the same after.
Ella never run.
It wasn't like a serious contender
before that fight.
They'd send me once in the,
uh,
in that,
in that gym that was downtown.
They have a little article on one of the
teacher companies the tap out place.
the oNe that anderson's manager.
Oh yay.
Black house.
Yeah.
And he was like,
I'm going to slam.
Looks like a light one was out for a
long time.
You were knocked ouT.
I mean,
like I couldn't move.
Right?
Oh really?
Pick you up.
He just,
he's just a light.
Like,
yeah,
you got to learn how to fall before you
do that.
I don't know.
I like not having not to.
You got to kind of,
as you going back,
you kind of like relax and kind of slap
the mat to dissipate some of the energy
for everyone's judo guys that role.
And as they roll them back,
they slap the mat.
It's like a big loud as shit.
Yeah,
it literally helps relieve some of the
energy of you hitting the ground because
also like relaxing,
knowing how to roll.
Did iT save my ass when I crashed a
bike?
I was doing this scene,
this Kevin James movie.
I haven't ridden a bike since I was a
kid.
I don't know how to ride bikes anymore
and in this scene me and Kevin James
chasing each other and I have to.
I'm whipping him with this,
this antenna or something like that got
flagged and as I'm hitting them with
this stick with the flag,
I hit the brakes,
I hit the front brake.
It's my left hand.
I go over the top.
I totally did.
I did it like three times.
I,
there's a,
yeah,
it was such a dick move and kevin and I
have known each other since we were like
super early 20 so it was like really
fun.
Silly.
Like
kevin likes shit like that.
Like will you slip like you don't get
good on the bike.
Anyway,
I crashed hardcore.
There's like there's like a loop real.
If you could see me flying off the bike.
It was supposed to have a crest on the
front break.
Yay.
If you press it,
the front brake,
he's supposed to break with the rear.
not supposed to break with the front,
but I'm holding the handle bar with my
left side and I'm hitting him like this
and I just hit that fucking thing.
Go over the top.
But then you brace yourself for the
fall.
But because I'm,
you know,
used to grappling and rolling around a
lot.
I was fine.
Just I just wiped out one time.
We went all the way over and I had to
catch myself on my hands.
I went over the top.
I was Like,
ooh,
this one might break some shit.
So you kept falling time.
Fucking times men.
Yeah,
it felt like three times.
Oh my god.
That was the bad one show.
Yeah.
You come right up a pavement.
Shit man.
Yeah,
dude.
As a couple of them,
that was the only one.
One of them I went in,
I flew off to the left and rolled in
this grass hillside.
I like wiped hard.
That wasn't what they wanted to abuse in
in the movie because they were going to.
Yeah.
Instead of having a stunt guy,
they had a stunt guy push in and he was
going to fly over the handlebars,
but I just fucked it up in my head
going,
how am I going to fucking stop?
That stunk.
I was bad ass.
Actually.
He did a scene with a.
He took one of those bikes.
He actually knew how to ride and he
jumped and entire flight of stairs.
That leads down to the boston common.
They set up a ramp and this dude comes
whipping around the corner under.
Those are nuts,
man.
God damn crazy.
Fuck up there.
You're breaking shit.
Yeah.
Like you're going to break break shit
regularly,
man.
their whole bodies that just crushed
dude.
I gotta break some shit.
I was going like three miles an hour or
something.
If you're flying.
There's another one.
See I'm trying to.
Oh,
you're really doing that.
Really beaten him.
But that's the one that I Did and
nothing happened.
what happened?
But um,
yeah man.
Fuck all that.
Those guys are crazy.
Yeah.
No,
I don't want any part of that,
those mountain bike dudes that do those.
You ever seen those videos?
They put on a gopro on their helmet and
where the fuck out there on the tip of a
mountain and there's death to the right
depth to the left.
Oh yeah.
Oh my gosh.
So many.
Did you get your thrill from that?
What the fuck?
Just watching it.
I get fucking excited.
I mean I Love to do that shit.
Bombing the hill on a skateboard.
You ever done that?
Go straight down.
Just when I was nominated.
I've done it recently.
There was a moment where you're like out
of control.
This is stop.
Stop it.
It's called thrill hill right by my
house.
So I have a,
I have a um,
a stick I paddleboard and nobody's
called thrill hill is what's,
how do you slow yourself down on a
skateboard?
Jump off it and run longboard no,
no.
This is all my short board during our
regular skateboard because I liked the
wheels better.
So I have my stick and I'm with the
girls were riding back from a party and
I go,
hey,
let's bomb through hill.
And they're like,
okay,
it's an open street.
Uh,
yeah,
it's right by their school.
And so it's back.
It's back.
It's like,
you know what,
if I'm not going this fast,
yeah,
this is alright.
How do you slow it down out?
We didn't.
How do you slow one of these things down
and push these guys do it sideways.
They go sideways when you do a,
I jump off and start running.
Or in this case I keep going too fast.
That's what happened to me.
And I.
Did you eat shit?
Uh,
I went for lying.
I was dragging my because I didn't
realize how big,
how steep it was because it's not this
deep.
Oh my god.
But it's still sleeps.
It's still steep enough where.
Wait,
hold on one second.
You know,
they do this on open roads,
like when cars are driving on the roads,
this kid is a wizard right here.
This kid is a wizard,
has got gloves that.
But listening or watching,
this guy was wiz down this hill,
a masterfully on a skateboard.
What's his name got blocks in is what
does it say?
What does this shows trucks.
So cal downhill longboarding fucking.
Hey,
this guy's a wizard.
Yeah,
that looks awesome.
But one of the reasons why looks sharp.
Solar rays,
his name sean woolery,
powerful sean,
Missouri.
One of the reasons why it's so awesome
is because the consequences of fucking
up.
So there's a split second where you're
going with.
and by the way,
this hill is nothing but your girls did
this on their bikes.
Totally do.
I totally put on a skateboard.
I just assumed I do it on the bike all
the time and it's not that aggressive.
And I start going down this hill and I
start picking up speed and I realized,
oh I,
I just signed a contract that I can't
renegotiate.
I'm going to.
And I might stick with me.
I start dragging my stick and I'm just
reading this stick and I'm.
And then I'm like,
oh my god,
I've got to fucking cause.
By the way,
when I do it,
I usually go ahead of them and check the
car,
the cross street to make sure there's no
cars,
but I'm like,
oh fuck,
I didn't think this through.
So I jumped off and ran,
blew out a flip flop,
ran out,
no shirt.
No,
it's great.
This fucking lit myself up.
Oh my god.
Flip flop,
busted one.
I bought a glue out the toe of a flip
flop,
but luckily they got six pairs of flip
flops because I love him so much and
they just ran out of it.
I ran out of blue out a.
Yeah,
what?
Barefoot.
And I was like,
oh.
And by the way,
the rest of the.
Obviously the rest of the trip home,
one flip flop sticks.
Reddit is obviously all uphill,
so I'm just like,
fucking why did I think you know,
when you're a kid you do that.
I did much steeper as a kid,
but it's just,
you didn't think it through,
man.
The problem is that the risk is so
fucking monumental.
The risk is like end of,
oh,
where did you get his trailer?
He gets off perfectly.
Yeah,
that's what you have to jump off and run
off it.
God damn,
that was nasty.
You when you get out of control like
bottles too.
She got wiped.
The only thing worse than only thing.
Worse than speed wobbles.
His whiskey throttle.
Like when it comes to speed,
you know,
whiskey throttled list,
whiskey throttles when you punch it and
you get scared and your natural reaction
is to hold it punched.
That's your natural reaction.
I get that.
I do that all the time.
We get you want to like punch it and
break,
but there's just like,
wait,
what am I pressing on?
and you jusT going faster.
Yeah.
You're like,
why am I stopping not stopping.
I'm going like,
we have this,
we did this.
We took snowmobiles into a lake one time
and we this guy nacho.
And he was the first guy to do it and
all they're saying is when you turn lean
a certain way and then you'll go the
other way.
And so,
okay,
we've,
none of us have done this.
They're like,
but you got to keep it fast and he
punches it on the lake and whiskey
throttles it all the way across the
lake,
into a fucking tree.
Dislocates his shoulder.
This is the guy showing you good.
This is the guy who's taking on a trip
of a lifetime trip flip dislocates.
his shoulder was our first activity
and he was like,
I couldn't let go.
I don't like.
It's a whiskey bottle.
It's like more like a mental panic panic
with cars too.
They say they think they're hitting the
gas or the brake rather than the gas,
like eddie griffin and then that
ferrari,
but he just didn't know how to drive.
That was a million dollar car.
Yeah,
it was like a,
like a ferrari or ends over toes and
enzo took it right out and smashed it
into a wall in a private club.
CloSed.
I did not know how to drive it at all
and they got out.
I was like,
fuck man.
wasn't good.
No speed wobbles in East Timor.
Going down a highway and like a big,
a really bad road for awhile and then I
got some good road.
I was like,
oh yeah,
I'm going to crank this.
And someone like a moped probably 80
kilometers an hour.
Oh,
that's pretty fast.
Yeah.
And then hitting a bump and another one
and the garment.
Fuck,
fuck them down.
And then it was just like,
I don't know how I managed to save it,
but it was like that lady.
When you start the heavy wobbles,
but you gotta control your,
you overcompensate every shift in until
you're done.
Done.
Yep.
I've,
uh,
I think it always think motorcycle
riding motorcycles is so much fucking
fun because it really allows you to feel
truly vulnerable.
Like I go in 70 miles per hour on the
interstate in a fucking motorcycle is.
There's no sensation.
I mean there's no comparable sensation.
Like you can stick your hand out a
window,
but it's nothing compared to like
fucking flying car flies by you and
you're like,
ah,
I'd erase thunderstorm home,
uh,
in,
at home.
But where we were staying,
I had to race a thunderstorm so we get
there and lightening start striking like
10 miles away from us.
And they were like,
we should probably go,
this is coming on quick.
And so we're flying,
trying to race a thunderstorm home
through,
uh,
through crow nation.
And I think in Montana,
dude.
Fucking flying down to open it up there,
man.
Oh,
it was,
it was pretty.
Uh,
I wish I could ride a motorcycle.
I liked that.
I would love to do that on sunday
mornings I think.
Yeah,
like a harley.
You have away mountain road somewhere.
People drive slow.
Not here.
Like go and do it here,
man.
Lonzo bowden rides motorcycle
everywhere.
He's a bad motherfucker.
He's weaving between cars.
Like thoSe guys set a ride.
he knows how to ride.
He said a few of them.
Yeah.
He Sent one of those honda vtech things.
I think that's what it was called.
He has that bmw,
like all world,
all terrain bike now.
Like the ones that you see people
really?
Yeah,
like a crazy bmw motorcycle.
They do like the,
the have a competition,
whatever the top competition is for
those guys off road.
I think he has that bike.
He used to have this bike,
alonzo's garage baffle.
Lonza bowden.
it's got a bunch of motorcycles.
No kids balling.
Keeps it all legit rides tracks.
Yeah.
Well he had this,
uh,
he's got a bunch of trIumphs and shit,
but he had this thing that might be a
few years back.
That was a yamaha,
I think it was called the v max and it
was this big giant cruiser thing.
See if you could find that because this
crazy motorcycle that he had,
it's like this stupid,
powerful,
really big.
Is it honda v dot?
No,
not honda.
Yamaha.
V max.
I think I know you're talking about.
I think doc from the date and funny bone
had one.
I might've been,
I might've even saying the name wrong.
Is that the right name?
Bowden?
Yeah.
No,
that's telling the boden,
but I mean no fucking motorcycle was
just,
I don't know shit about motorcycles.
Like if it was a car I'd be able to
remember.
It is.
It a yamaha,
something like that.
It's some jApanese bike,
but it was a giant cruiser and it had
this enormous engine is fucking thing
was huge.
It was really wide and alonzo had one
and I was like,
whoa dude,
you're driving some tron machine.
That's a scary,
a twitch muscle in your brain to allow
like I know you.
What's your car,
tommy?
That porsche thing,
like we just got a,
just a bmw the other day.
Just a fine model.
Five 45,
47 series.
Not like a tricked out one.
Not a sport edition,
just like a sedan,
but it's fast as fucking shit dude.
The regular bmw is like a regular three
series.
Bmw is a better handling sports car than
anything of like 30 years ago for sure.
By far.
So regular one without any
modifications.
Stock dude.
I find myself putting it in sport mode
and fucking following and going like.
And you told me you were like,
you have no idea.
I got from oxnard to la and 30 minutes
really fly man.
That's it.
what is that thing called flow?
The thing is so big,
it's hard.
Does it say it's.
You've got to find out what the fuck
that thing is called because there's a.
There's an overhead of them that's even
more preposterous.
What do you mean overhead?
The overhead view.
The thing is like this wide,
like I'm not exaggerating.
It's like literally wider than my body.
The side of the motorcycle.
That's enormous.
That looks nuts.
It's essentially like this enormous
engine on this super wide heavy cruising
motorcycle that just has stupendous
power.
I drove one of those indian,
a indian judges,
not judge indian chiefs.
The big fucking bags and the steering
wheel's out here.
I was flying through the talladega
national forest.
Just the beginning of all of them
listening to lynyrd skynyrd,
all my headset's just going,
man.
Where's the whiskey?
A little bit of a buzz and doing that
would be perfect.
If you could trust everybody to keep
their shit together,
it would be awesome.
Ride a motorcycle,
but you can't.
Is that?
It is.
Not it.
That's not the same bike.
You see the pipes are different.
That's it.
See how it has these massive pipes.
See that thing,
that thing is gigantic and it's a huge
three cylinder engine.
By the way,
those things get fucking hot.
A shit because you have an engine in
between your legs.
Time.
I drove to burns first time I rode when
I was like,
I think it's on.
I think I'm.
I'm don't have something unlocked
because it's hottest fucking.
That's the bike rack it three.
Is that it?
Yeah.
800 plus pound.
Super heavyweight to triumph rocket
three.
Oh,
is that it?
So that's not the same one as the other
one or is it?
No,
that's different.
That's different.
That's the honda or yamaha?
It says child does it.
Let's solid top.
Right.
You're right.
It does.
All right.
I'm wrong because another one.
See if you can google honda v.
Max told me to text because now I'm
alone.
Yeah,
text.
Alonzo looks.
He looks.
He looks different.
Is that it?
Let me give to give me an image on that
thing.
Was that it?
Yamaha.
V max.
I think that's it.
That's pretty wild,
man.
I'm so bad and I can Just call them real
quick.
We can find out right now.
I think,
yeah,
please do column because this is getting
boring for people just to try to figure
out what the board of the odds that
alonzo the same number from when I got
it come up.
Be alonzo mourning sounds like a fair
deal amongst those.
The worst voicemail message I've ever
heard in my life.
How long it was bird.
I'm with joe.
Joe has a question about the bike.
You have hay a lot until used to have
some crazy.
It was at a yamaha v max.
Am I correct?
Is that a crazy bike?
You had some.
You had some crazy large touring,
super powerful japanese bike or maybe my
memory's shit from all the years of
marijuana.
call us back.
It might've just been his dick in my
bathroom.
Like tHat's a big motorcycle.
Motorcycle spirit and fire.
I could get into sports,
car shit.
Motorcycles.
I could.
Yeah,
I could get into these things for sure.
I rode a bicycle around.
I don't think I'm wrong within.
I think I'm conflating this with another
bike.
I think the other bike was it was it
even crazier?
Biked in this.
I think this town is terrifying to ride
those in the.
It was some big ass touring bike.
I think everybody who drives member and
it was like,
it's just crazy with people,
especially with his weed,
smoking in cars,
people like they'll just cut you off a
fucking and all.
They see people doing this.
Oh yeah.
I constantly see people staring at their
phone.
When you're on a bike,
you see it more clear.
You have no idea.
You see like fucking three things ahead
of you going like,
this motherfucker's not looking.
They're not looking.
God dammit.
They're going to pull out.
Yeah,
it is.
It is.
And I think,
and um,
I'll say this,
I'm a very limited motorcycle driver,
rider obviously,
but like I think that's what makes it
enjoyable because you're truly in the
moment,
you,
you're forced to live in the moment.
You don't think about bills are more.
Yeah,
like fucking percentage deals.
You're like fucking.
And that's why I want one.
I want to take it up through the canyons
out to malibu,
malibu to the ne neptune's nest.
And then taking home.
I'm like a sunday morning when
everyone's asleep except the drunks that
are just coming home on adderall co dot.
You know what else?
Shit decision your phone,
you're going to feel that clarity.
Ninety days sober,
which we got to come on up.
Let's.
Well,
let's talk about this shit already.
Please.
cat crack that nut to crack a joke and
we make you a cocktail.
sure.
Most certainly.
I would like to hear what you fellows
have been thinking.
Oh,
well,
we've had a lot of big ideas.
I think some of us were speaking big
when the,
that's a quote easy.
She said,
well,
it's the longest you've ever gone
without drinking hours.
Well,
I,
I did,
uh,
13 years.
One time.
what was probably the longest I've ever
done six months when I went,
when I met leanne,
why did you go six months?
Because I wanted to,
if I could do it.
And uh,
I did six months and then we were in
Italy and it was snowing and venice and
we were having dinner and I said,
this is fucking stupid.
I want to,
I want to have a cocktail.
I want carpet.
Damn.
I want to be impulsive right now.
And so I.
Leanne looked at me and she's like,
you don't have a drinking problem.
Just have some wine and let's go walk
around.
St regret staying back moment.
Do you want his scotch and soda?
I'll have scotch.
There you go.
Here.
Let's take this one.
All right.
Um,
we use an ice.
Do you drink it with ice or not?
Oh,
look at you.
You fucking Russell Peters.
Travel.
That's it.
No,
that's an idiot.
It looked like scotch.
I said for a second.
It looked like it.
Dude.
I might be making up a fucking crazy
motorcycle in my head.
I don't think I am though.
I think there was some weird cruising
motorcycle that alonzo had.
Dammit.
It's driving me
fucking nuts.
But yeah,
I,
I did six months and then I started
drinking again.
It's,
I think it's good to reset your clock
the last six months.
It's like a reset button.
So that time you did six months.
Have you ever done anything comparable?
Sense?
Yeah,
I've done.
I do.
I can do like a 17,
17 day chunk,
but then the road starts back up.
That's the most I can be off the road.
It's a visual on the road,
on the road.
I got to be dead honest With you.
Like I remember tom being likes jogging.
It's got to be totally honest talking
about being habitual.
Um,
so,
uh,
I remember tom one time,
I was like,
yeah,
I went out with the staff and he's like,
do you drink every night on the road?
And I was like,
yeaH,
what do you do?
And he was like,
I go to bed.
Not that.
I was like,
wait,
how do you do that?
Because it's really,
it is difficult for me to go back to a
hotel room on the road and just sit
there and be like,
my night's done.
I'm done.
Thinking,
yeah,
you know what man,
I'm going to like these.
I write,
I write on stage,
I'm tall.
I feel like you guys are all doing much
bigger venues than me.
So I'm doing more shows.
I do not wanna hear myself fucking talk
or think of anything.
That's a perfect time to show him your
wife because that's the exact right time
for it.
If you were going to do that,
like you can just go over some
ideas in your head and it seems like
once you get into it,
it's fun.
That's the thing about writing.
This is a weird,
weird thing where writing kind of tries
to.
It's like your brain starts thinking of
it as this horrible task,
like you have to clean out a latrine or
something.
Your brain starts looking at it like,
oh my god,
I can't believe I have to do this,
but if you could just get past that once
you're actually writing.
It's really fun.
There's some weird psychological shit
going on with resistance to writing.
hold on just how much.
Yeah,
I've written the argue.
Well,
no,
I mean just this idea I've written my
next hour.
What I'm working on now is finding out,
so like my majority of writing I do now
is how do I connect things that are
good,
that don't have a connection and how do
I like a.
How do I close the story?
I'm obsessing with how you end a good
story and so I'm working.
I'm not writing new material for the
next hour.
I'm writing
is our.
You don't have to write anything,
but if you want to write,
you should just write like one of the
beautiful things about writing is that
if you don't have a guideline and you
just have an idea and you just let that
idea starts spilling out of your head,
shit will come out that you didn't
expect and that shit can become more.
But if you don't sit down and do that,
then it doesn't happen.
You'll have some things that'll happen.
Sometimes you'll have some things
that'll happen with friends.
There's some things that'll happen on
stage.
There's some things that'll happen with
the things that won't happen to the
things that happen when you're sitting
in front of that computer because that
is individual time focused only on the
idea.
Not thinking about killing with a crowd,
not thinking about,
you know,
making sure that you know,
the,
you know,
the show closes well and ends with all
the bullshit that goes on your head when
you're actually doing a bit or when you
actually performing a set,
when you sit there alone with a pad or a
computer or whatever the fuck you do to.
Right.
Or even if you just wanted,
like to do an a tape recorder,
you're thinking about all these ideas in
a way that you're not going to do any
other way.
So if you don't do it,
I mean you can definitely get by not
doing it.
I went by on not doing it for a long
time,
but there's a big difference in my act
between when I do it and when I don't do
it.
But I mean I obviously I write because I
have a new hour that I'm taping in
february so I do right.
Do right.
like to sit down.
I do not want.
I wrote a book like that and it was
taxing on me.
Like when I wrote my book,
sitting down every day at the computer
and just typing out an idea,
what I do is I get on the treadmill,
I have a pad on there and I will think
through an a story or I'll think through
a joke and then I'll and then I'll.
It's horrible to read and then I'll take
those beats and I'll move them over to
my book and then I'll
well be in any way you're doing it is
great.
I mean you don't have to do it in a way
that you have to sit in front of a
computer,
have to sit in front of a pat.
I said,
if you want to record it,
you can just record it by talking into
it.
I'll never lose anything you're doing.
The idea is just working and thinking
about whatever you're doing and
recording it the best way possible.
For me,
the best way possible seems to be a
combination of having my phone right
there with the notes feature on with the
voice,
a voice activated,
a voice,
whatever it is.
DetectIng,
translating.
I have that nearby.
Just in case.
A real quick,
when it comes into my head,
I gotta get it down because my typing is
not the best.
It's pretty good,
but I don't want to miss a beat of how
I'm saying something.
So if I say something into a text or
maybe if it's like really important to
say it with a certain tone,
I'll say it into the um,
the memo,
the voice memo thing.
What's that?
When you're listening to right back was
trying to work it into a chunk that you
do on stage.
Wow.
What I do in terms of like getting the
segways or whatever is a try to do the
bits in different orders as much as I
can.
And then you know,
instead of opening with the same thing,
what you're open with around and then
you'll move to a different bit and then
also start pits halfway through and then
Just got a crew to shoot two shows in
denver.
And so on sunday nights.
So I recorded two different hours in
denver for fruit for what I'm working
on.
And then I'll go through those and I'll
chunk the bits out.
And then I already chunk them out in my
head.
I think we all think probably very
differently.
I Think.
I think more in my head,
I think I'm a little more obsessive
compulsive and I chew on ideas
constantly and then I'll find a way to
link them.
Like today on the treadmill,
I thought I figured out a way to link
this joke about my dad with his dream I
had.
cause I never liked telling jokes about
a dream I had said so in such a really
did it really happen that thing.
But it's a funny.
It is a funny dream.
And,
and I was like.
And then on the treadmill I started
figuring out and I hop off the treadmill
and I write it down on a piece of paper
that's writing man.
Now the time you're spending with us,
I just think about
something is writing.
Some people do it by walking.
I hear a locking.
People say they have some of the best
ideas.
They walk with stature on the treadmill.
I'm talking about like in the
neighborhood.
Oh,
you know,
I do.
I just do it.
I do it like at a four for like at least
30 minutes and just with that notepad
and I just write it down,
walking for something I learned in New
York,
it would trigger the way I fall.
Changes your sites where you look at
different things.
So like a hardware store.
It's like you make your mind wandered or
something.
Yeah,
that's why I think they tried to get you
to go outside and do it.
Like go on a hike and then when you've
done that a long time pop into your
head.
Walking is great for clarity.
Like you think a lot of people though,
right?
Physically and then they'll think about
what they wrote when they go on a walk.
Right.
You know,
I've walked a,
I had a really good writing session and
walking through it.
Target like just walking up and down the
aisles,
but you get to see people interact and
you're allowed to mishear things.
When I mishear things that those are
sometimes the funniest fucking things in
the world.
Well,
let's talk about what your current
drinking statuses,
but like,
because to get into the approach,
can you recap like what an average week
is like?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Okay.
First of all,
this isn't an intervention.
We're all friends.
Right?
Your friends though.
I was nervous about doing this for that
very reason.
I was thinking,
okay,
did I suggest no booze for 90 days
because I didn't think you could
possibly do it.
Use adjusted,
adjusted?
Yes.
YeaH,
it was.
By the way,
I'll read the chat thread taxed because
it is funny and I will say already is
the sea was the best.
Just read it.
I want to say.
Um,
how did it go down?
Did I say 90 days?
No.
Booze plus America as a result of the
marathon claim by the way,
to a marathon.
Yeah.
Well,
it's like you thought you're going to be
able to do a marathon at the time it
took the,
the you're getting the treadmill once in
a while.
You fucking idiot.
He thought he could do a marathon in the
same time it took us to do a podcast.
We have like a three and a half hour and
he thought it was going to do a
marathon.
Run that shit.
Yes,
exactly.
Kenyan skinny dudes Who were just ripped
to the fucking bone who'd been running
every day flops.
Get off,
escape.
Such a bad idea.
Such stupid.
It's just so such a delusional
perspective on physical fitness.
Here we go.
Like to run a five hour marathon.
I'd be super impressed,
but who that could do that easy.
So you know,
hurt.
You can't run a marathon.
Easy.
But you can.
I can.
I tell you the one thing that you might
be able to run a marathon.
You can't run a marathon.
Easy.
Fifty five months.
Five hours is easy.
Okay.
I have a scale.
Let's put it back right now and how much
I weigh.
Scale,
scale.
I know I weighed 222 pounds.
These are just numbers is my point,
but not as bad as he looked before.
Okay,
good.
You've got that compliment.
No,
no,
but you've never run a marathon.
I've never run a marathon,
so you can't run a marathon easy because
it's preposterous I've ever run.
When you're not looking at a tv like off
a treadmill.
I haven't done the street running a
really long time talking fake running
your fake running on a machine that does
have to work for you.
It's there.
She comes towards you.
You just have the that I can tell you
exactly what would happen in a marathon.
You would hit mile.
What do you think?
What do you think it goes?
Well,
here's the thing.
Yeah,
for.
It'd be right about the halfway point.
No way.
No,
no.
I think right around there he would go
bad idea.
By the way,
by the way,
let's.
Let's,
let's do.
Let's.
Let's double up on this double.
Let's figure out a drinking bet one.
Then let's figure out a marathon bet.
By the way,
I will.
I just texted with a guy the other day,
my buddy calvin from calvin show and
he's like,
if you can run 12 miles,
you can definitely run a marathon.
That's way longer,
but wait,
this all started because you guys did
this.
Speak is you can.
You can do it.
The question is,
is it easy?
There's not a fucking chance in the
world.
You saying I could run a marathon.
easy is an accurate statement.
I can give me a five hour marathon.
It's burt is not a statement.
It's hard to do when you're 285 pounds
and you're out there.
Okay.
listen,
you fucking heard that and got so
excited.
This all started.
It's hard to tell,
man.
You ready to do.
That's why it's great.
You're not going to concede that it's
hard to do.
It's definitely hard to do so,
but you for sure,
definitely want to marathon.
That's what you mean by easy for sure.
Why?
Why do you think you can definitely run
every time funny,
a treadmill on the treadmill moves
towards you.
Get your legs up,
you get off and stopped to write stuff
that's running.
You're lifting your legs up,
but It's moving towards the treble.
Keeps going while you're off making a
fucking tito's and soda.
Can you do what you do a couple miles
and you run?
Walk.
I do run.
I walk a quarter mile.
I run three quarters of a mile,
quarter mile,
jesus to get my heart rate up and down.
Fucking marathon.
You walk a quarter,
let's get my heart rate up.
I'll walk,
run,
walk,
run.
One quarter.
but when you run sprints,
run three quarters of a mile,
walk a quarter,
five feet,
and then he the breaks and drinks box
wine.
So this is one of the new aluminum man
box wine thing.
Set up on his treadmill.
No bullshit.
His drinking like a box of wine.
While we would your.
Would your approach to the marathon
right now?
Be just wing it.
Good mood.
No plan seems to be a good or something
online for your treadmill you need
above.
You like a durable feeder so you can
drink while you're running a.
Somebody with a rubber attached to it.
This all started because a,
the guy you guys are claiming that is
not a runner.
Had a profile written in about him on
runner's world.
Yeah,
the photos.
He doesn't matter.
It's all the photos on to red would
write a profile about how he hates
running demons.
You're better than him.
He'll write a whole story about how you
are definitely better than him,
but I'm gonna still out running in terms
of the average marathon times.
Immediate average marathon was four
slash 20.
I can't do the finishing time and it's a
medium I could.
I couldn't do for 20 to put to dieser
fucking people that are in really good
shape to take into account the boston
marathon,
which is super hard.
Hold on one second.
You know what I'm saying?
for marathon running shoes,
people don't wait to be any pause here.
It shouldn't be paused here and
confusion as to whether or not you're in
really good shape,
but you should get the site.
You got your know.
You can't say this,
but hold on.
You can't say you're in really good
shape when you were attempting to say
you're in really good shape.
Hold on,
I'll get super listening to get my
feelings hurt.
If you say you're in really good shape,
go.
I am in good shape.
You're way.
Let's.
Let's just.
Let's just put the parameters down and
then just pretend you think I'm not
lying right now.
You have a very good run.
I run five miles a day on the thing
that's moving towards you and you lift
your feet up.
I agree.
I agree on that.
I agree on that every day and I'll tell
you what,
I'll go out and they'll run five in the
road and if I noticed that difference,
I will say,
by the way,
hey listen,
I'm not in really good shape.
Miles,
I'm in decent shape and I work out a lot
like crazy ruthless shit and I wouldn't
say,
you know why?
Because I know actual people that are in
really good shape.
Yeah,
okay.
That I'm not in really good shape.
Okay?
Now I'll listen to the important thing.
When you're discussing all these like
baby,
it's just like I ran.
I ran a five k drunk one time and go
half of the fucking field trauma.
We thought it was.
Oh,
that's right.
you told me about so and so what?
But I beat half of the fucking field.
Now those are the same people,
but the people drink and they came there
for a radio station to pub crawl.
Yeah.
One of them are actually elite athletes.
Wasn't a pub crawl.
it was an actual five k that I thought
was a pub crawl,
so I drank five beers before it thinking
we'd be draining and it was a fucking
five k and I beat half the fucking.
Can I say something?
It's a.
It's over three miles because I'm a
runner.
when you say you're in good shape,
yes.
Literally the shape of you is bad.
I'll take away.
We're all gonna.
Have different versions of what we
think.
Good shape and you can't have a low bar
when you're talking about reality.
You're not allowed a little bar.
When you talk about things like shape.
I,
I cannot run.
I could by the way.
I couldn't.
I couldn't run.
I can't believe I'm fucking.
I just got off the treadmill this
morning.
I was like,
maybe I should take a video and show
them what I'm running.
You passed out drunk there and then
granted it's a treadmill.
It's not trail.
This trail,
as you run this three miles this
morning,
because I was,
we had to drain our pool.
There's no benefit whatsoever to
exaggerating fitness levels.
I'm not at that level,
but there's an ego issue when people do
it and you just can't do it,
but you can't say I'm in great shape.
There's no fucking way.
You're in great shape.
It's really not possible,
but you are in good shape for somebody
that's in terrible shape.
I agree with that.
Agree with that.
And the other thing is,
you know,
like you do stuff,
you know you're active,
you definitely do stuff.
Okay.
Yet,
if we could get you to do those things
and not drink,
you would be in a measurably healthier
person.
It'd be 100 percent.
Do you think that that would be
something that you had wanted to do that
guy burt and shape?
No,
there's still no fit.
Their weight,
but I think it's 2:17
that you're pretty fit.
Their like fate or in his prime?
Yeah,
for real.
No,
he looked very fit there.
He looks strong too.
I was 2:17
to 15.
That's a different.
That's only four pounds.
That's two.
That's three.
Eight at least around your belly come
clean son.
Did you.
Were you in denial housing,
the flop out in the knots or do they
have to bring other scales in order to
get badly looking at this picture at the
top of your pants.
Into your pubic hair.
Standing up.
Oh,
hey.
Pull up a picture of tom.
Why don't we.
Tom never got that big.
Got bigger.
Joe.
We've got a belly.
He got bigger because he's five,
nine and under six foot or cirrhosis of
the liver for sure.
Right?
No,
no,
no.
It's only affecting the gut.
God,
is there an over under on you right now?
I'd say 54.
Wow.
It looks great.
Beard does not look good.
It looks better there,
but on the other one,
maybe it's there,
but I do think he's got a beard there.
HIs head would be twice as large book.
Yeah.
That's unhealthy.
Sweaty.
Yeah,
but here,
how about this?
Look at them now.
One hundred 80 pounds.
Yeah.
I guess like when 95.
Oh,
this is killing me.
This is making me regret ever texting
you.
We're still proud.
I was.
Runner's world could run a marathon.
You said that's obviously one bit.
Wait,
wait,
but we have to.
We have to obviously.
Wait,
let's set up because here's the deal.
I do run every single day.
Every single day.
I'd probably run a five,
four times a week.
I'm running.
I'm running no less than five miles on a
day like today is a little bit of a
difference.
Let me ask you something.
Shoot.
When are you proposing that the marathon
take place?
Look,
I just think that's an important.
That's an important thing to decide
which one you proposed from tuesday a
year.
I am sweating.
I need you to back me up a tad bit.
I used to.
I've always been.
I've always conceited that you are a
great natural runner guy.
You're the man of human shape.
You have to have good endurance running.
You do.
Hey,
you have a natural stride.
No natural advantage in this.
I'm like,
First of all,
is everybody jumping in on this?
Is everybody going to.
No,
no,
no.
This is all pile on.
Burton.
Burt's got approved.
He's not a liar because you said you
going to be tom.
I cannot meet you.
I will do something.
Okay.
I do not know if it would be a marathon.
I don't know.
I would have to put a lot of time into
running.
I put.
Can you,
can you,
will you consider another resources to
do that right now?
Yeah.
So another idea I had that I pitched to
you a little while ago was what if we
did a one day decathlon style event
where it's multiple,
like you have like seven different
things you do is.
Yes.
I will tell you that I bike around a lot
so when we get into cath lab thing then
no,
you would have no chance of still
finishing.
Still even finishing.
Wow.
I'm sorta like putt putt was one of the
events.
We'd have something heavy there.
So you couldn't do that and then I don't
know.
Oh,
maybe though you dominate.
We had some sort of eating contests.
No,
dominate,
dominate.
I had to do what I did the night before,
so we all have to drink.
When you guys were mocking him being
five,
nine,
I wish I was five.
Nine.
Take it on the chin.
This reality here,
motherfuckers.
Okay,
let's get 300.
Twenty six pounds.
Now here's.
There's two aspects to the bet.
The bet is we're going to coming up with
something physical,
some type of physical competition,
and then how long we're going to go
totally sober for.
You were saying 90 days,
right?
We're allowing marijuana.
Let's.
Let's be real.
If I'm going to be real about
everything.
You guys going to be real?
I can't.
I cannot do 90 days.
I don't want to thank you.
Thank you for quitting.
Before we started and coming off these
ridiculous statements and whatever,
we think everyone's going to be.
Whatever we agreed to,
you're definitely going to be wearing a
scram cam.
What's the scram?
Continuous continuous alcohol
monitoring.
Everybody else is on the honor code,
but bert has to wear a scram.
It's
for high risk offenders because you get
one,
of course you cops that listen,
that would hook us sweating profusely.
If you fail the alcohol part,
the bed is over.
There's no more competition otherwise it
has no stake,
so it has to be seat.
I'd you know,
I'd be down to do something,
but the problem with running a marathon,
a marathon,
right,
without really fucking your body up,
you should build towards it.
You could probably run americans,
you That logic and common sense.
Why would you do that?
Here's the thing,
I'm not averse to a challenge,
but I'm not interested in destroying my
body capital on over many days.
If you're going to do a marathon,
I feel like you should give yourself
some time and run a five k,
five k,
five k in vegas in january of 2000
meters.
Yeah,
do.
I didn't run at all.
It did zero preparation.
I mean none.
I completed it,
but it was way tougher than I thought it
was.
Oh my god.
I just.
It's about three miles because my
fucking thanksgiving a couple years ago
in cincinnati and agreed to a 10 k
training that was unbelievable.
Pain meds.
I'm like,
god,
how long did it take you?
I don't have no idea.
I have no idea,
but it was.
I was in real pain,
man,
so I started running after it.
After they did it,
I was like,
okay,
this is not good.
It's not good that I can't run three
miles and not be like,
how much are you running?
Well,
one hills.
I'm not running flat.
See,
that's my argument to is that I think
that what people were worried about is
two things.
One,
this traditional running shoe.
We have the big fat heel at the bottom
and you land on your heel.
Yeah.
That was all invented by nike.
Really?
Yeah.
You're not supposed to run and land on
your heels.
You're supposed to run and land on the
ball of your foot and your foot in the.
You know the strength of your foot and
your calf and all that shit decelerates
your stride.
That's how people are designed to run.
That's how everybody's supposed to run,
but somewhere along the line,
nike came up with this fat heal and they
changed the way people run.
Now they run like he'll heal.
You jusT not supposed to do that,
man.
Suppose to run your toes,
feel your feet and the ball of your
feet,
so things like these,
these things have like zero soul.
There's just like this thin rubber that
would protect you from stepping on hard
sticks.
Shit.
That's it.
You know,
and by walking and stuff that you're
supposed to walk in,
your feet gets stronger by running,
continuously run like when you're on
those hills,
like just keep going to these vibram
five finger trail shoes and it's like
they're so thin that the other day it
was so hot out that my feet got hot.
Like I could feel the heat of round
coming through the salt super thin
runner.
Neil runs ones the barefoot,
they're like griffith park and she was a
better man than I.
I bought a pair of those when I saw you
had them.
I bought a pair.
I thought that would help and then like
the very next week I was on the beach
and I was like,
you know how to run barefoot?
Man.
I woke up,
my feet were so fucking sore in places I
didn't even know
muscles.
Yeah.
That's the thing,
we don't usually use our feet correctly
because our feeder in these hard
sneakers and the heart sneakers act as
like a cast and so your muscles in your
feet atrophy.
They got a class action lawsuit against
them,
but for anybody who.
No,
no,
vibram five fingers shoes did because
they created these thin toe shoes.
There's a bunch of people got injured.
They said they will protect you from
injury,
but not repetitive stress injury.
Not like you not being conditioned for
them injury.
there's a bunch of injuries that you
absolutely can get.
I'm sure people are suing them.
Yeah.
You know what their claims were ruled to
be.
Either they settled or they.
There was enough ambiguity in what they
were claiming enough like,
you know,
what they were trying to say is that
they help you somehow or another from
injuries they could overall in the long
run,
but you've got to condition yourself to
where those fucking things.
Sure.
and if you don't,
you get like neal brennan blew out his
plantar fasciitis feet for fucked up for
a year,
wearing nose from running on a treadmill
with those.
He just wasn't fit for it.
Like you have to do a lot of shit
barefoot to build up all those muscles
in your feet.
PuT a,
a.
Showed us all the time.
Yeah.
Just walking with my heels would hurt
somebody that tell me that this
stretches to like,
how do you treat it?
Do you remember?
You sent me to a rolfer oh yeah.
I remember I went to a role for.
It's so bad.
That's when I started gaining my weight
was the same thing,
happened to neil,
happened to me.
I blew out my plantar fasciitis and uh,
and at the time I was probably like
probably exactly what I weigh right now.
Maybe even more,
but I got two to 65 because I could not,
I couldn't walk because hurt.
I went to a rolfer and for this guy,
his name ricky,
the offer or something is that I got to
hollywood and these are legit rick,
counteroffer I think.
And uh,
he goes in with his knuckle into the,
into the muscle or to the attendant and
breaks up the fascia.
And I started it and he goes,
just so you know,
you can yell.
And I was screaming,
screaming,
screaming.
There was a sign on the,
on the set,
on the ceiling that you're looking at
that says,
don't worry,
go to the light.
And I was fucking screaming.
I called you the second I got done
because I walked out of that place in
flip flops and went,
I can fucking walk.
And I called joe.
I was on laurel canyon.
I was like,
it was two things.
hey,
can you tweet it out?
My date and portland had the wrong
color.
I did say that ricky the ra for sounds
like a name under care for a character
in a tim and eric show.
It's don.
The role for the for plantar fasciitis
been was no joke.
Cruz got that when he came back after
his surgery.
Really?
Yeah.
Tried to go too hard,
too quick.
Feet feeder all taped up.
Now whenever he fIghts.
Well that's why I walked.
I walked that first 15 minutes.
Walk one mile,
tend to loosen up.
Some fucking happened in my butter.
If you roll your toes in the beginning
of the day too,
when you're lying in bed with your foot,
you just do this 10 times,
10 times that way.
Which foot do 100 pushups?
Why don't they know?
I'm joking.
Can you do maybe three?
Get the fuck out of here.
I can't do chin ups.
Chin ups,
man.
How come you only do three?
I,
when I was going to bootcamp or not,
you know,
chin up guy.
It's a lot of weIght.
To lift up is pretty impressive.
We buy into the propaganda of bonds,
but we're honest.
I feel like Donald Trump right now.
I don't know if uber rock,
obama and trump totally do it.
I could do for.
Are you proposing though that?
What are you proposing with the no
alcohol that was you guys that started
that I w I,
I am personally.
Personally,
I thought.
I don't mInd.
I think it's one of the things I liked
about the challenge that I did was that
people got into it as well and could do
it with us and they started shaming each
other and that's the one thing.
That's the feedback that I've gotten
from it is when people are like,
dude,
me and my buddy started fat shaming each
other.
Yeah,
that's cool.
It's a lot of that feel like the booze
option of taking booze off the table for
90 months or 90 days rather than a
stroke,
which was like you on the pch and a
motorcycle and you see your guy texting
for you doing that for 90 days,
just too daunting.
Ninety days.
So is it.
But is it because you appreciate the
feeling that being drunk gives you?
Is it because you enjoy going onstage
drunk?
No,
I don't.
I don't drink on stage.
I will bring a cocktail on stage with
me,
but I never performed drunk ever.
Ever.
I mean I have but I don't.
And,
and you can ask anyone that's ever seen
me for them.
I have a tito's and soda on stage with
me and I've barely touched it.
I feel like there's definitely some
tweets coming in like I saw you hammered
it
four shots at stage.
Here's the thing,
here's one thing that I've ever
absolutely promised I've never done and
never will do.
I will never drink a fake shot.
I've never drank,
never drank a shot.
That shit.
TheY do that shit.
They're like,
so and so does this.
I was like,
no,
I'm not going to take a picture that
just don't bring up some do.
Did that to me.
And like I don't remember where it was
and he just looked at me and I dragged
her.
What the fuck was that?
I like looked at him and I go,
what was that?
And he goes,
what did you just give me a fake shot?
I go,
do not do that,
sir.
I go,
go back there and you get yourself some
Jack Daniels.
Get me a real god damn shot.
What kind of amateur night shit is this?
Some people do though that would request
that and they would be like,
we're partying here fuckers.
Oh my,
my rule is don't shove me shots the
stage because I can't not do them.
Oh yeah,
of course.
Yeah.
Or I'd be cannot do it.
So let's,
I mean,
let's be candid.
Yeah.
Now you can,
like people,
they,
when I go out in the road of that for
them,
that might be their party for the month.
And so I've,
I get offered so many shots.
I think it will blow you away.
Like how many fireball,
how many just vodka shots get send.
What would happen if you left the club
just like right after the show and went,
went back to your room?
I don't know.
I tried to do a one time I tried that
and it got lost and the manager was
like,
hey man,
uh,
hooked up,
we told everyone that you're going to
this bar,
it's packed,
they're waiting for you.
And I got there and then tito's had sent
me a snowboard and it was like get my,
my meet and greets are a little
different cause I don't mind hanging.
I mean,
I know we all don't mind,
but like I don't mind,
I would much rather not do a meet and
greet and just go to a bar at the end of
the night and just if you want to come
up and tell me that you liked the
podcast,
you'd love tommy and or you think are,
he's funnier than tom,
whatever,
but I liked that.
I don't mind that and that is part of
what I do and I can ask a question.
Sure.
Do you think it's weird that alcohol
companies are sending you things?
Just gifts and.
No,
but don't you say a snowboard?
You had tIto sent me a snowboard,
snowboard while you're drinking.
That shit shouldn't be real clear about
that and I gave it to them.
I don't use what we're sending you use
what we make a note that we should be
sure it's super clear.
Otherwise you just see tito sends me.
Usually the local reps will send me like
a gift basket in my room every week
before I get there.
Like some sort of a deal with them.
uh,
they don't,
they don't do that.
I don't know,
but you don't drink it because I lost
weight when I was drinking tito's and I
was like,
well fuck it.
He's switched to vaka.
Move strong move for health.
I got told that somewhere overseas and I
was like,
I don't have gained weight when I'm so
much more active and I'm eating less
processed food.
She's like tchenguiz beer.
Yeah.
Switched to fucking gin and tonic or
something.
Take care of yourself.
Wait,
wait.
We also.
It's all week.
We set up that you said definitely not
90 days.
Okay.
I'm going to use 30 days sober.
Yeah.
When he got to go some time.
Okay.
I feel like I'm negotiating a hostage.
Hold on.
Let me talk to them.
Yeah,
I can't do it,
so I'm going to Australia or Singapore.
There's no way you're doing that in
Australia.
They'll never let you be,
so why can't you do?
Why can't we just start it before you go
on the trip?
Come on man.
When is that trip?
Why do you talk?
How do you get on this podcast?
You don't know me.
You can do 30 days.
You're always gonna.
Have an excuse why you're not doing it,
so why not just do it starting tomorrow?
I talked to,
I talked to know that can't lose.
I talked to him about it because dan
hope set when I told him about our
conversation and he's like,
I'll do 30 days stan hope with god in
standups,
and he goes,
but you gotta you gotta give me a heads
up because I got to carve it out.
Take some stuff away from her,
like risks and hope takes him.
He's like,
I can't.
And actually he was really excited about
it.
I can't because I'm in Singapore on the
personally 11th sydney on the 13th.
Melbourne and sydney on the m three has
been on the 18th.
Guys find me an Australia please in
sydney and melbourne.
Those tickets are moving slower than
tom's work.
You couldn't do a night in Singapore and
Singapore on your weight from Australia
also.
You're going to be at,
but you couldn't do one night without
getting drunk.
It's like it's the flights by the way.
I can do what?
I can do the lights,
right?
It's the flights.
Are you going to do any flight?
Are going to do any.
You're scared.
I'm willing.
I'm willing to do 30 days in october,
October 1st to the end of october.
Not thanksgiving,
halloween.
Why that I have.
I have.
Because I have a couple of road dates
and I'm an I and I,
I will be very candid with you.
Okay.
I do need to learn how to fly sober.
Yeah,
but I can't do it to Australia.
I would never do that.
I pretty much always fly liquored up.
Yeah man.
But hold on and now I'm telling you this
always.
You fly a lot.
Wait a minute.
Flight to san francisco.
We flew to san francisco and our flight,
that's an hour flight.
Let's recap.
Started off.
Fuck me.
Start.
When do you have on that flight?
I brought it.
I brought a cocktail to your house,
but it was.
There was a party that was a party that
night.
That's a different thing.
Can you describe the cup?
It was,
I think it was a 32 ounce,
32 ounce a styrofoam cups.
By the way,
I've cut back on 32 ounce dot and then
in the airport and the flight together,
it was eight by the way.
Hold on,
I got to tell you this,
you know,
for a fact that when we sat down and the
thing and the guy recognized me,
he didn't even ask what I wanted.
He brought what I said one for tommy and
okay,
now listen.
Those are like,
what's up?
bert at the airport bar bartender came
by to say hi because I tip well and I,
and by the way I don't like flying.
I had a period of time with a prescribed
me on xanax and that got away from me.
It literally.
Did you get on a plane so you always
take one,
one,
like a slippery fish headed downstream.
I take one in the morning before the
flight I get,
we'll take them on the plane and then.
So I was like,
um,
no xanax.
It's not healthy.
I was like,
booze,
it up on flights home as well as flights
there.
Oh yeah.
More so on those.
Jesus.
Yeah.
I'm being honest.
Please.
No,
no.
This is going to be a tough challenge.
We're still.
We're down to 60 days is what you're
saying?
I can do.
I can do october.
I think.
What's.
What's the travel schedule like?
Just peeing what?
You can't fucking see it so he just keep
going.
Too much of an animal.
Just go to the bathroom.
I don't want to miss any of this.
This is nothing to miss,
man.
We're talking shit and he's already
agreed to 55 days.
We'll recap you.
Don't worry,
ma'am.
We'll just let everybody know that
you're paying.
Now we have to deal with this jug.
Oh,
piss the nasty.
It's thinking about the difference
between a glass of kombucha and a glass
of piss.
Piss.
Smell slightly are definitely true.
If you didn't enjoy like the taste of
kombucha and you just smelled it for the
first time,
it's like kimchi,
kimchi for the first time.
You're like,
what the fuck is in the shot?
You're holding your ticket.
You're in the middle of a piss.
Do you need like a larger container?
Yeah,
he's going to switch.
Just drinking water.
You got to switch that damn animal.
Just go to the bathroom.
What's wrong with you on my floor?
For sure.
You're plugging your dick into the whole
curating,
like constriction of the pis.
Whole is not the first time I piss in a
bottle job.
It's time you piss in a bottle here.
He pissed it up all the last time you
were here.
He's an animal.
Doesn't sound like me at all.
Bird,
how are you finding october.
Everywhere.
This is what makes it tricky.
Uh,
but I'm totally,
I'm totally,
uh,
I mean I'd love to sculpt it so it
didn't make a tricky,
but I'm a dc on the 30th of September,
so a cross country flight,
cross country flight on the first will
be my first of do my first,
an old little while.
Uh,
I have done them recently,
but that would be my first one on the
first,
uh,
funded on the six hour flight on the.
This is where it gets complicated.
It failed right there.
Where's the second failure coming?
I have a chicago on the 19th to the 21st
or 22nd.
That can't be right.
You can get through at that time of
flight situation that's hanging out in
chicago without drinking good places to
drink though.
That's why it's a good challenge.
Yeah,
I could.
I could do it.
I'm doing a college the night before and
I'm sure that the reason I got hired as
they all want to hang out with me at a
bar afterwards.
That's fine.
I'll just get in the car.
No,
listen,
people get hired because you're a funny
comedian.
Don't hire you just because they get
drink with you.
I got hired at for a corporate for a lot
of money and I was like,
that doesn't seem right.
And I got up there and I started doing
the guy who was telling the machine and
let us go to a bar.
And I was like,
alright.
So I told the machine and we went to a
bar and aspen and I was like,
fuck it.
If that's what you guys wanted for that,
I'll do it.
Wow.
That's so weird to corporate as bunch of
millionaires from New York who just are
like,
we want that fucking guy.
We want that story.
Let's fucking party
areas.
Yeah.
And then.
And then this is where it gets it.
Uh,
yeah.
I will say that,
that I think sometimes it does.
It grates on you where you're like,
hey man,
I do want to go to bed.
You ever hear a kennison talk about when
he became famous and he would go to
parties and they would go hit sam.
I think he goes and they lay out a
fucking line,
like lay out some like crazy protein.
And he would,
he would
snort it and I forget how the bit wet,
but we've talked about like his heart
was pounding out of his chest.
You can barely alive,
but he didn't want to like let them
down.
Oh,
you know,
it's a crazy thing that I get is that,
people always want to do shots.
I don't like shots.
And then book.
When I go to take a sip of a drink,
I will drink my legit first drink.
When I do stand up,
when I tell the machine story on the
second show,
on the second show,
when I start that I go,
this is cruise control.
I'm going to have my cocktail start,
I'm going to try to catch a buzz in the
middle of the story and I saw I'll
murder a double t doesn't soda and that,
but also to make them never drank during
a show or just telling the machine
story.
But uh,
but here's the tricky part of this
challenge is that we're doing the
impractical jokers cruise on the first
and sow.
When we started doing this,
he went online.
He reached out to both of us and was
like,
hey,
please don't do this for our cruise.
Why?
Because there are guys that healthy.
They know there are guys that bought
tickets to party with us.
He's taking for.
He was like,
no more weed,
no more,
uh,
tripping,
you know.
Sorry,
I can't,
can't this time.
So wait a minute,
you're on the first november.
I see what you're saying.
October.
Yeah.
But we'd have to fly one more time.
My last october.
My last day of the challenge will be on
a fucking problem.
I'm going to spend.
I don't know,
maybe you're not,
but you can celebrate on the cruise
first,
but I would be landing on halloween and
new orleans.
Halloween.
We were already big.
That's what makes it a tough,
tough challenge.
Scrap cam.
You cannot cheat it.
Mechanical to scram camp camp.
This episode is brought to you by scrim
town.
Might have come scram.
A fucking heartbeat.
So by the way,
ditches be lying.
Colon,
andy,
dick,
and middle of the night.
Hey yo.
How do you fund your screen?
Cameras.
So on halloween,
whenever it was lit up and you're going
to the airport to go to new orleans into
the fucking harder darkness,
you're going to be able to survive.
You're not going to just say close
enough.
Nope.
It's got that script.
Look,
let me tell you something about me.
I promise you this long strand mickey
mantle dna.
Yeah,
I remember this shit.
I still got it.
Dude.
He's in great shape.
Let's do this right now.
Why can't we wait you right now?
Just pick me up and pick up buttons and
csf here and then look over our heads
and see you're shorter.
Shorter.
What does that mean?
He said you like talking about something
completely different,
like who's heavier?
He's heavier than you now.
We're probably the same way.
We're going to your house after this.
Yeah.
We'll get on your scale scale.
Please put that shit on.
Parents would love to see her script the
fuck out of that.
I got to do go instagram live perhaps.
Yeah.
Right now.
This is the people right now,
right now.
Super uncomfortable with their personal
weight yesterday.
Dreaming at the three of us.
You guys are fat shaming,
shaming,
shame.
He changed my life were just,
it changed my life for the better.
The back.
Can I tell you that the greatest thing
about this weight loss in the running,
it's just putting on my shoes,
my shoes.
So difficult.
What happened?
You know what I've always thought
though,
for real people
and then lose all the weight.
They must have incredible leg muscles.
Dude.
Uh,
what's,
what's um,
uh,
daniel tosh,
his best friend,
eddie gosling.
Gosling.
When we did a voiceover,
like a cartoon together something and we
were in the sound booth together and
tosh is in the other room and I go,
uh,
come in at a,
you got fucking big calves.
And he's like,
yeah,
I know.
I said,
no,
you got like really big calves.
And he's like,
no,
I get that a lot.
And I go,
no,
eddie likes,
you've got.
And I see tashi is in the sound booth
and he's laughing hysterically.
I go,
what is it?
And he goes,
here's to be thrown her 80 pounds.
So that's why he's got a big calves.
And I was like,
oh,
it's a good touch and pressure by the
way.
Three hundred 80 pounds.
Wow.
So okay.
So you must have similar calf muscles
then.
No,
it's not that big.
Beautiful.
Seventy five.
Scram.
Continuous alcohol monitoring.
I wonder if you could like,
do you think people play like role
playing games with their spouses and
they put those on if I catch you
drinking bitches,
I'm not drinking.
I don't drink at her gym machines.
Bullshit to machines.
Reading is always correct.
You're a liar.
Wait,
that doesn't do.
That sucked a dick.
Yeah.
That doesn't play role playing game.
Yeah,
exactly.
It's like,
oh,
it's,
you know,
it's.
I have girls who were those a pantyhose
with the elastic band around the top.
Why is that not as hot with the way your
pantyhose are connected.
Why is that not?
Yeah.
I don't know,
but it is,
right.
It doesn't make sense.
Why is it hot?
A girl we're in garter belt is extra
dirty.
I like.
I like when you find something that you
didn't know is dirty and then you see it
and you go,
that's new.
My newest.
Or like,
you know,
it's really sexy glasses.
No chicken can't see that.
Good.
But what's really good?
Tell us what I want to grow.
Smells like shit.
What do you like man?
Tell her to shower and hates shower.
No,
nothing.
Come on.
No,
I,
what I did for the last point,
I was like,
the last point I saw that really kind of
like register me in a new way and it was
like,
I was like,
it's this thing called the dancing bear.
So what it is,
is a,
what?
It,
hold on,
we got to hear the whole story.
You don't start tearing it apart.
Uh,
it's,
it's a foe bachelorette party.
So they come in with a dancing bear.
He was dancing around,
right?
And then he goes back and he comes out,
he's got a big dick and he's just.
And so does he get caught by accident?
No,
no,
no.
So this is what turned me on though.
What is,
he comes out and comes out and he's a
bachelor party but there's like 30 girls
so clearly it's like really big,
right?
So clearly like clearly like a couple of
them porn stars that he's going to fuck
because it's a porn.
Do you think his dick was taught them?
Tom?
Probably his,
the rest of them are hired.
Just actresses.
They're not.
Porn started to pay that much.
But what turned me on was when he would
join in with one of the regulars like
the and he just like,
he's fucking this girl and this girl is
like trying to like act.
And he puts his finger in her mouth.
The look on her face when she went,
oh,
I guess I'm in this.
I was like,
dad,
I want something real.
Yeah,
so much.
So this one girl that wasn't supposed to
get fucked,
they got fucked,
get fucked.
She just was like,
just sucked his finger.
Yeah.
And,
but,
but it was like regular girl regular
wasn't a poet and so all of a sudden.
But the look on her face and then she
started sucking his finger and you're
going,
oh,
this is how a real girl does it.
She was like,
nervous,
like are there cars right now?
Driving the whole thing I liked about
down blouses,
downloading told you just pulled down
someone's skirt.
Those videos were hilarious.
They pants people to down blouse was his
videos of girls.
I'm cleaning toilets in a loose fitting
shirt with no bra and then talking to
the camera about inane bullshit like
your wife would all you're doing and
you're so.
It's real.
It's fucking real.
She's like,
hey,
we should probably get new trash cans
and you're like,
you're watching it but you're seeing it
in the video.
I'm watching and I'm nodding going,
yeah.
What or whatever,
just to hint of tiddy today,
today we had to drain are above ground
pool and a pool and so leanne,
leanne and I were joking around the bed
talking about this dream I had and then
she goes,
let's do this now because before it gets
hot and she goes,
I'm going to go put a bra on and I go or
don't and I'll do the whole thing by
myself.
Just that little fucking side boob
action.
You see?
I fucking love that.
What she do,
she kept bra.
If I drain the pool.
Wow.
Look at you.
Then ran three miles,
three miles,
three miles.
Treadmills will you actually do run?
There's a trench out of the woodwork or
something like
they're non motorized.
Treadmill is use those now.
They use them in like legit strength and
conditioning centers.
They really take off my.
But this has resistance and it's built
like a banana,
like so you're running on it so it's all
entirely on the actual motion of you
pushing your body.
Yeah,
that's it.
They're pretty bad ass speeds.
Very interesting because the,
you know,
the faster you run,
like physically run,
the faster it goes.
You push it,
push it up to keeping up with it.
You're actually pushing it out.
So it's like a teleprompter.
No,
no,
no.
Like when you read a teleprompter,
it goes at your pace,
so if you read faster,
it goes faster.
If you read slower go slower
mechanical thing like the,
the physical action of you running and
pushing it because you're on the slope.
That's what makes it go fast so that
you,
you don't,
you don't have to worry about like
keeping up with it.
It keeps up with you and it's all a much
more natural stride.
Then keeping up with something that's on
a mechanism that's having the belt feed
towards you.
So this is what it looks like when
you're running on these things.
See how as woodward is one step higher
to increase your pace.
Like you're,
you're actually pushing it
step higher to.
Yeah,
I will say I will say in all honesty,
I know that we joke.
I will say I've been worried about the
idea that running on a treadmill is not
just,
it's making my legs move at that rate.
Well,
this is opposed to making my legs take
me sweating.
It's
good,
it is good,
but you see how this guy's running.
How is the ball of his feet,
his landing?
It's because he's running on a slight
uphill slant and that's how you're
supposed to land on your feet.
The body is designed to like almost lean
forward and you catch yourself on the
ball of your feet.
Know how much money I don't know.
When you're running on an uphill slant,
you're more likely to do that.
That's why I like this shit.
Are you serious?
Yeah sake.
It's not cheap,
but it's the name of it.
That's the way to running hills is the
shit and if you live in a place where
you can't run hills,
I get it,
but if you do live in a place that has
hills,
running hills is the shit man.
It is fucking amazing for workout.
So if you run,
do like put a heart rate monitor on.
Let yourself get jacked up to a certain
heart rate when you get an and take your
time.
When you get down to 140 beats per
minute,
start running again,
jack,
that fucker up again in one 90.
Go as far as you can.
Let it get down to 1:40.
And if you just keep doing that over and
over and over again,
you develop so you feel better,
your legs move better,
your feet are stronger.
The difference between like,
like if you have the opportunity,
like we live in a place that has canyons
everywhere,
there's fucking trails everywhere and
they're all stupid shit.
Like runyon is steepest shit.
If you can get to runyon and run up that
fucking thing,
that's a phenomenal workout,
man.
Fucking insane.
I will say this though,
and by the way,
and I have to say this,
I have to give a huge shout out to
cameron hanes because when I really
started doing all this was I think was
when you met him and I and like grid
trying to get in shape and I hear his
fucking mottoes and I'm sure he's
probably said to himself,
you know,
I should.
Whatever I hear his motto is a no one
cares work harder.
Like I hear that when I run.
Sometimes it's inspiration.
Yeah,
but,
but I will say that like I sometimes I
will say to people like myself who are
not as good of shape of cameron hanes.
Some models could be no one cares but
don't get injured because that is a big
problem with,
with running.
It's so tough.
If he get.
He got him to him.
He doesn't realize he got injured.
Not just keeps going.
Not him,
but I mean like people who listen to his
inspiration because ricard sometimes
I've been like,
oh,
I should not really try to kill myself
because I actually
can't measure yourself against that guy.
He runs a marathon a day.
Do you think you'd be disappointed?
Could not do a marathon?
You readily admitted it.
I think cameron.
I think if cameron hanes and I ran for a
day,
I think he definitely say you could do a
marathon.
Why do you know him?
I think
he would only be running with you for
the first 30 or 40 meters.
No,
he couldn't keep up with them to be this
preposterous conversation.
If you're talking to a man who's far in
the distance is too great shape.
Guys.
Guys who are in great shape,
I literally would go to his credit.
He was like,
can we add that to the study?
We'll have 205 miles.
What was his first one?
Hundred.
Oh,
okay.
This is a different one.
He's got a bunch of these disgusting
feet photographs online.
Love it of him losing toenails and shit.
Fucking love it.
So his last last year you ran 205 miles
and this year he's prepping for
something in october.
That's the first time they're doing it
at 238 miles.
Have you ever asked him about the
approach that he went from being,
let's say a guy in shape running to
doing the 100 mile,
like how do you.
Did he just start going like I'll start
doing marathons and then tack on?
Maybe one of the first marathon he did
was very difficult for sure,
but then he started running a more than
one time.
He beat lance armstrong and the boston
marathon.
He beat lance armstrong.
Lance was running the boston marathon.
I actually started out as a runner.
This was.
This was for real though.
Hey,
this is a good Question.
Was this before or after lance got in
trouble like I really thought that
that's so stupid,
so fast,
but he's one of the avengers are just
really good at biking or am I wrong?
Someone believes audio statements
mentioning the bikers.
SUper important and then he started
doing crazy ones.
Then he did a bunch oF 100.
Last year he did the big foot 200,
whiCh is actually 205 miles.
What the fuck was several thousand feet
of elevation to.
You're going up running through the
mountains.
Does he take breaks,
lance armstrong and that's not him?
Yeah,
it is.
That's cameron who was all skinny.
Campbell's real skinny at one point in
time.
Fly.
My guess.
Hold on.
terry.
Cam.
Yeah,
that's cam.
Many moons ago.
This thing is I wonder like coordination
of lance armstrong,
1008,
so it would have been right in the
middle of lives.
That's right.
So that's.
He got posted to the girls.
I wonder who's going to write it up.
lance armstrong.
Wow.
I wonder.
I wonder if maybe it was in his off
season and he was cycling.
Cycling off.
I wonder what.
I wonder what kind of inspiration it was
for cameron to realize your friend with
the camera is around the corner and I
see lance armstrong of my sites and I
get a picture where I'm passing it to a
fat chick at the fucking reservoir and
you're like,
I'm going to pass her fucking.
I'm noT going to walk past her.
I'm going to run his dreams.
He runs out so people understand that
you were talking about running the
reservoir,
the reservoir.
Everybody's like,
what the fuck are you having sex with a
girl high school,
but wouldn't you think that like the
people at home that don't live near
reservoirs don't know that people run
around reservoirs in la?
I didn't know.
I didn't think that into it.
La has so little wildlife will like,
let's just run around a fucking big pool
pool.
They call it the reservoir.
we're reading around it like assholes
that in the la river or the perfect fake
la.
Anybody with real fucking heard of it.
You see it.
You're like,
it's an underpass.
What are you talking about?
I remember like,
what have you seen it in a big rainstorm
though?
And we'll pass going up hill and stopped
and you're like,
wow,
that's our river Colorado.
ShuT your
water.
It's salt water runoff,
you know,
so nasty.
Did you ever see.
Look at that river full blast.
It does get full blast sometimes when we
do need that.
Like last year,
last year got fucking crazy with the
amount of water a lot too.
There was so much water.
It rained so hard for so many ways.
They lifted that drought.
Finally year we pulled us out
of the drought else.
Was that early this year or early this
year,
but here's the thing,
you guys know about the salt and sea?
No,
the salton sea was a place that they
created by opening up the Colorado river
and they literally made it a giant
inland sea and it was good for a little
while.
Excuse me.
I was good for a little while until the
runoff from all these farms from all
this like giant,
large scale agriculture,
all the chemicals and all the pesticides
would get in the runoff and then it got
into the water and poisoned to
everything and this mass fish die offs.
To the point where before this they were
calling it the inland riviera,
like California is inland riviera and
sonny bono used to go there and all
these people used to party there and it
was like this big resort location.
Now there are beaches that there's so
many dead fish bones that the white of
the beach sand is actually fish scale.
What's.
Yes,
millions and millions of fish,
but there's still fish there and there's
still people there because it's an
enormous piece of water.
Look at that.
Those are all dead fish from this one
place,
so they have these mass die offs where
there's no oxygen in the water or
pollutants in the water.
They have giant dead zones.
These fishes float up the surface,
but there's still people that fish in
that water and there's still people that
eat those fish and these communities
around survivor fish do this amazing
documentary on it.
I wish I could remember what it's called
val kilmer movie called solar,
but the documentaries,
the what's fascinating is they
interviewed the people that live in the
surrounding communities,
which are the remnants of what they
thought was going to be people around
the resorts.
Dude,
it's so crazy.
Plagues and pressures of assault and see
who produced that.
Somebody important produce that to John
Waters.
That's right.
Yes.
This is nArrated by John Waters.
Yeah.
That's the one saying,
dude,
it's amazing.
SonnY bono,
before he died,
he wanted to develop some sort of
desalinization,
like filtration system for the salt and
sea to bring it back.
Yeah,
because he remembers what It was like
when he was a kid and look how beautiful
that is.
One that John Waters movie,
when they net,
when John Waters narrow this movie,
you get to see the despair that's in the
community now.
It's really sad.
Back on screen.
Anyway.
What's it called again?
Tom?
You could totally look like that guy.
probably by the way.
I got to give a shout out to tommy.
That fucking mayor thing you did.
I don't know why that's not a tv show,
but it's so funny you ever see that?
Tom's got a mayor,
cincinnati,
uh,
detroit youtube because she just didn't
fucking short film where he's just is
fucking hilarious of play.
This.
Is that martin who's.
Is this?
No,
I didn't pay for it.
no.
It was the video stuff.
You want to get us pulled?
No,
no,
no.
I,
I can.
You can put.
You can play it short.
Wait,
wait,
wait.
back up.
Commissioner gordon's on his way over
batman telling me that's not the reason
you picked him.
Look,
when there's five candidates for police
commissioner and one of them's named
gordon,
your decision suddenly becomes very
easy.
Commissioner gordon is a video of you
smoking crack out.
Okay.
Crack had went to $100,000.
Should be mandatory in school that we
weren't able to sneak the word crack in
a few more to like that guy from
toronto.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
And then they actually,
we made this little while ago and then
they actually did a feature about it,
like were they straight up?
Just did it on him like very much like
this.
Oh really?
Yeah.
That was a character and a half man that
he was wild.
You ever see what he got locked up?
He was talking about fighting people
that he was like Mike Tyson.
We liked a lot his when he did it at
town hall.
And he's like,
no,
and it's like a midday pressing in those
wonderful.
And they're like,
uh,
just ask you.
They didn't ask him specifically about
this.
He goes,
and by the way,
lady,
I'm going to eat her pussy.
He goes,
I get plentY of that back at home
camera.
Oh shit.
It's.
I have to take legal aCtion.
Don't appreciate people home atlanta,
a prostitute,
prostitute here.
I'm very happily married at home.
That's very disturbing against my wife.
Unfortunately.
I have to take legal action against
size,
the grants and the ga stock lists and
mark two.
We have to take legal action against the
winter.
That said,
I was doing lines at the beer market.
That is.
Oh,
great lies.
That is not true.
My wife not.
They're calling a friend of mine,
a prostitute.
Atlanta is not a prostitute.
She's a friend and it makes me sick.
People are saying this,
but unfortunately I have no other
choice.
I'm allowed to take legal action.
I can't.
I can't put up with it anymore,
so I'm litigational you starting
shortly.
I've had enough.
I warned you guys yesterday.
Be careful what you wrote.
Okay,
so that's all I have to save for now.
And the next thing I want to call
America tanja,
it's in hamilton and tell that we're
going to have to
spank their little tiger cats.
oh.
The last thing was olivia gone back to
the sentence.
I Wanted to eat her pussy.
Like never said that in my life.
I would never do that.
I've got more than enough at home.
Drop by drop greatest fucking time.
He died and there was no like,
like there was no coverage of,
of that.
He died.
So there was a really sad.
He came to the store once we finished
with everybody.
Yeah,
it was great.
I wish I met him.
He was the mayor of toronto biggest city
in Canada.
Super recently.
Huh?
He was doing wild shit all the time.
That guy was that.
And brexit were to like,
if you look at history,
if you go back and look at like the rain
of trump,
like when trump became president and you
look at that and brexit,
like those two things happening,
that opens the door.
Well,
anything almost can happen given the
right set of circumstances,
given people getting cocky,
someone thinking they're way more
appealing than they actually are.
Looking at an alternative,
someone's charismatic,
they jump in and they can be crazy.
Let's take a chance with them.
Let's take a chance.
It's the small town politicians getting
big.
You know the best thing about the
current chaos politically,
I think people need to understand that
this can happen.
Do you think about how like I know some
of it is just pr stuff like how 20,
20 might shape up,
at least with.
It could possibly be celebrities.
We'd like To do this too.
It could easily look.
Donald trump is obviously he's got a
long history of being successful at,
you know,
being a television host.
So from a guy who's a.
Yeah,
it was a great interview on a talk show,
so long history of knowing how to kind
of work the crowd in a certain way and
do it only makes sense that someone like
that eventually get in to what I said.
The way I described it,
I was like,
you had a popularity contest and it
actually popular person entered.
Yeah,
that's the difference.
like most of these guys are popular for
politicians and here was this guy who's
popular period.
Yeah,
and he's way better talKing to them and
we were arguing way better at being
under the gun.
Like when those like little hot moments
with him and you know,
all the,
all the different candidates.
He comes up with nicknames for him.
Like the whole thing was kind of genius,
like chopped them all down and then made
it through.
But now you realize like,
hey,
probably nobody should be doing that
job.
It's probably too big of a job for any
one human being.
You know,
and this guy's doing it and he's doing
it because he won a popularity contest.
That's crazy because then you're gonna
have the rock.
He's going to do it.
What I'm saying wrong,
you're not talking about the qualified
people by
any stretch of the imagination.
You talked about the people that people
liked the most.
It's willing to be the rock,
not when.
So many in so many non-regular like
people who can vote that don't.
I'll be like,
I'm going to vote.
Although for Iraq,
no way.
That's ridiculous.
Would win because people think together.
No one thinks that'd be great together.
Shit.
Get on that introduction.
Ship.
Jesus presidents.
How about stop this fucking president.
Vice president.
How about you have to co presidents.
We have a new system.
The rockin.
Oprah taking over whole solar system
will realign the interesting.
It's not a bad idea why people would be
furious.
Yeah.
No,
I don't think.
I don't think white people think that no
one is.
Why the rocks white?
No.
He said why in man not black.
He's blaCk.
Claimed by whites.
He's gigantic.
He's barely a regular person.
You're saying that white people would
athlete might be able to.
The white people love the rock.
Why do people claim?
Because the rock.
You remember when the rock,
you're a twat moving the rock.
Give me a shout out.
Yeah.
He was like super Fat does not make it
all.
That was great because he brought up two
days.
He was like,
look,
two days,
fucking high school.
But you never did two days.
He goes,
no,
no.
play baseball.
Choose wisely.
Cim.
Bert,
bert.
Oh this for the bet.
This was back back.
How'd that turn out?
Tom?
One.
Tom,
be burt.
Weird.
Let's team up that mickey mantle.
Shit.
You were close though.
You were close.
I think I did much better than anyone
expected.
Oh yeah.
Both you.
Did you expect to win?
I,
no.
Did you not expect to win at Some point
when?
When,
uh,
I think we were talking on the phone one
night and you realize and I,
and I was having a hard time dropping
weight.
Weren't working out.
You're eating like crazy and drinking a
lot.
Yeah,
those are all facts.
Whatever,
whatever pain as well as food,
food a lot.
So emotions and everything for a couple
extra miles.
What your jam takedown around.
They're googling what is the calories of
one wendy's double double weight.
So when we talking about the amount of
calories at a wendy's double,
double,
double cheeseburger or run for two
hours,
total bird thought he was pulled out of
his brain on top of the pot roast the
night before.
IT's crazy bro,
but I still was.
I still did.
Good.
You did good.
But when did you think.
When did you not think you were?
Actually I was sitting in my bathroom
and I was talking on the phone and you
were saying something like you were
talking about your diet and I was like,
my diet is Just not eat over a thousand
calories.
Like I'm not thinking about what I'm
putting in my mouth per day.
You ate less than 1000 calories?
No,
no,
no way.
No.
Okay.
I'm not a fucking doctor.
Whatever.
I had sense.
Obviously I lost fucking 40 pounds in 30
days.
I lost fortY pounds.
Correct?
Yes.
It's so crazy.
A lot of calories.
I don't know what it was.
SUper healthy by the way.
It's definitely the way you did it,
man.
You got under obese.
That was great.
Yeah.
I was just trying to show my mickey
mantle gene and when I did my calories I
stopped.
I didn't drink a bond.
How mUch weight does your cut like two
days beFore that time.
Like how muCh do you not drink at all?
Well,
we both cut water the same days,
the day drinking the night before for
salty foods.
Water technically started to do like a
watercolor version of 24 hours before.
That's great,
and then when yOu had to go to the
secoNd day,
that was way harder,
man.
He didn't have a drop of water the
entire next day and then went to a
fucking sauna that morning and I was
like really unhealthy thing that we were
doing was we were making it a weight
loss thing instead of making it a body
fat set.
It's true.
We could have,
if we were smart,
what we've done is a dunk tank have so
place that does a dunk tank where they
check your body composition because they
could do that electrical one.
We hold These cables and you push your
hands on them and it.
It's pretty good there.
Read through your feet to body fat.
There's a bunch of different kinds of
these things.
This wAs the easiest way.
Weight loss,
weight loss is both.
These guys came into this thing like
with a fake weight loss because they
dehydrated themselves.
Birgit and he of salty food and drink a
lot.
Definitely the high.
Definitely.
I definitely did not.
The last day I was thirsty as fuck.
A really hard time not drinking water.
Before I got here,
tommy drank nine bottles of water as
soon as your entire podcast during the.
No.
Do we kept giving them bottles.
Water thrown them like a fight.
Do you remember what the number was?
I remember we calculated it was over a
gallon of water back.
Can I count you?
Made not obese like point one five of an
inch.
That's how close it was.
Great by.
That's where you got to like keep going
for it.
swaying how tall you are versus how much
you weigh,
but that's just bmi modified once and
they want to actually do a way to modify
that and condom.
Yeah.
To me for a second,
that guy.
That guy is crazy.
The way people listen.
If you're listening to this,
google that google image,
search barker fraud,
comedian bark chrysler,
keeping it low in those after his loss
against undisputed water champion tommy
buns.
Segora.
You're surrounded by genius.
Photoshop fried chicken faces from a
spike,
a spike video games award,
and I shaved clean and I saw the photos
from the red carpet and I was like,
good luck to nicotine patches on funny.
That is so funny and no one has seen all
the booze.
Right?
That is a great phOto shop.
She looks so happy with those doNuts.
You know?
That's the thing about the internet.
That can be some dude who has some
regular Jobs somewhere.
This board downtown,
a downtime on his computer.
He just creates that and throws it up
and there's people out there that like.
It's a secret,
but it's not a secret about guys like
us,
like what we do.
There's a lot of guys you could have
done whaT we did.
How about how good are some of these
guys making posters and like drawing.
My guy,
my guy is fuckiNg brett brock.
He is.
He is legit.
Like a very nice dude.
But man,
those posters,
some of them are really good dose brac.
That guy was amazing,
man.
He's really good.
Amazing.
There's a lot of the guys might tailor
inch.
Sherman,
Michael Sherman,
polgar.
Nice.
That was awesome.
He's made an amazing work.
The one bY one podcast guy.
Yeah,
he's good.
He's amazing.
Just great shit.
Hilarious.
Some of them are really just for the
podcast.
Yeah.
That guy from drastic effects.
He does some awesome shit.
You see the run dmc one for 1000 tasks.
YeAh.
That was so great.
So fUn.
That show what ge diaz made me laugh
harder than any human being has ever
made me laugh.
We had to look down.
I looked up and tommy,
he was looking at the Floor too.
We were both looking at the floor and he
was suCking all the oxygen out of the
room.
His.
He was killing.
So track was a way to breathe.
I lost track of what he was saying one
point because I just stopped listening
to him.
He's on fire right now.
I was really excited for that podcast,
dude.
It was fun.
It was easy for you to turn around and
start over.
Wait,
great.
So can we go back to this profile?
What is this bet.
So what do you think you could do now
that you're sober for fucking 10
minutes?
What do you think you could do your
october.
We're signing up,
right?
So 30 days.
Okay.
You want to do 30 days?
Thirty one days.
October,
october this from midnight at,
at,
uh,
on the west coast time.
Wherever you are,
what are you casting a spell I need to
send the moon is full right up to 1159.
Of course he is going to be.
He's going to be passed out drunk at
1159,
but no boobs call through the valley.
Of course he is.
Hold on one.
Disappoint your children.
Hang on.
How can I make this so that I'm going to
challenge where I don't feel like
everyone's against me.
Know what it's like.
It's like the ultimate holds.
Their breath lot will quit.
And for You to lose your home when
you're like a guy who's ready to break
the world record and hold your breath.
You know you're going to breathe again,
but it's going to be.
Yeah,
it's going to be a long time.
I think of how much fun that will be on
november,
but you're not thinking.
You're not thinking,
hey man,
maybe I shoulD just stop drinking.
Think about,
think about October 1st at 12:30
AM when you're like,
I'm the fucking fuck that.
Give me another drink and you fail
instantly.
Think about that.
Is that in two?
No,
no,
that's not even one day.
Thirty minutes.
There was 30 minutes and in my scenario
I assume there are people are out in the
party for five or six days before things
start getting really weird.
Scram cam come to.
First of all,
I think your marijuana intake would up
tick.
Can I say?
Yeah,
you can get high for a month.
Say it's a little bomb bomb.
A little bullshit that you would go to
marijuana because all that stuff.
Normally I'd say that's way healthier,
but I'm sayinG here,
all that's doing is writing you the gap
until you can drink again.
By the way,
I'll go no matter what.
I would like you to face sobriety.
That's interesting.
Look,
look,
I don't have no problem being on the
road with you and have him bombed.
So you look like a hero.
He was the only sober.
I can totally do.
Much better than if I was hammering some
next level of three d chess.
I think you're hilarious when you drunk.
I'm you.
You've never seen.
You've never seen me wait.
No,
you're right.
You have.
You have yet.
You know,
you saw me on stage the first time I was
ever high onstage.
Drunk his fucking at the ice house.
I forgot about that.
I don't drink black out about the time.
Did that.
Oh hey,
by the way,
who's in town?
Wednesday?
Wednesday.
You guys want to do the ice house for
Singapore?
No,
no,
no.
Could have been a good god damn time.
I would love god.
Damn,
that's how I booked the ice house.
It's cool.
I'm super organized.
So 31 days,
80 days?
No nothing.
No bad days and yup.
Days of 40 days of yoga in that time.
No,
you can't do that.
I'll tell you.
Just negotiating like an agent right
now.
Hold on,
hold on one second.
I will tell you why I can't do that.
[inaudible].
I don't want to lose who the fuck I am,
which is I like to.
I like to as is obesity truth bro.
You.
You're saying you don't want to lose the
party man image.
I will not go to that impractical
jokers.
Cruise with big j are all those comics
that I love and not trying to not drink
it.
That's just silly.
I'm a grownup.
I also make a lot of money by don't need
to do the bed,
but I wanted to do the bet because I
like the idea of the bet.
OkAy.
But I think 30 days,
31 days in october to start model
sobriety and totally,
totally.
Can I get some mics in the world police
when they get extra fuck scenes dude.
Shit on the girl's chest.
Just shit on him and pissed on.
Yeah.
Did that so they can cut other things.
I say this,
you can get done with you.
You can get those chalk pills that help
you deal with withdrawal chalk.
no,
I don't need you.
Will you?
When you got the shakes withdrawing or
I'll call these guys guys buy this truck
pills.
Chalk?
Yeah.
I don't need whole charcoal.
Charcoal.
Throw up.
Yeah,
but waiting because you're not gonna get
high off that.
She's going to save your life because
you will die otherwise because you're
unequipped to do this.
But do you remember the article I sent
you should write a well beforehand and
that was the article we read about.
You said that it's really not
recommended to Just quit cold Turkey.
Like you should start now and get ready
or or you know what?
I'm going to write my eulogy with you in
mind ahead of time so that way he's in
great shape and he can run a marathon
easily once.
Wait,
why won't you get withdrawals if you
just quit like that?
Because I beT you can do it all the time
because I'm not me.
I thought for a moment you feel like you
feel uncomfortable for a day where
you're like,
oh my god,
hold on the last stretch,
stretch,
stretch.
How long ago?
A car?
I don't know.
A couple weeks ago.
No,
really her house called unassisted
sleeps.
That's when you go to sleep without
drugs or alcohol?
No,
no weed.
No xanax,
no.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Okay.
Yeah.
We have a thing called unassisted sleeps
to.
I think that's a great idea.
I really do.
I think more people need to learn how to
relax,
meditate,
Just go to bed,
but you can also do your kids off.
You can get a hold of your own thoughts.
You can get ahold of your own thoughts
and it's a good.
It's a good practice to do that and if
you just give your own thoughts to
pills,
I mean it'll work.
Maybe it won't work for everybody and it
works for some people,
but there's other ways to do it.
You could do it with your own mind.
You can.
You can relax yourself.
You cannot medItate.
You can do it without that.
I mean you can do it with,
but there's other
pathways that a lot of people that try
the pills don't try and I wonder how
many would be successful.
I mean some people know,
some people have like real issues,
but with some people I think they'd
probably be just as if not more
successful with meditating,
relaxing,
just trying and figure out a way to like
consciously dip yourself down into the
place where you go to sleep.
I'd like tHat.
What are you doing?
You're going to try that?
No,
I did five days and a foreign assistance
sleeps.
This is what I'm thinking.
I'm thinking 30 days.
You 15 days?
October 90 90 minute hot yoga classes.
That's what I'm thinking.
No booze and then half the days.
So if you have one day on you have one
day off you.
Oh,
and if you miss them then you have to
make them up in a row.
But you have to do 15 days of hot yoga
in a 30 day time period with no booze.
I can do that.
Why do you want to do the hot yoga?
Because I think that would be super
beneficial for them.
I think you should do that ina mount and
it's fucking certainly difficult to do.
Going to fail on that and still detox.
No,
he said,
he said 30 days.
Thirty days.
Just cut.
Half the days.
Half of those 30 you have to do a yoga
class.
Hot yoga,
hot yoga,
90 minutes.
Once I've been.
I went once and I quit like 40 minutes
into an hour and 15 minute class.
I came back in.
I took five minute breather.
I took it because it was hot.
It was like fuck out of it.
I'm out of it.
But you also like a couldn't run a
marathon.
I could.
Oh no,
we all know.
No one would do that.
So do it.
So wait.
Yeah,
there's no way you could do 1590 minute
yoga classes in a month.
What?
Is that what you're saying?
In fact,
I've never,
I don't do them on time marathon know
what I'm saying is I like the turkish
state.
The thing about the yoga classes is
first of all you could.
There's like a real set beginning and a
set end.
There's no fudging was class.
Yeah.
You have to be there to get it in and
it's super difficult to do and I think
it's one of the most beneficial mentally
mental breather.
Not good.
They tell you,
they instructor say,
yeah,
that's what the same people.
To see those,
those,
those little packets,
they leave in the shoes say,
do not eat.
Those fucking retards should meet me.
Should know that you're not going to eat
some shit.
You found your shoe Just so you should
know that if you're going to die,
you should get out of the fucking yoga
class,
so I'm sending.
You should be able to get out of there.
IT's for morons and pussies.
I'm sorry.
Can you look up hot yoga deaths,
the other rape sweating.
When they die,
they die.
Thing dude,
you bring a cooler.
Bring one of those flasks.
They have these like giant can drinking
64 postures like you do two sets,
attitude sets.
You're allowed to have some more break.
Take a five minute breather over that
month will be three,
five minute brief,
but no,
I definitely had a panic attack.
You can take a breather and staying in
the room.
You're supposed to breathe,
they tell you to breathe.
Can you can breed in the room who Stay
in the room.
It's a mental thing.
You can get by a five minute break.
Go.
Nope.
stay in the room.
You want to take a break?
Okay.
But no,
you don't have to have stayed before
too.
Yeah,
I stay all the time.
And you're not allowed to leave the
place that I go where you all are doing
it.
But this is yogurt and ice cream.
Cones melting in New York.
I could do them.
This is a super measurable thing.
okay.
So it's not like something you could not
train for and then have to do at the
very end.
This is going to go run a marathon.
I kinda like fucking half acid up to the
time you got to run it.
This is like a sheer discipline issue
because this is what the.
What's good about this is this going to
cause you to absolutely be in a certain
place for 15 days,
7:30.
You have to make those up.
Like if you like,
say you fuck off for the first 10 days,
that means you got to do a lot of days
in a row.
Would it be safe to do hot yoga four or
five days in a row?
A hunDred percent.
You are.
That's how I plan on doing it again,
bro.
Please just go to the goddamn bathroom.
No nothing.
So we're going to.
We're going to talk about nonsense,
but bullshIt.
Go to the bathroom,
go to the bathroom please.
And bring that goddamn kombucha with
you.
That juggle,
like pulling it off his desk with your
fucking attitude.
Are you looking to kind of rip right
now?
Ever since he got back?
Look bad at all.
That's very legit.
Looking good.
Like a good athlete.
Great shape in the christchurch texts.
my jeans right now.
That looks like,
are you?
Fuck this.
Like you always got a legit six pack.
He does.
When he came back from yoga or yoga asia
st.
Never understand.
I never wanted to do this challenge you
can listen to.
I like this idea of 15 days of hot yoga.
It's hard to do man,
90 minute classes and then and he's
going to do a marathon.
You have to do a marathon.
Okay,
this will be a different thing.
It's a totally new about this as he
thinks he coulD run all the time.
He runs all the time,
but if you have to do this,
this is going to be hard.
Running is easy for me because it's in
my backyard.
This is going to be super good for your
body.
And then here's the other thing too,
like if you get in the middle of this
and you feel like you can't do it
anymore,
you could relax.
You could just sit down,
lie down,
and just catching your class and your
class.
People do it all the time,
like advanced.
People do it all the time.
If you feel like you've overwhelmed
yourself,
maybe try too hard,
you know it's fucking hot in there.
So 140 degrees and you do like these
really difficult bodyweight exercises.
When you stand on one leg,
he got one leg kick back and you got
your both arms leaning forward.
It's fucking difficult to do.
Sure,
you know,
and when you're holding yourself and
like weird positions.
Oh,
that's good.
That's a really challenge.
It's a pretty easy,
not easy.
A pretty not hard pace I should say,
to do a five hour marathon.
So it's 11 minutes and 23 seconds per
mile walking at like a four point five.
Isn't that interesting?
That's fIve minutes,
but 11 minutes and 30 seconds per mile.
You get it in six hours or five.
It's 50 k oh,
50 percent.
Oh that's right.
I mean I know that we're all making fun
of this,
but oh,
a five hour marathon is,
is literally walking into four or five
on a treadmill.
No,
but continuously anyone can do a lot of
it is,
is it 11 miles an hour?
I'm walking on a treadmill walking.
It's not running.
It's not running,
but it's not 1130 minutes.
Pramada casual.
brisk walk.
But by the way,
I'll tell you,
I saw my father,
he'd walk the marine corp marathon and
he did great for about 20 miles and then
it bottoms out.
I did,
I did.
Uh,
when you did the thousandth episode,
I love these kinds of things.
I love when I watched the Florida state
game yesterday and got on the trip.
What you watched boxing matches or
fights when you work out?
Yeah,
I like to,
I like a big event thing,
like the ending of game of thrones and
you guys were doing that three hour
podcasts and I literally said I'm going
to be running a marathon today.
I did,
I did not do it.
I did not do it When I was seven.
I did 12,
12,
only half a marathon.
But I was walking in it because joe was
so fucking funny.
I would start laughing.
Like we said he's changing color for it
actually would funniest human being
that's ever lived.
Yes.
But I started laughing so hard that I
was like,
I can't fucking run this.
I want to listen to it.
I want to be in the moment and just
giggle.
Good excuse to stop running.
And so,
uh,
and so I ended up doing 12 miles.
And in the three hours you ever do do
the marathon.
I hope there's a hype crew behind your
goat just quit.
Just metro stops.
Like what would be a challenging time?
You think you could still do it in a
marathon?
Yeah.
I'm asking you a 10 minute miles.
Tommy tommy,
planning.
He's been plotting something miles,
which is how long?
Ten minute.
Ten minute mile.
That would be really fucking challenge.
I will say that the one that we just
pulled up is still very challenging.
What's forced one to 10 minute mile pace
for $20.
You're just.
You're no way.
One hundred percent agree.
Hundred percent.
Great shape.
There's not a chance.
There's a chance you won't finish the
marathon unless you take about 14 hours.
I'm not taking long,
long breaks for meals.
I think you do it in under 14 hours,
but maybe overall there should be like
third high,
13,
casually resting.
Seeing a movie in there.
I alsO want to know this really.
You think you could do this time with no
preparation,
no training.
Just do it tomorrow.
The 10 minute miles.
We're not tomorrow,
but next week.
How much distance do you think you could
run tomorrow?
The 18th to buck tomorrow?
Tomorrow.
How would you say since you think you
could run,
how much could you say,
god,
this is the worst.
This is the reason I.
This is the reason I'll never quit
drinking because I love this feeling
tomorrow.
What nerves are crippling?
Anxiety.
I'll say this.
I'll say,
I'll say it thing a thing.
I'll say number and you guys tell me if.
What do you.
Harry potter?
No,
bartering.
Bartering,
easily,
easily run a five k easy run a five k
over,
over.
Over on.
On that obviously.
Obviously.
Yeah,
I could run a 10 k.
No problem.
For sure.
The pre problems?
No,
no problem.
I could run hard and we're talking about
no walking,
right?
There's a straight up run.
Straight to system.
Okay.
What's your system?
I like to.
I like quoting.
Well no,
I like to.
I like to run and then walk,
so that's all I've been doing because
it's fun for me.
It helps me for awhile.
Walk for awhile or shut,
get it done.
I don't know.
I don't like this.
I'm sweating again.
I don't fucking like you.
Do you think you can do 20 miles
tomorrow?
Because that's six point two miles short
of new hype band.
Yeah.
No,
we know what we're Going with this joe.
AbsolutelY not knowing,
so anticlimactic sunup to sundown.
Twenty miles away.
Twelve hours,
12 hours.
You could one running period.
THat's a pace for a 13 and a half hour
marathon.
Exactly what he was talking about.
Just the way ladies who finds a wife
finds a way making it easier to
tomorrow's.
I plan on being at your house,
so I like bitch.
Let's go back to joe's challenge.
I like health.
I like,
okay.
Word 30 1:31
october.
All of october.
Excuse me.
Midnight to midnight,
midnight.
Just putting it out.
What happens?
No booze and less and less and let's do
thIs.
Let's let's let's look like a.
This might be cheesy,
but let's.
Let's make this communal so I can
challenge.
I can challenge people.
Go naipaul godsy,
no booze,
no boots.
You let everyone and have them commit to
the ankle bracelet
on happening.
It's difficult to do that.
Challenge,
I don't know,
but I don't think if we're going to do a
stand hope one,
we should find out whether or not you're
going to die.
We should start with me.
I'm going wait a minute,
but are you doing.
Are you doing the full thing or just
want to join and they can join,
you know,
the yoga and they keep bringing them
out.
We sHould be careful though.
Yeah,
of course.
This is one thing that we have to be
careful about bert dying the reality to
the sheer reality.
Like what is the volume of alcohol that
you consume on a daily basis?
Could quantify that.
So wait,
can I ask you a question?
Are you worried about the alcohol
business going on?
I'm worried about that.
Hit the economist.
What you're saying.
You like to join again?
That's what I was thinking.
We're going to tommy's house in speedos
after this.
Joe.
I wouldn't imagine anything else.
Oh my quantity and I'll be very candid
about this,
but.
But once again,
it's like a.
I don't talk when I hit this,
you'd made a fucking Joke last time,
but that ankle bracelet and I'm fucking
finally got that feeling out of my
throat.
Interesting.
So anyway,
I know how much you consume.
That's what you were today.
What's your average day like?
Let's be real about this shit.
pretend there's a flight or pretended to
fight the good fight days and not fight
it.
Let's just have a regular day.
Let's saY.
Let's pretend for some strange reason.
You're home for a month and you're not
traveling at all because I'm not in a
month for a month.
I'm not drinking,
not drinking.
If I'm home for a month,
I would not drink.
No drinking.
shows,
comedy store.
I went to the store and you were like,
hey,
let's have a drink.
I'll be the starter.
I was not drinking one night and we all
did this show.
You would come up to me and so maybe I
say,
maybe I drink,
drink.
Come on,
go about your drinking.
I'll take a picture.
I could show.
Okay for drinking.
Old boys were fucking drink.
Come on guys.
You're going to give me anxiety if I'm
the only one drinking.
It sounds so familiar.
Okay,
good.
I'm fuck.
I'm going to be really nice to see my
kids.
What's the actual.
You'll be fine.
We'll be fine.
What's the actUal consumption?
Yeah.
Let's say the average day.
I wouldn't Start drinking until I woke
up.
No,
no,
no.
I don't.
Let's hear it.
My average day right now is on the road
and I and I will drink.
I'll have my first sip of a drink.
The second step on stage.
I'll take a sip.
I'm,
I do not drink that whole drink and
there's a lot of people that have seen
me live recently and they can probably
all attest that they're bummed out that
I don't murder the drink on the first
show.
you've never drank fake drinks though.
Never drink for exchange and need to
know that.
Uh,
I remember,
uh,
I'll tell I'll call them out.
So I called him about on my podcast who
tell when I worked with him in my why
Hawaii,
miami,
miami.
I'm really high,
really high.
Like I wasn't a england.
I was in Hawaii,
Hawaii.
Why might confuse those two?
What do you think?
You didn't have a stroke,
you might tell didn't do real shot.
And I was like,
because he was my hero and on his room
and I was like,
hey.
I was like fuck.
But he doesn't drink.
He stopped drinking milk.
This is 2004.
I meT him.
Stop.
He stopped five years ago.
Ish.
A.
Yeah,
no shame in marin.
Started his podcast.
Olin is,
I know that aaron had them on and he
wasn't drinking.
I need you in skittles.
That's more than that.
Then that's like eight years.
So it's been awhile.
Probably.
Maybe the telecos moving.
I go,
yeah,
but I think,
I think uh,
I don't know what I was talking about.
I heard marin is when she went in that
new wrestling show on netflix to a bunch
of people that he kills it,
this female wrestling glow.
It's called crazy manager character and
he was great.
He kills it.
Really?
It's like,
yeah,
it's like the perfect role for him,
dude.
Have you seen any sort?
Psyched?
I heard it was really good about that.
I'm terrified.
I'm on.
I'm on episode three.
I'm freaking the fuck out.
Did you see the end of the game of
thrones?
Yes.
Right there.
There's too much good shit on you.
So.
But I was a kid.
We had starsky and hutch.
Okay.
Well we had itv made us dumber and it
was like eating cardboard.
That was horrible.
The difference between like what people
have today on tv.
It's insane.
Game of thrones and ozark.
just those two really good.
Haven't seen it.
You watched that first five minutes.
First 10 minutes of ozarks.
You're watching the whole scene.
Jason bateman in that.
He's domino.
The casting of his wife.
yes.
Brilliant.
Phenomenal.
By the way,
her name again?
What is laura?
Laura linney.
She's amazing.
Fucking show is so good.
You get so locked in like jesus,
like it's just,
it's just one of those shows were like,
whoa.
Best comedy on on streaming.
No questions asked.
Angie tribeca.
What's that?
It is.
It's true because she said her name
wrong and drove back from tribe back.
Guy jones quincy or angie jo.
Rashida jones.
Jones asked jamie.
He's a proLific tones.
Deon cole,
black,
twitter that guy,
and then andre vermilion.
What is this?
So it is the naked gun,
but in a csi miami type show,
but it's,
yeah,
it's a naked gun.
So it's,
it's,
it's like imagine if you saw a brand new
naked gun or a airplane.
So fucking funny.
And I watched it with my kids and we
just.
And they'd never seen an airplane.
So it's that introduction of airplane or
naked gun to them.
So they go for big jokes like the whole
time.
Yeah,
everything.
Just joke,
joke,
joke.
It's really a great show,
huh?
That's cool.
How do we get to that by burt?
Prior probably said no.
I said have you seen ozarks?
Oh yeah,
like gaMe of thrones ozark and there's a
neW season of narcos.
It's out to see that.
It's just more good television aliens
right now.
Don't you feel like it's hard for a
movie to even work now?
Like when you go to see movie,
most movies are done because they don't
have to go for it.
But you've seen the same show.
Netflix,
the same shot at hbo.
The level of like,
wow,
this looks fucking gorgeous.
They have thiS opportunity to stretch
out these storylines.
This season was a fucking seven hour
movie.
Amazing movie.
I've never watched it.
I never watched tommy tommy.
I will.
Shit.
I watched the pilot.
I watched the pilot episode of game of
thrones the other day just on a lark.
I was.
I was like,
what's this?
Because I saw the finale and I was so
into it.
You started with the finale?
No,
hold on,
hold on one second.
No,
no one's listening to.
This is all the fat and I watched.
I watched.
Oh my god.
I watched the whole series.
Yeah,
with everyone else.
I watched the finale and I was so
wrapped up in what was going on that I
want on my own.
Matriyoga go and I click the pilot
episode,
dude,
watch the pilot episode and you will say
to yourself,
oh shit,
I get it.
Like all these things that were a little
plots that how they got there,
dire wolf's.
I didn't know how they got the dire
wolves.
I didn't know that.
They found.
They found a big elk that had murdered
and they couldn't figure how it was
murdered and then they went and they saw
that the elks horn had gone through a
dire wolf and direwolves shouldn't be
south of the wall in one fell.
And so as John Snow picked up for dire
wolf's and cubs and he said she just had
cubs,
You should all have your cubs.
They should go to ned stark's children
and cause.
Cause he's not,
you know,
they shouLd go to the starks,
therefore starks keeps them all a dire
wolf.
And then.
And then the guy got his dick cut off,
he goes,
uh,
he shouldn't get one.
YOu're a bastard.
You're watching it or yeah.
This is like the machine you're
watchinG.
You're watching him do this long enough.
And then aS they leave they see a.
I see a fucking run one.
Yeah.
Right.
And they go,
you should have this one.
You're,
you're the bastard.
You should have this one.
Dude.
That was a book on tape.
That was pretty cool actually.
That was pretty good.
It was fucking murdering me.
My medicine at your house,
man,
I was right there with the last few
minutes.
You've been alive and talking to her.
She would never feature for me.
A lesson bombed so hard that if there is
a tape of this bombing,
it was so bad.
It's so hard that you broke it down on
your podcast.
What was that one?
That was winnipeg by the way.
This one's worse.
This one actually is worse.
Yeah,
because no one spoke.
it's true.
So it's just listening to someone
monologue in a room of people where
everyone's like,
oh,
tommy,
back at the time you stopped his hair a
little longer.
Need feather it back.
Right.
And so.
But he was still balding,
You know,
it's the hiding a body.
Men.
I bring them into the club,
I drive up with them,
I drive up with them to sacramento.
I say,
I vouched for him.
This guy's fucking lyrics.
You're gonna.
Love him.
The manager.
Leslie is like a.
We had a feature book.
I go,
this guy is 10 times funnier.
Trust me.
She was.
He better be.
He goes out in his first joke,
flies out to nobody and everyone,
and this girl leslie walked right up to
me and she goes,
he's,
you said he was going to be funny and I
see sweat forming on his brow,
bubbling up and then I see his hair
collapsed to the side and start getting
wet.
Tom tom,
look skeptIcal.
It was terrible.
No,
no,
he,
he.
It was worse than he was.
It's worse.
It was.
I remember it's 2005.
I opened on a rape joke.
It was about hurricane katrina,
hurricane katrina rape joke because it
was,
it was,
it was right after katrina.
They said that people were getting
raped,
the metrodome.
So I did this thing,
but I was like,
what is it?
The super dope,
the metronomes would sits on a piano.
I made like some type of joke,
like,
like he like,
hey,
they say there's something.
Like they say,
people are getting raped in the
aftermath,
like nothing would turn me on,
like seeing a dead body float by like
some,
some or things like that where I'm like
making fun of it.
But like it wasn't a written joke,
it was just something that I said and
then I insisted on doing it a second
time and that's when the,
that's when the hair falls to the side
and capital.
I sweated it off.
Like I bombed on the,
I opened with it and I bombed for 25
straight minutes actually 22 because
when I got off she goes,
why didn't you do 25?
And I was like,
because I was dying and I thought,
and she was like,
I pay you for 25.
Oh mY.
And then I opened the second show on the
same joke and I ate equal shit for 25
minutes to it again,
I should say it was sold out.
So it was wall to wall packed,
peppered 300,
300 people.
And I was just like soaking wet.
And I remember the uh,
what was the mc?
Tommy.
Oh yeah,
tom.
Oh fuck,
goddammit.
Oh,
tom mcclain,
tom,
and you know you're eating shit when
you're the feature act and you walk in
the green room when the mc is like,
oh man,
you fuck.
Like,
oh.
He was like,
I've never seen anyone eat shit like
this in my life.
So crazy.
by the way,
this is a testament.
This is a testament to tom,
is that you like mutually.
If you brought a common companies bomb
that hard,
you'd be like,
I'll never talked to this guy again.
Like maybe you shouldn't be doing
comedy.
TOm talking to me in the green room
about his bombing or at the bar after
was me.
I remember we drove home on that ride
and I was like,
oh,
this is my new best friend.
Yeah,
that was great.
I do.
I also remember that when we got back to
la,
you go,
you didn't talk much and I know that's
because you were talking.
Do you remember the time you were like
you were talking about two different
memories of an event?
Actually,
he said,
I think I told you this before,
but you say he saved my ass because I
bombed so hard and think about.
Think about a straight uP 25 minute bomb
and then on the late show doing it
exactly the same again.
I know you guys are wrong.
I'll show you.
Yeah,
you do it.
I think I was convinced that I could
make that,
that stupid thing like I was like,
I want to.
I want to get it right,
so I'm going to do it.
I'll show them.
I can do that.
Right?
Rather than public is thinking.
This similar thing is hurricane harvey
right now.
People are coming together and you're
making a fucking rape or dead body.
I wasn't encouraging.
And what did you adjust?
What did you adjust on the late show?
I just thought that get it,
sit down with it and go.
Let me try to pick this.
I was like,
they were 2005.
How many years have you been doing
comedy?
It was my third year.
Oh wow.
He's my damn.
that's a slippery time,
right?
Well,
and then in the hotel or I'm not going.
I was like,
man,
this fucking is this where it's going to
be like I really fucked up over those
two bombings of how I met and then I got
back in time.
I mean it was,
it was pretty rough.
I got the next day was saturday,
so that was friday night to ethic
bombings and then saturday for show's
about to start and I could see these
guys are like eyeballing me.
Like,
yo man,
this is like,
like I'm a make a wish kid or something
like,
you gotta like me,
not me.
Well no,
but then you came up to me,
you go,
can I give you one piece of advice?
You drank and then you were letting you
go,
uh,
you go just open with a different chart,
just do everything else that you wanted
to do the same open with a different
joke.
And I go,
okay,
okay.
And then it went,
it went amazing.
Here's how shitty it was.
Like that manager loves the night before
it was like,
this is like,
you really a dog shit up.
They're white.
It's like,
I don't think,
I mean that's terrible.
She was me.
I was like,
ah.
So saturday it was also full and it
fucking,
it was like an epic show.
It was like exactly what yOu'd want
after a bombing like that.
And they had a curtain like this
separating the showroom from the bar,
like not even a wall,
just a curtain.
So after,
after my set,
he's on stage,
I just opened the curtain and I go,
well,
like nice recovery,
right?
She goes,
what happened?
I was back here.
Oh you heard that shit.
Horse
man do the same shit to me the first
time I've featured there,
she criticized me and then I uh,
I,
I did a good feature set and she was
like,
I was like,
what dId you think?
She was like,
didn't hear it.
And I was like,
oh fuck you,
you boys sound salty.
Yeah.
Well sophos is tough club to do.
That was a bounced check me to shout out
to steve groves.
I'll say his name.
I bombed once in South Carolina,
one on golfing trip with my college
friends,
high school friends.
Hughes me,
we went out there and I did a guest spot
at the coconut,
something in charleston and then we were
driving like a day later and some girls
were like,
you know,
because the vacation town,
they were like,
ooh,
like screaming at us in some ways,
like what are they saying?
And someone's like,
oh,
there's that guy who bombed last night
because I didn't mention it when I got
off stage it was like,
let's go.
Oh,
you want you wanna hear good bombing
story.
Yeah.
The comedy corner in atlanta,
I just don't stand up one time and I
signed up for the comedy quarter
atlantic's,
my girlfriend lived there.
So when mike night open mic night,
sign up,
I show up to an all black club,
but I'm unaware of the way open mic
night worse.
So I buy tickets for me and her and they
set us up front to watch white people.
The oNly two white people in the whole
room.
First guy comes on stage and starts
making fun of me and says,
uh,
what's your name?
I said,
it's burt.
And they go nuts.
I'll we're going to call you birdie.
Burt will give you a hood name is birdie
birdie.
I was like,
yeah,
yeah.
It's great and they make fun of me.
Every black comic comes oN,
make fun of me for fucking ever.
Then he gets the end of the show and was
like,
we got one more comment to come up last
time.
A good evening.
Ladies and gentlemen,
put your hands together for burger.
Crikey,
great teacher.
Honestly,
and then he goes,
oh wait,
oh shit.
It's birdie part and the place goes
fucking nuts.
This is the guy that had been fucking
with the whole night and I get up on
stage.
I go,
you guys ever jack off and a
cheeseburger and the guy they liked and
we're rooting for started sucking.
They fucking lit me up on stage like
I've never to this day been lit up and I
had no comeback.
Side note.
I was like,
ah dude.
They fucking went from love to hate in
an incident with one joke.
How uncomfortable was it after the show?
Oh yeah,
dude,
I in down in buckhead.
We be lined out of that motherfucker and
put guide.
The guy sitting next to her.
We were like,
oH,
he suck.
He's telling you like,
hey man,
she was a.
She was a good girlfriend except for all
this stuff,
but like she was the only one that got
me into comedy,
which he said,
well,
what?
She said,
no,
you were fine.
A little delusional about like how good
you had to be to do it.
She was like,
yeah,
you're great.
That was great.
You handled it well.
You were in a bad situation.
Chris to krista medoc,
she's.
She was pretty right with.
That's your second time ever on stage.
Second time on stage at the comedy
corner fence,
but,
but the no,
because fight somebody who when they
said,
oh shit,
it's birdie.
Bert.
The place went nuts.
I was the guy that they'd been fucking
with all night.
They lOve this guy.
Like if he's you today,
you would just murder that crowd.
Getting in a time machine letting these
motherfuckers know what's up.
Yeah,
just boom back.
Oh shIt.
It's birdie,
birdie 300,
80 percent of three 79 and he got flat
feet,
flat feet.
He's aside 13 but not really fat ass
feet and run a marathon because your
feet so fat.
So what do you think you can do?
we got to go do the cath lawn.
If you can do this ridiculous thing that
you probably can't do.
Okay.
What by the way,
I'm going to regret,
uh,
this part of my life.
Why?
Because I don't mind that I don't.
I like,
I think I would like to challenge myself
to the yoga and the,
and the not drinking,
but I do want to incorporate it into us
[inaudible] like I want it to be.
I liked having people to talk shit to
you on text.
Yeah.
Like,
and I know that you guys will be like,
are you drinking the night or whatever.
But like I'm gonna get a court people on
the outside,
but I don't know.
I think it should be.
I like to see the cap on idea.
Um,
I don't,
I don't have a problem.
Try and run a marathon.
But I do think tom said he didn't like
the idea to me personally because he was
like,
there's just no payoff.
Like it's like you fall for sure.
Quit.
Well for sure.
No.
So then what's the point?
It's not.
Maybe it was the weight loss challenge
or the drinking.
Not drinking challenge.
You can keep up with.
Yeah,
I don't think you can do that,
but normal people could.
I'll do it.
People with that problem.
Ninety days,
no one needs 30,
91 days.
Thirty days,
75 days.
Thirty two days.
Thirty days.
Eight days.
So can I say you can't drink or be drunk
during all of us?
Get it through his veins.
Call are going to be fucking drunk the
whole first night because it shouldn't
be drink for six hours.
And he's telling me.
Ask you this though.
Seriously.
For our own peace of mind,
like all jokes aside,
we don't have to worry about withdrawal
symptoms with you,
charlie.
I'm serious.
The metro,
the metro.
You think that we would rest easy.
I don't do this.
I say,
we don't do this unless you get the
charcoal pills and have metro house.
Well,
I don't think that's good enough.
I mean if you're really going through
the shakes were fine.
Can't belIeve where.
Can we have your doctor sign off on it?
One hundred percent.
Okay guys,
you can run a marathon.
EasY and he's in great shape.
Yeah,
no problem.
I hope I do know I'm going to be fine.
You're actually doctor,
not like fucking bullshit aside.
Like what?
What is the last day you didn't drink?
How long ago?
the wait.
We never even got to how much you drank.
Yeah.
How much do you still didn't say let's
just do this.
Let's just do it for a regular day.
Like what is that?
Then we'll do a travel guy.
I'll just tell you a little story.
Tom said this is better than the game of
thrones one.
Okay.
But how much do you normally drink
though?
for just do it?
Yeah.
Let's just,
let's just tell a story.
Just about to,
uh,
yesterday we had a half a handle of
tito's and we were going over to our
friend's house and of course,
and I said we should get a full bottle
of tito's thinking that there will be
more people there that would want
tito's.
yeah.
And she said,
I'm being dead serious.
If you go through a half handled tito's,
you have a legit problem.
Who said this?
Leanne and I still had an entity that
was when I came home last night.
So that's after the problem.
It's a lot,
but that's a lot of booze.
And after you cleared anotHer handle,
like this is.
No,
no,
no.
What's it just handle it?
It's the big thing.
It's probably drank at the party.
No,
it's more than.
That.
Handles more than that.
With the actual handle.
That's why they call the handle.
Yeah.
When's the last time he didn't do that?
A few days ago.
So few days ago.
What happened?
Do you drink at all?
No,
I didn't drink at all.
Fifty nine ounces or just sleep through
the day?
Thirty ounces.
So essentially you drank.
Did you play music on that once a
quarter?
A quarter of a handle to one shot.
Avant is one and a half ounce.
So you're basically drinking like 50
ounces.
That's what you're watching me drink
right now,
but I'm barely anything by the way,
but I.
I'm still buzzed.
What do you mean the amount of booze
you're talking about that much if
that's.
No,
no,
it's fine.
No,
don't bullshit.
Bullshit me that.
Yeah,
of tito's a lot.
If he can drink a half of one of those
cordage I said a quarter.
Okay.
Hang on one second.
I can also drink a good point.
I think it's going.
I noted that it's also scotch much last
10 or 15 shots.
30th five shots in the handle.
There's 35 shots in the hand,
so half of that 15 shots.
I'm drinking seven shots.
Shots,
shots,
shots with that?
Three hours?
60 shots over 35.
One and a half ounces.
I'm saying if I drank that much I'd for
sure bar.
Oh,
okay.
Yeah,
you're right.
You're right.
Yeah.
I feel like I don't want this to get
away from anyone.
What about on a flying day?
Okay,
what's good?
What's going on?
Maybe I'm being dead serious.
You guys are my friends.
You.
We'd love your shit.
Yeah,
I'll be honest.
But let's,
let's not go fucking overboard.
Boom.
We're going to make Jokes though,
you know,
listening to remember.
I like you guys.
We'd like you to you guys.
We're like,
okay.
Here we go.
Do you think it's Funny?
That's great.
Okay,
go ahead.
So,
uh,
we'll just shoot.
An average flight is at 7:00
AM.
Bars are open.
Uh,
I bring a full bottles with tito.
Little baby bottles in my bag.
But you drink on the way to get them in
your bag.
Let me just tell you guys.
Okay.
I pack him in the side.
You could allow allowed to travel wIth
up to eight bag that you check your bag
in my bag.
Like a could bring on eight,
eight little bottles.
Little bottles.
Yup.
I'll bring it to Singapore.
You're allowed eIght.
So you bring it,
bring it,
bring liquid on a plane.
It's small doses to liquid liquid
drinks.
Like a little tiny baby shots the size
of your library.
I'm saying I trust the extra on that.
Yeah,
I fly a lot.
I love you.
I'm just.
I'm stunned.
You think on the job like a drink.
I think the thing is that like if you
walked through with this and a little
bit,
they say no way.
It's that he has a small bottle with a
small amount of that volume but also a
tricky problem.
Right.
So they must have at that point look at
him and go,
yeah,
okay,
sure.
Yeah.
You need this medicine,
those little bottles.
That's crazy.
It's a crazy number.
And so.
But this,
you put those in your bag but you've
also made a drink before you left the
house.
Nope.
No,
we're talking.
I,
I'm talking to my worst travel day and
this is on the rig on a sunday when I
fly home.
No,
I want an average day.
Let's just start with way back.
So you get to the airport.
Yeah.
A don't eat anything.
Don't eat anything because there's
nothing in the airport.
It's just going to give it away.
But I'm still concerned with my food
intake so I won't have like an egg
sandwich or that protein.
Oh,
okay.
I guess the better than eating it,
I guess.
Yeah.
So then,
so you,
you get to the airport,
you get through security and then what
do you do a go find a place to scout the
food court for who has started foam
cups.
Because if you have paper cups,
the vodka will cut the seam and your
drink and collapse on your lap
sometimes.
So I find it's got a place for styrofoam
cups or plastic cups.
Mcdonald's.
Shout out to mcdonald's,
go over,
say hey,
can I get an orange juice?
And a big,
a 32 ounce cup of ice.
And then I go into the bathroom or
pretend take shit a crack for.
Sounds like a proud guY.
Bottles for them in the cup.
Pour the orange juIce and pants off
while you're doing this.
So you pour the orange juice?
I do,
I do.
I do take a dump while you're doing
this.
I take some time for the sometimes yeah,
sometimes you're in position to take a
dump during a naked sadness.
I get so excited when I sit down and
it's a warm toilette.
How long does it take you to get through
that drink?
I don't drink it.
So you put them all in before and sorry
for,
for in vivo and go to the and then go to
the airplane and Just wait.
And then,
and I now for me personally,
my anxiety is cut in half because I know
I have a cocktail if I need one,
God damn.
And then I get on the plane,
I sip it and I pass out.
What was the last gentleman?
And you generally don't drink those
other four?
He drank them up.
Maybe.
Maybe I do.
Maybe I do like he had eight I thought.
Oh no,
no.
I just drink for because I.
Because I want for,
for the flight safety,
for the flight home.
Oh yeah.
These rItuals or like I'm sure.
I mean so that's going to be a really
tough time.
Just flew sober one year ago was a
phoenix.
Not a big flight,
but I talked to your wife about it.
Uh,
what I,
what I've noticed is if I did a row of
unassisted sleeps and then the night
before the flight took a xanax.
Yeah,
at like five.
Then when I woke up the xanax was
effectively still in my system and there
was no panic and uh,
and I flew.
I flew to Minnesota sober and back sober
and I was like,
ooh.
Uh,
and then I did phoenix and then I did
the hot wings thing,
hot challenge,
and I the next night I was like,
my stomach's fucked.
I was an panic.
The panic from just how my brain works.
What do you mean?
Like what do you thinks is from doing x
10 college?
what do you center on?
What do you,
what do you.
is that a phrase I like?
Is it a fright or just overall panic?
That's more like a dread anxiety,
right?
Being up in the air.
dread of the fact that I can't get out
and then it might explode at any second
and I can't stop that.
And then I just like right now.
Right?
Right now you're gonna blow up right
now.
I'm going to pull up.
He had that thought.
If I'm sober man on a flight,
I cry sometimes like the legit cry.
So I have to wear bring sunglasses on.
Dude.
I am so ritualistic on airplanes.
You have no fucking idea.
I have.
I have to drink.
I have to have a cocktail when I get on
the plane because if I don't have it
then I started panicking.
I can't,
I can't take a xanax because sometimes
you get delayed and then you just
fucking.
How much would you drink on that flight
to Singapore?
You think the foods that give you free
boots,
those flights aren't super bad.
They're not as bad for me.
let me ask you this.
Talk about.
Have you ever thought about trying to
manage the way your mind about things
instead of like thinking about
medicating it?
No.
Just try to put yourself in a position
where you try to manage your paranoia or
your thoughts and guys are coming in to
sort of reject them and use some
meditation techniques to relax.
Like,
but what have yOu ever done?
like meditation,
while I haven't done,
I haven't done tom and everyone
suggested to him transcendental
meditation.
That's a weird one,
right?
A lot of people think that's like very
cultish.
You know,
There was a lot of criticism of that,
but I know a lot of like super
successful people like that.
It's a lot of weird articles on
meditation.
People get like a,
they get weird about other people trying
to be enlightened.
It's really interesting like people
start shitting on people like
mindfulness is bullshit bullshit because
it seems like if you're writing
mindfulness is bullshit.
Like for you it's probably bullsHit
because you're writing a fucking article
on people trying to look at things
objectively with clarity and be in the
moment instead of like be scattered and
cast about by the momentum of their past
and all the things happening around them
where it takes them out of control.
The idea is to try to like be in the
moment like,
sure,
how could that be bullshit?
It can't be.
It's like it literally can't be bullshit
because you're trying to like just be
like an easier person to deal with,
get through life smoother.
How can it makes me like people of
faith.
I would love to have faith stage.
I loved up faith,
great benefits to religious beliefs as
long as they're positive religious
beliefs.
If you could have a perfect religion
like a religion that didn't have all the
contradictions and hypocrisy and crazy
shit about like killing people that were
two different types of cloth or hey,
the weird shit that is in any ancient
text that gets translated into modern
times.
If you could create something that gave
you like a are like a rock solid,
sensible ethic that was based on like
science and the reality is what we know
and how vulnerable we really are and how
big the universe really is.
If somebody can read,
rewrite something where they weren't
trying to control people with it,
they weren't asking for donations.
They were Just trying to like set out a
way to look at the world and a clear
Framework that's open to all
possibilities but allows you to move
through.
This time and space in the most
harmonious manner with our fellow
brothers and sisters,
that's what we all missing because we're
too smart for the old,
stupid shit about people walking on
water and coming back from the dead
people.
I could,
if maybe it's an allegory,
maybe it's a parable.
Maybe it's based on some ancient story
that means something different,
but we lost it all in the translation.
We need something else because we're too
open ended and people get super
concerned with it.
Not meaning anything ultimately at the
end,
but what it means for sure.
Something is right now.
If you have good friends and you enjoy
your life,
then it means something.
For sure.
For right now.
There's no denying that.
Like in the moment it means something
and you can be an ils.
YOu could be.
You know,
you have this fatalistic view of the
future,
but if you look at the moment right now,
it always means something.
It always means something to be enjoying
yourself.
That's all you have.
You definitely said some things that
align with buddhism though.
Yeah,
that for sure.
Yeah.
It's all that was all connected
together.
People have had all these ideas for
thousands of years where they realized
like moments in their life where they
got it right.
You know those moments in your life
where you have a near death experience,
you almost get run over by a buffalo or
something like that and you just
standing there looking at each other and
it all makes sense.
Yeah.
what,
what matters is like love and friendship
and the moment,
the that,
the life that you're experiencing right
now.
I.
This is cool right now,
right?
Yeah.
Like,
remember That time you didn't drink for
five days?
That was a long time ago,
but it's probably the way I remember
riding a bike for the first time I made
the decision either way.
No,
you're not.
Hey,
can I tell you something?
Once again,
we're the secret time here.
Uh,
the last time I didn't drink for a long
stretch.
I had this moment of clarity where I
went.
I haven't made a lot of decisions as an
adult sober.
Like I didn't,
I didn't pick to get into standup sober.
I was the number one party in the
coUntry.
I'll just FuCking moved to New York.
Do you believe those rankings?
Do you think there's no one out there
that was fucking doing it up to the
university of detroit at a party animal.
Rolling stone.
Never contacted motherfuckers into a
carnal mind.
There's definitely some maniacs.
Oh,
there were guys in my math.
There was a guy named collin who little
bowl.
One time it was so high he passed out
and the bowl landed on his cheek and it
burned up.
What's the most embarrassing thing
you've ever done?
The where you fell asleep.
I couldn't tell you one.
One.
I did it awake when you felt sober.
I'll give you ever gone down on a girl
and fell asleep on her pussy.
No way.
No,
no.
You have.
I did.
Jesus christ.
Oh my gosh.
You have narcolepsy.
Ring pussy.
Shit.
If it was wonderful,
but I was delivering newspapers like it
was gone with the wind newspapers in the
standard a bit late,
so it was getting up every morning like
5:00
in the morning and I was working every
night and then during the day I would
work too.
I do do a bunch of different shit during
the day just trying to like just pay my
bills.
I was always tired.
I was working for a private
investigator.
That was like,
a lot of what I did was drive around
this private investigator following
people.
Yeah.
It was a lot of in insurance cases and
shit like that.
but meanwhile I was always tired,
like so tired and one time I was going
down and I just fucking conked out.
What did she do?
She got so mad.
She gets so mad and I might try to do
that.
Like I'm not.
I'm not happy to be that tired.
It's not like you're boring.
Like I'm breaking myself,
broke down.
I'm breaking myself.
Working out.
I was still kickboxing.
I was doing stand up comedy.
I was getting up in the morning.
I was delivering newspapers,
falling asleep when I was.
I was working all day.
Then I was getting to the gym that I was
sparring,
that I was going out and doing standup
and after I was doing standup I go over
house and eat pussy sometimes it just
black.
She was like halfway to comments.
You could feel it though the horizon
coming.
And I was like,
wait,
what?
Oh come on.
We got so mad at me.
I was only 21 or whatever it was.
That's good.
Move.
Come in there.
Sometimes it happens.
You got to put ice in her bus,
trying to get a third peanut butter.
I fell asleep like a,
you know,
like when like college,
like after making out but like you're
still like cuddling and I,
I start snoring and she was like fuck
this shit.
We thought like,
you know,
I've had them snow.
What time do we have left?
What is this?
What is this bet?
Yeah.
We got to do the best we got to do this
man.
And you gotta tell them to come over.
It's definitely sober.
Sober for october,
but yeah,
and I'm not drinking fucking october.
Perfect.
I like it.
That's perfect.
That's what I just said.
I came up with it.
All right.
Sounds it really sounds like a t shirt.
Yeah.
Sober knoxville.
I'm sure it's already been bought.
No,
you guys didn't make a t shirt so we're
not sober.
October.
Sell at your mom's house.
Darko.
I would never wear that.
Says he's the one who didn't put her on
your podcast.
So fructose outline of a like a soup
that.
That picture of burt with like the
obese.
That outline of october.
Sell it to bert.
Bert.
What is this product over there?
Sober.
How about october when these kids are
like,
good,
let's just add to that whatever.
Raise money for cancer support.
No.
Fuck that.
Or get drunk and partY.
Fuck's wrong with you.
How about we do burt's birth sober in
october.
No one's got that.
You can have a teacher that says sober
for october.
I'm sure they'll tell like a copyright
on that.
Franken available right now.
If they have a website,
[inaudible] dot com.
You can get those.
That's why they get websites.
They no one gets away.
I had to buy a bunch of stuff.
did you know that somebody made like.
not@ourpromptingmadeburntchrysler.com.
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Once we just said it.
It's already out there.
It's not good either.
Get really give the guy a little slack.
Probably not.
No,
no.
He,
I mean it's not exactly what.
They did a great job and they're all
fatter than me.
I know you meet them.
I meet them.
Hold on.
Joe fatter than me.
And you and you see their moms and their
moms are fucking obese,
like 400 pounds and then I guy a fat
fuck.
And you were like at the time you were
like,
I'm the same category as you're
medically medically I.
Yeah.
Medically I was.
Did you ever consider the possibility of
those people are like tests given to you
by the universe to see if you can
navigate the waters of stupidity without
barely getting wet.
You can't get that back to skirt around
them with like a kito,
like an old steven seagal demonstration
video.
I wish move.
I,
I just,
I don't like confrontation,
so I just go,
yeah,
just glide path.
So you're better now.
I think less.
I think if we weighed you and we will at
times you'll be less than you were
during the way and challenge.
I drank a lot of tito's and soda.
You got okay.
You got to piss a few times.
So we're in october,
october and october.
We'll get that tight.
Jamie.
We buy that real quick.
Silver october solver.
Someone got it.
So wait,
wait,
whoever bought it,
send it to me and tom over for october.
No pills?
No anytHing.
Step charcoal pills if you need them.
What's your will?
Definitely serious.
And your doctor's note.
We need to know a real number.
Like how many drinks do you drink a day?
We never got clay.
Wait,
what's the physical on top of this?
This dead?
Four shots.
Four shots of a.
Of a run of vodka.
How many shannon,
when you land you get more.
How many drinks do you have in a normal
day?
Today's what?
Monday?
Well normal.
It's not normal.
We're all right now.
I'll tell you right now,
it's labor day,
right?
You got to get a job.
I know that if I smoke weed,
my alcohol intake disappears entirely
and I start slowing down.
Hence a three hour conversation.
I've only had that.
That's something that's an okay and a
few sips of your scotch.
but I didn't like it.
So I went back.
I don't like scotch.
it did.
Reminds me of medicine.
So fucking rude.
and so I know that if I go to toMmy's
I'm going to loosen up and I'm going to
work.
Throw on speedos.
We're all getting the pool.
Yeah.
And then,
uh,
I,
I wouldn't be shocked if I'd killed this
whole bottle today in one day.
No,
I don't think anyone would be shocked.
All right.
What else?
Shocked.
Shocked is not a thing that came up in
that conversation.
And so what I'll do is,
uh,
I'll wean my,
I will wean myself from booze,
but we didn't ever give us a number.
How many a day?
Oh yeah.
How many drinks a day?
How many drinks is that?
How many drinks at a bar?
Deliberate.
Single drink.
You know how many hours,
how many of you had doubled again?
Doubled.
Tito's and soda.
How many if what do you mean the number
of drinks?
If you're hanging out at a bar,
let's say you're at a bar to drink.
We're not playing.
We're not playing dumb.
I'm afraid to be honest.
Be honest,
be honest,
be honest.
We not funny.
You probably get like six would
definitely be like a very comfortable
number.
What do you mean?
What do you mean comfortable?
Six double six.
Double 12 drinks in a bartender's poor.
Comfortable number.
You mean like that's mean a line.
And are you hammered at the end of that?
Yeah,
and I,
by the way now if I,
if I drink.
So when the.
Hold on,
slow down.
If I drink at
say a word,
I just have weed wherever.
I just have weed in Arizona.
Some of denver I would have to smoke
weed.
Yeah.
And then I have two more and I go to
bed.
Okay.
So forth.
Still a lot.
So I'm partying tonight by the way,
stan.
Hope.
If I mean I'll,
I'll,
I'm.
Here's the.
To be as honest comes.
Do you hope know is under the bus.
I want to know.
I'm super honest with you guys.
I'm being honest,
but when talking to stan hope I do this.
Did we do this on a podcast and a super
honest about a rock wall intake?
I wouldn't say no.
I don't remember.
And I forgot immediately.
Stand up.
Well,
I'll tell you what,
one of the most beautiful things that
standing up and I said is people go,
uh oh yeah.
I quit drinking because I like getting a
good night's sleep.
And I was told stan hope.
He's like that ridiculous.
I go,
yeah,
I'm going to quit drinking,
striking,
use chopsticks in the morning,
doing no jet eating sushi sashimi in the
morning.
Like at like 11:00
AM after you've had partied hard.
It's not doable.
Yeah,
it's a little bit of a struggle,
but I'd definitely say it would be
doable on your hands trying to keep up,
shake chopsticks,
shakes,
shakes.
No question.
You have a problem,
but we're going to be.
That's a true statement.
Is that a true statement?
Yeah,
I legit right now.
Right now.
Uh,
I'm,
we've talked about this a bunch,
but like I'm pushing myself way too
hard,
the
capability to do.
Okay.
THis is what I think we should do.
What I think we should do in all
earnestness.
It's like we,
we haven't even,
we're in september.
What?
Well,
what is September 4th.
Okay.
Why don't we give ourselves a week and
we could do this again and sit down and
see what you think about whether or not
you could wean yourself off slowly or
whether you even want to do it.
I do.
This is what I really want you.
I really want you to think about it
because I think that I think you could
either decide to not just live your life
the way you live in,
which is obviously very successful.
People love to see you party with them.
They love you.
I mean,
it's a big part of the fund that you're
in,
you're having,
you're enjoying with your standup comedy
career,
but legitimately like as friends,
when you see someone who's taken in that
much alcohol,
you start getting nervous and you start
getting like,
okay,
how long can you do that?
Like,
um,
that's,
that's tricky.
That's super dangerous.
It's not dangerous.
It really isn't that.
It's dangerous to have 12 drinks a day.
Hold on man.
This is why.
Oh no,
no,
no.
I'm taking the financing.
I'm sorry.
No,
I'm not taking the fun out of it,
but I'm saying that if you do that all
the time to do an intervention,
this was turning into the sad shit.
I'm just being honest and being honest
about that.
Number one thing that's
you have to admit is a fair thing is
like,
you do see that,
like let's say if you were examining,
let's say your last week,
you realize it,
that that pace could not continue for
every 100 percent didn't with you.
No one can keep up with you.
I took two naps close to keeping up with
You.
We talk about it all the time,
lIke how the fuck does he do it?
like this is the opposite of what I
wanted out of this.
Yeah.
I think it just turns into like a.
People go,
oh shit,
he's really got a problem,
but that's what it's turning into this.
Don't listen to me joe.
I can't.
You're overreacting.
What I'm saying is you could live your
life the way you're living at right now
and you're obviously enjoying yourself
or I don't know if you think you have a
problem,
if you feel like you have a problem and
I don't want to make any judgment
whatsoever,
I literally want you to act the way you
feel because you can hunter s thompson
this thing right into the grave and a
lot of people have done it and they
probably had a better life than people
that have lived sober and regretful and
and deepen melancholy states of mind
until you know their fucking body shuts
down.
I don't know what's better.
I don't know if a a short life filled
with partying is better than a long life
of meditating and we're in an orange
robe.
I mean there's a real good argument that
it's not because a real good argument
that the party life is a better life,
but what I think about any type of
situation like this,
I don't want to change the way you
think.
I want you to Do whatever the fuck you
want to do.
That's why I said that already in the
car.
I was like,
I can't do 90 days.
It's not the Way my brain operates
because.
But I'm sorry to interrupt you,
but this is really important.
Do you think that it's possible that
once you got into it and once you were
in 20 days deep and you realize like you
can feel better every day and keep going
at that point,
right?
You could like I think part bert is
going to get out of the first 10 to fit.
I'm not a fucking doctor.
I don't know what,
what it's like when people have
withdrawal from alcohol,
but you are 100 percent right?
The hardest part,
10 days or so.
It was probably sunday morning and the
dc airport.
Yeah.
That'll be the hardest part.
And by the way,
by the way,
I've,
I've definitely done this like I've
definitely not drank for fucking five
days.
Like it's totally doable and I'm not
going to die.
That's the other thing that.
Well we were a little worried about you.
You have to admit that the concern for
that,
like it's.
I don't think you're gonna die but,
but having the thought like,
hey,
my friend who drinks like 80 drinks a
day,
he's going to stop drinking.
You know,
you have to have as a friend.
You go,
is that a safe?
No,
no,
I don't.
I honestly,
I don't think you got the shAkes.
I think he'll just drink again because
there was no way you can do fucking 30
days.
I think that if he can get past a
certain number of hours,
the longer you can get past this,
there's like six.
It's like,
listen man,
this is really what it's like.
It's like gravity.
It's like when you're closer to the
planet earth is there's
a lot more gravity and you got to get
further and further and further and once
you do,
you can see what you're saying.
I see what the gravity of alcoholism
clearly wrapped up in it.
It's.
I wouldn't,
I wouldn't say alcoholism because I
don't,
but the only because when you really
call it,
call it you to get away from babu and
figure out a way to not need alcohol
every day.
I think you can do this.
I think you can do it,
but I think it's a good challenge.
We we're down to 60 days,
30 days,
31 days.
Thirty one days or bust.
Here's the deal.
Just keep it rocking in the free world.
And burt.
Okay.
If you can do october,
we're going to do it sober.
Sober sober.
October.
November.
So bourbon.
So are you participating?
Are you doing it?
He won't do it.
I don't have a problem.
I enjoy drinking.
Alcoholic set.
Go ahead and keep saying it weird.
Getting drunk.
Is that how we make it?
Is that how you make it like a,
you know,
or is it.
It'll be enjoyable for me,
but listen,
I'll do it.
It's super easy that I could easily do.
Or do you feel.
Do you feel like we're picking on you?
Because that's what I really wanted to
make sure we avoided.
It got serious for a second.
They got serious for a second.
Most the strongest amount of mocking of
you possible without hurting your
feelings.
That's what we're going for.
First of all,
here's a look.
Fuck.
Jimmy can get more ice.
Everybody loves you.
So I understand that.
I understand that,
but we both know shoulder to cry on.
I can put my tee shirt on.
We both know that when we did this
fashion shit yet it got out of control
like this out of control doors.
Intellectual like,
hey,
you know,
I like you,
right?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
That's what joe just said.
I need.
I've had.
I've had a real moments with every
single one of you and I know you're my
friends.
I know that you're not.
You don't talk behind my back.
All this shit that bad friends do.
I know that shut up,
but like there is a part of me that goes
to do something stupid.
We keep our mouth shut.
I have talked about know what were
talking about.
Oh man.
If,
if it gets to the point where you can't
mock each other,
I just don't want to be here.
Yeah,
yeah.
It does.
It does sometimes and you're like,
hey,
everyone likes me.
Right guys,
love you.
We love you,
but I,
I hear you're the best.
If you stop drinking,
you could lose 15,
20 more years.
It's going to be first month.
Actually.
It will ruin your brand.
Do marathons.
He will win marathons.
He will weigh a hundred and 48 pounds.
You will have your shirt off stage and
how the shippers from being so fucking
cold and then it's going to be weird.
They're not going to be happy.
We take your shirt off and you got a six
pack.
No,
he shredded.
You got lattes and do this.
Oh,
you got to stretch my back with that
side.
So my dad lives in Florida,
which was 40 pounds.
This sounds like though it's just a bird
challenge.
Is that what I'm doing?
We should all get in on something.
What I.
That's one of the reasons why I was
saying it's already 3:30.
Maybe we should like,
we have to happen.
It will happen.
They'll challenge.
You can do this and then you have to
fucking fake this in shape.
Challenge against us.
How about I get to pick the next
challenge?
You,
but you're not going to America.
It was so gross way you said it,
dude.
I felt my bucket and he said it like
garth brooks and business,
social media friends and low.
Is it?
Is it out of?
Is it out of a brand?
No,
you can get clean for me.
This is for me to get like napalm,
like get people to help me back.
Me and during this challenge or they'll
fill up.
That'll make you feel better or
something.
No kidding.
Like standard.
Like oh,
okay.
And standup's like amen.
If you're in I'll do it.
Okay.
That'd be great for everybody.
Stan.
Hope in it too and okay.
Do you want to get some balls?
Wants to try to get ron wyden.
He'll spit in your face.
What the fuck did you just say?
Yeah,
I'm from Texas.
They just run away from.
You're sober sober october,
november.
Also soapbox our sober october.
It's october and then whoever can join
in can join in if they want to like.
It'd be cool to run into guys like,
what do you think your percentages are?
Fail or succeed?
Hundred percent.
Of course it's going to say that he can
run a marathon.
That's a ridiculous number.
What's the number?
One hundred percent is ridiculous.
There's no way.
Almost nothing is that are your favorite
principal in highschool dies and he says
in his will,
I want you to drink one more drink for
me.
Let me ask you a question.
What is the.
What are the odds that you can run one
mile?
I can run a mile.
Okay.
what are the.
What is that?
Ninety eight percent?
That's a good number.
That's a pretty reasonable number.
one mile.
It's so easy.
Ninety eight disasters out of the
equation.
That's why 98 percent loss of family.
My dad passed away.
I'm going to drink.
I'm just talking about injuries one
mile,
one mile for most you can twist 20 steps
in.
That's a strong number number.
So
what what happened?
I can do it.
Ninety eight percent.
That's a good number.
A good number for like running flat.
Now when you run in hills like ari that,
that,
that trail that you and I went down,
but we did that podcast together.
That's not a 98 percent.
I think about that sometimes.
Like if I broke my ankle or something
down on how do I get out of that?
That's an option.
There's no phone service down though.
Yeah,
I'm going to crawl out of there so I
think about it,
but I think I can crawl out of there
pretty easy for broken ankle.
I think you get it to change your
percentage again.
I think crawl out of there would be
pretty hard,
but I'm getting now.
Okay.
What's your percentage?
They're legit percentage.
You could do it sober for october.
October.
What percentage?
Really think about it.
Okay,
I got it.
What's going on here?
Bert?
$50 to flip the coin decision away.
By the way,
I think you're wrong,
but I think it's way more realistic than
any of the other two numbers you've
given about.
What about kundalini yoga?
You ever hear kundalini yoga?
Kundalini yogi supposedly could do a
psychedelic experience with.
No.
No,
no.
If I'm sure he told her because if I
don't know what I'm saying,
doing kundalini yoga,
it gives you a true.
Okay.
I'll try it.
And you know danny,
one of eddie is black belts.
Yeah.
Pro publica.
Specify the greeks.
Great motherfucker.
But he.
He does it all the time.
Really?
Yeah.
He's like legit,
like he's like a yogi and he says that
kundalini gives you a complete total
psychedelic state.
I've never tried it.
Wow.
We could all try it together.
That will count as one of the holidays.
What if we do this?
What if we get someone to.
You're going to stick around here.
Are you going to just sit around you on
where you go?
You went to fucking asia for a month.
Their cell phone.
You can't hang around with here for
sober friend sober and do kundalini
yoga.
We'll see if we can get high.
Let's see if we can do.
I'll do it.
Let's see if we can meet the aliens.
Okay,
so what I have heard from people that do
it,
if you do it long enough and correctly,
you can have intense,
full blown hallucinogenic psychedelic
experiences that rival mushrooms and
wait long enough.
You mean enough times in a row or long
enough in one time?
That's a good question.
I.
I have zero experience and this is
purely anecdotal.
All finished.
Too many people that are trust that have
done this and had that have had
psychedelic experience.
Are we all gonna do soBer and yoga or is
it.
I'm down.
I'm down hot yoga.
Come on,
hold on.
Hold on.
One sober.
We're talking.
We'd use.
I can get into that place.
I can get it to that.
No,
we'd place for them.
I don't know.
Do you want to be there?
I.
I'm working.
It's weird.
I can do that.
I could do it.
I don't mind it on the cruise.
I could do.
No,
we'd already.
October.
Intense cardio.
Intense cardio produces those same
sorts of weird euphoric feelings.
It's like,
and you brought up the way this started
and you're fat,
you burn it off a little bit.
Yeah.
A little bit of that.
When extends cardio does is gives you
that after we'd feeling,
you know,
the after we'd feel them.
When you're super high and the end with
the tail end of it,
you just feel great.
You want to just put weed in the bucket
and we'll have.
We'll do we just in case.
Okay.
We should think about it.
We should definitely not do anything
rash.
We should realize that he doesn't love
us as much as he loves going to Vietnam
and hanging out with people he doesn't
even know.
15 days of yoga aren't.
You?
Don't have any scheduled.
Were you gone 15 days of yoga,
31 dayS sober.
all of october.
October.
What are you going to do?
Not.
What else are you going to do?
I couldn't go to Thailand to make my own
rice.
I live off a backpack.
Sleep would weirdos text them the fuck
shit.
No,
no.
That's the fam who he texts him as
issues.
Problems should head over man riders on
the storm.
Yes,
3:33.
This means we're about.
No,
we're fun.
We got to keep going.
something sober far.
I'm just trying to think what this
means.
This means no,
no,
we'd.
Okay.
On one hand I don't want to do the
knotweed.
On the other hand,
I think if he does sober but also smokes
weed,
it's just gonna be a stop gap to get
them right back to drinking heavily
again.
It's interesting you say it again,
that if you're allowed to smoke weed,
you're smoking into drinking more.
As soon as I'm like,
oh,
there's no way around,
but I can get drunk tonight.
Okay,
that'll laSt me till tomorrow.
I'll tell you that in all honesty,
once again,
uh,
I have,
I have a problem with tee total
learning.
So if I,
if I don't drink,
I actually won't do anything because I
get a little obsessive compulsive.
But are you permitting?
What do you mean by what do you mean by
that time that have no teetotaling means
I don't do anything like I become really
strict about.
It also means it happens if I want a
little bit.
If I smoke weed,
I'll pRobably end up wanting a beer.
Well,
let's let him express himself.
what do you mean?
Like you have a problem with tito,
tito and his obsessive compulsive
compulsiveness.
I get like a seven Days right on drink.
And I go,
fuck dude,
I don't want to drink at all.
You given it even means you Have no
problem with.
You could just go right on solidly.
Not no problem because the problem that
comes up the first day of drinking
again,
I get obSessive about it and I can't
have a drink because I go,
man,
you do it so good.
Don't fucking drink.
It's almost a way.
You know.
So like if I,
I just won't smoke weed.
That's just real.
But I don't care if you guys do.
You should smoke weed and do yoga.
There you go.
That's what you should do.
Here you go.
But you'll say he'll smoke weed and
drink drinking.
Because if I see you guys at the store
and you guys have joined,
I'd want to smoke.
Should get together and do what the
young kids would say.
Hell,
a bong rips and then go take some
fucking yoga class.
I do that helmet.
Let's do it.
We should do it.
We get vice to get in on this.
I do that in a heartbeat,
but the yoga classes in 30 days,
so do it.
I'll do it
sober,
sober.
Doing yoga classes in 15 minutes and you
kick on the road,
you can get high.
You got to do the roads on the road.
Yeah.
Fifteen,
15 hot yoga classes.
Yeah,
but you can get high as you want chemo
sobbing and they'll follow you to the
road.
Whoever device or whoever does it or
whatever.
Ankle bracelets device.
That'll hold me accountable.
We would move into a weird area if we
don't trust each other.
I tried this.
I agree with you,
but I don't trust part.
Are you serious?
No way.
There's no way.
It'd be too crazy to say.
Just trust me.
You know him saying he's in great shape
and he can run a marathon.
Easy.
I've held that need to be 100 percent
unbiased and complete ideas when the
fucking keep that body cams on.
I had a glass of red wine with dinner.
What's the big deal?
Okay,
so scram.
Scram.
Cam.
Yeah.
I don't.
I don't want them to where it's cramped
with a wonderful opportunity for bart to
come clean.
Just just come clean with us.
You don't need skype cameRa.
You're not coming clean.
But that like,
you don't like that.
you're just,
there's not even a possibility.
I don't think there's a possibility that
you would lie to you unless you know
this is a binary thing.
This is the one in zero thing.
This isn't like what brett's talking
about before.
Sort of like fun and exaggerations,
but when you're talking to like one or
zero,
did you yes or no drink?
Yeah.
I trust you.
If I drank,
I just start drinking again and let you
guys knoW.
I don't mind losing the next steps.
Cramped.
I don't need it.
Don't need it for me.
And tom have the fans.
The fans probablY would appreciate it if
you would acquiesce.
I'll tell you what.
Here's my deal.
I mean you guys.
Yeah.
If I do good cop,
bad cop in chicago or somewhere,
but go on the road and you want to scram
cammie for a weekend.
Scram.
Cam and they sleep on your stomach or
back?
left side.
Left side.
Sober october.
So october.
Did you get sober?
Sober,
sober.
October 12.
Ninety nine.
phase.
The fucking government gets sober.
Sober.
October sober.
October.
[inaudible] dot com.
So do the fucking 31 day.
It's grabbed him.
Of course.
Yeah.
You're doing scratch.
I'll describe him if you need me to.
I do.
I'd like you to shying away from the
yoga part.
Yeah.
I want you to take classes.
Yoga classes.
You can tag on that or I don't know how
I do that.
Tom,
you have a lot to catch up on.
Yeah.
What happened?
Okay.
He's doing yoga.
I'm saying no,
but Joe says no you.
You're the deciding vote.
Scram.
Cameron knows cram.
Cram,
cram camp.
I was playing.
Good cop.
Bad cop getS fucking crying.
So fucking district attorney just came
in.
Scram camp.
We got to set up notifications for the
three of us.
We'll all get a message if he be on this
grant,
like marijuana is acceptable during
this.
I was like I said,
this is some shit that like men and
women do when they're role playing games
like one plays,
the detective and the wife plays the
lonely housewives drinking martinis.
Dick,
he should wear it like before we start
and just fucking get hammered.
Let's see what the scram cam does.
We should just do this.
How about this guys?
Powerful.
JamIe.
Come up with sober october.
Someone sent that to me.
I want to take full credit for that.
Got the website sober.
October.
That's october.
No,
no.
You're confused with fucking everybody
bro.
Bro.
Go still go through shirts though.
Scotia has nothing to do with it.
Birth.com.
sober october.
Unless you're looking to buy tickets for
all birds.
Scram,
scram.
Canvas tests Australia on September
31st.
Oh,
where are you?
What?
The dc improv at that show.
You will watch me go for my number
first.
You might die.
You can't do september.
Third be you can't drunk that night.
September 31st september the day.
The date when the day starts,
he starts when he's already in dc.
No,
no what I'm saying.
But we're getting to October 31st is the
last day.
I said september,
september 30.
First to october for weight.
But what happened September 31st.
You've got to stop drinking and probably
drinking.
Oh,
you don't want to see what I registered
him like going into october.
Yeah,
but.
So if he starts at midnight drunk
because he got.
That's over 100 percent,
right?
You have to stop the 31st or september.
He's going to stop the 30th.
The evening of the 30th.
I stopped drinking.
So technically I have a full day of
sobriety or wait,
wait.
No,
no,
no.
There's only 30 days in september.
September.
Already.
What I'm saying is I need to stop a full
day before october starts.
Yeah,
29.
Okay.
Yeah.
So I start.
You want me no booze so that stuff I.
It was stopped by noon stuff.
I knew no one drinking the day.
No problem.
Then she started at 12:45
PM.
So bird story.
It's the day and we're drinking.
You say you don't drink in this episode,
brought to you by scram cam just brought
to you by day drinking high risk
offenders.
It said the craziest thing you've ever
said.
Well to red plastic cups.
I don't drink it every day while you
drink.
Love the
hyperbole of me like I speak in
hyperbole.
That's beautiful.
I speak like in a like whereby you find
her way were you always win and that's a
really important thing.
If you want to get out of this drowning
world of prosperity.
It is 30 days,
31 days.
October,
october.
So I will enter october sober is what
you're saying?
Yeah.
Okay.
And then what's the physical part?
The 15 yoga sessions?
Sessions.
Ninety minutes.
Not bullshit.
Sixty minutes by the way,
by the way,
I'll be texting both you and I don't
mind for that first week hitting you
guys up and find them one that we can
all do together.
Like go together.
Let me ask you a question.
Let me ask you a question about this hot
yoga.
Yeah.
So you're saying if it does get too hot,
it enters a dangerous zone.
I can just sit on the side,
drink a lot of water on the side.
You sit on your mat,
I'll drink a little water,
drinking lots of water,
but you don't have to leave safely.
You don't have to leave.
Don't be a pussy.
Okay,
but come on man in there and these are
we adding that?
Like if you leave,
you leave in three minutes,
you're a loser.
You can't even give me three times.
We'll leave for four minutes each year.
Here's the other thing.
So wait,
that's decided.
No,
you can't.
Don't be a loser.
Not even a few times.
The 17.
You can't leave three times and start
doing yoga very seriously.
Two and a half years ago,
I have left zero times.
What are the sex?
That's the only other thing we haven't
talked about.
When yoU got to also say,
how do we.
How much water I have to bring in there
to do that saFely.
We'll talk to you a gallon of water
before you don't want to do.
Honestly,
I have like one of those flasks,
I think they're Called hydro flasks and
it's giant.
It's sitting there.
It's really fat and wide.
Look at elephant deck,
fill it up with ice to top of small ice
cubes and then I fill it up with water
so that you know,
the ice has a lot of room for water.
It gets so there and then when I'm in
class for that 90 minutes I'm drinking
like cold water every,
you know,
five or six poses or something.
I tell you to take a break and have
something by the end you have no water
left.
Pretty close.
Usually I've just sort of like a little
bit of ice.
So I've drank a whole 64 ounce thing in
a 90 minute class.
It's hard to do man,
but I think that's one of this done in
90 minutes.
This is what I think.
I think it's a real difficult to 60 mine
with yoga says the standard was 60
minutes pussy when,
when you can get through it.
If you can get through 15 of those in 30
days,
I think you even fucking get through a
lot of shit,
but I think you surprise yourself.
I think you're totally right and the
amount of discipline it will you'll need
on two fronts.
That's great.
But here's the other thing.
You're such a cunt.
No,
no,
no.
Here's the last one.
Real stakes.
What does that mean?
Mistakes,
man.
One hundred Percent.
You get you lose your beard.
You had somebody,
a trowel chocolate.
Well asked you for what happened.
What's bmi is a measurement of the
height and weight.
I said,
okay.
You at the height,
his height,
so just fucking measures height.
I'm six foot four man line.
There was no question.
It was trying to say
it was after you right now for enforcing
negative stereotypes.
Oh,
you are a measurement of height and when
they got the national to know how many
tweets did you get a wealth.
I've got my nipple pierced diaper for
dates.
It's true.
Your voice breaking like kevin
mccallister.
I saiD these boys basketball game you
did on your own.
I was in a fucking play the guitar with
you guys are fucking eating pizza.
I was never.
Well you went to asia before.
Four months to get out of a bag.
Already went on a walkabout across asia
where you can not reach him no fucking
way,
man.
do you remember that guy?
The guy I met,
a guy in fucking some city somewhere.
He was like,
she couldn't pay up that bit.
Really just they're doing his duty,
slut shaming,
you know?
Some people shame you to me.
One day,
enjoyable to get on the road after shows
and be like,
alright,
we're going to be on the road.
I emailed you and saying I was going to
fucking pay off.
That was my last test.
I said,
oh my god,
you barely passed five,
11 point seven,
point eight five and you got it,
but
it was fun to pile on you.
It was fun.
I'm telling you for real now.
The first 15 to 20 days I was out there.
I fucking angry at you guys for telling
me I was a whale shark.
I was like,
these motherfuckers.
I gotta fucking calm down saying I'm a
welsh measurement.
I don't feel like I said you were.
I tried to stay.
I really don't.
I tried to say that a two,
but the fans wouldn't have it somewhere
in.
Woo.
We good?
Yeah,
we're good.
I remember you somewhere and then I was
like,
uh,
someone's like,
burt,
you look skinny and,
and someone goes,
thomas fat.
And I go,
yeah.
I go,
well,
we don't know that we had a backhoe and
then someone gelled as a jew.
Get paper towels.
Maybe I should have told this story it
later.
Or is it jus?
Sorry.
Listen boys,
we're going to be fun.
Great.
That's totally bombs.
Oh no,
it was a check drops.
When you're trying to explain to game of
thrones,
does that bother you at all?
No,
I.
By the way,
I thought you stopped thinking about it.
Have you blocked it out?
How bad it was that now really for tom,
if you told a story like that center
stage and told that story,
was that,
was that worse than the laugh lounge?
How would you feel?
What was it?
That would be my worst story ever.
That would be.
That would lower the standard.
What would you feel about yourself?
Would you be like,
did I have a seizure?
Like what went wrong?
I'd be like,
I drink too much.
I'm super fat.
My story
boys.
We're going to be fun.
Okay.
Okay,
so if you do these 15 year old class is
90 minutes long each.
What are the stakes?
What?
Okay,
there we go.
That's what we started with in a
marathon.
What if we do all these in my new
studio?
All of the yoga class?
Yep.
We can get in there for a month.
We can get in,
but you have to.
I'll pay you.
I'll pay you to pay tv money.
You make.
Stick around a lot of money on the road,
but do you have to.
Do I get to see my family over that
fucking neighborhood with all the time.
One of those women that looks like their
noses,
a pto and talked to her.
Take a walk on a saturday.
You asshole.
Find one with thick yarn hanging off
their belt.
You'll be akin.
Just stay here with us when you need
them.
They're always there.
They're inside.
All of us.
I don't know if I could sit here
thinking how much fun it would be.
Why the fuck do you want to go to New
York since october?
This is the best time with your.
Oh,
the hotdogs with her
could write this stage.
Listen,
listen,
listen to me.
I will rent you a house.
You,
you go on airbnb.
Oh,
pay for your house rental.
I'll pay for a rental car.
I'll pay for a rental car for the entire
month of october.
This is entire percent free for you.
I will pay.
I will give you a food allowance,
a daily food allowance.
Are you doing this article about that?
I have a lot of money for every podcast
you do with me in that time period.
I like the brother.
Let's have some fun already.
Do it.
I want.
This is the challenge I'm taking.
I want you to be like,
you're not seeing your family for a all
of us.
We're going to do yoga together 15
times,
over 30 days old life there for a
fucking month.
A chick you haven't fucked yet is your
whole life already.
All you got to it.
On the east village,
you just called him out.
That's all like hanging out with big jay
lewis.
I get it.
Sow.
Come on man.
Come on and you're over here with us and
and all that's taken care of.
And you're here lewis.
He's talking about big jay oakerson.
He said big j dot lewis,
bigj in miami.
You guys and Louis Gomez.
It was a different person.
I know like big j dot lewis.
I said their names and in repetition
we're off pace.
It's like if someone asks you for your
phone number is three,
two,
three,
four,
five,
six,
seven,
eight,
nine spots.
Fucking a quarters on the ground here.
There's a lot to do,
man.
You can come and tyler listening make
shoots with thinking about kidnapping.
Anyway,
learn how to stop.
I'm tired of being on the planet to
knowing.
Stay over here,
dude.
For october we'll all be sober.
Will all go to the yoga classes.
Will get closer and we'll get healthier
and we'll run a marathon.
Stop pretending that the comedy store is
the greatest place on the face of the
earth.
I'm not pretending that.
I'm saying I want to be 3000 miles away
from that.
That's what I'm saying.
Why are you doing?
Stop attending is not the greatest
place.
You've got to Be here,
bro.
All of october to financial arrangement.
I'll rent you a corvette and right
around the corner,
a black one,
a sleek new one.
If you get me a honda civic with gps,
listen,
you're going to drive a corvette like
god damn americans.
I don't want him to drive a corvette.
You've never driven one.
Get the tacky on the highway to do that.
It'd be nice,
but not every day.
Girl.
It's no way.
I'm not driving of those.
That's a separate bucket.
And shelby mustang you can rent.
No,
no,
no.
How about this?
What about like,
give me a 67 mustang to drive around in
for breaks are terrible.
You'd want a resto mod.
It's a lot of complications.
What about like,
if you're talking about like a new car,
a new car,
what?
I'm going to bmw and if I got to go to
london for a week.
Oh yeah.
So it sits here and uh,
that's how life works when you're not
here.
It doesn't drive itself.
It's not like herbie the love bug fuck.
But I'm saying what if I got to go to
london for a week for press?
But I think I do go back to london for
press.
Yeah.
I got to go to chicago.
So I'm doing here for 90 days.
You would probably be a week.
What are you doing for press in london?
What's going on in london?
I could do a netflix brunt of press from
fucking london one in New York.
Like what do you do?
You do radio over there,
which a panel shows and radio and
podcasts.
ShIt,
you got to do that.
So you got to be stories.
You're going to arrive with stories and
you're going to do sets out there as
well or just say.
Yeah,
for sure.
For sure.
You have things scheduled yet or no?
No.
Okay.
So you're in your,
in your,
in your head.
So you're in.
So how many days is this?
You're talking about october.
and then go straight from here to go
straight from here to the fucking joke
was cruise me.
And you go to the summer that I got to
meet in new orleans a couple days early.
No.
Nobody out in the next flight the two
days before?
Nope.
Yeah.
Why not?
Two days before because I can't miss
halloween.
Oh,
maybe I can.
the kids are used to not having you
around.
Burt.
sorry.
Bad father.
Let's do it.
You have to submit your texting yet.
Guy texted them.
I haven't been replying.
Okay.
Stop this for hours.
Finish it off though.
We were not sober.
October,
october,
october.
Finish it off.
And then correct it.
Okay.
I think we should talk about this and
I'll announce it in the future.
Project was one.
Let's talk it out.
Ready?
Sobrato party october.
What's red octobers tasting here towards
doing it?
If we could figure it out like the
corvette.
Be a black.
I like black.
I love personal pain to me.
Makes me excited.
These are locked down.
Yellow.
A yellow corvette has already.
Come on,
bro.
They even gave me terentino's pussy
wagon,
wagon kill bill.
Should we hold hands while we do this?
So if we do that,
if we do that,
if someone doesn't do it,
then what happens twice in four hours.
If someone doesn't do it.
I had to fly home to meet my family for
three days,
then come back.
I didn'T go to london and come here,
face it here.
What is it takes a ton of money right
now.
How about sobriety related?
How about the loser has to throw a party
for the other people in their honor and
you have to do like ice sculptures and
make it crazy.
Crazy.
I fucking hate you.
That's a great idea.
Why don't we do this all day?
And they're shooting sculptures like
half limp dicks are dripping down.
IT takes longer for them to like break
off and they all go into birth.
Mouth it.
Because if the artist is good enough to
show how much you love,
it sticks to your face.
What's the measurable variable for.
For like if everybody gets to drown in.
No,
no what?
So if we all do it,
the capital on,
then the loser of that.
Oh,
okay.
So it carries over.
That's what we're before,
which he said before it was instead of
marathon,
what he said before,
tom said before was,
um,
that he couldn't do 90 days,
but if he did do 90 days,
then
you could get the honor of challenge and
goes to a marathon,
which we'd never.
No,
no,
no.
The winter,
the winter calphalon for who's the best
thing?
Shape.
That's good.
And the loser,
the decathlon pays the winner of the
decathlon.
The party.
Yeah.
So,
so here's what we're doing.
Okay.
Thirty days sober.
October 15,
15,
31 days sober.
October already in october.
Yes.
Can the,
can the loser also have to shower the
winter in good words.
And um,
and praise.
I would love for a period of at least
four minutes.
Interesting.
Maybe we should do it the opposite.
Maybe the winters shower,
the losers to rebuild their self esteem.
HorrifiC defeat.
I think of things show that burned up.
That's really what we're able to look at
that point because for sure die off
round 13 yoga classes in six or seven
days and no booze.
So once you fail,
can we all just stop,
stop talking to me directly if it's a
competition we're all doing.
WHo do you think of this table would
have the hardest time quitting booze for
sure.
Who do you probably already know way?
Especially in la when I drink for the
first,
like 15 years that I knew I drank it at
New York because it's a New York fucking
thing to do.
Yeah,
he barely drank in la.
I'd give him a drag.
Scott.
he'd go,
oh yeah,
you made disgusted.
What's wrong with you?
Sober from alcohol and october.
Yeah.
Who's,
who's goIng to have a hardest time?
The hardest topics.
That's nice.
That's beautiful.
who's going to have a breakthrough
moment with the hot yoga?
Yoga?
Rogan will have the easiest time.
Uh,
I enjoy yoga.
I probably the hardest time because I
get claustrophobic and never do it that
much.
I Never do it.
Fifteen days,
30 days.
I'd never do it at the most I've ever
done it ever is.
I think I did three times a week once.
I've done twice a week,
multiple times.
Most of tHe time I do one time a week.
Okay.
Let me ask you a question.
If I pass out and what people have to
dragged out.
Dragged out in your mouth and then you
don't.
You lose against your will.
They take you out of there and getting
people to take you out backwards.
People against your will.
Cops.
I'll tell them the black.
Listen.
All you should do is when you get to
like you got.
It's really on scout's honor.
When you get to an unmanageable state of
heat and exhaustion just laid down.
It's called savasana.
You laid down flat and just chill out
and then when you feel like you've
recovered a little bit and then you get
back up and ritually yoga,
hot yoga is going to be 60 minutes.
Ninety minutes is better because it
shows between 60 and 90.
That's what separates the girls from the
women.
I'm saying,
okay,
fine.
I'll be the woman girl here.
I'm just yoga break.
It's tom's a power lifter.
he's not even like cardio guy three
times in a five minute break,
three of the 15 weeks,
no breaks,
break,
huge challenge,
no breaks pussies.
Let let it be a little challenging to
you guys as well.
Health wise.
Let's get super challenging.
yeah,
I will quit drinking.
End to the yoga.
All you guys have to do is not drink,
which is a challenge.
And then do the yoga,
which is a huge.
I think what we might all fail on that.
Then what happens?
We're not going to,
not even one time convinced that I could
do it and uh,
I'm the one who does it all the time.
I'm saying we should be able to do it.
So three,
five minute breaks three times over the
break room arguing as much as this.
And I didn't like.
All right,
good point.
The harder challenges me not drinking,
no breaks,
bitch,
no fluff,
sure fail.
And then I'm thinking to myself and then
the person who wins that challenge picks
that up and gets the name that the
capital event.
We do some sort of a physIcal event.
What kind of shit be like a one day of
bike race,
school track meet basically.
So the benefit.
Well we set up the benefit of choosing
an olympiad.
You let's say you know you,
you're like,
well I'm the best sprinter or whatever,
so we have to do this sprint.
I'm the best at whatever pull up.
So you'd be like,
do we have to do like you named the
events if you win against all the the
winter and all the events,
you would just name it all on your
favorite.
ObvIously.
Hold on,
but that,
that makes sense for suck dicks.
Dominate fucking nacho far.
No,
no,
no.
it's not physical.
It's a physical events.
We'd all have to have some say you have
more say.
AlrigHt,
what would you choose if you had the
opportunity to create a gauntlet?
A gauntlet of different difficult
exercises.
Got it for 40 a 100 yard dash.
How about four?
So sprinting a 4:40
is one a quarter mile,
quarter mile,
and then a hundred yard dash.
okay.
This to to run a break in here and say
that's a long distance from a marathon.
you fucking.
No,
no,
but that's what I think.
That's where I think I'd accept.
That's where I think excel.
You asshole.
You fucking liar.
You ain't fucking.
I do an 800 and a sprint.
I definitely do a model running stuff
stuff.
No biking,
no swimming.
No fucking on.
Hold on.
I get to pick the fucking marathon.
That's why I picked it.
Wait a minute.
So you thInk that you could win one of
these things?
I could win a number of these types.
What things do you think you could win?
100 yard dash three slash four.
You think you could win?
What do you.
No way.
Who do you think you think?
I definitely got tommy in this.
No,
he just said right now.
I don't think you can.
No,
no,
no.
I think you could beat me in a mile for
sure.
I don't tHink you went in a mile.
I'd definitely beat you in a mile.
I did.
I beat you in an 800.
You know that.
Where do you went on a sprint?
Off the blocks.
Yeah.
I beat tommy in the sprint 100 percent.
By the way.
This is why the decathlon is going to be
interesting because we all get to pick
our events.
What we do is everyone who does it come
in first place.
I had the opportunity to come in first
place because I didn't drink for a whole
month and I did.
THe yoga can beat him at sprint for
sure.
Of course.
Here's your list.
If you win,
you should get to pick two events.
Listen,
listen,
listen.
Let's see.
Let's say it's five events.
I'm just making her motherfucking
weekend.
We called it the cap on.
We have to call doodads on tech.
It has to be for track and field events.
Total of 10 meter sprint,
110 meter hurdles.
Four hundred meter event,
1500 meter long jump,
high swimming.
No,
we don't want those.
We're not doing the swimming,
biking and running.
We met.
We met in the camps who were saying for
track for track or track advantage.
Let me draw them and stuff.
It's trauma and kettlebell over a over a
jesus combine involved in this.
Are you are definitely involved out of
this is for me not to drink in october.
We don't need to do yoga with you.
We all hang out.
We all have a good time all throughout
october.
Hold on.
Oh,
sorry.
Sorry.
Go ahead.
Go ahead then and then we all beat me in
a 100 yard dash.
No,
wait,
hold on.
Hold on.
Special bonus points.
If you beat rogan in any event,
a that's a lot lighter than you man.
And in shape.
I mean you're both in great shape,
but she has to be confident to say that
I would beat you if you weren't so
confident to say he'd beat everybody.
I'm like,
he doesn't know worse.
You wouldn't be,
but you'd be japanese guy walking out
and pride in it,
but you're not covered.
And I'm fading.
Seventy eight pounds lighter than you at
least to 50 50.
I'm getting being nice.
You're 3:50.
How much do you weigh now?
Twenty two to 22.
When I get up,
I take a leak in the morning and then I
weighed myself.
I'm about one 95.
Wow.
It might go.
That's
it.
That's what advantage is.
Definitely much lighter bodied.
I do have like when it comes to muscle
twitch,
I got that long strands that run I do
with me one day.
Okay.
Yeah,
that crazy.
Tell me one,
tell them why men love to do it.
I'd love to do it.
Do man listen to that on your.
On the hike or playing.
I loved it and I was like,
I know you guys smoked a joint before
the uphill.
Nope.
Open for that paleo and get down to the
basin and I was like,
I would never.
I would never be able to do that because
I would totally be huffing and puffing
up it up hill.
No,
honestly mad at it actually dilates your
lungs.
I do cardio after I smoke weed all the
time.
I can't do that.
Go longer because you doing literally
can go longer.
Yeah.
But you know,
I think jamie knows jimmy marathon
runners that blase,
but they'll smoke a little bit before
they run their.
Cool.
My thought on all of this is it would be
nice if we all did something just like
your weight loss challenge did,
but I think the weight loss challenge,
we might've missed the mark quite
honestly with the idea that you guys
could be hydrate yourself.
I mr mark [inaudible].
I said that's what.
That's where three straight days,
no,
but what I'm saying,
because they wouldn't listen.
Are you wrong?
Because that's super bad for your body.
That's like insanely bad for your body
to be that dehydrated three days in a
row and drinking's not bad.
It's not nearly as bad as dehydrating
yourself like that.
Drinking is normal.
Your body is normally processing
alcohol.
If you drink on a normal basis,
your liver processes that,
but when you dehydrate yourself like 15
pounds of water or like a yoga class,
you're body's not firing 64 ounces while
you're in class.
You're gonna get a fucking great gallon
in the middle of the class.
I do think.
Wait,
hold on,
hold on.
Before you go and come on,
stop.
Hold on.
Every of us I think twice in this
podcast.
I'm.
Yep.
Again,
you've got to give you a chance to pee
out in our makeup.
This is all mental.
Why?
Why would you not be able to do it?
If I can do it,
of course you can do it.
Different sizes.
That's one reason you can do it,
man.
You gotta let me pick.
If I run it out,
you get 90 seconds.
Here's better.
Better.
We're going to do it.
We're going to put plastic down and to
let You pick your parents.
Gotta hang in there.
If you get me a bottle at a corner where
nobody can see it,
I can do that,
but a corner somewhere like a that the
fucking room.
Where got the shit in?
This is his escape clause.
No,
come on you guys.
You can't do an hour and a half without
pen.
Might not.
Sometimes I can sometimes have to pee
before you go into class and you'll be
so dehydrated while the is going on.
You will be drinking water.
You won't even have to pay because you
have to get out so bad.
If we don't have to be to.
I can take.
I take soMebody wiTh me to show.
Look,
he's actually paying.
Or you could just hold it in.
I mean you couldn't hold it friday.
I'll try to life depended on you holding
you.
Can you
can the three of us get together?
Hold on.
I'm a jew.
Yep.
I'm just saying I'll try not to pee,
but like,
come on guys.
If I really haVe to pay,
what are you going to do?
I'm not going to piss my pants.
I'll tell you what.
There's not a chance in the world.
There's a way that I could have to pee
so bad that I couldn't hold it in for an
hour and a half.
I'll tell you what,
five people for batman,
batman.
I pissed my pants in the theater.
That's interesting.
will you make.
Will you vowed to pee before every class
people,
if you have to get up and pee a lot
beforehand,
the odds of me not having to pay not
only think about a little crazy.
Do they have much water?
The fIrst five classes?
no more paying classwork and piss in the
class.
Find me a safe here.
If you gave me a safety,
a safe space where I can piss in public
and not to fucking jail.
No asparagus.
Mother fucker.
I'll try.
Can we please all get together to pick
the car for him and said,
can we get it?
What was delivered?
Be like to have no tears.
Tell them that yellow corvette.
You can't,
you know the new ones.
Get the new ones.
The new ones are beautiful.
Well if we,
if you could pick a car that you can
drive,
like if also money became free.
Yeah.
Like what kind of car would you drive
around?
Like new cameras.
Four runner.
So.
Oh you pissing that thing and it fills
up that bad.
Joe buys your 30.
We're good.
Solution has been reached.
We can now pick up his car that we're
going to be buying.
So what kind oF car man?
The car to the car.
I'm like,
no,
you don't need god.
What about like a bmw?
I bought a four runner.
Okay.
Oh shit off.
But like compromise,
can we compliment what he wants to go to
joshua tree or something that they
don't?
Yeah,
they'll.
They're,
they're really good off road cars.
Had toyotas are like bulletproof.
Yeah.
They're bad ass a day off.
If it's like a really nice night where I
could go out there.
Wait for drinking.
Yeah.
With the truck.
Yeah,
yeah,
for sure.
For sure.
Okay.
Can we look at vehIcles but come on,
give me something.
No,
no,
no.
It wasn't.
I wouldn't have to fucking put that shit
back down.
Can we get it wrapped around october?
Wrapped it
all up.
Get it wrapped.
Maybe we should get it wrapped with
that.
What was that one?
That one.
Eat mushrooms tee shirt that you came at
me in the face.
I'd have more of an issue.
Second note that I see the value in
that.
To this.
What about I do this research is on.
No,
no,
no.
That's rude.
What about I rent you a car and I put
that all over the car.
Is that okay?
no,
not myself sober October 2nd here.
No.
How about yourself?
how about you?
That's pretty great on the hood of
frequent.
That one.
How about this?
How about no name?
Look it.
Turn to your left.
Look to your left real quick so you're
better.
How about name?
We don't need your name.
We just use that image.
Only that image on the hood,
but it looked like anymore.
What about.
What about?
What about what You look like?
Reynolds poses sideways.
Naked on each side of the.
Now that's not dangerous enough.
Ooh,
how about that one?
That's the one that's on your hood here
wIthout the art of the grit to ari with
the group.
Whereas.
Oh yeah.
That's great.
Yeah.
That's one big one on each side.
We perfect.
How about one on the roof of the car?
The roof,
the hood,
like a firebird,
a thunderbird do it that way.
And then branding on the side.
Who are your.com?
How about booking info about you?
Yeah,
about we instead of.
Instead of.
How about instead of a corvette,
we get you one of these new camaro zl
one.
The front is one of the stupidest
fucking cars in americans have ever
made.
It's amazing.
This thing is,
it's so preposterous.
They just did this like insane record,
norberg,
ring title,
um,
time.
And this is a fucking $650 american
beast of a vehicle.
I am there.
They're letting me borrow one of these.
I'm going to get a six speed.
One of these fucking things for your
prom.
Talk about it just coming out.
It's like a press car.
So we're going to review it.
I'm going to review it on a podcast.
That's an awesome car,
man.
That thing is a monster.
Get that fucking thing.
ThAt picture on the front hood scoop.
Picture that hood scoop with brandon.
The side doors,
the side doors.
Are you down with this?
Please say yes.
At least one of these.
I swear to god.
I will say I don't care for it.
The comedic value drive it and you
realize it's a goddamn 2017 spaceship.
Wow.
I think the zero to 60 in like three
seconds.
I think it's too cool.
And to bring it down a notch back on the
tail of the car,
it has to say I'm
a comedian.
Exclamation point.
That's horrible.
Yoga.
Come on,
look at that image and look at that hood
scoop and scoop.
Scoop that thing on the hood.
That thing in five minutes.
That's gonna be where the fucking
stairs.
yeah.
That's where the wrap gets put down.
I like to sign off already to sign off.
Sign off and it says I'm a funny guy.
You have american men run hot blooded
american males are furious that you even
bulkier.
I'll do that if you'll let me.
Fuck.
Fucking hot yoga class.
You have to be again.
Don't.
Of course I knew I had to 15 minutes
ago.
We'll green light.
You breathing in yoga class.
Go pee.
We're going to hang out with.
I can fucking.
Pete thinks she'd be able to pee.
That's ridiculous.
He's concerned about this while you were
out there.
I don't think we got as far as I thought
we were going to fuck.
No shit.
Right?
I mean we're four and a half hours in
because we barely have a barely have a
handle on how the fuck this is going to
go down.
I heard handled thought about tito's.
That's the book.
Put up a pull up,
2017 camaro,
zl one nurburgring time.
I think they just got some insane
nurburgring time.
I think it was faster than the corvette.
Zero six.
That's a crazy car,
man.
Americans doing some nutty shit now man.
They're developing these vehicles.
They're just off the chart now.
This one is the most exciting new
american car in in years right now,
for example,
beast and it's.
It's an affordable car comparatively
compared to the kind of performance of
the other cars like it.
Seven minutes and 23 seconds In the
nuremberg ring.
That's faster than the nine slash 11 gt
two rs.
That's just under a mclaren f one,
which is like,
well how much is that?
Like a million more than a million and
just under the a c,
six corvette.
Z o six.
And the dodge viper acr.
So it's like one second,
one second point seven under the a dodge
viper and the [inaudible] is seven to 19
is.
It's such a crazy fast cars.
The point,
I mean the difference between one second
here,
there is just a lot of that times it's
understanding the core course
conditions,
driver error.
I mean you're talking about like really
close margins so it would have it's
super car and absolute supercar.
It's impressive and I had never got into
cars but I think that's like so much
fun.
I'll probably drive it on the open road
and if I die on your heads so you're on
it.
You're on it
juSt on the creek and a bunch of water
beforehand and durIng.
It's like you're just telling me I'm
going to lose the tail of the car.
Has to say got jokes,
but the,
as a compromise I could come off.
Funny guy or comedian.
I'm a comedian guy.
Funny guy.
But this big.
How about do you think I'm funny?
No way.
I see website,
yes or no?
No.
Okay.
How about nita laugh.
They laugh and then you go number dick
for chuckles.
Yeah.
That's good.
Let's do that.
We got through a lot on this podcast.
I'm super glad we did it.
Okay,
so then we choose the decathlon.
It's three events,
three events.
The winner gets four.
What is going on?
Like physical events?
Yeah,
like runs to find out if anyone is
really in fitness,
sort of.
Everyone completes it and you're a
psychopath that you're writing like
you're talking like this fitness
certainty is so hilarious.
You have to reach your arm,
your alarms.
Like my mom after jazzercise.
I love your level of delusion though.
Not the illusion.
Reality.
Okay.
What's the reality like?
Is the sky you'd like the hardest core
trump fan.
It was like,
we're doing a great job by you in great
shape.
I'm not in great shape.
Why?
I didn't like.
I remember one time I remember saying to
you one time I said something about
being famous.
You go,
bro,
you're not famous.
And I was like,
no,
I definitely am.
And you're like,
no,
I'm not famous.
You're definitely not too late.
You're talking to joe,
joe,
joe and joe.
And I was like,
oh,
that was good.
It was good leveler of what fame was.
I was like,
you get recognized a couple of times,
like a day or a day.
If you get recognized at all in a week,
you're like,
oh,
that's crazy.
Uh,
I think the fitness thing,
I think if I don't drink,
I feel like I feel much better.
I feel like we went back in time.
You do another game of thrones thing.
Jesus
right?
pilot son tells me,
have the second episode.
Raven took over the boy's body size back
deep into his head and hold your
protection.
So painful in various being assholes.
Um,
um.
Oh yeah.
Um,
okay.
If,
if everyone does the 30 day challenge,
yes.
Then we do a decathlon winner.
Why do you want to do like a physical
coach?
I don't care.
Where do you put it?
How about the fucking parties after the
30 days,
and if we all do it,
then what?
We shouldn't make this too complicated
because we always keep doing them after
our realizes that la is way better than
New York decides to stay.
Stay bitchy.
putting in november and you'll make the
best month in worked best.
Oh my god.
The bagels thrown unstoppable.
How about no dogs arE ripe.
The bagels.
You go and.
No,
I'm not kidding.
Not kidding.
But then like five exclamation points.
I'll take that.
I'm not kidding that.
That's.
But I'll take that.
I like it.
Can you believe that shit?
Okay.
I'm not kidding.
Not kidding.
Party party at the end.
Alright,
wait,
wait.
But as soon as they would have cash to
pay for it,
we're leaving a couple days before.
Oh my god.
They just leave it just like that.
That's perfect.
Hold up aesthetically.
That gave me on the side.
Should also be fucking mouth.
That's a perfect car.
The colors of the place.
It looks awesome,
dude.
It looks great.
Red and pink.
That's not pink.
It's beautiful.
It's white with pink stone.
All pink.
Blue would think.
Honestly,
I think it should be bright blue.
Perfect.
However we do whatever.
How about we give you a full pink wrap
and then that's the cover.
No,
that's too much.
The bright blue.
I'll do the breakfast.
No,
no,
no.
That's some shit.
That's intentional.
We get you a hot pepper.
I later or a month.
What?
Hot pink camaro.
No,
no,
no.
Come on.
Someone's already done that.
I'm bringing up the amazing racist stuff
on the car to a website with.
Enjoy your previous.
I'd been amazing.
Grace is on the website.
No,
no one's going to google.
It was a different age.
Now says I'm the amazing racist.
It's a hot pink camaro in the back.
Says I'm not angelian not doing that.
Black or white as the wrap or we can go
right after that,
but I just think it doesn't go as well.
No,
wait actually.
That way I won't get laid for the
fucking month.
No ridiculous either.
How about you start wearing like an
artificial fur coat and just go deep.
How about those yellow glasses that
hunter s thompson used to wear all the
time,
like aviators with yellow lenses.
I love.
How about that?
That's what I'm saying.
I'm saying let's go deep.
Let's take this to the next level.
How about you were like a little further
on you have to wear wardrobe wardrobes.
Every yoga class.
Yoga be fucking hard.
Your pants go.
Definitely wearing yoga pants,
press your cock right up against your
side of your legs.
Everybody could say like,
jesus,
oh yeah,
I'll take pills beforehand.
Which you might actually help your
performance performance enhancing drug.
Yeah.
Some sort of performance.
Yeah,
it does.
It's like it works,
uh,
to enhance your performance.
Certain athletic events banned certain
events.
Like I feel like I said that,
but somebody told me it was wrong and I
forgot.
Make sure that that's true.
like do they,
is viagra banned in the olympics?
I think I might have said this isn't
really where he took a bunch of other
shit in it.
I don't think that's true.
I think.
I think actually jeff dubitsky that saw
the guy might've explained it to me.
That's not true.
So the stakes,
the stakes,
joe explained by agra is not currently
listed as a band drug in the usada and
sport or not.
I'm going to let you saw it.
okay.
Okay.
I'm wrong.
So if everyone does it,
if we do,
what if we don't do it?
What are the stakes here?
What's going on here?
Everyone who doesn't complete the whole
challenge has to throw like what's,
what do we do?
Have grand five grand?
No,
not everyone's making.
no,
no.
Money.
I thought we were throwing a party party
party.
Well,
someone's got to pay for it.
Obviously the person doing it pay for
it,
but I'd make it nice.
What about the money?
It's about what you've decided to do
with it.
You got to live in a fucking dj.
Are you just trying to put up the party?
Are you going to have a party that would
be super annoying to go to.
No,
I don't want to make it fun for
everybody else.
What kind of party would that be?
To stand up there?
Yeah,
you can.
Part of the bet they'll come.
You can invite them if you want to go in
a fucking heartbeat.
He's busy.
Go.
Doug would go.
He has told me,
and I quote,
I do not like bert kreischer fucking,
you know,
you're such a liar.
So diamonds raised.
I love this podcast.
Took a dark turn so we got to go do
eight hours into this bitch straight.
So you have to wear a brace.
15 days of hot yoga,
of hot yoga,
wear a bracelet,
we'll figure it out.
This party thing,
we should throw like a really cool party
that we'd want to be at the event.
If there's somebody that does class
clearly when there's obviously like some
spin that it's me that you're going to
win a 100 percent,
98 percent,
you'll see,
well what are you going to win?
You're going to be the only one.
How would you,
when we,
if we all do it,
I think ari's going to tap out with
yoga.
Probably true.
But this is the thing.
This is the thing.
Just a thought process that would allow
you to jump ahead and say,
I'm going to win.
We don't even know what winning is.
That's why this is so ridiculous.
Like if winning,
if we both do it,
how are you going to beat me?
How you believe me?
I think they think you're going to.
Right.
So tell me how we both do it.
How do you.
When I,
I'm a mickey mouse doesn't make any
sense.
I'm making a into this.
Going,
I can't go into this going,
I'm going to fail.
That was the option.
You said that you're going to win and
how could you win and why would you be
so quick to jump to the idea that you
would win groomed carefully considering
I believe I believe in winning.
I believe in winning.
Wow,
bro.
You're like America and you should be a
bald eagle.
I'm a liTtle competitive and when this
challenge starts to the fucking
committed,
no way.
I'm going to let me tell.
Let me tell you,
I will not lose.
Wow.
That's amazing.
Before.
Yes.
What happened?
The last weird.
For one,
we should believe him.
It doesn't make any sense.
His records pictures really use.
I mean I hear what he's saying and I
want to just believe him
what's wrong?
But I mean you tell me what,
what am I?
My scrollable my goal to go run 20 miles
screaming.
I feel like he could do a marathon.
easy,
easy peasy.
Further,
I think you did.
Yeah,
and I feel like he's quit drinking for
many,
many days numerous times,
but I feel like other alcoholics is
going to be fuck used girl rogan.
You fucking assholes are ganging up on
her friend when he needs you most.
What he needs you to do is validate all
of his exaggerations bullshit stories.
Hyperbole.
What if.
What if we all do it?
I'll do it.
What are the stakes or if none of us do
it,
we can continue that.
We can continue to be a trip.
It should be a trip.
A trip because that's what we did Last
time.
I think the party though is like it's
different and it has to do with all our
friends.
Taking that off comedy.
It's fun,
man.
Just do a real party bar music.
It's just a cool band tHat wants to play
for us.
That sounds fun.
Time.
So we're all great.
The entire month of october.
It's done sober.
October 15.
Hot yoga.
October.
You get paid twice?
No,
no,
no ip.
When they have to pay,
i'Ll come right back here.
You have to pee sessions for the whole.
No,
no,
no.
You're making me look,
I will try not to pee,
pee and come right back in or provided
me a safe scenario where I compete in
the.
In the room.
We'll figure it out on the curtain.
So hot yoga?
No booze sober october.
yes.
There's our website.
We've got it sober.
Bert bert,
october.
No,
so october,
october.
He lost him.
Somebody grabbed it while we were doing
it.
I was trying to check out and someone
got it on other weapons.
Can you just please once you get
solicited for that?
Fuck that schedule.
I still give it to him.
Might not on it.
It might be some person who's like a
industrial.
No,
no,
no.
It.
I think the good side.
Obviously if you listen to podcasts,
you know,
why would they buy it if they need to
make sure that no one else got it.
IT could be that maybe they didn't
realize that.
I'd be like,
oh,
here,
take a bus to give me the $12 for it
doesn't need to do it.
Do it all through social media.
We can do it another place where we have
to.
We documented all through social media.
FIfteen days of hot yoga,
30 days of sobriety.
Go to drunk fat bird.com
and see if they'll say it out loud.
Just buy it next time.
Tom bird dot constantly.
Jamie,
go to two fingers.
Two fingers.
Type quickly.
There you go.
That's not the fat burn.
Fat burn.org.
Get that tip says burton fund to drunk
fat bird dogs already.
Trunk fat bird dot nat would be way
better.
Drunk.
Fat bird.org
will be the best one.
Bird.tv.
If we get option for a car.
Drunk fat bird.us
to show patriotism and to show that he
could be a kid.
Rock tattoo.
Drunk fat bird dot isis.
If you just want to isis,
if you just want to like combat
terrorism from within with a little
simple blast.
Oh shit.
What's going on?
Jamie?
Got damn podcast.
Can I say queen?
Say dates.
Fuck yeah,
dude.
Say.
Anyway.
Okay.
I'll be in los angeles.
SePtember 13th.
During a storytelling show in the main
room at the comedy store.
God,
I'm not gonna tell you the lineup is
going to be great.
And then,
uh,
tickets go on sale conference today.
New whatever Presale on wednesday for
boston.
Providence.
And what are you doing in boston during
the wilbert for the first time?
That's all in like january and uh,
and I got a storytelling show in denver
at the comedy works also in january on
sale now.
The whole tour will be out soon.
Wilbur's on my shortlist for filming my
new netflix special.
Really wish I said netflix clearer.
Really?
Yeah.
The wilbur is on a drunk fat
fatberg.com.
Do we have it?
We haven't,
we haven't.
We got it.
Wow.
We're going to build that shit as a
short list for what to do.
My netflix special,
it's going to be,
um,
my shortlist is austin,
uh,
at cap city comedy club,
boston.
The wilbur,
and I'm thinking a couple of other
places,
a couple of small places,
but those are the two places I'm
thinking leaning more towards comedy
club,
but the wilbur is like three comedy
clubs stacked on top of each other.
The wilbur is like very deep,
are very shallow,
rather it's only 300 seats,
three floors of 300 seats of.
Yeah.
It's great.
You've never done it.
I've done shit for.
Oh,
it's fogged when doing the wilbur into
january.
I might go with you.
I might go with you just to see what
it's like to watch a set there feeling
good because I have to make a decision
somewhere around january is when I
wanted to make the decision where I want
to be.
I will say if you do it at a club,
keep me in mind.
Okay.
I'm doing my specialist,
the trocadero.
Trocadero philadelphia.
Oh,
the trocadero theatre and places.
It's got a lot of lIke.
Tom and I had a great conversation when
you did the truck.
Yeah.
People said tom couldn't sell a ticket
and then he sold.
No,
I did I think four or five.
Five.
I think.
Five shows of the truck.
Oh,
philly's an epic comedy city.
It's fucking amazing.
Epic commentary to five shows the
tropical,
I think it was four or five.
I don't remember whose five.
Trust me.
I know your story better than you do.
It's impressive,
man.
They have helium.
It's one of the best in the country.
That's great.
Clips on the spot.
Thinking of going in and out,
but maybe that's another spot we can do.
Especially you.
Especially helium.
That could be real helium so hard with
paramount.
It can be the cameras that there's no
seats.
You have to lose in such a tight space.
Do you though with today,
with what they can do today
with cameras,
you know,
if you could really like put a lot of
small cameras up on the wall,
mounted on the wall,
get all your footage and then decide
what you pick and the only reason why
you would move from the center shot is
if someone gets in front of it and then
you have to really strongly.
Yeah,
this is what real problem.
You can spend,
let's say four or $500,000.
What?
Hold on.
Let me bounce.
This is my feeling on,
on standup,
on television.
Now as a stance,
I feel like when you're watching someone
in the audience are sitting there and
you're watching them,
you're seeing them like from the waist
up,
right,
or close to it at the store,
something like that,
which is a perfect environment at the
ice house,
same deal,
perfect environment.
ThAt's how you should watch it at home.
You actually watch it flat on with no
edits.
The only time I think you should ever so
side to side as if you have to edit
something or if someone's doing
something that's odd because we want to
see from a does it.
It doesn't get boring and I watched.
It doesn't get boring when I was doing
watch.
Stand up.
You're.
You're automatically on its own shifts
back and forth.
You get to choose what you're saying.
You look over the piano guy,
you're not looking straight on at the
stage the whole time.
As long as what they're saying is funny
and it's good and they're locked into it
and do it.
I don't think that's the best way to do
it because you knew you're conscious of
the fact that changing angles.
Why does that enhance the bit?
I don't think it does.
I thought that it does because they do
that with everything else,
like music videos,
rock and roll,
concerts.
Anything that people do,
they go at it from different angles
because it.
It'll sort of stimulate your mind,
but I don't think if you went to see a
standup comic,
you go see joey d as in dog or you're
watching them head on and it's perfect.
Sometimes you're looking at his waist.
Sometimes you're looking at his belly in
his eyes.
You can do that.
When you watched him from the waist up.
You can do that if you're watching them
from where the head of the eu arguing
that you should tell him.
I think you should have different
angles.
Someone wants different angles.
I just pay for this myself and I can
tell you from me going like,
I've been on tv for awhile and I know
what I'm doing.
I still got a plethora of cameras,
including a jib.
Even for some time.
you don't want a job.
I bought it already.
I already paid plans around like a drone
at the comedy works.
I couldn't do it,
bro.
Manage on pilot,
but you're good.
I'm super serious.
Super serious.
Super serious,
super serious.
Fuck all of you.
how that.
I'll be a drone.
Oh,
tommy's a shooting.
A special in depth discussion.
Yeah.
Two nights before the fox theater in
oakland and then I go to the toronto,
the sony center at the end of the month.
I have a bunch of dates up.
Go to thompson.
Dr.
Com.
Oh,
shit.
Told me there's only tickets available
for tom's late show in denver.
Just a few and I know that because I was
just in denver.
Oh,
okay.
I was saying that every show because I
got nothing but love in my heart.
God,
thank you.
Denver
might be the best place to do comedy in
the world.
It's awesome.
It's right up there.
There's a certain.
There's a there in the mountains there.
They're kind of freaks.
They're survivals of the people that
traveled from the old west and there's a
bunch of people that moved there because
weed's legal.
Yeah,
and the money's flowing like water.
It's cool there.
It's a weird spot to weird spot.
I'm doing the belko.
I think I'm there in november.
Something like that.
That the delco theater.
That's awesome.
To denver's the shit.
Did I say date?
You did know Singapore still have a
solid house room to move to Singapore.
Don't worry.
It's a walk up market.
Yeah.
How many people live in Singapore
speaking the their business,
so no,
no,
no.
11 sydney on the 13th.
Melbourne on the 14th.
Sydney again on the 16th and brisbane on
the 19th.
I said brisbane and take it from there.
It doesn't them a shovel.
Melbourne,
melbourne,
melbourne has been man.
Alright.
Fires.
Damn podcast.
October.
No booze.
Lots of yoga.
Yeah.
Drunk fat burn fat dr.
Com for all your bird.
Don't come get squarespace to hook that
up yet.
It's going to be fucking suck.
I wonder if you could be able to do it.