Boom, ladies and gentlemen, Josh Barnett,
youngest ever UFC heavyweight champion,
and now we're retired.
Uh, sorta tired. Just, um,
I'm a free in the wind.
I'm like a Bald Eagle.
I'm just out there riding
on that freedom America,
just a,
uh,
I decided to leave the fold
of the UFC and a chase my,
my own futures by my own hands.
Are you actively competing or
going to be actively competing?
There'll be some grappling
stuff this year, but uh,
I'm figuring by the start of next year
I'll get back into the MMA circuits. Um,
mainly because it's just going to take
some time to set up camps, managers,
the structure of everything. I have a
proper sparring partners and all that.
And the meantime,
we were talking about you're
doing commentary for new
Japan pro wrestling with
Jim Ross and you do it on a access
TV, right? That's right. Okay.
Every Friday night at eight,
uh,
you can see me sit down and run
my mouth about wrassling. Yeah.
Uh, we just did a, the live show up
at the cow palace in San Francisco,
which they've been having
sporadic a wrestling events there.
But it was a,
it was a big draw and that building
in like the 60s and seventies I guess.
So it's a bit of a historical,
it feels like wrestling pro wrestler.
He's making a renaissance.
It's like making a return. Yeah. I think
that um, there is a
certain audience of a, um,
of a certain age gap that our age group
that has come into flourishing in,
in, into the Internet and other ways
to which to to go ahead and, and,
and bring wrestling back up
there and show that wrestling,
whether it's the biggest company like
the WWE all the way to say, you know,
number two would be new Japan.
And then there's all these independent
companies all over the place that, uh,
some of them have quite
a decent following.
You know, uh, Billy Corgan from the
smashing pumpkins, huge wrestling fan.
He owns what, what is the company that
Nwa the national wrestling alliance? Yeah.
So he owns hard men. Nwa Is Nwa
the rap group. It's that too.
You mean?
That's what I hear when I hear Nwa.
I'm sure there's some attitude
involved. Gratitude, a Nwa. Think
about the rest of it,
but, uh, um, Nwa was,
is I guess it was, it's a legendary, um,
sanctioning body and so it wasn't any
one particular company, but it was a, um,
a sanctioning body that would
then oversee certain titles.
And so if you're going to be
on this show at this time,
you're going to defend
the Nwa Championship.
The NWA commission would get involved
and they had their specifications as to
how the title matches would be run
and whether or not you could lose by
disqualification or not.
Or if you go over the top rope would
be a DQ and little stuff like that.
Who did killer Kowalski? Russell for
killer Kowalski. I couldn't tell Ya.
Do you remember him?
I know the name but
I don't really, I mean school famous
trainer after the fact of it was,
yeah, when I was in high
school it was it ed doe.
Yay. That's right. Did we talk about
that with Billy? I think we did.
He was like local cable when I was in
high school. It was like killing days,
like a claw. He would like grab his own
rest and ground your head or something.
Like a guy,
Eric,
look at his head,
he's got his hand up the claw.
It's like there's some nostalgia to it.
That's one of the reasons why
I feel like it's coming back.
It's like people who liked it as a kid
or now as adults going back to it as a
nostalgia,
the Internet,
it's,
it's much easier to go out there and put
product out so it makes it more easily
disseminated to any audience that might
want to see it. Especially with like a,
um, you know, shows that are abroad.
Like there's some shows that'll go on
in Germany and Austria that we'll get
streamed and people get ahold of them.
They get to watch them.
So it's not like the tape
trading days of the, yes.
Does Jim Ross Hook you up with
his barbecue sauce? You know,
like he's got some fucking killer
barbecue. He's got this, he's got sauce,
he's got rubs. He is,
he's got all kinds of, uh,
a whole menagerie of all your meat.
Fixin's is he a pitmaster
is one of those dudes,
does he do the whole thing with the wood
and I don't have, I don't know, smoker,
hickory chips. And then he's got
his, his white oak on the side.
One of them guys maybe. Maybe
he lost to my mind. Yeah. Yeah.
There's like two types of people
that use like that barbecue.
There's people like me that you've
pellet grills, which is like infallible.
You know, I use one of those triggers.
Sure. It's easy for the Palestinian.
It does all the work for you,
but then there's a serious mother fuckers.
You chop wood and dry it out
and they've got the Coleman.
There are those old or the uh, uh,
the ones that start with a w, uh,
the Weber grills that there's
just nothing to it other than,
oh, those are cattle grills.
Yeah. Those are for amateurs, Bro.
The real series dudes, they get those
side, those side smokers. Oh, sure.
We have like the main chamber and then
you got a little wood box on the side
where the woods heating up and then the
air goes through and it smokes from this
debt sales people that
cook and like to 25,
they never let anything that I
throw stuff over over a gas flames.
That's right. I was guiding my luddite. I,
I have no business having any,
any voice in the realm of barbecuing.
But it seems like something you'd
be interested in. I love it. And it,
it's just a man who was into
all things manly. This is true.
And I like setting stuff
on fire and then eating it.
But you still drive a manual
transmission all around Los Angeles.
Just drove one today. Yeah.
Yeah, man. I just, uh, I, I've
been driving around, I just got it out
of the shop a little while ago. My,
I have a 75 formula a Firebird,
but instead of doing the ls swap,
which everybody does, and I
understand why, uh, it's got a
four 55 Pontiac in it that we board.
I had a board 60 out.
It's got forged Pistons. Uh, I didn't
go with forged rods that didn't need it,
I think because, well no, actually I
did put fours rods and forged pistons.
But iron heads, dual quads will you
look at at uh, you know, I don't know.
The goal was to just make
maybe one horsepower per
cubic inch but have well over
500 pound feet of torque.
That was the idea. And it's,
it's an automatic unfortunately.
Yeah.
Center for Sydney and we'll gives
me crap about that all the time.
She's getting swamped out cause I like
just being able to drive it there at
whole sun. Third hole on the floor.
But the clutch pedal in there, I'm,
I'm more than down, but uh,
you know, hell, it needs paint.
It needs interior done a, you
know, so Burt Reynolds car, right?
Is that the, you know, that's a 77.
Okay. You're 75 75, so it's got big,
big hood scoop,
solar headlights,
a circular headlights,
still kind of a square round off,
rounded off square for the,
the center Jamie and pull it up.
You can pull up 75 Firebird and the
formula has the big Ram air scoops on it.
Right,
right.
Th th the to write the big snorkels
that come over the toes are dope.
There it is. Oops. That's a
transaction. And mine's a formula.
Ooh,
look at that car.
Like that yellow one on the
right or that gray one formula.
Oh. So I've been driving that around
quite a bit and Hotchkiss did all the
suspension on it. We'll
look, did the brakes.
It stops in a heartbeat.
That's a nice magnaflow exhaust.
That's one of the few cars that
I liked from 75. Like it feels,
I feel like everything after 71
it's real risky in a way. I mean,
some of the styling lines
of these mid seventies cars,
I kind of like it in the
obnoxiousness of it all. But, uh,
and you know, whatever you
get with these as far as like,
so this car came with a 400,
the one that I bought and uh,
it was like seven and a half to one
compression. So it was just a total dog.
People like, Hey, do burnouts. I'm like,
I wish, I wish that was the year that,
I mean the years where the gas crunch
was on and they started making these cars
gas efficient. Right. Well are
they attempted to in some way?
And not to mention they would.
Um,
they started trying to incorporate um,
uh,
Smaug uh, elements to try and reduce
the amount of smog, these things,
but they were just highly inefficient
the way we're going about it with the air
stuff and different
processes that were like,
things connected to the heads
and it was bad news. Yeah.
It was a rough time for America.
Don't have,
I know the rare of the rare times that
is right. Yeah. One of the rare times,
it was a rough time for cars,
like from 71 to the 80s
all through the 80s.
We just make dog should cars made
some real, real, real snoozers.
Pontiac was one of the few
that was putting together a
decent looking car,
the Firebirds and the Trans Ams.
And then of course corvette Corvette's
still had some good looking cars in the
days they did. And especially because
they, even with the low horsepower motors,
they, they're still liked cars. He can
still get up there and hustle to us. Yeah.
And then with even into like
77, 78, you had the 6.6 liter,
the 400 or the four oh three. I guess by
that point in the Pontiac's right now,
chicks are turning off
their fucking radio in mass.
I don't know if any, any chicks wanted to
tune in to listen to what I had to say.
Anyway. Come on, Bro. You're Josh Barnett.
Chicks wanna hear what you have to say.
They want to learn the ways of men,
the ways of men. They want to learn.
They want to it.
There's a lot of fake men surrounding,
there are a lot of fake make.
I have a theory that, uh,
so not that long ago, I, maybe
just a handful of years ago,
I finally got like a
leather biker style jacket.
And so Fonz kind of, yeah.
But Eh, and uh, oh ray,
every time, you know what, but every
time I smacked something electronic,
it doesn't work better. So there,
yeah. He had a magic touch. Absolutely.
The ladies loved him. Yeah.
Yeah. Keeps her dildos and shape.
But uh, he uh, or I,
so I got this jacket and I've always
wanted one ever since I was a kid and I
went to this store in New
York because there was no,
there wasn't a location locally where
I could just try the jackets on and I
didn't want to buy an expensive jacket
and have to send it all this stuff.
So I was in New York, went to the store,
found the jacket that fit me, loved it,
bought it, been wearing the
ever living crap out of it,
taking it all kinds of places.
It's been a nasty black
metal mosh pits with it on.
I've been all around the world with
it had been in far eastern Russia.
Leather jacket is made to tell a story
eventually at the end of it. Right.
But people will go, oh you know, do
you ride a bike? And I'm like, ah, no.
The reason why I have the jacket is
because of Mad Max, the road warrior.
Cause when I saw that as a kid,
those jackets look bad ass and you know,
here's the bronze, the, the,
the MFP running around in their falcons
just tearing ass and blowing shit up
wearing these jackets. And I'm
like, I want a jacket like that.
But I started to notice that this jacket
was everywhere. Everywhere. Everybody,
everybody was making a version of this
jacket somehow or some way this biker
style jacket guys are wearing
it everywhere. Chicks are
wearing it everywhere.
And then I'm like, Huh,
that's a weird fashion trend.
I didn't really see that comment.
And then as I started to think
about it more and more and more,
it seems like there is a attempt within
society to try and present the image of
toughness,
right?
So from haircuts to jackets to all
these different kinds of things that
everyone's trying to appear to be
tough and bad ass all the time without,
but people aren't going out there and
necessarily risking it like they used to.
They're not, they're not in
generally taking on these
jobs that are dangerous or,
or even just your people
want to have muscle cars,
but they don't want to work on them.
They don't want to.
It's like by having the item,
it somehow in implies some sort of
character. Yes. I'm sort of toughness,
some sort of a rugged element to
yourself. Like, you know, I'm a bad ass,
like you've gone through it. Right?
But you know, when that check at your,
fallen off your bike going 70 miles
an hour and just rolling and dusting
yourself off and you'll
see all the, like, uh,
like the 30 year old Hollywood he type
dudes with the manicured beards and all
that on their Harley's that have all
been turned into choppers and like, okay,
it's like a, uh, a big
show of toughness without,
because people aren't going out there and,
and living tough lives anymore toughness,
or is it coolness and are
they the same things? It's,
I think it's a coolness related to
the idea of being tough and attempted
authenticity. Correct. And I, you know,
to use a term masculinity,
right. And even though, uh,
a woman that's a appearing to be tough.
I mean,
you would call it a masculine trait even
though that doesn't mean that they're
being a man. She's putting
out a signal, right? A,
a chick that wears like a
leather jacket and rides a bike.
She's putting out a signal like,
you better be a bad motherfucker if you
want this bitch or I'm going to girls.
Maybe it's one of those
previous could still apply
to the ladder, but, uh, it's,
it's like, um, you know, I'm a bad
motherfucker. All right. Whatever.
Whatever vibe you're trying to put out
there. And then you go and you're like,
well, okay, what's bad motherfucker
about you? I don't take no shit. Yeah,
sure you do. Hey Bro, don't take
any shit. My agent calls me.
I tell him to fuck off.
I walked in, I nailed that audition. I
didn't even have any product in my hair.
I don't give a fuck. You don't
know me, man. I'm different.
It's just a, it's just a little, it's a
casual observation is totally anecdotal,
but it just seems like people are
attempting to try and it's like things I
always tell people about looking
at human history, I go the, the,
the issues that we deal with,
the things that affect us or not new,
it's just in a lot of ways
are just more magnified there,
especially with social media.
Um,
social media I believe like picks and
preys on certain elements of our way of
being, our process. Uh, and it, and it
heightens our responses to certain things,
but it also heightens what we see from
these responses because when somebody is,
let's say,
massively insecure,
so social media can really pray,
help play hell on that and
make you feel more insecure,
especially if you're putting,
depending on where you're putting value
on what you see or what is said about
you or how you, or necessarily if
you're comparing yourself to others.
Also when you respond to that in some
way through your own social media,
be it by trying to take more grandiose
photos or, or, or, I don't know,
whatever sort of
signaling of,
of how to make up for that,
it shines even that much
more to everybody else.
So what you do get seen as much as you
see what everybody else does and then
you're given an option on how do you
react to that? Well, if you're not,
I mean these are the sort of that you
can go back into old books on philosophy
and uh, you know, old historical texts.
Insecurity is not going anywhere.
We're not any all that much more different
from a thousand years of 2000 years
or 3000 years. And the way we react
and respond to things than we are now.
It's just that all these
things are amplified under the,
the elements of technology that are around
us and how they can affect us and how
much easier it is for that,
for those things to get to us know,
radically amplified. I mean I see people
fighting with people on Instagram,
you know, see people fighting
with the commentors. Yes.
If someone posts something and then other
people shit on them and then they take
their posts and comment on that and you've
got to go with this is like hours of
your day man,
and people just sniping at you for the
clothes you're wearing or your fake lips
or whatever it is something, right. And
you, you, you could say, well, you know,
you've got the person who's got,
who's turned their,
their social media into a very self
absorbed sort of a platform. Right.
That's a lot. And then even in amongst
that, it's like, well, I mean to a degree,
if it's your social media and you
are the prime element within it,
of course it would be a bit self absorbed.
But yeah.
But I think there's more
nuance to it than that.
And it's not just to pick on say,
you know,
the gals that are taking all the sexy
selfies and all that kind of stuff.
There's the dudes that do essentially
the same equivalent and it's all in a,
you know, often it can be in a response
to drive attention towards themselves,
but what do you, why do you want
that attention in the first place?
And then of course that's something
that you can't know until you know the
person. Exactly. Well a lot of girls
make a living off of it. Yeah, 100% yeah.
There's a lot of girls that they do like
sponsored tweets or sponsored Instagram
posts at once.
They can get foods are making a living
off of Instagram that way for like that
got famous.
Like for girls it's like girls with big
asses and there's one girl that I just
started following her whole
Instagram was her ass.
I mean that is it man. I was thinking
I was a terrible thing to think,
but I was thinking of a dog ever came over
and bit her ass. She'd be out of work.
That's it. It's fucked up.
She's have an arking spray of,
of fucking jail shooting out of her house.
He should have Kevlar pants on everywhere
she goes. That ass Lloyd's of London.
I have a, what will you give
me per cheek on insurance.
I mean she has a tremendous ass,
don't get me wrong,
but it's just weird when
there's this like one,
here's body part that essentially
defines your identity.
Like this essentially does, which,
which is weirder, that great ass though.
This person with this fantastic
monumental epic level ass is out
there taking photos of it and putting
it out there for people to see or that
people not only continue to look
at it but more flock to this.
This a religious icon of
an ass apparently. Yeah.
Well it doesn't get old apparent. It
never gets old. No, it's not for dudes.
I mean for girls. Is there like one
bar? I guess it's abs isn't abs?
Like what is the one body I
turned to Jamie. Jamie, yeah. Hey,
tell us about what the girls are
for girls until wallet.
Look how fat as well. And this
is kind, kinda fat wallet. But,
uh,
well on also it wouldn't be surprised
that the women in terms of that,
that kind of shallow aspect of
social media in that way could,
could make more impact out of it.
Because even when you look
at say all the men's Mag,
all the women's magazines and all that
kind of stuff and like women want to look
at how women, right. So women
are even driven to look at,
and we're of course obviously
driven to look at hot women. Well,
women know about filters too. Like, oh,
this bitch is using filters. Look at her.
That is not what she looks like. And then
when we got, she looks like a cartoon.
Sure enough,
look at her face and then they're trying
to find out what filter that was. Well,
it felt beauty filter. What
Cameron did she use? Yeah. If, uh,
if girls found out that there was
like one camera that really did it,
they would be, every girl would use
that one phone that has that one camera.
Exactly. They nailed it. I guess
they're all pretty good now.
But if there was like one standout
phone that took better selfies,
like that would be the one that they used.
Oh,
it would be a marketing avalanche
towards that demographic for sure.
Your rear phone, like if you have
a phone, the camera on the back.
It's always more powerful
than the selfie camera.
That's a bigger lens and
for chicks, that's fucking
bullshit. Like they need it.
They need a good reverse.
The other way I need like multiple lenses.
You can choose which one you
need. They're like, I know it.
My friends look like I see them.
I want to see myself selfie sticks.
If there was dudes only dudes on the
planet, they'd be no selfie sticks.
That shit would've never been invented.
You don't think so? No. If we found,
if it was only men and we,
we found a guy with a selfie stick,
that would be the guy we fucked.
I called them down all the way down.
What is this? Is this, did you get
injured? Is this a walking stick?
Is a portable baton in
case you get attacked?
Are you using that to take photos inside
of a bear cave because you got about to
go in, do you want to make sure you know
where the Grizzly is? Are you a, you know,
putting that thing around corners
to see where that rabbit is? Yeah.
Is that what you're doing? Because
if not, I've got a problem with this.
When my arms are short lucky dudes with
selfie sticks, that is a dark thing.
There's something about it
like holding it up. Hey,
I'm in front of a Blob of why, why
is it, why is that even bottom?
It doesn't even make any sense.
Like why is it okay for me to take
a Selfie with a regular Selfie Lens?
But it's a problem if a dude as
a selfie stick. I don't know,
I just seems a bit obnoxious perhaps.
Well,
it seems that way. I can't say that I
have a reason why it makes sense. Make me,
hey, maybe it's simply because we
view it as something that, that,
or we see women do it
more. And so we, we, uh,
think that a man is somehow doing
something. Well, it's like mainly,
I don't know if a man gets fillers in
his face ever see like a older dude to
gets fillers in his face. He's like,
Bro, I didn't want to pull them aside.
Come here. I'm sure I have. Yeah,
you want to go? No, just don't,
you're going to be wrinkled. This
is just it. You're 65 years old.
You've got to let it go. And the headache,
it's letting go on its own anyways.
But some, some gals can kind of pull
it off and you feel bad for them,
but they still kind of pretty, so you
let it go. You know, personally myself,
I'm not really all that into the,
especially manipulating the
face like that and for anyone,
I just think that it's, it's one the
potential for it to go really badly,
real beds there. And two, it
just, I think that people, um,
you don't have to look perfect
to be a beautiful person. Yeah.
Your personality,
your personality is at least as
important as the way you look.
And if your personality is such that you
need to shoot plastic in your face in
order to feel good about yourself,
you know, I've got to go, Ooh,
like what's happened in their
bone below the surface. The,
it could be a indicator of
something more serious that,
that no matter how much filler,
how nice it could look maybe there,
there's still gonna be an issue per se.
It's also one of those things,
just like anorexia or bodybuilders that
can never get big enough where they have
body dysmorphia, people don't know
what they really look like. Do you,
do you know about the FIBONACCI
sequence? Uh, the numbers, right?
It's the golden ratio.
It actually applies to facial features.
See if you can find something on that.
And now there was one of
the sea documentary on that,
right? And at the time,
as I thought,
and there was something about symmetry
and Elizabeth Hurley when they made that
thing was considered one of the most
beautiful women in the world by the
[inaudible], by the mathematics of
it all. She's still one of them.
I don't doubt it. Yeah. That checks like
88 years old. She's still hot as fuck.
She's rocking it.
Um,
but there's something about
the way your face is shaped.
Um, your, you're like a good
example is my friend Ari Shaffir.
Ari has a thin face in a long
nose and it all works together.
Like if he had my nose on his
face, it would be like, hey,
the fuck's wrong with your face.
But the ratios of the width of his
face and the length of his nose,
the size of his eyes, all that
stuff, somehow or another syncs up.
So you're saying it's not that any one
thing, it's the sum of your parts. Yes.
It's all those things go together.
And if one of them is off,
like say if your hair is
golden ratio on the face.
So if you are a black woman
and you have white lips,
like a white woman's lips,
people like what the fuck is
going on with even whistle, right?
She's got a large nose or
a wide nose and you know,
my grow this facial hair, no,
hide my skinny little skinny lips.
I can platelets lips. You got Viking
lips, Bro. I haven't been told that I've,
this is a, I've had some
girls go, man, you're,
you're actually in way better kiss or
than I expected because you have almost,
it seems like you have no lips. I'm
like, ah. Do you know the good, the bad?
Someone told Kylie Jenner and that's
why she got facial stuff. Yeah,
I was reading that today.
This is what kind of a loser I am.
50 year old man with children. I fucking
pay taxes. I got a lot of shit to do.
Meanwhile,
I'm reading some article about why Kylie
Jenner decided to take all the filler
out of her face. It was a fucking article
on my Google feed and it was like,
what is this? They know what
you're into. I guess they do.
I don't know how they've got your
name tag. They signs of pitches.
How do they know they know the
inner workings of Joe Rogan?
We'll fill her is a fairly
recent thing in human history.
I mean I'm not long as I've been
around Billy with it. I mean,
I don't proclaim to be too much of a
know what's in it. What is filler? Well,
it's okay. Let's facial filler. Google
that. What's in facial filler sand?
A JB weld. Pando gorilla come. Yeah.
Probably depending on how
high a grade it is or,
and there's the freshness levels.
The gorilla club.
Does it feel like if they touch your
face and you've got some shit and then it
makes your cheeks,
some girls look like they got rocked
like their cheeks injectable fillers for
the face. Oh Jesus. A
hydraulic hyaluronic acid. No.
Siena college in a hyaluronic acid are
both going to get absorbed into your
system eventually.
Yeah.
I think that's the good part
about it is that it's temporary.
And then if you just let your
body raising scour depressions,
enhancing lips and replacing soft tissue
volume loss through facial injections.
Hmm. Huh. Enhancing Lips,
Huh? Hmm. Get it done.
But that's why it looks weird with girls
when they have big fake lips because of
the golden ratio. Your face
doesn't, it just doesn't work.
Like go back to that article on the golden
ratio of the face, please. And you'll,
you'll see like they have a,
there's a whole mathematical sort of
algorithm that they can use to short sort
of,
uh,
explain what is and is not
normal in the shape of your face.
Like look at um, what the
fuck's his name? Angelina Jolie.
You remember that song?
There was a fucking song that someone,
there was a song, God
dammit. This is like 2002
some like it was a song was Angelina
Jolie got some big ass titties,
the name of the song. It was that a big
Larry as that was, that was that top 40.
I'm not amongst me and my stupid
fucking friends. It was we, it was,
it was a funny song. Like the
dude who sang it. Is that,
is that funny sober as well or that's
a good question and you'd have to ask
somebody else.
Those are the years from the,
from 2001 I was doing
fear of fact is that it
suggested to be
stating the obvious,
is that the name?
Yes. It's got some pig ass
it, it's such, it's so stupid.
From 2000 to two somewhere around
2007 I think I was high every day.
It's all a blur. It's just the, it's
just like driving through fog. I would,
I was so bored where I was
doing fear factor. The only
way I enjoyed it, I was by,
you weren't,
you weren't enjoying all eating pig
anuses and people screaming about having a
centipede on their head and
after a while it got bored.
He got me get desensitized to it.
It just didn't, it just can't watch
general porn anymore. Right. It's like
if there's not a robot right in there,
you know, having sex with a
tiger while a midget films,
it was clearly that stuff does happen.
Right?
Like this is a reason
why people like gag porn.
Was it rule 34 if there's not
a point of it that, uh, it,
there's,
if you can think of it,
there's a porn out there and 35 is if it
doesn't exist, it shall be made. Yeah,
that makes sense. It's a four Chan thing.
Not that I'm a fortunate all the time,
but, well, someone's got to
on all account.
There's something about like people
getting desensitized that's fucking
absolutely real. And that's one of
the reasons why, like in times of war,
people are capable of doing
more and more awful shit.
It's like you get desensitized,
you get normalized.
Like people are very malleable, you get
accustomed to all sorts of things. Yeah.
Some of those things don't necessarily
stay forever. They're, they're subjective,
you know, for that, that
time and that moment.
And plus there is everything that's
going around you. And, and if,
if we're all in here and we're
saying we're drinking coffee,
we think that this is the way to be.
And then other foot everyone else
out and around us and like, well,
they're all drinking energy drinks,
energy drinks are actually
the best thing to do. Ah,
well now there's this other thing that
you see that in perhaps then that bleeds
into what, oh no, let's do energy drinks
instead. Yeah. And if you go from that to,
you know, let's drink a grain alcohol,
well maybe not the bill could be. Yeah.
I mean, sure. People just imitate
their atmosphere will show and,
and if someone else is, you know,
God and war, if they take one year,
your your teammates and then cut them
to pieces and send them back to you,
then all of a sudden, yeah, you're going
to do the same events. Some, you know,
reprisal. Yeah. Yeah. There
I used to know dude who, uh,
he was a Mormon and Mormons aren't
allowed to drink coffee. Well,
I thought you were going to go somewhere
else, but I knew he was a Mormon.
He used to cut people a piece in the
center. No, he didn't do any of that,
I don't think. Well, I mean, Mormons,
they're just so friendly. Yeah. There's,
there's something got to be going on
underneath. Somethings there's a trigger.
You've got to find it.
But to put the hole in there,
they get a hole in their magic
underwear and they're just, that's it.
But I would fucking place down, I offered
him a cup of coffee and he's like, no,
uh, I can't drink coffee. And he had
a fucking, one of those huge monster
energy drink. Seriously. Yeah.
He was drinking them all day long to
the point where he was having heart
problems. He's kidding.
Fucking hard palpitations.
He was drinking. Oh No, it wasn't,
wasn't monsters. It was rock stars.
I wonder which one has more
caffeine if I know what you want to.
I think Raj mark has more caffeine
than a monster. Monster is doable.
Like I drink, I'll drink a sugar free
monster during UFC broadcasts at times.
I drink those during the, uh, the
new Japan shows if four hours. Yeah.
But the problem is you've got to Piss.
There's whatever's in there,
goes right to your system. I
use caffeine. Ain't helping.
Goldberg used to drink those fucking
things like they were water and he was
always pinging.
Both monster and Rockstar have the
same amount of caffeine per serving,
which is eight 80 milligrams per
eight ounces. Yeah, but what?
Haiti is not that. Wow. That's crazy.
That's our list as being two 40 at or
something around there at the whole can
and monster list as being one
32. This is to 70 G. Whoa.
See if she had these little bad
boys or two. Seven. God dammit.
Tate trying to give you kind of
made me jump out of his chair case.
Trying to take,
try to give people heart attacks.
Shadow Tait Fletcher. Shout out to take
Fletcher and caveman coffee. Yeah. Um,
there's uh, people are weird with trends,
right? Like whatever the fuck happened.
The acid wash jeans.
I was thinking that the other day.
Like people used to
love acid washed jeans.
You remember they'd walk around with
genes was all sports all over them.
I think they're kind of making a bit of
a comeback. Yeah. It's like fanny packs.
Yup. And and and have the same, you were
ahead of the curve way ahead of curve.
I never left. You're basically a late
eighties pro wrestler. Yeah. Right. Like,
oh Cogan like all Gogan like, yeah,
right here. Ladies and gentlemen.
This pitch never left my side. All
leather never left my side. This is real.
It was made from a big horn sheep
that you, a, you tracked down.
I shot with an Arrow.
I should get one made.
I've got these access
deer hides out there.
I should get one turn into a fanny pack.
That'd be dope. Please. Before on it.
Fuck yeah. Right. Yeah. Hope
you don't get any ticks. No,
there's no kicks on those.
I don't think they have ticks in Hawaii.
It's weird,
you know.
But that's the thing about paradigms
is you don't really realize it when the
paradigm is over until you're out of it.
Right?
So we're in a paradigm
now of some sort and,
and it's easy to get lost in that
and not be able to see outside of,
what do you think is happening now
that will be ridiculed in the future?
Um, tough. I mean,
I didn't think that in a lot of ways
we would end up to where we are at this
point and,
and so many of the social and cultural
elements and that didn't even just
specifically stay within the u s but
seem to be bleeding throughout all of
western society and civilization at large.
Um,
I've got one word Yeezys
Yeezys Yeezys be marked
with that says that's a shoe,
right? That's just for Jamie.
He loves those fucking things. He bought
me a pair. I won't wear them. I told them,
next time I go running in the creeks,
I'm going to wear them.
Jamie loves these goddamn things,
so I'm not going to hit this.
It's still got the foam thing in that bro.
Put them on. Nope. Yeezys that come on.
That looks like a sneaker from the
80s. Right. I wouldn't even say that.
We'll just say this by the way. You're
talking to a real man here. That's okay.
I understand this and understand this.
Is that just like the bottom of a,
of a fucking
mailman form Styrofoam Coleman coolers.
It's the bottom part. The
ultra boost. Ultra boost.
What is this? This is like a
glorified fucking water sock.
This is like the thing, you
see some, some doofus with a,
those frog skin things on his
glasses to keep him from falling.
Always wandering around in the, you
know, I don't want to get too wet.
So you wouldn't wear those? No. Weird.
I wear weird how manly
men where these cars.
I wear chuck Taylors custom
chucks. Fuck yeah. With uh, my,
my logo on the side. I was drawn
by Dan prenotion. Look at that. Uh,
skulls and shit. God Damn dirty. Stinky
Chuck. I wear black metal tee shirts.
Fuck yeah. Look at that. See that? Chuck's
got damp classics. Jamie, not this.
What is this a fuck's going on here?
It's comfort.
I bet they're comfortable as
fuck. Right? They feel like soft.
They're like crocs while
I'm wearing. I'm like, damn,
I should probably put these on
when no one's looking. God Damn.
He's like being like, you're just
wearing Angelina Jolie's titties. Right?
It's a big ass holes. Yeah,
they look comfortable. Pitch.
I could see JP and some, what's
that jacket? See Jp and some Yeezys.
Jp Jordan Peterson.
Peterson easy. Oh yeah.
I could see him wearing some atrocious
sandals and no one's looking like,
whoa man. You'd have to talk to him to
do, to do good. Take those off with a,
we hit with like some wool socks on.
Yeah.
Jamie and I were talking
about this the other day.
You're allowed to wear socks with slides.
Slides,
so there's no,
there's no toe.
You're allowed w who says guys wear
them all time. Fuck that noise.
The fuck is that about? I
don't know. It's a thing loud.
No, it's not allowed guys
wear them all the time.
Keep your socks out of your sandals.
We were just in Vegas and there was
some basketball thing going on there.
There was a bunch of basketball players,
half of them slides with socks.
Here's the deal with that though.
It's, I can at least say as an athlete,
they,
maybe they've got the slides on because
they're going to take those sides off and
put their basketball shoes right on.
So for them it's like, I'm uh, I'm,
I'm out of uniform at the moment.
I'm ready to go to combat basketball
wise at any moment. I don't know.
But in general, as far as a fashion trend,
fuck that noise. But it looks ridiculous
amongst like rappers. I see rappers
wearing those things with socks,
it just looks like he just,
I dunno, like you given up. Yeah, kind of
money. Just wear sweatpants all day too.
Like you're a dude with a wife beater
with your gut hanging out of the bottom of
it and you just fucking kicked it back.
Fuck it.
I'd only,
I can't even bend over and tie my
shoes class to the velcro on my Yeezys.
Yeah, yeah. They don't velcro do that.
Well, you know, I guess, I guess you
don't need a real shoe. If you throw on,
you walk out with your socks on,
you throw on your sliders and get on
your hoverboard are fucking what your
electric scooter
me.
Would you ever drive a Tesla?
Uh, I would drive a Tesla.
Uh, but you know, here's,
I got one of my beefs,
not with Tesla's per se in any way,
but I would say talking about cars
as some gunny, uh, out and about,
and they'll, we'll have
some conversation and, uh,
I'll bring up some car or talking
about something like the dodge, uh,
and I wasn't the demon when the hell cat
came out. And so like, Oh yeah, those,
those hell,
I've heard amazing things about how,
not only is it obviously incredibly
powerful and fast, but that they're,
they're massively comfortable.
You could, it's a gt car.
You could grant her at all over the U S
and B comfy the whole time. And it was,
yeah. And they're like, oh, but
what about the Tesla? I'm like, um,
that's another 40 to $50,000
more. Oh, it's almost,
I heard it's as fast if not faster.
I go,
if I'm paying over a hundred fucking
thousand dollars for a car, get better.
Be Fast. It better have all this shit
like, and I would talk about, you know,
certain other and a lot of times it's
like my Firebird doesn't cost that much.
Dude,
I don't care if that Tesla winds,
you just spent $150,000 on a car.
What if cost wasn't an option?
What if you were Elon Musk? If
I'm Elan Musk, I'm, well God,
I don't think he can not drive
a Tesla if he's out there and,
and a goddamn three inch
exhaust for 70 you know,
big block I Pontiac people
are like, what the fuck? Yeah.
He probably can't drive anything but
tussles and Oh, what a trap. Yeah. Yeah.
No, I wish I would rather,
I would rather drive a car.
I don't feel like electric cars have soul.
They don't have any,
there's nothing that doesn't.
Thank you.
And then a little printer comes out
and I just doesn't do it for me. Well,
they're really cool, but at the
end of the day, there's a problem.
The problem is it feels good to
hear the rumble of it. Engine.
I mean the fucking put that
clutch in and pop that gear.
What does that Elan's to gas cars.
He owns a Jag.
That's an old school jag.
That's a hard, hard top.
It's probably a V12 actually.
Those are amazing. That's the first
love. Wow. Oh, it's a roadster. Okay,
so that top pops off. Wow. That's, that's
shaped man. Look at that. The
edible. What year was that?
Oh yeah,
that's
[inaudible] 60 [inaudible] 60
70 67 and it's a gorgeous car.
Ah, so pretty. Let me see that
picture again. Scroll down. Oh,
look at that.
Yeah,
but there's something about the
sound of combustion engines. Just,
it's so magnetic. Tesla's are
cool. They're silent. They're,
I'm sure they're incredibly comfortable.
Oh yeah. And that pad that they,
big ass iPad that you have where
your navigation screen is. I mean,
it is the shit while you're
driving and that thing.
And you just ask it to play songs
and it pulls them up on Spotify.
I'm also a little bit
weirded out by the over elect
tronic element of modern life.
I realized the usefulness of it,
but I always think about,
you know when some shit goes south,
like I can't just fix it and we keep
going or if something goes bad it could go
bad and a lot of different
ways and there's a chain
of command of bad that that
it's all linked to that it could go
to as well. And so I'm just like, Eh,
it just doesn't it. Plus when you
talk about engines, all right, you,
you start up your Porsche,
right? You start up know Yvette,
you start up an ls motor and then you
started up next to a big block Pontiac.
You started up next to a big block forward
and everything has a different feel,
a different, the different cam that's
in it makes it sound different,
makes it operate different.
The exhaust,
it's on everything changes based on all
kinds of different elements. And so the,
the car even of itself,
not just the exterior of it but the
internal is make it seem like a different
vehicle. Yeah, for sure. Like have
you ever been around Ferrari? Uh,
not a ton, no. But I know they have,
they got this sound like
they had their own.
Aston Martin is famous for having,
it's a very specific exhaust note.
There's sounds that they have,
it's like a celebration.
It's like better not drive it too far
cause it's probably going to break before,
before the next 12 minutes. This
is fantastic. Nothing like it.
The way they sound like I used to
love top gear with Jeremy Clarkson.
Jeremy crusher. Yeah. He's the best.
Whoever he punched he said. Sorry.
Yeah.
Do the show Brad,
get over it right along BBC conscious lap.
It's what you were talking about earlier.
People are pussified there.
Pussified there.
They're playing tough.
They're doing a Goddamn car show
with a bunch of men drinking booze.
You guys got in a fight and
you got hit. Well, okay,
take a little settlement and move on. Give
them, take an apology or even just say,
Hey, let me hit you one back. Fine, I
wish I was there. Jeremy, how much money?
What do you got in the bank?
Six to $70 million.
Give the man a million people wanting to
sort of live at parents' house for the
rest of their life.
Except then it goes from being mom and
dad to them being a state of some sort
that does all your work for you.
Cause you don't want to have to take
the responsibility of either winning or
losing that confrontation. Maybe.
Well I think he just got punched.
Was a drunk asshole. Maybe
so, but if it's on Jeremy,
you can just go in and be like, all right
dude, I'm going to, I get one on you.
Yeah, it's, and it's even, we're
done. I'll move on with my life.
But what if the guy can fucking crack?
Maybe she called Dale shouldn't have
fucking hit him that he shouldn't have
fucking hit him at all.
Well that's the realm of people that
don't practice martial arts. Like,
how many people get drunk
and get in fistfights that
actually know how to fight.
It's pretty small.
It's according to the Internet.
It's real small and he wants his father,
right?
It's always what they're doing.
You know, they think it's,
I'm always amazed at people's,
uh,
overestimation of what they
can do with their body,
especially in it went
to pertains to animals.
Like what you would do if an
animal is coming at you. Like,
you know what my favorite
thing to watch is?
One of my favorite things are the
last couple of weeks I got to stop.
I watched fucking running with the
bowls. Oh Man. When is that zen?
This brands actually this week I think
I have a bunch of friends over there.
They're going to do that. Call them. Call
them. Tell them you love them. Tell them,
get the fuck out of there.
Hey, let's, let's uh,
hey,
let's get this two ton animal fucking,
I don't think people understand a,
how strong those things are and B,
how shitty their body works. People
have this idea. The, come at me, bro.
I'm going to fucking just get out of the
way. I'll just sidestep it. Meanwhile,
you're on these slick beer
soaked. What is this, Jamie? Oh,
this is the end of it right now.
It's the sixth of the 14 it's happening
right now. I can't believe it.
I've been watching videos.
I didn't know it was actually live.
This is on Instagram.
So fucking insane.
This is so insane. People are so
insane. What if it gets a beat on you?
And then all of a sudden,
like a note,
you're the only one out of this entire
crowd of 500 people right now that it
wants to Gore. Oh yeah. Well, I mean,
if it finds one that sits still,
it's going to tickets, frustrations
out. And the crazy thing is,
look how many people were there watching
this and watching these fools running
around in the middle of this bull fight.
I want to see someone
get fucked up by a bull.
Have you ever watched a bull fight? Uh,
I have not. I have seen plenty of clips,
footage of it, what have you, but
I've never watched a bullfight. Yeah,
I'm not interested. It doesn't
really do anything for me. No.
I mean I can up until the
point of, of, of killing it.
I, okay. You want to go out there and
dodge a bull? Uh, seems like a bad idea,
but all right. But then you, all right,
you've already proven that you can
maneuver yourself out of the way.
No need to spirit and kill it.
Yeah.
It also seems to me that
I know it's tradition.
I know it comes from a different
era. I know. I understand that.
And so I'm not gonna sit
here and then just like
go railroading bullfighting this is,
their acquisition is tradition too.
There's a lot of things that
are very successful. Yeah.
There's a lot of horrific traditions.
It just seems to me to be a, uh,
a bastardization of our relationship
with animals. Like even,
I don't think there's anything
wrong with domesticated animals,
but obviously factory farming is this
disgusting. It's nasty. Why, why do it?
And there is no,
I,
it's possible to have animals that are
able to live a more natural way of life
then it is to jam them into a
cage and force feed them until,
I don't know if it's possible to do
it the way we've been doing it though.
The real problem is the way we expect
to be able to just go to Jack in the box
and get a burger. Well, we eat
too much meat. Yeah. I in general,
I think that your average person doesn't
need to eat nearly as much fucking
varieties of meat as they do. They need,
they definitely need meat in their diet,
I believe. Uh, on average.
Do you know, you know about
the carnivore diet? Now, see,
here's the thing. I've been, uh,
uh, I heard you talking to you,
you've talked a lot about, and then
Jordan Peterson and his, his daughter,
I talked about it with Chris Bell First,
who's been on it for,
I think he's been on it for
at least six months or so.
And he's having radical improvements
and one of the reasons that he's having
improvements and then Jordan's
having tremendous results and uh,
Jordan's daughter as well is arthritis.
They all have arthritis.
Like Chris Bell has two artificial hips.
I don't doubt it.
Tried to be that Marcus Smelly,
smelly Chris, Chris, Chris's boar,
Chris Board Bell. And Chris is the
one who, uh, produce bigger, stronger,
faster. I met Chris, I've met, I've
actually never met mark. They're great.
Chris is a fantastic, always got
us backward baseball cap on. Yeah,
they're both fantastic guys and really,
really smart and just,
Chris has suffered from serious,
debilitating arthritis and pain
in his joints his whole life.
Having a carnivore diet knocked it out
for him. And, and that's thing. Uh,
I was familiar with the ketogenic diet
and all that kind of stuff and having a
higher, it works for me as well
to be honest, to eat that way. My,
my problem is my love affair with
fucking breads. Their problem,
you're out there getting a coffee
maybe in the morning, like, damn,
that looks like an amazing
croissant right now.
You know how it looks even better in
my face. He like a chocolate croissant.
I do like chocolate croissants. You
know, you always get the best ones.
Coffee Bean, those Starbucks ones
can suck my dick. You know what?
I don't eat croissants. I
don't eat. I'm a Seattle Guy,
but I don't need Starbucks for science.
You don't know. They're terrible.
They used to be okay.
They used to be pretty good.
You know when they went south and they
started putting them in plastic bags,
they give them to you again. They're
already sealed up in a plastic bag back.
No one's at coffee bean have way more
chocolate in them. They're thick.
If you're going to go deep, go deep.
That's what I say. I go to the, the off,
you know the non chain coffee
shops that will like a coffee,
coffee and food and coffee commissary.
He's down the street
here or Russian bakery.
These chocolate croissants knock
dick right into the dirt. Can Bet.
Ooh Rich and delicious.
Yeah.
I'll just want to get driver for
them. I got good coffee tonight. If I,
if I stick to eating and then
any more ketogenic way it's,
I feel better. My joints hurt less. Uh,
I lose fat easier, but I still
can, can put on muscle mass. It's,
it is a better way for me to eat.
And I don't know if there is something
about our genetic makeups say meet you
JP. We probably have some
crossover similarity there. Yeah.
I don't know if there's
anything to do with that.
I just know that it's been
useful to me and I've seen it be,
you know, that's the way
you eat. And I've seen,
I've heard Jordan talk about his daughter
and how useful it's been for her and
as you,
I mean she's had her ankle replaced or
hip replaced like an auto immune thing as
does he,
it's the same.
It's same exact issue and an autoimmune
issue is also what this radical
arthritises.
I mean there's so many people have
these issues and these are isolated
incidences, you know, isolated issues
that people have. But you know,
I know people that thrive on vegetarian
diets. I have no problem with it. Yeah,
a vegetarian is the way to go.
For a lot of people that are
thinking about being Vegan,
don't be scared of eggs,
folks, just get eggs are good
for you. Eggs are great for you.
Just all this fucking Peta propaganda when
they called him chicken periods. Look,
if you don't want to kill animals, I get
it. I get it. I told him, I love animals.
Get free range eggs.
You can get them at the fucking farmer's
market and they have a dark orange yolk
and they're fucking great for you.
And the chickens don't even notice
they're gone. They don't give a fuck.
No chickens going to
have eggs no matter what.
They just lay them and less there's
a rooster to exactly to fertilize it.
They just kind of fucking lay.
Hey. Yeah, it's just free food.
It's like a gift that they give
you a free tans. Keystone chickens.
I had six eggs this morning for breakfast
and credible, thicker and heavier,
and it's actually good for you and
a of all things. One of chickens,
one of their favorite little snacks.
That's something that they
just absolutely love. Eggs.
Chickens love scrambled eggs. Yeah.
You know what they really love?
They love shells. They love the
fuck shit. Shells. Shells. Yeah. No,
they love more than that. Mice,
mice, lizard sale. Fuck. Oh fuck.
Yeah. But you know what? They
don't fuck with squirrels.
Well, they're a little big.
Yeah, but they just don't even try
like squirrels, like a rat, you know?
It's basically a rat. Everybody loves
squirrels. Even chickens step bushy tail.
It's crazy. That bushy
tails. All you needed,
that cute haircut is like this little
snap and a wink and ah, yeah. Yeah.
Well, I had a, I had four
chickens and one time, uh,
there was a little miniature Chihuahua,
a little chihuahua or a little
mini docksin maybe or mini mint.
It was a min pin and it got into the yard
and ended up in the backyard and the four
chickens cornered it and wouldn't let
it leave. And so it's back there.
Wine and, and Yelp in. And eventually,
uh, my ex at the time went and caught
the dog and then tried to figure out how,
whose it was and what have you.
And it turned out it was chipped.
I think [inaudible] got given somewhere
where someone can then track them down.
But it was just hilarious that these
chickens were like, fuck you motherfucker.
You're in the wrong place. You
know else loves squirrels. My dog.
That's a different animal
all together. Yeah. Marshall,
they hardly ever catch him though.
He got that one.
It was like this sweet golden retriever,
this kind dog who loves everybody.
Yeah. He likes fucking
up squirrels too. Well,
the problem is the squirrels
go into the chicken coop.
They'll find a way in the chicken coop
and they steal all the chickens for food
and Marshall just decided to wait outside
the chicken coop because he knew where
the hole was.
I just sit in there and snatch that
mother fucker home and then he's just with
the biggest shading ground space. Yeah,
Mrs Rogue and does not like the squirrels.
She doesn't like the squirrels
getting into the chicken food. To me,
I feel like we just buy more chicken food.
Poor little squirrels hustling.
It's hard life being a squirrel.
It is just trying to get an melodies.
You know church is trying to get by
trying to live your life are out there.
They're all this peer pressure from all
these other squirrels smoking young.
Yeah.
They find this sweet spot where all
these fucking nuts and all this grain is
like, this is amazing. Yeah.
It was issued scroll gang.
You know when they fucked up though,
they started stealing eggs.
They stay stealing eggs.
These cons,
we're trying to roll eggs out of the
chicken coop. That's when she got mad.
I had no idea that squirrels ate eggs.
And then we started finding videos online.
Jamie pulled up a bunch
of videos of squirrels,
Rolan chicken eggs out of a
chain of murder that either
the motherfuckers we, they have, we have
egg boxes, they're elevated egg boxes.
Okay. The egg boxes like two and
a half, three feet off the ground.
Squirrels got up into the egg box, got
the egg, chucked it out of the egg box,
lands on the ground. The getting it
in their role in the egg. Look clever.
Little fucker's sneaky and they're cute.
So they're like,
I can get away with anything. They do get
away with more. Like rats must be like,
what in the fuck man?
Where's the smart as shit?
We were way smarter and yet
people can fuck him on us.
Just stab us left and right. Yeah. There's
no industry for Squirrel killing. Like,
no,
not really.
Maybe in the deep south and that's not
an industry get their mortgage is paid by
killing rats. Like they're driving
around in a nice car from killing rats.
This Nolan and nobody cared. Nobody
feels bad. Like, Oh, I'm an exterminator.
We're all racist when it comes to
certain animals and bugs, right?
People collect butterflies, nobody
stomp, roaches, everybody stomps,
roaches and swats mosquitoes. Well
fuck mosquitoes. Those things,
they will give you everything, you
know, all kinds of diseases and shame,
gay fever.
Larry,
the only part of the mosquitoes life I
enjoy or think is interesting is when
their larva and they're these fucking
vicious little with these giant hook teeth
that will can't even eat little fish and
all that kind of stuff in the ponds too.
When I first moved to California,
I rented this house in Encino and nobody
lived in it for like a year and a half,
two years, something like that. And uh,
they had a pool in the backyard that was
just sitting there with Terrell gamma
green.
He wasn't just,
there was schools of mosquito
larva swimming around like fish.
I went out into the yard. I was like, what
the fuck is that? And the guy was like,
oh, we'll take care of that. I go,
what is that? You have that? Yes.
You poison the, she just pour
bleach into it. Yeah. Well,
the first thing you do is you bleach it,
then you've got to drain it. You gotta,
you gotta take all this Goop,
all that shit out. Yeah.
You got to drain all that water out.
They had to bring like a machine and
then they had a clean, all the fucking,
the bottom of the pool.
It was all green and funky.
But the crazy thing is they were moving
through the water. Like, you know,
I see those, those big flocks of birds.
Yes. And they all moved together.
They were doing that in the water.
There was fucking thousands of them.
It was crazy. But then they didn't grow
legs. Oh, it would've been a real problem.
It would have been a real problem if
that got out and started flying around,
I would've got fucked.
Doug. There's a meme out there,
uh, and it's, I think it's a, um,
it's a picture, um, and it's repeated in,
in on the bottom as well of a
peta billboard and it's got,
uh, you know, uh, these animals, all
Sydney at standing in a line and it says,
where do you draw the line between
food and friends or whatever?
And then someone else has,
then they've got the same thing down
there and it's like, uh, you know,
this is normal food is a catastrophic,
that apocalypse.
I've seen that, I've seen
that. Yeah. Well, you know,
being a vegetarian or Vegan is a very,
it's a very first world option.
The reason why people got to this point
is because we figured out a way to
survive eating all the animals around us,
just like they figured out
a way to survive eating the
animals around them. Well,
I need the argument that,
oh,
this culture is mostly vegetarian or
veer this or that. And it's like, okay,
well it's also highly developed
based on what was available. Yeah.
Like they didn't just say, I don't
want to hurt the animals. Well,
the only people that did is the Hindu
hidden. Those are fascinating, you know,
and there's a lot of speculation
as to wash starkly clipboard.
He developed civilization
at certain points in time
in comparison to the rest of
the world. Oh yeah. I mean you go
back and read the Bhagavad Gita.
I mean they had some really complex
philosophy and really interesting thoughts
about the universe.
But a lot of people believe that
that was due to psychedelic drugs.
And one of the,
yeah,
well one of the reasons why they believe
they had this interesting relationship
with cattle but not with lamb was because
cattle shit would grow magic mushrooms
on it.
This is because so much is a big part
of the ancient Hindu folklore and their
religion and their ancient texts,
they talk about Soma and so much was some
sort of a psychedelic mixture and they
don't know exactly what it was, but
they know that Hindus, um, the, um,
like a lot of the ancient Hindu text,
they deal with some sacraments and
they know that they were in to hash.
And like a lot of the Yogis,
Assad dues, they're into chillums,
they smoke chillums of Hash.
So they knew they were into hash,
but they think that their aversion to
eating cows may have had something to do
with the fact that these cows would shit.
And then the mushrooms
that grow up in house shit.
And then they would eat these mushrooms
and have these profound experiences.
And so that these, the thought of
these cows as conduits to God, right.
But then there's, you know, also the
probably drank the mill, you know,
they probably use them to plow the
fields to grow their food. So it's,
it's real.
It's interesting because when a,
when a culture has an aversion to
eating as a very specific animal,
and that specific animal also is the
main source of psychedelic mushrooms,
to ignore that connection
seems a little bit weird. No,
I don't think it's arbitrary.
I think it's something that would be
worth investigating, right? I mean,
why not?
And it worst case scenario come down to,
you have to figure out something else,
but we'll just look at Shiva like, right.
You see that picture of Shiva?
Shiva has arms,
six arms and Shiva
standing on like a little,
it looks like a baby and I always am like,
I have a giant bronze Shiva in my house.
And when I bought it, the lady said,
uh, this a shiva is standing on ignorance.
This is what it's supposed to be.
I go, I thought ignorance
would be way bigger than that.
I felt like that ignorance would be like
a dragon. That Shiva was like fighting.
It was much larger than him. But when
you, that, that thing that she was doing,
that's what happens when you
trip your balls off. Okay.
If you trip balls and you were
started moving your arms around,
I would think Josh Barnett,
it's got six on that. I mean,
there's so much of ancient
Hindu artwork that is, uh,
I thought they were just fan and a bad
fart could be, that could be that Jesus,
that's what we'll all get to fire
around it. Maybe that's what it is.
They're lighting matches, but the
like ancient Hindu art, there's,
there's this a iconography,
there's like these iconic imagery,
this iconic imagery that you
see when you do psychedelics.
You see a lot of this stuff,
particularly on mushrooms for some
reason you'll see like ancient Hindu and
sometimes ancient Egyptian shit too.
Well, I know, you know, you can see,
you'll see a geometric shapes appear out
of and you know, to me I'm just like,
well that's just what you see when
you're poisoned. But it's a great,
it's an interesting way of looking at it,
but it's not poison.
That's the thing about it. It's, it's a,
the way it's affecting the way your
visual processing it perturbance of your
visual cortex. Yeah. But it's not
poison. That's the crazy thing.
It's like the LD 50 of mushrooms.
It's almost impossible
to eat yourself to death.
Like you'd have to eat your
own body weight. Like you,
you would get way too stuff.
Put them inside those fucking croissants.
Chocolate croissants.
Now you talking and might be the move.
So that's a term that has
continued to go throughout.
Uh,
it's like a sleeping pill now that,
and then it was also a major element
within all this Huxley's brave new world,
which, uh, I am that was
based on that probably.
So I'm firmly of the belief that what
we're living in is not a Orwellian,
uh, potential, just stop, just
opek future. We're living in a,
in a Huxley version because Huxley and
Orwell was sought from two different ways
and in Orwell was more of the,
there would be force and violence and,
and direct suppression of
individuals and groups and uh,
retrain. Now there is thought
policing and, and you know,
even though they call them equity,
diversity, whatever departments,
I mean, there are people that are there
to, you know, they have these cabals that,
that try to force everybody to
be in line, but it's, you know,
they're not necessarily gassing folks are
beating on him or what have your shock
therapy.
However Huxley's version of how this would
all go badly was that everybody would
be so comfortable that there would be
so much luxury and pleasure and that you
would just not fight back.
Yeah.
Anything that they would try
to impart upon you though,
the way they would get you to do it is
just make your life even softer and even
easier.
Yeah.
Huxley was right in that regard.
And also all there's so little danger in
the world and so little real drama that
we look for drama. Of course, we
look for it all over the place.
We've made the world's going
on most of the world. Very,
very safe, especially for,
at least for us in west,
in the first world nations.
There's a something that
Dave Rubin tweeted today, see
if you could find this. Um,
it's real reason that the nearby stars,
I don't think so.
Now the mayor of Durham,
uh, apparently, uh,
said something about Jordan Peterson
that Jordan Peterson is not welcome in
Durham,
North Carolina because of his
transphobic and racist views.
What, yeah, what is it?
Let's see. I can't read.
That man can make that a little larger.
What a fucking misrepresented person,
Jordan Peterson has become just, well,
it's gotta be late. Very strange.
We believe that Durham is a place for all
of us. Black, white, Asian, Latin ex. Oh,
I like how you went Latin x instead
of Latino because if he say to next,
it's like Latina, Latino, you get all
the Latinos. I'm not taking any chances.
Indigenous and mixed race, Trans
and CIS. This is in the real word.
You're getting crazy. Mayor, gay and
lesbian. Queer and straight scissor thing.
Queered Lens cover all of it anymore.
It's not here.
Uh, I'm always confused by
that. It got down very open.
Vague term.
I mean it may be there is a an there.
Maybe there's some sort of
accepted standard for what?
What defines queer versus
studying asexual.
Is that all right?
How come you didn't put that
in the asexual people? You
should march. Oh yeah, now,
now, now, now they're
fucked. A tap. Asexual,
a activist lobbies coming from those who
seek to exclude or deny the humanity of
others will find no confidence.
Interesting.
That's always an interesting
statement that people like to make.
Deny the humanity.
Like who said that you who's denying
your humanity even even assholes, right?
I mean even some of this is just a prick.
It's like they can't,
you just heard it and responded to it.
You're living the life that you want to
live. How can they deny your humanity?
What?
Look at this,
we wish to emphasize that a person's
right to free speech does not include the
right to a platform or an audience.
Well here's the thing,
you can't deny that people are
listening to him and enjoy his work.
But if you're gonna make
these broad statements,
you have to have some sort of evidence
to back up what you're saying.
I know Jordan Peterson and
he's definitely not a racist.
He's definitely not transphobic or
homophobic or any of those things.
He was against compelled
speech compelled speech,
state compelled speech,
meaning that there was a
bunch of different words
that they were forcing people
to use that were these new gender
pronouns and they were compelling.
And they have human rights councils
in Canada and he is, and he's a,
I mean he's a clinical psychologist and
he's very well read and he understands
like Marxism and all the pitfalls
modernism in neo Marxism and its,
its evolution from classical Marxism
and how it's been influenced,
the difference between emphasizing the
super structure over the base virtue
signaling in its worst form. I am a,
a very, very familiar with jps work.
He actually sent me a copy of his book
through Twitter. Oh that's amazing.
Which was fantastic.
But the way I came across Jordan Peterson
was that as a big fan of nature and
his philosophical writings,
so I'd go on Youtube to see if I can
find lectures on Nicha and in his maps of
meaning lectures. And this is
before any of the like, uh,
the issues with able to see 16 really,
I didn't know about any of that.
I was just listening to Jordan Peterson
lectures because of him referencing and
talking about nature. So, and then from
Nietzsche Dostoyevsky and all this.
And he then start talking a lot about
Marxism and communism and postmodernism in
reference to each other in other ways.
And then then the [inaudible] stuff.
And then I was living with a Marxists
for awhile, so I started, we really, yes.
Oh Jesus. Yeah, it was not fun. So,
but at the same time I had to try to
understand what the arguments that were
being made and why. And so you got to
go research them. So if someone says,
oh, the wage gap, blah, blah, blah,
blah, blah. And I'm like, okay,
well I guess I need to look up
the research on what that is.
Then you come back and you go,
oh,
well that's actually not an apples for
apples comparison and it's not 70% on the
dollar.
And then you just go into it and then
they'd just look at you and they go, no,
it's like I read, what's your source?
Well, this thing, I read that source,
it doesn't talk about education level
job for job hours work like it does.
It doesn't. I mean, no one's saying
that, that things couldn't be better.
It's just different. Heard this argument
before. When you hear about the wage gap,
the gender wage gap, it's not this,
it's not people doing the same job.
That's what's this is this
is the best way to set up.
It's not people doing the same job and
it's not people working the same hours.
The reason why men make more money
as they do different jobs now,
are those jobs more difficult for women
to get is a real question. Some of them,
I imagine they are perhaps.
I mean,
I never doubt that there is a potential
sexism or any sort of ism to some degree
in some or sexism coming from
both sides of the tracks. Sure.
The way they're sending.
How many women want to be working on a
fucking oil rig out in the middle of or
doing pipelines up in frozen South Dakota,
North Dakota or something.
I mean they not.
And how many of them are physically
capable of doing the work to which isn't a
woman's fault at all and you can't,
I wouldn't hold it against anybody or,
and if they didn't,
if they chose did,
did not want to choose to
do that kind of employment.
There's nothing wrong with
that either. No. You know,
if a woman wanted to go off
and make artisans soap, right?
That mother fucker could make the best
soap with essential oils that are the
best for like, you know, like
how you use defense soap stuff.
Like if that was a woman that
came and created all of that,
like that's a valuable,
respectable,
fantastic thing that they just require
physical strength anyway. Don't,
don't diminish the a compliments to
someone else just because it doesn't fit
what you think is, well the
problem is when we get into teams,
man mean toxic tribalism
is the real problem.
The real problem is people get into teams,
whether it's male versus female
and this mayor of Durham Guarantee,
well it's weaponized.
A lot of this stuff is weaponized.
So most of the stuff about the patriarchy,
which I'm also in grants with Jordan
Peterson, you know that it doesn't exist.
That's not the way the human history has,
has rolled out.
I don't buy that at all. Not to men or
the wage gap. These are weaponized things.
They use them in a weaponized
way to try and destroy your,
your argument or your
position or your way of being.
It's a weaponized diminish
your point of view by saying,
tell me what's your white privilege
talking something like that.
A lot of white privilege today. I am
so white, a big white guy too. Very,
very white with a red beard from
the Pacific northwest. How much,
how much more white can you get?
If I get any wider,
I'm going to be wearing a
fucking Birkenstocks with
socks on ponytail and a and
wow man buttons, a Bolo
ponytail. But uh, it's, it's uh,
these are, these terms are used in,
in, in conflict. Well, and when,
why wouldn't they be?
Because most of the,
the source material that the creation
of these sorts of ideological viewpoints
are from postmodernist,
neo,
Marxism and it's all based on
the concept of conflict theory.
So there's always going to be an
oppressor and oppressed. So if you,
what you are doing is, uh, is trying to
argue with or even just make your case
to someone who's an oppressor. Well,
it would be weaponized because
as far as you're concerned,
everything they do is weaponized against
you. Right? So you've already chosen, uh,
a confrontational position.
There's also a problem with people wanting
to be right. That's human nature. Well,
I also like whether it's someone who's
a postmodernist or someone who was a
staunch conservative,
people go into any discussion with a pre
suppose or they have a preordained or
are pre,
they have a collected group of ideas
that they have attached themselves to and
they do not want to let those go.
And you have yours and I have mine.
It's very difficult for people to just
talk and very difficult for people to
just,
someone to lay out their,
their position and someone else to lay
out their position and to people to like
cordially discuss the merits of each
position with an open mind. It's,
it happens so rarely and it's
something I try so hard to do.
And it's something that I,
it took me years to
cultivate the mindset to not,
not have these preexisting conditions or
preexisting ideas or if I do have them,
don't attach myself to them and be what
ready to abandon them at any moment.
Like under the under new evidence.
Sure. And it's, there's no
problem in saying, okay,
well I believe a new believe B and
we both believe them to be correct.
Well, tell me why I am, why Aa
is incorrect or bearing yet.
Tell me why you believe what you believe.
Right. You know, give me some reasons.
What are the facts and let's find
if those facts are real. It's right.
And I used to, uh, you know, I'd
have these conversations with,
with this person used to then I was
living with, I would say, they're like,
well, you just always have to
be right. I go, no, no, no,
no. I don't have to be right.
But if you're going to make a claim,
you're going to have to defend
your argument and I'll defend mine.
But ultimately I don't care if I'm wrong.
Cause being wrong only means that I can
then perhaps work towards a way of being
the, having the most
understanding that I can have.
We as human beings are wrong so
much more than we're ever right,
but by being wrong,
but by making mistakes,
it's like a through martial arts by
being on the mats and you know, I,
I'm going to get this guy's
ankle right now. Oh fuck that
up. I fucked that up. Oh,
I got caught up. Fuck that up. You can't
get to the point to where you're like, oh,
this is how you set it up.
This is the way that you can,
I wasn't securing the knee well enough
so it was always sliding out of position
and I couldn't,
you know,
keep the leg framed in such a
position where when I applied my hold,
the pressure went through the
joint that I needed it to. Nothing.
None of that happens until you
make mistake after mistake,
after mistake after mistake.
And there's nothing wrong with,
with before making them, uh, uh,
moving forward on something to sit back
and to study a little bit and to try and
understand somewhat of the landscape.
But eventually the only thing you can
do is you just gotta go right now that
paralysis through isn't
gonna help you either.
Well, I lived a good portion of my
life wanting to be right. Always. Sure.
And it's a toxic mindset.
It's terrible for you.
It's terrible for you
because you don't grow.
And then you have to live in denial.
And then you have to always tell yourself
that you were right and they were
wrong. Even if you get, you know,
out debated or even if you're
faced with new evidence, you,
you try to ignore that new evidence. I
know the mindset. I lived in it for many,
many to be, it's an easy place to normal
and you know, not too hard to go on.
It's hard to relax yourself and
just realize that you are not facts.
You are not your ideas, your, uh,
not your opinions, your, your you,
and if you attach yourself
to these opinions, these
ideas, like you're going to,
it's a fucking trap. Like you have to
know what, like here's, here's something.
I know for a fact,
this wood is hard.
If I've hit this would meet with
my knuckles. That shit's hard.
If it dropped on you, it would hurt.
These are undeniable facts and you,
there's a gang of those that you have in
the world. There's a gang of undeniable,
if that's what I cut down. There's
things like objectivity. Yeah.
Whether or not Marxism can be successfully
implemented in the large scale with a,
a sensitive, compassionate group of
human beings that all live together.
Who can it? I don't know. I don't,
it doesn't seem to be, yeah.
Well I don't know though. See what I'm
saying? Like this is a, this is a comp.
It hasn't been done before. Socialism
never really worked. But can it work?
Did the argument that it can't work.
It seems to me that doesn't
make any sense either.
Like maybe you could work well, the
argument that it could work is that, but,
but see what I'm saying?
Like these are,
these are like really need
to think about Rod. Yeah.
Complex nuanced concepts that need to
be discussed up and down and back and
forth. And you also need to look
at the weight of human history,
the myriad times it's failed,
right? And just human history.
And even in ways that,
which is not directly
related to say Marxism,
but just to look at
patterns and trends and,
and ways of people of
operating and to see how, okay,
we'll give it a different circumstance.
How would that process work within this
one or this one or this one or this one.
And then even if you wanted to say, well
if you, if you're like, well I don't,
I don't think Marxism work,
well you can't say that until you actually
study what Marxism is and what its
principles are. Because if you
don't understand the argument,
and this is like you know John,
John Stuart Mill,
you can't just defend your side
without knowledge of the other. Yes,
you have really no position. Your
position isn't any better than theirs.
Yeah,
that's a really good point.
I mean I think everybody should do
that no matter what you are looking at,
like whatever you're trying to defend,
look at even even if it's something
horrible and it's like a racist position,
find out why these people support it
so they believe it. Right and so what,
why do they believe this racist position?
What is it about them that they think
gives it validity and you can look at it
and go, I could see where they could take
this way too. It's extreme in that that,
I mean that's nonsensical but you see
where it started or you can see like that.
That's everything about this is clearly
driven by something else and not the not
what they claim so
well it's also the,
one of the things about societies that
we really have to take into consideration
as the momentum of the past.
Like there's this country has unique
freedom to it because it was literally
created by people who decided to get
on a boat and risk traveling across the
ocean to some new lands.
Yes,
it's a country filled with savages like
crazy people that took wild chances and
did wild things because of it.
And if you look at the history of this
country that's clearly established by
look at the art,
look at the music,
look at the things that
have come out at the comedy,
all of his things that had been created,
the cars,
all the different things that
have come out of this one place.
And this one place just happens to be
the most recent place with the least
amount of historical baggage.
Yes.
But then you look at the places that have
the most amount of historical baggage
like Africa or you know,
some parts of Russia and like these are
places where they have the hardest time
breaking out of the weight of the cultural
momentum of the past. You know, it's,
it's very difficult for people to,
to radically change an established system
that has existed for a thousand years.
Well, that's true. And if you were
to say, think about, you know,
communism and the Soviet states in the,
the length of what constitutes human
history is, has only been gone for,
it was only,
it was around for a short time and then
it's only been gone for an even shorter
time.
And it's not really like coming on Robin,
it's gone,
but it's still a dictatorship over
there. Uh, yeah, I guess their China,
Russia to share about that lady and
I ran, that's, she's going to jail.
The dancing and dancing. Yeah.
Oh No, the Egyptian girl,
the girl,
the Lebanese girls going to jail for she,
she made a youtube video about
getting sexually harassed in Egypt.
So they sentenced her to eight
years in prison. She's 22 years old.
Holy Fuck it terrifying.
She's a young 2124 or something like that.
She's young and they sentenced her to
eight fucking years. Pacha people here
in America or Western, the Western
civilization at large, just fucking,
they just put on the blinders about
stuff like that. It's like their places,
and I'm not going to demonize these
places either, but at the same time,
you as a 22 year old could have a
complaint and say, Hey, I am like,
you know this thing happened and I'm,
this is fucked up and all of
a sudden they can go, Huh,
you think that was fucked up,
boom and throw your ass in jail or
have you executed or whatever. I mean,
it's like, okay, well I guess I don't
have the right to express myself. Whereas,
you know,
people will show up and bang on doors and
do all kinds of crazy shit when Jordan
Peterson comes and does a talk and
the thing is they're allowed to,
they're allowed to protest
what he has to say,
counter protest if they want or to
express their unhappiness with things
political and things,
media,
why anybody can say what they want in
terms of what makes someone happy without
fear of the government silencing you.
Right.
That's a major thing.
It's a major thing. And this poor
girl, Iran, she's just dancing.
I know people that are always rail
against Islam or Islamophobia.
There's so much Islamophobia in this
world. Yeah, sure there is. You're,
you're right. There is, but
you know what else there is,
there's also radical Islam and radical
Islamic governments that are putting
women in jail because they
fucking dance religious.
And that's actually right now it's
just resist religious zealotry
training. And while I have, you
know, people will often, you know,
we'll get into a conversation
about this and they'll bring up,
well what about the Crusades? Or
what about this? Like A, hold on.
These are all relevant things to,
and while the Crusades are not nearly
as cut and dry as you think they are,
in fact,
which two?
It ended in like the fourth crusade
to two groups went down there, uh,
and then end up fighting each other. It's
like a, you're both Christians. Yeah.
What the fuck are you thinking?
But then you had things like
the inquisition you have,
you've had all kinds of stuff and it's
like, yeah, no, you, you, you just,
that doesn't erase this. And that doesn't,
they don't balance each other out.
And it's because it's one religion and
not the other. It doesn't make, it's the,
the, the motivations are
the same. It kind of comes,
it comes from the same concept. Even if
it's not technically the same religion.
Well, it reinforces it
in my opinion. I mean,
the idea that it's not the idea that
Christianity is so amazing and Islam is so
bad, it's that ideologies forced people
into very terrible behave. They can,
they can very, very much. And
they often do. Yeah. I mean,
most of the time it goes bad
when you have a powerful,
potent ideology that is dominating
well imagine. Okay, you had, um,
Christian zealotry and let's say Islam
and Christianity had swapped and Islam
had all kinds of reformations
and different sex break
off from it and all this,
and it'd become more like
Christianity is in this modern era,
but Christianity's stayed in a more
less developed sense and had a more
rigorous, uh, fervent zealotry in terms
of adherence to doctrines or at least,
or even, uh, uh,
interpretations of doctrines
in certain ways to MIT style.
But within this context of the modern era.
So now you have the Internet.
So any you would say,
you know,
you only got like a million people
in the world that feel this way,
but these million can all connect with
each other via social media of your
different electronic
ways. They can create, um,
weapon where they can weaponize
things much easier. They
can coordinate, they can.
It's not like the Crusades where you
had to get money from a king and other
government, other monarchs get
together. All these troops get together,
all these supplies,
marched them all down into the Middle
East to where you've got the Turks waiting
for you,
that they've done the same thing.
And then you guys all meet up on
these different points of battle. The,
you could literally be at war
all over the world, all day,
every day, all at the same time because
of the modern advances of technology.
And not to mention you have firearms,
you have a explosive and chemicals and
things that you can use to your disposal.
Drones, it just a or a truck. Yeah,
right. You didn't have, you know,
six ton trucks and drive
in to drive into a crowd.
Um, that's just technology.
It's, it, it helps,
it makes our lives better.
But in, in other ways,
it can also create calamity for us.
And it's really their tools. You know,
social media is a tool.
I think the social media is,
if you were to track mass,
the mass shootings that have happened,
the rise of social media and the
rise of mass shootings would,
would be on a parallel.
I really think that it's social media
that's increasing the amount that you see
at the school shooting
and things like that.
I think that's because
they get fame from it.
They get fame or you're able to antagonize
someone and they can't get away from
you much more easily. Uh, the,
the resulting mom using a Nietzschean
term in terms of, uh, you know,
the resentment,
the resentfulness from seeing other people
having what you think you deserve or,
or doing,
thinking that they somehow are having
more of what you think you want that as
well. Why do they get
to have it? And I don't,
or any number of reasons why you can be
incredibly potently resentful and now
you have this thing that's just in your
life pumping all this kind of stuff that
you all the time.
And I think that it can affect people
in some really pathologically bad ways.
And now you have technology to also
enact it. And if it's not in the eye,
and you can also easily make the
argument if it's not a firearm,
it could be something else. And, and
that's doesn't make it any better.
But I think that the, the rise
of social media has been, is,
is a direct, uh, correlator.
It's directly responsible for the rising
and the school shootings and directly
responsible or directly correlates to it.
I think that there's a correlation there.
I think it's certainly,
there's a lot going on in society.
I think the big factor, well,
there's a lot of factors.
People are alienated. Yes,
there's terrible child rearing.
People have mental health issues,
people are medicated. Does the big
one is now imagine all that with the,
the technology of social media able to
heighten some of the effects of some of
these things or to create,
so someone that feels alienated.
Imagine now not only do you feel
alienated in the real world,
but then when you're on social media,
you, one, it's not a real, you know,
it's your body knows
it's not the real world,
but you could be alienated out there too.
And that which alienates you there could
still penetrate and get to you while
you're out.
What you're away from it.
If people are fucking with you at school
or what have you and then you're at
home,
you're feeling alienated there.
This is continuing to fuck with you
through social media or other people are
fucking with you on social
media would say you're,
you're playing your video games and
people are talking shit cause you keep
getting shot and you know a battlefield
five or whatever and then all these
things are just compounding compounding.
And while no one knows, I mean there's,
I'm sure you wouldn't necessarily
know that if I say, oh you know,
fuck you knew or something on some video
game that this person is essentially in
real life being told fuck you every day,
all day feeling like the
whole world thinks fuck you.
How would you know that?
But it could be then that person
snaps or that person has a,
there they have a psychological
issue that they're not,
I'm sure there's a bunch of factors.
There's a bunch of facts. First of all,
does the ability to kill large groups of
people, which is unprecedented, right?
The ability to use assault rifles and
just fucking semiautomatic guns and going
in to kill large groups of people. The,
the knowledge that if you do do that,
it'll make a huge splash and
giant headlines and you'll
be, you'll be infamous.
The, the fact that a lot of these
people are on disassociative.
So a lot of these people are on like
serious psych medications that we really
have only been studying the effects
on human beings for the past couple of
decades.
There's,
there's not a whole lot of data on
longterm use of these SSRI is correct.
2030 40 years. Right. So
you've got varying people's,
a varying mental illnesses,
varying psychological pressures and
stresses and lives that are just beyond
fucked.
And then they have access to guns and
they want people to hurt the way they're
hurting. There's a lot of that,
there's a lot of factors going on.
Well and you know, even if they
illegally require the guns, I mean they,
they still, I mean it doesn't matter, but
in this case with the tool is per se. But
well, you know, I don't think
we're meant to, to understand,
I don't think we understand,
nor are we meant to live in large
groups of people where we don't know the
people around us.
That's another thing.
I think that is a really new
situation for human beings.
And they overlook the historic
go significance of the population growth,
the, the population density that has,
uh, been, uh, gathering as these
wheat dense, we get into these,
these, uh, high density,
civilized, civilized areas
like cities, these big cities.
And it changes everything.
Yeah. And people are less
likely to know that many.
Like if you live in a town of 150 people,
you probably know 150 people.
If you live in a city of 5 million people,
you probably know 10 people you know,
you know, people you work with, you
might know a couple of friends, you know,
unless you're like a really social person.
Sure.
You probably have a way more limited
number of people that you actually know.
Then people that have a tight knit,
small town and small community.
But you know those people are obviously
in your business. That's one thing.
If you haven't fucking, I know
friends that live in small
towns. Fuck man. There's,
there's things that come with that too.
A lot of busy bodies.
People peeking over the fence.
I think they had the anal sex last night.
Jesus is going to punish them.
Glad when he says next line
in store and come through.
You don't fuck no one live,
but fucking
speaking of blood fucking let's talk
about you saw yeah. Without the loop.
Yeah. We were, um, we,
we started this podcast talking
about what we talked about your,
your situation with Brendan Chub and I
had talked about your situation where you
a war, you tested positive
from a tainted supplement,
like legitimately tested positive
from a tainted supplement. It,
you were cleared, but this whole
process was a goat rope. Yeah,
right. It took a long time to work out
and you didn't feel like you were fairly
treated.
Not In the least. It, it, uh, it started
one way, then took a fucking curve.
What happened? Well,
so what did you take a,
I took a supplement that had
tribulus in it. That's all.
It was just a Chinese herb.
It's a Chinese herb that stimulates
testosterone and by the way,
barely works. Yeah. It's not, it's not a,
it's not going to turn you into
superman or anything like that.
You get more sleep. It's better for your
testosterone production than Tribulus.
So it's just tribulus is all it was.
And uh,
they in it, the, the supplement
itself, as it turns out,
was contaminated with a
sore arm called Asta Room.
But when I say contaminated,
I mean like,
it had such trace amounts that the people
that did the lab testing on it said,
well, it's clearly just contamination
because this wouldn't help you.
This wouldn't do anything for you.
Let's explain how that happens.
A lot of these places.
I know this for a fact because I am one
of the owners of on it on it is a third
party tested company where we get our
stuff tested by an independent party to
make sure that there's
nothing funky with it.
But we've had some issues in the
past with stuff being in our,
with our earliest formulations of Alpha
brain and weren't supposed to be in
there. And what it comes from is you
buy your ingredients from a company,
the company has these vats that they mix
everything in and they don't properly
clean the vats and if they
don't properly clean the that,
so you're buying some stuff from China
who knows what they're chucking in there.
They got steroids in there,
they got this, they got that.
A lot of creatine is tainted,
were all sorts of shit.
A lot of different supplements or taint.
And that's what you saw it.
I thought it could have been at first.
[inaudible] means yes, it happened to uh,
Ell Ramiro.
Yes. So this stuff is, is,
is contaminated. Right.
And so you signed up
was, was testing me. I,
I had had a fight in September of 2016
against our Lawsky and then after that I
was like, Yo, I'm just going to take a
break for a while. I'm not fighting for,
I'm going to tour Europe and goof off and
whatever. And then when I get back, uh,
you know,
I don't really,
I don't know what I'm going to get back
in the ring and they're like, all right,
whatever. And we UFC, we told
them and I, but you saw it,
it would still come around and
test and say, okay, fine, whatever.
So this is post testing
positive. This is pre. Pre. Okay.
And so you fought Arlovski and you said,
I'm just going to chill a while. Yeah. And
then one day, um, well like for one,
when I'm out there in Europe
and I let them know like, Hey,
I'm going fucking where the wind
takes me in Europe and I don't have a
whereabouts to fill in because I could
be on a train moving here, moving there,
whatever, which is your prerogative,
right as a human being. And they,
they know that and yet then they go ahead
and sent someone to my fucking house
to try and test me while I'm in
Europe and I'm just going, Whoa, okay.
Isn't there like an APP we've filled out
as an APP? But if I'm at work, you have,
you can fill out what you're supposed
to be ahead of time for the most part.
So on Tuesday the 16th I'm going to be
at this place from this time to this time
and then, and then, but
what is your home base?
So if we don't go to these places and
we'll just meet you at your home at some
time or whatever. He just decided to go
to Japan. Yeah. Do you have to tell them,
hey,
today I'm going to take a train to Osaka.
Today I'm going to go to the mountains.
So you have to give them a detailed
itinerary every day. Every day. Okay.
And so I'm like, fuck dude. I'm
just trying to be out here living,
just doing whatever. I'm not fighting,
but you know, when I get home,
you test me wherever you want. Do you
just want, wanted to enjoy a vacation,
just travel. Correct. And uh, they go,
they send someone in my house. I was like,
fuck. All right. And then
there are times where,
so what happens when they send someone
to your house but you told them you
weren't there? Uh, well for one,
no one told the, I don't know how,
what mechanical elements within
their organization, how that works.
But they sent someone there anyways.
I'm not there.
That head count.
Does it count cause you,
did you tell them that you were
going to be on the road? I, we did.
So they still counted that as you
not being there for a test? Yes.
Well that doesn't make any fucking
sense. Well it is what it is. So,
but wait a minute, if they're going to
give you a strike, like don't, don't,
they have to follow their
protocol and their protocols.
You have to inform them or where are you
going to be? Right. Because you did that,
you inform them more.
You're going to be
my manager literally told
Novitsky and the UFC,
he's not going to be home for almost
a month and he's fucking practically
backpacking all through Europe
going from place to place to place.
So he's going to be real hard to get
ahold of. Good time to take steroids.
The Oh yeah. Get just,
just fucking give it back
to the gills. Yeah. You'll pass.
If they showed up in Europe,
you did give them your location and you
told them where you are if they would,
but I was gone. I didn't feel in any
locations. I just went wherever I went.
So when you went,
wherever you went and your manager told
you solder that you were in Europe,
they still showed up at your house in La.
Okay.
Well that doesn't seem to make any sense.
And then they give you a strike. Yes.
Hmm. So I'm like, okay, that's aggravating
cowboy a strike when he was at UFC.
Yeah. Yeah. So it's stuff like that. And
I saw that and I'm like, you know what,
I just, I can't fuck around
with any of this stuff.
I don't want people to use this as some
sort of a kindling to try and start a
fire about me. And so then I get back
home and they're, you know, test me again,
like, all right, fine, whatever. And then
they test me again and I'm like, okay,
now you may just made me late to an
audition as you just showed up out of
nowhere. Cool. You can do that.
Like they can just show up.
You can't say, Hey, I have an
appointment to keep their there.
But even if you are not fighting,
like say if you're running out the door
and you have a business appointment,
how long does it take for them to test
you? A, it depends on what they're doing,
whether it's blood and
urine or just urine.
But with me it's always been blood
in urine. So you can't say, hey,
you guys are going to have
to come with me because, uh,
I got to go to this fucking audition.
You know, I dunno, I didn't try that.
I would say that get in the car,
bitch, boom, boom, boom. Well,
how are you going to sit there and have
someone draw blood and not going to you?
You guys are going to have
to deal when I'm done,
like if you want to keep an eye on me,
come with me the whole way.
I always took it as they showed
up. It's like, well here it goes.
That doesn't seem to make any sense.
If you have previous commitments
and you have to do something,
they shouldn't have like ultimate
precedent over your life.
Like they shouldn't be able to just decide
like showing up random that I sent it
as they could. They could make
an argument in some way on that.
But if you have a life, well, in any case,
so okay, I take this test and I'm like,
all right,
I'm just going to retire for now.
I got too much shit I got to do.
I'm not fighting anytime soon.
I've got my new Japan stuff, I've got
auditions, I've got all these things.
I'm traveling and I just, I'm not going
to fight. Right. So just leave me be,
and then I'm in Japan and the fucking,
the very last test I took
right before retiring.
Oh, you're flagged. I'm like,
you gotta be fucking kidding me.
Really, really all these
tests over all these years,
me being the first person to do complete
out of competition or in competition,
random urine and blood testing.
When I worked with a Wada and the Nevada
state athletic commission when I fought
Travis Browne. So no one had ever
done actual random testing before.
And there was no, you saw to involve
in the UFC yet going through,
why did you do that?
It was something that the NSAC
wanted to see done and I'm like,
fine.
Know what?
I wanted to see that done because
you had tested positive in the past.
And so I was like,
you tested positive before in the
past you've taken some stuff. Right.
I tested positive for
antibiotics in the past. Why?
But I mean the supplement market used to
be way wilder than it used to be. Well,
and also we'll end the way.
The just fighting was way
wild riding was way wilder.
The supplement industry was way wilder.
It's like back in Oh two you could still
buy all this shit over the counter.
That bio for got
reclassified the steroids.
I remember I was taking this shit called
Mag 10 do you have that higher number
mag? Ooh, what was the name of the
company that makes that a death?
Incorporate ethic cooperated.
She I should
is all steroids. Shit was
steroids. It was steroids. 100%.
I remember meg 10 he came like 10
pounds in six weeks on that shit.
You just get Jack. But that
was all over the counter. Yeah.
You used to be able to buy a lot of stuff.
And by the way,
liver toxicity is probably off the charts.
Probably was a lot of those things
that are like super bad for you. Yeah.
But real effective, they fucking it
work. This stuff worked. But uh, so,
you know, there was a whole different
era. And then with California,
you know, I, I had an issue
with, with a contaminant,
what I believe ultimately
to be a contamination,
but I didn't take all the
steps that I had this time.
And once that whole process
was such a mother fuck,
like this is never going to happen again.
So every supplement lot that I took,
I would always keep bits of it
behind for until I knew I could get,
I felt there was enough time it expired
and get rid of it because no one's going
to come back and test me.
I passed all my tests so,
so once you pass your test you
would get rid of the old site.
I don't need to keep those lots in.
You're supposed to take the
only third party verified.
That's not what they say necessarily.
They suggest it I guess now.
But I know that uh,
with this brand of Tribulus I had taken,
I had taken three or four different other
supplements from the same company and
all pass no problem on their tests.
So it was just some weird
contamination which does happen again.
It happened at Tim means,
yes,
it's happened to several
fight as far as I can tell.
I mean I'm not testing
their whole product line,
but it just seemed like a fluke
and just such a simple supplement.
In any case over one ingredient deal. So
then they come back and they're like, oh,
you tested positive for this. And I'm
like, well, that ain't fucking possible.
So then I send in some supplements, which
I had to pay for to have them tested.
They run them through the testing and
then bang, they find it all right.
There you go. There's your deal. Then they
went out and bought a brand new bottle,
unopened. Same Lot tested
that one. Verify the results.
Same thing. Test, same thing. Doesn't
happen then Tim means as well.
So then you were in contact with
Usada throughout the entirety of this.
So we don't ever break contact with
Usada. Uh, we have a specific guy,
and I'm not gonna throw his
name out there or anything,
but we have a guy that we spoke
to directly the whole time, uh,
through my manager, uh, speaking
with him and I've seen the emails.
And so we're talking about how we know
this is a contamination. And when,
you know,
when we get done with all this,
why don't we even try to put
together something, some,
some promotional stuff,
anything that we can do to try and keep
athletes from ending up in the same
issues. And we, we'd like to do whatever
we could to help you guys out with this.
You know, we're not against you. We're a,
we don't mind being a part of the system
and we understand why you're here.
And I'm not against them wanting to do
drug testing or whatever and try to keep
a, a, a clean and fair playing
field. I get the point of it.
Uh, so we get the, the supplements tested,
they test the secondary batch, they
have all their information. It's like,
all right,
this would be
a fucking rock and roll.
And then they got real quiet.
Okay. Uh, now you're not talking
to us anymore. What do you mean?
Like you would contact him? They wouldn't
respond. They would take him a week,
two weeks. And what were they saying
when they do respond? Eh, you know, I,
I can't entirely remember myself.
It was my manager was in touch with them.
And what is the protocol?
If someone tests positive for something
that's a tainted supplement and it's a
third party supplement and where it's
not or it was not third party verified
rather well,
I don't even know if it was third party
verified that anything would be any
different. Hmm, okay.
Well if it is third party verified
and still is tainted, yeah,
that would be an issue, right? Yeah. If
you tested positive, he tested positive,
they found a supplement.
I think the idea about
third party verified is it's
much less likely to be a to
solve anything. And this is coming from
someone who's in the supplement business.
You know there's a certain amount
of this stuff you farm out.
So far as I know what the deal is,
there's a period of ineligibility sort of,
or basically what,
what happens is you're effectively
suspended until this thing is all finished
out and they tried to say that you're
not suspended, there's no suspension,
but that's not true.
But no one's going to book you for a
fight when treats you as you're suspended.
I tried to corner Travis Brown because
I was training him and they wouldn't let
me, they wouldn't let you
the corner. Yes. Okay.
And so then they're like, you're
suspended so you can't, you can't corner.
But you said you're not
suspending. Yeah, exactly. Okay.
So you're effectively suspended.
You can't work.
You can't even work as a
tertiary individual, as a,
as a corner man or anything like that.
He can't be at the event.
And this is after the fact where
you brought them to supplements.
They independently verified that
it was tainted. Yes. And uh,
so then we start talking and the,
throughout the process I said, look,
I'm not taking a punishment for
contamination and I'm not even fighting.
I'm not fighting anytime
soon. I'm not you. You can't,
like what you did with means and
these other people, you punish them,
you know that there was contamination,
but you punish them. Yeah.
They gave them many
months of, uh, you know,
suspension so that they're more able to
compete or make a living during those
months. And I'm like, no, I'm
not dealing, I'm not taking that.
That's not acceptable because I'm not,
that's not what's going on here.
Nobody is doping. Nobody's trying
to cheat the system. There is no,
I'm not even fighting.
You don't get by punishing me.
You're trying to live guilt on me.
You're trying to make me out
to be some sort of, uh, uh,
you know,
uh,
guilty party as if I'm trying
to be a cheat of some soreness.
Like I'm not dealing, I'm not taking that.
So how did it ultimately get resolved?
Well, ultimately what ended up happening
is we had to go to arbitration.
That was all,
it was really left to us because then
they started trying to bring up, uh, uh,
stuff from my past and then weigh that
against me as well. And it's like, Whoa,
dude,
you guys weren't even around.
And now you get to decide
to add to the weight of,
of whatever punishment you want
to levy against me based on, uh,
things that didn't involve you. Great.
That's two. What were they talking about?
They're talking about 2001.
No, 2008. They went to 2008.
Yeah. They tried and they tried to
say, well, oh yeah, well this happened.
So then therefore, you know, now
they start talking about two years.
[inaudible] thank you.
And you gotta be fucking kidding me.
They started talking about suspending you
for two years for a tainted supplement.
Yes. Wow. And I'm just going, there's no
way I wouldn't even accept six months.
You think I'm going to take two years.
And so we go and we inquire
on the Arbor and I've done,
I did an interview with the guy that
we were dealing with through Skype. Uh,
we've,
we've been in touch.
It just like at some point
everything turned and changed.
Their tone changed there.
Even the original penalties,
they were looking to levy
increased new shit gets brought in.
It's like they became a completely
different animal. As soon as you know,
there was the evidence of contamination
and that I wasn't gonna I wasn't willing
to take the punishment for it.
It wasn't.
What do you think their motivation
is here? I don't think that they,
and this is just my opinion, I think
the way you saw it, it looks at it and,
and it's an easy way to go about it
is that the more people they ding,
the more effective they appear.
It's their effect.
Their efficacy is based on punished on
punishments, doled out, not necessarily,
not on lack of punishments at all.
So do you think this is, you know,
also remember they get,
they get you to mention by the
people that are working there,
so they arbitrarily get to
decide how things go about right.
There's not like a very strict
protocol that they must follow.
They're tainted supplements are for this?
No,
there is actually quite a
bit of a lever or there,
there is leeway in terms of how they
can enforce and what they can enforce.
So when it's subjective, it's up, there
is subjectivity in it. Um, they, uh,
they have a lot of discretion. There
is some outlined elements of protocol,
but there is no, it is always this
or it is always that. Right. And, uh,
you know,
I didn't begrudge them for a period of
ineligibility while you're going through
the process of finding out whether this
is contamination or what have you doing
any testing. And that makes
sense to me. That's fine.
I understand that if this guy
supposedly has something in a system,
well let's figure out what it is
and once we have a better idea,
then we can decide about whether you can
go back into the pool or do this or do
that or if you're going to leverage
any punishments. Makes sense to me.
But in addition to that, then tacking
on more shit in terms of my case,
I was like, that's not
acceptable. So we, we go,
well I guess the only thing left
to us is to go to arbitration.
And so my manager spoke with,
um,
when I was working through them to
arbitration and we said, okay, well we'll,
what is that going to take?
Well that's going to cost more money
out of my pocket. Um, you know,
the arbitration process is these are guys
that they're paid by Usada to do their
arbitration. Like they worked
for them in a way or they're not,
they don't work under them directly,
but they are,
they do get paid to be a arbitrary to
somehow there's some get contracted by
Usada. Yes. And uh, and
so that was like, ah,
I don't necessarily feel the
most comfortable with that,
but I can also understand how it's not,
there's probably not an easier way
to go about it, but, okay. I got it.
Then when we,
uh,
then we get notice back from Usada
that we have to limit the scope of our
argument. We're like,
Whoa, Whoa, what you,
you're going to tell us what we
can and can't argue in arbitration.
I don't remember what the definitions
were exactly, but it was like, you can't,
you know, you have to keep it within
this boundary and this realm and this.
And I'm like,
well,
you can't fucking try to say the levy
this against me and then you stuff from my
past and then tell me I
can't argue my full case.
So the eliminating the amount that you
could defend yourself as every site,
they were limiting the,
um, the range of argument,
you could make the argument
be that you would bring up,
that they would want to limit?
Uh, that's a good question.
I don't know exactly.
Did they define that?
They know they had definitions
in the emails with,
with back and forth from my manager.
And he goes, well fuck we, you know,
cause we could argue about, um, you
know, this is contamination. Um, and,
and go from there. But if it's
something really potentially limiting,
which was weird about how they pled it,
you just don't remember what exactly,
I don't remember all the details. It's
very detail oriented. It's legal ease.
And uh, and then so we get to
the point, it's like, well fuck,
well this doesn't even look like a very,
you know,
this might not even be a useful way
of trying to approach this thing.
And it got down to the wire to where,
and we kept pushing it back and pushing
it back and, and saying like, you know,
we can we get an extension and to try
and figure out how the hell did we
approach this? And, and also like how,
how could we approach without having
to spend money on having lawyers get
involved.
I mean that's the last thing you want
to do is get to litigation or you know,
even arbitration and it's a legal
process. It's complex and it is, it's,
there's a lot of uh, and lawyers
love billable hours or they do.
And so it gets down to
the wire essentially.
And we,
I just sit back and I go,
I won't accept any ruling
if it's a punishment at all.
I don't care what they say. I'll
just be like, Nah, not I, I don't,
I'm not going to abide by it.
You can't force me to do shit.
And I guess we'll have to cross
position is that if you are accidentally
taking a tainted supplement and also
trace amounts that have absolutely
zero effect on performance,
there's nothing that you're doing by
accidentally taking that that in any way
would help you and that's a
fact. That's a proven fact. Yes.
So your position is you
shouldn't be punished. Correct.
Then you're out of the year once you,
the time that you've been out.
Here's the thing, that's enough. Exactly.
It's one thing you don't need to say,
oh well if you, if it took six, if it
took a seven months to get the, the,
the information that you needed the
data, right to then clarify, okay,
well you're not at fault to then say,
oh well we'll suspend you for six months.
But since that six months is already past,
it's like we didn't suspend
you at all. No. Motherfucker,
when you look in the end
of the hunt at the data,
when you go and look at this case, it says
suspended, which means you punished me,
which means I was guilty in some way.
You said I'm guilty because that's how
you got to punish me, right. It's not,
it's under investigation or you know,
after investigation exonerated
after invest. No, it's just,
no, you still levied a
punishment in there to say that,
look how we caught this guy and we
punished them and I'm like, I'm not,
I'm not gonna, I'm not down
for that. And so oddly enough,
so I was like on aerials or something
like that and I said, I, I won't accept,
I don't care what they say. I don't
care what punishment they tried to levy.
I don't abide by it. I won't agree
to it. And I'm done with them.
And someone from the arbitrary,
the arbitrators office
who we were dealing with,
calls us out of the blue and goes, so
you still sure you don't want to do this?
I'm like, well, and my manager goes, well,
they said that we have to limit the
scope of argument to this and this and we
can't talk. And then he goes, no, you
don't. You can talk about, you can,
you can bring any argument you want.
Who is saying this to you?
The arbitrators office and
this. So who would initially come to
you and said the had elite? The scope,
your argument. You sorta,
okay, so you saw it.
It was attempting to establish
some boundaries for your arguments.
But the people who are the actual
arbitrators said that that's not true.
Right? They, that's not the
case. You don't have, it doesn't,
they can't force you
to argue in a certain,
oh, okay. So is it possible that you
sought as lawyers? We're trying to,
here's the thing I've found
about, about lawyers, like yeah,
for sure they're necessary and that's
all well and good and you need them.
But there's a reality,
and this is something that I had to deal
with recently in doing something with a
friend through lawyers where they
attached a bunch of shit to this deal that
wasn't supposed to be in there and
he didn't even know it was in there.
And then my lawyer is like, what the
fuck is this? And so I contact him,
what the fuck is this? And he's
like, what the fuck is that?
So he contacts his lawyers,
what the fuck is this?
And it turns out this is a common thing.
Lawyers they do with each other.
Yeah.
We put this in to give you leverage.
I don't think you necessarily want that,
but we're looking out
for your best interests.
And so now you have a
good negotiation point.
If you just go in with what you want,
then they're going to
ask for more than that.
And then you're not in a strong position
because you can't ask for more after
you've already established your
initial position. Right. Makes
everything convoluted there grows by,
but that's the world we live in.
Your grandfather was a Tejas world.
Pretty Pretty Fair lawyer.
He was assistant attorney general,
the state of Washington.
He actually wanted me to get into
law of all things, but I'm like, Eh,
I think I'll, or the beat out
my brains yet. Seems like, well,
you haven't beaten them out.
Very impressive with your
memory. So we, uh, we get to,
my manager comes back
to me. He goes, hey man,
they just contacted me out of
nowhere. And they're like, well,
if you want to do this, you can. And No,
you can't, you, you can make the argument.
There's no limiting in the scope of your
argument or anything. So then it's like,
well, yeah, all right, I'll go for
it because he wants our least. Yeah.
Cause at the very least,
I thought maybe I could have some
sort of record down of, of what,
what we talked about, what was discussed,
the arguments made. So in the end,
you know, no matter what, how it came
out, I can go here, here's what's legit,
then you can, you can make your own
decision from there. And so we go in, uh,
I brought my legal team.
They, he, they had a,
their lawyer come who was the same guy
we were dealing with throughout the
entire process and they made
their argument and we made ours.
And you know, and there, there are times
where I'm sitting back and I go, you know,
making, they're making closing
arguments that each lawyers,
and I'm just sitting there listening
to the Usada Seigel oh man,
he's just pushing them. He's just
moving the goalposts. He's, uh, how so?
Well, it's just taking a certain
element and then trying to, you know,
you slippery slope arguments and
moving the goalpost on things.
But he's just doing anything he can to
use rhetoric instead of logos at this
point because you know,
they're lawyers and they're trying
to make their case and trying to find
impassioned responses, you know,
consider the people listening at home.
Don't really know your case,
don't know the scope. Okay.
So it's like trying to
say that, uh, you know,
find ways at which to move
the goalposts in terms of,
so what,
like I said to you earlier,
I keep batches of all the supplements
that I take and especially when I'm in
these, this program, and
especially after dealing with the,
the cluster fuck that was
California and it's like, well,
I didn't have anything that I could
bring to you that I could fuck, you know,
so I'm like, this is never happening
again. So I keep everything.
They go and they test stuff and
they find it and I kept notes.
I kept this and it's like,
what more could I have done for you guys?
Even if it,
it doesn't matter if there's,
let's say what they were all
third party tested as well.
I would still keep batches of the
supplements in any of this stuff.
I take third party test. What was the
issue then? Well, it's just simply,
it's just they kept trying to say that
I didn't do a good enough job that, uh,
did you use the, uh, did you see this uh,
thing on supplement form one?
One?
It's like that came out after the fact
and yes, I have seen that. I'm fact,
I use all the resources that
you provided your global dro,
your other supplement form one, one,
two check against ingredient lists,
supplement names,
company names to make sure none of this
shit is on the list so that I don't make
that mistake.
So I use the resources that you give me.
I keep batches of my supplements
so they can be tested if need be.
I do what's available
to keep from any issues.
And yet they just kept moving the goalpost
on that and trying to say that, well,
but you didn't, uh, you didn't
hire a psychic. You know,
it's just that kind of shit.
And I'm like, well how,
how could this have been any better?
And not to mention I'm not fighting.
Right. So at the end of the day, what
were they looking for in arbitration?
Uh,
they wanted to levy a punishment
against me and suspend me for years.
And this is Usada. Yes.
So you saw to ultimately,
even though they knew that you took a
tainted supplement that had no effect
whatsoever on your performance,
right.
They still wanted to punish you
for two years. That seems stupid.
That just seems stupid. Now, let me,
let me read Jeff Novitsky because Novitsky
texted me because I told him this was
going to go down and his take is
a little bit different than yours.
I don't imagine. It isn't. All right.
I'm, I'm not surprised that it is.
And I, uh, I told you what
it was, um, the, so this is,
I'll just read you what it says.
Uh,
he'd said he'll complain about the
amount of time that went by with Usada
process,
but he notified us of retirement right
after the positive sample was collected
before a positive was announced.
So he was off in the wind for many
months and not communicating with Usada.
A big reason the case took so long to
resolve to his positive was from a tainted
supplement,
but he didn't do the number one thing.
We advised the UFC athletes on
UFC athletes on supplements.
He didn't choose a supplement that
was third party certified, uh,
as a banned substance free.
Like on it, supplements are,
there are literally hundreds of certified
supplements out there and virtually
and virtually ensures no issues to a
foreign athlete if they stick with those.
Uh,
one other point for Barnett,
when he was unresponsive to case he
missed all of his deadlines to file for
arbitration.
Uh,
he came to the table later and said
he wanted to go to arbitration.
You saw automate and
exclusion and let him,
which ultimately led to his
favorable ruling by arbitrator.
Their reasoning was that they wanted
to rule in favor of fairness to athlete
rules. Say they didn't have to after
time, uh, to file expired. Well,
but they're saying you it ruled favorably
towards you ultimately at the end of
the day.
Yes.
They like all those in our favor.
Gobbly goop does that the other
probably shit. He says that, oh,
well he retired and he was in the wind.
You know what my in the wind was?
It wasn't even that long.
I was in Japan for rising with my athlete,
Alyssa Garcia. Mm. It wasn't in the
fucking wind. Sounds good though.
You're in the wind and the wind
fucking you. And that motorcycle
jacket just drives him. Yeah.
I'm dragging from behind me.
Like Django through the Nevada desert.
Somebody pulls you over,
got eight days growth on your face.
You Charge Barnett some days where you
Sada we're, we're looking for your broken.
I, he pissed this cup for me. I've
been breakup. Just, yeah, I was in Japan
at rising, you know, I wasn't in the wind.
And uh, they, so it takes in your favor.
They arbitrator arbitrator. And what
did they say? This is the same guy.
The arbitrator is the same guy that
put together is he's an ICARUS.
He produced ICARUS, the
movie on, on doping. He is,
he's one of the major figures in
terms of the world of anti-doping.
So it's one of the guys who worked
with Bryan Fogel. Uh, the arbitrator,
Bryan Fogel was the guys
who started in Icarus.
This guy is a arbitrator or water,
actually, why am I doing this? Either
way. You look, Jamie, Jamie can handles,
but it doesn't matter. This guy has the
end of the day. Everything in terms of,
of drug testing in your favor.
Yes. And he said he does it.
He couldn't see any way that I could
have done hardly a better job than I was
meticulous with my record keeping that uh,
I may,
I did essentially everything I could
in the means of a normal person to do.
How was it resolved at the end?
It was a, the last of reprimand.
That's it. Reprimand? Yeah.
What does that, what do they do?
Richard h average. And Mclaren. Mclaren.
Yeah. Oh, see, chief arbitrator. Yes.
Okay. So at the end of
the day, after all this,
they say they give you a reprimand.
What does that mean?
That just means like don't do
that. Be careful. Yeah. Okay.
[inaudible] and this took no punishment.
Right?
And to your shit from Usada was on
unwarranted right and heavy handed,
heavy handed as hell. And, and junior
dos Santos went through that too. Right.
Started at at six months.
And then by the time we,
they have both supplements tested,
then all of a sudden it starts
getting weird. And you know,
this claim by new whiskey that we were
out of, no, we were always in touch.
Novitsky doesn't work for you saw it.
And I know this is what's kind kinda
funny is new whiskey is such a public face
on this kind of thing. But when it
comes to actually dealing with Usada,
he's all, he's hands up. I
mean he'll come and he'll,
he'll make sure to put something
out there in any of the sphere.
But in reality he ain't got a
fucking thing to do with any of them.
But in his defense,
he's a UFC employee and it's inappropriate
for him to have any influence
whatsoever on the way they rule things
that, but that's, that is that is that,
I think that's actually the proper
thing for him to do a in a way.
But I mean it's just,
it's a, it's a, it's it,
the presentation is a bit of a misnomer.
I think so.
Well initially he was responsible for
the drug testing. Now he's, what is he,
the president of athletes safety
and wellness talk pop thing.
They're running the performance
institute. Yeah. I mean what they're,
what they're concentrating on now I'm
just saying it for Jeff and his sheriff
that I think they're concentrating more
on encouraging fighters to train and,
and, and fortify their body with nutrition
correctly and giving them education
on how to do this and that Jeff is at
the forefront of that stuff and showing
them how to avoid accidentally taking
something and definitely had a little boy
coming with this is that he is not fully
in the loop with what happened between
me and Usada cause he's not involved.
Right.
So some of some of what he's saying
there is incorrect and it's not,
I don't blame him because
he's not a part of it.
So is he misinformed?
I at the very least that they,
they're not being
straight forward with it.
It sounds to me like they
wanted to punish you badly.
They wanted to punish me badly. Yeah.
Two years is a fucking crazy punishment.
And also when,
when people get you to remember
when I'm Nick Diaz was uh,
was being interviewed by all these people
and then there was that mean lady who
works in Nevada at a commission and
she was grilling him and I'm like,
you were talking about pot here.
You crazy lady.
Like what in the fuck are you doing?
You're acting like you've robbed a bank.
Even not if he's not getting in the
ring. Hi. And leave him alone. Exactly.
And I think he probably did a few
times, I think. I mean, it wasn't there.
I think in the Gombe fighting, he might've
been, hi, I'm bleeding. Oh my God,
maybe I should choke him right now.
He didn't give a shit fight.
Jon Jones is going through this right now.
I don't know where John Jones stands,
but it's been pretty well established
that at the very least what the,
the numbers, if you look at the numbers
when he was tested. Um, and you know,
I don't, I know a lot of people
like to say that he's a cheater.
This is a lot of this going on right now.
Look real clear.
The first test was proven that
he took tainted Dick Pills.
Okay.
Yeah.
Well it was a actually,
so that got brought up to my attention
as part of all this because you know,
you saw it, a felon that relevant.
The difference between that first one,
let's say, and I'm not, I don't know
about the second shift with John.
I don't really follow close on this,
but this came across my
plate because he had,
he was taking like a liquid Cialis and
it was from a company that sells sarms
and peptides and all that shit.
So it was a company that also
sells banned substances. Right.
And so their argument was that dude,
you're buying or using shit from a place
full of illegal shit that you're not
supposed to take.
Definitely a dumb move.
Does it mean God damn
prescription for Cialis?
Right? You don't need to take
this funky shit. I imagined, um,
the second one,
what he took had such a minuscule
trace amount that he tested negative.
Denny tested positive,
then he tested negative again.
And this is something that's supposed
to stay in your system for months.
So this is indicative of someone
who's not taking something to get into
performance enhancing and benefit from it.
But rather someone who had something
that was tainted. And these lab techs,
technicians
are smart on this shit.
Like the guy who saw the results from the,
the first little batch of
supplements we gave him, he,
he had seen everything and then some under
the sun and all different
levels and this guy knew what,
what constituted contamination and
what wasn't. He could tell, right?
Of course they can tell
just by the numbers. Look,
if you're taking trace
amounts of anything,
it's not going to do a damn thing to your
body in terms of performance enhancing,
but it is going to show up in these
tests because he's tests are incredibly
thorough. Hey Jamie, Google,
what's going on with Jon Jones case
because particularly after this weekend,
it's very, very relevant. You know,
I mean with Brock Lesnar getting in there
with DC just becoming the first light
heavyweight to consecutively hold the
light heavyweight championship and the
heavyweight championship, you know,
and the spectacular fight by DC.
But Jon Jones is always going to be sure.
I mean there you cannot,
you can go on and on about the,
the extracurricular woes of John Jones.
Sure. His capabilities as an
athlete, his talent, his is, he,
it's undeniable, undeniable look,
whatever the fuck he took dick pills where
it's not making them a better fighter.
He didn't knock DC out because
of Dick Pills. That's crazy. No,
it has to do with great skill and talent.
Beautiful left high kick.
That's what it was. And he recognize a
tendency, you know, DC he has, you know,
uh, but with this whole you
Usada a process. It just became,
and it drug on because w you know,
we said to them,
I'm not going to take a punishment.
And they said we won't,
we're not giving you any option on this.
And so that's,
it's like there was this negotiation.
What happens, what I want,
one of the things that I've talked about
when it comes to police officers is
that when you have police officers and
the people they're trying to arrest,
it becomes a game. And I don't mean
a game in terms of his bullshit.
I mean it's a game in terms
of one person's trying to
win and they're trying to
get people and arrest him.
And this is why people plant guns and
plant drugs trying to win to try to win.
And that's what killed me was that to me,
in my opinion,
you Sada was trying to win.
It was more important for them to win
than it was for us to have a clean sport.
This comes back to what we're talking
about earlier when it comes to arguments
and discussions, then people oftentimes
are not really searching for the truth.
They just want to be, right. Yes.
And I've had this argument
about bureaucracies in
general, and this goes to,
this isn't just about, you know, not
Usada and they're bureaucratic elements.
I mean, they're like the
government. There are other things.
So you come and you say, Oh, you fucked
up. And then the bureaucracy's go, shit,
we didn't fuck up. And they're going
to say, we didn't fuck up to the very,
they'll take that to the very longest
lever until either a they'll scape goat
someone or be, they can figure out a
way that they didn't. Because looking,
making a mistake on a bureaucratic
level makes it seem like, okay,
well fuck if we f and here's the thing,
if you saw this as, oh, you know,
you're not you, you didn't,
you're not going to get punished.
Then Tim means and Yoel Romero
go, uh, why did I get punished?
Or if they, if you sat and say, Oh,
well, you know, that was a miss.
That was a mistake. Well, if that
was a mistake, we'll then, hey,
I got fucked on that mistake.
You got to take care of me.
So no drug testing is bad,
but too much oversight is also bad.
I think that a clean sport is,
is AOK and the idea of the
random testing and all is fine,
but you can't do it at the expense
of the athletes in that were in the
administration of the testing
that you're trying to blast them.
Like these three Brazilian guys that
just got busted over contamination that
they traced back to a compounding
pharmacy, those different things.
This is just recent,
uh,
three different guys in the UFC
and they were all getting, uh,
supplements from a compounding pharmacy
and everything was traced back to it.
It almost seems like you shouldn't
take any fucking supplements. Well,
that's the other thing.
It's like you'll do, we are,
we not allowed to take anything,
anything at all? Nothing. No on it.
What are supplements? What do they
do? They help your performance. Yeah.
You know what I mean? Should you take
no performance and answers? She should.
We take nothing. She just eat food. I
mean it's gotta be someone out there.
It's just, well there's food that will
enhance your performance too. Right?
Like kangaroo meat, the Frank Mir took
it takes a bad kangaroo meat and all man,
that kangaroo meat, fuck you get
a good pump on that. First of all,
ain't nobody giving steroids to kangaroo.
Okay. Kangaroos are fucking everywhere.
Investigation identify as
compounding pharmacies,
a source of tainted supplements behind
three positives and your don't. Santos,
Alameda and Antonio and yeah, uh,
Minotauro and here's the weird thing.
So it comes all the way down to it and
then they're there highlight on this is,
and you know, they've or we
put, gave him a suspension that,
but at the time has already lapsed so they
won't actually have to serve any time.
It's like, but you just fucking
suspended them nonetheless.
You didn't have to do that.
Right.
So they took seven or eight months
or whatever for this get cleared up.
And that's unfortunate. Junior tested
positive for a diuretic, is that correct?
That's what it was. Which uses your
cloth something. I just diarrhetic,
which is crazy because he's a fucking
heavyweight. Not losing any weight.
Junior's not on the high side of
heavyweight. He's not like a to 65 God.
It's kind of wait to make the upper limit.
Well,
he's just trying to keep those
wrinkles out of his face.
Just trying to look good, baby. That's
right. Does diuretics make you look good?
Fuck. I don't know. I don't know. I
thought it makes you show yourself.
Just try to do, essentially, it just pulls
all the polls, all the water on bones.
Jones,
keeping in mind life is a journey,
not a race and God's will for me to
be there. Blah, blah, blah, blah.
I forget.
I'm still the youngest guy in the top
five of heavyweight and light everywhere.
Yeah, he's young. What does
that, what is unique music?
What does that someone's account.
Oh,
was he responding to somebody tweeted
that a couple of hours ago. Hmm.
It's up to a four year span right now.
He remains a provisional suspension of
wind in the outcome of the situation with
Usada after testing positive for steroids.
Last July following the knock out one
of over call me. Um, was it a steroid?
Uh, man, I couldn't tell you.
John faces up to four year suspension
due to second. You have anti-doping
poverty policy, but obviously
the young side ever champion.
But obviously first of all
when it says second violation,
the first violation was proven to be
something tainted. So it's, he's not,
when you say violation, I want, I
want to hear this guy took steroids.
He took steroids because he was trying
to get it performance enhancing a result
from it. Suspend that guy. I don't
want to hear, oh he got toothpaste.
It's from China and it had fucking
something in it. You remember that too?
Don't you want that?
A fucking crazy story about the
toothpaste that had some poisons in it or
something that they were selling in China.
Yeah. What was that? Some wild shit.
What was that toothpaste in China then?
The poison in it.
I'm vaguely remembering this. I just
said it just cause it sounds stupid,
but it's a real thing.
Yeah.
I think you just made it up
and all of a sudden it's true.
It's probably in the back of my
memory somewhere that I just, I hear,
hear what you're saying. Toxic
toothpaste made in China. Found us.
Look at it for sure. A fresh,
sure. Fresh. Sure. Fred.
That's like some people that don't
really understand English. Sure. What?
What does that mean? I don't know
Sheila. Good. Very good. Shira shellfish.
I think it's a Chinese romantization
of Chinese words door in Maine.
They're trying to kill people in name. Oh
yeah. It's one of those green up there.
Pay for, what is it? What was in
it? Antifreeze. Okay, cool. Cool.
It's main look at how
cold it gets it there.
Why wouldn't you need
any of these reasons?
People that they were doing a good job.
I want to teeth falling out.
Freezing shattering.
Glycols little propylene glycol.
Oh,
I'm 100% for testing.
I'm 100% for them stopping people from
taking performance enhancing drugs,
but this sounds very heavy handed.
It was just an I'm,
I had no problem with the system.
And then this,
the way it unfolded to me, it
was just like, this is, I don't,
I don't need to be fighting
multiple fronts. What?
I'm just trying to do everything I can
to stay to stay in this as an athlete.
Now,
when you first started,
I mean you won the UFC heavyweight
title in 2001 two at 24 years old,
youngest ever. Um, when you won, that
meant everybody was on some shit.
It was just, it was the beginning
of the cleanup everywhere.
And even then going into the Nevada state
athletic commission, previous to that,
before [inaudible] bought the UFC,
the idea of having giant fights
in Vegas was fucking a win.
It was a possibility. No, it was
not going to happen. And even then,
like the testing back in 2002
that wasn't official per se.
It was like, it was like, it was Esther
over him when he fought Brock Lesnar.
Fuck 2002. How about when we
saw the Rheem, when he was,
when he was Uber Rheem, when he was
ubering? When he fought Brock Lesnar,
Jesus fucking Christ.
Damn Comic Book Hero.
I mean there is not a God
damn drug testing agent alive.
That would have been great.
Grab him, hold him down.
He's clearly overnight that that guy
did get the picture of him on the scale
mean. That picture's amazing. Look
at both of them. Yeah, they're both,
but that one hold them down. Everybody
would have been like, hang on, hang on.
What did needle even, could you
even get a needle in his vein? Dude,
he's just like pings Benz.
He was so jacked.
This part of me just wishes he would
leave and go to Japan and go right back to
it. You know, just fill him up.
I mean look, everybody knew
what the fuck it was back then.
I mean it's interesting like Brock
Lesnar being back, Brock Lesner,
he's not asking for over him.
Over him was the last guy to really fuck
him up and he wants to fight DC and he
brought in Overeem's just not the
same guy anymore. Clearly not.
He does not perform at the same
level as he does. Still very good,
but he's still very dangerous.
Here's the thing,
even when he was a two o five pounder,
right.
And he had a tendency to gas
out, gas out and get, you know,
be Chiney to a degree.
But he was always super technical,
highly skilled.
I don't think you could Overeem,
him and his brother both are actually
very good fighters. Yeah. And you know,
their struggles. I've never been a
physical one for the most part. I think,
you know,
they've had,
and that's a difficulty that that is most
common amongst fighters is the mental
game of it. Well, we saw that within
Ghana this week. Yeah. We see the fight,
but I heard it was one for the ages.
It was one for the ages.
Let some lines loosen that thing and just
like, okay, let's crank this up a bit.
It was the worst heavyweight
fight I've ever seen.
It was the worst in of mine before
he came down to,
it came down to the sea.
It was the second lowest
output fight ever. Uh,
they couldn't even make it the
lowest output fight to be number one.
I didn't even get to number one.
Number one,
they failed it failing Jens Pulver versus
Joe Hoke from like a fucking UFC 13 or
some shit.
I don't even know what day that fight was,
but that fight was number one with 23
or 22 strikes landed in three rounds and
this fight was number two with 23
strikes landed. That's weird dude.
It was insane.
And then ovary,
I mean a Francis go to Francis
and Ghana was a Instagram.
He released a statement today and his
statement was essentially that he was a
over, he carried the fear. He said,
I'm not proud of my last performance.
I have carried my fear from
the last fight to this one.
I completely understand the frustration,
anger that it's caused my fans, coaches,
teammates and family and friends,
weird that he would have fear from
the last item. We got fucking owned,
wrestled.
He didn't know.
He thought he was the man
and then he got owned won't,
but he's letting everyone down again.
All I can do now is proved
myself and make you proud again.
But look at this picture that he
puts up his swinging on him, him,
him connected one punch.
I mean that's kind funny.
It should've been him with his head down
Frances. In the future, if you're gonna,
if you're gonna post a humble
shot, look humble. Yeah.
This is like I'm calling him. I can't say
that, that he doesn't legitimately made,
maybe he is carrying some kind of fear
from the last fight in terms of losing
the result or is a lot of mind fuck that
can go into being a fighter and yeah.
But uh,
with bounce back,
you've been on both sides and you know,
the first fight back after a kale
loss or after getting dominated,
what does that feeling
like? That's a good, yeah.
I don't know. I've been at this shit
for so long that for me it's just like,
all right, that was then, this is
now don't make the same mistakes.
Everything you've been submitted,
you've been knocked out,
you've knocked guys out,
you submitted guys who've won the title.
You beat some of the best guys in the
world. You've had fantastic performances.
You'd have performances
that frustrated you,
you've experienced at all you've
got in your long career. I mean,
from being the youngest ever
heavyweight champion of the world ever.
To how old are you now? 40. 40,
man. Dude, you fucking seen it all.
You've literally seen it all.
How long do you think you can do a,
I don't know, but I'm planning to run it
out. You do have a lot more in Japan, bro.
Keep going. I also have
this bad car habit. Yeah.
That need cash. Yeah. Yeah.
Well, you know, for 55,
Pontiacs don't get built and put into
a 75 trans ams Firebirds for free.
Well, sometimes they do. If you
have the time, that's anything.
How are you going to work on your car
when you're off all over the world doing
all this shit, right? Doing
seminars and doing pro wrestling.
Common to all my fighters. I had
two guys just fight, uh, last, uh,
this Friday at CSF in Burbank. One of
them defended his title, a Jay Bryant,
the other ones show a moto on his fight.
And for people who don't know,
that's not lucrative to train fighters.
I mean at the very highest level,
it's barely lucrative. Barely. Yeah.
I'm not, this isn't a money thing.
This is a passion project,
but he's training guys out of with
Jim I the UFC gym in La Mirada,
let us use it for a fantastic feat and
we get use of all 55,000 square feet.
Oh, that's nice. We also
work a lot with Chad.
George has a gym called Cmma and we'll
send you, we'll go down there too. Nice.
Good comradery between John Marotta.
Where's that at? Northern Orange County,
I would say. Yeah. Is it like, um,
what's it like Northern Ireland?
It was the border of Orange County,
La county at that border.
It's either southern,
most La county or northern most orange
county. It's that kind of thing.
Yeah. Those UFC gyms are fucking bad
ass. They are great job. Super Nice.
And plus they've been an
opportunity for fighters.
I think cub and Bisping also
have stakes in some, you know,
CJ does as well. I believe Frankie Edgar
does. Frankie has one in Tom's river.
Um, yeah. There's, uh, there's
quite a few of them now. I mean,
they're all over the place.
Yeah.
If you look at for a place to hit the
heavy bag and work out and liquidate some
martial arts classes,
cages and maths and all that.
And so we use those facilities.
They've been really great to
us and uh, yeah, with these,
these kids that I work with
and they are pretty much kids,
it's just about trying to
help people achieve, you know,
work towards the things that
they want as an athlete,
but also they're good people that I want
to see them make the most out of their
life.
Yeah.
So I'm trying to be a person that can
be a positive influence in terms of,
you know,
bringing philosophy and ethics to their
life and helping them be good people and,
and to pass that kind of shit on.
Be the ripple in the water that the drop
in the water that sends ripples out and
makes a positive effect on other folks.
Throw you a poet.
What the fuck?
I know brodes is something comes to me,
man.
You should put that on an Instagram
picture and show your butt because that's
where a lot of those girls
do. I don't to show that, but,
and then they have like something about,
you know,
don't like negative negativity into
your life because the ripples of that
negativity can infect the people
around you and you don't want that stay
positive.
Look on my ass.
Fucking pull up on them on these.
Look at that peach.
Yeah. Um, I think that UFC
gym is a brilliant thing,
so brilliant move. You
know, cause if I'm like,
if I see 24 hour fitness and it's
right next to the UFC gym, like Oh,
fucking heavy bags, everything. What
the fights are on TV. Yes. Put that on.
They also,
uh,
at least the one in La Mirada has like
a whole little section that has astro
turf down and all that with ladders.
It had been painted into it so
he can do foot drills. Oh, nice.
They've got a sleds and tires and shit.
I mean,
so you can do other nonconventional
workouts, kettle bells.
So they have a really like a real
strength and conditioning. Yes, yes.
I mean you can do really anything.
They have a whole set up of TRX is and
shit like that shit. Yeah. That's bad ass.
Yeah,
that's a,
I mean that's what you want from a
gym and he'd go to a lot of gems.
They just don't have that kind of stuff.
You know, they have your standard stuff,
you know, machines and shit
could lift with. It's just
not, not quite good enough.
I agree. And so this gives you
that, that full spectrum to,
to work in whatever ways you
want to just about, yeah.
Would you be interested in open owning
your own gym? Sometimes I think about it.
I do. I wouldn't mind having, having
my own gym, but it's just,
it's such a, I don't want to,
burden isn't the right word,
but there's just a lot of responsibility
that comes with it. You know,
the overhead of having a place
and creating a program, uh,
and having people manage
and run those programs.
And with me being as busy as I am,
um,
I wouldn't want to do anything half ass.
And I also don't want
to commit to something.
And then not be able to put into
it what I think is necessary.
You obviously love teaching. I, I
do. I do love to teach. Yeah. I like,
for me, it was such a big
thing in my life. The people,
not just a in terms of athletics,
but the people mentored
me and helped to mold and shape me and
help give me the tools and sometimes a
kick in the ass as needed to move me along
in life to get me to where I am today,
to give me not just in terms
of, you know, what, what you,
you would argue for is successful or not,
but just to be the person than I am.
And while far from perfect,
uh, you know, I can't,
I can't think about exchanging bad moments
for different moments in my life for
the fear of that. I wouldn't
be who I am today. You know,
a Nisha talks about eternal recurrence
and one of the idea of that is,
is that um, and your loneliest
of loneliness of a demon
showed up and it said,
well,
you're going to live your life in every
way as you ever have in every single
aspect of it. It's like, well, you
have to, you have to be okay with that.
You have to live a life that,
that, that's, that's reasonable.
That you would be fine with
doing it all over again,
doing it all over again
if you're going to become,
if you're going to be specific, she better
like pushing a rock up a hill. Right?
Whatever mistakes you've made, they've
made you who you are right now. Correct.
As long as it's not catastrophic to the
point where you've caused a loss of life
or someone's devastated and destroyed
someone else's life, you hope not.
I hope not. I mean, you know,
it's interesting thing like that there's
the concept of reincarnation. There's,
there's many concepts.
One of them is the,
one of the most haunting for some people
is that you will live your life over
again. Exactly the same
way until you get it right.
I actually heard Leo Gracie
talking about this once,
that everything in your life, every
mistake, every choice you make,
if you do not do the correct thing,
he believed that you would have to come
back again and do it all over again.
Exactly the same way. And this is his
philosophy, the way he lived his life.
That's terrifying for people.
This idea that somehow or another
you're going almost like you're going to
repeat high school, start off. But
here's what happens. The brutal,
brutal period of my life. Mine too. But
here's my question. I think everybody's,
and the people who it wasn't brutal
for those fucking people turn out to be
losing
the stories are that the fucking
homecoming king and this, I mean,
that's like a fucking Billy Joel Song.
The king and the queen of the prom.
You know, that's a, it
seems from an Italian recipe
shrunk. That's, that's literally the, the
premise of that song. I think it was a,
it was, uh, um, uh, I'm mortal song too.
Norway brand new in any way.
The puppy to,
he's in the king and the queen of the
prom running around with the cod top down
in the [inaudible].
Nobody looked any finer who was
more of a head of the Parkway Dinah.
And we never knew we could walk more
than that at alive. Remember that
Billy Joel, I don't know it as well
as you do. Whoa. It's a good song.
Um, the idea of living your life over
again. It's terrifying for people though.
Dying alone. The living over and over
and over again for in finisher, but,
but why is that when living right now
is fine for most of us. I
mean, unless you're depressed,
unless you depressing life's
a wreck living right now
it's like, okay, I'm alive.
I'm here, I'm doing it. Sure. Why
scared to do it over and over and over.
We had forever.
It's a strange thing.
Like there's something like
the futility of it all.
The idea that this is just a
repeating cycle that's just going to
you forever.
Well,
that would end in the idea that there
would be nothing that you could do to make
any effect to it. I mean to me, fuck,
even, even still, like I
couldn't, me personally,
I couldn't think of something
that in terms of like a,
I want to do something that as a
mental idea as like as a mind game,
that if I live my life in a way that
I could be okay with doing it all over
again. Just exactly the same
way. And here's the other thing,
would you know that it's going to
happen like that? How could you, well,
there was a, I kind of, I wish
I could remember who it was.
There was this philosopher
who was saying that
if you were given the ability
to absolutely and utterly
control your dreams in
all aspects and elements of it,
and so at first most people would,
would go to sleep and they would turn
it into every fucking wonderful thing
they've ever wanted.
They would just be the ultimate winner at
everything all the time, always. Right.
And then they would get tired of that
and then they would create chaos and
catastrophe and, and, and, and, you know,
make meat probably make everything
is horrible for themselves.
And they could possibly do.
And as they're going through these cycles,
ultimately the one thing that you're
going to end up wanting in the end is that
you just don't know what's
going to happen at all by,
by knowing everything prior to
it, to it occurring, it takes,
the want to experience it
away is Cormac Mccarthy wrote,
uh, um, how many people,
if they knew the path of their lives,
which still choose to live it. Ooh,
right.
Well there isn't that ultimately
expressed by fighting.
Like fighting is the ultimate expression
of that because when you step into that
cage,
if it's just you and you're looking
across the ring and another guy who's a,
a legitimate top flight mixed martial
artists and you really don't know,
I have a theory about fighting
and that fighting is actually a,
not the only,
but a great conduit into what I think of
as the highest point of is of being as
a human being that you
can enter into this state,
that it's not a place that you can
exist that all the time, like it's,
it's just not possible.
But when you reach it,
it's as if you are so
alive and you were at your,
the peak of being at that moment.
And even though it is,
it is brought on through,
through being in the, the,
the intensity and the stress of combat.
Uh,
it's as if every aspect of your
being is charged in electric and,
and living and being, but it's not a
place that you could be at all the time.
You would just be a maniac.
I,
it's not a place that human beings
can exist in for more than maybe short
periods of time.
Hmm.
Well, your senses have to be
insanely heightened. Your,
your, you, the consequences
of your actions are grave.
The only thing that really is
elevated passed out as war.
And one of the things that you find about
war and Sebastian younger wrote about
this in his book tribe,
is that the people that experience
it have an incredibly difficult time
adjusting to regular life and they
really miss it and want to go back to it
because they never felt more right.
I believe that that
war is a similar place.
I think that when you are faced
with death that that is a,
a conduit to bringing you towards
that highest point of, of being. Mm.
And uh, yeah, I suppose it,
it's like that once you get past that
point of theirs and there is no fear at
that, that level either. It is just an,
it is a way, it's just an existence.
You don't consider,
you don't think,
you don't think something
isn't this or that. It just is.
And it's a, a place that you
can't be forever wouldn't,
it doesn't work that way.
But when you've been there and you're
just out here dealing with petty can
Internet trolls and dumb shit
and people doing stuff that,
that cut their nose to spite their
face and undermining this and you know,
the fabric of our relationships for
no good reason. It's, it's tough to,
to sit in, exist in this and
go, fuck, you know, I how,
how do you get back to that other thing?
There's this state of purity,
this existence of where these,
none of those things matter anymore.
I don't know if she can, I mean
you, you might have, I mean look,
we have a certain amount of time on this,
on this planet, in this life, right?
You have a hundred years.
If everything goes great,
you can't really expect
to just live in that.
That perfect state of both chaos,
n n
chaos and I guess being
in the moment there's,
there's something about something
that's dangerous and intense and
overwhelmingly filled with anticipation
beforehand and the preparation is all
consuming.
There's very few things in life that
are the like these big moments like a
person stepping into a cage for a fight
and the consequences are so grave.
It's just for your emotions,
for your physical health,
this is this really nothing like it.
Is it really the,
the to expect that you would
find something else similar
in life and to be able
to achieve a similar state
outside of that? It's, I don't,
I don't think you ever will because I
feel like part of what makes what you do
and what all fighters do so intense and
so incredibly enjoyable to watch is that
we all know how much is on the line.
I think. I believe I'm 100%
in agreeance with you there.
And I think race car
drivers and fighter pilots,
I think people like that also likely
experience that state of being as well.
Yeah, I'm sure. Yeah. Fighter
pilots. It has to be, you know,
fighter pilots apparently I was reading
some story about this,
about wife swapping. They,
that they uh,
they're more inclined to have a
polyamorous relationships. Really. Yeah.
And then the wife swap because the
idea was that they know that their life
easily could be wiped
out any day at any time.
And the the people they
care about the most,
their wife or their girlfriend that
they want other people to love them
cause they might not be there.
Interesting and that they would want the
people they care about the most loved
them because yeah they're thinking in
a altruistic fashion of doing what they
can I suppose to help this person that
they care so much about continue to find
joy in their life because of their,
their realization that what joy
they may be able to derive from them
specifically is, is always on a thin
line of not being there anymore.
That's fucking intense.
That you love someone so much.
You want other people to fuck
him cause he's not going to be,
how do I get on that list? Well it's
probably already on. You just got to ask
the,
which comes back to the one thing
that is I think poison in life,
which is to live a double life,
a grave, a a boring no risk,
10 or run, no thrills,
no challenge, no growth,
no knowledge,
no learning.
Just this stagnant bullshit life
that is so prevalent in our society.
I think it's one of the main problems
with our world is that we have set up
these really safe cities and
safe societies and cultures,
which is wonderful.
It's great, but also we,
we haven't given people the
discipline or the structure or the,
the like the framework for living a life
that's going to satisfy your needs in
terms of your biological needs.
Yeah. Psychological, this and
people start determining that.
Totally inane things are what
their needs are. You know,
they're difficult to acquire,
right?
Like you think of Ferrari's going
to make you happy, cause a Ferrari.
He's hard to get. Sure. Very look at
it. Like how much do you cost? Shit.
If I'm just had that man, I'd be bawling.
I'd be driving around Red Ferrari. Yeah.
Be balling. But then you get that
Ferrari like this is just a car. Yeah.
Like unless you just really love cars,
like you could love,
you know your Firebird and you appreciate
it from a mechanical standpoint.
You want to step back and look at it.
It's enjoyable.
But if you think that the fucking thing
is going to make you happy, you're crazy.
Not more happy than me being happy with
who I am as a person and the life that
I'm living. The Firebird can't do, can't
do that. There is no item. You know,
I have to sit back all the time
and try to think for myself that
you,
Ew,
I, I love my library, that I
have all the books within it.
I love the cars that I have.
I love the relationships that I have,
but there's a good written
instead of the relationship,
but just the things and it's
like these are all great things,
but if I don't have them,
I am still me.
I still have everything that
I need in this world. I,
I don't like to think about
them being lost, destroyed.
I certainly hate the idea of it being
destroyed because even if it wasn't in my
hands, I'd like them to still
exist for others. But without them,
I'm no different than who I am now.
And I guess that's kind of a
thinking of like the Stoics,
you've been more defined by your
accomplishments and your thinking and your
philosophy.
There's lots of things
that people obviously they
couldn't know about me. They,
because it's not the kind of
thing that is just my who I am.
Right.
And,
and I don't need someone to know whether
or not I'm smart or whether or not I
know this or whether or not I can do that.
It's like I'll do it when I need to do
it and I have to try and look to see that
I have my own inner peace is based on
my own self knowledge and knowledge also
that I am lacking, that I can
be better, that I, if I want to,
I can choose to. And those days that I
don't, it was a choice not to be better.
It wasn't that I couldn't cause even
going and failing like we talked about
before is a worthwhile endeavor because
it will move you towards either a
eventually getting there or B that it's
not something that's going to be yours,
but you know what it is and you
know what it takes to get there.
And that's a different
perspective altogether and
okay,
that is where I feel like that's where
I can be okay in this world and deal in,
in.
There's all kinds of things that you can
draw your focus and really eat at you
and bother you and you're giving weight
to these things and allowing them to
have an effect on you and that's natural.
That's a normal thing and it's
easy to fall into. But you,
if you can be okay with,
all right,
if all I'm left with is just me and what
I have, if I no longer have anything, no,
no more luxuries, no more this, no more
of that. Can you be okay with that?
You know,
what kind of life would you make of this?
And I like to think the same one I
have now. You can pick me up here,
take all my shit away,
throw me some other part of the world,
the third world country
and it will be jarring.
It will be difficult and there
will be some lament of course,
but I will continue to be who I am.
I will see what is necessary to to
communicate with others and to continue to
propagate this that I'm
trying to create in me.
Yeah.
I think we're all trying to navigate
this really incredibly difficult thing,
which is your, just your life. You're
the emotions, the, the, the, the,
your goals, your tasks,
your relationships, your,
your dreams and aspirations.
All these things are just so complicated
and the whole idea of not knowing what
the future holds is stressful,
but it's also incredibly rewarding when
things work out well and even when they
don't work out well.
What's rewarding about that is you get
the gift of knowing that you fucked up
and you get the gift of the feeling
of fucking up and the horrible,
just the,
the feeling of failure and to understand
that that's fuel for you to regroup,
repackage your fucking thoughts and,
and now move forward with the knowledge
of the mistakes that you've made and
you're going to be a better person.
How can you fuck up if you
don't do anything? If you
don't ever day, you don't. If,
if, if you just sit back and
you try to lead the simplest,
safest version of a life,
it's not a life.
It's on a line and it's not a life I can
really imagine that anyone can really
be truly fulfilled living.
And you know,
things are ultimately
incredibly soft on us. I mean,
we have pressures in other ways,
but ultimately most of us are living
quite comfortable lives with no immediate
dangers and no,
no real impetus to put stress on
ourselves where it doesn't exist at times.
Because let's just say you
wanted to learn new language.
There's agitation in terms of,
of forcing you to have to endure
something. There's some suffering in that.
And you know, I believe in the
Nietzschean concept of, you know,
suffering creates growth.
You know, life is suffering.
Suffering doesn't have to be catastrophic.
It doesn't have to be this
sort of thing that, um, is,
is going to debilitate you,
but that suffering is needed for you
to continue to become better. For sure.
Everything with exercise, with
learning, with everything,
with the even relationships, learning
in relationships that, that the,
all those uncomfortable
feelings are how you learn.
Yes. Learning relationships.
I, I've always said to two
friends of mine, you know,
the first time they have like a big
blow out with something called me up and
I'll fuck,
you know,
so and so said this and I don't know how
their Dick ended up there and all this
stuff. Just like look, ultimately, yeah,
no one wants to get
into a row with someone,
especially someone that you
really care about. But if,
if this is an important relationship,
the only way it becomes a relationship
that has that deeper lasting meaning and
that really has any real depth to it
at all is what you do when you guys are
faced with adversity that shows
you what relationship you have.
Because when things are fun and easy,
anybody can be a part of it, right?
We all just,
you
know, Hump in and drinking and going out
and woo, that's great. Fucking wonderful.
But when I'm, I'm good. Once he has a
pretty, it's not bad as a single guy,
I'm constantly looking for that
opportunity. But uh, ladies,
if you look in a hump and drink hump and
dragging that mainly whiskey in coffee,
but drinking and hopping and muscle
cars, if you're into that, uh,
but when you get into these,
all of a sudden adversity
comes across your doorstep,
how you'd handle that.
And you know,
whether you're the person who brought it
or you're the person who's in enduring
it from the other side and,
and if you haven't experienced that in
your life and also in experience it in a
relationship, man, you might not be ready.
That's true. Might not have the tools.
Yeah. You need to know about everything
that you do. That's difficult. Right?
It gives you the tools to
navigate difficult situations
and the other aspects of
your life are agreed. Yeah. It is
the, the stresses of having to,
to deal with a problem and how you handle
that problem because there will never
be any shortage of, of problems, of
difficulties from, from great too small.
And you,
your way of mitigating those problems
and dealing with them is so important.
It's, it determines how it, how it works
out for you. That's right. Bitches.
Josh Barnett dropping knowledge, like
advertised. Let's wrap this up. Josh.
He's the man. We got to do this more
often. We do it like once a year now.
I would love to come in more often.
I,
I especially would love
to even at some point,
like when you've got Bret in here
and you've got Jordan and all that,
and I'm just want to sit in,
talk on philosophy like that.
I love the shit out of it. Let's do
it, Josh Barnett, ladies. Gentlemen,
bye everybody.