And Effects Donna or was that you?
That was me.
Okay.
Alright.
I thought you.
I thought you paid for that were live
Ron White.
Hey Joe.
Are you ready to take notes on this?
You know,
you,
you shove some paperwork at me when I
don't have my glasses.
I don't even know what it says.
You have glasses on?
I do.
Oh yeah,
Yeah.
And I'm not sure,
but I think I've just agreed to find.
We trust me.
We wouldn't do anything terrible to you
know,
you're my friend.
I know.
I love you.
I love you too.
We have a mutual admiration society that
we don't let anybody else in.
It's been so on in,
but fuck them.
Fuck down.
It's been so nice having you run a store
man.
I got to tell you.
It's really fun.
Yeah.
That's great.
When you were man,
our little home base up there.
It's a fucking hoot.
It is,
right?
It's like a work on everything there and
then venture forth right spot.
And I've driven that,
you know,
I've just got this big quandary now,
whether it even do another special or
what it would do for me and you know,
Netflix is offering me money,
but they're not offering me be,
you know,
huge money.
They're offering me regular money trying
to figure out if you want to.
Yeah.
You know,
it takes me.
I'm not like some comics.
Some comics will spit out of our year
and uh,
and I don't,
you know,
I did takes me three years to write a
new record,
you know,
but it's good,
but it's.
But it takes me forever to do it.
I just not that prolific.
I guess that's the big debate with
comedians.
Like how much time should you wait?
And Tom,
papa and I were just talking about it
and I've talked about with burn with
Louis Ck and a bunch of different guys
and lily's doing like one a year for a
while.
But he stopped doing that and I think he
kind of agrees now that when you do one
a year,
it's almost like,
um,
it's a special full of like a adolescent
premises.
Yeah,
yeah,
and I've always found it.
My stuff ripens well,
you know,
on the vine,
if I leave it there,
if I pick it too early,
you know,
used to do a bit that was on my last
album and the punchline is not even on
the album.
The punchline I wrote later,
which was a,
it's about my wife buy me a bicycle
thing and I might ride it for health
reasons and it is for sale and if you're
looking for a bicycle is a great deal.
It's got 750 yards on it.
It was a demo when I bought it at 350
yards already on it,
but I put the other 400 yards on it
myself.
That was the whole joke.
Now here's the punchline and if you'd
like to buy the bicycle,
just go to my house in Beverly Hills and
it's 400 yards from there.
So I didn't even have the punchline.
I didn't even know what I thought was
funny about the other part,
but when I went back and listened to it,
I'm like,
I could start doing that bit again
because they still don't know how it
ends.
If I wanted to.
Mitch Hedberg did that.
He had a bit on his album and he goes,
this is a bit from my old album,
and he does a bit.
He goes,
this is the part I left out.
This is the punchline.
That's hilarious.
Yeah,
it's a,
it's a funny thing,
you know,
development of material,
like you're the only one who really
knows when it's done and sometimes
you'll have something.
I've had bits that I didn't put it on
specials that I was doing.
I was like,
this thing is not just,
it's not ready.
And then maybe two specials later,
I'll stick it in somewhere.
Right.
Yeah.
So I don't know,
you know,
that Netflix wants an hour.
I,
I really think that fluke spatial should
be 30 minutes.
I really,
I really do because I would do a 30
minute special and that and that burnout
in our material on it.
Uh,
and,
you know,
I,
I go back,
I want shoes the other day,
which was great.
And uh,
and uh,
I watched the,
uh,
the uh,
Ali wongs special and it was just long,
you know,
it just long an hour's a long time,
uh,
for,
special and that as much as I was
impressed by Allie and I still am
impressed by Allie,
uh,
but I've been impressed with what I see
in the club when I go back and watch
your special.
I see what kind of confidence that
broader,
that success of that thing.
It made her a better comic.
You know,
she now she really has a great,
I mean,
uh,
be even better presence on stage and
works even slower and more commanding,
but I can,
you know,
that's what I learned from watching it
was,
you know,
that kind of,
that kind of success makes you better
for her.
I mean,
she sort of emerging right now.
She's one of those people that,
you know,
people started to talk about.
She's very,
very funny.
She's really cool to really nice person,
but it's just nasty and funny on stage
is vicious and I don't know her because
she's got a kid so soon as she gets off
stage,
he's out of there.
So I talked to her on stage a couple of
times when she was bringing me.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah man.
I'd like an hour,
like an hour,
like a good hour special,
you know,
maybe just don't want to have cheap.
It's don't want to do it.
I don't want to do the work,
man.
It's so daunting to put it.
I mean,
my last bedroom was an hour and 20
minutes and I,
and that's just,
cause that's how long it was and when
I've,
when I sold it,
I'm like,
I don't want to go ahead and let,
you know as I worked like that you can
have the whole thing.
And then I'm standing there naked,
you know,
I could've gotten away with 48 minutes.
Uh,
you know,
because it was on television and nobody
saw it on tv because it was on cmt.
Nobody wants his fucking cmt.
So nobody's even heard the last album.
And I don't do it,
you know,
country music,
television.
Isn't that real popular was called
country music television anymore.
They just call it cmt,
uh,
started.
Uh,
yeah,
I think it still stands for country
music television,
but they're trying to do a bunch of
other shit now too.
Right?
They try to do,
you know,
they did a,
I did it.
I had a special with them once a year
and I would do then I would just have to
come up with 15 minutes.
And uh,
which was doable,
you know,
I,
I that,
that I could actually put on TV,
most of it you shouldn't even put on TV.
But uh,
but that was great.
It was a salute to the troops thing and
raise money and awareness for good
stuff.
And then they quit doing it and uh,
somehow bought my special and a put.
But.
So I just,
you know,
if I do a bit from it,
it,
it kills.
Like nobody's heard it.
So I really don't think anybody really
hurt it.
Only sold 12 copies of those people,
you know,
12.
They know that.
I have no idea how many we were talking
about that before the show about like
buying things,
like nobody buys comedy albums anymore.
They don't,
they just don't make any money,
right?
Like none.
Yeah,
I did.
I just started watching stuff on Netflix
the other day because I just wanted to
watch some of the specials at some of
the people I knew up there to see what
they were doing,
you know,
what they're working on.
And,
and,
uh,
now why would you buy a fucking record?
You can just flip it over to Netflix and
watch it.
I like listening to shit in my car.
I like when people release things on
itunes.
He had did that.
Uh,
my,
uh,
my best.
I'm a comedy album store story and I
don't mean this to be mean or anything
else.
Uh,
but it was a,
I was watching the red,
the record sales because my records were
selling and then uh,
then Dane Cook comes in and he just
blows by me and I'm like,
who is this guy?
Because I'm an la guy.
I'm a road guy,
you know,
we don't know what's going on out here,
nor do we give a shit and uh,
but I thought well it must be.
So I was at a bookstore and I saw it and
I thought,
well I want to,
I want to buy it and see what,
see what it's like.
So literally I'll listen to it on the
way home.
When I got home I pulled it out,
throw it in the trash.
Not not to be mean,
but just because I don't keep things I
don't use,
but I knew I wouldn't listen to it again
and I wasn't going to give it to
somebody else to listen to.
And so I don't need it anymore.
It's a,
it we've run our,
you know,
run our thing and not to say anything
bad about Dang because that been plenty
of bad things have been said.
But,
but I just went.
That was so unintuitive that I'm like,
if that's what they're doing out there,
then they're getting away with murder
because that was our punchlines.
I'm sorry to tell you,
that was a weird time.
He locked into some weird thing where he
sort of appealed to young girls like he
did comedy girls.
No,
no,
that's not you.
That's not me either.
Yeah.
It's not.
A lot of us leg had fascinating stage
presence too and you know,
just really walk on stage and take
command of anything,
you know.
I don't know if he can still do it,
but at one time I'd watch him and I'm
like,
you're lacking or not.
If you're a comic you could probably
learn something from watching him.
It was a young comic,
you know,
just walk up there and start doing it.
Stare him down.
Don't be timid,
you know,
when he was a great stage presence.
But the content I was like,
why,
what,
why don't get it.
I don't get it when we,
but,
and now it gets.
It's turned around on him.
I mean it's not know.
I don't know.
Well it turned around on him when that
whole Louis ck plagiarism thing came out
and there's a lot of shit going on.
I was supposed to have sold something.
Stole something from Louis.
Oh yeah.
Like a lot of things.
Yeah,
before Louis was famous.
Yup.
Oh yeah.
Well that's when it's easy.
Yeah.
Lilly was a,
while.
They're young.
Lose wasn't young.
He was older than him,
but lilly,
he made it first.
He broke through first and then it
became a giant controversy.
Like Louis could even addressed it on
his television show.
Like he had Dane on as a guest on that
show and they kind of went over it.
It was very weird.
Like Louis,
he's so nice.
Like the way he handled it was so nice.
Like he wasn't mean about it at all.
Right.
They not like you as well.
That was a difference there.
Was this the best thing ever?
That was that where you had every comic
in the country just cheering her fucking
name,
man.
Go get them Joe.
And,
and you're such a bad ass.
What's he gonna do?
Slap you,
you know,
you can either listen to it or you can
beat you up or whatever you want.
What are you going to do?
That was the worst I've ever seen
though.
I've seen.
I've seen plagiarist before.
I've seen guys get away with stealing
people's shit.
But I've never seen someone that
blatant,
he was a bully about it.
Like he would do your shit.
He would go on in front of you and do
your shit.
Like he would bring you up at the store
into your closing bit before we brought
you up,
man.
Yeah,
I think it's one of those things like a
serial killer wants to get caught.
You know,
you think that's what it is.
Yeah,
I do.
I really do.
Well,
you know,
the,
the only thing that matters to me really
is.
I mean the,
or the thing I'm most proud of is that
I'm respected by my peers that I didn't
get here in some fucking cheap way.
I did my fucking 30 years and uh,
a mad million clubs and 12,000
shows and,
and if I didn't have that,
I don't know if I'd be able to show my
face around here.
No,
that's all there is.
I think it's the.
I think for people like us,
it's probably the most important thing
because there's so few of us.
I mean it.
Is there a thousand working comedians
is,
or even a thousand?
I mean,
there might not even be a thousand.
Yeah,
it's a tiny,
tiny subculture.
Tiny and none of that subculture.
Maybe 300 of them I want to see,
you know,
maybe.
Maybe,
Right.
So you're one of 300 people at a $300
million.
That's a,
that's a tiny fuck.
Yeah.
Fuck yeah.
I'm going to get.
I'm getting buff.
I'm getting above.
Just sitting here.
You get fired up right there.
Last sheer.
It is.
I wish we brought you Tequila,
man.
I'm glad.
I really,
if I would have had to sat here and
drank it with you and then I'd been out.
Now I had to go get that range rover
back to Uber's for.
And that's got some good goddamn
Tequila.
I love the fact that you sell your own
Well,
you know what?
We wouldn't have done it,
but the rescue his family that makes it
wouldn't sell it here.
And so we just passed her up because we
couldn't buy it.
And,
and uh,
until then my brother in law did and he
pestered him for four years and they
finally said,
okay,
you can,
you can bring it over there.
They only sell it in Mexico.
They,
they only sell it in Mexico.
They say in Mexico,
they sell it for three times what I sell
it for here.
And they only sell it in the resort
cities.
People coming off those boats.
And uh,
and you know,
it's the Best Tequila that most liquor
stores will ever touch.
And,
and,
uh,
so it was called the gift of God over
there.
The,
there were a,
I don't know how to say it,
man.
Spam.
She's Mexican.
So she can tell you though.
She speaks fluent.
Oh yeah.
Did she get mad at you and speaking
Spanish?
Uh,
no.
But when she does do it,
she's a voiceover artist as well as a
singer,
so she can do any accent.
There is.
And she has different wigs for different
accents and she lets me fuck them all.
Oh yeah,
it was fucking great man.
It's fucking terrible.
I can't ask for them specifically.
They just show up.
Oh,
what an interesting little situation.
Yeah.
One of them is,
uh,
one of them's name was Donna and she's a
bank teller from Denton,
Texas and uh,
you know,
she's a sloppy,
sloppy,
blowjobs and different on it.
That is don is off the charts.
She a favorite.
There's a little French girl.
There's a little,
there's a little girl from China,
Japan.
Uh,
I like them all.
I like to mix them up.
Don't ever want to say the data gives a
better blowjob in Margo because it's
technically not through,
but she's still like,
Oh really?
I'm like,
Yeah.
How could you say?
Could you get upset at you?
She's getting jealous of herself.
Right?
That's ridiculous.
But it can happen.
Why?
Just because she spits on your Dick.
Whoa.
Yeah.
Okay.
When you say that on,
definitely.
Got It.
Okay,
good.
Sure.
Yeah.
Some people are into that spitting on
the tech thing.
It's just like,
well,
we aren't getting dirty for sure.
Push,
push.
Yeah.
It's the people that can't afford lube.
What do you think that started to
spitting on the deck?
Because I don't think they did that in
the eighties.
You don't think so?
I don't think so.
I never saw it,
you know,
just uh,
I think youporn brought it around a
brought it into the,
into the light when you see variety
instantaneously.
Like you don't have to venture forth
into the weird sections,
you know,
like if you're in a video store back in
the old days,
you had to go through those beads
around.
And I remember though it was a saloon
doors or beads,
right.
We had to go into the section of the
video store that had the porn and you
always felt so full of shame when you
were wandering.
Affordable.
It was a horrible man.
Nobody does this but me.
But now you know,
but at least back then no one had a
phone with a camera.
So you couldn't like take a video.
Look,
I'm watching Ron white go to the fucking
dirty section.
What I said before,
he's looking at the gag stuff.
He likes people to gag.
I do,
but that's the thing now it's like you
can go to any one of those websites and
have the porn on it and you can just
keep scrolling like,
oh,
check this out,
check it.
And you get it instantaneously and it's
free.
Right.
But that's what I like about,
uh,
you porn is that a is I don't have to
worry about seeing something I don't
want to see,
you know,
I'm such a raging heterosexual and I,
I tried one time I was in a hotel room,
they had gay porn,
like I'm going to have watched them gay
porn.
See if it does anything.
Click nothing.
Not a damn thing.
I'm like,
oh Jesus Christ as his horrible.
And I guess I'm getting fucking.
Some people are just straight.
Well as women like Dick.
So I mean it makes sense that some men
like Dick,
I get it.
I do too,
but I didn't get it when it just
doesn't,
you know that fucking story that you're
telling on stage now,
the story that you told about the
prostitute situation.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
They,
you encouraged me to do a show funny
crying.
I'll,
I'll tell,
I'll tell you,
you're are,
you're our,
you're our listeners now.
They're our listeners to joe and ron
show.
Thank you.
I'll be here every Thursday at 1:30,
but it was true.
It's a lot of lost my virginity when I
was 18 years old to a girl,
a prostitute and a in Tijuana,
Mexico who was overweight and her teeth
had no general direction or color,
but she was well within my budget but I
got stationed at Pearl and if I found
out after awhile when she'd been on one
part of Awahoo wasn't hotel st these
really cute girls are jumping in your
car and blow you for $5.
And it's like the best deal I've ever
even fucking heard of.
I mean,
I was there twice a day,
you know,
and,
and uh,
I was there for eight months and then
six months ago I was watching this
documentary on transvestites and they
started talking about the transvestite
scene on hotel street on a wall who had
been there for 55 years.
I might know 150 dudes suck my dick.
Like,
what's the record?
What's the record?
Before you find out when I went to
record,
is that I don't know,
but God,
I have to be close.
You know I've dodged that bullet,
but I've come close a gang of time.
I think I've dodged the bullet.
Yeah.
If I had to dodge the bullet.
Kudos.
Everything pretended to be to apparently
it.
Tongue is a tongue and a tooth is the
tooth because you can't tell man man
from woman mouth.
Now if it would have been a hand job,
I'd been going,
hey,
you're a plumber.
Dude.
That hand on my cock.
Sick gorilla hands.
Jesus,
what do you think I am?
Yeah,
and I would imagine that somebody who
has a deck probably knows how to work
it.
If I guess with.
I tell you what,
these girls had made quick work at me
twice a day,
45 seconds.
I was in my little dots and be headed
back to the ship.
Do you say girls with air quotes with
air quotes girls?
Yeah.
Well,
I still don't like to think of them as
dude.
You know,
in my mind that I don't let myself go
there.
They're still hot little girls,
not little girls for these were fully
developed in with tits tits.
They did and I was always wondering
what,
let me play with her pose.
You know,
they,
they let you get some teddy,
but you started going down there where
the junk is and they were like swat and
your hand away and I'm like,
now that should have been a flag.
I don't know.
Yeah,
well now you know.
Yeah.
So what,
you were in the navy,
is that what you're doing?
How long?
I wasn't in real long.
Uh,
they uh,
you know,
I just wasn't cut out for it.
I had that.
I did,
I had the wrong mouth for it.
That stayed in trouble.
I didn't,
you know,
it just did a lot of drugs and you know,
I just,
it was horrible out.
They discharged me with an honorable
discharge under medical conditions from
the Naval Drug Rehabilitation Center in
Miramar,
California.
Oh Wow.
So what would you have to get
rehabilitated for?
Well,
I'd actually never seen drugs until I
got to the drug rehabilitation center in
Miramar,
California.
I mean,
everybody had drugs,
you know,
I was positive for heroin,
a Westpac,
but,
so we're eight other people on the ship
and,
and uh,
then when we ate a ton of acid and you
know,
it was 75 and I was 18 years old and
that was off the hook wild.
And uh,
and you know,
they just actually in my,
in my hearing to get me out the,
the,
the commander of our base called me a
hole in our national line of defense.
Like,
that's horrible.
But what's worse than that?
I wonder nothing.
It seems a little exaggerating.
Yeah.
Like I remember playing Red Rover,
you know,
relax,
holding our national defense.
It weren't even at Warren 75.
Right.
Wasn't the tail end of the Vietnam War.
Yeah.
Wow.
Did you join or did you get drafted now?
There was no draft.
When I,
my father drafted me.
I got kicked out of high school and uh,
and they weren't going to put me back in
this time.
And so I was 17.
I kind of had my life mapped out because
that worked washing dishes at this,
a huge restaurant called Lynchburg
crossing in a close to Pasadena,
Texas and right on the channel,
gigantic place,
unbelievable and served family style,
all kinds of seafood and chicken and
stuff.
It was really popular,
but they didn't have,
they didn't go hire people to wash
dishes.
They would go buy all these drunks out
of jail and they had bunk houses in the
back and the dishwashers asleep back
there.
They'd drink all the half drinks that
came back and crash there.
So I really,
at 17 years old I was thinking,
well,
I could,
uh,
when I'm 17,
I joined the 16.
I joined the merchant marines at 17,
which was wrong.
And uh,
and then I worked there until I retired
and then I go wash dishes until a dine
that bog house.
He liked the old drug that used to roll
his joint so we couldn't roll joints
very good.
And this guy could.
And we came in there one day.
Just data that you be.
Isn't it funny when he was dead,
that will have cirrhosis a problem.
These guys were bad.
I mean bad booze hound,
but you know,
pretty good dishwashers.
Isn't it funny when you look back in
your life and getting kicked out of high
school,
all the trouble you were in getting
kicked out of the navy,
getting bombed by a bunch of dudes.
Accidentally.
It's all the recipes or being a great
comic,
but nobody ever looks at it that way.
You don't have some of that stuff are
there.
What are you getting?
What are you going to ride around?
He needs almost like you have to come up
to everybody who is a fuck up and go,
look,
I know you're not fitting in here,
but there's a place where you do like
there's a place to sit.
There's a fucking whole clan of us just
kind of.
You've got to figure out how to do it.
I'm telling you,
Joe's first time I walked on stage,
I literally,
I went to myself.
I'm A.
I'm a fucking comedian.
Why didn't somebody tell me I could have
avoided a bunch of that other stuff and
just started.
I was 29 when I figured it out.
Twenty one.
Same feeling right after I did it.
I was like,
this is it.
I found it.
This is it.
This is the one that works.
Yeah.
I mean I wasn't good.
I knew it wasn't good.
I knew I was like,
there's a lot of work to be done,
but I'm like,
this could be my job.
I go,
I didn't think I'd ever do it
professionally or anything like that.
I just knew I was a comic,
you know,
that knew I was a comedian and.
But I never ever saw all this fame and
fortune shit coming.
I mean,
I never really sat around asking the
universe for it.
I never thought it would happen.
Even though I watched it happen to
Foxworthy,
you know,
he biggest selling comic of all time by
a lot.
So more records than prior and cod.
We combined and he blew up standing
right next to me,
but I never gave it one second of
thought that it would happen to me.
Well,
in the blue collar tort kicked off and
then,
and then it took off for you.
How old were you?
Let's see.
Probably 45 or so.
40th five or 46.
So you just working as a comic up to 45
and then 16 years clubs 50 weeks a year.
I'm doing nine shows a week.
So,
which is how you get good at this,
you know,
that's,
that's the best way to do it.
Not,
not here.
We're out there working,
you know,
different crowds and,
and then uh,
Jeff,
you know,
sign me up for this thing.
And uh,
first time I heard the idea,
I told him that's retarded.
That's how smart I am.
And um,
they uh,
the,
the whole clincher to my career is
warner brothers decided to make a movie
out of that thing and uh,
and I didn't even see that.
I mean I had a gang war road is going to
make a movie out of it and Kathleen
Madigan's fallen out of her chair.
They're gonna cheat.
What I'm like,
yeah,
that's what they say.
But I'd had no idea what that meant.
I don't know.
I'm an idiot from northwest Texas,
so I'm like,
it sounds good,
but then if for some reason they just
tested it was really well liked across
the board and uh,
and uh,
and then it was one of the biggest
selling comedy albums of all time for
dvds,
4 million copies.
It was giant.
I remember when it came out,
it was just one of those things like,
whoa,
nobody ever did that before.
Nobody ever put together a bunch of
killers and then did a movie.
Wow.
They'd actually the kings of Comedy da
and get him first.
Yeah,
we totally ripped off the black man
again,
you know,
goddammit ron white the a way,
but,
you know,
it was just a blue collar,
a shot at it.
Not necessarily,
you know,
redneck but,
but you know,
just people that work for a living.
They lots who likes us,
you know,
and,
but the catalyst from that we made Dan
Whitney ridiculously famous and uh,
and made me famous and did a lot for
bill,
but jeff was already,
you know,
Jeff.
So do you call Dan Whitney?
Dan Whitney,
or do you call him Larry?
The cable guy ever call my pain Larry,
uh,
though I don't call him Larry.
I don't know if you know him forever is
Dan.
Yeah.
But you know what?
I never knew.
I never saw the act that it wasn't all
Larry the cable guy and I know it used
to be.
And uh,
one of the funniest things I ever saw
was that there was,
used to be this tape and uh,
uh,
the South County funnybone in St Louis
and the condo where they literally
shitty little apartment they put us in
and it was a,
it was called bovine women from
somewhere and it was about huge fat
girls and uh,
and he had stayed,
it was a copy.
It had been around for awhile,
the condo.
So we play it for people as a joke when
they came over and,
and uh,
he had a vhs camera and because that was
a copy,
he edited himself into the movie and it
was fucking outrageous.
Really funny.
So was it a porn that was a yarn.
Yeah.
And so somebody be fucking her from
behind.
And then it turned the camera around in
his day and just work.
This can be you,
Marty,
the manager of the club.
But it was very,
very funny.
Maybe me,
somebody stole it after that.
Nobody wants to steal it before it was
edited,
but somebody took it after that.
Uh,
yeah.
That was back when you need to edit
things.
You used to have to have two vcrs
whereas to have a little bit of this and
a little bit of that and go back and
forth and back and forth.
Yeah.
But those vhs cameras at the end,
you know,
because I had one too.
I used to type nearly everything I did.
And,
and uh,
so,
you know,
they,
if it didn't have a tab broken off of
it,
you know,
you could just record right over
whatever little part of it you wanted it
to.
And that's right.
The Tab.
If it had a tab,
you couldn't do it.
So that's what you did for your wedding
video.
I forgot about that tab.
Like if you took the tab off then nobody
could record on.
It was still there.
And this one was still there,
so he just,
he just punched himself right into it.
The first thing is this big old 500
pounder.
She's opening the refrigerator door.
So the reveal is the light of the
frigerator through her thighs and in
gigantic and it's a cutaway to him
drinking a glass of milk,
going real slap sticky stuff.
But if you're working,
if you didn't see a covenant,
it was uh,
it was,
it was a big laugh.
I saw a video of him doing standup as
Dan Whitney and I was like,
wow,
this is so weird.
Yeah.
So he had no shirt tucked in his pants.
He had like a polo shirt on,
right?
The whole deal.
And it was a,
was really smart.
I mean,
what he did.
And,
and uh,
you know,
one day,
one time Larry was just a character that
he did in the act.
And then the,
then the billingsley Larry took over.
That's like the dice man.
Yeah,
same thing because he was a,
he was a character that he did in the
show.
Yeah,
he was Andrew Silverstein.
He would go on stage as Andrew
Silverstein and he had a bunch of
impressions that he would do.
He'd do an impression of Travolta,
he would do an Alpha Chino impression,
and then at the end of his act he would
do the iceman.
The iceman was essentially aversion his,
his take on Jerry Lewis and the nutty
professor.
Remember when Jerry Lewis and the nutty
professor and he was like this nerdy guy
and he'd drink some fucking potion and
all of a sudden it becomes this really
cool guy.
Like that was what Andrew did.
He had just become this dice Mande
character and you put the leather jacket
on.
Oh.
And then the rhymes and all that shit.
Right.
And his act was so unique because he was
the first guy where you could repeat the
punchlines pack and everybody liked it.
Almost like a,
like a song,
right?
Like if someone's singing a song,
you like to sing along,
but if for comedy that.
Because there's no such thing as they
hit joke,
right?
There's a popular bid,
but there's no such thing as a hit job
or want to hear to get,
you know,
the joke,
you know the joke and fans,
you know,
they,
they bitch at me because I won't do
anything that's old and,
and uh,
they want me to,
they want to hear me do tater salad and
they want to hear.
We do some of that stuff.
But there are long bits,
there are long stories they already
know.
So if I start one,
I did it in Madison Square Garden last
time I was there,
I opened with it.
Oh really?
I hadn't done in 12 years.
I had to go back and listen to it 10
times because there's a complicated
piece of comedy.
It doesn't sound like it,
but it is,
you know,
it still pays rhythm and timing all the
way through this eight minute long joke
or story.
And so I did it and they,
when I started it,
you thought I was one of the Beatles.
They would just went absolutely nuts.
But then I got to drag them through an
eight minute long piece.
They already know.
So now they're not,
you know,
it's not the response I used to get that
I love to get from it.
So if I don't get what I want,
then you don't get what you want.
So.
But it was fun to do that one time,
but that I just won't go back.
And you know,
Gaffigan is a prisoner to hot pockets or
he's in prison.
That's a good prison to be in.
It's a great president being it's funny
guy,
but he has to do that bit like a Fox
foxworthy has to do the,
you might be a redneck buddies also got
10,000
of them.
That's fine.
No,
that's different.
He's got so many versions of it.
We have many only does five or six at
the end of the show and that's been for
years that he hasn't hardly done any of
that and that's what he was always known
for.
And uh,
which was just a great idea for a bit
that now has calendars and you know,
just crazy,
crazy the money made off.
That was a genius pit.
He just nailed it.
He figured out like this perfect
formula.
Yeah,
he's a funny guy,
man.
Jeff Foxworthy does not get the credit
he deserved.
No,
no.
He's probably the most prolific a writer
that I know
and I also just owe him fucking
everything.
You know,
really nice guy too.
He is a sweetheart of a man.
Humble takes his kids to school every
day,
goes to church,
has a mission project that he works on.
Very,
very straight.
It was a little wilder when he was in
the club,
you know,
but,
but that's the way he was raised in.
That's kind of what he went back to.
Where does he live?
In Georgia?
In Atlanta.
While we had a house the size.
What college.
I'm sure I'm not talking about this
University of Phoenix shit either.
I'm talking about.
Yeah,
that's,
you kind of have to buy one of those
when you get that rich.
Well,
you know,
he's uh,
he's just a,
he's just the real deal,
you know,
and,
but you're right.
If people of randomly,
if I hear you got other comics,
you know,
sometimes they'll rag on the blue collar
tour,
you know,
a lot of people didn't like Dan and I
mean,
but it was all comics and I've never
performed for comics once in my life and
I tell the comics,
here's the worst thing you can do,
perform for those comics in the back
because that's not whoever's going to
come up with I see you or pay money,
don't perform for them,
but for,
for those people in the seats and so you
know,
it it and whatever it was,
whatever it was,
and he just got popular and if it
wouldn't have been for that huge
popularity,
nobody would have given a shit.
That thing that happens when something
becomes really popular is that people
decided to shit on it.
Even though it doesn't mean like there's
nothing wrong with Larry.
The Cable Guy's act.
It's a funny act.
He's a funny guy and he's a paced rhythm
and timing comic and he's really good
at.
He's very good at it,
but I remember when he was huge,
when he still is,
but when it was all happening when it
was first happening and he was doing
fucking football arenas,
all these,
like a David Cross wrote some fucking
letter to Larry the cable guy and I'm
like,
what are you doing?
Like this doesn't make any sense.
Like,
what is he doing wrong?
I don't understand.
What are you trying to say that this
character,
this ridiculous over the top character
he's doing isn't funny or racist or
people that really took issue with it.
And it's just this,
just comedy.
If you don't lack it,
listen to something else.
Yeah,
exactly.
That's the end of the long and the short
of it,
uh,
it,
you know,
it's not exactly my cup of tea,
but I know how good he is still a,
you know.
And,
and,
uh,
I would go out of my way to see jeff and
I probably wouldn't go out of my way to
see him just to see,
um,
but,
uh,
but that his style is not exactly my cup
of tea,
but that doesn't matter,
that I can still see how good he is at
it and uh,
and saw what he did and the impact that
he had.
And then also the addition.
He wasn't one of the original guys,
the other,
there was another guy and then jeff got
a got rid of him.
And who's the other guy you don't
remember?
Nah.
Okay.
I can remember.
I know I totally would say,
but it was a guy from.
I just have a shitty memory sometimes I
could remember his name and sometimes I
can't remember his name,
but he's the last beetle.
He's that last beetle,
that one kind of get kicked out of the
box and fucking to this day
beat his head against the wall.
I don't know what he does now,
but uh,
he was a good comic and,
but he was on some kind of medication
that made him just getting Jeff's face
and talk to him nonstop.
Doesn't like that.
And Jeff's like,
Hey,
I know I'm taking a piss dude.
GimMe a minute.
Oh No.
Adderall type things.
I guess so.
And then he would,
you know,
we're doing these big shows.
They're like,
well,
I put $12 on a cab and nobody's paying
me back.
And,
and uh,
read you your right about 12 bucks.
Wow.
That's the wrong guy.
Right.
So,
and then Dan came in and shook things
up,
you know,
and,
uh,
really,
you know,
like it don't,
like it doesn't matter.
He destroyed every night and still
involved to the stairs.
Yes,
we'd audition for the same part in the
movie,
uh,
in the not too long ago.
So I saw him at this audition and it was
for a,
I don't remember the name of the movie,
but it was supposed to a huge cast.
Really big people in it.
But they're all sucked and I mean,
they're always just nothing in.
And then I got sideways with the people
doing the interview because they said it
was a reading,
so I didn't memorize the script,
you know,
and I came in,
but I wear these tinted yellow glasses a
lot of the time.
And uh,
she,
she said,
can you take off the glasses?
They're too modern for this,
this piece.
I'm like,
well,
if you want me to read it,
the glasses are not for sure.
They just happened to be yellow.
But.
So whoever's watching it,
have them close their eyes and imagine
with me with shitty glasses on,
if that's okay,
but I'm not going to take them off.
And then she goes,
well,
I guess if you,
if you get this role,
you'll cancel your lab schedule.
And I said,
no,
I won't.
No,
That was cleared with them.
I said,
you got to where if I'm going to do it,
you got to do it around my schedule.
I'm not canceling any days for it.
And I'm like,
Oh,
now I'm going to fight at the casting
office.
That probably not going to get this.
I didn't want it anyway.
I'd just come off the roadies and then I
was kind of disappointing.
So it's a fucking weird
businessman and that,
that,
that inner.
The interaction that you have with the
casting director is very strange.
I've had some good ones are really,
really nice conversation.
People want me to.
Gail have been his boot cast me for
Brodis and she's wonderful,
but there's a lot of them that are
wonderful,
but there's a lot of them that are not.
These two chicks were.
There were snobs.
Yeah.
I mean they,
they really were,
you know,
they were really talking to me like I
had not accomplished a single thing in
my life and maybe if this happened,
you know,
I'd be able to call myself a man or.
Well that's their rule.
I mean that's their position,
their positions.
That's one of the reasons why actors are
so fucking crazy.
It's because you walk into this room and
your life depends on whether or not this
person puts a check next to your name,
whether they gave you the green light,
and so you go in there and you have to
memorize some bullshit that you don't
really care about most of the time.
Some nonsense Sitcom or some fucking
stupid rail and a movie and you gotta
it's half charming them half doing
this.
I tell Brian to this day that they have
fucking ruined them.
I go ruined them.
You,
you don't know how to disagree with
people.
I'm like,
Brian Cowen will go into Rodney's
charms.
Everyone in the building because he's so
good at an audition.
So I'm like,
they fucking ruined you.
You don't know how to like figure out
that this person is not for you.
Well,
you know,
now
I just turned 60 and on a Sunday.
And uh,
if I had to,
if I signed up for a TV show,
I'd be signed on until I was 66 or 67.
And uh,
in my day that if 51.
And so that seems like an awful long
time.
And so if it,
I mean,
if it happened to be someone I really
liked,
you know,
like if,
if Jay Mcgraw was producing it,
I would do it,
probably would do it just so I could
hang out with him,
but I would have to really,
really like somebody,
you know,
that I was going to be hanging with that
time because I couldn't just
do it.
Don't ever guest is Dr.
Phil's kid is such a cool motherfucker.
Well you have a mutual friend,
Shane Mcgraw who's a buddy of ours,
both of us.
He's a fucking coolest guy.
Yeah,
he is.
He's,
he's something else.
So is his dad.
His Dad is his dad is a hoot.
I'm sure he is.
But who would have ever guessed it?
Nobody.
Why?
I'm friends with both of them and they,
but a jay is just solid.
I mean
the,
uh,
I can't even tell you some things he's
done for me to start crying.
Don't cry.
I cry.
So don't do it.
Don't do it.
So,
uh,
I don't cry for sad thing.
So I'm aware.
I'm weird.
Like sad things,
I can sort of deal with some weird way,
but when things are epic,
like epic moments,
I'm like,
Holy Shit,
don't cry bitch.
Right together
like a Nadia Comaneci.
It's doing those little back flips out
of cried like a bit.
Excellence is a,
his chokes me up a bit,
but you know,
my friend died last weekend and uh,
and that kind of stuff.
I'm okay with.
I mean,
I don't,
I don't get real emotional about that
kind of stuff.
Uh,
unless,
you know,
unless I've known you for 50 years and
uh,
so,
you know,
but uh,
j Jay,
Jay's just a great guy,
you know,
he's an unbelievably solid dude when he
doesn't have to be.
He just brought me back a three boxes of
killer cigars from Cuba.
So how can you not like it?
Oh yeah.
He just went to Cuba.
You can bring those back now.
Yeah,
I,
yeah,
I think,
I think he was on his plane or
something.
Yes,
you can kind of do it.
You can kind of bring them back sorta.
You can get like a few of them.
Well,
they,
the thing is that you can get $200
worth,
but the people that customers have no
idea how expensive they are,
so you can just say this was $185 worth
and they go,
Ooh,
that's expensive,
but it's really $1,500
worth of cigars.
Yeah,
I mean if you pay them in American
money,
it probably is 150 bucks worth.
Right.
I can probably pretty good.
I actually,
they probably
know they're really not.
Well,
I don't know,
didn't I didn't ask him but because he
gave them to me.
But uh,
you get a deal on him.
How often do you smoke cigars?
Uh,
you know,
every day as I smoked,
when I smoked,
I saw you walked in with one.
I was like,
God dammit.
Ron White,
you're a fucking caricature.
Look at what do you got there?
That's one of the,
one of the gaming these,
uh,
boulevard.
It was a good.
That's a strong one.
Yeah it is.
And it's.
And it was that big when I started so I
just smoked it and cut it off.
It does.
That's a strong cigar.
I liked boulevard,
I'm going to,
I'm going to crank a crank that back up
if there's still air in my tire whenever
I get out of here.
Boulevards and.
Well,
it's something about that soil.
There's this one area of Cuba where they
grow most of their tobacco and it's like
some,
it's not even that big of a place.
It's not like that many acres,
right?
Just this unbelievable soil.
Like what is it that much different,
like you will like a sore or are you
like a Sim?
All,
Yay.
Of Cigar,
sort of.
Yeah.
You know,
a,
you know,
the,
the thing is that the smart guy was,
you know,
Davidoff Davidoff cigars and because he
saw that he saw it all coming.
And uh,
so before it all happened,
he moved his rollers and his factory and
everything over the Dominican Republic.
So whenever they came in and took the
land from those people that started
these iconic brands and they just kicked
him out of the country with nothing,
will they all had seed so they could
grow that same tobacco if they stayed in
the same kind of region,
the same parallel like Dominican
Republic or even over to Ecuador.
Uh,
that was still perfect conditions for
growing these,
these,
these plants.
But what they didn't have was rollers
and uh,
these cigars,
uh,
these handmade cigars are rolled by
experts.
I mean these people in Cuba,
they spend their whole lives.
It's a good job and they have these huge
role in rooms and these people just
rollies perfect cigars and somebody sits
in the front of the room and read them
books.
Really read some books.
Yeah,
the reads like a book on tape,
but someone's Ds.
If somebody is actually up there with
the reader,
they come in and shifts and,
and read to them.
They sit there and listen to the stories
and roll cigars.
Fucking fascinating.
I have a book at home.
It's all photographs of a Cuban Cuban
cigar business and the Cuban people
rolling the cigars and it's fucking
amazing.
They're smoking a fat cigar while
they're rolling cigars,
you know,
and the whole thing is just,
it's got such a weird sort of romance to
it.
Yeah,
yeah.
There we go.
I used to smoke a,
you know,
a couple of them a day and I always
spoke on stage so.
But actually now I'm,
I'm such a dinosaur.
They're really starting to crack down on
the.
Oh,
the cigar,
so I'll just lie it and I'll take it out
there and put an ashtray,
let it go out and do the suction because
like the theaters will let you smoke in
the theater.
But they used to give me some wiggle
room.
But now like in Canada,
they started saying,
well,
here's
what we do.
We don't know what we're going to find
you,
but we're going to hold all of your
money until we decide if you smoke on
this stage.
They told you that before you went out
the buzz kill.
Well,
I'm glad they didn't tell me after Jesus
fucking Christ,
but someplaces Massey Hall in Toronto,
you know,
that's fucking Charlie Chaplin was on
that stage.
I just loved that place.
Great.
Toronto.
Toronto's incredible.
I just did it two weeks ago with Russell
Peters,
me,
Russell and big joker son fellow.
What a fucking show.
I don't even know if I've seen Jay.
I've ever met him.
He's funny dad and I've heard him on
radio.
Right?
He's got a radio show and podcast.
Legion of skanks.
Yeah,
one of the greatest names for podcast
ever.
He's a funny dude.
He's a good dude too.
And just end it again.
Another one like a real comic,
like you know,
like you know one when you meet one.
Yeah,
sure.
You know like if I ran into him
anywhere,
be like a,
like a life vest in the middle of the
ocean.
If I ran into him in Dubai,
I'd be like,
there's,
there's one of us.
Okay.
All right.
I could go with you to the pathway
there,
but not to Dubai.
You might go buy now.
No.
You know what's up buddy?
I'm not sure that I wouldn't somebody
people talk about this huge,
huge money that they're offering guys to
go out to Dubai and in India they got
crazy rules though in Dubai.
They do.
Yeah.
Yeah,
yeah.
Dubai is a crazy religious rules like if
you in any way insult royal families or
in any way.
Who was it,
Jamie that's talked about?
That was it.
I think it was how sparks was telling us
that he did a Gig in Dubai and someone
after he got off stage told him to do.
He's going to be arrested for something
that he said because he referred to one
of the royal family as like Sir rather
than your highness.
Like something as simple as that.
Yeah,
I better not go,
fuck that.
I can't do it.
I can just,
I can,
I,
I won't do colleges.
I won't do anything either.
Five years.
Seinfeld bitching about the political
correctness of a college students these
days.
I'm like,
why don't you go perform for people your
own age?
Maybe that's.
Maybe that's it.
The universe.
Think about that.
Well,
it's not your people and they're super
sensitive and they're just,
they're finally disconnected from their
parents that are looking to call
bullshit on everybody there.
That's one thing about college kids is
they're looking to be right and they're
looking to establish what you can and
can't say and they're looking to control
people because they have.
They're just free for the first time
ever themselves.
Right.
It probably would have done the same
thing.
Yeah.
If I hadn't gotten kicked out of high
school and joined the navy,
I pro.
I just,
uh,
I can't do like regular school work that
I can't do that kind of stuff.
I've never owned a notebook.
This isn't mine.
This is your habit that's for you to
gift like Christmas.
It's very nice.
Christmas.
You don't write down on notebooks.
He just,
uh,
you just come up stuff on stage or you
come up with stuff.
Do you like if you have an idea where
you write it on your phone or something?
No,
no.
I have my attention deficit disorder so
bad that if I pick up a piece of paper,
I'm done,
then I'll start thinking about that
piece of paper and then I'm off to
fucking ag land and so it just doesn't
work.
And uh,
I've forgotten so much stuff I know that
I could have done on stage and,
and uh,
but,
but once it gets to the stage,
I record it.
So I don't.
And I should record these,
these,
these short sets,
but I don't.
But I record all the big sites.
You don't record like the comedy store.
I can do it on your phone,
you know?
Yeah.
Well,
it's funny.
Now that's another thing.
I don't,
I don't know a lot about that.
Have a look.
See this.
It's so fucking easy.
See this little thing right here.
This is a voice.
Recordings like that.
These are all my sets for the last six
months.
Just keep going.
You got to put it all.
And I make notes.
Make notes for each one of them.
Did you know you have it?
You have it on your phone.
It's a,
it's an application that comes with it.
It's called voice memos.
It comes with the phone.
So you have an iphone.
It's in there.
I'll show you afterwards.
I'll help you,
but it's so easy,
so easy.
Ron,
you just take that sucker.
You press record as you're walking up
the stage.
I sit on the stool right by me records
my whole set because there's many,
many times that I'd have a new punchline
or a new outline.
I'll have a thought in the middle of a
bit mobile and one.
What the fuck is that?
And I'll go off on something just free
and I'll say afterwards,
thank God I recorded that because I got
to go listen to that because for me this
store in particular,
it's the best place for that.
And the Ice House.
You have to do the Ice House?
No,
fuck.
You could have done it before but uh,
but I should get over there and they
have like an open mic or something or
the.
Well they have a bunch of shit there but
we do shows there on Wednesdays all the
time.
I'm there like January.
I think January fourth or something like
that,
that it January fourth.
You want to do it with us?
It's always sold out and it's the
fucking best room in the world.
That room,
the ice house room is set up.
It's the best setup on our.
You will fucking murder that place.
I've,
I've done sets there a long time ago.
Uh,
and uh,
and,
and I,
and I know I loved it and everybody
says,
is this the best room?
There is
comedy club in the world.
It is the oldest comedy club in the
world.
It started in 1961,
I believe.
Nineteen 61.
Nineteen 62,
something like that.
Yeah.
It's the oldest concurrent working
comedy club on Earth.
And it used to literally be an ice house
before they had freezers.
People used to buy ice from the Ice
House.
That's how fucking old that places.
Yeah,
they on the fourth.
I,
I'll,
uh,
I'll come out there if you guys got room
for me gentlemen.
You want to do a show?
Do it.
I got room for you.
So have some fun.
Yeah,
I'll browse Tequila.
I'll leave her out there with the,
with a bottle of,
uh,
that extra nda.
Whoa.
Now we're talking.
So you guys looked at a number one and
j.
u a n Tequila.
That's what I've got to hock.
Yeah.
Okay.
Well we're going to buy a case of that
shit.
Bring it in here.
Set it up.
Boom.
You didn't,
you don't.
They have it at the comedy store now.
I always have a bottle back there,
but our distribution is just now getting
fixed and in California.
So there I'm sure that they'll pick it
up.
Uh,
as soon as these guys get all hooked up,
they just got their Tequila the other
day.
So it's a dark tequila too.
You have,
do you have more than one kind?
Yeah,
I have a block.
Whoa.
That's kind of straight out of the
faucet and a and then an extra,
uh,
than in a reposado which is a haze for
nine months in two different barrels and
then blended at the end and have a
French oak wine barrel.
Half of it's a bourbon barrel,
retired and then nine months and then
blended together.
And uh,
and that's,
and that's what,
uh,
my brother in law,
that's all he drinks is that one in and
I drink the other one because I come
from a scotch background.
So it's a little heavier.
Yeah,
it's got like a dark sort of smoky.
It's dangerous.
It's a dangerous bottle that have just
sitting near you with no protection or
you know,
just with a couple people just because
once you start drinking it,
it just,
it's just,
it offers no resistance at all.
You can just sit there and Polish alibi
feeling we shouldn't be having a
podcast,
but I have in like a little drink.
Okay.
I feel like we should have a little
drink,
get some Jack Daniels on the,
on the box.
Let's do it.
A little drink with ron white and come
on,
come on,
come on.
Yeah,
it's a good Tequila.
I'm happy you're,
you're,
uh,
you're doing that as well.
It's nice to see comedians branch out
into different shit.
Well,
I'd like to see some of the different
stuff I do ever make money,
but you know,
we,
we have a lot of fun with the Tequila
and somebody will come by and buy it one
day and said,
you know,
we win everything with it.
How's that not making money,
not making money.
And now,
uh,
again it made money.
The third year it made a,
it made.
We made the third year we made $17,000.
That's the whole year.
And that was a possible,
uh,
well,
because it's kind of expensive to get
into.
I mean we're,
we're,
we're shoestring and it,
you know,
I'm not putting,
I'm not putting my nut in there,
you know,
I put money in it but not,
not too much.
And then,
so,
you know,
we're just kind of as really slow
growth,
uh,
until somebody comes along,
you know,
and then,
uh,
and then if they,
you know,
somebody wants it worse than we do,
they'll have it.
So for you is just sort of like a goof
just to get into it for fun.
A not.
Well,
a couple things I'd really like to see
my brother in law.
He had really like to see it work for
him.
Then he owns more of it than I do.
And a mechanic,
right?
Yeah.
I Alex from the window box very well.
He's one of my best friends and he
literally,
when I started doing standup a September
17th,
1986 is when I met him and I was nervous
I was going to do four minutes,
first time open mic and went straight to
the bar and order a beer and a shot of
Tequila.
And he handed me the beer and a shot of
So he was the bartender in the club I
started at in
Arlington,
Texas.
What's it called?
Funnybone comedy club.
If they could say something else now.
But,
but that's where,
that was my whole weight.
What's Arlington near Dallas?
Fort Worth?
That's where Texas stadium is.
And uh,
in the ballpark.
And where's that funnybone not funny,
but an Improv.
They don't have an Improv.
Know they have Improv,
uh,
up in uh,
Irvine Irving or something up at North
Dallas.
There's one,
but there isn't there too.
Yeah.
All right.
What is this?
This.
There used to be two.
There used to be one right down on
central expressway,
but I don't know if there is any more.
This is a Sinatra select frankie baby.
Where did we get this?
Somebody sent it to us,
right?
The Jack Daniels Send Simon to us.
Yeah.
Jack Daniels send this to us.
They found out we drank Jack Daniels on
the show,
so they sent us to Sinatra select tool.
Yeah,
baby.
It's mostly toupees.
Come on and cheers,
sir.
Joe Rogan.
Cheers.
Blonde White Jack Daniels to me means
fun times and bad decisions.
Almost everything that I've ever done
that I should've done that a lot of it's
connected to that shit.
There's just so much.
Fuck it in Jack Daniel's.
It touched her slogan.
Jack Daniels.
Fuck it.
It's like A.
almost every time I go on stage,
I have a shot shot shot of this.
Not the Sinatra stuff,
but kind of tastes the same to me.
I wasn't really.
That's really pretty good.
I'm not much of a bourbon guy,
but that's
pretty tasty stuff.
Finally,
Weed's legal,
Ron White.
I know you're happy about that.
Well,
I've been treating it like it was
illegal for about 50 years,
so I had know it's going to have that
much difference.
Uh,
you know,
they had medical marijuana here anyway.
And,
and uh,
and I was actually using medical
marijuana to get off of regular
marijuana and that works like a charm.
It's almost like Jesus came from heaven
and healed me of this regular marijuana
problem that's been haunting me since I
was 13 years old.
And now that they've legalized
recreational marijuana,
I'm going to use that to wean myself
from medical marijuana.
That's nine.
I've got a plan that's like methadone.
You know what?
It's a,
it's,
it's so it,
it came,
it took so long to get here,
uh,
you know,
to,
to even this little seven,
what?
We have seven states now that are a
group,
how many states?
Jamie,
legal,
recreational.
That was recreational,
but then a bunch of,
uh,
you know,
in Vegas there they're going to have
recreational.
But,
but now that they have medical,
if you have a card from anywhere you can
go and,
uh,
in the vegas a dispensary,
what's up is there's so
many people that are in jail for life in
Vegas from the seventies,
right?
For life,
for like getting caught with a dime bag.
Vegas used to be the worst place in the
world when it came to pot.
I don't know why.
I guess they were trying to discourage
you.
This is what it was there.
They got legalized prostitution,
legalized gambling,
open carry,
handguns,
liquor available 24 hours a day on the
street.
You can actually walk out onto the strip
at 5:00
in the morning,
crack open a beer and bad on the camel
toe races.
But don't you dare out of joint because
there's children here.
Children,
I think they were just trying to
discourage people from getting high
because it probably cut it on the
profits when you assume that,
uh,
the last thing I want to do and I get
high as gamble.
I want to look at buildings.
I go,
look how much,
much money this building cost.
Where are they getting their money?
They must be for people like me,
like me that don't smoke in here to
always feel like I never had the urge to
gamble when I'm high ever.
But if I was drunk and I walked into a
casino,
I'd be like,
let's see what happens.
Absolutely.
Come out.
But I'm not much of a gambler.
I'm good.
You're good.
I'm not much of a gambler.
You know what?
I
played a lot of cards when I first
started working in Vegas and then I got
hit a couple of times and,
and uh,
uh,
literally.
I mean,
if you're gonna,
if you're gonna bet 300 bucks a hand,
you better have a half million bucks
sitting there or you'll get beat because
it hit.
It just accelerates so high off of the
three grand off at a $300 bet.
And so if you're not ready to really bet
it,
you should just not.
If you don't have a,
if you can't stay there until it all
cycles back through a in case you start
on the wrong side of it been,
now I'll go my mother.
My mother's 81,
she likes to get hammered and gamble.
She does.
She's always in Vegas.
I was there two weeks ago and I looked
over on the side of the stage and my
mother was there.
I had no idea she was coming all the way
from cocoa and she was just over there
waving.
That's awesome.
And she gets hammered.
Gambles.
Yeah.
She plays blackjack,
Texas.
Hold him.
And she was one of those harder mother,
you know,
or you know,
jen,
you,
you think that Jim can't be skill all
skill.
But anytime I play my mother in Jen,
she's like,
it takes one car and lays them down.
And I'm like,
well,
how can you do that?
You can't be good and just draw those
cards.
What are you doing?
In my grandmother was worse than her
was.
So she plays serious poker but not with
serious money and uh,
more than she used to.
But,
but,
uh,
and then my son loves to play Texas,
hold 'em.
So if he comes out to vegas then I'll go
play with him.
I have a bunch of friends and gamble
really high and I don't have that gene.
I'm missing it.
That's a good one not to have because
it's a,
you,
you can really feel stupid the next day
when you're going accurate,
uh,
gotten well.
One of them at least a moderate late
day.
Ford escort,
you know,
are,
are several escorts.
I gotta get something out of this
instead.
I got absolutely nothing except free
booze.
So my friend Dana white is lost as much
as a million dollars in a night.
It lowered.
Yeah.
But he won like,
did it say one seven?
I think he said he wants seven one
night.
Yeah,
I don't get it.
He's got it though.
Whatever it is,
he's got better.
Yeah.
But you know what,
that's also,
uh,
that's uh,
one of the,
a big thing with people that have been
punched a lot.
Like he was a boxer for a long time and
a lot of MMA fighters,
a lot of people that have had
experienced a lot of head trauma.
They like to gamble.
There's a weird correlation there.
They don't know why.
I wonder,
wonder if John Daly ever got hit in the
head.
I'm sure somebody punched that guy for
sure.
Right.
Who didn't punch that guy?
He's a big dude,
but still somebody probably punched him.
He's A.
Yeah,
probably.
So
baby boy,
he just has a gambling problem.
He's finding he was sober for five years
and he's a buddy of mine.
I mean,
got to say he's a buddy of mine.
Whenever the masters comes to,
uh,
Augusta,
the,
uh,
he's always there and he sells merge
avis genius because he's the only
person,
number one.
He's the most famous golfer in the city
at that time is John Daly more famous
than anybody playing in that tournament.
And then he's accessible.
He likes people.
And so he'll go out there and sell
$250,000,
$300,000
words a merge out of this huge,
you know,
you got this big prevost tour thing and
the big old trailer instead up and wow,
his own store at the hooters right next
to the ride next to the golf tournament.
And uh,
so that's genius during that time.
Yeah.
And,
and,
and he,
you know,
it's all his brands and uh,
he just makes a kill and doing it and
uh,
it is brilliant in.
But uh,
I parked my tour bus right next to his,
so that's the time I see him,
you know,
is whenever he's doing now.
He now he's on the senior tour,
so I don't even know.
I don't follow golf,
but I followed that guy,
you know what I mean?
Like he's a fun dude,
you know,
he,
he gets crazy.
It does a lot of wild,
nutty shit.
Likes to get hammered.
Right.
It's like I liked the fact that there's
a guy like that out there that can do
it.
Yeah.
And he's not,
he might not be the best golfer in the
world anymore,
you know,
but he's still a very good golfer and he
still like this character.
Like it's part of the thing.
It's not just who wins the golf
tournament.
It's like I want to see John Daly play,
I want to see them talk.
I want to see them get crazy.
Right.
Yeah.
So,
well he gets crazy,
you know.
And uh,
he got sober for a few years and then he
got,
he called me the other day,
like,
oh,
whenever that started again,
that was just baked and then the last
time I was at last year to go.
So we got really trashed and he was
doing a podcast or a,
some kind of radio show out of a,
at hooters.
And besides that,
he's got a radio show or did for a while
and,
and he's just drunk as shit,
just trash and the PGA tour.
And I'm like,
you know,
you really golf on exemptions,
they're going to.
But uh,
I didn't say anything to him,
but it mean he's just either over the
top,
sober or over the top drunk.
He can't be,
he can't be in.
There's also just dead honest.
We will not lie to you to make you feel
better,
will not lie to you,
make you feel bad.
He just won't lie.
He talks about how he feels and you
know,
he's just one of those guys that,
uh,
that,
you know,
and that's why it's so popular.
That's why everybody,
that's why the people love it.
We could all use more of that.
All of us,
right?
Uh,
I don't know how many.
I think I could use less.
I think that's what my.
I think I'm going to start lying more in
the 2017.
Just stay drunk and keep lying drunk and
keep lying.
That's a great one.
Yeah,
I know what you mean.
At a certain point in time,
you know how much fucking sand is left
in this Goddamn hourglass.
What are we doing with it?
Right?
You know it.
Any.
Yeah.
Right.
We can on a continued path of
improvement and spiritual enlightenment.
Or do we eventually go,
hey guys,
there's a cliff coming up.
Let's just have a drink.
What's happened is a fucking cliff was a
cliff right over there.
Oh yeah,
that's what,
you know,
that's what Margo and I are saying is,
uh,
is that,
we're already dead.
That's how fast it goes.
We're already dead.
So while we got this last couple of
minutes here,
let's have some fun.
Let's not forget that.
Buried some really close friends and
really not right next to each other.
About a year and a half ago.
And that broke my heart,
I didn't want to do standup anymore.
And it just horrible stuff.
And then,
uh,
and then,
my buddy that dad this weekend,
I saw him three days before at a party
and he was fine.
He was laughing.
He's fit as he can be,
plays hockey.
He's a 69 years old,
but he was just really,
really.
He ate a hamburger without the bun while
I was sitting there with him.
And I was like,
I bet he regrets that now looking back
on it,
fuck,
I should eat.
And that fucking Bowen.
And then in then boom,
dead in three days.
I'm just.
Was the actor guy that just died
recently?
Alan thicke.
That's who it is.
That's what it is.
Yeah.
I don't think it was on fear factor.
He was a sweetheart.
Go.
He's a,
he,
he's a charming human being.
And I don't know when I'm bad at.
I'm really good friends with John Paul
Dejoria who,
who,
uh,
owns patrona and Paul Mitchell and,
and he is just a biker that made a
billions of dollars with the,
just a great.
Just a brilliant man.
And,
and uh,
so he has these,
you know,
men's nights that are kind of a League
of extraordinary rich dudes and a,
but every once in a while and
entertainers sneaks in there like me and
Allen.
And so the first
one I went there,
I was,
I knew,
I recognize that of course because he
was a hugely famous television star when
I was watching television even.
And uh,
but what attracted me was this to him as
a man,
you know,
just uh,
his charisma and he just,
he just one of those guys,
they can,
uh,
that,
you know,
just a man's man,
man,
just want to hang around them.
Yeah.
I was really shocked.
I was really shocked too though.
Nice and friendly was.
And uh,
you know,
took his last.
He had to do some physical things.
You had to climb on something on the
side of a building or something like
that.
And he won.
He wound up losing.
Took it like a champ,
right?
Oh yeah.
Smiling the whole wave play.
Contact hockey with faith needs to stay
the wrong.
He got his knees done.
Yeah.
You still play hockey.
They told him not to,
but he,
he's like,
what am I going to do?
Oh my gosh.
So it works pretty good in it.
But uh,
he was playing hockey with his phone
when he died and the end,
his son told me this and it was really
funny.
He goes,
while he was on the fucking stretcher
putting him in the ambulance and uh,
he goes,
sorry guys,
I'm an asshole just to stop in the
gangs.
And then he was dead 15 minutes later,
but he,
but he got a laugh on the way out the
door and people were saying,
man,
I want a tragic thing that,
you know,
he died quick and I've had two friends
die slow.
You don't want any part of that.
And so quick.
That's when we all agree with that
quick.
We want to go quick,
I want to go quick.
And uh,
you know that that's what he did and he
was with his son was with him when he
took his last breath.
I think that's a good thing and I think
it's,
I don't think it is too,
when he looks back on it,
if he doesn't already,
you know what a real touchy subject
isn't a real touchy subject,
right?
People dying.
It's a real touchy and it's also a real
touching.
Like what we think is gonna happen after
that right now.
There's people that are there,
they're like real,
real sensitive about what they think is
going to happen and whether it's
nothing.
A lot of people are like convinced it's
I'll say to you with such fucking
conviction,
listen,
when you die,
it's nothing.
Well,
it goes dark.
I know for a fact that's not true
because I lived in a haunted house and
uh,
if there's a haunted house,
then somebody,
there is an afterlife if,
because we.
There was definitely a haunted house.
Where did you live?
It was a,
it was a Lake House that side of Austin
and on Lake Lbj and Kingsland,
Texas,
and we had to sign documents at closing
saying that it had been told to us that
it was a haunted house.
You have to do that in Texas a and
they'd had a,
they had two mediums that I'm an extra
large and said the same exact thing.
It's the ghost name is Whitey Sour.
Oh my God.
And he was the barber for the town and
uh,
and,
and they couldn't tell why it was still
there,
but he was obviously there.
He could,
he would do these things in front of
people.
You could put,
take a pot of water right out of the
tap,
put it on the stove,
stove turned off,
and just sit there and wait.
And it starts to vibrate and that it
vibrate to where the waves came in from
the center to the middle and then bounce
up in the middle.
And then you could get a hold of it
because you're obviously stronger than
the ghost.
You can sell it back down and let go of
that.
And,
uh,
and he would do it again.
So,
uh,
you know,
so I,
and I know that is,
I mean I happened to just know that to
be a fact that,
uh,
I lived in a haunted house
was how many people do you think have
actually lived in a haunted house and
how many people are just fucking crazy
because that's the problem if you really
did live in a haunted house.
And I believe he did,
you know,
that some people who've told similar
stories are just fucking crazy and that
might be the problem.
The problem is trying to differentiate
between real unusual experiences which
may or not be possible.
That can happen to anybody just because
it hasn't happened to you or it hasn't
happened to me.
I'm walking through life assuming that
it's bullshit.
But if it did happen right in front of
you,
you'll go,
holy shit.
How am I going to describe what this is?
How many people are pretending things
like that are happening now?
I don't know,
but it's just something that I've always
been able to say what after I've lived
there that I know for a fact that the
somethings happens afterwards in,
in,
uh,
I had a talk with a yet I bought the
house.
It was still making payments to his
daughter and uh,
whenever we first moved there,
uh,
my girlfriend at the time,
her uncle's helped move her stuff down
there and they had a bunk bed set up in
my son's room,
but they didn't want him at a mattress
on the bottom and along the top.
And he put his shoes up there and during
the night for no reason,
the shoes got pushed off and fell and
hit him in the chest.
And I was totally whining and a,
that's fucking yet.
And so the next day,
uh,
I walked into that room and I said,
why did listen and we'll make a deal
with you.
I love it that you're here.
It's filing me.
Uh,
uh,
we have one of his chairs.
Then we wouldn't let anybody sit in with
his chair.
So,
uh,
and uh,
as I said,
well,
I'm gonna tell you something right now.
You fuck with my little boy,
I'm gonna hit your daughter in the mouth
because I,
I saw her every month when I made the
payment.
So if he was going to Jack with my
little kid,
fucking punch them teeth and you're
going to punch his,
his daughter.
Not really,
not really,
but it's rent to coast to coast.
That's so gangster.
Yeah,
went in me.
Never,
never,
ever saw any activity in that room
again.
My grandparents had a guy died in the
house and they always claim that they
saw him.
He was like a,
um,
a guy who rented a room in their attic
and uh,
he died and my grandmother always would
swear that she could hear him walking
around up there and he'd be there.
You know,
if there is,
we know that this is like most people
here,
ghost stories and you'll get the fuck
out of here.
It's because so many ghost shows me.
How many times can you watch a person go
into a basement with a windows night
vision screens on and look at?
Nothing and go.
What did you hear that?
What was that?
Oh my God.
Television shows dedicated to one thing,
like an egg will move in inch over a
year or something.
I think it would be super arrogant to
assume that it's not possible to go
surreal that you just haven't
experienced them yet.
Most people haven't experienced them
because if there's all sorts of types of
life,
right?
There's people that are born with birth
defects that make them tiny and other
people are born with gigantism and deaf
is this and life itself is not like this
perfect mathematical science.
It's filled with all sorts of mistakes
and errors and weird shit.
If there's a transition between this
stage of life and the next stage of
life,
would we assume that it would be
perfect?
No,
we.
We assume if there is a spirit or some
sort of a soul in people,
we would assume that that transition
sometimes misses and sometimes you get
caught in the howling in between the
worlds and he just ricocheted back and
forth off of both places.
Well,
you can't unsmoked that joint can.
You can.
Hey,
you know what?
I'll tell you something that's kind of
an interesting story.
Uh,
my uncle who was a preacher,
a southern Baptist preacher,
a brilliant man who's age three
doctorates in psychology,
philosophy,
theology,
wow.
And a fun,
fun,
fun guy to talk to and uh,
was at one time the president of the
Southern Baptist Convention,
Dr Charles [inaudible] is his name and
uh,
which is a very,
very powerful position to have in the
south to be the president of that
convention.
Uh,
and uh,
so I was talking to him,
he was a long time ago and they have a
lot of disagreement.
He kind of had a nervous breakdown and
he showed up at my grandmother's
birthday party and he had a,
uh,
riding a harley with no shirt on.
And then he went down.
He taught Gus Gospel according to
Charlie for a while.
But,
uh,
this is what he took because we were
just talking about this exact thing.
He goes,
he goes to that well,
run a,
here's what I believe.
I believe that when we die,
we're going to be surprised.
That's all he's got.
That's all you got after all these
books,
all these years of Vietnam,
that's all he's got his fucking gun.
When I was young,
I was real dismissive of religion
because I was real religious at one
point when I was real young.
I went to Catholic school and um,
that was really,
it was a,
it was a good experience because it was
a bad experience.
So I realized that these are like these
mean flawed people that are teaching
what they think is supposedly God's
word.
And I became like a very anti religious
person for a long time where I thought
of religion as being like an ideology
that controls your brain.
But as I've gotten older,
one of the things that I've been
thinking more and more is that although
the Bible's definitely been altered by a
bunch of different people,
there's a difference between the Old
Testament in the new testament and even
the translations of the Old Testament.
They were trying to say something.
They would try.
They wrote this fucking thing down and
passed it down more than anything else.
Like the Bible's almost like the story
of life because if you go that far back,
there's no other stories.
You go far
back in the old testament stories.
There are no,
there are no books.
You have to go to other cultures that
had similar stories.
Right?
And that there were all the same thing
like the epic of Gilgamesh.
So similar to like know when the art is,
all these cool,
but you know,
they've got all these similarities were
trying to tell us about something,
right?
And most of it was be a good person,
you know,
I mean,
that was Christ message.
I grew up in the watching my uncle
preach.
And so when I was a kid,
I loved church.
I mean,
I loved it,
loved it.
I love to go watch him preach.
I'd go watch him preach on Sunday,
Sunday night and go watch him preach on
Wednesday and a charismatic,
funny,
uh,
and uh,
just,
uh,
and he comes from nowhere.
His mother was a hooker and uh,
but,
uh,
all of the self made man.
And uh,
so I loved it.
And then we moved and I went to a
regular Baptist church and I was like,
this fucking get me out of this
motherfucker now where's the youth
group?
He used to have these youth groups that
were more fun than I've had anywhere
else.
We had went on a choir tour where we had
raised money for it,
own pins or whatever the fuck it was.
And then we all piled on a shitty bus
and took off saying it in churches.
And uh,
and it was a,
it was freedom.
It was total freedom because I could
buy,
I could eat whatever I wanted.
I had $3 and fifty cents at 13 years
old,
12,
13 years old,
11 maybe to spend in any restaurant I
wanted.
I could get whatever I wanted.
So every meal,
Chilean French fries,
that's all I want,
baby.
You just go bring me the Chili and the
fucking French fries and pile them up
right here.
But,
uh,
so that's.
But once I found out that it's,
you know,
there are these really great orators and
there some really terrible,
horrible.
It's like comic books or as actors,
you know,
all the above this.
There's always a bunch of that know he
made no bones about attitude that did
it.
If somebody was coming in to look at him
to preach at a bigger place,
he would pull stuff out of is a
repertoire,
you know,
because he knows that he's got a killer
45 months in particular that borders
with and he didn't make any bones about
that to me.
He goes,
yeah,
they're coming in to watch me.
So I want to.
I wanted to do my last story or
whatever.
Which is great.
You know,
and uh,
but uh,
well Mike,
you were talking about with your
material that it takes like three years
to really ripen and I'm sure they'll
come up with a new show
every fuck and Sunday and then you
couldn't do the same thing Sunday night
or the same thing Wednesday night
because you had people like me with
every show.
It's a lot of jazz improvisation.
Yeah.
Lot of re we're recalling facts.
It's kind of like a,
like Dr Phil is because Dr Phil does
three of those shows that day with no
script has no idea what he's saying,
walking into it.
No idea what's going to happen when he
walks into it and I've got to tell you
right now,
nobody else could do it.
You can do it.
I dare you not do it.
I couldn't do it.
You don't have many days a week or a
month.
I'm actually interesting.
Like for the rest of them,
I'm me.
I'm getting a dial tone the rest of the
time I'm getting a dial tone.
I'm telling you.
But uh,
but,
but doc,
I mean just a three hour long shows that
day when those scripts all day long.
No one.
Yes.
You do it just like this.
Like you're doing it right now.
Yeah.
There's no.
There's no reason why we can't get them
introduced to your conversation.
You're not no fucking way.
That's the weed,
the weeds fucking with you.
You've been telling some amazing
stories.
How dare you,
you could do it.
He was like,
there's no reason why somebody figured
out that Dr Phil can do it.
He can do it.
He did it.
He's doing it.
He's currently doing it.
Somebody figured out that he can
improvise about health and all.
You could do what you're doing right now
all day,
every day,
whenever you want to do,
don't need any help.
I don't need to fucking Shitload of
hell.
I know,
but if you're going to,
you're going to still make it home
either way.
You know,
these are tough conversations,
right?
There's to be banter,
banter.
You fucking hilarious.
I dare you.
You know what?
I got offered a t o a radio job one time
when I was a,
uh,
it,
it was probably for twice what I was
making as a standup comic and it was
with Eddie fingers in Cincinnati and uh,
uh,
and I was really 125,000
bucks and a bunch of cash to me at the
time.
The right the pilot boat boat,
you know,
Mr.
that's the thing about money.
Is that why you think that the rich
people have twice as much money as you,
but they know they have a thousand times
you really was.
So when 25,
but anyway,
but what I realized was that they saw me
come in once a year and a in murder on
their radio show,
but getting that out of me every day.
There's no way Ron black five days a
week where we differ.
We have a problem here because I have
fucking hang out with you all the time.
Now at the comedy store.
How many times we drank together?
A dozen.
At least.
Maybe two dozen every fucking time.
It's been this.
It's been awesome.
Oh well,
but know I'm just saying don't count on
it.
Possibly count on you not being,
you know,
that doesn't make any sense at all.
He went up to that joint.
Oh,
we got another one man.
Oh fuck that one.
That one's gone.
Oh No,
no,
no.
Thanks.
This is important.
We're already struggling with reality,
right?
So let's get things notice.
Notice you're the one carrying the
conversation.
Like what the fuck you telling like 10
epics stories,
Dermott Rowan warrant.
Why is it,
that's something I don't mind to make
you embarrassed,
but why is it,
it's something that all the great comics
have was this like a ridiculous humility
and a lot of ways,
you know,
almost everybody had a conversation with
Dave chappelle once Dave Chappelle and I
were talking and we're,
uh,
we went to this fucking Hollywood party
was a dba,
but the hills,
it was Naomi Campbell's birthday party.
This was a 50 foot tall naked photo of
Naomi Campbell.
We had to go to a place and we had a
park and then from where we parked,
we had to get on a bus that took us to
this fucking house.
This house is ridiculous.
And uh,
I get up there with Dave and I was like,
it was so many,
so weird.
It's like Demi Moore was there and Lenny
Kravitz was there and all these famous
people were there.
I saw like a ton of famous people and
I'm like,
dude,
this is so weird.
There's like this gathering of famous
people I get.
This is so strange.
It was,
yeah,
man,
I wouldn't ever be one of those.
I don't want to be one of those.
I go,
what are you talking about?
The most famous person in this fucking
room.
And he looked at me like,
what?
And I go,
dude,
you're the most.
We're,
we're both body ached and we were beyond
high,
were beyond high and we're hanging out
at this famous probably go,
dude,
you're the most famous person here.
He goes,
Joe stopped lying to me,
man.
No doubt you're the most famous person
here.
I was playing the Denver and he was
working at the,
it was working out stuff.
It's a d at the comedy works in Denver,
which is one of the best comedy clubs in
the country.
One of the best and a,
the ice house.
He was,
uh,
he,
you know,
he was in there all week,
doing science and uh,
so he,
uh,
he called and I,
I,
I paid to see him in,
uh,
in Santa Barbara like a year and a half
ago.
We were walking down the street and it
was for sale.
We walked up there even though he was
there.
Oh Wow.
I just have paid,
me and my wife were paid,
walked in,
sat down,
and just how,
I mean he,
he's a ca.
What kind of like you in a way and that
he'll walk out on some pretty thin limbs
and just jump on him and uh,
and has a punchline to back it up with
him.
That was,
I was real,
real impressed.
And then he called me when I was in
Denver and said,
would you come out and do a segue
because I was coming in today,
early in,
in front of me and uh,
and I'm like,
oh,
fuck yeah,
I'd love to.
And uh,
so.
But anyway,
after his set here one night,
I hear it like we're at the comedy
store,
the comedy store.
I was leaving and uh,
I was walking up to my car and he's got
a bunch of people in a big old,
huge suv.
And he goes,
Ron,
white,
you're coming with us now.
I got to go up.
No you don't.
No,
you don't.
You're coming with us.
You have to come with us,
you are coming with us tonight,
get in this car.
And I'm like,
okay.
So we went to some club,
couldn't tell you where it was.
I mean,
I,
you know,
not that far downtown somewhere,
but really no door,
no name,
you know,
just to get through it.
And,
and what it,
what we did is we went out and we saw
how much fun it was to be Dave fucking
Chappelle,
you know,
that the,
I go to the comedy store because I'm
famous when I'm there,
you know,
it's,
I'm not famous everywhere.
He's failed,
was everywhere.
And uh,
and he's also,
you know,
fun about it.
Some people mean he'll go engage every
table and talk to him.
I mean,
he's the,
he's not,
you know,
see if that can be a comedian.
Oh,
get away,
get away with now.
He's a great guy.
He's,
he's a,
he's a weirdly great guy.
Always has been to,
I think I met David.
He was like 18 or something.
He was always like,
just a super nice guy.
Just always been very genuine,
you know?
And in the amazing pressure that you
face and being I in a lot of ways,
the voice of a comedic generation when
he was doing chappelle show,
it was sort of the defining show of that
generation,
but it's really no parallel.
He does like what two seasons did he do
two seasons seasons and then he had a
$50 million dollar contract and then he
showed up in Africa or something.
I don't know exactly what happened,
but had some of the best sketches ever.
That one,
the blind guy who didn't know that he
was black and he was a white
supremacist.
Holy Shit.
I mean he was in the KKK and he didn't
know that he was black because he was
blind.
He doesn't.
One of the funniest bits the fucking
universe has ever seen.
He did.
He did it for two years and it sorta
when,
when they tried to change his show and
he just walked away,
it's sort of like,
you know what?
I don't know anybody tried to change his
show at.
I know they did.
You do?
Okay then.
But what I,
you know,
that he couldn't go into stand up
because they wouldn't leave them alone,
you know,
we couldn't start going because right
then he was ripe to play every major,
whatever,
whatever he wanted to sell,
he could sell it,
still can.
And uh,
but they would rick,
James,
Bitch,
they would just scream at him the whole
time and it,
and I can only imagine how frustrating
that would be.
And uh,
but,
uh,
that happened for a little while.
Yeah.
Now it's security heavy.
I mean,
if you want to get thrown out of his
show,
there's a good chance you will because
there's a bunch of big guys walking
around and then they're,
you know,
they try to stay pretty low.
But if you're,
if you think it's gonna be about you and
Chappelle exchanging pleasantries,
urop,
you're going to be shut up and then
found out and set.
But,
and I,
I get it,
I'll have somebody throwing out on one
of my shows and in two seconds,
yeah,
they think you just have to.
Oh,
I,
I saw Christa,
Leah's instagramming instagram the day.
And there was some,
a couple that was leaving and apparently
they were just really rude to him during
the show and they were yelling out,
you're a loser and all this shit.
And he and he,
you know,
is so silly.
He's on.
Chris is so silly.
He's on stage.
He's like,
you fucking idiots.
Like,
you know,
he's laughing about it.
He's like,
one more thing,
one more thing by you fucking idiots.
And the whole crowd starts cheering and
it's,
it's so ridiculous.
But this a couple.
Apparently they just wouldn't stop
heckling him.
They wouldn't stop calling him a loser,
like managing pain and go see somebody
and then calling him a loser.
Like,
like,
what the fuck?
Like,
what happened?
What happened?
Where's,
who needs a hug?
Who needs a hug first?
I got a pretty good.
I got it.
Pretty zero tolerance policy.
I mean,
because I'm not going to banter with you
at all.
I'm going to ask you to shut up.
And if you don't do that then I'm going
to tell you this.
Things have been set in motion that I
cannot stop because you didn't listen to
what I said last time and I can't
because if I do that somebody is already
walking over and they're going to get
thrown out.
I'm talking about some fucking mortal
Kombat.
Goddamn.
Yeah.
Oh,
some people see this.
There's a lot of different kinds of
people,
folks.
Some of them just don't get it.
They just.
They're just too frustrating to interact
with.
They just want to make it about them and
scream out interruptive show for
whatever reason,
and it's not their fault.
Maybe it's the way they were raised.
Maybe it's the fucking genetics.
They were handed down.
Don't go to the theater a lot.
There's a lot of things.
They might be drunk.
They might be fucked up.
They might have anxiety.
Who knows?
I think sometimes they think it helped
you know that to give the comedian
something to do,
you know,
to.
I think they think it helps.
I don't think they're trying to stump
the comic most of the time because me or
you
handling a hacker hacked hillary.
There's like a.
it's like playing ping pong with a
chicken.
It's so fucking easy,
you know,
it's just.
But I just don't want to do it.
I don't want to spend any time doing it.
I spent all my time entertaining these
other bunch of people.
I agree.
But occasionally I will.
I will open to the fact that this is a
weird exchange between a comedian and an
audience.
So weird exchange.
And occasionally people say Shit,
that's fucking funny.
You know,
it is unfortunately,
should be,
I should be more like that.
And I'm not,
I'm not.
I'm so.
I'm so fucking humorless.
And uh,
because,
because I,
you know,
I bounced,
laughs off the laugh.
So that's what I'd do.
I'd pace rhythm,
timing,
boom,
boom.
So I'm going to start you here.
I'm going to dribble you to be slamming
you,
but if you stopped,
I gotta go.
Okay.
Fuck you're right.
And I'm going to start dribbling down
here,
but I'll get there quick.
But I mean that just so it,
I,
it always makes me mad and it shouldn't
make me mad.
That shouldn't be the reaction,
but it does,
it makes me mad.
It makes me mad because I,
I have what I want.
Right.
And you're fucking it up.
And uh,
that definitely does happen.
That happens too.
I just think every now and then someone
says some funny shit.
You're right.
I should,
I should like the fuck up.
I'm a fucking comedian.
One joke is,
is one time one of the best hackles
ever.
It was in New Jersey.
I was doing a theater in Jersey and I
had this one joke,
we're about a Kim Kardashian meeting the
aliens.
And I'm like,
well,
who do you think is the most famous
woman in the world?
And this guy goes,
your mother and is the way said it was
perfect timing.
Or maybe he might've said,
your mom,
your mom.
I think you said your mom was like,
this is fucking hilarious.
Your mind anytime you can say your mom,
was he wrong?
That's funny.
I mean that's 80 percent of the banter
that already should fear and I have with
each other.
Was it your mom that sucked all those
dicks?
No.
Okay.
The guy never handled again.
It was the one hackle in one show where
it's like,
perfect.
He went in like a Ninja.
He dropped a nuclear bomb.
Boom.
Your mom and gotta laugh.
You gotta laugh
now.
Did you tell him that?
Don't try it again.
The admitted.
It was really funny.
Whenever you can say that,
that's fucking.
I want to get why I can't do that,
but I sure can't.
It just makes me,
it just pisses me off sometimes.
I agree.
I'm not a heckler supporter,
but I'm not.
I'm just saying just like this is what a
live show is really some weird
interaction.
Right?
And I think people like to know that
you're right there.
Well,
when I'd been doing standup for for six
years and I was headlining comedy clubs,
I prayed to God,
somebody would heckle me because I
couldn't get to 45 minutes without it.
So,
you know,
I needed to about four or five minutes
of Jabber and I asked him how he sees
where they're from and,
and,
and uh,
which is pure third grade comedy and uh,
and I'm clearly a fourth grader.
How long is it before someone does a
Hologram show where you go to a theater
and the holograms are so good that it
looks like it's already there,
but you are running on another side of
the planet,
right?
It's already there.
Do you think so?
Yeah.
They are.
It's unbidden Bev on,
uh,
how to,
whatever rodeo drive.
There's a company over there on Rodeo
drive that are doing the most amazing.
The thing is it's still needs to evolve,
right?
You know,
it's a,
like these,
um,
well anyway,
it still needs to evolve.
See
when they did it on CNN,
when used,
they used it for the elections one year
they had like Wolf Blitzer in the
Hologram.
Right.
Do you remember that Jamie?
What was that about?
They tried that one time and then like
this is freaking people the fuck out.
Like what do we star wars?
What is he going to be map now?
That's what the fuck is wolf blitzer do
it in a hologram.
Can you just put a camera on them?
Wherever the fuck he is.
Why do you have to show me a Hologram?
Like what's going on here?
People just read right?
Well,
but it's now they just can't do it for
as long as they want to.
So without it costing a gillion dollar.
So they eventually,
you can do it on your fucking phone.
You can project an image of something
you're thinking right there in front of
you.
Look at this woman,
she's glowing.
She's like,
help me Obi wan.
You're my only hope is my pussy CNNS
Jessica Yellen via Hologram from
Chicago.
It's a really fucking cool looking
Hologram,
but she's got a.
didn't even know we were watching
something about holograms.
I thought you were talking to me.
You're watching television.
Look at it.
It's right there.
That's that woman.
That was the one.
They did it on CNN where they had her,
uh,
as a,
this was a during the Mccain Obama.
Oh Wow.
And she's a Hologram.
He did this on CNN.
She's glowing like the applicant.
This is so freaky.
This is so like Saifai,
like I think America is like,
no,
no more of this.
You know what else it is.
It's really bad radio because though
nobody can see it.
Yeah.
But there's a lot of people watching on
youtube too.
We'll tell them,
okay,
this is also on.
What are we going to tell Cnns Jessica
yelling via Hologram.
Just Google that and you can watch this
video.
CNN hologram first is a video we're
watching and you can play that,
record it and play it while you're
listening to Joe and as Banter,
let's just tell me what.
Tell me what you're seeing.
Does it freak you out?
I see this person with this blue glow
around them.
Like there's some fucking alien.
What are they preparing us for?
Like money to me.
I don't want to go straight to Alex
Jones here,
but I would say that looks crazy.
Yeah.
How long before people started doing
standup like that where the audience
will heckle but it won't work because
you're not really there.
So it only works if everybody shut the
fuck up.
Just keep on moving us through.
Sometimes I feel like that.
Well what they'll do is they'll film you
doing us set somewhere in front of a
crowd with this hologram thing,
projecting it.
So there'll be.
You'll do a live show,
but the live show is only going to be,
it'll be something that you can,
maybe I could be in your living room at
some point that I,
for a limited amount of
dates.
No,
still can if you have a lot of money.
But eventually,
I mean,
I'm just saying,
where does it stop?
Where does it stop?
If you can do that right there,
then eventually you will be able to do
it on a small scale.
And uh,
uh,
you know,
I,
my drone
is a drone now that will follow you and
take pictures of you or have you seen
that?
It's like it floats,
floats above you and films,
films,
pictures of you.
So you didn't like film stuff?
I have one.
You have one of those,
what do you do with it?
Well,
lately,
now that I live at the montage in
Beverly Hills,
I,
I flied down beverly drive and uh,
and take a,
just take footage of it and turn it
around snapshots and show up.
But the thing is I used to live off of
canyon,
right?
So if it crashed,
it was just going to go into the canyon.
Now it goes into some kids had been
fucking falls out of the sky,
right.
Fall never.
But I still can't keep from thinking
about it every once in awhile that it is
fucking weird.
You can just have a robot always
looking.
You can go right over to the Beverly
Wilshire and just park it right in any
window you want.
And if those curtains are open and you
want to watch those people,
fuck they're going to get pissed when
they see that Guy Dale drone.
But you know,
they don't know who's flying it.
Oh,
what are we doing?
And it goes 80 miles an hour so it will
fall out of the sky here in a second.
It's going to fall out of the sky or the
new Gopro Jones a couple of weeks ago.
Oh Shit.
They were over at baseball field and it
just took a nosedive.
Didn't hit anybody,
but he didn't follow up.
Don't really drive later on during the
Christmas season.
Oh my God,
that's crazy.
Just happened.
So that thing just fell out of this guy.
Did you see the one where the um,
the guy that looks like bullshit to me,
I just happened.
I'm pretty sure this looks like bullshit
though.
This pose looks like bull shit.
Maybe I'm just too quick to call
bullshit.
But did you see that one where there was
a guy that was on the ski slopes and he
was in some sort of Olympic competition
or something and the drone fell behind
him,
like right behind him,
like
barely mentioned was a big drone.
Big Drum with a movie camera on.
Or here it is,
is this guy's skin?
What is this competition,
Jamie?
The Olympics are so shit.
And look at that.
So he never saw it but it fell right
behind the Mike.
Wait,
this is crazy.
I would've killed him.
It probably would have fucked him up,
man.
Look at this with this thing and you've
seen it in high speed.
Whoa.
First of all,
look at that watch.
Boom.
Right behind them.
And it looks like it's hard to tell.
We got back to them,
but it looks like just to get to about a
billion pieces that would have fucking
hurt,
like hell that hit him.
Yeah.
He can't do that.
I'm going to quit flat it over beverly
drive.
I can tell him my gut when I'm doing
something that if I shouldn't be doing
it,
you know,
I got really do have a little signal
inside of me that goes and that I rarely
listened to it.
I rarely do.
And,
but yeah,
I think
I probably got to quit.
Fly The drone up and down Rodeo drive
when I came here.
Even see it.
You definitely don't have that robot
monster flying in the sky,
dropping on people's heads up.
That thing.
I took it to a.
we're actually a place where sturges is,
uh,
the bike thing.
Yeah.
Where is that a?
Anyway,
there's a little town up there.
A little casino town were deadwood.
Uh,
is uh,
it,
it was,
I think it is dead wood.
How do I not know where?
Sturgis's where is it?
It's in Idaho,
Dakota,
South Dakota,
right.
People in Idaho.
We're not fucking South Dakota pro.
Yeah.
So it's like a,
that sturgis the big motorcycle thing,
right?
Where everybody gets together and they
just,
I mean,
there's a million things,
a million people.
This is it.
That is insane.
See how beautiful this little charming
little streets been like this except for
the pavement for 1785.
Holy Shit.
It's always been intact because it's
always been a town that always made
money and doing something.
So a big gold town.
But so it's all in tact.
So this is all going uphill where he's
going right now and uh,
and it keeps going up hill for way.
And then back up to the left is way up a
hill is the hotel where I'm at.
So I'm going to take my drone and I
wanted to shoot.
I want to go down that strip and chute
that street,
you know,
just from one end to the other.
And I had a spare battery in my pocket.
And so I took it out front and I took it
off from there and I just kind of walked
it over like I was flying a kite and I
get up there and uh,
and I send it down the street,
I just flat down there just for a
practice run and it's,
you know,
almost a mile,
uh,
and then red flat back up and,
and,
uh,
and then a flat back down there and get
in while it's flying a this really good
looking girl goes,
oh,
you're the one with the drone scaring
everybody.
And I said,
the kids love it.
Then I looked back around and it wasn't
there,
the drone was gone.
And uh,
and then,
uh,
I start running down that hill.
I mean,
just kind of walking fast,
going where is it?
And then I,
uh,
and then I send it up,
you know,
because you get it up,
but,
you know,
go straight up until you can see it.
And it wasn't,
that wouldn't happen.
I was walking down and then I looked.
And once the battery is so low,
it takes,
it just takes over itself and takes us
back to where you started from it.
It says,
you know,
take him back to the home base,
which is right in front of that really
busy hotel.
It's going to come into my little drones
going to come drop it in.
So I got to just have.
And I'm a downhill guy.
I'm not an uphill guy.
And I see the drones flying over my head
towards hotel.
I can't stop it.
I'm totally out of control and I'm just,
uh Huh.
I can't.
I mean,
I can't stop.
I got to get there.
I got to beat the fucking thing to the,
to the,
to the fucking hotel.
And I don't,
but it doesn't matter because it goes
down about an hour,
you know,
just comes in and really slow and just
lands.
And uh,
so I'm like bent over holding a chair.
Just,
uh,
I mean,
this is,
this is out of breath as I've ever been
in my life.
Just,
uh,
and uh,
this guy goes,
he's anyway,
I could get a picture of me while I'm
dying.
Is that what?
So those are their drones that can
navigate around trees and things.
These won't hit a wall if come near.
Yeah,
it'll,
if you have that.
What are we doing?
Ron White,
why the fuck are we allowing these
flying robots to be?
Was that big
case in Texas?
My son was telling me about it where
this guy was a flu is drone into another
guy's yard and he shot it with a shotgun
and he's like,
well,
you're filming my family.
And um,
and so now it's,
you know,
who's at fault.
He didn't own that airspace.
I may send,
seems like you don't,
a foot or two of it,
right,
of your own airspace.
Totally new dilemma.
And it's one more piece of technology
that brings us like weirdly more
connected,
some sort of strange,
almost forced way.
Like now we thought the only way to get
around was essentially by being on foot.
So you can put up a fence.
But now if you can fly in three d space,
well,
um,
where am I allowed to go?
Where am I not allowed to go?
Right?
I owe you allowed to fly over anybody's
house.
How does that work?
And as technology gets closer and closer
and closer and closer to whatever the
fuck the singularity is,
we're going to probably physically be
able to do that.
See what?
Right?
Right now,
we can't physically fly around.
It's too difficult to have some sort of
a jet pack
situation.
Listen,
those empty promises rang hollow years
ago.
The jet packs
they did,
but as technology improves,
there's a possibility,
there's a possibility within our
lifetime,
have some,
some sort of propulsion system that
works on some sort of a vast that you
would wear.
It's totally yours.
All you gotta do to see what's gonna
happen the next hundred years is look at
the last hundred years.
And,
and uh,
and that kind of momentum is going to
continue straight on until this,
it looks like an antique.
Why did they ever do it this way?
One hundred percent.
Everything we're doing is stupid.
Everything.
So Ron gotten a car and drove and they
did what they meant,
you know,
I don't know what it's going to be,
but yeah man,
these,
this is like the
strangest times ever.
I really feel like every day it feels so
strange like the,
the,
the fact that Donald Trump is really the
president.
Like,
that feels so strange.
Yeah.
You know,
I,
I didn't,
I didn't vote for the president elect
and uh,
uh,
but I did get my tax estimates two days
ago and when I looked at it,
I was like,
go trump now.
I don't mean to say that I agree with
anything he's ever said to live,
but,
you know,
I don't know how these,
how these really risk either getting
away with paying three percent and I
play paid 34 percent tax on this money
and,
and uh,
you know,
then,
well,
he did get elected.
So,
you know,
I am going to get the benefits of those
tax breaks.
I wouldn't trade my country for it,
but I'll take them.
It's just fascinating because he's the
first truly famous,
like super famous guy who ran for
president and one,
no Reagan,
I don't think Reagan can fuck trump and
the super famous to park on Reagan with
a movie star Dude.
There was a movie star and back when
they had televisions that when I was,
that was
six or whatever it was.
I don't remember.
I don't remember
that was either,
but I remember I was not good with
numbers.
It definitely wasn't voting age during
their deed administration.
I think Reagan was as big a star as
trump.
Is that apprentice celebrity apprentice
show that was a big world
wide?
No.
Worldwide.
No,
but us wise,
yes,
I am absolutely every bit as famous and
uh,
and,
and so it was a source of anger,
swartz for short of sorts and ran for
president.
He was allowed to.
He's not allowed to because he's born in
Austria.
He'd went fucking when I think it went,
I think,
I think if trump can win for short
swartz Nigger,
and I think he does.
Todd is very important,
uh,
that,
that I think changed the lives of a lot
of people.
You can unfuck the babysitter can do it.
You can't have a babysitter,
you can't.
It is what it Adele fuck the babysitter
is what it is.
Look what can happen,
but people still love them.
They know what he is.
He's a,
you know,
that's all he,
he,
he smokes cigars at this place where I
smoke cigars sometimes as I'm walking
out of a building.
I said,
hey governor,
he didn't say anything
when you still call him governor.
I mean,
I would call them whatever you want,
sir.
I met him once.
I think I probably called him brother.
Everybody brother.
Right.
But uh,
he was super cool.
I met him at the,
uh,
UFC.
I was like,
I'm shaking his hand.
I'm like,
God damn shaking hands with
motherfucking sports negar.
It's one of those weird ones.
Yeah.
Certain people you meet and you go,
whoa.
Certain people you meet and you're like,
hey man,
what's up?
Nice to meet you.
And other people you meet and like,
I can't fucking believe I'm meeting
Sylvester Stallone.
It's just weird,
you know.
Right.
Jack Nicholas or Jack Nicholson rather.
Either one.
One of them's dead,
right?
The Golfer died.
Denise.
Nicholas.
Yeah.
He died.
Jack Nicholas.
Yeah.
But Jack,
Jack Nicklaus.
Arnold Palmer died.
Oh,
that's right.
Sorry.
I'm so sorry everybody,
if you're listening,
Jack Nicholson though the actor,
like if you met and he's alive.
He is alive to all these people are
alive.
Josef.
And that's what I'm saying.
I knew somebody died,
configured which golfer it was.
But I'm like,
that's one you,
if you meet Jack Nicholson,
you gonna Freak out a little bit like
you have to.
He uh,
he,
yeah,
he played
through our group at Bel Air one time I
was playing and go doc.
And uh,
him and Joe Pesci played through our
group.
What was that like?
You know,
what they,
they,
you know,
they just,
they just played through our group who
was a par three that uh,
I played the course a lot with doc and
uh,
and then,
but they were,
they turned around,
you know,
they both gave you the movie star Look,
and uh,
you know,
it wasn't much,
but it was definitely a to really,
really,
really cool famous people,
you know.
So it's,
it's not often I spazz out at,
uh,
about meeting somebody,
but I was in the,
I was the,
the grand marshal at the Talladega and
Margo saying their national anthem.
So we were like the king and queen of
the Talladega speedway that weekend and
they were filming a talented and the ice
was about to come out and Pharaoh was
there and uh,
we went to this dinner was a buffet,
but by all these famous chefs supposed
to be really,
really nice and he was in line and I
just started walking towards him.
I had nothing to say.
I had no plan I had.
And then I just stopped myself and Ron,
would you go sit down?
Jesus Christ?
But I'm such a huge fan of
and I mean,
I,
you know,
I might know some other famous people in
it,
but you know,
feral,
you know,
is a,
that's a,
that's a big deal.
And you know,
who else I,
every time I'm around him,
I know it.
I've been around him several times and
is a Dan Akroyd and every time I'm
around Dan I say something completely
fucking stupid because I'm just a
gigantic.
I mean I've,
I couldn't even tell you how big an
ackroyd fan I am.
He's going to be that socking blues
brothers.
He's,
well he's Dan Akroyd and come on right
now and,
and,
but,
but that was when I was stopped.
We were stopping parties to play this
stuff,
you know,
so easily.
Anyway,
stop in parts.
So he's an I.
Yeah,
there'll be a party going on Saturday
night.
It was stop it and turn it on Saturday
night live and watch a Belushi and Bill
Murray and,
and a holiday.
Anyway,
it was amazing.
And,
but every time I'm around him,
I always say something just.
I mean,
I know I haven't had,
it's just like the most unimpressive I
could possibly fucking be.
And uh,
I'm a,
I'm a comic and he's like,
yeah,
you told me that last time.
Be Like,
oh,
come on,
give me something.
There's this fucking interview that they
did recently with Jerry Lewis.
It is hilarious.
Have you seen Jamie?
Apparently the annoyed the fuck out of
him,
right?
Like Jerry Lewis in his nineties and
they were in a bunch of people that are
in their nineties.
It's still work and they interviewed
Jerry Lewis and I guess they had annoyed
him so bad and bringing in a bunch of
assistants and lights and cameras and
shit.
So Jerry Lewis gave them like one word
answers.
Yes.
No,
it didn't play out with these people.
And the guy starts a weird nat will play
a little bit over here.
You can see what is it?
The Hollywood reporter?
Is that WHO's doing it?
Is it going to come in through my
headphones?
Yeah.
You'll hear it through your headphones.
This,
it's,
it's fucking hilarious,
man.
Seven painfully awkward minutes with
Jerry Lewis.
People were still working in their
night.
Have you ever thought about retiring?
Why was there never a moment that you
thought it might be time to retire?
You would want to come from?
I come from a generation and a little
older and I think of Bob Hope.
George Burns Sinatra.
Fuck,
love there.
Do you see similarities with them?
None.
What do you think drives people like you
and then to want to keep working because
we do it well.
And how about um,
what,
um,
what's different about performing now
for you than say 20 years ago?
How is it,
how is it different for you?
Not,
not at all.
Not at all.
I kind of see his point.
I see both of them.
No,
but he's pointing to Jerry's point.
This guy's asking ridiculously stupid
questions to one of the most famous
comedians are convenient for certainly
the best comedic actor,
one of the best comedic actors that ever
lived.
And he said,
why aren't you more like your dead
friends?
Oh,
well,
because I'm not fucking dead.
Yeah.
I think.
I think with a guy like that,
if you're going to have a conversation
with them,
it's going to have to be like in a
podcast form and it's going to have to
be with someone who really respects,
you know,
someone who's going to have a
conversation that at this point in his
life,
after all the movies and all the stuff
that guy's done,
he probably doesn't want.
He doesn't want to deal with any
bullshit anymore.
You know,
it seems like to him it was like,
this is stupid.
What the fuck am I doing?
Why am I doing?
Feels uninspired.
You know,
what I did the other day,
this was the worst decision I ever made.
Not the worst,
but it be really bad when mother,
my mom's in town and we're staying at
the montage because the house got
destroyed.
And,
and,
uh,
and I'm like,
well,
what do you want to do?
He goes,
well,
I've never been to the labrea tar pits
and uh,
and like,
well,
that's Kinda like a puddle of mud.
Uh,
with that.
Well,
I'd like to go on one of those tour
buses and uh,
I'm like,
all right,
well I'll take you on one of those tour
buses,
take you in.
So we go on the TMZ bus cause I saw the
TMZ is the big double decker things,
but that's not their bus.
They advertised for TMZ on the side of
those buses,
but their buses are little buses and
they have a big bunch of television
screens and they just blast all this
footage of uh,
of the.
I mean everywhere you go.
What happened in there?
Every time Paris Hilton was on there
show your real fucking loud.
Really,
really,
really annoying.
And I was like Mama,
I because we thought we were going to be
really passive,
you know,
like,
and that's where Jerry Lewis live for 45
years.
And right there is where there's George
Carlin with the house and there,
you know.
But no,
it was in your face loud.
He was like,
you were just forced to watch an episode
to TMZ and they,
somebody tied you to a fucking chair and
wouldn't let you go and just turned it
the fuck up.
That's how fucking annoying it was.
And it just horrible,
horrible,
horrible.
And uh,
so at one point in the tour they said,
we'll be passing the montage hotel.
And I'm like,
Hey,
let's get off mom and she would get out
of here.
So we scooted off.
But it was,
it was nightmare.
She was.
And I liked those guys at TMZ when
they're friends of mine.
But,
uh,
would you please fucking turn it down?
My mother brought,
my mother,
brought my mom.
I feel bad for the guy that was asking
the questions to Jerry Lewis too because
he probably thought he would get to have
a nice,
friendly conversation with a legend.
Probably totally intimidated.
He's in Jerry Lewis's house having a
conversation with them and he,
it,
it's going to that one answer.
One word answer place.
No.
Why?
You know that that was when he starts
doing that.
It's like you're in verbal combat,
but listen to what the questions were,
questions guys,
90 years old,
he's talking about why aren't you more
like dead?
I agree.
That's what do you.
How do you answer that question?
It was a poorly designed conversation,
horrible,
horribly designed conversation and it
was obviously that's how Jerry Lewis
felt and,
and you could tell the guy who was
asking a question,
it was kind of,
you know,
it was treading on water,
is trying to figure out how to get the
fuck through this while he's talking,
living in and figure it out.
No,
he didn't.
He didn't figure it out.
He thought he should have met.
Well,
he probably meant well and just ran into
everything.
Preparedness.
Unpreparedness.
Yeah.
It's just,
that's a weird Gig to the,
the,
the ability to ad Lib and ask questions
to some living legend like Jerry Lewis
and just not realize while you're doing
it in your narrative that you set up in
your head as probably disrespectful to
him because he's,
you're comparing him to all these dead
people,
so why are you still working?
Why you're essentially saying that.
Catch that.
Abby that catch that,
it's got to be fucking why?
You almost have to wonder why he decided
to do it.
I guess it's just the Hollywood
reporter.
Right?
It's a big deal,
you know?
Yeah.
I Dunno.
I mean,
you know,
I don't know that maybe.
Does he still sell tickets?
I don't know that he works.
Does he?
Does.
I think that's what the guy was talking
about.
See if Jerry Lewis still has standup
shows.
I think he had just got done.
Fuck,
I'd pay.
I'd pay to go see that.
Fuck.
Yeah.
That's uh,
that's,
you know,
I was bill,
Bill Burr and I had talked about going
to see bill cosby before the scandal
broke,
like,
and we had talked about going and either
one of us flaked,
I don't remember what happened,
but bill wound up going when he was
somewhere in California,
we're going to make a separate trip to
vegas just to see a bill cosby and
burst.
Said he was fucking amazing.
And then the scandal broke afterwards.
This touring stopped and they're like,
we just became a totally different
thing.
You know,
we have that VIP company that we
promoted,
we do other people's be api stuff
besides my head,
we do other peoples and we had just had
cosby this stuff breaks and he wouldn't
be the perfect client for it because he,
you know,
he's looking for trim anyway,
after the show.
So he was going to want to hang and so
it would've been a great.
Probably would have been our best client
and Aa still solved a lot of tickets
after that.
Look at this and even with Jerry Lewis,
Saturday,
November twelfth,
2016.
So real recent.
The last shot could find listed.
Wow.
That's a really recent chair of it.
Where was that international film
festival?
That was probably him talking about,
which still would be fascinating.
Yeah,
that would be fascinating.
But I'm pretty sure he does stand up.
I'm pretty sure Jerry Lewis still does
some sort of a standup show.
I think he had to show it.
Said that at the South Point and Vegas.
Yeah.
I didn't have any recent shows listed or
any.
Oh,
when?
When was the last show?
There was a article from September,
so have some shows at the end of the
pretty recently.
Yeah.
So within the last year he's still
working.
Ooh.
Yeah,
that's crazy.
Crazy.
I mean if you go back and watch like the
nutty professor like we were talking
about and how that influence dice,
you know,
if you go back and watch that and just
realize there had been nothing before
this,
you know,
like it was Charlie Chapman and there's
a few chaplain wouldn't say,
Oh my God,
I'm an idiot.
Don't listen to me.
I'll stop now.
But three stooges,
you know,
there was some fucking great shit,
but God damn man,
those,
those guys were like real pioneers
account.
How many decades ahead,
movie comedy been around back when Jerry
Lewis was doing those movies?
Well,
you know,
it's,
you can look at it.
Here's the thing,
the,
uh,
some comics build bridges and most
comics walk across those bridges after
they've already been built and it's
substantially and set in stone.
So Louis certainly built a bridge that
Jim Carrey walked across in Ballerina
shoes and he knows it in and uh,
uh,
but because that extraordinary,
a comedic talent that comes out of those
two people are view,
so identifiable and uh,
you know,
I think that Pat Paul's and were built a
bridge that uh,
Steven Wright walked across.
Now that doesn't mean steven didn't do
it better,
but he didn't invent it.
But don't you think all of us are in,
in essence,
in a,
in,
in a way some sort of a group thing
because we're all kinds of lily.
Yeah,
absolutely.
We're all kind of influenced by each
other standards and what you appreciate,
like as a comic has been doing it for as
many years as you have.
You know,
I'm,
I'm just two years after you.
It was a.
well why don't I start August 27th,
1988.
So it's about two years after.
You
mean,
which means we basically started the
same day?
Yeah,
pretty much.
That's a,
I started like literally a week apart
from Greg Fitzsimmons.
Do you know Greg?
I don't know him well,
but I,
we worked together somewhere and uh,
and he's very funny.
He's fucking hilarious.
He's a smart dude.
Tell you what,
I tell people all the time and if you
like,
standup comedy,
go to the comedy store and make a
vacation around it and it goes it in
there because people are going to come
in and that room rattles,
rattles and you,
you better be prepared to do something
or that you're not going to follow some
of these fucking guys.
Uh,
uh,
there,
it's really,
really strong and,
and it's fun.
That's what makes it so much fucking
fun.
Pirate ship fill with murderers.
Kayla.
Kayla
water fast.
You're going on after savages.
Jesus Christ,
but everybody's riding the wave of
everybody else and it's an unbelievably
supportive place.
We stop and think about how much
comradery and friendship there is
between the convenience.
You would think if you get all these
national comedians at tour all over the
place,
you put them together.
Well,
ego battles.
It's going to be weird that it's a total
opposite.
That places a love fest.
Everybody's hugging everybody and high
five.
And then having drinks,
I had a lot of fucking me,
I go on,
I do my time and uh,
but I tried to hit him as hard as I can
right in the fucking mail and a and a
because that's what I like to do is hit
him right in the fucking mouth.
So.
And then I guarantee you if somebody's
just got through it and him in the
mouth.
So there's still.
I've been bled off their face when I
get,
as my attorney did have in the mouth,
but I'll hit him in the mouth anyway.
It.
But it's a,
it's a,
the crowds that you get a hold of are so
alive.
I mean there's lots of swordfish on the
end of a fucking line.
It just vibrates,
you know?
Joey
was slaughtering so hard the other night
in the O,
r that I felt like I was having a
religious experience.
I was in the back room with Joey Diaz
was slaughtering his face was beet red.
He was screaming and I was like,
I was running out of air.
I was laughing so hard.
And I remember thinking like,
this is a special time,
this is a special place,
like this is a rare,
rare little jewel in the universe of all
the different performing arts at this
one place.
It's just sort of fucking cracked down
the focus.
I mean,
the other night,
Chappelle,
Chris rock bring up,
brought up Chris Rock rock right up.
Chappelle.
What?
Neither one of them were even on the
schedule.
Chris Rock's pops in and brings up.
That's what I have to help me with
governor,
the comedy store.
You know what you're going to see for
your $15 crazy spot.
You're not going to see if you were
going to pay those guys to put a show on
for you that you just saw tonight.
It's $17,000
a ticket.
So,
or whatever it is.
It is expensive.
It's also like a really like honestly
critical place to shoot.
If your new stuff sucks,
I'll let you know.
Oh yeah.
Uh,
when I first started here,
I really had a great little burst of
material that I really like and,
and,
and it's all the front end of my show
now.
It's about 20 minutes long or that I
want for the front end of the show.
That's what I want.
That's what I'm doing now in the front
end of my live show.
And uh,
so it's.
But now it seems like I'm just playing
around with the order that stuff to just
see where it works the best and just how
to just fucking really slap him in the
face with it.
And uh,
because eventually over time your act,
we'll get into a place where it does
drift into the spot it needs to be in
but don't have that kind of time.
So I need to look at it and do it
different ways and see where it needs to
be a to just slap the fuck out of which
is my only go is the slap the fuck out
of them.
And uh,
and when I can't do that anymore,
I'll keep doing it for a little couple
of years.
He slapped the fuck out of him and I,
I enjoy watching you slap the fuck out
of him,
but I enjoy watching you slap the fuck
out of.
I feel inspired.
You know,
like you're going to walk,
you ain't gonna just waltz on behind
Rogan and I did,
I,
you know,
you know how big a fan I am of years and
it,
and I didn't,
you know,
I,
I know exactly who you are and know
exactly who you are and not as much as I
do now,
but you know,
uh,
but I really sit to stand up in Atlanta
one time as a feature act in long time
ago and he just really fucking tore this
crowd up and I was like,
ah,
this guy's really good.
And uh,
so then,
you know,
I don't like you hanging out there and
watch,
you know,
but sometimes you're right in front of
me or right after me and uh,
and,
and I just got,
you know,
is huge respect.
I mean,
it just,
it's so much fun to watch.
It's a [inaudible] he do physical
things.
I couldn't even do much less get the
words out while you're doing them,
you know,
the uh,
but it's just great writing and that's
cool.
That's cool.
Well,
thanks man.
I feel the same way about you and I
would say that whether or not you just
said something nice to me,
but you know,
it's,
I'm,
I'm honored to be friends with you.
Bullshit.
As a comic.
I'm like,
that's,
that's an honor,
you know?
Well,
um,
uh,
well,
since I'm now one of the Godfather,
the Godfather,
who's gonna like if you wanted to run
for president of the comedy store,
he just got here and you'd win son of a
bitch,
right?
You can.
The uh,
disrespectful went up against,
you know,
you'd with under.
No,
your statesmen in the staff.
The voice wouldn't.
Whatever.
Whenever a jammer Gra first met you.
He was asking me.
He goes,
do you know Joe Rogan?
I was like,
yeah.
He goes,
what do you think about it?
Like,
he's a great guy.
He's a great comedian.
That's what people don't know.
I mean,
a lot of people don't know,
but a lot of people do know,
but a lot of people don't know that.
He's a great comedian.
Not a good comedian,
a great comedian.
That's very nice.
I didn't know enough.
They don't need to know anymore.
I'm good.
No,
you're a great comedian,
you know.
Okay.
All right.
Well I'm just saying that's fine.
But uh,
but anyway,
that's just what I told him.
I appreciate that.
Uh,
and uh,
and he said,
but he doesn't talk much.
I'm like,
Huh,
you know,
it's like you guys were learning how to
be boyfriends,
but he seems to get a,
you know,
I don't make small talk,
but I know,
you know,
that's what I tell him.
I said,
you know what,
you know,
you're going to love this guy.
He's,
he's,
he's solid.
He's,
he's,
he's got a big heart.
He's,
he's right.
He's what we're looking for for friends.
Oh Man,
this a love fest.
Love Fest.
Frond white.
So now it's now,
now joe and I are fucking face timing.
Jay is the gay is fucking three way in
the world.
If we don't end up beating each other up
before Christmas,
I'll be shocked.
Facetime is a another level of
commitment other than texting with
friends.
If you start facetiming friends,
like,
Whoa,
right.
All right buddy.
He's got the body
set me up.
I wouldn't even do that with my wife
because I don't want to prove where I'm
at.
I don't want to.
Oh,
really?
To turn around and show me the
Christian an android phone.
They can't communicate with each other.
That's the move.
Get yourself an android phone and she's
listening to this skyping from the other
side of the movie.
I don't do anything wrong.
I wonder if there's like some sort of a
setting that you can have on you.
You know,
that they have those goggles.
Have you seen these God damn things now,
these never walk.
Never looked through them.
What do we call it again?
Jamie?
Um,
snapchat,
snapchat goggles,
right?
People have these goggles where they can
stream.
They can stream video from their fucking
eyeglasses like anyway they want
wherever they are,
they can stream video from eyeglasses to
pick up where you could,
like,
I could show you.
I could show what I'm seeing.
I could look over and see James Show it
to me.
How do I see it though?
People could watch it online.
They can check it out online.
These are these.
Fuck,
this is crazy.
I mean,
we're,
we're experiencing some next level
technological innovation shit that's
happening,
like some new,
like even more invasive internet sort of
thing.
This is the next level.
The next level is you can literally show
the whole world what you see.
So is this a,
I mean,
because I do periscope,
this is highly drunk on the bus
essentially a lot like that,
but you don't have to hold onto it.
It's on your glasses.
So it's,
it's similar and there's a live
streaming 32nd clips at a time too,
which that's all the little show.
Okay.
Yeah.
But do I stay on it?
It's a,
you know,
it's a blast.
We have this thing because I got a
friend that does my vip stuff on the bus
and he's,
he was,
he was also at that first show that I
did.
So for years and Holy Shit.
And uh,
and so his name's Dave and we do the one
where to go down the road.
We just were like this.
We get just baked,
you know,
after the show we traveled at night and
we'll do these broadcasts and uh,
the big gay Dave and Ron Show and uh,
which has no content or anything,
but you know what,
I don't know that it's growing that much
a periscope and it's the most amazing
thing that you can do a live broadcast
and you can pick it up.
Uh,
Cairo as easy as you can pick it up in
Lubbock.
I think it's pretty popular,
isn't it?
Pretty popular periscope.
I know Scott Adams.
Scott Adams had a very popular Paris.
Twitter owns it.
They just made it,
excuse me.
It's built right in now to twitter's
apps.
Like if you hit twitter and you're like,
instead of putting up a message,
there's a button that says live video
and it's periscope,
but we'll just open right now trying to
just figure out how to make it more
available for people to be.
And do they have a limitation on how
long the clips?
I don't believe.
So there you can go a little over an
hour.
Crazy.
That kind of interactivity that has
never existed before.
There's never,
there's never existed in anything like
that.
Scott Adams,
like he was doing coffee with Scott
Adams like several times a week,
right?
Wasn't he?
Yeah.
If,
if we have no idea.
No idea.
I know he did a bunch of them.
Seven.
How many,
how many times did you do it?
I might have just made it doesn't easily
access and turning it on.
It's on now.
People know it's on now where you are
and just turn it on and they get a
notification.
Ron,
right.
They do that on periscope.
You should have one on periscope and
says Ron White is.
He wants to talk to 25,000
followers on periscope.
I traveling.
I don't know if that's true.
You might get them after the other.
This podcast podcasts will just tell you
you have them and everybody jumped on
follow way.
We don't have a good enough signal for
awhile,
but I got bored with the periscope
thing.
I'm like,
Jesus Christ,
don't expose the instagram live.
Just started up.
I know they've been pushing that around.
I saw that's a little limited to an hour
and those videos don't last after.
Oh,
that's weird.
It just disappear.
Oh,
that's too bad.
That's too bad about,
but I would guess that the amount of
fucking data that they would have to
stock pile.
If everybody's shit saved every every
fucking dummy out there,
save the video of them flexing on the
beach.
All the fucking stupid videos of some
guy telling a shitty joke at a bar.
All those things just gigabyte after
gigabyte after gigabyte,
stored on the twitter server.
They'd be like,
fuck you.
That's what happened to the TMZ bus ride
that we miss the problem with futures
that everybody's going to know
everything.
Everybody does all the time.
Just kind of not going to be as much
craziness going on in the next hundred
years in the future.
I think everybody's gonna know.
I think we're about 50 years away from
us becoming some crazy hive mind.
That's what I think.
I'm stoned and drunk.
How long do you think I'm making some
fucking points?
You've got to just eat what I'm eating
and get to come to yoga class with me.
Who live out in the country.
I'll send somebody to you.
You're a wealthy man.
This is all we have been working with my
yoga girl.
Uh,
and uh,
it's pretty,
pretty basic stuff,
but it's a,
but I'm working on it all you need man.
Basic stuff's all you need.
If you could work your way up to do a
hot yoga class now,
fuck,
you know,
my wife took it.
Even one of those.
There's a worst thing I've ever done in
my life.
I walked out.
That's my stuff first.
How often do you do?
I'd never do it more than twice a week,
but I really should practice some of it
at home.
Like I do some shit.
No,
no,
no.
I'm going to do it at home.
I'm just working on basic exercises,
stretching shit.
But uh,
never more like in class form than twice
a week.
But when I,
when I have done it twice a week,
I felt better than when I did it once a
week.
Yeah.
But a little bit
for 25 years.
And in Margo is strong.
I mean she's strong.
She did had handstands,
but you know,
she's a big time upper body stronger.
Do you think she could you?
She could.
She kept her back if,
if,
if you look at her in the dark,
kind of from behind.
If she's flexing her muscles,
she looks kind of like Floyd Mayweather.
I mean just a,
that's not fun.
And she's carrying,
you know,
thinking like floyd mayweather,
but she's just ripped.
She got to rip the back and she's a
really,
really strong.
But she does.
She's always done that.
So I'm,
I'm,
I got to do something,
man.
I can't be fucking going into my
seventies without being rude,
but it's just to get you on a nutrient
dense diet.
Drop a little body fat.
Yeah.
What'd you bring to the fucking party?
A bottle of fucking whiskey joint,
but I wouldn't have that too.
You know,
I.
How about breakfast?
I had a Kale shake with mct oil and
beats raw beets.
Then I went to Yoga.
We have that new,
a new shoe presser,
new juice presser thing.
It's shit.
Yeah.
We've just got hooked up with it.
Oh Man.
If you can just get used to drinking
juice,
just fresh squeezed vegetable juice,
you can just get used to doing that just
a few times a day.
It will drastically improve your life.
There's so much nutrients and plants
that we need and we fucking escape them
for days.
Potatoes and meat and shit.
I don't have any energy for a workout.
And you know,
I just don't.
I get there,
I'm tired.
I don't want to go.
I hate,
I dreaded going in a dreaded.
When I'd get there I'd read putting on
my shoes.
I do.
I don't know why.
Some people are just lazy as I am.
And,
and I know that's what it is.
And I used to be a runner.
I used to run five miles a day,
just I would run like crazy and I hurt
my knee really bad,
but I just don't like to go to the gym.
I hate it,
but I know I have to.
I know I have to because my friends are
all dying and uh,
and I'm going to be 70 and 10 years and
uh,
so I've got to.
But I know yoga is the thing because
this guy that this dave,
Dave is a golfer,
a buddy of mine,
but he's also yoga for forever.
Well
bless you.
Big Gay Dave.
Bless you.
Take him.
Take him where he needs to go.
Yeah,
man,
Yoga is the best thing about it too is
we'll get your heart rate up.
It will be very difficult,
but it's gonna.
Straighten your body out.
It's going to stretch you out.
Straighten you out.
It's going to calm you down like you're
not trying to be a power lifter.
Know you want to do anything ridiculous.
You want to do anything to hurt your
back.
You want to do is something that's going
to make you feel better.
Well that you know,
new trainer.
And uh,
and I told the guy,
said,
listen man,
I'm a pussy.
You phone's gonna.
Go by what?
You want to talk to him right now,
but please put the play.
The music fit rings when your phone put
it up there.
You know,
he's a buddy of mine,
Brian Johnson,
he,
um,
his hearing apparently it's all fucked
up from all these crazy concerts all
those years.
Well,
they're,
uh,
you know,
it's kind of an interesting thing that
a,
because we're talking about the holiday
evolution of anything,
you know,
and uh,
but there was a guy in Australia who
invented the ear in ear monitors which
destroyed his hearing to begin with.
So he dedicated his life to find a way
to fix that.
And so he did.
But the problem is,
and he does,
I mean,
if you've watched the tape of people
putting these things on people that are
almost completely deaf,
putting this system in their ears,
everyone starts crying.
Wow.
Every one of them.
And uh,
so he,
he had an open letter to Brian Johnson
said,
Brian,
I want to come to your house in
Sarasota.
I want you to put these in your ears.
But the problem is it's not portable.
That is not it.
It's portable in that it's this big,
like a laptop size.
It says it's bigger than that.
Like a large.
Yeah.
Right.
And uh,
so,
but,
uh,
but the technology's there,
I mean he can,
he's amazing and he hates hearing aids
and uh,
you know,
and he's a surgeon,
he's the sweetest guy.
He was a wonderful,
wonderful human being.
But you know,
what was cool about it,
man,
when Axel rose started,
I was like,
should I accept this?
No.
Should you accept axl rose saying and
ACDC,
NIH excepted it 100 percent because I
thought it might not be Brian Johnson,
but it's still why that's so fucking
rose.
Right?
And it's kind of interesting.
Like Brian couldn't do it anymore.
Actually steps in.
I like it,
I like it.
I'm happy with that.
That's a freak show,
but in,
in an awesome way.
It's like how often you're going to see
this.
How often do you get to see axl rose
seeing it as a lead singer for AC
fucking DC?
Like wow,
whether they're digging shit,
their ticket sales dropped by 70
percent.
That's a bunch of puppies in America.
Well that's true.
They know.
But the thing is,
that's Brian Johnson's voice.
Brian Johnson is back in black,
was the second biggest selling album
of all time behind thriller and 52
million copies as Brian Johnson,
not fucking axl rose Johnson is still a
freak show vocalist.
And,
and at some point,
you know,
his brother,
Malcolm Malcolm was the better guitar
player anyway,
better than angus and angus knew at
everybody.
Fucking yeah.
But,
but he was the engine behind that really
complicated.
It doesn't sound complicated.
Really fucking complicated rock and roll
and uh,
that's why it was so engaging for the
whole fucking planet.
And it was.
But it was Brian Johnson's voice,
not been,
not bond Scott's,
you know,
that he was their lead singer for five
years.
But Scott has some great fucking songs
to write.
He did,
he said he did.
But with Scott,
I,
yeah,
I don't know.
God Damn it because I've,
I've,
I've only,
I've only heard Brian St but,
but back in black is,
which was the second biggest selling
album of all time was all Brian Johnson
and no doubt about it.
I'm not saying he wasn't,
so you know what?
And,
and I'm wrong as I usually am because
why not?
And anger still loves to play it.
And you know,
when,
uh,
it got ugly,
well that's not my place to talk about
that.
But uh,
but there was some political shit,
you know,
but.
Well,
whatever.
But yeah.
And I also heard some reviews that he
did a really good.
Yeah,
job are these who sings these Jamie?
Which one's dirty deeds?
Highway to hell.
Oh my God.
Go back up to 30 days.
That's Brian Johnson right?
There it is.
If you want to,
if you want to hear somebody sing it.
Well,
he was fucking amazing.
Look,
they were both amazing.
No,
I'm not like a picking sides.
But what if Brian Johnson just came out
to the shows.
I mean,
he can't,
he can't do it and I wouldn't do that
because just because it would be cool to
see them.
They're like,
oh man.
Wheeling them out.
He just can't.
Yeah,
well he's still racing cars.
I mean he's,
he's got a fucking car team that he
races these low.
There's these big old guys that were in
Pan Am races.
These cars were running 200 miles an
hour.
He racism.
Oh Wow.
And he travels the country.
He's got a new car show coming out that
I'm going to be part of.
No Shit.
He insisted on my part.
I a couple of days for the whole season
can.
But can they in any way restore his
hearing to the point where he could
start saying yes,
andy would tell.
I felt like,
you know,
when,
when he stepped out,
I was like,
this is a weird moment in our,
a love of these,
these epic rockstars when we see,
you know,
well,
I went to see Chicago the other day with
my son and uh,
it,
it was great.
It was fucking great there.
There's three guys,
uh,
and not one of,
one of the singers,
the one that wasn't as good and uh,
and he was replaced by Irish tenor that
could just hit every single one of those
notes.
And it was great.
And that was with my son.
We were partying.
So I,
the only reason is it's kind of personal
to me because he's a friend and so I
know what he was going through that year
and uh,
and with also the death of his best
friend and then his loss of his hearing
and then the laws of his band and,
and there were only a few dates left,
but that's the other way when to go out.
But he's brand fucking Johnson know
shit.
He's the,
he was literally a treasure of a fucking
guy.
He's right up there with Charlie
Chapman,
Charlie Chapman,
Brian Johnson.
Yeah.
I mean,
there's no doubt about it man.
I mean he's a fucking epic vocalists.
Epic,
you know,
fucking impact.
And his intensity got me through many a
workout when I was struggling.
Adolescent.
It's still on my phone.
That is one of the,
like the all time.
You can actually a kitten bands ever.
You could pull up of footage.
I guess you can have a Margo and Brian
onstage and Jacksonville,
Florida and a gun club yet.
But uh,
Brian Johnson and Margo Ray.
See if that comes up.
That's awesome.
Oh,
good Lord.
It was margo show and towards the end of
it Brian was there and I was like,
you know,
or uh,
her band knows,
shook me all night long.
They'd been working on it all we do.
You want to go sing it?
He goes,
where did,
I don't know if I could show you.
I would foster that.
And uh,
oh,
there it is right there.
That's my wife Margaret.
This is crazy.
This is so crazy.
When was this?
Twenty four,
three or four years?
Was it two or three years ago?
So video.
Wow.
She has a friend of mine is going to
come up.
Azalea Song Shit from a AC DC.
Brian Johnson.
And how many people are in this runner?
Seventy five.
Same.
Oh my God.
That must have been the most epic shit
ever to be in that room.
God Damn Man.
I saw Gary Clark Jr and honey.
Honey play in front of like 300 people.
Do you know Gary Clark Jr?
He was in an episode.
Roadies.
God Damn,
that dude's shit.
Him and honey.
Honey,
they played this midnight show in
downtown
La.
Dang.
You've been waiting for your Hendrix,
Stevie Ray Vaughan.
Where's that guy coming from?
That's who it is.
Clark
to.
That guy's.
He's,
he's got something crazy going on the
way he,
he has got such a specific guitar sound
like he did this riff and while he was
doing this,
this,
they,
um,
they play.
They did a cover of the midnight rider.
They decided on the spot.
So Suzanne from honey,
honey didn't even know the words to
songs.
So she got on her phone and downloaded
the words.
So she had the words on her phone.
She's reading off the phone and people
got mad because always bitch keeps
checking her phone while she's singing.
She's literally joked around about it.
She doesn't know the words to the song
because although she's a fan,
she hasn't Sung in years.
She doesn't know which probably never
sang it live.
So she live for the first time ever
improvising on the spot.
Sings her version unprepared of midnight
rider.
Why Gary motherfucking Clark junior
plays all the dickey betts part.
Look at this shit.
Listen to this.
I'm recording this in the front row.
Get fucked up.
And listening to music is an alien can
feel comfortable in saying that's the
most intriguing guitarists since
hendricks.
I feel real comfortable saying that
that's,
that's a bad motherfucker.
And they see that live in like a couple
of maybe 300 people at the most
blade.
Uh,
you know,
he came out whenever my character died,
he was one of the guys that came to the
funeral and saying.
And the character of roadies,
nobody watched it.
So.
But he was anyway
psyched about that man.
Before it came out.
I was,
I was.
And it was,
you know what it was,
it was good.
It was,
it was really good.
I thought it was.
I thought it was wonderful.
And it was,
the problem was,
it was,
you know,
a lot of people have a fucking hard on
for Cameron Crowe for some reason.
Really.
Like,
you know,
they jumped on this shows back so hard,
so fast.
I mean,
the critics did relationship with the
first word out of their mouths was just
this,
fuck it,
it's the worst piece of shit.
I'm like,
what the one.
I love it.
I think it's a,
you know,
it was,
cameron always has sweetness to it shows
every.
His movies always have a sweet edge to
them,
you know,
no matter what it is,
whether it's a fast times at Ridgemont
high or the whole lot of movies,
Jerry Mcguire,
uh,
almost famous,
you know,
they all had all
too fast times at Ridgemont high and
almost famous.
Those are epic movies,
right?
Yeah.
Oh yeah,
absolutely.
In general.
Dryer one best.
Somebody wants something for something
in Jerry Maguire.
Show me the money.
It could be a junior.
Yeah.
And uh,
so anyway,
the uh,
I forget we're talking about Tom Cruise.
Tom Cruise?
No,
no.
Oh yeah.
The movie,
they just jumped on it.
They just jumped on it.
They were shooting,
you know,
the course because they could and uh,
and their cousins and whoever that
branch is,
it reviews for variety magazine.
One day she's going to feel a Turd in
her throat who's turned wellbeing?
And we might turn shit right.
Shit in her mouth and shit.
These are strong words.
Oh,
they're horrible words.
Yeah.
Okay.
Maybe I'll just flick some economies.
Dress.
I think it's going to be way easier if
you,
uh,
I,
I think about like the,
like the kind of sort of grudges that
someone can have with someone like him,
like Cameron Crowe.
It's going to be way easier to avoid
that stuff if you're being reviewed by
everybody instead of just being reviewed
by a bunch of,
like selected outlets like the
Washington Post,
the New York Times,
the Hollywood reporter,
Blah Blah,
blah,
blah.
Just the open ended aspect of the
Internet is kind of changing that,
don't you think?
I think so.
No,
Uh,
they,
you know,
they canceled it.
My character was going to die anyway and
uh,
the.
So I was like,
Eh,
but I still love the cast so much.
It was a,
you know,
fucking machine gun.
Kelly's got a fucking huge hit on the
radio or just,
I just did.
That kid is cool as fuck machine gun
Kelly,
do you know who they don't know that
guy?
Oh,
he's a,
he's a young.
Jamie just nodded at me like I'm an old
man.
Yeah,
you're young,
old fucking unbelievable rapper white
guy.
I've added is Cleveland.
That's what the world needs more white
rapper.
Fucking crazy.
The age of trump.
No,
they don't need more,
but they need this one because he's the
real fucking deal.
And he's a uh,
he was great in the show.
Just great.
He was a.
He really gave the honesty to the
fucking show because he,
because he is a big party in Rockstar.
I'm writing his name down by UK.
Yeah.
Nice.
It's,
well,
it's always cool to see and hear about
new shit.
That's awesome.
I heard there's a documentary on Netflix
called rat.
I'm scared.
Have you seen a chemi?
Nope.
I think I told you about it.
Heard about smart rats and rats in New
York.
Jesus Christ.
Morgan spurlock while you trying to
fucking freak me out again.
I saw it.
I saw it on there and that chose not to
watch.
It freaked me out about Mcdonald's.
Now he's freaking me out about rats.
That God,
Dan Morgan,
spurlock,
rats.
Apparently in New York City there's as
many rats as there are human beings.
I made that up.
That was with you in the days before the
Internet.
I could get away with it.
I think it's probably pretty close
though.
Honestly.
They might actually be more rapture
because look how much space they take
up.
Whoa.
Look at this.
The Morgan spurlock flying over the big
rat right there.
The space of a Jack Daniels whiskey
bottle.
Yeah.
It was about the size of a good look at
the floor on this thing.
Wonderful.
As viewed.
The floor.
It's a beautiful bottle.
Be Awesome for a bar.
Fight.
Some shit broke out.
We have to do.
Are we had ice?
Do you care how it dropped back?
Yeah.
I'm not about taking the I gotta.
I'm going to have my car towed and
that's what I'm saying.
Fucking car towed.
Don't worry about the ice.
There is plenty of missed.
Why?
Where are you?
People like text messaging and my wife
and tell him you're on youtube.
Out in Al Gore's into webs.
Floating through space and look,
it's young.
Jamie with the ice.
Bam.
Young James Cameron or opera camera
operator.
Ice Catheter.
Bad motherfucker.
Ron White.
What are you doing?
Text messaging.
Traveling.
No,
I'm just trying.
My wife is trying to find me.
I told you this was gonna be about an
hour,
so I told her get her a drone bro.
Like a little one.
Just keep it right next to you.
Right.
Have a good on red.
Okay.
Also,
it's like my fucking balls.
You have like an artificial children's
flying over your head like that.
It gets a.
At least it gives you like this mental
discipline.
You have to ignore the drone.
Ignore the drone.
Ignore the drawn them.
I get it.
Okay.
I'm going to bring her onto.
Don't do it.
If we could wrap this up if you want.
No,
no.
I don't want to wrap it up.
But um.
Oh,
she thought it was gonna be an hour.
We've definitely done our podcasts.
Only a couple.
Like maybe three.
I don't care.
I'm having a blast.
Okay.
I want to stay here and drink wild.
Nobody wants to.
Nobody cares anymore.
That's not gonna happen.
That place isn't going to exist.
I'm still at work.
Ron Wyden is at work.
Ladies and gentlemen.
These cameras aren't on.
There were definitely not.
Why would that be?
Are they?
Yeah.
For sure.
Oh good.
We're streaming.
We stream on youtube.
Okay.
And the record.
And then it gets uploaded after the
fact.
We put it on the itunes.
So are we live to anybody right now?
Probably like,
let me guess.
10,000
people.
Oh,
I guessed.
Really?
Wow.
That's a fucking good cast.
Holy Shit.
He says I wouldn't even have had gas.
I never,
uh,
I've never asked before,
like only in the big ones,
like when we do fight companions,
what's the most it's ever been like 30
or something?
Thirty 3000,
33,000
at the most.
I can get stirred up on the periscopes
about $3,200
maybe.
I don't know what I got.
Um,
I don't,
I haven't used it in so long,
but it's,
it's one of those things where if
someone found out,
like that's one of the things that
happened with that,
uh,
the um,
Scott Adams guy because people found out
they were like,
wow,
this really intelligent guy.
He's also a trump supporter.
Is he trump supporter?
No,
he's not a trump supporter.
He's literally not even voting,
but he's breaking down.
Why thinks trump's going to win?
And people are freaking the fuck out.
Like he literally,
he's telling you,
I'm not voting,
I'm not voting for anybody because then
I'll have some sort of a player in the
game.
He knew he is a weird guy,
that Scott Adams in a good way,
like he's sort of defined.
He's,
he defies a lot of sort of a democrat
democratic.
He will.
He's very open minded,
I would say.
But he got unfairly labeled as being
like this a trump supporter.
Whereas I don't think he was a trump.
I don't think it was.
Most certainly was not anti trump.
Well,
what he was trying to send to hurt
trump's a program for him to say,
trump's gonna win for sure.
And I'm the one that knows.
And he also has the background and he's
the one that knows.
So it wasn't,
it,
you know,
it was one of the several blows that,
uh,
that Hillary took besides being a
horrible candidate that she took that
knocked it out of her hands.
You know,
there were these two people are running
against the only people that they could
possibly fucking be.
And uh,
you know,
if she just wouldn't have said basket of
deplorables when she said that,
I was like,
Jesus fucking Christ,
bunch of them,
give them a hammer.
But anyway,
just,
you know,
when people,
even people that wanted to look at it as
an alternative vote,
like,
is it an alternative to the potential
chaos that trump could cause,
you know,
and some people looked at it that way
and some people honestly,
I think,
um,
I don't know what percentage I would
guess it would be because there's a
bunch of pragmatists that got in there
and when it came time to vote,
looked at that fucking ballot and said,
do you know what,
let's just see what happens.
Let's just see what happens if we put
this fucking crazy guy in here.
We were in England,
why not?
And uh,
it,
it went to Margaret,
his friend's house and this guy who I
really,
really like a,
he goes,
well,
the monkey in me would love to see
trump.
Yeah,
the monkey in me,
if get and areas,
you know,
what could he really do and,
but I
don't know.
He could definitely do something,
but what would he do?
Good.
What,
what,
what
complete shakeup of the system look
like?
I don't know,
you know,
and I think that this is weird defining
of things right now where everyone has
to absolutely say in one way or another,
either support or deny,
either support him but don't sweat it
gets to me to be real cultish.
It gets to me to be real
liked fucking Patriot pride,
you know,
Yo,
I'm fucking,
I'm for the dolphins no matter what.
It gets real weird to gets real good.
A guy wouldn't take a picture of me at a
meet and greet because I was.
Somebody just brought up the subject and
I don't fucking bring it up.
It might meet and greets or my show.
I used to do one bit about it and uh,
that was barely could be conceived as
anti trump.
But uh,
because half my fucking fans,
I'm not gonna lose half my fan base over
a goddamn presidential election.
You can be as greedy.
I'm know I'm not a dixie chicks.
People will get mad at you about shit
like this.
Literally they go is two girls with him
and they took pictures because you're
trying to take a picture.
He goes,
if he's not going to support trump,
I'm not going to take a picture.
And uh,
either what?
I said,
well,
you know what?
There's a door,
right?
The fuck there.
And you can just walk there.
You can just walk the fuck out of it.
Wow.
He wants to drain the swamp.
That's all it is.
Hashtag nobody's driving to know swamp
swamp being drained down there.
Dick Cheney emerging as key.
Trump advisor,
Jesus.
Jesus Christ.
Darth vader has returned.
Reagan,
Halliburton back into the of bitch
bom,
Bom,
bom.
He's been on ice.
It turns out for eight years,
the only Dick Cheney that we've ever
seen in news reports has been this
artificial Dick Cheney's.
Dick Cheney's cryogenically frozen
himself for eight years to get through
the Obama administration and then the
pop back up and then the administration.
It's a fully renewed and invigorated.
He couldn't go three months without
having open heart surgery back when he
was the Christ.
Ron White,
Jesus Christ.
You mean?
There was a point in time where Dick
Cheney literally did not have a pulse
and I was like,
Jesus Christ isn't this and the fucking
Bible.
I'm going to really if you want to,
if you guys want to follow the Bible,
but the end of the world,
I don't know if it's in the Bible,
but he had a machine inside of the body
that pumped his blood and it didn't make
a pulse,
so he didn't have a fucking pulse for a
long time while he's waiting for a heart
transplant.
See,
Cheney has heart.
She's fucking popups.
Cheney has heart pump,
but no pulse white.
That's gotta be a Zombie.
Okay.
Are you excited?
Are you not?
I can't even tell you.
I put my fingers on your neck and I
don't feel shit.
You fucking vampire or you're still
going.
You're still going.
You're still running.
Halliburton and here.
The steel in politics is not fly.
You know what?
I really
thought.
I haven't heard his name.
In the years I've.
I'm like,
you,
I mean many years,
he had a heart transplant.
I had a joke that I could never figure
out how to get to work.
It was about how one secret service
agent realized he wasn't really a secret
service agent.
He just had the exact same blood type as
Dick Cheney and they'd be like,
well,
how am I going to eat food?
And you guys were eating Burgers,
man,
what the fuck?
And they just never told him.
How come I got to run every day and you
guys don't have to fucking run.
Shut up,
bitch,
get running.
And there was this Epi,
their car pacing with them smoking
cigarettes and then.
And then one day Dick Cheney as a
fucking heart attack and they opened
that dude up like a fish and just scoop
out his fucking do some roadside
service,
figure out how to get to where.
It's very funny,
but I don't know if you're going to get
it to work.
It's never going to work.
It was terrible.
It was about heart attacks and dead
people and not funny enough.
Yeah.
I got baby duck pussy lip tacos to work.
That was a one thing I can come from
myself and is knowing that Dick Cheney
did knock in,
get any advantage as far as waiting in
line for a heart guarantee you it was
100 percent fair and across the board.
Without a doubt,
Dick Cheney did not have any influence
whatsoever in anyone moving him to the
front of the line to get a young,
fresh 20 year old basketball players.
Heart was definitely.
No,
no,
no chance about it.
No,
no,
no.
Absolutely not.
That the motorcycle victim.
Seventeen year old super stud athlete.
There's no way that heart is going into
Dick Cheney's heart.
No,
it's not going to get it.
I would guess so.
Yeah.
So,
uh,
how is he doing that?
Why did that happen?
Did he have A.
I don't know.
Does anybody know who know who,
whose heart was?
He had a transplant at age 71.
Jesus Christ son,
he suffered five heart attacks,
undergone open heart surgery,
multiple catherization ones.
And,
and Joe Angioplasties had a
defibrillator implanted in a pump
attached directly to his heart.
All of that before his transplant at age
71 where some young,
strong man winter marries a sprinter,
they got some fucking kid from Iceland
that dropped one of those ballots on his
head and they just grabbed him and just
throw them on ice.
Settlers attacked.
Just keep alive.
Jack's going to be your search and bring
this thing back around.
We're going to be fine and that fucking
super hearts and Dick Cheney,
all of a sudden you see him.
Posture looks better.
Face starts to suck in a little bit.
Loses the jowls.
Hair's growing back.
I just don't know why I got like that.
Would want to still be in the business.
Look at this stage of the game.
Like is it just he doesn't want to bail
out money.
Halliburton was like
$150,
million dollars and that was to become a
vice president.
So you know,
I don't know.
I have no idea.
I have no idea what drives any of those
videos.
Yeah,
that's what you would get a worry.
Like what,
what?
What's the end game like?
Where are you going when you're working
that hard?
At 70,
what do you,
what are you shooting for you trying to
save the world.
He trying to tell people how it is.
What is it?
I wonder,
you know,
catch.
Keep making money,
right?
Can it be ego?
Maybe.
Maybe while you're alive,
you're just alive.
Maybe all of these ideas that we have
about people getting older and wiser.
Maybe I'll all just bullshit.
Maybe you just get older,
like a lot of people get older.
So if they're fucking crazy when they're
30 and they want to take over the world,
why do we automatically expect them to
be on some path of self regulation and
improvement?
The point where they become enlightened
and they don't want to take over the
world anymore.
Now they're 17 and they've had 15 open
heart surgeries.
But no,
it doesn't.
They're just people.
My goodness gracious Joe Rogan.
Hey,
you know what the,
uh,
I,
I think that,
uh,
that uh,
this has been a lot of fun and I love
you to death.
I think it's been a lot of fun.
I love you to death as well.
And uh,
the,
you know what?
I can't believe it took us this long to
go do this.
Uh,
this thing I've been getting so fucked
up that I can't respond anymore.
You're fine.
So it's always better if I just don't
respond.
If I,
once I get this fucked up,
I completely understand your position
from a fan's perspective and a friend.
You've been amazing and fine and you
could skate right through this like a
goddamned champion,
like,
like a Tonya harding before the
incident,
right?
Good Lord.
A little freak.
It shows good last.
She was amazing.
That's you.
That's you right now
if you'd like every great comic,
you have a low self opinion of yourself.
The it takes a certain amount of ego was
a great year to say.
I'm telling you right now.
It takes a certain amount of ego to be
great and then a certain amount of ego
to move past that where you have to
understand your ego and you're one of
those.
Understand your ego guys.
And so you squash that motherfucker
every time it gets.
So you're always looking for self
deprecating moments in being in front of
people that love you.
Well,
maybe I do.
Maybe I do it.
It's because you're a bad motherfucker.
There's no way you wouldn't be if he
wouldn't be as funny.
It's,
that's,
that's a whole part of the whole thing,
man.
You know,
and uh,
getting to know you and be friends with
you at the comedy store has been really
fun,
man.
Because,
uh,
I love your comedy.
Have always love your comedy.
I love watching you work shit out.
I love hanging out with you.
It's just fun,
man.
It was just fun.
And having you on here has been just
nothing but a blast.
I knew it would be.
So right now we're saying no,
don't stop.
I still have to drive 45 minutes to get
to New Hampshire,
New Hampshire.
Fuck yeah.
They listen to this shit and Dubai and
Dubai,
we,
God it,
we have gotten worked there.
If you wouldn't have been disciplined
was just being honest with
dumb.
They're going to get straight in there.
The game up
can arrest people from saying the wrong
magic word.
They do.
You know?
I don't know if they do,
but I just really want to get the game
up.
Uh,
you know,
at some point,
I did that to getting high with getting
doug with high or whatever.
How was that?
I got so fucked up.
I couldn't,
I couldn't even think.
Doug wasn't there like a flight
attendant trying to bring you back into
the runway with Josh who smokes more
weed than anybody.
And a blue.
The comedian's comedian from Denver who
won last comic standing and who he has
cerebral palsy.
Right.
Funny as fuck.
He mean he's one of the rare people that
actually uses medical marijuana.
You can watch it.
You can watch it relaxes at that fucking
tension is fucking muscular dystrophy
arm or whatever the fuck it is.
Yeah.
It's good to bring up.
Very important to bring it up because
that sets a clear beneficiary of actual
medical marijuana unlike you or me.
Oh no,
that's not using it for Madison.
You know what I,
I was taking Xanax to sleep,
to know,
to get up,
just to,
just to get out of bed for awhile.
Who?
Xanax is a tricky one.
Yeah.
How about,
how long did you take it for?
Twenty six years.
Jesus Christ.
Pharmacological expert.
Yet though I'm not,
I'm not understanding because I'm good.
I'm good.
The uh,
I spoke a lot of weed and that's good.
And uh,
you know,
I drink a lot of Tequila,
but I'd really,
I'd like to thank the Jj for sending
this over.
Fucking delicious
a wow man.
I think I,
I think we're all real lucky right now.
I think it's just a perspective issue.
It's really a perspective issue of
understanding what a strange time this
is,
you know,
for all of us.
Well everybody's freaking out about
trump and freaking out about the future
and what are they going to do with
Russia?
Fuck's gonna are you worried about
How often is in Ron White's day as ron
might worry about fucking Russia
throughout,
you know,
we're already dead.
So,
I mean,
in my,
in my opinion,
there's,
I don't know,
I don't worry about Russia,
I really don't even think about Russia,
but I also don't think about any of it.
Uh,
I mean not,
not on,
not in details.
I don't know.
I was a presidential candidate for my
paperwork.
It was completely filled out.
I was a candidate for the president in
that space to hear.
How dare you put who put you in?
I did.
You put yourself in now you a part of
the Bilderberg group or you have a
supporter of any sort of the Illuminati.
Anything that's going on is ruling the
world.
Ryan White?
No.
You're just going to run for president
as a normal.
Normal dude.
How come I didn't
hear about this until right now?
I don't know.
Research.
Uh,
how the fuck am I supposed to know you
ran for president will look at credit.
Pull up Broadway for president.
Who to try to make the election.
Are you willing to do it again for
years?
No,
no,
no.
It scared me.
Was that I didn't realize anybody was
taking this seriously.
Oh my God.
Ron Wind for president.
Vote smart because you can't fix stupid.
That's me at my house.
And uh,
does
I made that face before.
So I don't know where they got that
image,
but it's certainly not me.
How weird man.
And so what happened,
people took it seriously,
help support service members on drugs,
war on meth thing.
There's a that I felt like because I,
you know,
I have the same,
have a comics perspective of the
American people,
which means for the last 30 years,
yeah,
my laugh,
I've done nothing but travel back and
forth across this country,
up upside,
downside.
One left to right,
right to left.
And I've made these people laugh.
I've drank with them in bars,
had dinner in their homes,
have cried with them when their kids
died in,
uh,
you know,
I know Donald Trump doesn't know nobody
else up there though.
I know,
you know,
I know who they are and know exactly who
they are and know what bothers him.
And it was,
he was a bothersome.
Is the fucking math is just killing
everybody.
And uh,
and,
and nobody ever brought that up in this
election.
Did math,
the math.
Even the meth made here and not even the
meth from Mexico.
The meth made here in America is a,
is it kills more people than isis ever
will in this country.
And unless something fucking,
I mean,
you know,
this is going on right now.
100 people a day.
Dad,
dad,
everyday.
Hundred people a day.
Dad over the either the
byproducts of doing math over a period
of time.
That 100 people a day easy.
How many people die from skateboarding?
Google that.
I'd say a half a person today you think?
Yeah.
What do you think is the most dangerous
sport that people die from a day at
Honeywell?
For Math.
If,
uh,
if it would have been.
If I hadn't been elected president,
here's what,
here's my plan.
A,
the.
So this would have been the most
dangerous sport would have been run a
math lab.
That would have been the most dangerous
sport.
That was a.
because I wouldn't put US troops on the
ground and I would.
And I would put a bounty of $20,000.
If you can show me an operating math lab
will go in there,
boots on the ground.
We'll give you eight seconds to get with
the meth babies.
And then we're going to kill everybody
in the fucking place and we're going to
blow the place up.
You would kill the dude from breaking
bad.
You know?
I don't think that's real.
But if it was a real.
Yeah.
Fucked fuck yeah.
He's because he's killing people,
right?
He knows he's doing it.
They're doing it with just for profit.
He is a prophet here.
Could you just enjoy a little math?
Like a wine tasting?
It's just a little.
Just a.
So I could,
but still I would like to see if the
navy seals did meth.
If you could take like guys with a
tremendous amount of discipline.
Like if you got Tim Kennedy to do math
one time,
I guarantee he's not going to become a
math junkie or crack crack cocaine is
even more addictive.
Is it then.
But,
but math,
you know,
you watched the deterioration of
somebody on math over a 10 year period
of time.
It could be a most beautiful woman in
the world all the way down to the skank
and 10 years complete toothless.
Fucking is horrible for him.
Yeah man.
We're going deep,
deep down the world of neither one of us
know what the fuck we're talking about.
No,
no,
absolutely.
I told you some meth.
I've told you a while ago.
I'm too fucked up to keep doing the
show.
You're the one that kept going fine.
We're just in a civil debate about
whether or not a navy seal could smoke a
little meth and just put it down and
walk away because it's not a bitch.
Okay.
No,
I ain't.
He grabs your DNA,
doesn't it?
I think a navy seal.
I don't think Nav,
so we'd do it in the first place.
That's the whole key to the
investigation that the army had to find
out.
Is it?
What is it?
Is it willpower?
Is a physical like what's the deal?
It'd be sucking a dick for a sandwich in
the know they don't want sandwiches.
They want meth.
Yeah,
they right.
If they have math,
the sandwich has no importance.
It seems like for a lot of people that's
the case,
but the question is how?
How even our.
We all of us like how many?
Why?
Why do some people have cat allergies?
Why did some people have pain or
analogy?
It's like,
what the fuck's going on?
How many people that smoke meth?
Just smoke it and they go,
look.
How many people smoke meth in pain?
Just his size.
I note like we did with me and you.
I don't think we know.
Right?
Right.
Because some people smoke pot and they
go,
well,
I'll never do that again.
But I didn't say that.
You didn't say that?
No.
Uh,
I don't like things that make me vibrate
and I liked it.
I liked it.
I like to nap.
Responsible,
methamphetamine,
use and community.
I use math on occasion.
It was crazy before work.
Oh my God.
I don't know if this is real,
but I mean there are people apparently
that agree with them and there's a whole
community course.
They do a bunch of methods.
Methods are all getting together on each
other's fingers off saying everything's
fine and you know,
who is pitching in to the fucking or
fucking
going.
Yeah.
Do a little math to a little math gonna
make you a metal team.
That will do from the James Bond movie
jaws.
Remember that guy?
Metal teeth for a while,
rappers were going with the metal teeth.
Jamie,
has that led up interesting to grill?
Yeah.
You agree that grills are still in full
force.
Interesting.
Ron,
why have you ever considered getting a
grill?
Like maybe perhaps something like
platinum and diamonds,
something?
Nope.
Nothing.
No little wayne ask.
Perhaps.
That's when Cameron decided to make my
character ball.
I don't know if you ever saw it or not,
but it was pretty funny.
You laugh at it.
Did you see him?
That character?
I didn't see that show once.
If I had known that in any way I could
have helped and kept it on the air.
I want to watch every episode.
Find out who's watching.
How do they find out a dick for not have
watched your show now?
I think I probably wanted to get around
to it,
but there's a lot of shit.
Like I haven't seen that.
Uh,
who's the black superhero?
Luke.
Luke cage.
I want to see that show.
I keep hearing awesome things about it.
Now I'm in trouble because I said the
black superhero,
even though he's exactly that.
What other ones?
Like netflix has a couple of.
They have daredevil.
They have luke cage.
What else they have on a shirt?
I think.
Oh,
they have the punisher.
That's right.
That's what I'm hearing.
Good things about that too.
But more about luke cage than anything.
Heard a lot of people.
If somebody has a bit about luke.
Oh,
John Horton.
Horton.
As a really funny bit about Luke Cage.
John Horton,
who uh,
opened up for me in Denver at the comedy
works.
Yeah.
No,
he's from here.
He's from La.
He brought an opener all the way from
money,
man.
I always bring opener so you don't bring
openers.
What are you doing?
What's happening there?
That's my character.
Oh,
Jesus Christ.
What does he do to you?
How rude and balled it made you look
like?
Shit.
I like the glasses though.
And the t shirt with glasses that they
did a lack of fucking audition.
Fast as fuck them.
That's funny man.
Yeah.
So do you enjoy doing that show though?
It was a blast.
It was,
it was,
uh,
the,
the dialogue was a blast to do you know,
you'll,
you'd lack it.
You watched episode eight.
Is it available on Netflix or a.
you've got to go to the showtime APP.
I know I have showed.
Do they do it on demand because on
demand,
I don't know.
I saw it was on a,
I think it was a Delta flight.
I think right now those providers,
all these different people trying to
figure out how to get that straight so
you can watch pretty much.
I mean,
how many years do you think,
if you're realistic,
how many years are we away from?
Everything that everyone makes.
Being able to be watched online per real
close.
It's just got to be some universal
currency thing.
So the universal one click like Amazon,
something along those lines.
We can get things on the spot right
after they come out because you know
it's going to massively increase how
many people watch your show or any show
because some people just don't want to
pay for that showtime package.
Maybe they're broke and they have one
chance,
like,
what do you want to,
oh,
let's get hbo.
You know?
Or maybe they were really cheap and
they're like,
oh.
With cinemax said,
cinemax actually only was,
I call it 50 bucks.
I don't know.
I don't know what it costs.
I have no idea.
Cinemax is awesome because that's not my
point.
I point is that if you have it online,
if it's easy to get to,
you get this open river.
It's like the blockades you put up where
it makes it hard for people to buy shit.
That's what fucks everything up.
I call you want me to sign up A.
I don't want to sign up.
I gotta put my email address here.
Comes to spam.
If there was just some one easy way that
you could put that fucking thing online
is one simple way where everybody could
just give you like a book or whatever it
is for an episode.
Just really easy.
Let me watch the episode real quick.
You know,
God damn everywhere.
It'd be everywhere,
everywhere,
everywhere.
It's just too right now.
It's too complicated right now.
They're trying to figure out that the
various portals for people to be able to
profit off these things.
How do we start this?
I can't wait.
I can't wait because I don't profit off
the internet at all at all.
You definitely do because people on the
Internet.
I love you.
So they come see you
well there.
Yeah.
In that way they do you know that?
I'd do that.
Yeah.
That's a big part of it.
Right?
To get the run white shell started.
Jamie is important.
Needs to be done right now.
Now what do you mean the podcast?
You shouldn't do something like once a
month now.
I went to once a month.
Once a month.
It's not that much time for an hour.
Brian White answers questions.
All right.
I'll do that here.
You don't have to put you on the spot.
No,
I feel bad now.
Now to do it.
But once a month.
Nobody said that once a month.
So we already said that everybody else
is like 17 days a week and I only have
17 days a week and fucking do this shit.
So what else are you going to tell you
earlier?
I would never encourage any changing of
any of what you do because then you
wouldn't be ron white.
But if ron white decides at one point in
time that he wants to change whatever
behavior,
if Ron Wyden decides that he wants to
start drinking carrot and ginger and
garlic juice every morning going to the
fucking crossfit gym.
I'm drinking Jack Daniels reviewed Mr.
mixed message.
I am definitely a mixed message.
You are
present and uh,
I'm guilty as charged.
Just trying to squeeze as much life out
of this thing is we can run white and
middle school,
but I'm not sure that helps.
I don't think so either.
The
uh,
the expression is little old band,
not big old man.
Old Man.
You never hear anybody
say big old man.
Tiny little loop for that is the great
grave pulling him towards it.
How fucked up is that?
That's ultimately what is actually
happening to your body.
As you get older,
you have a stick to fight off the slow
pull of gravity nation.
That's just stuck
one window.
It's undeniable.
Then pull that you could use to kick
your ass when you were a baby
and you just fall over and kick your ass
all the time and you got a little
stronger and then it got to where you
could fucking run and didn't get to
where you could job and you're like
kicking.
Gravity's asked for a few years and let
gravity never stopped.
Never gravity.
Never fucking stopped.
Gravity kept on fucking tug on your
goddamn ass.
Gravity's like fucking
earth.
Nick Diaz in his prime would land a lot
of like 50 percent punches.
It was just kinda like punched your face
until you got hurt.
And then he would start digging hard.
Boom,
boom,
boom.
That's Kinda like gravity.
Gravity is just slowly chipping away.
Discuss this idea,
your posture,
your hips wider,
your feet hurt.
Gravity bitch a suck your fucking mad at
Tara's job.
Gotcha.
Dat Dat,
Dat,
Dat da Da da Da.
And on that note,
ladies and gentlemen,
that is the end of this podcast.
Ron White is available for children's
parties.
He plays clubs in colleges all across
the country and you can catch him.
Oh,
throughout the land run underscore white
on twitter.
Ron White official on instagram.
Is that correct,
sir?
Yeah.
I don't even know about the instagram.
You one of the baddest motherfuckers
alive runway.
I hope you appreciate that you were the
one of the greatest motherfuckers left.
Thanks for having me on the show.
Please make it.
It's fine that we hang out together and
we just really talked about this last
week and said,
uh,
but it was a lot of fun.
This a good time,
man.
Thank you so much.
All right.
We'll be back tomorrow.
Brian Red Band and A.