Yeah,
I'm here with my brother,
Daniella,
but lily,
one of the few men who can pull off a
union gang Bandana,
like some renegade bike or on an episode
of Grey's anatomy.
Look at that fucking thing,
but you,
you fucking balance it out with a Frank
Frazetta,
Conan the barbarian tee shirt.
That shirt is the shit.
Where'd you pick that up?
Oh Man.
I was looking all over the place for it.
They probably had it for like some of
the comic book store Milione are sickle
and I thought that was a dope shirt.
I might have to hide that one for my
wife because she probably tried to throw
it out.
Why?
I don't know.
You know women are men.
Come on.
This contains Saturday decent.
That's good in life.
Maybe it's time to grow up.
Maybe you shouldn't have a comic book
guy and your shirt.
It's not a fucking comic book.
It's an.
It's a novel.
Robert e Dot Howard wrote a series of
novels.
It's about Conan the barbarian.
People don't know.
It's like my entire life philosophy is
based off of our barrier like galaxies
called mentoree.
You can get in trouble for that kind of
philosophy.
Crombs a good God could obviously solid
because he doesn't give a fuck of here
to help you.
Nope.
Not going to save you.
That's the beauty of the color.
It's very real.
You know,
it's like,
Hey,
life is tough deal to fuck with it
because that's the way it's going to be.
Yet there are horrible things that can
happen.
Yet there's no guarantees about the
afterlife.
Yeah,
all of that.
But in the meantime,
there are women.
There's red wine,
there's enemies to be killed,
or Marty wants probably parasites,
all sorts of weird diseases.
Nobody's ever diagnosed yet that parties
did last year as I feel you're lucky you
live to 30.
It's kind of amazing when they keep
finding these new species of people,
you know,
there was,
um,
they've just,
they had this article yesterday where
they're,
they've examined the teeth,
the teeth of the Hobbit,
people on the island of Flores.
And so now they're like,
you know,
99 point nine percent positive.
It's 100 percent,
not 99 point nine percent positive.
One hundred percent,
but 99 point nine percent positive that
it's a completely different species of
human being.
They found the teeth of these things and
you've got to think like that's the only
like 14,000
years ago,
you know,
and we don't even remember those things.
They're there.
They've sort of become like this weird
little legend,
like how many different versions of
people were out there and what a hard
scrabble life it must have been extinct.
Shootings,
the name of the game.
I mean,
when you think about it,
like overwhelming majority of pieces
that I've ever been around.
They've all gone extent.
Yeah.
More than 90 percent,
right?
Yep.
So it's uh,
yeah,
it's uh,
that's my point.
Calling on the throats,
you know,
with,
with bear claws,
runs neck.
That's a fucking awesome picture.
Yeah.
That's why I it in my house as a
pollster,
I might have to be obsessed.
I have a bunch of his old books for
Zetas,
old books like sketch books and books
that are collections of his paintings.
And God,
that kind of art that he did was just so
indicative of that time.
It was like so 19 seventies fantasy art,
you know those days,
man,
you know,
but no one has really captured it
correctly in a movie.
They just have not done it right.
You didn't,
you didn't think of.
The first one was fun and it was campy,
but it was more like the comic book.
Then it was like the books.
I think Jason Mamoa was the best version
of cone and physically he looked just
the beginning that it was dog shit.
Shameful.
Their movie was dog shit.
That guy is awesome.
I love that.
Jason Mamoa.
He's great.
In game of thrones.
He was.
He seemed like the most likely Conan
might have to get them on the Jews
though.
I know there's that to get them on some
fucking heavy duty powerlifting program
where he has to look a little more yoked
because Conan was just supposedly
ridiculously impressive as a person.
I knew in fact,
when they put power and old as the first
one that's kind of high.
That sets the bar pretty high right
away.
But.
But Arnold was built incorrectly.
He had all these unnecessary like big
titty muscles,
like you know,
you need a guy who's built more like
Yoel Romero,
like a,
like a barbarian Yoel Romero.
The sword was me just to say that.
But you're here and I want you to feel
embarrassed.
It's okay.
I can accept limits.
It's fine.
So tell me about your book man.
Not Afraid,
uh,
on fear,
heartbreak,
raising a baby girl and cage fighting.
That's an unusual combination of things.
That's what makes it interesting.
No,
I mean,
to me these was um,
oldest stuff I've written so far.
What's going to have more Fritos,
Alfie,
cutting nature,
DC's a bit more personal.
These is very much um,
my life.
It's sort of divided up into three
parts.
The first part is about dealing with
Fiori martial arts and he's kind of like
my experience.
Self stumps with the testing.
The boundaries are getting crashed.
Try again to find a way to make a deal
with the skating feeling of when you
have somebody coming in at you always
been training for the last few years and
wants to take your head off and you're
like,
shit,
this is a little intimidating.
There's all the pressure of people
watching you.
The idea of getting fees if you fuck up
and getting fuzzy,
cuddly dominated by another man,
which is never a fun feeling.
That kind of shift and so that's that
part.
But then to me that fire just serves as
a spring board for the other stuff which
is about.
That's good age when you are on the
match when you're in the cage for that
stuff.
But what about the rest of life and in
this case,
you know,
part tool deals with what happened with
my wife,
you know Betty Quique,
a guy,
all of a southern.
What the fuck is going
on in your bodies are falling apart,
diagnosed with brain tumor that within
six months from the time the first scene
Don came up.
So it was really quick,
really harsh.
When will the stuff that you may imagine
with debts and then the power three sort
of,
okay,
now what you know,
what do I do with it now and life
afterwards when when my wife died,
my daughter was 19 months old,
the old,
this shit was happening as you might
imagine,
and so it's like in some way that the
story elements kind of go together is
like the martial art part was circled
for water mop in terms of learning some
things that then I would have to apply
on a much bigger,
more important scale in day to day life
and then you know,
when shit hits the fan and then
afterwards would.
That changes my attitude about sayings,
my life overall and,
and you know,
when I was talking with publishers or
regionality,
they wanted a nice pretty arch or you
start out as the scared we wimp and then
you discover the secrets and then you'll
come back and Yardi,
fearless guy will go through life
without fear.
And that's bullshit.
I mean it's.
I like to sell it that way.
That would sound cool,
but I'm not in the business of bullshit
in my saddle for anybody else.
So I'm like,
it's not the seven steps to get rid of.
Fear is not that stuff.
It's a,
to me,
my experience self dealing with fear,
he's a fucking constant battle.
You know,
it's like you wake up a,
um,
you woke up one day and maybe you will
learn to deal with it.
The zero point zero one percent better
and that's a win and that the next day a
tto again,
and you have to deal with it again.
Like for me in particular,
what afterwards,
what happened is the reality of
realizing that everything is fleeting.
Everything can be taken away from you.
Everything you care about can go in the
snap of a finger.
That really freaked me out.
You know that I use one thing to know it
intellectually is one thing when it hits
home for real.
And so once in a while,
you know,
I left my days when I'm totally fine,
I feel strong,
I feel great,
and then all of a sudden will hit me
when the thought of men,
everybody I love will die.
There's,
I've limited control of what's going to
happen in my life.
Everything I care about can be taken
away from me in a second shift.
Welcome to your day.
Now deal with the next 24 hours is like
savvy.
And so dealing with that aspect,
finding ways to and you know,
and then I find a way to do it.
And then a month later we'll hit you
again.
And maybe because you found a way to do
it before he actually delay.
But don't you think that's everybody?
There's no one.
This is a false narrative that someone's
figured out how to get rid of fear.
It doesn't exist.
If you have no fear,
that means that you're not experiencing
any danger or anything unknown.
And somehow or another you're a mortal.
Yep.
Because if you think about the
consequences of death,
you're going to get nervous.
You're going to get afraid if you're
taking any sort of risks or chances,
you're going to get nervous.
It's part of being a person.
Part of it's part of what's fun about
getting things done in,
in succeeding is knowing all the mental
roadblocks that are in place to keep you
from being successful big time,
and that's the way today.
They affect everybody.
So to me,
this is just,
you know,
these,
my experience,
but he's like,
it's not that I have any illusion that
a,
I'm fighting battles that are unknown to
other people because the reality is that
everybody has shit to deal with.
Know every body has horrible things
happen to them.
Every body and you know,
horrible may Vadie for one person to the
next.
You may be slightly luckier than the
next guy,
but the reality is that everybody deal
with it.
So the question of how do you deal with
it?
What are the things that I help you get
the job done and which ones?
That's one of the great things about
martial arts,
the dealing with the fear and the
pressure and stress of training.
It helps mitigate some of the pressures
and stresses of everyday life.
That's.
That's exactly.
That's why,
you know,
when I went to some publishers
initially,
they were like,
ah,
you know,
the,
your wife life.
After we got that part about what the
fact is,
martial art I've had to do with data.
I'm like,
and it says everything to do with it,
you know,
because those are the same dynamics,
but I get to train them in a safe space,
know martial art contest and then you
apply them to the real game.
I'm the big girl scaling.
It's a controlled space and in terms of
it's going to happen at 8:30
on Tuesday nights.
You get in there,
you know,
it's like you can prepare for you eat
for you,
make sure you have your meal is digested
in your stomach before you get there.
You have a cup of coffee before you get
to the gym.
You stretch out,
you prepare yourself and then you go
through it.
But,
but in doing that it,
it definitely helps.
You know,
I've,
I've had so many twitter messages and
facebook messages and people that I meet
after shows that told me that they
started Jujitsu after listening to this
podcast and it changed their life and
that it helps them so much and deal with
pressure and now in pursuing a health,
a healthy lifestyle.
Like even guys like Anthony Bourdain who
was in his fifties,
I believe he was 58 when he started
Jujitsu,
the eight,
58,
57 or 58.
Um,
he was a lifetime smoker.
Heroin user,
I'm like pretty much like abused
everything.
Alcohol,
everything now is way more healthy.
He's off.
I talked to them off statens off of high
blood pressure medication,
lost 30 pounds just from training,
eats healthy,
still likes to party it up a little bit.
A little bows on.
But I'm,
the guy looks great.
He looks great and he's obsessed with
Jujitsu and he loves it and it's sort of
transformed his life.
You know,
his wife is a phenom.
Yeah.
So I saw she's a beast.
She trains every day.
I mean,
she's essentially,
I mean she's,
that's her life.
Her life was training.
She loves him and uh,
it just got them,
it got them.
She said that she talked him into doing
it by promising him narcotics,
which is one of the most hilarious
stories ever.
She said like,
if you,
if you come to train with me,
I'll give you some vicodin.
I'm in Nice.
Well he's the one of the few guys
that has been like a self professed
junkie but was not only able to kick it,
but you know,
still get high,
still drink and obviously doesn't have a
problem.
It's very healthy.
It doesn't do anything when he's at home
and you know,
when he's on the road in filming a show
and the fillings done and he'll,
you know,
have a few drinks or even while filming,
you know.
But uh,
it's not like he's got a problem.
It's definitely is now a problem.
I've hung out with him.
He's,
he's,
he's healthy.
Hey,
that's as good as it gets.
You've got to fire tea without paying
the price.
But it's amazing because everybody has
this idea where most people that are in
recovery that you can't do anything
right.
It was very few people I know that we'll
do something like,
I know a few guys who had alcohol
problems,
we'll smoke a little pot,
but uh,
or,
you know,
do a little mushrooms every now and then
or something like that.
But he's one of those guys that he'll,
he'll do everything other than the
heroin.
You know what I mean?
If you can do that,
I think he's everybody's psychology
psychologist.
Different.
Some people,
once they opened the door a tiny bit,
right.
Can Tell Dan I need to open it all the
way.
I kind of stopped.
But then if you know your,
that kind of person yet,
then don't open into tiny bits then you
shouldn't.
But if you are not,
then what the hell is wrong with
enjoying a little bit if it really does.
I think it depends person to person.
Some people can do it that other people
have to go cold Turkey or they can't.
Yeah,
that's definitely,
that's definitely true.
It's um,
it's just cool to see someone do
something positive always is because it
gives you.
Inspiration is a real fuel for human
beings.
When you see your friends or someone you
know that you like and they're doing
something that's really transforming
them and helping them,
it fires you up to.
Yeah.
I'm like the biggest way and every time
I see you're the cheesiest the
speciation of do I start crying like a
baby.
I'm like,
move it.
It's everybody sitting.
Go like that to such pitch.
I don't cry over sad shit that much
though.
It's weird,
but it's.
My cat died.
I didn't cry.
I knew I've had her for 19 years.
I felt bad.
I felt sad,
but I felt like,
well she lived a great life and she was
a cool cat.
The but um,
it's not like if something cool happens,
something cool happens.
I'm like,
wow,
you know?
Yeah,
I'll have the same thing,
but it's like,
I think it would be like,
come on,
can I afford it?
That's what a bitch.
Where does chrom hang out?
These colleges having another.
He has a different place,
right?
I forget where it is.
They mix the toppling Balaji's though.
They played Lewis,
but yeah,
I don't remember what crumb,
where chrome hung out.
Civy already human heads.
I was giving me a hard time on twitter
the other day and it just for a Goof,
he was spelling was so atrocious.
I was like,
oh my God,
what does this go into?
Like I love it when people get mad at me
over.
It was like a Ted Cruz posts.
He got mad over a.
So I went to his twitter page and uh,
I was just reading these posts about him
looking up into the heavens.
Wondering what,
you know,
what God is like living in the clouds.
Like this motherfucker serious.
Like,
dude,
we could.
You could drive a fucking plane through
the clouds,
asshole.
All right.
There's nothing up there.
That shit was back when people didn't
have planes right now that we have
planes.
You can't say that.
God's right up there,
man in the closet.
No,
no,
no.
Fucking southwest is up there going
right through the clouds with a jet and
they give it out.
Free.
Peanuts.
EBC Dog got docking trying to avoid the
planes.
And Tim it,
these Ted Cruz motherfuckers are scary.
They got a little victory under their
belt and Iowa and they're doubling down
on the Bible readings.
That's scary to me.
Oh,
that fucking guy.
Then we'll kind of take party socks,
but that I probably come parked has gone
so far off band that is just downright
nuts.
Well,
did you ever see that guy tweeted a
quote the other day from Barry Goldwater
were barren,
cold water back in the fifties.
It recognize that there was an issue
with preachers and ministers in getting
involved in the Republican Party,
that they would ruin it.
I know.
That's the scary thing is that you'll go
back 50 years to the guys work when see
that are not Kansas back in the day and
they would be considered moderate
centrist today.
They'd be like,
oh,
Barry Goldwater.
What the reasonable voice.
He would always.
He was the one that was warning against
it.
Right?
But no,
exactly.
That's what I mean.
He's like,
he had some positions that were three
men,
but he will set a bunch of others that
were very,
very reasonable the way it made sense,
you know,
and today he will be seen as fucking
liberality.
Yeah,
it's a,
this,
these are strange times where it's the
most,
it's kind of strange because this is the
most advanced,
uh,
as far as our ability to access
information.
It's never been like this before and as
far as our ability to access studies and
find out the actual real scientific
facts about certain things.
But this is like,
it's more important now to profess a
love or a belief in God when you're
running for president,
I think,
than ever than ever.
You have to say it.
Like everybody has to say it.
Yeah.
There's never been one sad guy who could
just skirt the question and not discuss
it.
You have to go in and believe what I
believe or not believe what I believe
because I'm about to give you not want
to make sure that is like,
I thought I just stay away from the
political discussions because they are.
There's no point in the weekend about
zero point one sec when it becomes,
fuck you,
fuck you.
And it's just there's not even a.
yeah,
there's not even like I get it.
If we had to eat our school and through
oversee,
okay,
that can be fun.
It can be interesting to hell.
We can even let her for some stuff from
each other,
but that's not even that point is just
pure crazy extremist insults back and
forth and I'm like,
just as my all time favorite election
all time.
Oh,
it's the stupidest yet.
Is the shittiest choices.
The least inspired candidates.
This is the best one for me.
This is the best.
That's the only thing.
He had a whole show going on about
how happy he was that Donald trump was
in the race for the entertainment factor
that does it because he was sick.
He was making a good point because they
say look,
like in the primaries,
for example,
in the Republican primaries,
the game is you have to go zero point.
One millimeter more conservative than
the next guy when the primaries,
but you don't want to go too far because
otherwise you lose the janitor of the
lecture and you have trampled steps in
and it goes like 20 yards past everybody
else.
Everybody else is like,
shit,
if I don't follow you,
but lose the primary,
but if I follow him,
I'm done in the general.
So that was having a blast with that.
He was laughing.
Which episode is a.
is a common sense or is either.
Why not?
Maybe after the first Republican debate,
that's what he was.
God,
I got to go listen to that throat.
I mean,
that's.
That's the way it is.
Well,
Donald Trump has nothing to lose.
Yeah.
I don't think he really wants to be
president.
I really don't think he does and I think
that's why he's so outrageous,
but I think along the way he's kind of
fucked himself because this is what
people have been asking for.
People for the longest time have wanted
someone believe him or don't believe I'm
agree with him or don't agree with him.
He's speaking his mind right when he's
saying he's saying because he doesn't
give a fuck.
There's no filter whatsoever.
He's talking about Mexicans.
Well,
someone's doing the raping.
Fuck,
this guy's running for president.
It's time for putting a wall up like
some fucking Berlin Wall up between us
and Mexico.
Like,
Holy Shit,
man,
that seems reasonable.
Does it?
It's going to let Railo that over the
rapists one does.
There's no represent.
Well,
someone's doing the raping.
Someone's doing the raping here.
Jesus Christ.
That was half of the sixth grade.
You can't even.
You can check like maybe a non on site
or it's hard to keep track of which was
started.
Odl was bullshit.
Well,
because they are so similar that it was
wide where they asked him something
about what does it take to make a,
make America great again.
Adhere had through this whole speech
where he's clearly not answered.
You know,
he said running around just throwaway
toward salad.
That had nothing to do with the question
at that.
He tends with him going like,
oh,
I look at the police turned up.
That's an awesome at it.
Like this.
Like I've got to leave with this
question because I don't want to deal
with it.
They look at the guy with the
announcement.
Yeah,
well he's a good medium man.
He's very good at.
He's been doing interviews for years and
he's also been on that reality show for
a long time.
You got fired from it while running for
this election because of the
inflammatory stuff.
He said about Mexicans though.
It's a.
But I agree with you and this is
entertaining it past the point of being
to the point that it's entertaining.
That's why I would dig a agenda that
Sean tramping sanders because at that
point teacher so wild and weird that
he's enjoyable.
You got,
you know,
the professional guys were like,
they measure every single statement,
uh,
you know,
the politically internet.
It's,
it's boring.
You can write or the radio every single,
you know already
what's going to happen,
right?
It's with someone.
These guys,
you have no idea what the hell is going
to come out of their mouth.
It's makes it for,
hey,
at least I got to watch something that
doesn't put me to sleep there.
Well,
you want to talking about putting me to
sleep,
Hillary Clinton puts me to sleep because
there's nothing inspiring about what
she's saying.
Nothing inspiring about her presence or
her speeches,
but I think my daughter,
my seven year old daughter said it best.
She goes,
I would vote for her because she's a
girl.
That's a lot of people feel like that.
I know.
Like fuck it.
We had a black man.
Let's have a white girl.
Right.
But it's like maybe you can pick some,
but okay,
sure.
You want that.
Pick somebody back there.
Jesus just who's better?
Elizabeth Warren.
Nine.
She's not in anymore.
Right?
She,
she dropped out,
but when she was running they found out
that she wasn't really native American
and she tried to fake that.
You get a scholarship or something for
that.
I think that's what he was the,
the drop down the hall of fake.
That's one thing you can't fake.
You can fake like you're one eighth
Swedish.
They will give you a hard time about it.
But if you say you one eighth,
native American and Torres on.
Oh No,
that's fucking native American is like
noble and mystical and you have like
magic fucking eagle power.
So you can hear like a wolf that if you
watch all the 19 sixties movies,
they were like Batty Indians will come
into sculpture and chop your head off.
Why?
Because they already know what the fuck
knows why.
It's like the dragon in the story,
right?
Pulse 19 sixties is old.
Hug the furry creatures of the forest.
I have a visual and said it's not what
it was.
It was the guy in the commercial that
cried when he saw the ground,
the garbage on the ground.
Oh,
that's what it was.
And incidentally that guy too was fucked
up is that that guy in that commercial
where the Indians crying because white
men are littering,
but we from the sixties on,
we've sort of associated native
Americans like spiritual things like
dream catchers and this guy,
that guy is a Guinea.
He's from fucking name.
The same island has me looking at me and
his canoe is seeing the pick it up.
You fucking driving right past it.
You don't have to just look at it.
Dude,
throw it away.
Jesus Christ.
Give a hoot.
Don't pollute,
but give a damn.
Pick that shit up man.
And he would,
he would pull up in his stupid fucking
buffalo skin canoes and cry.
That was new.
But guys,
so Italian,
he could be on the sopranos that made
them wear a wig and shit.
Yep.
People are throwing things out the
window right at his feet and he could
ice.
Oh,
it could all go to Bonnie fuel.
I don't cry too.
Something about keep America beautiful.
Yeah.
Well it definitely shouldn't be like
hanging out by the highway either.
So yeah,
it doesn't tell.
Just standing there was moccasins on and
shit.
Yeah.
But,
but native Americans from like that
point on where they're associated with
like a sweat lodge is pod ceremonies and
spiritual things and you know,
we have these ideas.
There's a lot of people,
they have these ideas of native
Americans that they lived off the land
and they used every last piece of the
animal and they had a spiritual
connection to their surroundings,
which,
you know,
a lot of is true.
There's a lot of truth in that,
but that's the problem with stereotypes,
right?
You take 17,
that's partially true,
and then you blow it up the entirety of
the experience,
so torn with the carrier at that point
is very far from debbie out of the deal.
Well my friend,
Steven Rinella,
the host of the mediator has the best
stories of native Americans.
He has a deep knowledge of the history
of native Americans and he's got some
fantastic stories about the Nez perce.
First of all,
they were fucking cannibals.
Alright.
That was super common to not only attack
neighboring tribes,
but to eat them,
eat their babies,
eat their family.
Yeah,
eat them rail.
Yeah.
There was a lot of cannibalism going on
in the old west,
especially apparently amongst the Great
Lakes area in the Great Lakes area.
That's for sure.
Why is that?
Is it just because it's called know
different people?
You know?
It's kind of like the culture.
In fact,
that's why it's hard to generalize with
distinctions among native stuff is so
much difference.
You know,
the guys put on them to Great Lakes have
nothing to do with the guys from the
plains to do with.
So each one is.
But yeah,
good.
A plague stuff is pretty intense.
The fire that I liked the most about
that is on you will,
would go out to get captives,
you know,
you will go on at wateraid,
you'll get copies this and once you see
you get captured,
you have one of two options.
If they like you,
then they adopt you as a family member.
You replace one of their dead family
members so you get treated that way.
You are love you.
They don't like you so much.
Then they torture you through that over
a four day period.
So it's,
yeah,
it's blitzing skydeck,
but it's kind of a flip of a coin data,
which I guess are lyrically clean.
Tony was a good thing,
but for everybody else,
not so much.
Yeah.
He told me the story of this one guy got
captured.
There was two guys captured.
One Guy,
they killed him,
killed him in front of his friend,
and then they told him,
I think they might've aid them in front
of his friend too.
They killed them and then they told him,
we're going to take off all your
clothes.
We're going to let you run and if you
can get away you can live.
And so this mother ran like the wind
jumped in the freezing cold river and
hidden a beaver dam.
Nope.
He got smart enough to climb up into a
beaver dam,
which by the way is a risk and a fucking
half because what if it climb in there
and the beavers in there that beavers
gonna fuck you up.
People have died from before.
If beaver bites your artery leader or
shoot,
they shoot the retreat.
That will fuck you up.
And uh,
this guy,
he fucking made it and he walked for
days and some ungodly amount of miles
naked by the way,
freezing cold,
lived off of whatever he grabbed and
stuff in his mouth and eat that.
And I managed to survive some crazy way
and lived to tell the story.
Some of the.
That's what
I dig like for history on fire,
those kind of stories that are so like,
it's like,
come on the screenwriter from game of
thrones,
throne that right,
it can be real and then you dig it and
he's like,
no,
there's reality and there's wars and
it's more intense than anything you
could imagine the revenant.
Isn't that based on a real story and.
Yeah,
it's um,
yeah,
that don't.
Is that guy as bigly entail?
They kind of tailored it a little bit,
you know,
there was no Indian song and there was
none of that power to.
It's always an Indian.
I know there's no sell it to white
people.
You've got to throw an Indian in there.
The them like they been into black elk
hunting and then the Grizzly fucking
game up or just two guys leaving for dad
and taking off even with this rifle.
That's all true.
But yeah,
they,
they tweak it a little bit.
Somebody needs to write a movie about
that suit Akins lady that lives up in
Alaska because that lady got,
she's the one who's on that show life
below zero.
I heard about it.
I guess she lives 200 miles plus above
the arctic circle in this place called
Kavach.
She was one of my guests.
She's amazing.
Amazing.
I mean,
she is as fucking gangster as a human
being can get by by just being awesome.
Just so cool.
He's a really nice,
intelligent woman,
you know,
she's,
she's just like so powerful.
Anyway,
she was up there and she got attacked by
a bear and fucked up real bad.
Broke her hip.
I think.
Broke her leg,
fucked her head up.
I think it cracked her skull like
serious,
serious injuries.
She survived.
She crawled back to her,
her dwelling.
She doesn't even live in a house because
where she lives,
you're not allowed to put permanent
residences.
So they're like 10 things that are up
there.
Yeah.
They're made out of cloth.
These like weird sort of buildings with
like wire structures and it's thick
canvas tops and she was there for days
before someone.
She owns like a refueling station up
there.
Someone flew in,
they found her,
they brought her to medical help and
patched her up,
fixed her up.
She heals up,
goes back,
shoots that bear and eats it.
That's the way he wanted to do it.
That pitches gangster as fuck.
Yeah.
You imagine eating a bear just cutting
into the you motherfucker.
Not So cocky.
That's a bad ass revenge tale.
Let's do it.
Fuck yeah,
man.
To her watching the revenant.
He's like,
yeah,
that's Thursday morning.
Whatever.
Come on Pussy.
I mean,
it's amazing.
The cloth fan.
Norco for the Arctic.
I mean that we Mahal for would be with
right.
She's a grandma.
A.
Yeah,
of course.
He's like pinched the gun kids,
so I've seen the bear's heart.
Jesus Christ.
She's crazy.
Yeah,
but that's what she enjoys.
She enjoys living out there in the
wilderness with the wolves and foxes and
the bears and the Caribou.
She loves it.
She loves going out and shooting or
meals
and bringing them home and cutting it
does all the butchering.
All the food she gets,
she gets from the land around her.
She's just a wild.
It's just like the life she loves.
She found it and,
and she's smart man.
Like she could do a lot of shit.
She's not a in an unresourceful person
who's trapped up there.
She just really truly enjoys it.
That's a choice native person,
which is absolutely fascinating person.
She's one of my favorite all time
guests.
I need to move back to Danielle.
He bought his course.
I need to go back and catch that one.
I think I saw he was there and I didn't
catch it too.
I need to listen again,
so he's amazing.
Myself or I missed it.
I would like to go up there and hang out
with her.
She sounded awesome.
I would have to go up there in the
winter though.
Otherwise it'd be a pussy.
You can't go up there.
Hey Kim in July,
but I bet it's cold fucking July to.
Yeah,
exactly too,
but I think.
What is the time of year where you go to
see the Aurora Borealis?
The northern lights?
I haven't been.
I don't know.
I think that is a summer thing.
Is that a summer thing or is that an all
year round thing?
No idea.
I don't know either,
but that would be worth traveling just
to see.
That's supposed to be insane.
Yeah,
that's like the whole sky is filled with
green missed either died or you can stay
in La and take them out.
Shirt with sudden.
You've got to say,
but it's better,
right?
Yeah,
that's better.
You have to know that.
Just.
Do you ever been to Alaska?
No.
Never know.
What's crazy about it,
man?
It's how big it is when you fly over it,
you go like Jesus Christ and you look at
it on a map.
You're like,
what the fuck?
That place is?
I think it's the biggest state.
Is it the biggest?
Isn't really.
Yeah,
by far.
Jamie says.
Yeah,
I think it's like almost too Texas's.
Seriously.
They do some really shitty job with man.
Find out how many Texas's fit in Alaska.
Oh,
they do a shitty job with math does not
look like two times.
Texas.
Well,
if you ever seen how big Africa really
is,
like when people talk about Africa,
I think people get this idea that
Africa,
the continent of Africa is similar to
the continent of North America,
but it's not even close.
Look at this sick Jesus Christ twice the
size of Texas.
Yeah,
that is huge.
Damn.
Alaska is larger than all but 18
sovereign countries.
Holy Shit.
Look how big it is when you put it in
the middle of America.
Freaky fucking a man.
God.
It's huge and it's so lightly populated.
It's amazing.
I fucking love it up there.
I got to get back.
When was the last time?
Two years ago,
Ari Shaffir and I did a anchorage.
We did a comedy show up there and went
salmon fishing.
Saw some.
I saw my first movie I ever saw some
eagles for the first time.
That was awesome.
He goes,
or he told me that they were pretty
intense.
Oh,
there's.
So.
It's so strange when you look in a wild
eagle in the eye,
you know,
even though it's kind of far away and
they don't let you get that close to
them,
but when you're passing by,
we were on a boat and we're passing by
these trees and there's an eagle up in
the tree and you're like,
Whoa,
what the fuck?
I big fucking animals.
That's for sure.
They don't get hunted by people either,
so they're not afraid of people,
but you know,
they're not stupid either,
but that places a legitimately wild
place in that when you get out of your
car,
you have to run to where you're going.
Are you going to get swarmed by
mosquitoes that.
Yeah,
that's what I heard about.
That's the part that I didn't like about
Alaska.
I call it sound awesome.
And then I heard about the level of
like,
intensity is mosquito wise.
I was like,
yeah,
okay.
That Ari and I were laughing.
We couldn't even believe it.
Like this is ridiculous.
Like I'm not kidding,
like open up the car door.
Um,
put your boots on and just the time it
takes to open the door and get your
boots on the car is filled with
mosquitoes,
like hundreds of mosquitoes,
like a swarm.
They find you instantly.
What's about to climb out there that
attracts mosquitoes so much?
I think they're just fucking desperado
because they know they're only gonna be
alive for a month,
you know,
that's what I think.
And there's like three humans to buy it
and sanders.
Gotcha.
I think,
I mean,
do they bite other animals?
Right?
Definitely.
So I just don't think that they have
much time.
I think they only stay alive for a short
period of time,
so while they're at it,
they're addicts,
so they are berserker mosquitoes.
Just going for it then.
Well yeah,
that's a scary fucking place.
Fuel have.
Yeah.
More so than Florida.
You would think like Florida mosquitoes
would be the most rabid.
That's how you figure tropical place.
Lots of humidity.
All of the Florida people though they're
fat and lazy.
They could get these.
It's like,
ah,
there'd be another tourist.
I couldn't get that one.
I don't have to chase these one.
Yeah.
Florida has its own problems though,
man.
Florida is.
It's so funny.
They're doing a big python hunt now
because so many people have released
pythons in Florida that they,
they've bred and overread.
They have like a gigantic python
invasion problem to the point where
they're offering rewards for people to
kill Python's.
The headlines that come out of Florida,
one of the things that are at constant
stone source of entertainment,
you get things that are like,
again,
these must be the on your right.
It's too fucking crazy.
Then you it into like,
no,
that was real.
That really up and yeah,
there's a great twitter page called
Florida man and it's just filled every
day.
There's some new crazy shit some guy
tried to do while huffing paint.
Fucking dog.
It just,
it's not a real state.
What did I read?
What was the last thing?
Oh yeah.
This guy was um,
at all been a house and I think the
owners get back.
So the guy to call and they were looking
for anyway.
Flashlights like it dove in this pond
right outside alligator.
Exactly.
Yeah.
Team.
I've heard that before.
There was another one recently real
similar where they were chasing this guy
in a stolen car.
The guy gets to a bridge,
jumps off the bridge and immediately
gets jacked by an alligator,
like literally jumped on an alligator.
Good timing.
Good job man.
But you got to be fucking crazy to jump
in the water with those things,
man,
if you've seen.
Have you seen an alligator scared be big
ass fucking dinosaurs.
They're not as dangerous as Nile
crocodiles,
which coincidentally have also been
released in the everglades.
Good.
They have a shoot on sight kill on site
order.
If anybody sees a Nile,
crocodile is supposed to kill them
onsite because they've started to breed
in the everglades.
So you're talking about those 18,
20 foot long,
gigantic African crocodiles that take
out willdabeast yeah.
Let's say you live in Florida too.
Yeah,
that's a rough state.
It's funny man,
because all the tree huggers,
they're like,
don't kill the pythons.
Not Their fault.
Like,
okay,
you know how big pythons kit you crazy
bitch.
They're gonna.
Eat your family.
They'll.
They'll eat babies,
they eat people.
Fuck man.
Florida.
The joys of nature.
I've been watching narcos on Netflix.
Thinks about it.
So good.
I'm sad because there's only two
episodes left and I don't know if
they're doing a second season.
I don't know if they can.
I mean,
I think Pablo Escobar gets caught.
I think that's the end of that,
unless it goes on further.
I don't know though.
I wasn't totally aware of the entire
story of Escobar.
I just knew that he was a drug dealer
and I knew,
fuck man,
those guys.
Look,
it's so well done to the show.
So.
Well done.
Yeah,
no,
that's a.
that's on my watch list because I ever
done it.
Every single person I talked to told me
to tell someone that one insane he went
to war.
I mean I don't really want to tell
anybody anything about it because it's
fucking shocking and it builds up really
well.
Like it really builds up well from the
early days of his drug dealer.
Just finding out about drugs to the end.
But that's what's funny about it that
people got old like,
oh the Kadima now the mafia,
that when you look at like mafia
stories,
they are identical to the history of any
state or if any nation,
you know,
it.
Just the dynamics that are.
Did you know wine is in a suit and tie.
The other one is with the AK 47,
but other than that,
the bezirk seeing.
Sorry,
it's a struggle for power.
It's a game off fuck over your enemies
sheets.
The other one who can get you do what
you can expand your.
It's the same story over and over.
Whether you're talking about that
extended to great or fabulous go buyer
is not that different.
Really know the specifics are slightly
different,
but the big picture is not.
It's a struggle for power.
End of story and it seems like when you
get to the really high levels of finance
and of volume and the amount of troops
in the amount of people that you're
controlling the area control,
that's when the real trostle he's
kicking like you almost.
It's almost a universal that horrific
acts get done to intimidate your enemy
and to make sure that you retain control
over certain certain areas.
Yeah,
it's hard to sing.
Where is like in that sense you might.
History's really kind of fucked up and
weird when you.
If you approach it with them through a
moral lens because you see so many nasty
things take place and in the weird ones
are the ones who were.
There really is no good solution where
you don't know what the healthy thing
would be like.
There's one that I was researching for a
history on fire maybe a year from now or
something.
I was searching distorted from the 19
eighties in El Salvador.
At that time there was a a right wing
government in El Salvador to the US
government was supporting and there was
a leftist gallery are there was in the
logic of the cold war.
There are only two options here,
either protocol,
Muni story,
our pro us.
There's nothing in between.
Right?
So in the process of fighting these
leftist Galleria,
the government of El Salvador is doing
nasty things right to anybody will
criticize them,
doesn't matter whether they're a
communist or not.
To get tortured that chop off their
bodies will leave them in the middle of
the streets.
American Congress at that point because
like,
oh shit,
you know,
we can really keep sending millions of
dollars to.
These guys were doing horrible human
rights violations,
so they pass this law that in order for
any more aid to be sent to the governor
of the sound of other,
the president of the United States has
to sign off on a document stating that
these guys have made huge improvements
in their human rights record,
that they are on the right path,
you know it's getting better.
Problem is the deadline is coming up
that a gun is each and to be able to
send out all these millions of dollars
to the government of itself rather and
in that moment,
the Salvadorian army on these offensive
against the gallery and they find some
villages that just wanted to be left the
fuck alone.
They were not pro communist,
but they are not anticommunist theater.
They were like bunch of Evangelical
Christians,
peasants who just wanted to farm their
fields and be left alone so he.
They will lead.
The communists go through.
They will let the army go through to
figure if we stay neutral.
Everything works out right?
Well,
not in the Cold War and the Cold War.
There is no neutrality are either on one
side or the other,
so Salvadorian army come in,
grab every single villagers,
separate the men from the women,
kilos demand or April.
The women don't kill them all,
kill everybody in that village and New
York Times.
The New York Times did an article on it
and I'm now.
Reagan was like,
Oh shit,
what do I do now?
So he said,
the guy who wrote this article,
it some crazy communist.
None of these is through is a smear
campaign against our allies.
The government has made huge
improvements.
I'm sending that millions of dollars of
course years down the road and saw that
the original story,
it was through that the staff did that
happen and the but other than bitching
about Reagan,
this is not even an anti Reagan thing is
that it's a messy situation because you
do support the government of Assad
rather.
You're literally supporting death
squads.
Child rapists mean it doesn't really get
any worse than that.
You don't support them.
There's a chance that hillside rather
who turn into a communist state,
in which case he's not exactly like
communism around the world is a higher
reputational for human rights.
It's fucking awful.
Right?
So he's like,
what do you choice here?
No,
the you choose to support them or do you
choose?
It's like,
how do you see what I'm going like?
It's a situation where no matter what
you choose,
you're fucked.
You're doing bad things.
But clearly the moment our support in
death squads that can not be the right
solution,
but at the same time,
what is the right solution?
What is the good thing you should do?
You know,
character at the same exact problem.
You know?
Right before Reagan Carter,
some guide,
the Archbishop of El Salvador,
this guy,
Oscar Romero sent him a letter saying,
stop fucking sending money to my
government because they are doing
horrible things with it cart.
I was like,
Eh,
I don't want to look at this because
this is politically traveling for me.
So two weeks later that squats,
walking into the main church and outside
of authorities,
guy was celebrating mass.
They gunned him down,
killed him,
so he's not a Republican or democratic
thing,
you know,
it's like both sides of the game.
They are did not know how to handle this
in a situation where it's like which
mass murderers and we support and which
ones do we oppose because that's the
reality of it was like those are the
stories or like what the fuck do you do?
What is the right thing to do?
Windows case,
there almost is no right thing.
Right,
exactly.
When you're dealing with certain parts
of the world that have been embattled,
they've been just in inter tangled in
these horrible bitter feuds and
rivalries.
Horrible things get done and war and
when you're dealing with two horrible
groups and you can't really
differentiate substantially one being
more moral or ethical that over the
other one and oftentimes like if you
were more and more or more ethical,
you wouldn't survive in those terrible
environments.
Like you have to do horrible things just
in order to stay above water and that's
what keeps it.
The stories keep you on your toes
because if you condemned wine and not
the other yarn,
paypal credit,
if you can.
Then the other,
the first year and a booklet,
if we get even to what we are seeing,
which is the right thing,
right,
is like,
well,
it's a fucked up situation and you have
to do terrible things.
If you say too easily,
it's like,
oh yeah,
well,
so go chop.
The kids had had off no big deal.
So you have to,
you say Baylor,
so safe to say the opposite.
It's like it's a weird dynamic there
where there's no real place where you
feel comfortable.
Like,
ah,
that was the right thing to do.
I can glad we made the right call.
Now I can go through easy and stuff.
Well,
let me ask you this because you're a
legit historian.
Was there ever a time in human history
where there was like a noble ethical
government of any sort of,
uh,
an empire or country that didn't engage
in any human rights and did the right
thing?
Like was there a utopian government and
anytime in history?
No,
I think you've got these different
degrees of fucking up.
Some degrees they're like,
ah,
that's not that bad.
Come on.
We can.
We can live with that,
but we can live with.
That does not mean it's good.
It's still kind of Shitty is just a lot
less shitty than the alternatives
outside of modern times.
What's the most Utopian version of a
government that ever sort of ran?
I think what you get is in you do around
into society.
Swear may be like for example,
if you have low population,
vancity hunters,
I'm glad that are,
but the keyword being low population
density because once you have too many
people,
they compete for hunting grounds and
they do horrible things to each other,
but if you have a relatively low
population density,
these guys,
there's really no reason to go to war
with another tribe over wealth because
they are nomadic.
You have to fucking carry it on your
back.
You don't want.
I don't want your shit.
They have to carry it to them.
That's part of the work,
so you don't do.
You don't fight over weld.
You don't fight over religion because
most of these guys have have kind of
inclusive approach where whatever you do
that works good for you.
There's no competition there,
so you have removed two huge things that
people do nasty things to each other
over.
They're still fighting over.
I'm hunting grounds.
They're still fighting over women,
so that will still happen,
but so it's not an idea like utopia.
Oh,
those noble hunters and gatherers who
could do no wrong.
No,
they did horrible things to each other.
They just have less reasons to do so.
Then later societies,
so agriculture in cities and
civilizations,
that's when things started getting
really rough.
Well,
I mean,
again,
it's the placenta mine Australian
glasses because you stay in one place
and you can accumulate wealth.
Now I don't have to carry every single
human on my back.
Every few days I can sit in one place in
the coma late.
Well,
you do start seeing the growth of social
class as you do.
Start seeing.
I mean,
I'm a hunters and gatherers.
You don't have reach hunter and gather
under poor line.
You know,
everybody's kind of on the same game.
When you become sedentary,
you can accumulate wealth and so you do
start seeing these game played out in
the good way.
You know,
people who have the resources to
dedicate themselves to staff other than
working for a living and so on and in a
horrible way.
We told the nastiness that take place
over the fighting over.
I want your shade is a little terrier
family in order to get what I want.
You know,
so it's,
that's why to me,
when you read those and as usual with
human beings,
there's always a good and bad kind of
logic is you have.
The guys were like,
man,
Petey,
Yoga,
culture sock.
He was a horrible,
harsh life where it was terrible and
every and how can I call it?
You're a devotee body and states are
wonderful and all that.
There's an element of truth to that and
there's also an element that's not and
vice versa.
The Guy,
White Lis hunters and guides that are
says the best you once ever,
and they could do no wrong.
It's like up to a point,
you know,
even both scenarios,
there are some huge advantages in some
huge these advantages.
He just that they change which ones they
are.
Yeah,
when you get so much wealth and so much
prosperity that you start getting
royalty when you start getting people
that accumulate massive amounts of
wealth and then they have this
incredible ability to control all the
people around them and everyone's
fearful of them because they have
ultimate power that can have you killed
instantly and face no repercussions.
I was reading
this article about this guy who is some
Middle Eastern print and he was living
in Beverly Hills.
Did you hear about this guy and you want
to do sexually assaulting people that
worked for him and they arrested him and
then he fled the country that we gotta
wait,
wait.
He was saying like,
you know,
you can't do shit to me.
I'm a prince,
you know,
and he's like saying that to them like
was 2016 and he's still like,
I'm a prince.
Should I know that wasn't even one like
that.
Fuck,
I wish I remembered the details.
I kind of lost them,
I think.
I don't want to say.
Well,
there was two of them real recently.
There was one,
maybe you will remember it,
but the right.
There was one where to justification was
didn't rape her.
I fail on air and I just had been to
Bri.
Was that dye penetrate those in the UK
though?
That was in the UK.
The wars.
The fencing to history.
Like if you can come out,
let out.
Are we going to defend this guy?
Let's be Goodi thought like she was
under age.
Yeah.
You'll get laughed out of the room like
the defense ever and he got acquitted.
See if you can find that.
He fell on her and how did they acquit
him?
They,
whoever was on that jury,
I guess it was a jewelry or whatever.
Who the judges follow that guy forever.
I wouldn't say that their bank accounts
for somewhere.
You're going to find a hole in the
ground where the bag of gold.
Here it is,
British Manitoba Police.
He may have penetrated teenager after
falling on top of her cleared of rape.
Whoa.
Was a British millionaire who told the
police may have pantry,
teenager,
director fall on top of,
has been cleared of rape,
a try saying that name as Han Abdulaziz
was accused of forcing him,
said,
oh,
she was 18,
18 as she slept on the Sofa in his
Lincoln apartment after a night of
drinking at an exclusive nightclub when
he was questioned,
the 46 year old businessman said he had
slipped and fallen on top of the girl,
which may have caused his penis to
penetrate her.
I'm fragile.
I fell down,
but nothing ever happened to me and this
girl,
I'm fragile so I can keep my balance.
You know about a pinnacle,
have great aim because somehow he
managed to find her vagina with the
jury,
acquitted him of one count of way rape
after just 30 minutes of deliberations.
Wow.
That jury is going to be a tank coon.
Big Time.
They're going to be on a fucking yacht,
Paula to to like a Jay z video doo Doo
Doo Doo Doo Doo to to.
Well,
it's also fear to when someone has that
kind of thing,
you've got to wonder,
is he a billionaire to say bi or men
air?
Well Posey have a billion come on son.
I wonder how how he got away with that.
That doesn't even make any sense.
Unless they just picked a super
sympathetic pro Muslim.
I'm assuming he's Muslim with that name
pro Muslim,
but even.
I mean it's like,
come on,
how did they do it?
Well,
I really think what
you laid out is the value option or I'll
have you killed option are really the
only two logical explanations because
other than that,
this is not a defense.
This is the most.
Like this is a late night joke.
First of all,
look at that guy's fat face and telling
me that guy keeps a raging erection like
all the time while he's walking around.
That is not healthy at all.
You're not 15.
You're not like some.
Some young boy with a throbbing heart on
that.
He just like literally it runs his life.
That guy's probably lucky.
Unless he's on Viagra.
He's lucky if he can get it up here.
Look at him,
it's all fat and swollen like I was not
healthy enough to have a rod is all the
time.
Fucking raging.
Boner.
Slipped Hodge.
He's got it in there.
You like his dick is like a like a heat
seeking missile.
Just fly finds its way into vaginas.
Only have to do is fall near the girl I
in there.
Yeah.
It's not that easy here but.
But what do you.
You have to work at it.
Jury acquitted him.
Well,
yeah.
There's no justice in the world.
If I was at girl's dad or if I was that
girl or her mom or anybody.
The girl herself.
Yeah.
Find that guy.
Yep.
Well what is she saying?
That he was as she was asleep and he
just stuck his dick in her while she was
out cold by Zip code and she woke up
fucker today my phone inside,
you know,
big.
Did you imagine the odd.
But imagine if that's really what
happened.
Like what if he's like walking on
hardwood floors a is a wearing socks and
he steps on a piece of paper and just,
whoops,
she's still wearing anything.
He claimed he had gone to see if the
young woman wanted a tee shirt to sleep
in or a taxi home.
But he said she pulled him on top of her
and placed his hand between her legs.
Oh,
his semen and DNA were found inside the
young woman.
But he said it was possible that he had
semen on his hands from having sex with
a 24 year old earlier.
Um,
we more complicated if you got semen on
his hands.
How did he get it?
Inside of her?
I slipped in my penis.
End.
My hands went inside of her vagina is
huge.
It's got us.
He's a God like that.
Don't even make any sense.
The she pulled him on top of her and
placed his hand between her legs.
Boy,
that's a squirrely fucking story.
Hmm.
Early our,
the young woman said she had woken up in
the early hours of the morning with Mr
Abdulla Aziz on top of her forcing
himself inside of her.
He claimed he'd gotten to see if the
young woman wanted to tee shirt to sleep
in or a taxi home.
Okay.
I believe her.
How about that?
I think it story sucks.
Well,
this stories definitely socks about like
slipping and falling into that sucks,
but it sucks even more.
I've gotten to see if she wanted a t
shirt to sleep in or a taxi home.
What a wonderful person you are.
You are amazing.
Did you also donate some money to a
charity of your choice?
I was up all night trying to help
orphans,
but it Horsley you think,
how stupid do you have to be to make up
your story?
Because you can say you can throw it
into a.
He said she said kind of thing.
No,
it must consent in Charlotte.
he wasn't.
You know.
Then it's harder world,
right?
There's an article there.
This is like the most fucking ridiculous
story ever.
How did you even sit down and say,
no,
I'm not going to go for the sexuality.
They've got to recap this crazy weird
estela like he make no sense.
Meanwhile,
he's free right now with his feet up on
the coffee table,
smoking a Cuban cigar,
laughing.
Probably getting his dick sucked by some
Russian hooker.
That's probably why the first few
seasons stuff that backs there were so
popular right before they fuck they
thought,
but buddy was still a good show.
First season was awesome because
everybody's got their thing right.
There are so much nasty sheet that has
been in the ward with no repercussions
that everybody's got the fan.
Does he off?
Fuck you.
I'm going to get you.
Boy,
did they fuck that show up?
They took that.
That show was like a work of art that
the writers from murder,
she wrote got a hold of and they just
started.
Just shitting in the mouth of every
character became awful.
It was awful.
I was so bad.
People kept telling me,
no,
you got to give it a chance.
It gets better.
Fuck you.
I don't have that kind of time in my
life,
you know,
masochistic effort.
I stuck through it.
All I've seen is on the.
I didn't know,
get that idea and I think,
you know,
you got,
you've got second team because you got
the first three,
four,
five,
whatever many sees on the first few are
good,
right?
And did like three,
four more than that.
Really not.
And,
but you're like,
no,
but maybe they'll get the next one,
right.
Was like,
yeah,
that didn't all that.
Um,
and I,
I,
I really didn't realize what it was when
it first came out,
but it hadn't really changed.
Was the first episode of the Sopranos.
It was a comedy.
It was.
Well,
I mean,
yeah,
we are way.
But yeah,
there was a lot of comedic element for
sure.
Like when the woman had the machine gun
and she ran outside with the AK 47,
the wife like that was so out of
character,
like who she became later in the show.
Like that episode was like,
it was preposterous.
Gang,
family,
you know,
mom,
family.
It was weird.
But even though they have some moments
in there,
like I don't remember,
even at the end of season one where they
are chasing these do through the woods
to shoot him and the dude is like
screaming all of a sudden one and
definitely he's like,
you got shot that.
He's like,
no,
fuck poison ivy at his old piece of golf
about that.
And it's like they throw in these weird
data bits to make it.
He goes,
it doesn't really well or eat them.
Yeah.
It was definitely really well written
and it got better as it got darker and
weirder got better.
That was one of the few shows ever where
they figured out a way for you to feel
sympathetic about a murderer because
Tony Soprano wasn't a murderer.
He killed him.
You liked him?
Huh?
Should I even add the height?
Remember having nightmare self shit.
The FBI trying to get me.
I
have to hide the stuff I was.
Because you relate to the guy.
At least I did feel.
I felt like it's a fucking exited
heritage.
Your last name as well.
But it was a dark time for Italian
American.
So because everybody wanted to be like,
connected to the mob was really dumb.
East Coast Guineas,
we're like,
so celebrate Tori and they were upping
older Guinness.
That's painful.
They would crank it up to a 10 guy with
the thing and the goes like,
hey,
blamed the sopranos for Jersey Shore.
I think that was a direct connection
there.
I think you have a point.
Yeah.
In the real housewives of Jersey,
which is the most disgusting version of
real housewives.
Real housewives of Miami.
They should just give them knives.
They just give those bitches knives and
let them cut each other.
Was a fucking savages.
But jerseys the grossest.
And then,
uh,
now that one family,
the woman's in jail and she's doing time
and then she gets out,
the husband's got to go in because only
one can stay out and watch the kids.
So they take turns.
Yeah.
They take turns like a tax evasion
thing,
right?
High five each other on the way you net
out is like,
okay,
you're recording now.
Go.
I'm in favor of people going to jail for
stealing things.
But man,
that tax evasion thing is a tricky one.
How about you just fucking pay what you
owe?
How come?
It's the only time when you owe
something,
you'd go to jail,
like fuel credit card money.
You have to pay it,
right?
You know you owe student loan money.
You have to pay it.
You owe taxes,
go to jail,
bitch block you in a cage.
That's nuts.
Gangster.
You know they are the big gangster.
That's what I mean.
That's exactly what I was saying about
sort of mafia and government's been
identity cut the same shit.
I mean even like the Mafia.
It's funny because a lot of the early
mafia stuff came up as a form of
government.
You know,
when like in the south,
they're neat that he went,
God invaded by dishpan yards by the
French.
So the government was not on the
people's side.
They were a occupying force,
trying to squeeze as much wealth out of
the country as possible.
So because they couldn't turn to the
government,
a lot of the people started turning into
these,
made up local organization,
which eventually,
because they provide all these services,
but they are also the mafia,
you know,
they do instill deal with teaching
staff.
You can see the logic why besides
academia now that element,
the 90 devolves completely into Jessica.
You mean apply them into nothing goes.
But he's like,
there's no way,
you know,
there's a logic to it and it's immediate
versus state university level,
you know,
the hierarchy of the way they handle
these nice,
you know,
the whole thing gives me an alert on the
state.
Yeah.
And if you look at the amount of
atrocities committed per capita,
I mean it's probably pretty similar.
I mean the mafia does some awful shit
but.
So government.
Yeah.
So does the military.
So I mean think about the amount of
innocent people that are accidentally
killed everyday during military.
No,
that's why you need to be a war to call
and quit or worse or the mafia bosses.
That's why those stories are the same
thing.
It's about the guy struggling for power
against 80.
I mean
the same thing over and over,
you know,
it's uh,
yeah.
The,
the mafia has its ancient system of
government and laws and rules and you
know,
so to the sandinistas the contras.
So does you know the so did you can go
down the line.
So to gangas conduit.
So did Alexander the Great.
They all had their own sort of systems
of government and rules that you had to
live by.
And speaking of getting gas gun,
did you check out the show Marco Polo?
Yes.
It's good.
I liked it.
It's a good show.
Yeah.
They didn't finish it and they hate it,
but equal that I know they did like a
half hour on the bad ass.
That waste among.
Yeah.
Pretty cool.
Right?
Doug?
It's well written.
It's a,
it's good stuff.
It's a very expensive show apparently.
He said yeah,
because they're,
the sets are massive and they make it
look like the,
the Mongol era,
like 1200.
So they don't kind of sell it for money
because you know what kind of stuff for
money to kill me.
My probably my favorite tool for the
times.
Have you ever seen that Oma?
Be One.
Oh No.
That was so good.
It wasn't really an amazing,
brilliant instruction at trait bits
about it.
I don't know.
It was back when was it 2004 or five,
something like that wasn't that long
ago.
It was a while back,
but they only did two seasons,
but they are fucking awesome.
Like I watched every season twice,
so maybe even more.
It was that good.
The main character,
um,
he's pretty much a variational call and,
and it's so cool.
The,
oddly enough,
the guy who created the show was Jamil
Lewis was the guy with directed the
first call and I was,
the guy was behind a part of the
creative directing of the early UFC.
He's the guy who wrote the apocalypse
now.
He standing so many of the sinks side
dig and by.
Yeah,
that's your money if you have never seen
it,
check it out.
I mean today looks tame by comparison
cause so much stuff has been done
afterwards.
That's just dates a 10 notice before the
time he was over 18 times with nudity
and violence and the grittiness of it
all.
It's a.
it's an awesome trauma.
So it sort of opened the door maybe for
things like game of thrones,
bake time,
big,
big.
That's funny how a show like that didn't
catch on,
but a show like game of thrones does,
you know,
or soprano's does.
I think what he was is it almost
actually doing fairly well but not well
enough for the budget.
I think the budget was too inflated
compared to the results.
The results are good.
You know,
people liked it.
The critical reviews or to create an
audience you know is good,
but you know the Sopranos,
you shoot somebody silos,
you know the budget is not going to be
what you have to recreate.
Ancient Rome when I could and scale.
It's a different kind of game right
there.
So Hbo,
I think he wasn't that old tanking is
this show is doing well,
but it cost too much fucking money.
Those shows they didn't have the option
of selling them on itunes back then.
Did they know exactly what 2004?
Did they have itunes back then?
They kinda did.
Right.
I want to say that even dad would have
been said much the early stages that
isn't that crazy fucking 10 years ago.
I know,
but it's another universe completely.
It might as well be with everything,
with social media,
with everything.
That's another,
a whole nother universe.
How many podcasts were around back then?
Was there like a few people's 30 fucking
with data,
but nothing got a big scale yet.
It's probably something.
There's probably something.
This podcast has been around since,
um,
for six years.
So since 2009.
Nine slash nine.
10 somewhere around then I think.
I think we do and we were doing it in
December of 2009,
so right before 2010.
Well,
I'm sure when you started podcasting,
Ward was a fraction of what it is today.
Yeah,
it was real small.
So it's,
um,
Adam Carolla had one.
Um,
and there was a few other ones.
You know,
Adam Curry had one of the first ones and
John Devork.
Uh,
but I,
I didn't know about them.
I didn't download them back then.
I got the inspiration to do mine from
Anthony because Anthony Kumina from opie
and anthony had this set up in his
basement where,
uh,
you know,
he had a lot of money and he had a cool
house.
He live by himself,
so he put up a green screen and set up a
stage where he had a nice desk and some
real professional cameras and started
doing this thing called live from the
compound and live from the compound was
like his own little fuck around,
have some fun at home show we had like
Guinness on tap and he would just drink
and talk shit.
And it was really fun to watch and I
realized it was like,
wow,
here's a guy that's on serious,
you know,
he's on the opening.
Anthony showed it's very popular show on
Sirius and he's decided just for fun to
do this thing in his basement that's not
making any money from it.
It's just for fun.
And I thought about it and I said,
you know what,
I could probably do something like that.
And so we started doing it off of,
I'm just ustream just sitting there with
a laptop talking shit that's.
So my podcast didn't become a like an
itunes podcast for like a few months
after the first one.
We realized once we started collecting
and we then took the audio and start
putting it up on itunes.
But there wasn't that much going on back
then.
And then,
um,
we got it in like right at the right
time.
And then like in the next few years,
other comics started starting their own
podcast,
you know,
and then everybody,
all these different people,
Bill Burr and you know,
and Dheas and Dunkin and everybody else
started,
you know,
doing podcasts as well.
And they all took off.
Well you are single handedly responsible
for like the [inaudible],
like there are so many podcasts that are
people who came through your show and
then went,
Huh,
I should the one,
you know,
there's like a long list of people with
a few.
Yeah.
I try to help him to.
I want them to do podcast.
I just think it's the best form of if,
if you're a comic is the best form of
expression where you can.
You could just,
you just talk to people,
get to know the actual.
You like 100 percent with you for three
hours or it is when you do
yours over the course of 700 and now
we're like 7:50,
something 7:55,
755 podcast.
Most of them intoxicated.
Good percentage of them.
I know.
I've seen that lately though.
It hasn't happened as much intoxication,
buddy.
You,
there's some conversations you can't
have toxic.
She will just scatterbrained.
I didn't want to talk about smurfs are
fucking the edy's or something in the
middle of someone talking about the
economy or bit coin I feel there.
There's some that lend itself to it and
some that don't.
It's really completely dependent upon
the guests.
What the subject is and I like to mix it
up too.
You know,
that's the thing about being a marijuana
enthusiasts unless you're like a Doug
Benson Kinda guy who everybody just
assumes is high 24 slash seven because
that's kind of a shtick,
you know,
like even the name of his podcast,
getting doug with high,
like,
let me get it.
You can't see,
you can't speak,
you know what I mean?
I,
you know,
I don't think Pi,
I think he's like everything else.
It shouldn't be all the time for
everything.
Yeah.
Everything.
Yeah,
it's a car.
It could be a crutch and it's not a
crutch,
you know,
it's um,
it's a fun,
beautiful aspect of nature and a great
way to perturb your normal states of
consciousness and give you some unique
insight and yeah,
it's a lot of benefits.
It makes you feel good.
It makes you enjoy wine and make.
It makes me like very friendly,
like pot makes me want to hug people and
they'll tell you,
you know,
but I just think you should be cool with
just life.
I'm a big fan,
so I have to say I'm a huge fan of the
effect that has on female sexuality the
way,
at least in my experience,
women that respond to weed wouldn't
call.
The good ones do.
Yeah.
My best ally ever.
It's definitely you feel like a god
you've touched.
Have multiple.
Oregon's somebody up like that was easy.
That didn't think much.
Will it?
Makes hugs feel good?
Yes.
Just hugs.
Forget about sex.
Just smoke weed and hug.
It feels amazing.
You know you ever done ecstasy?
No.
It's been on my to do list,
but I've had a.
You could hold hands with dude.
When you're on ecstasy and you feel bad
at all,
are you going to do it?
Can Be rubbing each others hands.
Does it feel bad at all ever fucked one
thing that it does.
It's,
it's fucking terrible for your brain.
At least I should qualify that.
That was when I did it.
I probably did a little too much and uh,
the next day I just was so fucking
stupid.
Now my brain didn't work good.
I've talked to many people who don't
have that problem,
but they don't have to do the same sort
of things with their brain that I have
to do.
So it's,
it depends on what you do,
like if you go to work and you have a
normal job and you don't have to do
anything important and maybe you know,
great,
maybe it's fine,
but if you're a person who has to think
for a living and you have to do like
stand up comedy
on stage or you have to write or the
podcast or something like that.
Like I couldn't imagine doing ecstasy
and then doing the UFC the next day.
Yeah,
that would be a rough.
I,
I wouldn't be able to do it.
That kind of the whole theory that there
are these,
I don't know what Saturday are,
but that you take after you take
ecstasy.
HTP,
is that what it takes that allow you not
to have the Dow and thereafter words?
I've never done it.
Um,
but I would imagine,
you know,
like I said,
only did actually once in the one I did.
I just totally did it naturally.
But I do take five htp,
I take new mood,
which is five htp and l trip to fan.
That stuff definitely works.
Hey.
But I've never done it in conjunction
with that with acid but,
or with molly or ecstasy.
But actually that's how it got invented.
That's how new mood got invented.
Really trying to figure out a way to
mitigate partying.
I love,
I mean that's just as it was called roll
off did the other day and she had these
old perfect scheme for basically every
legal prostitution by using a loophole
that,
you know,
if there's a cabinet,
our role in that.
It's part is not the restitution.
That was true.
It was true.
I at even sign a contract,
you could hire someone,
sign a contract to,
uh,
to have,
a porn film and even just for your own
benefit,
you could have it for yourself as long
as you're filming.
Right.
That's hilarious.
It's so stupid.
But yeah,
I love the way.
Oh,
but it's brain work,
but he's not the only one that stopped
that.
I'm sure.
But it's still,
the porn loophole is how,
um,
like porn stars get away with doing
quote unquote prostitution like that.
There was a girl that was at the comedy
store and she was telling guys that you
could fuck her,
but you have to pay her her rate and you
have to turn a camera on.
Yep.
And she's like,
I'm not a hooker.
I'm like,
okay.
I don't even know what to say.
I gotta go.
I don't know.
I would have entertained that cover sick
before ally.
Yeah.
It was getting ugly.
It was getting.
I think she had this dude with her.
I'm like,
how does he fit?
Yeah,
that pitch.
Well,
he was like,
I didn't know if he was the boyfriend or
if he's the pimp,
but he was right.
He didn't.
I mean,
unless he had a gun,
I don't know how he's going to protect
her.
It was very strange.
But that's the comedy store.
How many stores have vortex of strange
somehow or another,
it just drags those people to that one
place that I sat in the rainbow.
You ever go to the rainbow bar and grill
as the place where they.
When Lemmy died from motorhead,
they saved a seat for him.
Oh,
I'll have a seat that's permanently
reserved and I'm like,
yeah,
it's permanently reserved.
I like it a place to.
Let me see.
Yeah,
they have candles there and shit.
Like maybe if one of his band members
comes there and they're all sold out,
they'll let them sit there.
Maybe.
Maybe not.
Maybe you have to be like Lenny's
friends if friends and they want to sit
at a table.
I think that's,
that should fly.
That's okay.
You know,
I think I can see a different factual is
going to war over it.
He's like,
nope,
this is for Lamean.
Motherfucker can all do it.
And the other guys being like,
yes,
this friends.
Come on,
you can do it.
Yeah.
That's,
I would religious warfare begins.
That is.
Yeah,
right.
Like sacred.
Anything sacred,
sacred grounds,
sacred places.
Sacred.
The word.
Just this sacred things.
There's good and bad in them.
There's like,
there's,
there's definitely merit in sacred
things,
but you know,
like there's an area in Hawaii where the
Keck observatory is and they wanted to
construct a larger,
bigger telescope and apparently they
have problems because the native
American,
I guess I native American Hawaiian,
they're sort of native Americans,
Hawaiians,
um,
the people that lived there have some
sacred ground up there that they don't
think that you're supposed to build on,
which,
you know,
I get it.
It's their spot,
you know,
false on some assholes come up there
with a telescope.
Yep.
I got that.
Have you ever been up there to the Keck
observatory?
Not that I want.
You have been to the big island a no.
Be normally to Maui big island is
awesome.
It's so strange because it's the biggest
of the islands,
but it's the least populated of the
Hawaiian islands duct.
It's,
and it's also one where it has all these
different ecosystems on one island,
like if you go like near the Hilo side
where Bj Penn's from,
it's all like tropical beautiful God.
It rains all the time and it's lush and
green.
It's magical.
But then you go to like the other side,
like the Kona side and it's like,
it's totally different.
It's drier and then there's areas that
have these giant lava beds and it's up
to the tape to hold the whole place is
amazing.
Even seemed the lava beds.
Yeah,
I've seen.
I've seen some pretty crazy shit on the
whole.
I don't know why he's one with this
place.
This is kind of a nice steady.
That is even part of the US because he's
going to be the love,
the fucking pissing people off anything.
But it's a beautiful place.
I can see how you want to.
Well,
how about Alaska?
You have to fly through Canada gets
elected.
It was bizarre.
Except frozen Puerto Rico.
Yeah.
It doesn't make any sense.
That's the APP right there.
The I'm nobody to think you are saying
about the sake of it.
And to me it seemed interesting because
precisely because you hold something
sacred to me.
You need to be able to have more to
laugh to not because you diminish its
importance.
He dirt to avoid fucking up and throw an
18 to a dogma.
You know the one theme that keeps things
loose like you speaking of American
Indian stuff is bad twat at the.
I remember being like at some Lakota
ceremonies wedding,
was he liar.
He was to see people who have grown app
with dates so far damaged that he other
thing versus like some white guys were
coming up and then they will find out
about.
He supposed to be right as he ladders.
That was during the break of the
ceremony.
They were giving some of the Sunday and
of giving bikes to settle with the
people we're supporting their right and
these guys were taking the pipe.
They will smoke it,
they will pass it to other people and
they gave it to this white lady was
clearly
ticket ourselves real seriously.
Right.
And so she's tried to like the five but
she can that she feels she failed.
So she thrived and then taking herself
superseded he or she takes a deep breath
and she goes,
oh,
the spirit's the one metal light this
pipe today.
And there was a lady next to her was
trying to not die laughing,
but she was trying to be polite,
right?
But she was like,
look,
it's a windy day just to be okay for the
whole Lakota lady.
The spirits of the love that is
precisely because it's real.
You can call when sometimes the spirits
are trying to tell you just to relax a
little bit lighter up.
Yeah.
It's like someone saying to you in the
master chief in most people who say,
no master are assholes.
I don't mean that.
They're mean people around me.
They're assholes like me,
but you just shut the fuck up bitch.
You know,
come on man.
You don't really mean that.
You're just trying to be like super
spiritual.
But I swear to God,
like there's Yoga teachers that can say
it after a yoga class and you'll say it
back and you mean it because you just
did 90 minutes of hell together and
you'll,
you'll say it and mean it.
But that's a tricky thing that sometime
that the guy was there,
yellow deal and the guy was the thought
Elforni can sound exactly the same
except that one is three.
I don't want like,
to me like a lot of these six about
spirituality,
they don't make me throw up or because
they are so cheesy,
so made apps or fig.
But then there are the moments where you
go,
oh shit,
that was it.
Like the other day Mandy's was three p
like this guy I'm from Canada,
emailed me and he's like,
oh,
we had this,
it was a Lakota thing,
right?
American Indian stuff.
And he was like,
we had a ceremony and uh,
was um,
we parade also for your daughter and
blah blah blah.
And I'm like,
okay,
thanks.
That's sweet.
And the guy goes,
oh,
by the way,
I kind of have the feeling that she may
be sensitive to things like the task or
if by any chance she had a dream of
having to do with American Indians.
And I'm like,
that's fucking weird because she doesn't
remember the dreams nine nights out of
10.
And you know,
Indian,
she never mentioned that one,
so there's no right.
But I figured out it doesn't matter to
us so I try not to ask a leading
question.
So I just asked her,
hey,
did you have any dream last night?
And she goes,
no,
and I was like,
you have say bullshit,
whatever.
And then she goes,
no,
wait,
wait.
I had a dream,
like my grandpa was taking me to this
place where they were Indians and they
taught me to speak Lakota and yeah,
we had a good time.
And I went like,
and I don't run with it,
you know,
I don't say,
oh,
it's because of this period,
this I have no fucking idea.
Right.
I'm just reporting what happens.
But when you look at it,
you go like,
Oh shit.
Maybe the universities a lot weirder
than we assume sometimes the problem
with something like that as you can't
measure it,
of course you can't.
There's no way.
Whenever anybody has a clairvoyant
moment or a moment where they kind of
have
an instinct that doesn't seem to make
any sense but turns out to be true.
And they go,
well,
what was that?
Was it coincidental?
Like what was that?
And you know,
there's like some Sam Harris type people
that are like very straightforward,
rational thinking.
They'll,
they'll,
they'll sort of boil it down to
coincidence and I'm not entirely
convinced I like Sam and I don't mean to
talk shit about it because I like him
and I did stuff,
but I think that's complete bullshit to
me or a fundamentalist as much as the
religious fundamentalists like the going
so badly to explain every single tool
whether you're explaining the as in it's
because God the dds or because no,
it's because he must be a coincidence
because the probability of these,
that it's like that can you just doesn't
meet the life is weird and we don't have
all the explanations and leave it at
that time.
He's right most of the time.
No.
See,
I think there's a lot of people that try
to make things sound spiritual and
connect circumstances and say,
you know,
it's fate and it's,
it's a psychic moment when really it's
just total coincidence.
There is a lot of that.
A lot though is not everything,
it's not everything,
but it's hard to differentiate like what
is like you wouldn't you talk to a guy
and he says that your daughter had some
sort of a dream about native Americans
financially.
She's sensitive and then you asked her
and she said,
Oh yeah,
I had a dream about native Americans.
Like the fuck.
What are the odds?
Most kids you.
Yeah,
I had a dream.
I was on the my little pony store.
I had all the money in the world that
night.
Like literally what the fuck are y'all?
It's right.
And he's like,
what are the odds of the Sheila remember
anything?
What are the odds that you'd have to do
with the topic that she never mentioned
once in our life?
Science,
you ever have a dream about someone,
then you get an email from them the next
day and you haven't talked to them in
years ago too.
I don't.
I don't necessarily believe that the
only connections that people have to
each other a physical,
like you have to be there and see each
other.
They're there very well.
Might be some sort of a,
a dream state connection or a thought
connection that we just can't.
We can't put on a scale that we can't
like take a ruler and go,
oh,
this is a seven inches long.
You can't,
we can't measure it.
I said I've had enough of those
experiences.
And again,
not to believe because I don't know what
I believe.
Right.
I have no fucking idea.
I don't know how the universe works,
but do we have enough experiences that.
Let me think.
There's no way to dcs that Queens
student's thesis at Queens.
It didn't do.
And Stephanie single time that he just
leaves me with kind of my mind is open
to possibilities.
I don't know what's out there.
There's stuff that I experienced there.
Stuff that I don't experience.
I have zero beliefs about the nature of
reality because my tools are very
limited about what I understand.
But that had been enough of those cases
where you go,
oh shit,
that was a coincidence.
I was maybe 18 or something.
They had,
um,
went to hiking with my friends,
go off into my own thing,
and we go back,
which was great because I was alone with
this two hot women.
The other guy was with going off.
I'm
like,
fuck you,
plea of disappear somewhere and enjoy a
day.
Should have this too hot.
We went for the rest of the day.
This is as good as it gets.
And like at one point I literally,
it's like somebody,
like a phone rang where I got up and I'm
like,
fuck,
there's up at all these duties have been
a problem right now.
And there's really no reason to think.
He said he'd be back four hours later,
an hour had gone by.
There's no reason whatsoever to feel
that way.
And that's what I tell myself.
He's like,
that's bullshit.
Why are you making what kind of a
bullshit excuse not to deal with the
women?
That's beautiful.
You know,
stay.
Yeah.
What are you?
And I try,
I try.
I keep getting in my head that I was
like,
no,
there's a fucking big problem in.
You may not be a bad idea to pay
attention to it,
and I'm like,
Jesus Christ here ruin my day.
Even when you're not here.
Fuck you.
I don't like it.
But I'm like,
okay,
this is bugging me.
I'm fine.
I'll walk up.
I'll start going up the mountain and see
what the hell.
Like none of this makes sense.
Going up the mountain,
there's 15 different paths that you can
take to go up to the mountain.
I don't know which one I can take a stab
and just pick one because I don't know
what else to do and I keep going and I'm
a year these voice called limit.
So I called back and eventually a year
did my friend's voice calling again.
I find him,
the dude got dehydrated.
I'd gone up too fast too.
And it was done right.
He had no energy left.
He was on the floor.
Just collapse them.
Pussies.
You're hanging around with what?
Him and a peak hour?
No,
no,
it was.
He said he was going to be back at a
tie,
but he had been there longer,
but I don't know.
He said it because I don't like him
anymore,
so I'm all good with that.
I liked your trx like,
fuck you.
I have a little problem with that,
but that's the universe universe.
One of them to dietary should've left
bang those church.
That's like one of my deepest regrets.
A skull and use it as a candle holder.
Exactly like that.
But you know it doesn't love it.
You're like,
why did I have that thought?
Why?
You have to carry them down.
Yeah.
I carried him down.
Yeah,
it was a painting done.
Now I just better get up to starting
now.
Pissed off.
No Wiemann.
Save this asshole.
Or would the girls do this whole back
there eating each other out?
Yeah,
they were right.
When they're done coming.
They had this attitude which was like,
really?
You want to go?
Okay,
your loss at my doing this.
Will you at least a hero when they found
out that the guy was sure a great.
I was a hero.
Who Cares for the people listening is
making the hand job gesture.
That's just not up at all the.
Yeah.
I wonder what that is.
Maybe you just didn't have any faith in
your friend.
You knew he was kind of an idiot.
He,
uh,
I don't know,
man.
I don't know.
It could be.
I'm not saying that like the dream thing
from last night,
that was even weirder.
Ds One.
I can see how it could be something goes
right.
Or if I was Sam Harris,
I'd say,
well,
let's just think for a moment.
The possibilities,
right?
Yeah.
I don't,
I just,
I don't
think that he's necessarily completely
averse to the idea of there being some
sort of connection.
I think he and like you and I agree,
most of that stuff is like the lady that
says the spirits don't want me to let
the cycle.
Yeah.
Most of it's bullshit.
I agree completely,
man.
I'll tell you one thing.
It changed my perception on,
on just the supernatural and the
spiritual is looking into it.
When I did that Saifai show and when I
did a,
I did a show called Joe Rogan questions,
not Joe Rogan questions.
Everything I'm a game show in my head
and the game showing my head show was a
hidden camera show or the people had
like an earpiece in and we would tell
them to go do things and we set this one
up in Hollywood and you know,
they would have a game show like here's
your task.
This is what you have to do.
And one of the things they had to do was
we told them that your reporter for a
local television station,
you're doing the news and you're
reporting on a Ufo sighting.
You have to find someone and tell them,
listen,
I had a witness.
They were here for this Ufo story.
We have the cameras here,
but they took off.
Well,
are you willing to say that you saw the
Ufo to wow and fucking everyone said
yes.
They just went right?
Not only did they say yes,
they went right into these elaborate
fake stories on camera and I went,
wow.
It was such an eyeopener for me and I
was like,
how many of those people that you see in
those Ufo documentaries?
Like the famous one was the phoenix
lights,
use the phoenix.
The Phoenix lights was a,
uh,
a series of sightings that happened in
Phoenix,
I want to say in the early nineties
maybe.
And uh,
it was very controversial because the
governor,
uh,
was,
was saying he was going to get to the
bottom of this,
this is all like,
this is a very controversial.
And then he held a press conference and
made a mockery out of it by having
someone,
a dress up like an alien and say we
found the culprit and here he is.
The guy comes out,
he's got an alien costume on.
And the UFL believers were really pissed
off because they were like,
fuck you.
I saw something.
There was a triangle shaped object the
size of a football field.
It was flying overhead.
It wasn't making any noise.
Like all these people had these,
all these things that they said that
they saw,
but there's almost no evidence is only
evidence of these lights that are
floating in the sky that they think
where there's the governor,
Arizona Governor and the fucking alien.
So hilarious.
But what people were saying that they
saw there was,
there was one,
there was one explanation that made
sense and that was they were flares,
that the government had a let loose with
parachutes and they were drifting down
from the sky slowly and they fell behind
the mountain ranges and that's why they
disappeared.
Like if you look at the actual video
that,
that people did get there just lights
that are hovering in the sky.
It doesn't.
There's no triangle shaped black objects
that are flying around.
But everybody had all these.
It's soon as soon as you start saying,
hey,
there's a phoenix lights and people saw
you have for me too,
man.
I saw it.
I was on my porch was strange that night
was electric.
I felt it in the air and I agree with
you if they'd like.
To me 99 percent of the stories are such
bullshit,
but to ease.
Like sometime there are some that you
can't explain,
which doesn't mean it's real.
It doesn't mean we know why your.
Yes it was a euphoria was anything goes
or he was that.
Yeah,
there was something that came into
somebodies dream.
Who knows,
right.
I have no idea,
but why the hell are we trying to
explain it that way?
Every single time,
you know,
sometime just saved.
There is no explanation why.
Who knows why that's a hey,
that's weird to leave it at that.
You don't have to run with it,
but you don't have to deny it either.
You know,
you know what's amazing man?
Go shows.
What's that good?
Those ghost shows.
Ghost hunter shows.
Oh yeah,
there was fucking years and all those
episodes and those motherfuckers got
nothing.
It's faithful.
Let's see what comes after the
commercial break.
I.
That was the bass player tape recorder.
Listened.
Listened to.
Very clear.
Did you hear that clearly?
Clearly what he was saying.
Yeah,
those are the best.
Yeah.
Well know what the fuck that is.
There's so much shenanigans and fuckery
going on.
No shows.
Wasn't there like a fucking murder
recently?
Like a,
a,
a ghost hunter,
like killed his wife and killed himself
or something like that.
Yeah,
something like that.
Like a famous one,
right?
On television or something like that.
Yeah.
What Dow Jamie and find it,
but yeah,
that and um,
those mediums like the long island
psychic,
the fuck Outta here.
And I think finding a problem that,
that word is so many charlatans that is
not even fun.
Couple appear featured on ghost
adventures,
dead and apparent murder.
Suicide.
Damn.
Who self styled paranormal
investigators.
Yeah.
They don't give a fucking degree for
that paranormal investigation.
Mark and Debbie Constantinos says m and
a third still unidentified man were
killed yesterday in sparks,
Nevada.
That's where it goes down on a domestic
violence incident.
Turned deadly.
That constantino's killed themselves.
What?
Build themselves as electronic script
make that larger looked elect as
electronic voice phenomenon experts and
made frequent appearances on reality
shows about the supernatural,
most notably occurring on travel
channel's ghost adventures.
Oh,
the couple were a strange.
okay.
She found him with a new dude or she or
he found her rather with the new dude.
He killed them both and killed
themselves.
Debbie Constantinos had been living with
two roommates,
approximately 8:00
AM.
Tuesday.
The police were called department after
one of her roommates found their male
roommate dead.
And Debbie missing.
Yup,
that's it.
Police eventually discovered that she
was being held hostage by Mark
Constantino and apartment belonged to
one of the couples.
Adult children attempts to negotiate
failed around 1:30
PM.
A Swat team breached the apartment door
and found both people did Jesus Christ
heavy.
Oh,
can I can't compute.
Why can't people just break up?
Yeah,
see it.
He's like,
what the fuck?
Like murder suicide.
When people break up like God damn you
pussy you fucking pussy.
You can't handle her.
Finding a new person.
God.
People are so weak in that regard.
That is one of the weaker aspects of
humanity is the inability to accept that
someone doesn't want to fuck you
anymore.
She knew Dick let her go.
She's still,
she's still got some life left dinner,
but the thing you are 17,
you should be over that.
He's like,
you deal with it the first time.
So brutal.
I don't even dig.
Like when people flip out about access,
you know he's almost a stereotype.
I everybody thought about their ex.
No motherfucker.
You borrowed them into your life.
You are the one who like if you didn't
see it,
worry about what's going on with you.
If they were really that bad,
if they were such horrible human beings
and yard,
a wine opener with that mean or maybe
they are not a fucking bad and you're
just blowing it out over a bar from
[inaudible] they are meeting and you can
deal with the fact that they are with
somebody else.
He's like,
there's,
there's definitely that.
Well,
there's definitely some people that got
fucked over like divorces were dudes
have to pay hundreds of thousands of
dollars for the rest of their life,
but even that to me is interesting
because it's like,
no,
it's not easy,
but it's,
it's the same woman that you built in
your life and you need to fucking see
that she was capable of that.
You know what I mean?
So yes,
why she's the scum of the earth and you
can and should be a piece with her.
I would also reserve a little bit for
your own judgment of how you open the
door to this lady and the problem is
that there's a legal option.
It's not that she's a scum of the earth.
The problem is you are breaking up.
She does feel pain.
When I'm not saying,
I'm not saying that you shouldn't feel
pain when someone wants to fuck someone
else because you're going to.
It's just,
it's going to happen.
You're going to feel terrible.
You're going to feel jealousy,
you're going to feel sadness,
you're going to feel lost.
It's going to happen,
but what I'm saying is you have to have
some fucking perspective.
All right?
You are a human being and if you're here
in America,
you live in the best place on the planet
in 2016,
which is the best time ever to be alive
and you fucking pussy.
You can't.
You got match.com.
You Got Tinder,
get to crack and baby start slinging
Dick.
You Know You could sling Dick Today like
you could sling vagina.
You can.
You can do whatever you want to do
today.
This is a different world like move on.
You'll find someone that you don't want
to not be with or that you do want to be
with it.
You can get along with work on yourself,
like figure it out,
man.
Don't go on a murder.
Suicide rampage.
I know,
but this woman,
like I have a friend who was.
I've told,
talked about him before he,
he was divorced and the divorce was
brutal.
It took forever.
She went to all the other lawyers in
town so that he couldn't go to them
because she had context.
Yeah.
She had contacted them first,
like it's just a brutal,
brutal shit.
And she tortured him for like two years,
like changing the terms of the divorce
re going back.
All the while he's paying for her
lawyer.
Hey,
she's paying for his lawyer.
He's paying for everything.
She was trying to bleed them out.
Then she got this ridiculous settlement
and she got his house,
massive beautiful fucking house
overlooking the ocean like the whole
deal.
And on top of that,
because they were married for 12 years,
he has to pay her for the rest of her
life.
So he's paying.
He's paying her hundreds of thousands of
dollars every year for the rest of her
life.
And that's not it.
I mean,
you could say,
well,
hey,
he should have known he let that person
to his life,
but he used to love her,
but she,
in that time of loss and pain and
suffering,
she had a legal option and the lawyer
came to her and said,
listen to your,
your,
um,
you helped him write you.
You helped to make me wild.
She didn't do shit.
She walked around fucking beverly hills
with a little tiny dog though him and
got her nails done and got her fucking
pedicure done and talked a lot of shit
about him while he was at work.
And that guy busted his ass all day
long.
But because that was his quote unquote
wife,
because they scribbled their name on
some paper and said,
I do that guys fucked for the rest of
his life.
That I.
I mean,
I see it a point to,
don't get me wrong.
There are other cases where the axes,
the evil demon from hell,
I get that,
but a steel wild.
It's their full that is not yours.
Steel Yard Awano didn't see that.
They were a demo from highland middle
domain and too old,
so he is yet a sock now.
What?
I think they suck.
She's got nothing going on and this is
there.
To her.
It's like,
what is she gonna do she gonna work all
day and take some job?
That sucks.
She's in her late forties,
early fifties now.
She's an older lady.
She's not.
She doesn't have the best health.
Like what is she going to do?
She's just going to keep taking hundreds
of thousands of dollars every year
because the law says it's okay.
Well,
I think that there's a lot of like those
are pretty dramatic extremes.
There's like,
I'm never going to take a banyan.
I got to go back to work 10 hours a day.
Says that or says that they never passed
that my point.
Right.
But the other one is also Yara.
NASA is not just each day or is an
option is you choose an option that's
designed to bleed.
The other person that I.
When you know it's not right.
Well,
he makes good money so it's not like
he's been getting bullied,
bled dry,
but he has to pay an exorbitant amount
of money every year to a person that he
doesn't fuck anymore and now he has a
wife and he has children.
He has a whole new family and still a
giant chunk of his income goes to this
lady that he doesn't have anything to do
with anymore and it will to the day she
dies.
So she lives to be 500 years old because
of modern science.
Fucking dude is paying her for the next
400 years.
Yeah,
but it's.
that makes you think twice about.
It's incredible.
It's stupid and I'm married and I'm
happy.
I'll tell you right now,
I'm a happily married person.
I love my wife.
I love having a family.
It's nice for me.
It works,
but it's stupid.
Like the contract is dumb.
It's a dumb legal contract and it's.
It's an archaic one and I can understand
a child support.
I can understand all that stuff.
I understand all that,
but what drives me crazy is this idea
that in my friend's case,
somehow or another,
because he lived with her for 12 years,
by the way,
it was more than 12 years ago that they
separate it,
so let's think of that so it,
but because he lived with her for 12
years,
he has somehow or another fucked her to
the point where she can't work anymore.
He gave her so much dick during the time
we're together.
She just discombobulated.
She can't fill out a form if you have a
child.
Okay.
When the child turns 18,
you're no longer legally responsible.
That's an adult.
They're gone.
If you have child support,
you don't have to pay it after 18.
When they become 18,
that's your.
You have to get a job kid.
You have to figure out a way to feed
yourself.
It's part of the growth of life,
not when you're a grown woman and when
you're a grown woman and she was in her
forties when they broke up and for
whatever fucking reason.
We have these wacky laws that state that
this person doesn't have to work again
forever.
No children by the way.
No children.
That's cool.
They never had kids together.
What is it?
These 12.
The magic number is like if it was 11
then.
Oh fuck it.
You don't have to it like,
I don't know.
I think,
I think it varies,
but I think in California for whatever
reason,
it was 12.
You know,
I think 10 is a big one,
like 10 years is the big one.
So it might've been that it was 10
because a Ralphie may just got,
just got jacked.
Apparently his,
uh,
his woman just divorced him after 10 and
that same number 10 and at 10 the party
begins.
So if you are thinking about it,
now is the time to call it.
It's hard to imagine someone not being
in your life,
but yet you have to pay the money.
Yeah.
That's fucked up.
And they're just no way around it.
But in his case,
like his wife has children or his ex
wife now has children from him and so he
is definitely financial responsible for
her children,
his children,
their,
you know,
their children and I think he should pay
alimony because she has to take care of
those kids and she can't really work.
Like,
you know,
she's not like a free person who's
single,
but if you're a free person that's
I can understand you needing a couple of
years to get on your feet.
That's fair.
That's what I mean about the grades is
like one is one extreme,
one is you get nothing years.
Fair enough.
I mean if you say if you live with a
woman and for 10 years you're married
and for 10 years she doesn't have to
work because you're some fucking diamond
merchant downtown la or something like
that.
And you break up with her and then you
know,
you got a house,
bitch,
you're on your own.
She doesn't have any skills or anything
like that's fucked up.
Capital fierce.
These fierce,
fair.
Something like that is a reasonable
compromise.
But there's this weird thing that they
do where it's called the quality of
life.
You're supposed to maintain the same
quality of life.
Like what?
Yeah,
that's bullshit.
So if you're living with like coby
Bryant,
like coby Brian's wife,
like she's responsible for his children.
So she should certainly get money and.
But how much money man,
how,
how does she get hundreds of millions of
dollars.
Like how does that work?
You know,
forever.
Forever.
Yeah.
That's nuts to the end of time.
Till till the day they die.
And if you don't have a Prenup,
get ugly.
So.
Yup.
And he's like,
no,
it prenup is not real bad.
Like fuck you.
This is a construct.
Anyway,
the whole thing is a colon threat with a
volts the states.
And if you don't have a Prenup,
believe me,
those conversations get way more intense
when things get ugly.
When a woman knows there's no prenup
involved.
Yeah.
Like I have a buddy who doesn't have a
prenup and him and his wife are fighting
and I go,
do you have a prenup?
You know,
how dare you could say we were having a
conversation about.
He's like,
oh,
I couldn't figure out a way to like
justify having a prenup.
I go,
here's a way.
If you were in love and you're married
together and you're going to be together
forever,
the Prenup doesn't mean shit,
but it doesn't mean anything.
If you really plan on being together
forever,
but have that person wants to fucking
abandoned ship than drain you like a
fucking plug at the bottom of a bathtub
will will,
will,
will blow,
will bump.
That's when you need a prenup.
Because if you're gonna break up,
that's an a prenup comes into play and
then you need it and you should have it
right,
but if you're going to be together
forever,
the Prenup doesn't mean a goddamn thing
because you're going to be together
forever,
so don't worry about it.
Get a fucking prenup.
Silly Bitch.
It only.
It only becomes a factor if you get
divorced.
That's why any woman that says he wants
to have a peanut,
you don't think it's gonna last?
No,
I think it is going to last,
but it's.
It doesn't this fucking.
The logic of not having a prenup is
insane.
If we break up,
I want to get financially fucked.
That's how much I love you so much.
I want to stay together.
I want to stay together with you under
the threat of being financially ruined
because otherwise it's now through love.
No,
it's fucking chick said to me.
The date was hilarious.
She goes,
well,
I'll tell you what.
More and more women today are paying
alimony.
I go name one.
It's like silence.
Roseanne Barr,
that's all they say.
Roseanne Barr.
Tom Arnold.
Okay.
We got one under our belt.
That's one victory as opposed to a what?
What?
Hundreds of millions of guys that have
been fucked over by the system.
Yeah.
I don't get.
I actually don't even get the huddle
idea of marriage and I don't mean like
committed relationship.
I got that.
I got a little that about why the fuck
do you need to bring into state and low
years because it's a business.
That's what I mean is like if it said a
nature of shape,
why do you need to all this shit in?
Well,
it's a business in terms of like there's
a business of the diamonds,
you know,
is three months to add too much to ask
like those fucking diamond merchants.
Fuck,
I'm bringing them up again on a wire.
But,
but diamonds,
the idea that three months salary,
three months,
that is a fucking
crazy for guy has to work three months
out of a whole year for a little rock
that goes around your finger just to
show you.
You have too much to ask.
That would be a deal breaker right off
the bat.
He's like,
what you first of all fucking month,
what you want the.
We're all going to cost thousands of
dollars.
Fuck off.
I just have nothing in common with you.
I'm done.
Most people don't have enough money to
get by period like there scraped,
but most people are going pretty much
checked the channel.
They have like,
you know,
a little bit of money in the bank case
fucking shit goes terribly wrong,
but they don't have three months worth
of money in the bank.
So what are you going to do for three
months?
I'm going to suffer so that you could
have a rock on your finger.
What am I gonna do?
I'm gonna eat potato chips for lunch and
fucking starve to death.
Ramen noodles at dinner every night.
Whoa.
Save 20 books to go through the jaw.
So it goes into the diamond jor now.
But that to me is the ultimate bullshit.
He's like,
do people actually fucking like diamonds
is not a status symbol nights come on.
He's like,
you fucking fake thing that looks
exactly the same.
And you,
unless you were a jeweler with them,
but it's not the same.
But that's what I mean.
He's like,
it's about it costs a shitload of money
is a symbol is not the yellow thing.
It's like,
what can you do with three months
salary?
You can do so much fucking good stuff.
How about we do that?
So celebrate the wedding or whatever to
hell,
blah,
blah.
Give me the rock.
My aunt got fucked over the.
She uh,
she married this guy.
He was real shady.
He was always shady,
like from the beginning.
And she had a nice wedding ring.
Nice fat rock.
When they got divorced she went and go,
checked out.
Cubic Zirconia.
Ah,
that's the way you have to do it.
Yup.
She fucked him over.
He,
he got her a fake rock.
That's the way to do it.
They look so real,
man.
It's hard to tell.
I guess a diamond merchant can tell like
that,
but not a fucking dynamometor trends.
So how about we don't deal with that.
We know.
It's not like having a fake Ferrari.
Yeah.
You know,
like a fake Ferrari will drive like
shit.
Exactly.
That there's something good.
Yelled,
yelled the diamonds and there's nothing
so crazy.
I know a lady who's a billionaire,
uh,
her and her husband,
her husband's is very,
very wealthy tycoon type character.
He's kind of hilarious.
He dresses like sergeant pepper's lonely
hearts club band and it was like those
little outfits on throws these magical
parties in Malibu or just fucking huge,
huge,
crazy parties would probably cross like
a million bucks.
The guy's an animal,
but he got her to this rock that I don't
know enough about diamonds to say how
much it cost,
but it's well over a million dollars.
Well,
it's huge.
I mean it's fucking.
It's like a watch.
It's a flavor.
Flave watch.
Hang it.
It's like our clock on her finger.
It's so big.
What is this?
Was this a new guy?
She's with?
This just came out of this weekend.
Thirty five carat diamond ring that
makes.
Who is this dude?
She's with some billionaire from
Australia.
Will look at him.
Let me see what he looks like.
Yeah,
that looks like you need a 35 to get 50.
40th five.
Thirty five it says.
Yeah.
She's still hot.
How's that ass look big,
right?
Big Juicy Papao.
Look at that ring.
She was like much smaller and thinner
when she was younger.
Huh?
Not that I liked that.
That's 35 carrots.
That's what that is.
I was expecting bigger.
I don't mean.
I don't know.
I was too.
I'm telling you that the lady that I
know her ring is bigger than that.
Yeah.
That shit makes me like,
how much does that cost projectile
vomiting?
Just looking at this.
Yeah,
that's probably,
that's probably a million bucks.
This is a lot like you remember when j
Lo and Ben Affleck were a character?
They were.
There were one we ever a great story.
Great Story.
I know a dude who's a construction guy
and uh,
he uh,
was dealing with them at the time and
uh,
allegedly the story is,
the J lo.
Ben Affleck had like a full 10,
a basketball court that he had at his
place.
She wanted to take the basketball court
apart and put it in her house.
I guess it's a surprise to surprise him.
And the guy's like,
what?
No,
I'm not doing that.
Pokes you imagine what kind of fucking
craziness that bitch has in her head.
She's like,
I'm just going to move his favorite
place to my place.
That way when he has his basketball
games,
you'll have to have it at my house.
Like what?
Like she,
she wanted to move it,
like take it,
put it,
I want it.
It's mine.
He's mine.
A basketball court in my house.
I like the Bursa nation.
Oh my God.
People do some crazy shit to get into
relationships.
I mean,
he's like poutine APP with people
request to Jesse because he's like,
fuck that.
I don't need it that bad.
I don't know man.
I don't get it.
It's never call friend and his wife
answers his cell phone.
It.
No,
I'm missing out on that experience.
You've got a lot that happened more than
once and I'd lose all respect for that
guy unless he's in the middle of
fucking,
uh,
holding up a pan of hot oil that he's
carrying the stove or something and it's
an emergency phone call or something.
I mean,
why the fuck would your wife answer your
cell phone?
I think that's an accusatory way.
Hello?
Who is it?
This is Joe's.
Dave there.
Joe.
Who?
Joe Rogan.
Hold on.
Hey Dave.
Why is your fucking wife answering your
phone?
Like,
um,
some chick who was calling or a gay
lover?
He fucking Weirdo.
Will you keep your phone in your pocket?
Bitch?
Don't let her have it.
Not that I think that's like our
security daylight.
There is like Ken Score,
a hot woman,
so if I cannot underscore one,
I'm just going to hold onto her.
No Metro batshit crazy.
She Gans I'm going to put up with
anything because I'm afraid to be alone.
That I think is speaking of the book
stuff.
That's another thing that I noticed
changing in me.
It's for the longest time I had these
exact dynamics that I'm criticizing.
I had that made me right.
That was like,
I don't want to be alone.
If I'm a woman I want to stick to her
and she does some crazy shit.
That's totally fine.
It's like that's fear.
That's insecurity.
That's if I let her go,
I'll never get laid with the hottest
woman again kind of thing.
And at one point I think is like I had
dealt with an app shade that something's
not me where I was just like,
you know what?
From now on,
and I don't even mean that in a bad way.
I don't fuck.
You want to make one compromise in my
life if I have to be anything gathered
and why am 24 slash seven?
I don't want to be with you.
You may be a nice person.
I'm not criticizing you,
but I don't want you in my life.
Right?
But what if you smoke a joint with her
and she throws that Posi around like
fucking John Elway,
just with the,
the long yards.
Woo God damn walk.
Like when elway wax that ball,
that helps for those two hours.
But then there's the rest of your life.
So those two,
our sort of good eight.
Now let's move on to something,
but then when you're at work thinking
about those two hours,
you know,
loosen up the God damn it.
You know what I'm saying?
Now I'm going for a layup.
Flying from the three point line right
through the net.
This bitches hot.
Yup.
Then you now if you break up with that
phone is just ringing off the hook from
dudes trying to get ahold of that Voodoo
Pussy.
Right?
What are you going to do now?
You're going to be cool and calm and
collected.
You got to try because he fucks up the
rest of your life or does even if he was
every single day,
that is the most magical sex in the ward
for the two hours that you spend.
There are 22 more hours.
Just sleep a lot that it's all okay.
Right?
Then you can put up with a thought.
It's solo artist.
I know this dude who to,
who was a mobster and talked about going
to jail,
going to jail was no big deal.
The key was you got to sleep your time
away.
We'd sleep like 18 hours a day.
That works.
And I was like,
really?
Like,
yeah,
that's you gotta do just sleep with time
away.
A lot of people are up to doing pushups
now me,
I sleep my time away.
By the time,
you know,
two years is gone,
nothing.
I slept,
I got arrested.
Okay.
Eighteen hours a day.
Jesus,
he's an asshole.
What are you going to do?
Yeah.
But um,
yeah,
there's some,
some girls are just so hot and then it's
also like there's something else that's
going on.
Love is real and emotions are real and
appreciating someone is real and there's
definitely that,
but there's also some biological tricks
that go on when you connect with someone
and you have sex with them.
There's like some weird sort of
possessive tricks where your DNA doesn't
want them to be with
anyone else because your DNA wants to
procreate with them and that's where you
have to protect this.
This one person who you're shooting
loads into who you're going to have
babies with.
Where'd you go?
What are you talking to?
That guy I saw the way that guy hugged
you,
like all this craziness that comes about
that person becomes you.
They become your property,
but you can't control them.
And then if they're freaky,
if they're crazy freaky bitches,
you got to go this crazy freaky bitches.
Probably crazy with other dudes too.
And then she's probably been crazy
freaky bitch with other dudes before me.
So now I have to think that those dudes
know that she's slinging that fucking
superstitious stitious pussy out there.
What I think anybody ever in the history
of mankind use of still arts together.
That's,
that's first,
she's got some fucking Voodoo Posey.
She's got some supernatural pussy.
There's people that can do things better
and includes fucking,
you know,
like everybody.
I have you dated a girl who was really
hot but just terrible.
Terrible in bed.
No,
I miss out on that experience.
I went on a couple of them,
but I had one of them.
I was like,
I gotta stop with your Skus.
Stopped doing really bad.
Yeah,
she's just a for all sorts of reasons.
I guess like maybe it wasn't her fault.
Maybe she was just like insecure or
uncomfortable or unaware or,
you know,
it turned out later on that I found the
shed like a coke problem that I,
I wasn't aware of that would,
that I've never done it.
But apparently that just blocks you off
from like emotional.
What of it is that,
what made it bad side?
We just,
it wasn't good.
You know,
it's like the girl that I dated before
her was a freak,
so I was like,
oh my God are lowering sucks.
It's not fun.
Yeah.
It's like when,
when someone's just,
when they're all in,
you know,
and then the next girl is not all in you
like kind flying someone was all in my
head a gamble for the next one.
I'm not here to pay play penny slots.
I'm here to push a fucking mortgage into
the center of the table and go,
what are we doing there?
That's where the excitement is,
right?
What do you make of Australia and
ability to instead turn off.
The second thing you are talking about
sort of that DNA like your mind and you
know,
the possessiveness,
the jealousy,
all of that.
The whole uh,
Chris Ryan ability.
What do you mean?
Well,
you know,
he sold it to theory about just fucking
monogamy.
It's all about happy monkeys having sex
with each other and just let it be.
Well,
I think that's something that you can
learn.
Yeah,
I think it's really when you boil down
to what it really is,
when you boil it down to,
you know,
if you can be objective about if it's at
all possible,
it's a pleasure.
Like why is,
why should you be the only person that
can give that person pleasure?
Why should that person be the only place
where you get pleasure?
Are we slaves to these ancient emotions
and ancient connections that we have to
other human beings that were really
based on scarcity?
I think whenever things are based on
scarcity,
you know the idea that you'll be alone
if you don't want.
I've heard she,
I'll be with them.
It's like famine thinking.
If that means if I don't eat this meal
hills,
we do more meals.
Does that fam and thinking when it comes
to friends,
like if you ever have a friend,
like what were you hanging out with them
for where you fucking even hang out with
me anymore.
That's the surest way to lose a friend.
Upset.
What could become like really needy,
where you'd get upset that that friend
hangs out with other friends.
That's ridiculous.
It's crazy.
People like that are ridiculous and I've
had friends like that before and they
get it when,
you know,
only when I was younger.
When you know,
when you're younger you're sort of
figuring out what style of person you
are and how do you live your life and
what's acceptable and what's not
acceptable and you know,
the people that are like that,
whether they're aware or not,
they're just incredibly manipulative.
They might not even be aware of why or
what they're doing,
but when it comes to relationships,
a lot of times people also mirror the
family that they grew up in.
Like if you grew up in a really jealous,
really abusive family,
sure you can,
you can,
it can mirror itself,
you know,
mirror itself and you or it can be the
exact opposite where you see how
retarded your parents were and you're
like,
well fuck that.
I'm not going to be like that anymore.
So I think Chris is obviously a very
brilliant guy and a Chris Ryan's book.
It's an excellent book,
which is,
you know,
really highly respected.
I think he's got some real good points
and if you can intellectualize it and be
objective.
Yeah.
You know,
if you,
if you're happy living that life and
he's happy,
you know,
and he knows a lot of people that also
live like that are happening.
It's nothing wrong with it.
No,
exactly.
I mean I,
to me,
the,
I recommend he lays out.
Makes perfect sense.
I think he's right.
He's just a.
for a lot of people it's hard tool.
Got Overdose.
They still are possessive and jealous
and don't have that and they can deal
with the idea that somebody's date law.
He's supposed to be all me.
Fuck.
Nice.
You can't have sex with somebody else.
They flip out.
But yeah,
with.
To me when you think about it doesn't
really make sense.
Well,
you know,
what else does it make sense?
Monogamy doesn't make sense,
but neither does polygamy.
It [inaudible] make sense?
You should do whatever you want.
Right?
Like what if you're in monogamy
monogamy's great.
That's what I mean.
Exactly.
If you work for you,
why should ensure way.
It doesn't work with everyone.
If you find one person and it doesn't
work with them,
then that's not the one you should be
monogamous with.
But it doesn't mean that you can't be
monogamous with somebody else or maybe
even that same person in another stage
of your life.
You know,
sometimes things change.
I get a chance.
To me,
the idea idea is the one that makes the
most sense and all philosophical.
But every single dive,
try to throw it out there at the lady I
wanted to get into a relationship with
the discussion.
Was he variably it makes sense.
Your Pauline's bots can.
Nope,
sorry.
It's not going to go.
And then it's a choice,
right?
He's like,
do I want it anyway?
Giving these fetal is off.
He called it sound cooler or not.
And the times when I have gone for
eight,
10.
So he was dead in monogamous
relationship.
That's totally with it.
You know,
it wasn't
like,
oh,
I spend my days thinking about what are
missing.
I was completely happy with it.
So I uncompleted way too dark to me is
not a test to be one way or the other is
whatever works at the end of the day,
but whatever works means.
So having the flexibility to say maybe
the traditional monogamous ways,
not the only fucking way to get there
are other ways to go about it or just as
good.
Well,
there certainly are other ways to go
about it.
I mean there's people that live in the
house and it's a man with like three
women,
right?
You know,
or a woman with three men and it wasn't
like a fucking drug dealer moving.
Wasn't that like an Oliver Stone movie
where there's a chicken two dudes and
they used to have threesomes look so
stupid.
So stupid as it looks.
I haven't seen the movie.
I read the book.
The book was actually awesome.
Yeah.
The movie,
I try to watch it.
I quit that.
It always looks great on paper,
you know,
it's just,
it's very hard for people pull off that
open relationship unless they're
disgusting.
I'll tell you what you want.
You want to see disgusting people go to
a swingers convention.
Oh,
fucking people are.
He and I were in a,
I think we're in Nashville and we did a
whole weekend at this place and we had
this guy drives around,
uh,
you know,
we,
uh,
hired a car service and got the same guy
to take us to the airport from the
airport and we became friendly with him
and as he's taken us to the airport at
the end of the weekend,
starts opening up about being a swinger
out of nowhere.
Man,
we're fucking driving to the airport.
He goes,
Hey,
well next time you guys in town,
I'm be happy to take you to a swinger's
party.
We're like,
what?
Huh?
What are you talking about?
Dude opens up that uh,
him and his Mrs.
have this relationship where he can
decide like whether or not she sleeps
with,
uh,
with other men.
If he can,
he can give the veto.
Yeah.
But uh,
diesel out.
Okay.
Yes.
That was.
Yeah.
So I go,
well,
how do you decide?
He goes on legs,
someone that just don't know.
I don't want it happening.
I go like,
what?
Like some hulking six foot five foot
ball player with a giant Hog August
thick is your calf like,
is that what it is?
And like he started getting
uncomfortable and I'm like,
well how are you?
How can you be uncomfortable man?
You just open up the doors saying that,
you know,
like what is it that turns you off about
some Guy Banging your woman?
Right?
What?
What's the big deal?
He could,
he couldn't answer.
He was starting to that.
We got deep into it with them in the few
minutes that we had left before we got
to the airport,
but we were laughing the entire flight
home writers,
guests.
So bar sometime because you get eat the
weird that I was with don cutting where,
where are we?
We call and we got off the plane,
got in this cab and we closed the door.
The guy started his ball to look right.
It's like there was the cup that I ever
started.
Let me tell you about our governor.
I heard governor socks because he
started like this 50 minute monologue
where he went and taught eddie clearly
was just eating to get it off his chest.
What we're looking at each other like
what the fudge.
We tell them to shut the fuck up,
but we haven't divided the conversation.
We are not really participated and he
just started for a word top to the last
cycle.
That's an evolution.
Like a limo driver in an uber driver
too.
Like if you get a limo they kinda like
they.
Hello Sir.
Let me open up the car door for you sir.
It's like there's like,
there's like going to a really nice
hotel versus like a shitty motel where
the,
the person at the reception is smoking a
cigarette,
you know,
you get what you pay for that.
Again,
a bucket.
He managed to use that material for.
I called him Eddie beat that he was also
he.
So I was like,
Hey,
look at that.
Totally shifted conversation and come
out with these.
Awesome.
Well,
yeah,
if someone's completely retarded or
someone's completely out of whack,
you could definitely make a good,
a good sketch about it.
This guy in Nashville,
I still think about this guy.
Every time I go there,
I'm just hoping I get him as a driver
just like it's so what?
Give me an update man I haven't seen in
a couple of years.
How's it all working out?
That will be awesome.
Yeah,
I'm back there in May.
I'm in uh,
May 19th,
I think,
or 20th.
I'm in Nashville,
so I hope I'll find that dude.
I'm really thinking about everybody.
Everybody.
Nashville,
please ask your cup.
I've heard what they seek about swinging
gate.
If you'll catch that.
I guy send him back to Joel to pick him
up at the airport because they have
clubs that go to.
They have specific swinging clubs.
I'm like,
well,
how does that work?
So I could everybody just,
you know,
sits on people's labs.
You go to people and.
But,
but they all probably looked like him.
He looked disgusting,
you know,
he's like a balding dude with a ponytail
and he was tall,
but he had a gut and like it was just
skinny,
but fat six,
I was also bored.
You have your playboy.
Does everybody look like they are out of
that?
That it's awesome to see the reality or
like,
oh that totally sucks.
Yeah.
The reality is most people that want to
do that,
they don't have a whole lot of other
options,
but there's probably only like one super
hot slutty girl that goes to those
things just loves being the Belle of the
ball because if you go to like a
swingers thing and you're actually hot
or hot girl if everybody wants you.
Do you remember there was a showtime
show for awhile about people that were
involved and like these big swinging
sort of relationships now why was.
It was terrible show,
but it was,
it was really weird because they would
show them getting together and making
out and doing all this stuff together,
but it was like this obviously like
really well lit room while they were
filming,
you know,
because there was cameras on me.
These people were supposed to like,
okay,
everybody act normal.
Yeah,
exactly.
It's like the comment off prs was these
other reality show or something.
Yeah.
Huh?
It was on showtime.
No.
Yeah,
it was just,
it was a polyamorous show you found it
was called polyamory.
Yeah.
That was it.
It was gross.
Get out of there with that very
monitored family.
Okay.
It's not modern had been doing that
forever.
Okay.
It's just,
it's odd,
but there's always like one dude who's
like,
you know,
just like this is way people should be,
man.
They should just relax and just enjoy
each other's company.
Man.
To me,
that's the thing is I fuck shoulder.
There's no shoulder.
Whatever your rapid weight,
if he works for you,
it works for you.
Exactly.
I know.
Star,
it gives a shit.
Do whatever you want.
What makes you happy?
That doesn't fuck over everyone else.
That's for anyone else or the
environment,
but people can say that you.
If you want to fucking open relationship
and fucks over my life.
Danieli,
do you understand?
I need a man,
a real man,
a man who doesn't want another woman?
You should.
It shouldn't be a compromise.
Should be.
You want to stack of romance novels and
lives based on this fucking artificial
narrative created by fiction writers.
Fucking fiction.
I hate that shit,
but what about those 50 shades of Grey
bitches?
I don't find those because that's an
untapped freak vein out there in
America.
A big one,
big one.
A lot of chicks want to get choked and
they're just not getting choked.
What is that about,
man that I don't get?
We don't get it and we never will.
That's the male female dynamic,
unfettered,
unrestrained that we don't understand.
Never got understand it.
Some of that shit is entirely above.
I want you to try the wrap your head
around this mental exercise.
Imagine you're a woman who is going to
take a condom.
The guy came in and squirt the contents
inside your pussy or not.
I can't imagine it.
No,
but those people were real.
Yeah.
So imagine that.
A man who doesn't want to have a baby
with you,
but you want to have to pay with this
motherfucker.
How do I do this?
I'm going to take the condom and stuff
in my posting.
Number it down and I'm gonna.
Get my fingers in there and I'm a
fucking shove it in there and we'll try
to.
I'm sure people have gotten pregnant
that way,
right?
I'm sure you all pregnancy to all
condoms.
Come with spermicide.
A lot of them do,
right?
The little sperm side in the kills them
little fuckers.
Wow.
That's some weird fucking people out
there.
Right?
But that's a human thing.
Like there's people that want to be
connected so badly to someone that
they'll lie about being on the pill.
Like I've had friends that uh,
they were having sex with a girl and the
girl's like,
I just don't,
I'm not on the pill,
but just so you can pull out.
So they'll google,
you know,
when you dicks hard,
you have like 10 percent mental capacity
that you're operating on.
Right.
And so they tried to pull out and the
girl wrap their legs around him and
wouldn't let him pull out serious.
Yeah.
More than one guys had that happen.
I've talked to more than one guy happen.
Yeah,
I've heard like the,
you know,
I'm on the pl where it's bullshit and
they get pregnant.
No,
I haven't.
Third is one weird trick.
Pregnancy is fucking crazy cause it's,
it's terrifying that not only did you
fuck up so hard that you got someone
pregnant,
you didn't want to get pregnant,
but they tricked you.
They lied to you.
And this,
this is the type of person that you now
have a child with.
So you have to raise a child with a
liar,
a manipulative liar who decided to get
pregnant.
Ooh Boy.
Oh yeah.
There's a couple of nitinol weird.
That's the lady got pregnant team time
shortly after telling him,
oh no,
no chance in hell.
And then of course he dcs under the
file.
This is the perfect family that then
they tell their kids never have sex
before marriage,
Dah,
and they were.
I remember talking with their kid like
the kid was like 14.
I was telling me all about,
oh shit,
but they say no sex before marriage,
ds and dace stocked with.
And I'm like,
no,
they didn't.
Technical mind was bugging guys like my
mom and dad met in Bible class and my
mom was pure.
The guy flipped.
He was like,
serious.
I'm like,
yeah,
I don't lie to you.
It's,
that's where it sets.
But at he was like,
oh,
holy shit.
I was like,
yeah man,
I'm sorry.
They just fed you a bunch of bullshit,
but at least you've got relaxed.
The Dep secs now just,
you know,
just the idea that some of them would be
so many nipples and so self centered
that they would decide to have a baby
with someone against that person's will.
Now that's,
that's when you know,
you see it as live problems,
you know,
that's where we are mentally fucked in
the head.
You're not just mentally fucked.
You're now connected to this person.
You're you,
you like that you've,
you're not just mentally fucked and
manipulative and evil,
but you're connected to a person who had
a baby with you know,
and it was all because you live.
It was weird.
It's weird.
Sex is weird because it's,
it makes people feel good.
Like if it was just like hugging or just
like,
you know,
being affectionate and just making out
and like,
oh,
that's all great,
but it makes people like blow jobs don't
make people,
they're awesome,
but they do not make people.
Fucking actually makes people like what
a bizarre way of reproducing that be
about it.
Like you're drawn to someone you can't
live without them.
The touches so magical.
Find your person what ridiculous.
That's when you got to see that the
universe has been designed by somebody
with them.
Lots of sense of your worry if there is
any design behind it because he's like
so much of a shit.
He's just fun.
It's just like,
it's funny,
but it all makes sense.
I mean this the only way to really truly
ensure that people have sex when times
are tough and you know the world is
rough and logically and intellectually
you wouldn't have a baby,
but you have a baby and you have to
figure out a way to hide it from the
barbarian hordes because you love it so
much and you have these urges and
meanwhile the reason why the barbarian
hordes are showing up in the first place
because they're looking for pussy.
So little things crazy.
That's the when he studied,
what does it show?
Some condoms use to contain spermicides,
but most don't.
It's best to use condoms without
spermicide says who?
The person who wants babies.
You fuck
it says the most looking at right now.
So spermicide can actually increase.
Chances of sti is such as HIV chlamydia
because it can cause the irritation
which can lead to the rubbing and blood
shadow.
Maybe on your Dick,
Bro.
Not Mine.
My,
my,
my Dick Lapses.
Promissory,
my digs.
Like whatever bro.
But um,
if you have like Lambskin,
I think lambskin condoms,
you can get pregnant anyway.
Like the ges can get through those
things and I definitely know the
diseases can.
I thought there was no pregnancy by yes
diseases.
I want to know how when heterosexual
people like Charlie Sheen gets HIV.
Come on Charlie,
you come clean about everything.
What were you doing?
I want to know what you were doing.
Right?
We share needles with somebody.
Like what were you doing?
Did you take it in the booty?
Right?
What were you doing?
There's no shame in your game,
right?
Man.
Come clean.
The problem is that he charged the case.
I don't think he burst.
No,
I'm sure I did.
Sad thing,
but who knows?
He's so hilarious because when he came
out and talked about it,
it wasn't like he wants to set the
record straight.
He just doesn't want to pay anybody
anymore,
so he decided to just to put up,
put a stop to all the financial bleeding
that was going on in his life.
That's a.
that's an interesting tale.
The Charlie Sheen tale because it went
from a tale of sort of almost like
heroic excess to like a sadness thing.
Yeah.
Victim ever.
See his teeth?
No,
like falling out of his head.
Yeah.
There's photos or I dunno.
I guess smoking cracks.
Not good for your teeth.
Yeah,
I would imagine.
I would guess that Fox and CNN,
one of his girls that he used to date
says fucking teeth are all falling out
and then if you see him when he smiles
he smiles like this.
Like it's Kinda like his,
his lips are cold,
curled over his teeth.
He like,
yeah.
It's like,
it seems fun when you hear about it.
He's doing blow and that's how he rolls
and he's having hookers and.
But then at the end of it you realized
like,
Oh,
this guy is probably like completely out
of control.
You know,
I'm probably a slave to these chemicals,
but also talented enough that he can
figure out a way to make absorb it and
amounts of money and he has really smart
people behind them because you went from
that two and a half men show where he
made exorbitant amounts of money to this
other show,
which was a terrible show.
Which one was it?
To?
Anger management.
Oh yeah.
Terrible Shell.
But he got an insane deal where they
filmed all 100 episodes,
like really quickly.
And so he made hundreds of millions of
dollars.
They were afraid it would end the
traveling.
No,
it's um,
it's a thing where you,
um,
it's like a guaranteed syndication deal
where if they did that they would do
like a 10 90,
like the way that the show would work.
Like you would do 13 episodes and then
you would do the back nine and the back
nine would equal 22,
which is a real season.
So like when we first did news radio,
I think the first season we did like 13
episodes.
And then if you get a pickup,
everybody gets excited.
Oh we got to pick up for the back nine.
So would they decided to do inside
instead of that was due a 10 90.
So you do the first 10 episodes and the
first 10 episodes go well you get picked
up for the full hundred.
Yeah.
So the idea is like,
look,
we've got a hit on our hands,
let's negotiate accordingly.
Let's go.
We got Charlie Sheen,
I don't know if you know,
but Charlie Sheen was a big part of
anger or two and a half men made
billions of dollars for the network and
we can do the same thing for you fx and
so they,
they bought hook line and sinker into
this deal and it just fucking went right
into the shit to her.
No success whatsoever.
Like it was just that not only talk
about,
nobody watched it or what to a good
question because I imagine watching the
beginning watch artist just because it's
like a train wreck about the weapon.
Well,
it was not a bad show at first.
It was one of those shows where people
watched it and it got like those.
It's hard to do a good Sitcom,
man.
There's not a lot of good writers.
You have to have really good dedicated
writers that are funny and then you have
to have an actor who knows how to pull
it off.
You have to have a show runner who's got
experience and putting those things
together.
There's an art form to creating a sitcom
all,
all itself.
You know,
I was on one for five years and I got to
see it pretty intimately from a bunch of
different levels,
from like the level of like really
talented,
really smart actors who configure out
how to manipulate a scene and make it
funny and the level of really smart and
really good writers who really know how
to craft a scene and then networks with
good ideas and networks with shit ideas
and then you've got to put them all
together and good luck and then you have
to back then you had to have a good time
slot to.
That was a big part of it because Peter
had to know that you were on it.
Gay Now times have changed,
right?
Nobody cares about it anymore.
It's just not even an issue,
but that's why Netflix has got it down.
Watch it whenever you want.
Not only that,
the whole season comes out at once.
That's of photo.
That's the best way I can watch seeing.
So one episode,
one week,
one episode,
the next.
That to me is bullshit.
I wait for them to be able to just tune
spoilers out and if I cashed out for gas
anyway,
doesn't matter.
Engine just being donate once it comes
out with and just watch every single to
30 days and be done with it.
I don't know.
I watch,
um,
I watch walking dead every week.
You're watching it on TV.
I don't watch it.
Like while it's on tv,
I'll watch it on itunes the next day
I'll watch on appletv.
I wait for them.
Fuck those commercials.
That's ridiculous.
What do I have to pay five bucks to not
have a commercial?
Fuck you.
That's it.
My time is way more valuable than those
15 minute chunks where you just
interrupt with stupid music and dancing
frogs or whatever the fuck is Geico
then.
Oh,
I'm selling insurance.
Fuck.
He's just ruined a Zombie show.
You've ruined the show is awesome.
It's a good show.
It gets better one with the La one.
I saw that one.
The walking dead.
They only did a few episodes,
but it's well really well directed and
well shot show and really well acted d.
only thing I agree with you,
I said,
awesome.
It's very well done.
The only thing I didn't dig where the
characters,
you know the character stuff,
the main story of the walking dead or
something cool characters that you dig,
that you care about them.
These guys,
you've kind of want them to all get
eaten by zombies.
Don't fuck about Daniel for them.
They are all like,
I want the woman to freak out.
She doesn't seem to freak out.
Very.
Yes.
Yeah.
She's almost to calm.
She should be shitting her pants for
eating people all around you,
bitch.
Your neighbors are monsters.
They haven't turned into a Zombie
looking either.
They're like,
they haven't deteriorated enough yet.
The beginning with the steel looks
mostly human.
I'd like it though.
I think it takes time to develop those
characters,
but like as far as the way it's shot and
acted,
it seems like it's Daniella.
We're almost out of time,
my friend.
I got to get the fuck out of here.
Cool.
What else is going on?
What should I tell?
I tell people about history on fire for
sure.
You're amazing podcast.
Thank you,
my man and you,
uh,
you opened up first episode with that
first episode,
but episode,
not zero,
but episode one was with one of my
favorite stories you've ever told that
fucked up story about the crucifixions.
I feel it's a fucking of stories.
The latest one I think was episode five
as a story to make it a crucifixion look
like at these Ne Bowlby.
What is it about a,
there's a story.
It's a complicated long story,
but to go for the essential element,
there's like these two Persian brothers
were putting sis who are fighting for
days in the CV of the water for power
and I'm the mom of both of the guys.
He speaks to and off them and get
killed.
And so at one point she's already pissed
off and she wants the guy who actually
killed their son to be executed,
but she can't ready to go through a
rather song and say execute this
motherfucker.
Because he was doing,
he was obeying and so orders.
Right?
So she find a way for him to fuck up for
him to say something that will piss off
or rather than the king.
And then the way the execute this
annuity is,
they put me in a box,
we thought he said he saw her Monday
slags sticking out with buddies,
sold baldies property bulks.
They force feed him horny and other
weird shit that for the next few days
the guy is being forced,
fed,
started shooting all over inside the
bulks.
These tracks matt goats like flies the
lay
magazine there and stuff.
And he literally started walking their
way inside of him.
So he has maggots hatching inside of him
and meeting him for the next two weeks
and they're file happy tails from the
award.
The kind of crazy shit that you want to
be.
I mean,
what a crazy mother fuckers sit down and
think,
I want to kill somebody,
but I don't just want to kill him.
Let's figure out in a slow torture
method of killing someone that's pretty
fucking weird.
God damn creative.
You look at what they did during the
inquisition,
all the different ways that killed
people.
Yup.
Yup,
yeah,
the game of thrones one where they put
the rat on your stomach,
put up late on a light that's a through
star.
That's like inquisition stuff.
They did that for real,
but actually just so not all of his
thrill fireys about crazy stuff that are
actually some pleasant stories here and
there,
but yeah,
of course they weird moments.
Our data as well.
There's one that you would dig.
I think the episode three was about the
iceman to guide that they found in the
Alps for 5,000
years ago and he's kind of like this
murder mystery because we have found out
that he was shot with an arrow.
We found all these scenes about these
life and death or some crazy ass details
that archaeology can give us about this
guy's life.
What he was doing there,
savvy dance that he may have been doing
acupuncture 2000 years before it was
ever done in China that were like crazy
stuff.
But what was the evidence of him doing
acupuncture?
Needles?
No,
they found like these tattoos,
but they're not that.
It was like artistic that they are like
dots and the lines and they roll along
the acupuncture points.
They are all alone points where he was
in pain,
so they think that he was kind of some
form of acupuncture that you would dig
in that spot with needles and then you
would see late with like possibly like
the way they do mock trial where they
burned herb,
some bright spots and the leaves that's
probably out of those attitudes
originated.
It's creepy.
It's like that rewrites history in so
many ways,
like some crazy European 2000 years
before acupuncture was in China,
was doing something very similar to
Trudet.
Pretty Weird in itself.
Never mind the whole murder mystery
aspect of it.
Also,
I don't know.
I dig they stories.
There are so many out there in history
that I have a field agent speaking one
and then researching the hell out of it
for a couple of moments.
There's another new one that we're
saying,
reef rewrites history.
They've found a mammoth of a dead body
of a mammoth that had a clear evidence
of human predation,
like one of the ribs had been shattered,
they think with a spear or something
like that,
but the problem was it was 45,000
years old and Siberia and they didn't
even know that people were their back.
Right.
So like they got it.
Okay.
Well,
I guess we're a little off here with the
time too.
It's just,
it just keeps going on and on.
I don't remember.
I don't remember the exact specific
details.
The story.
That's almost the problem with the over
abundance of stories in the Internet.
You almost get too many of them.
I know.
They're just coming at you all day.
I was starting that to Jamie right
before we started.
I was like,
Jesus Christ,
I love Internet,
but at the same time I need to get out
there wasting time because it's just too
much.
Too much.
There's good stuff.
You could go down or motherfucking
rabbit hole.
I went down a penis,
a penis operation rabbit hole.
The other day somebody sent me a link.
Matt stags.
Actually sent me a link to some guy who
grew back is for skin when I was like,
all right,
let's see what he did.
So this guy like put like weights and
stretched out.
It's for skin and all this different
shit.
And so then from that you know like the
suggestions over the right hand side on
youtube.
One of them was like this penis
operation.
I was like,
oh,
so then I go to this thing and this guy
is under and this guy they install a
pump and his ball sack and so the doctor
with his rubber gloves covered in blood
is squeezing on this guy's balls and
it's turned.
These guys don't work.
What?
Like that's what liberace had.
Apparently he had one of them pumps.
They put a a like a pump.
You're pumping your dick up with fluid.
I guess it's like a fluid in there and
then you hit a button and it releases it
and your Dick goes flacid again.
Fuck and bizarre.
The head doesn't get hard though.
The head is like sort of like a floppy
head.
It didn't seem like I was disappointed
because it kind of defeats the purpose.
I was just.
It was strange numbers.
All these other penis operations that I
just.
I couldn't do it.
Couldn't get into it.
That's the third editorial.
Yeah.
You can go deep.
All right.
Daniela [inaudible].
Thank you very much,
sir.
Your book.
Not Afraid.
It is outright.
Now,
Danielle,
a author also have create your own
religion.
History on fire podcast D Bolelli B o l
e l l I on twitter.
Thank you my brother.
Oh,
he's good time chatting with you.
Alright fuckers.
We'll be back tomorrow with Kyle
Kingsbury,
former UFC fighter all around.
Great Guy and fanny pack.
Enthusiastic.
He'll be here tomorrow.
See you.
Bye.
Yeah.