Store just lip singing songs and he
played drums.
Yeah,
he would play really good.
You'd pull the chairs up and jumps two
drumsticks and start playing to chairs
and it was good.
Music is really good and it would just
go on as long as there was one person in
the audience,
they will keep going so it lasts for.
I'd be like,
alright,
I bet it's 2:00
AM.
I got to go and then I'd stay there for
another hour and a half.
Yeah.
You know,
all the problems that we talked about
with the comedy store and all the,
you know,
the issues they have or how it's being
run.
At the end of the day,
that place is like one of the weirdest
spots ever for like cool development of
comedy is one of the best spots ever in
the country.
As dark as it is.
There is that element of creativity and
excitement there.
There's something,
there's a weird sort of a community and
a commodity like Tammy Presca Deli
posted something on twitter today,
like a comedy store gang.
All her friends from the comedy store
and starts,
you know,
putting all these people's twitter
handles together and I remember one time
me and Brent did a show in Florida and
printer.
It's just slade and he got offstage and
as he was coming up to me when comedies
to a motherfucker and like knuckles,
like they have that,
you know,
there's so many good comics that have
come out of there and they have that
disease history to that,
like being a marine or something.
Yeah.
There's something.
It's undeniable miserable and we love
it.
Yeah.
They just need to clean that place up.
Get rid of ever going back,
get rid of some shitty baggage in human
form.
The spot itself is fantastic.
Yeah.
It's one of the most historical spots in
the world of comedy.
I mean,
it's probably the.
If you thought you stopped to think
about it,
what is the most historically important
stop in the world of standup comedy
that's still around?
I'd say it's the comedy store.
I would say it's the comedy store to
prior film live that sunset strip there.
Is there anything in New York that
really counts?
I don't think anything's left.
I think he did.
Was that.
When did he film it?
There was of the roxy.
The Roxy was Kennison.
I want to.
I want to say that he filmed live.
One of them at least he filmed at the
comedy store in the main room.
Remember the background?
Yeah,
I think.
I think that was it.
I think I'm pretty sure that was it and
that was prior when he was just the
greatest stand up to ever walk the face
of the planet.
He was the number one guy,
which in my eyes what I have to rank
like the all time guys.
He's always number one prior.
Yeah,
I feel like priors,
number one,
I think.
I think Kennison in 86 was as funny as
any living human being ever has been or
ever will be and it always makes you
laugh.
Yeah.
It's never like,
oh good for him.
Oh very clever.
It's like he was the best for like two
years,
but then coke just took its toll coke
and booze and just fucking drinking
bottles of vodka.
And we had Aaron on the show and Marion
was telling us this story of,
I've heard some of them out with
Kennison after doing coke for like three
days in a row with no sleep and how it
like for years fucked with his head,
like he said for a whole year,
like he heard voices in his head like a
hole.
You can you imagine
having that kind of memory of Kennison
yelling your name at you.
And they were always locking each other
out of the house and fucking with
Saki about psychosis words in his head.
He was having,
like people were talking to him that
weren't really there like he was.
He was hearing things because of the
fact that he just red line his brain
hanging out with kids for like x amount
of years.
And he's a young guy to the point where
you're going to get out of town.
Yeah.
It drove kinison drove him out of town.
Well his,
his fucking story about hanging out with
Kinison is what?
One of the greatest all time Hollywood
party stories.
The way merit tells it.
It was from,
if I don't remember what number of
podcast it was,
but God damn it was good.
It's such a good story.
It's such a good story and such a.
When you stop and think about that,
like the history of standup comedy,
like one of the most epic things was the
comedy store explosion with Kennison and
the in the late eighties because it
became like everybody recognized that
there was this one spot we're kennison
developed in Hollywood and this is the
same spot where prior came out of and
David Letterman came out of it.
All these other people came out of it
like it put the spot,
like it became like an even bigger spot
in the mind of like standup comedy.
You don't really hear that about.
The improv was always a great club.
Still a great club,
but that places a nuthouse yeah.
Comedy store is always has been a
nuthouse.
It's crazy place.
Yeah.
I heard Schubert telling some story
about how he took kinison offstage on a
motorcycle one time.
How fucking awesome is that and I don't
know how that's possible,
but he told the fucking store and we
went through that back hallway,
said that was so hilarious and like can
I think kinison told them to do it,
but then you said kinison seemed pretty
scared when they were doing it.
Yeah,
I'm sure that's a shitty way to break
your leg twice a risk because you can
see out the window.
Yeah.
If you fall,
you could ruin a good set.
Yeah.
It's interesting that there's a,
there's no spots like that left in New
York.
Like there's a new spot,
you know,
the comedy cellar is like the new spots
and there's carolines which was always
like a big headliner club,
but as far as like a development club,
like the store,
there's really nothing left.
There's something in Queens called the
creek and the cave,
which isn't quite the same thing,
but there's comedy there every nights
and people can do it.
The only problem is there's no real
audience,
but there's like three or four shows a
night and you can just hang out there
and fuck around on stage,
but how long has it been around?
Long at all,
but that's what I'm saying.
It's like these weird things like the
store is one of the weirdest places
because it's a place that's still around
and still in the same form.
Like the way the shows are set up,
it started eight artists goes on at
8:30,
you know the show goes on throughout the
day.
Everybody tag teams,
it's an 8:00
PM to 2:00
AM show every night and that's just what
it is.
Like there's no other places that are
rocking it like that.
Yeah,
like how many places are left that are
running it like that?
I think it's the only one.
I think you're right.
I think there's very few other ones.
I mean there's some organized shows and
there's a main room shows that coincide
with the or shows that are organized,
but at the end of the day that that's a
weird club because it exists back like
the clubs used to exist in the hay day.
Yeah.
It's still running the same way and even
running more free than any of the other
clubs ever ran like that.
Yeah,
like the tag team thing.
Who the fuck else?
Tag Teams.
Is there another club in the whole
country that's known for only having tag
teams?
Nobody that's known for it.
I've only ever seen it.
Comedy magic does it.
They'll do it occasionally,
but it's not their thing.
Yeah.
They'll also have an MC with comedy.
Magic is the weirdest one ever because
they always have a magician on the show.
Yeah.
You know the fan.
I'm not crazy about it.
Definitely don't like following it.
That's for fucking sure.
Will.
Does it feel like you have to restart
the crowd when you follow it?
I feel like all they want is magic after
that.
Yeah.
Definitely have to restart your jokes.
Just not as impressive as disappearing
doves.
Yeah,
I've won.
I always say I should learn to juggle or
learned one trick just for situations
like that.
Yeah.
Music acts are the hardest,
right?
Use It gags.
Yeah.
You have to follow music.
Acts like God damn.
Especially if they're good.
So much energy in music.
Yeah.
I was just gonna say I was thinking that
when went to see,
um,
went to the um,
uh,
hard rock in Vegas.
Yeah.
House of Blues Rather in Vegas and saw
steel panthers.
I saw that same place.
I was blown away.
Did you like it?
Incredible.
I was so surprised at how funny it was.
I thought they were just,
I was going to be laughing at poisoned
songs.
They were so fucking funny.
No,
it's really good.
It's a really good show.
A,
it's like they're really good musicians
to.
Yeah.
And it's funny and it's like the music
is really good,
but there was one time where he was
doing this ozzy osborne impression and
his eyes,
he impression is so fucking good.
So I'm laughing like really hard at how
good is Ozzie impressionists and I'm
going,
God damn,
this is like,
they're nailing it,
right?
I mean they,
they,
they were fucking nailing it.
He was doing crazy train and I mean it
was incredible how good it was.
It sounded like he was moving like Ozzie
and I was sitting there thinking like,
what am amazing amount of power music?
I was like,
imagine if I had to go on after that
until a joke.
No Way.
Fuck it.
Fucking suck for at least 10 minutes.
Yeah,
you're fucked.
You're fucked.
You could try it and start off with
some.
Like,
you better jump on them right away also
because now their attention span is for
ready,
set.
Go like perfect,
smooth,
exciting beats rehearsed music over and
over.
No,
no,
no.
What?
I mean it's all perfect and it's all
like powerful and different and
completely different kind of tone than
you setting up a joke and being
conversational,
trying to draw them into the way you're
thinking about things.
What's up with Ikea?
I know men and women are different.
I even,
I had,
I opened a show for Brandon Flowers,
the killers,
you know,
this band,
the killers,
I've heard the band before,
he had a solo tour and they had me open
the show at the troubadour and that was
one of the worst experiences in my life
and that was just opening.
But at a music show they don't even
introduce you.
They're like,
go up there and introduce yourself,
you know?
Yeah.
I've only opened up for a couple of
bands.
I opened up for Bon Jovi.
Really?
Yeah.
That was,
that was,
I was terrible.
Was it?
I deserved whatever I deserved them to
think.
I was funny.
I wasn't very good,
but it was uh,
was also so strange because it was in a
theater in a round.
It was the kid I was on stage with all
their equipment,
so I had to like move around these drums
and try to tell a standup and I was not
really used to doing standup and places
any other than a comedy club.
I'd only been doing it like a couple of
years when this had happened.
So there's no way I should have been
like opening up for a big band.
Right?
No,
that's,
that's a,
that's a tall order.
Yeah.
I had some weird deal with MTV.
So they offered it to me and like a
greedy little bitch.
He doesn't know his place.
Accepted.
Yeah.
Well you have to.
You have to.
And so there was people behind.
You either walk around someplace in.
It was either Brooklyn or Queens,
I don't remember,
but it was weird.
New York bands use of e-cigarettes and
public.
Isn't that crazy?
What?
Forty three day eight.
You're no longer allowed to blow out
fake smoke.
And that is ignorant.
That's ignorant of what that is.
That's really stupid.
That's just vapor.
It's water vapor mean.
It's not.
It's not toxic.
It doesn't smell bad.
It doesn't anything.
Well,
I don't know why it exists though,
that maybe that's a good point.
Like why?
Why can't you make a vaporizer that
doesn't make smoke like that?
I think you can.
That's all part of the fun.
Is that what it is?
Probably smokers want to say it.
Probably most likely otherwise,
if you can't smell it and he can't see
it,
then what are you doing?
Dude?
I went to a restaurant the other night.
I went to a restaurant the other night
and there was this lady on the patio
that was smoking and uh,
you know,
it wasn't that she was smoking outside.
She has every right to smoke outside of
a restaurant if they have an ash tray
there,
if it's legal in the town,
it's that she was putting out our
cigarettes in this plant and you know,
we went out there afterwards and I was
talking with my wife saying,
do you think that she got rid of the
cigarettes?
Like,
just like,
no,
they're going to be right there.
And we walked right up there.
I'm sure enough,
four cigarettes in writing this,
you,
it's a nice place to stick it in a
plant.
She just decided right here,
this is where it is.
Like you wouldn't take your soda can and
crunch it up,
leave it there.
But for cigarettes,
there's a weird disconnect with
cigarette smokers.
It's a fact.
They know they're doing something toxic
to their body.
And they don't care,
so when they're done,
they're done.
They'll throw it on the earth.
They don't have any respect for their
own body,
they don't have any respect for the
earth.
And they always say it's biodegradable,
but how can that.
Even if it is so what it's going to
exist for 100 years.
It'll look like that for 100 years ago.
Tracy talk.
Yeah.
It's a little foam thing.
You know how long it's going to take for
that to.
It doesn't rain here stupid.
Even if it does,
if it degrades,
then it's going to go into the
environment.
You know it's going to become a part of
the dirt.
That's not good.
That's toxic.
That's shitty things.
You're supposed to put it in a bag and
then some supposed to pick it up and
they put in a landfill somewhere until
somebody figures out how to make it into
fuel,
you know?
But until then we got piles of places
where we stick shit like this
because we don't want it just laying
around on the ground.
It's not biodegradable fuckhead no way.
It's not.
Even if it is,
it's not.
Know even if it is,
but they all say the same thing.
They've all been given the same
pamphlet,
like,
this is what you say,
this is why it's okay to do it.
They all believed that early.
Say That
when Duncan and I were filming the Joe
Rogan questions,
everything show on Scifi.
We went to Utah.
We went to this one place.
This guy was supposed to show us
something.
It was the dude was nutty and he's
making shit up.
It was pretty obvious,
but one of the things that was weird was
that he was smoking cigarettes and I saw
him smile.
He's like,
oh,
it was supposed to be like this expert
that knows this terrain and knows the
area.
I see him smoking a cigarette and then
all of a sudden he's not smoking anymore
and he doesn't have it in his hand and
we're nowhere near garbage.
So I look at him and I just go,
what'd you do with your cigarette?
And he goes,
what do you mean?
I go,
what'd you do with your cigarette?
And he goes,
I go,
just throw it on the ground.
He goes,
yeah,
I did.
I go,
why would you throw it on the ground?
Go.
We're in the wilderness like,
like we're out here.
We're supposed to be like the stewards
of the land.
This is public wildlife land and you're
taking cigarettes out and thrown on the
ground in front of everybody.
You have a pocket.
It's not like a cigarette waste.
Fifty pounds.
You can't carry it back and you'll die
up here.
Put it in your fucking pocket man.
Like this is disgusting.
But for him it was instant.
It was like,
this is what you do.
You're done with your cigarette.
You throw it on the ground,
you step on it,
you walk on.
So he didn't think twice about.
I mean we're talking about beautiful
land,
gorgeous landscape,
crazy rock formations and shit.
He doesn't think twice about throwing a
cigarette onto that.
Just leaving it there.
Yeah,
but you wouldn't do with anything else.
That's a weird thing that people do with
cigarettes.
It's crazy.
It's real weird,
man.
Hmm.
It's real weird.
And it took Bill Hicks.
Yeah,
that's the worst part.
Most honestly,
most likely.
I mean,
maybe it was something else,
maybe it was genetic,
I don't know,
but I still smoked a lot.
Dean del Ray the other day and he rides
a motorcycle and he's like,
uh,
the worst thing is when people flick
their cigarettes out of the car and in a
year and a motorcycle and it goes right
into your like suit,
like driving and you're trying to get it
out of.
That's a weird one anyways though.
It's like that's the whole new level and
you see that all the time.
It's like,
I'm just going to throw out of this car.
You don't know what happens to it.
It's only California where everything's
dry as fuck.
It happens every week.
The whole fucking mountain side goes up.
All retards,
man.
We just got to get better at educating
people from the jump better at educating
babies.
That's what we gotta do to take babies
away from retards.
Giving that kid,
you're going to fuck them up.
He's going to be a cigarette tosser do
you watch?
Obviously I say no,
but I know the controversy.
I thought it was fascinating.
I posted some from the borrower report
today,
um,
and uh,
you know,
I guess a lot of people thought that it
was real.
I thought it was real when I first read
it,
like when I first read the title and
then I saw it was the bar,
what's report,
but it was that Vince and Scalia defends
a,
um,
hold on a second,
I'll pull up the tweet.
So I say someone tweeted me and said not
to talk about duck dynasty and I know no
idea what they were talking about.
This is why I'll tell you why the,
the,
um,
the thing I tweeted,
it's in the New Yorker and someone
tweeted me or sent me the headline and I
looked at it and I was like,
what is this possible?
And then I realized it was the borrow
it's report.
He's,
he's a comedian.
Oh,
okay.
Said Vincent Scalia Calls Duck Dynasty
decision unconstitutional.
All I saw was the New Yorker Dot com,
you know,
so I thought it was some sort of a news
story.
So I,
I posted it and so many people got
angry.
There was so much anger he'll fucking
supreme court to say with a lot of
people who agree with and I was like,
Whoa,
whoa.
I got a lot of Jesus tweets,
a lot of people talking to me about sin
and the sins of the flesh and Jesus says
that you,
there was a slew of them,
came my way,
and I was like,
wow.
And then so I had the tweet after that,
hey folks,
not familiar with the bar,
which report,
he's a comedy writer and when I post it
was satire.
Everybody take it easy.
He was just being funny.
But why is everybody getting mad about
the duck guy getting removed from tv for
saying that he doesn't understand
someone choosing a man's anus over a
woman's vagina?
You,
let's compare that to a lot of things
that people are allowed to say and not
get kicked off TV for.
Yeah,
right.
You know,
I mean,
is that really a big deal that he's
saying that I don't understand why
anybody would choose a man's anus over a
girl's vagina either?
I wouldn't.
Okay.
It doesn't mean that,
uh,
I don't believe that people should be
allowed to do whatever they want.
It's just that it's not that way for me.
It's like I don't understand when people
go to the opera,
I know people love the opera,
but I've been to the opera and I don't
understand it.
And I'm like,
it doesn't work with me.
Just like men's boutiques don't work
with me,
but they do work with some.
What'd you pick a man's anus over the
opera.
That's the question.
It's a toss up because I could,
you know,
you fucking got correctly.
You're done in 10 minutes.
Operas take three hours,
hours.
They take hours in their fucking mental
torture to me,
obviously not to you,
but you know,
that the duck dynasty where he fucked up
his,
he was a,
he wasn't just saying that he doesn't
understand people making that choice.
He's also talking about sins,
you know,
and people start talking about people
writing in hell for being gay.
And the network has to show a certain
amount of,
uh,
I want to say,
I don't want to say guidance,
but they have to set a certain amount of
an example if they are the people that
are ultimately responsible for putting
something on television and a guy says
something that is kind of homophobic and
I mean,
not even kind of homophobic.
What was his actual,
uh,
the actual quote,
let's,
let's pull up the actual quote because
uh,
it was,
um,
to me it's like,
you know,
you're talking to a guy who wrote a book
and his whole thing is about,
his shtick is about being controversial
and you know,
being a wild man with this wacky beard
and him and his sons and they all hold
hands and pray at the end of every
episode.
You know,
his fucking cock shore.
Yes.
Talking about the queers now,
it's not like the president said that
it's not.
I mean,
what is the redneck on TV?
Do you know what he looks like?
I mean,
oh,
you really surprised.
I mean,
thinking about the shit that archie
bunker said,
and it's classic television and people a
long for and cherish what is his exact
quote so you could pull up his quote
says,
think it's funny.
It seems like to me a vagina as a man
would be more desirable than a man's
anus.
That's just me.
He adds.
There's more there.
She's got more to offer.
I mean,
come on dudes,
but hey sin.
It's not logical,
my man.
Okay.
See that's not that bad to me.
He didn't guy that sounds like a guy
who's trying to do some comedy and
trying to be funny and he's not good at
it,
you know,
he's trying to be interesting or what?
Then he can take his whole life.
He's grown up being a duck call
manufacturer and then over the next,
you know,
x amount of years he becomes one of the
most popular people on television and
people think he's funny on top.
They love that.
He talks crazy shit.
So I think,
you know,
he gets into that sort of vibe.
Obviously that's who he is in the first
place.
The guy's not going to invent this
character at 65 years of age or whatever
the fuck he is.
He's not the owner of chick fil a.
He says he's.
He continues start with homosexuality
behavior and just more foul from their
beastiality sleeping around with this
woman and that woman,
those men,
they won't inherit the Kingdom of God.
It's not right.
He's,
I mean,
I don't want to sell much because I,
you know,
it's fake,
so I just,
I don't watch any of that crap,
but they show a lot of church scenes in
it,
don't they?
Like I remember seeing at least one.
It's a very religious show.
You don't fuck with God's America.
He released a statement.
Listen to this.
He said,
I myself am a product of the sixties.
I centered my life around sex,
drugs,
and rock and roll until I hit rock
bottom and accepted Jesus as my savior.
My mission today is to go forth and tell
people about why I follow Christ and
also what the Bible teaches as a part of
that teaching is that women and men are
meant to be together.
However,
I would never treat anyone with
disrespect just because they're are
different from me.
We all,
we are all created by the Almighty and
like him.
I love all of humanity.
We would all be better off if we love
God and love each other.
That was his quote.
What Dick?
Well,
TMZ has a thing up right now.
It says Phil Robertson publicly bashed
gaze for years and he knew all about it.
I love how they have and he knew all
about it and caps.
Well,
you know what,
man,
there's a lot of those dudes out there.
There's a lot of those weird dudes that
care if guys are gay and then they do it
because they think that Jesus doesn't
like it and they get angry about it.
I don't think anyone's ever read the
Bible.
A few people that read it doesn't
matter.
I tried one time.
I sat in so many hotel rooms.
I'm like,
I'm so many people talk about this
thing.
I'm reading this fucking thing.
Couldn't get through it.
Very boring so it doesn't hold up.
You think the alter states doesn't hold
up.
The Bible really doesn't hold up.
Yeah,
I mean there's no mention.
There is no mention of iphone comes.
There's a lot of people that fucking
read it though and they'll quote it back
to you when it our in that scripture.
16 chapter four,
and they'll just start quoting it and
you're like,
why?
Why does it?
Why is quoting some book all of a sudden
give like this?
Why does it have power?
Because it's the word of God.
I come,
I can understand it.
Yeah.
Why hasn't God talk like more clearly
covet thy neighbor's wife?
What are you saying?
What he's saying?
I can't fuck her.
Is that what would you please tell me
what the fuck covet means?
I don't know.
Dude.
This is long before the Dick Van Dyke
show.
You were not allowed to use those words.
Covet thy neighbor's wife.
Why don't you go tee off?
God,
Wham,
wham.
But yeah,
those shows are like,
they might as well be silent movies,
you know?
Might as well be the first,
the first minute and a half with him
just getting his golf bag together and
shit.
You know what else minds will be silent
movie.
Unfortunately men watching TV shows,
watching it on actual television with
commercials might as well be silent
movies.
Yeah.
And like it's gotten to the point where
it's like,
why would you sit down and watch what
someone else's programmed for you.
It's like,
you know what?
You want to watch what I'm trying to
sitting down and watching it through
commercials.
Yeah.
I'm saying like if you don't have a dvr
or if like I tried to watch the walking
dead the other day I tried to,
I taped it on the dvr but I also had
like an itunes subscription for it so I
could watch on ipad and I mostly watch
it on Itunes,
on my tv,
but I decided to try to watch it live.
Like actually watch it with the
commercials on because it was on phone.
Let's watch it now.
Oh my God,
this is like a 15 fucking minutes,
like six commercial breaks and they
played the same commercials.
Do not only that,
there was one time where it was like he,
they showed like five minutes of the
show and then it went to commercial.
It was crazy.
It was like,
this doesn't make any sense.
Like how the fuck can you.
You can't concentrate on the action.
You're not really into it.
You get lost in this,
this breakup by all this shit that you
don't want to see and then you got to
get sucked back into the action.
It takes a couple minutes and then next
thing that was another fucking
commercial.
I forgot how unbelievably like
disjointed.
Watching a show is like that.
I trying to watch a show like that
because I haven't done it so long,
but I did it the other night and it's
fucking terrible.
Yeah.
I don't enjoy it at all.
I can't believe they do it that way.
That is the TA.
They're having commercials on in the
middle of a show is the shittiest
fucking way to break up a show.
Like it's one thing if you have like a
two hour show and you have an hour break
to pee in the middle or something like
that and everybody knows it.
You come back in,
look at the opera.
Yeah,
like a five minute commercial break that
everybody enjoys and that this and that,
and then it becomes a contest of who can
make the most creative commercials that
make people actually want to stick
around and watch them and then they have
this five,
seven,
whatever the fuck minutes of commercials
and then the next shell plays.
That's how they should do it.
Just mixed the products in the shows.
Yeah.
But then you can't trust the show.
You're like thinking,
well why is he have a coke there?
Because they paid them down there,
you know,
as the Zombie of a sprite.
They already do that.
If they already do that on television
shows.
Yeah.
But if you go to my house,
you're going to see a coke,
you're going to see a sprite.
Why make it some fake one that's even
throws you out of your,
you know,
the real wisdom to begin with.
You know like if you have like a pop
soda,
you know,
no one has pop sodas.
Do you look at it and go,
oh this is fake because they don't pay
you unless you prominently feature.
They don't pay you if you just use it.
Like they give you free shit to use.
Like when we were on news radio,
they had like fake coax.
They were like the had like a sticker.
They would put over a real coke but the
logo was approved.
It was approved to use that.
If they want to pay you,
then you got to do a coke commercial.
You're going to have the coke right
there.
It's like this.
They're just giving you coke.
But if they wanted to pay you,
you know,
then then things would get different
than you would have to actually say,
you know what,
why don't you just have a coke and a
smile and shut your pie hole.
And then it would be like written into
it that you have to say coke every day.
I think there's a big difference between
like product placement and then like a
real commercial,
like the kind of monies that you get
when you're doing a commercial.
They get a lot of money when they're
doing like think about like how many
people were watching walking dead,
what is it,
like $16 million a show or something
crazy like that.
Who knows what the number is?
Something huge,
something huge,
right?
So just thinking about how many fucking
people are watching those commercials
and how much those commercials are worth
to the network.
Big money sign,
big money because if you're getting past
a million views,
2 million,
then you become a phenomenon like the
walking dead.
They're going to get some cash for those
ads,
those ads,
they're worth something and then those
ads are fucking up the whole show.
They got to figure out how to bumper it,
put them in the beginning,
put them on the end,
let the whole thing play out so you can
get drawn into it.
Just need.
Just wait for the season to be over
with.
Downloaded it all.
Well you don't have to wait.
You can download it as it's,
as it's airing.
Yeah.
That's where we get it from itunes.
But uh,
it doesn't,
I don't think it comes out the day of,
I think the day after or something along
those lines.
I might be wrong about that,
but I think I looked for at once when it
was only on the Dvr,
which is why I had to go with that
terrible.
Another thing that happened,
which isn't half as bad but still
annoying as shit is the whole fucking
advertisement right on the show.
Oh,
oh,
I'll take you out of it about sports.
Do that all the time.
You're watching one thing and at the
bottom is all this other shit about,
you know,
the guy pops up and he's like,
yeah,
those little floaty little ghost in the
corner that tell you about an upcoming
show coming up next on CBS.
Yeah,
no shit.
It's with,
they're,
they're dinosaurs.
Those things are all these like old
ways.
When that was the only way to get the
word out.
Just go tweeted NBC.
Okay.
Tweet it.
Yeah.
Don't don't run a big little fucking
little Munchkin in the corner that's
dancing around telling you to tune into
the next show while the show was on
right now,
hugging Munchkin.
Confusing the fuck out of me,
man.
The scroll is definitely the worst
though,
right?
Yeah.
Scroll that you can't stop reading.
Yeah,
you can't pay attention to this girl and
shit.
Watching,
watching a scroll.
Fox Sports,
lots of sports places.
They love that shit.
They love just giving you like if you're
watching a sports show,
they're not just going to give you the
sports.
They're going to give you fucking stats
and info at the bottom of football.
People love that Shit,
man.
Stock Market.
People love that shit.
If you watch a financial show,
they run the fucking market up five
points.
I'll get that fucking numbers.
How exciting.
Lot of new shows like Fox News does that
too,
don't they?
They'll show you the news and they'll
scroll.
Some Taliban commander killed.
16 dead drone strikes,
have all that shit on the bottom while
it's going on.
California man kills Jesus Christ.
Again.
He was only a tuna sandwich,
says the homeless men.
Yeah.
This,
this,
that inundation with shit,
which is constantly coming at you.
It almost makes the Internet less
complicated in a way.
It's an actual television aided.
Well,
the beautiful thing about the Internet
is there's a few live things,
but most of this stuff is just there to
download.
Yeah.
You can just stream it and get it when
you want it.
It's just there.
I mean,
there's a few live like honey honey did
a live music show from God,
I want to say England.
They in England,
I want to say they were in England.
I might be wrong,
but it was a,
they had it streamed through some
website and it was pay what you think
it's worth.
Yeah.
Cool.
That's great.
So you can put a dollar in or nothing or
50 bucks or whatever and uh,
they would show you a live stream of
their concert,
which I thought was pretty dope.
Nice.
But other than that kind of stuff or
this kind of stuff like it ustream or
something along those lines,
it's just,
you're just downloading things.
It's just most of the time it's just,
it's already out there.
Yeah.
TV shows,
man.
The idea,
you have to wait and it's Saturday
night.
Is it seven yet?
Thirty?
It's ridiculous.
Thirty more minutes.
Yeah.
And then you sit there and then you have
to sit through the commercials and all
that.
That's a Goddamn silent movie.
Yeah.
No,
that's what happens to me.
You know,
and I'm on the road or I'm in a hotel
room.
That's the only time I watch TV as TV
and I'm like,
I can't find anything I want watch.
You never don't change the channels.
You just get the shit.
Yeah.
When you're in a TV,
especially if you're in a hotel and the
they give you like a guide,
like you have like right next to the
right,
right next to your bed.
They'll give you like a big piece of
paper that has like Hbo Channel Ten
showtime shelter or whatever the fuck it
is.
But other than that you don't know
what's on.
You have no idea.
Just changing channels.
So he constantly changing channels,
watching some stupid piece of shit
changed,
handle watching that stupid piece of
shit changed.
Very unsatisfying experience.
Almost every single thing you get stuck
on his hbo and Public Access.
Local public access or if I like a
really good show comes on that you
didn't expect or really good movie,
that's a nice thing because it's a one
out of 10.
Then it's like hunting and you get that
satisfaction of winning the lottery.
But it's rare.
You know,
gambling is a tough game.
It usually leaves you unsatisfied.
Yeah.
The,
the.
And then if you want to get movies from
movie,
like those movie things where you press
menu and oh yeah,
he pays $17.
Ninety nine to watch some terrible
fucking moving.
You know what's really funny is when you
self,
when you,
when you go to the movies now and you
see something really funny,
you're like,
you're reaching for the remote control.
Like I want to see that again.
Oh I can't.
That's funny.
Yeah.
I think that when you're a you have
access to shit like we have on the
Internet,
we're getting super spoiled to the idea
of immediacy,
just being able to get things whenever
you want it and being able to like if
you want to watch an ad,
you watch an ad.
You know what I like.
I like when I go to a youtube page and
it starts playing an ad and then it
says,
skip this ad.
I go,
yes,
unless it's something I'm interested in,
I'll watch a little bit if it's
something that I'm interested in but I
don't want to have to.
It's awesome that they know that they
can't get away with showing them a
minute add.
Well sometimes they're really long.
Sometimes like four or five minutes.
You can skip them though,
right?
Yeah.
They sometimes they're like little shows
like you're,
you're forced to watch it,
but I've seen some interesting ones.
I've seen some cool ones,
some luxury extended trailers and some
interesting ones.
They've really upped their game.
When you consider like in the eighties,
it was like folgers coffee.
I really enjoy this drink,
which you rarely see though if you watch
a youtube video is you rarely see
commercials in the beginning and then
they pause in the middle and then have
more commercials and then they pause
again and again.
You don't see that.
You get to see the whole thing.
I don't know.
Probably the vast majority of what
you're downloading from youtube,
it's probably short clips for most
people,
but there's some pretty long shit on
there too.
Yeah,
you can watch TV on.
Watch our podcasts on there.
All three hours of them.
Yeah.
So there's some,
there's some long shit that's on there
as well,
so I don't buy the idea that like it has
to be done that way,
that it has to be every 15 minutes.
I think that's one of the things that's
going to kill them.
Yeah,
it's gonna.
It's gonna cripple the business that
people are going to get annoyed by the
fact that this is what the experience is
limited to.
And then once people start putting money
into like,
like Hulu plus doing original
programming,
original programming,
Netflix,
doing house of cards.
And uh,
what was the other show they were doing?
A black is the orange is the new black
is a good one and that is the prison
prison prison show.
So when guys like that,
when they started doing new shows and
creating their own content and putting
it online and making it available
through devices,
like,
you know,
I get my netflix through my DVD player,
you can get your netflix through
appletv,
you can lose a lot of different ways.
You get it and you get it instantly.
Yeah.
You know.
And it's going to be real hard to
compete with that.
If you make me watch commercials,
you know,
it seems like I would rather pay seven
bucks a month and not watch commercials.
It's seven bucks.
That's not that much,
you know what I mean?
How much is apple TV?
Every time you download the show is $600
for the whole season,
you know,
hours and hours and hours and hours of
entertainment and you don't watch a
single commercial.
I'll fucking take totally worth it.
It's worth more than that probably.
If you really stopped and thought about
it,
like it's probably worth like 100 bucks
to watch a full season of a really good
show.
You take a decent amount,
you pay hundreds for like 20 years ago.
Yeah.
To have that kind of access to a TV
show.
You think they're going to do that with
movies ever will.
They're going to have the option where
you could download it to your home and
you're like,
you have to pay 50 bucks.
Like you can't.
If you go to the movies and you're going
into a,
you know,
like an Imax and you're gonna see some
fucking new,
you know,
Saifai thriller or some new fill in the
blank.
Whatever it is you're going to probably
spend.
How much is it?
How much does the ticket these days
nowadays?
It's like,
oh,
at least avatar.
Liquid.
The 10 bucks,
15 bucks.
Let's go to the high.
Let's go to the 20 [inaudible].
Let's pretend we're in New York,
right?
You to see Avatar and you got to pay 20
bucks a ticket.
Would you pay 50 to watch it at home?
You probably want some people.
Definitely was somebody who is already
doing that,
so maybe he's already doing that now at
theater movies on itunes or movies that
actually came out in theaters in.
They're giving you the option to watch
it at home.
Really know these movies good.
Or they usually independent movies
usually like the independent or smaller,
smaller budget ones,
but there's been a few,
you know,
that actually I've been pretty big size
but then then again there's something
really cool about going to the movie.
I really like going to the movies
lately.
I find that's one of the only things
that can get me out of my head lately.
Liquor don't work.
No more pot.
Kind of.
Does that occur?
Don't work on the full job?
No,
no,
no.
I'm immune to it now.
What's going on?
I don't know.
I haven't been to a movie in over a
year.
You build up a tolerance.
Movies are great because you're not,
you're not allowed to check your phone.
Well,
I mean people still do it.
I don't.
I follow the rules and I'm in there.
I'm in the movie.
Um,
I can,
I can get out of my head and it's all
full up here.
I like the movies.
The ladies behind us.
We went to see the desolation of smog.
Wouldn't stop talking to each other
about the movie
in the movie.
Yes.
And it wasn't loud enough where you can
really say anything.
Yeah,
it kills you.
It kills you because you're like,
should I say something?
And then if you say something you feel
bad.
It
wasn't loud enough.
But the reality is it shouldn't be God
damn talking to the entire.
Like they kept it throughout
the movie,
but you'd be an asset.
It was like at the level where you'd be
an asshole if you brought it up.
It's,
it's,
it's awful because the movie's so loud.
Like how can you even hear?
But you can.
You fucking can.
You know it's there and it's,
it takes away from the experience a
little bit.
You're not.
It's wrapped up in it.
It's a level of purgatory that's worse
than hell.
Smog is good though,
man.
Let me see.
Anchorman that looks good to anchorman.
Looks hilarious.
You can't go wrong with a will.
Ferrell movie,
did you hear who's a in it?
All told.
Oh,
come on.
Kanye has a cameo.
Oh,
that's hilarious.
Yeah.
Harrison Ford.
Harrison Ford has cameo.
Yeah.
If you remember the first one,
there's a good fight scene.
Yeah.
Connie and Harrison Ford fight.
I think Louie Anderson's there.
How do you know this?
Somebody told me that they were.
They got the seed.
A premier.
Brian's.
Yeah.
Anchorman looks good.
You know,
it looks good to Godzilla.
Wolf of Wall Street was my idea.
Oh,
how is he going to hear it?
I saw cheech.
Marin,
no doubt you did at union station
downtown.
Let's hear it.
Okay.
Tommy Chong,
the wolf of Wall Street.
My idea.
So I heard that you shared a cell with
Jordan Belfort.
Yeah.
A cubicle or cubicle.
And we don't sell it and call each other
cellmates we call ourselves sellies.
You also mentioned it was very similar
to goodfellas.
That was nice.
You mentioned it was very similar to
goodfellows.
Well yeah.
Well that was my favorite part.
So please like,
did you guys have to have someone like a
wife smuggling bread or like what
happened?
Yeah,
we actually,
we had people smuggled Turkey and course
for uh,
for Thanksgiving.
Oh my God,
that is awesome.
Yeah.
We show one of the wives,
put her dinner boots are big boots.
I heard he also urged him to write it
down.
Do you think you deserve any of the
royalties from that movie being made?
Coming up for Jordan?
I get inspired.
I wrote my book called a meditation from
the Jordan and Jordan asked me,
you know,
I'd write everyday and what are you
doing?
I told him so he said,
did he,
he's so used to reading his book and
they wrote a few pages and he showed me
and then I kind of insulted him because
I told him you haven't written anything
and he got really mad because he's a
genius.
So he ended up rewriting.
I told them how to do it right from the
heart rate of but what you know.
And uh,
next thing you know,
he's got a best seller movie.
That's ridiculous.
You should get a crazy.
I just seeing him do good.
Actually,
my biggest thrill is watching him make
money,
honestly,
because he was such a genius,
but he was,
you know,
he was like all thieves,
they had twisted.
Wow,
that's much different than the headline
is different.
I was just going to say that that's
really irresponsible headline,
but that's what got us to listen.
If it was like Tommy Chong salutes a so
and so for the success.
I mean,
all he said is that he helped the guy.
Right.
You know,
now I didn't know that the guy who wrote
that was a guy who was selling to Tommy
Chong.
I didn't know he was in jail.
That's interesting.
Wild.
Yeah.
I don't know.
Is that supposed to be good wolf of Wall
Street?
It looks great.
Looks Pretty dynamic that Leonardo
Dicaprio flies under the radar with a
lot of people,
but he might be the baddest mother
fucker of them all.
I think he's fantastic and he,
Miss Garcia Square says he put us
something every Christmas.
This is great dude.
That quintin Tarantino movie,
the Django moving when he makes the turn
from being a good guy to bad guy.
He's a bad motherfucker.
I think he's great.
He's he.
He's too cute.
That's the problem.
Got To fucking handsome.
And Duck Dynasty said he's the only
asshole that's better than a vagina.
Did he really say that?
I'm sure it sounds like something they
would say they suspended.
The dude pulled them off and for that I
feel like the headlines are way worse
than the quotes on these things.
Yeah,
I agree.
I just had an issue with this microphone
here.
We'll be right back folks.
This would actually be a good place for
commercial commercial.
Turn off a broken thing.
Fix that shit.
Do.
Hm.
This is just a shitty microphone arm.
I was going to switch this to those
anyway because it's actually a bad
commercial for these mics.
Brian stole a Friday.
Joe Rogan and jody said ideas are going
to be a house with a few other comments
this Friday,
this Friday.
ICEHOUSE chronicles and tomorrow's show
tomorrow.
Uh,
we got a bunch of good people on that.
And Joe Rogan's going to be at the
Hollywood improv.
Uh,
it,
uh,
forget New Year's Eve.
Beautiful.
I got a commercial for Ya.
Nice new CD.
This is the part of the job I hate now
on Itunes,
a job I hate.
It's now an itunes.
Now when I tune it's available to the
public,
just get another one.
We're going to have to switch out
microphones here.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we had an issue.
This is what happens.
Shitty Chinese made Mike.
Um,
we just went to America.
Detroit makes a fine.
Mike,
um,
is actually ones that Fitzsimmons has on
his,
uh,
serious show that are pretty dope and
I'm trying to find.
Couldn't find them.
Don't mix.
The mikes are great.
The Mike Arms Soco fat one,
the ones that,
um,
that um,
Craig Simmons has on his serious show.
These really thick,
like tubular aluminum looking ones.
They don't like the,
the wire goes through the center of
them.
Yeah.
It doesn't have all this a velcro.
Bullshit.
Need.
Get this.
Why don't you guys talk yourselves.
Okay.
To Texas tour,
uh,
me and Tony Hinchcliffe are coming to
Houston,
Austin and Dallas,
one January,
ninth,
10th and 11th.
And we're also bringing a surprise
guests that are about to announce.
Tell us,
tell us the tickets are on sale now.
You can just go to [inaudible] dot TV or
will you.
Will you bring me back some ribs,
Brian?
I was thinking about some Texas ribs
today.
Have a mouth water and can't wait to go
back to Texas.
I can't wait.
I hope to run into Aubrey on.
It's there.
I want to hang out with Alex Jones.
I might spend an extra day in Austin
maybe.
Have you ever spoken to Alex Jones
outside of the time she'd been the show?
Yeah,
he is my.
He once in a while,
text me back in the day.
He would text me back and forth and
Alex,
but then I would text him and somebody
else would have his phone number.
Barbecue is.
I know the best.
Barbecue is where the CIA is.
Not watching you every five seconds.
Wait,
try.
Enjoy a fucking brisket.
I love Alex Jones.
No,
he's great.
I can't wait to get back to Austin to
see that.
Dude.
I can't wait to have him on the show
sometime.
I'm surprised that we've never had him
on the podcast.
We'll
eventually.
He's just never in La and he,
when he has,
he's busy dodge and chem trails,
so a lot of busy work will have many
people get a chance to see a different
side of them.
We do,
you know,
I'm sure he'll go crazy and yell and
scream,
but you'll get to see a side of him.
Well,
you'll get it.
You'll go,
oh,
that's why they hang out.
Like he's a fun dude and people always
ask me,
wait a minute,
is he for real?
Yes,
he is.
he is for real,
for the most part.
And uh,
he's fun to hang out with man.
Uh,
but we are having Roseanne Barr on.
She's going to be on here.
Thirtieth next week is going to be
Monday.
Joey Diaz and Tuesday Duncan trussell.
Nice.
So we've got a lot of shit going on and
there was a gentleman and a lot of
things happened with Alex Jones back
when the old car Cap City Comedy Club in
Austin,
Texas.
When they,
uh,
showed you camp trails.
That was the old.
The old.
The old back room.
Yeah.
It's so stupid that they got rid of it.
There was so much history on that.
Yeah,
they fucked up.
That was a dumb move.
That room was awesome.
That room was just filled with people
signatures for decades and decades of
comedy and they decided to paint over it
for some strange reason for no reason.
Right.
Whose idea was a cap city?
How dare you.
Meanwhile,
I was one of the greatest clubs over.
Yeah,
it's a must stop.
Like if you're a comic and you're doing
like a national tour and you know you
have like 12 spots we're going to hit.
You're going to.
Austin.
Got To go there.
You get booked at cap city.
You'd be retarded not to go.
You gotta go silly bitch.
Start the wall all over again.
They're good.
They're smart.
They're cooled.
They're.
They don't give a fuck.
They're from Texas.
Not Show biz obsessed.
No.
It's a totally different vibe and they
liked to party and drink some beers.
People locked you part and
that sounds like matthew mcconaughey
forecasts everybody's to be there,
Yada.
Come.
Texas is a fun place to stop.
I'm not sure.
I'd want to live there,
but it's a fun place to stop.
Really.
Not,
not like an Austin.
Um,
I think maybe outside of Austin I'd like
to have a ranch where have a trusted
assistant guards the perimeter,
perhaps a wolf dog by my side.
You got to get guns and you got to get
dogs.
Have you seen this?
A thing that they discovered in Bolivia.
Brion.
Pull this up.
It's on my twitter.
Three hundred foot wall in Bolivia has
over 5,000
dinosaur footprints.
Whoa.
That's crazy.
The earth has moved so much since then
that this is like,
it's now like a straight wall,
like a flat cliff.
It's really crazy to look at,
um,
because you know,
the earth's topography changes and this
where these things are walking at one
point in time it was probably like a
creek bed or something like that.
But now now it's vertical.
Yeah.
That muddy water or that muddy ground
that they were walking on,
there's a bunch of them.
They found a shit of a shitload of them,
but it says the title of the,
um,
feed is a twisted sifter,
twisted sifter.
I guess it's an archeologist website or
something.
What do you want to do with your life?
I want to look for this 300 foot wall in
Bolivia has over 5,000
dinosaur footprints.
It's crazy that it's a wall now,
so at one point in time they were
walking on it and then the earth fucking
radically shifted.
So much so that it's like a wall and
these muddy footprints are up the side
of the wall.
It's crazy.
So I wish someone was here that knew
what the fuck was going on.
So they explained this to us.
Yeah,
because I'm just assuming it tends to
happen.
Hey,
what do you guys know a lot about
dinosaurs?
Are they really those bright colors?
No,
but as much as anybody.
No Bro.
No.
It's awesome.
Dinosaur Gel speculative.
In fact,
there was some recent speculation that
because of the way t rex was built that
he might not have been a Predator at
all,
that he might've been a scavenger and
that he might've been very vulture like
that.
Instead of looking at this green
murderer that we see in Jurassic Park
that he would have like these really
bright red skin.
I called out to see if you could find
those images brion,
pull up a t rex,
vulture scavenger,
t rex.
But if it's interesting because you
realize when you see something like
that,
oh,
they're just guessing type in bad rap to
Brian just understood dinosaur Tbx,
vulture x's.
Oh,
um,
it,
yeah.
You can find there's some right here.
No,
that's not it.
If you go down to other,
this one,
this one here,
they uh,
they,
they drew him with a very bright red
face and a black skin behind it,
much like our door.
And that was,
uh,
one of the,
one of the speculations was that he
wasn't able to run fast enough because
of the way he's built that it really
just wood lumber onto dead things and
fuck them up.
And there's also some evidence that
something's got away from him,
which is pretty interesting when you
consider how fucking big they are.
How did anything ever get away from that
with that mouth?
But there was bite marks on things that
actually had had survived for x amount
of years or x amount of months or
whatever after been attacked by one of
these fucking things.
You think we got a lot of big animals
still that aren't that fast.
And I'm like,
this motherfucker,
you know,
the thing about the time of the
dinosaurs is also that the whole
atmosphere was different than the
atmospheric pressure was different.
The amount of oxygen,
the air was different,
the temperature was different,
and if it was a really super oxygen rich
gaseous environment like I think has
been speculated,
it might've been easier for a big thing
like that to move.
And that might've made sense why there
are so many big dinosaurs.
Dinosaurs were fucking dwarfing
elephants.
They were huge.
Really?
Yeah.
If you look at like Brontosaurus,
you know,
look at all those really giant plant
eating dinosaurs.
They were fucking enormous.
We went to the Natural Museum of history
in New York.
They have all those bones of the
dinosaurs.
When you stand next to one of those
things,
you just go,
oh my God,
like you,
you really get it in your head like
Jesus Christ.
Why did it,
why is it that big?
Why did it grow?
That was everything.
Right?
And now you look around and everything's
small horses.
Not that vague,
you know?
Right.
And that's little ass dudes are running
this shit.
Giraffe is like a baby compared to a
dinosaur.
Like that's the biggest shit.
We got crazy long neck asked a
you're received.
But if a t rex it looked like if it was
furry because I always thought what if
they had for.
They look kind of like crows,
like look at this.
Wow.
So they don't even know if they were
offering.
I don't know.
But you know,
it's crazy.
They know that a lot of dinosaurs did
have feathers.
Yeah,
there's the direct descendants.
What if a t rex to us it looks scary
because it'd be like taking a bird and
taking all its feathers off and then
yeah,
it looks scary.
It looks creepy as fuck.
No,
they look scary,
but it was cute.
If you have a bird that has a head that
big,
it's probably even scarier.
A bird with teeth like that and a head
is big as a t rex,
be fucking terrible.
Evil.
Just an eagle can fuck you up.
Right?
I'll look at that shit.
You know,
you should google maps,
Google terror birds t e R,
r o r birds.
These were these gigantic six foot tall
birds that they might've been even
bigger.
They um,
they didn't fly.
They just fuck people up.
They just fucked things up.
Dude.
Two point five meters.
So yeah,
they were a six and a half feet tall or
six.
How tall?
Two and one and a half is a meter,
right?
Three meters.
Three telling me an American.
So they were a seven.
A half feet tall.
Seven and a half feet tall.
It says eight foot.
Two inches.
Okay.
Why didn't you just say that?
Why you making me do math meters?
Three is a meter.
Three feet or the yard?
Three feet.
A yard is three feet.
So what's a meter is close to three to
three,
but it's not exact.
Okay.
Either way,
eight foot two inches tall and weighed
approximately 330 pounds and it was a
fucking bird.
God Damn.
Just this big ass spooky looking fucking
bird.
Imagine that.
That's just the birds.
Seven and a half feet tall and eats
meat.
Running around with that hatchet for a
face and it wasn't that long ago,
man,
please.
Things were alive when people were
alive.
Is that true?
Yeah.
Fifteen thousand years ago.
They did not become extinct until 15,000
years ago.
That's fucking terrifying.
Oh my God.
Jesus fucking Christ.
The Romans could have had a fight that
okay.
Maybe that's not true because there's a.
apparently there's some controversy
about that,
that it has been suggested that species
did not become extinct till 15,000
years ago,
but more precise dating by a Dr.
Mcfadden and his colleagues refutes such
a late date and that all known the birds
called the tight tennis tight tennis
titanic.
Fossils appear to be at least 2 million
years old.
Wow.
Giant flightless birds called fos.
Whew.
Okay.
For Russ.
So high.
I'm not even gonna try.
I'll spell it for you.
P H o r u s r h a,
c I d a e.
good.
Fucking luck with that one.
For a psoriasis a did the which are
named Tara birds has been thought to
represent the youngest species of the
lineage.
That's interesting man.
You know what's interesting to Congo
still has like big giant flightless
birds.
That's why I don't go.
They have these weird birds that go
fishing in the Congo.
Yeah.
Oh Dude.
There's a video.
Brian.
See if he can find the video of ancient
bird.
Eat snake fish please.
Brian,
I want to see it eats snake fish.
Congo,
do you think he's going to look any
extra heart?
If you ask them,
please make fish.
Shoot bills.
That what it is?
A shoe bill.
EATSA snake fish.
Yeah,
that's what it was.
Shoe Bill.
Eat snake fish.
See why we would watch television with
commercials in it.
Will you just type in birdied snake fit?
Yeah.
Dude,
that's it.
Shoe bill video.
You've got to see this fucking thing.
This thing looks like something that
should be extinct.
Like when you see a shoe bill,
you,
you look into.
I,
and it might as well be.
What was that movie?
Who's
The fucking movie where there was A.
There's a guy who's like not wes craven.
Fuck.
What is his name?
He had a bunch of really cool
hard novels that had been produced and
turned into movies.
All I can think of a Stephen King,
but I know that's not right.
No.
John Carpenter.
No,
no,
no.
Gracelyn Gresham.
No.
Horror.
It was hard.
Look at this fucking thing.
It's crazy.
Yeah.
Night dwellers or something like that.
Fuck.
What was the guy's name?
Look at this fucking thing though.
My point is that this thing belongs in
that movie.
This doesn't seem like a real being.
That seems like something out of Haiti's
that's walking forth amongst the earth
among the people.
Is that still alive?
Uh,
not in my world.
Snake fish in it.
I find that fucker.
Take it out.
Zombie.
I take it out,
bro.
I don't let this thing stay in my
environment because if it grows larger,
it's a threat to my ancestors.
It's the Rogan and joey show my progeny.
Look at this thing.
So what do you want from me?
This fish.
I got meatballs.
That's all I got for you.
This fish goes up.
This snakehead fish goes up and sucks.
A big,
deep gulp of actual air cat right there.
Get this fucking bird.
This bird is a giant bird.
I think there are about four feet tall.
Where?
Snuffaluffagus.
Wow,
that's crazy.
Hey,
forget about bird comes up to me like
that.
He gets a hold of that fish.
What a scary fucking creature.
Oh my God.
What a fucking scary.
Yeah,
the fishes scary too.
But that bird is just extra freaky.
It looks like he could fly with those
wings.
Can they fly?
God Damn.
That thing is big.
So weird.
What's so fucking weird?
Animal man,
very large stork like bird derives its
name from the massive shoe shaped bill,
although at some like somewhat stork,
like overall form
and has been previously classified,
blah,
blah blah,
blah.
The true affiliations with other living
birds are ambiguous.
That's interesting.
So it might not have any affiliation
with other living birds.
Some authorities now reclassify it with
the Peli and formed the adult is mainly
gray.
While the juveniles are brown or lives
in tropical east Africa and large swamps
from Sudan to Zambia,
birds,
you're amongst the trippiest fucking
things that are alive on this planet.
Well,
they can fly and even if they can't fly
their trip like we're freaking out about
those terror birds.
The ones that walked Joey Diaz was all
pissed at this bird because he did one
of those snakes and ranch.
How big are these fucking things?
It doesn't say how tall they are.
Identification.
Hmm.
I'm just fascinated by birds,
man.
I'm fascinated by the fact that they
used to be dinosaurs essentially.
Have you ever seen those gigantic eagles
that live in the forest of South America
and they eat monkeys.
Monkeys.
Oh my God.
Dude.
Heartbeat Eagles.
Brian,
Google w.
What did that bird do?
Just eat a duck.
It just was like,
hey,
how's it going?
To what?
Bird was a Pelican,
a Pelican and says like,
Hey.
Oh,
no way.
Oh my God.
Did it just swallowed it whole in front
of all these people too.
It doesn't give a shit.
Look at that.
The other ducks are kind of cool with it
too.
They're not that scary.
I don't think they're smart enough to
know what the fuck happened.
How about that?
I think you're right.
They probably never thought there was
going to happen.
Someone's going to come along and
swallow them.
No one of their breadwinner.
What did I ask you?
Just five seconds ago?
Uh,
to look up.
Um.
Oh,
the heartbeat.
The Harpy Eagle.
Just,
we'll,
we'll end on this because this is even
more prosperous is the biggest eagles in
the world is the heartbeat.
Eagles.
Venezuela.
Brian,
can you please look that up for us?
Thank you.
Second.
Seems a crazy man.
They've,
they've caught them stealing.
Sloths.
Just snatching them from their trees.
If you go to a heartbeat,
eagle grabs a swath.
He could see this fucking thing.
What?
Los Eat vegetables.
They're really slow as shit and they
don't have much defense.
Especially not against a flying raptor.
Especially like the,
I think the biggest ego in the earth.
I don't think there's any bigger egos
than the Harpy Eagles.
They're enormous and this thing swoops
down.
He got it.
His heartbeat eagle training.
No,
go to a harpy.
Eagle grabs the slot.
There's a video that shows this thing
stealing one of these slots from the
world of the living.
Watch.
This shit is just upside down.
Poor bastard did look how slow they are
learning they're designed to.
The Eagle Food is there for the taking.
It's not even putting anything in
between the two of them.
Oh,
he's.
He's probably so dumb.
Look at him.
Okay.
Moves.
Forget about it.
Oh my God.
That is freaky.
That's probably fun.
Now for him right now,
for the sloths right now.
Right now he's dying because he's
getting his body punctured by these
giant swords.
This fucking thing as the end of its
feet.
Nothing fun about that feeder.
These claude things,
the the raptor clause or frightening
man,
especially a big giant one like that.
There's a reason why those dudes have
those goofy shoulder straps on.
You know those things that they put
these big leather things on hold to the
Eagle on their arm or whatever those
things are called.
What are they called?
Eagle gloves.
Sarah name for one of those things that
are an eagle lands on called him gloves.
I don't know.
There's a name for it.
Oh God is he is to say it.
No,
no.
Joey Dsa.
What are you waiting for?
Fucking falcon land on your arm.
Eddie Bravo had a leather thing as well.
Is that real?
Is it?
Has It?
Has all those little swords in the end
of its feet?
Dug deep into and it's just flying.
That's a big ass carp to Leslie Eco.
Look more scared than the fish because
the evil evil evil and it knows it's
evil.
The wicked never read.
Would it be like when I die,
what will it be like when I died with
that?
Go to hell.
All right,
ladies and gentleman,
this podcast is basically reached in.
Thanks everybody.
Thanks everybody for listening.
Thanks to everybody for being a part of
it.
Thanks to red band.
Thanks to the full charge.
Thank you.
Thanks to Jay.
Bob will make things happen over here.
We've got it all going down tomorrow
night.
We will be at the ice house in the
little room.
It's the fucking sweet spot.
Just calm j-pop.
Yeah,
that's the new name.
Oh,
because it's not jam band anymore
because he's got his short hair.
J pop pop hair cut now.
Can't have jam band and not abandon your
pop your pop star singer.
Now I'm whatever.
I don't even know what I was talking
about.
A Friday night.
Joe Diaz,
me,
Brian Red Ban,
ngf follow a Mike Young.
Beautiful,
powerful.
Mike young were going to have some fun
Friday night.
Like I said,
it's the little room.
It's one of those places that you very
rarely get to go to.
Mike young just has an amazing news.
Maybe he's coming to a huge network very
soon.
Nice
for my account.
Right.
Thanks to everybody for tuning in and
thanks to tim for sponsoring the
podcast.
Go to [inaudible] dot ting.com.
Save yourself 25 bucks.
Ladies and gentlemen,
it's worth the ride.
Thanks also to [inaudible] dot com.
That's o n n I t,
makers of Alpha brain and thanks also to
wanting hundreds.
Today is one.
800 flowers.
Let me read this because they've got a
new thing that's just for today.
Only today one,
800 flowers just for today only,
so when you hear this in the future,
that shit won't work anymore,
but the offer code j,
he will still be good for savings on
whatever their all their new offer is
one 800 flowers.com.
Enter in the offer code J r e n for this
special day you get one dozen red roses,
you will get another dozen for free and
it's available only today.
One 800 flowers.com
and one 800 flowers if you call them,
just mentionedj r e dot.
Thanks also to [inaudible] dot com.
Go to o n n I t use the code name,
Rogan and save 10 percent of any and all
sub hummus.
And uh,
we'll be back Monday,
Tuesday,
Duncan trussell.
The week after that will be the Great
Roseanne Barr.
We got a lot of the people coming on.
We've got a lot of shit happening.
Ladies and gentleman,
we love the fuck out of here.
We appreciate you very much and we'll
see you very soon.
Big Kiss.