Gentle man,
what's up?
You dirty bitches were live.
Refresh your browser saying you could
see us in the youth stream like we are
seeing ourselves.
I muted it.
You Fuck,
you can't get me.
Good job.
Yeah.
So.
Hi everybody.
It's a week like 20 or some shit.
This is insane dude.
With this is we're all the way into may
almost.
This is April 27th.
Is that what it is?
Yeah,
we started the late December.
we started at the beginning of the
Christmas.
Yeah.
We basically started at the beginning of
the year and here we are.
It was a number three last week on the
itunes for podcasts,
which is ridiculous because the fucking
production value is God damn awful for
itunes.
I Apologize Ladies and gentlemen.
It's Kinda,
it's Kinda cool to get better.
Well it's definitely it's garage,
but uh,
we got a bunch of new shit coming where
right now.
This is just my,
uh,
my desk,
um,
we have cleaned everything out and the
couch couches coming in Thursday and the
green screen slightly after that we got
new,
a MP,
three audio recorder,
some big fucking serious jammies here
before the cow,
smallest after accounts saying it is
okay to use dreams [inaudible] up on me.
I've been watching.
We just went from zero to 850 viewers
within what,
two minutes?
One minute.
And then let's sort of those boring or
so this is some new shit.
We got to make the sound better for you.
I tunes people and thank you very much
for putting up with it up to this wall
and I appreciate all your suggestions
and I know people get harsh with the
criticisms,
but the bottom line is that's your real
opinion and uh,
I appreciate it.
You know,
um,
I've got a thick skin.
I've been in show business for a long
time and most people have been saying I
suck ever since day one.
So you get used to it.
But I think all your criticisms are
valid.
Uh,
we're working on the production quality.
We have real microphones now of course
we have this and then we also have.
I'll have to hold onto this for a
second.
We bought some serious sennheiser
microphones just like you would use in a
recording studio.
So at the end of the day when all is
said and done alcohol swabs to clean
that shit off and make it all nice.
Nice.
We don't want to,
I guess get nerves,
but uh,
so we're turning this thing into a real,
a production studio.
We're going to have cameras on tripods
and the whole deal.
And I'm stealing a page out of Anthony
Kumi.
His book,
Anthony Kumiai is one of the dudes from
opiod,
Anthony.
Super Cool Guy and he does a bad ass
radio show from his house.
Um,
and uh,
he's one of the ones that gave me really
the first inspiration to do it because I
saw his son up and he set up his fucking
bad ass.
He hasn't set up basically just like a
real radio show,
you know,
with like real jam and microphones and
he has a backdrop and a green screen.
So I'm basically stealing anthony's idea
with his blessing and with all due
credit to Mr Kumi,
I should add something to it.
They're like a hot tub or something
crazy.
Anthony is do when you were with us in
New York last time,
right?
You see his gun?
Yeah.
Carries the gun around a special permit
to so you can carry a gun everywhere.
It was weird when they brought it up
because everyone else in the room was
like,
oh,
they were all like,
they're all concerned about him.
They're all worried that he's going to
go bananas and kill a bunch of people
would she may very well.
What kinds kind of make that already.
If you bring a gun into a room,
even if you're comfortable with your
gun,
you're now like,
that guy has a weapon that could kill
me.
Yeah.
That is kind of weird,
right?
That he wants to do that all the time.
I have gone to and I appreciate you
wanting to shoot them and use them and
it's good to have something to protect
yourself because there's a lot of crazy
flux out there,
but carrying one everywhere.
It's just a little strange,
but I just say what the fuck.
It's like better to happen.
Yeah.
What's that expression?
A better than need it and to have it
than not needed and have it.
Something like that.
So like that,
you know,
better to not have it and not need it
than to need it and not have it.
That's the expression.
But uh,
yeah,
I mean he's fucking walk around drafts.
It's crazy.
It's a big ass fucking gun man.
He's got a glock on them at all times
with talents,
black talent,
bullets.
I have some of those too,
but black towns are like,
they don't make em anymore,
man.
They shred you up really black towels.
They don't just go through you as it
goes to spreads out.
So like talents,
like treads the inside of your body out?
Yeah.
From Mexico.
Mortar grenade or something like that.
Yeah man.
That he carries a gun or they just
stopped making.
Oh,
there's still legal if you have them,
if you have them,
your grandfather and I believe you can't
go out and get them in Anthony's while
those graphs and he finds out that Oh,
these fucks.
They're making things illegal.
He'll go into the store and buy like
fucking,
you know,
like wheel barrel falls.
He's crazy.
He's got like a room in his office or
his house that used to be a walk in
closet.
Whereas girl used to keep our shit and
now it's an armory.
It's an armory.
His room is all guns and ammunition and
rifles and ak 47 [inaudible] and fucking
pistols and everything and it's got
alarms,
like you have to press separate lumps.
You get into that room retinal scanning
the Goddamn punisher man.
Yeah.
He's going to fucking room in his house
with an alarm.
My dedicated to guns.
You open a door and so lik,
you know,
with like cool lighting and shells and
the compound to house houses.
The compound.
He's,
he's alone man.
But,
but being alone makes for fun radio.
He's fucking great on the radio.
He's hilarious.
He's just funny guy.
I liked him.
He's a yeah,
that's one of the coolest radio shows to
do.
I have been doing them since like 2000.
This is fucking great.
Show so much fun.
It's just the best hand.
You know.
Jim Norton is the funniest guy on radio
for sure.
That guy's Goddamn Polaris and the way I
just mean and nasty and quick like is
the shit that he says like anytime
there's some new thing in the news,
he's always get like a million.
Any refund.
He's just riff and just talking shit
about people.
If you haven't listened to them,
opie and anthony,
every radio show is hit and miss.
You know what I mean?
You can't even this fucking thing we're
doing,
obviously it's hit and miss.
You can't be awesome all the time
because it's just talking.
You know?
It's like when you talk for hours at a
time,
they're talking for like four hours at a
time.
There's going to be times you're doing
something sucks.
Did you follow the Tito's Shit at all?
Should we talk about that?
I got to talk about it because I think
it's very crazy,
especially if you're following it
through.
If you don't know,
and if you don't know,
tell us what was supposedly.
Tito was just arrested for allegedly
beating up Jenna Jamison and,
and then he came out and said,
I never hit her.
She has a big.
Oxy was Oxycontin,
oxycontin problems,
you know,
so it's fucked up on drugs and that's
it.
So what I thought,
I thought that was weird.
And then I was watching this clip on tmz
where it was Jenna saying he did not
beat me up.
We had a altercation,
you know,
but he did not beat me up.
People are thinking he's a wife beater.
Then like a half hour later,
an hour later,
Tito puts out a press conference saying,
Hey,
she is fucked up on Oxycontin.
And then immediately her story now is
wearing an arm brace.
He beat me up and threw me in a brace in
the.
Even in the beginning,
but,
but saying that he beat me up and threw
me in a hot tub and all this,
throwing a chicken arts hub.
If you're gonna,
if you're gonna throw a chicken or
something.
Well,
how to have a good banker.
Yeah.
But she's a porn star,
so you should be allowed to throw her in
a hot tub that comes along with a
dating,
a porn star fucker.
She retired and ms dot.
But uh,
um,
so I think she had a,
I think she had the uh,
the thing on her arm in the beginning
did shit.
Yeah.
But,
but it was kind of weird how the story
changed.
Right?
Well,
if she does have,
I have
that problem,
that's a terrible problem.
And I know a dude who had that problem
for a long time and he,
uh,
he got prescriptions from.
He lived in Texas and he moved to La and
you got prescriptions from both doctors.
You just couldn't help himself.
He's very self indulgent and he just got
whacked out on that Shit.
But apparently it's,
it's easy.
It's hard to get off and easy to get on.
Like you just start popping up,
move.
We've talked before on this show about a
documentary,
and we'll just briefly say it,
if you haven't seen it,
just google the oxycontin express and
it's all about how many people are
addicted to this stuff in Florida where
they're wacky laws.
Florida doesn't have a database of
doctors,
so the way my friend did it,
he got a prescription in Texas and he
got a prescription here in California
and then he started using ballroom at
the same time,
getting both of them were filled and
I've got all fucking loony.
But in Florida you can go to like 100
doctors.
You don't,
they don't have a database of doctors.
That's crazy.
It's scary shit because it's like,
for sure it's pharmaceutical companies.
They absolutely know what the fuck
they're doing with this stuff.
They have,
they've been accused and convicted or
it's been proven rather than they lied
about the,
uh,
the uh,
addiction qualities of Oxycontin that
they knew and suppressed information.
They knew that it was super,
super addictive.
I mean,
it's basically,
it's heroin in a form when they call it
hillbilly heroin,
that's really what it is.
Have you ever been to Florida folks you
might want to go just to see these
things called pain management centers.
I mean,
you know,
people go on vacation to see like the
Great Wall of China.
You might want to go on vacation to see
the pain management centers because it's
a fucking trip.
Yeah,
it's a heroin store.
Shit's fucked up.
But I mean,
do you think,
did you see her reaction and the video?
Did you see like the light,
she kind of looks,
here's,
here's the problem,
here's the problem with both of them,
right?
Is I liked both of them.
Can talk about them.
I'd like to know.
And,
and we,
you know,
I met Jenna back when she was with her
old husband and she's always been there.
She's still with him.
I heard,
I heard that it never got a divorce.
Well,
either way,
she's always been nice to me and I can't
talk shit about her.
But yeah,
it's um,
it's a whole thing is unfortunate.
I'll tell you,
I can't talk shit about,
about that,
that Faggot,
that was fucking Larry King's wife.
Now he's talking about it left and
right,
giving up all the Jews like it was bad
enough when all these women were coming
out about tiger woods and then Jesse
James chicks trying to make her money
like it's.
That's bad enough,
but this fucking guy that's been banging
Larry King's wife is the biggest bitch
out of all of them.
This fucking guy.
Okay.
Was the baseball coach for Larry King's
kids.
Okay.
He starts banging Larry King's wife and
he's banging Larry King's wife and Larry
King's bed while Larry King show is
being filmed because Larry King wants to
know where his wife is at all times,
so he makes sure watch the show at least
according to this guy so he can quiz her
like,
what did you think about like Joe did?
I asked Tom Cruise the right questions
and so she has to be ready to answer.
So he's banging her and as he's banging,
she's like watching the show,
making sure she pays attention to what
you know.
Fucking Paris Hilton necessarily large.
This fucking guy gave up everything,
man.
He's such a fucking snitch bitch.
This is a man.
Okay.
This is an,
uh,
a wounded female who dated a guy for a
long time.
He told her he loved her and she thought
that she was going to leave him there.
You know,
that's not what's happening here.
This is not a,
this is a man,
this is a fucking man.
A man who knew the deal right from the
get go.
And apparently she started buying him.
Shit.
She's,
he's a young guy.
Okay.
And she's hot for Larry King.
But this guy was like,
I'm in love with you.
I want to marry you.
This fucking guy was doing to her the
same thing,
rich women due to older men.
The same,
same thing
that fucking Larry King's wife was
doing,
a Larry King.
She was trying to get paid and he was
trying to get paid to and now he's like,
just spilling the beans for just all
these magazines and he's talking about
his acting career and Larry King helped
him.
So like kind of like Tito's telling the
mother of his two children that my wife
is a meth meth head,
you know,
and stuff like that.
Now that's kind of like breaking a weird
kind of trust like,
Hey,
the woman that mother your two cheered
on,
hey,
no,
she's on
Meth,
met Oxycontin,
oxycontin or whatever.
Well,
yes,
I could see your point,
but if you want to help somebody,
maybe that would be the thing to do to
make it public.
If someone's going wacky and accusing
you of doing shit that you didn't do,
it's telling everybody the whole entire
world and trying to ruin that person's
telling the whole entire world that
you're a wife beater.
If that's not true.
Yeah,
but if you have a drug problem and then
you love that person,
you know that then.
All right,
come on.
You know,
we both know people with drug.
I guess we can't really talk about it,
but we can't talk about people with drug
problems.
But isn't it interesting when someone
has a drug problem,
like how do you.
Then the interesting question is,
and if you don't know anybody that has a
drug problem out there,
well how lucky are you?
You're so lucky because it's one of the
satisfying things when you know someone
who's addicted to anything.
I've known people that were addicted to
gambling,
you know,
I know a lot of dudes that are addicted
to pussy and that's real.
You know,
there's,
there's people that are addicted to
things so they're not just trying to get
legs,
they're Horny,
they're just fucking,
they're obsessive,
you know,
and there's,
there's drugs that will fucking for sure
take over someone's body.
And what do you do about it?
We've had the problem,
we've had problems with friends of ours,
you know,
like what do you do about it?
My friend Johnny,
my best friend growing up,
my good do that.
I used to play pool with and hang out
with in New York.
He died from drugs.
He died.
He was 33 years old.
You know,
it could happen to anybody.
Anybody that fucks around with drugs
like Oxycontin's heroin and math and
stuff like that and coke.
You can get caught.
And what do you do?
What do you do if your friend gets
caught?
Your rat them out the fuck you do?
I don't think writing out,
at least not when you're in a situation
where you're not only writing out to the
whatever authority you're reading them
out to every single person in the world
and when you're in a field where you are
based off of your persona,
like you're an extrovert,
she makes money if who she is and she's
playing a role,
you think he fucked up,
but it destroyed her,
her,
you know,
tiger woods style with her in front of
twitter,
in front of everybody,
in front of everything.
Her career and the mother
have children.
But if he didn't do that,
let's just say,
let's just play devil's advocate.
If he didn't do that,
so let's say that she just got super
dramatic and fell down and decided to
call the cops.
Or maybe he grabbed her when she was
doing something wacky and she fell down
and hurt herself.
Let's just,
I don't know if that happened that I'm
certainly not defending anybody who
would do anything to a woman.
You know,
for no reason like that.
I mean anybody who loses their temper
and physically assaulted women.
I'm not defending that,
but I've been in situations where people
have accused me of things that I haven't
done and I know people that have been
accused of rape and I know you want to
tell yourself.
Yeah,
let's us to luke.
Brian has a great store.
I mean,
I'm kind of in the same situation.
Back in the day I,
I dated a girl that was completely
dominate this a long time ago,
10 years ago,
10 years ago.
I dated this girl that was a blackout,
crazy drunk like every time,
like,
like her parents were drunks since she
was 18.
She black out every day,
just drank like boone's like five
bottles of beer machine when you were
dating.
I would say she was like 22,
something like that.
Twenty one,
22,
something like that.
And uh,
I broke up with her because she uses
when up like on knew like five times a
day.
You're just like,
come on,
you still to dig dick out first.
And then.
But no,
uh,
so once it was,
like,
it was always one of the things,
like I break up with her and then I was
like,
Oh God,
she has big tits.
I got you.
No,
no.
Oh I forgot to fuck her again.
But,
but then one time it was like six months
go by.
She's trying and trying.
And finally I'm like,
all right,
look,
it's my sister's birthday this weekend
we're going to go out and have some
drinks if you want to come out,
but you have to be cool,
you know,
you can't,
whatever.
And so she came out fucking stupid.
Let's black out drunk fucking
embarrassing people,
you know,
I had to like get her in the car and so
they get back to my house and I'm like,
look,
I'm going to bed.
You can crash downstairs,
uh,
or,
or I can call you a cab or somebody
you're not allowed to drive.
She goes,
fucking driving.
Start breaking my shit.
Just destroying my house.
I'm talking about taking picture frames
and smashing it,
throwing things.
Like I had this huge dent in my
refrigerator where she threw something
at my refrigerator like,
and I'm like grabbing her,
like,
stop,
get the fuck out of my house.
You crazy woman.
And so I opened the door,
throw her outside.
I literally throw,
not like,
hey,
through our,
against a brick wall or anything.
I just like pushed her out the front
door,
slammed the door,
went upstairs,
went to bed and forgot all about
boulder.
You for.
That's a bold move.
I was like,
you saw what if you saw the,
the shit that she was doing in my.
I look out the door to see where she
went or not.
I did not care.
I was so upset because my.
I assume she would just start lighting
your house on fire.
Yeah,
I think to a point I probably look
outside,
see if like she walked down to her car
or something like that,
you know?
But what she did was go to my neighbors,
start banging on their door two in the
morning,
go
won't drive me home.
I slept through it.
You have to pay attention.
I slept through all this.
I guess the cops came online,
whatever,
and I was just like,
I remember.
Then I woke up in the morning,
casually went downstairs making coffee,
get a doorbell,
rang the door,
open the door and the go,
Hey Brian.
Damn,
we wish you went and answered.
They answered the door.
We need to arrest,
you know what?
And they're like,
well we got three charges for your
arrest.
I guess you wouldn't drive her home and
you wouldn't let her leave the house or
something like that because I wouldn't
let her drive was unlawful restraint
because I went in a.
When you give her keys,
I want to get her keys.
Gets you with blackout wasted.
Oh,
you should have called the cops.
I should've called the cops.
Yes,
absolutely.
But when you're young and.
Okay,
so,
so you were falsely to Sorta,
you were involved in a fucked up
situation.
It's basically,
it's a form of Karma.
I mean,
you,
you were involved with someone who
shouldn't have been involved with your
instincts,
are telling you to avoid them.
Absolutely.
The Ted sucked.
It sucked me right back in.
Like so anyways,
I got all these charges against me and
then I had to go to court spend,
I think it was $20,000
in court fees.
I had to go to all these different
things like I went to this,
had to go to a psychiatrist that they
maybe go to a,
and this is by the way all nicknamed the
Oj Simpson Law because after the Oj
Simpson trial,
they now have it like a woman.
If a woman wanted,
she could go through the phone book and
go arrest this person thing,
hit me and without asking anything or
anything,
they have to automatically arrest that
person,
put them in the system.
Oh people this shit.
Just kidding.
Ha Ha.
People are gonna Start Anyway.
So we're not responsible for anything.
So I just made that up,
made that up.
So I.
So I had to go to like the psychiatrist
and this one person,
he was like the deciding factor.
If this person says that they,
they believe I'm a crazy woman theater,
they don't have to go to trial.
And so we sit down and he goes,
excuse me,
what was the woman's name?
This is in the psychiatrist meeting.
I'm like,
I told her the name and they're like,
I'm sorry,
I'm going to have to stop this right
now.
I actually graduated with her.
I'm going to have to get my partner in
on this.
And so he could interview me.
And so I think it's like to the partner.
I'm like,
all right,
this is this guy's friend,
you know,
that went to school with this girl.
The Guy Sat and listened to me five
minutes because yes,
this does go to trial.
He is out of control.
And the whole time I'm like,
I went home,
she was going crazy.
I stepped up,
you know?
And so then I had to go to court,
this guy with like the girl or
something,
she went to high school,
they graduated together and singing
class.
So he hooked it up for his friend.
Well,
if you work with your partner and you're
like,
Hey,
I went to school with this girl,
fuck this guy up,
you know,
that's probably what happened.
So I had to go then go to back to court
to get the judge to approve like a
separate person.
I have to say,
look,
they went to high school together and
then they whispered.
So then I had to go to this other view.
You but you got that off.
Yeah.
I had to go to court though.
Okay,
next or what?
$10,000
or something like that.
Then finally what happens?
They dropped everything.
Uh,
this is like $20,000
worth of court fees going to court for
about two years.
They dropped everything for a.
what's that ticket where you can go
outside and just scream outside.
Uh,
uh,
it's like a minor ticket.
It's like a $50 tickets during the
piece.
Yeah.
Disturbing the peace.
But it's called something else.
It's called something else.
But I got that.
Let's see if any of these fucking.
What's it called?
Degenerates will know what that means.
Uh,
yeah.
But so and so it got all that drop to
that end.
The day Mr Jones,
9:30
says,
let's hear the real story.
You Chris Brown,
that bitch.
No,
I did know.
And what's funny is I have a,
a mugshot and in the mug shot,
I have a black guy and my nose is all
fucked up because she throws something
at me and hit me in the face and I
didn't even know about it.
So the moral of the story is,
if you know crazy
bitch,
get the fuck away from me.
Disorderly conduct disorder.
Well,
here's the,
here's the funniest thing is,
right,
right when I did that,
the next day after the trial where they
ended it and say,
alright,
disorderly conduct,
pay a ticket.
Uh,
she called me.
She goes,
I want you to know I'm so sorry about
this.
I actually didn't press charges or
anything.
The police press charges and they
wouldn't let me.
They wouldn't drop the charges.
The true,
true story.
She's like,
I had nothing to do with this.
I was pissed off that night.
That's all that happened.
I went to the cop.
It's so great.
Well,
that's the truth,
that that is a part of the law.
If you get accused of any sort of
domestic violence,
the police have to try the case.
The law has to try the case.
Yeah.
He can't.
Woman can't just drop it.
You can't drop domestic violent cases.
Yeah,
pretty nutty.
When you think about it,
that is the problem.
There's a lot of people that do a lot of
fucked up things to human beings for
sure.
And there should be last protect people,
but we don't know who's telling the
fucking truth.
And if you run in and bad circles and
you hang out with crazy bitches,
you could have a bad situation.
Right.
So that's what sucks about this whole
thing with them because they're
celebrities.
If all that shoot was on TMZ,
Tito and Jenna,
all my shit was on TMZ.
That would be great.
People would think that you're a woman
beater.
Yeah.
I've already just told you.
Use.
You're probably half the people there.
Think I'm lying
your.
I've never had a truck hit me.
I have a check swing on me once and I
ducked under and grabbed her and then I
calmed her down and then it got okay
after that.
But I've never,
you know,
never been in a situation where I hated
somebody worlds with them.
And I hated them,
but I know people have man,
I know people that are in relationships
with they fucking hate,
you know,
and it's almost always people that had
really fucked up parents and it's almost
always people that have parents that
fought and for some reason they think
that it's normal and especially when
you're young,
they kind of like it because they think
it makes them feel like an adult,
like they're doing like adult type shit.
Like their parents did their fucking
screaming and yelling at each other.
Like there's been many times,
especially when I was way,
way younger in my early days for how to
grip on the type of girls to date type
of girls.
If a girl is hot,
I would date her.
It didn't matter if she yelled at me,
demean.
You had to be really fucked up for me to
break up with,
you know,
especially in Boston because it's so
hard to get laid in Boston.
In Boston if you're single,
you fucked.
It's not like too much Stevia.
No,
I got all grinds.
I made cowboy coffee.
I make coffee with a French Press and at
the end of it there's,
you get grinds,
but I like it.
It's all,
it's gritty,
but what,
you know,
it's so hard to get laid,
in Boston and when you're a teenager
man,
especially,
I don't know about you,
but me,
when I was teaching,
I had to get laid to stay sane.
I had to get laid.
Otherwise sex was all I thought about
all fucking day.
You know,
nature has you primed for that nature,
has it set up so that if you're not
fucking okay and if you like 17,
18 years old and you're not fucking,
that's all you're going to be thinking
about.
You're not gonna be able to concentrate
on anything and you can get distracted
so easy.
You could get registered completely
removed from whatever path you're on.
If you're trying to,
you know,
become a fucking sprinter and the
Olympics are you trying to,
you know,
become an author.
Whatever you're doing,
if you're not getting laid,
a girl can come in and just just fuck up
the whole situation just by giving you
pussy that others.
But when you know you're 30 something
years old and you've been around the
block a few times,
then then it becomes a matter of,
okay,
who's the dummy here?
You know,
who's the one who's being silly?
why?
Why are you getting involved with these
crazy bitches?
This is one people need to do you.
First of all,
you need to get your own shit together.
That's like number one.
You need to be a happy person and you
know,
a lot of people don't like weed,
but here's one thing that we'd is really
good for.
If you smoke weed and get paranoid and
you start freaking out about things,
almost always those things that you
freaking out about are things that are
in your subconscious that you're not
comfortable about.
The things that had been bothering you
for a long time and you've been trying
to push them to the back of your head
and when you smoke pot,
whatever it is about pot,
especially when you get too hot,
what?
There's some,
there's a quality to marijuana that
makes you think about shit that you're
suppressing.
It makes you think about things from
your past that you don't like.
It makes you think about like things
that you did and it makes you think
about like your own issues,
you know,
and especially like marijuana and the
isolation tank together too.
You haven't even used my tag.
Have you done the isolation tank lately?
Have you been still doing?
Yeah,
I always do it.
Want to do it last night,
but I was too tired to get up early in
the morning and do radio for Montreal.
I'm in Montreal.
I'm May 8th.
I believe something like that at the
metropolis is that may.
The was in May,
May.
It might be seventh or eight.
Will show I find out.
I probably.
Sure.
By the way,
your twitter name is now.
Joe Rogan.
Yes.
So it's not Joe Rogan.net
anymore?
Yeah,
there was a,
I a fucking scored.
I got it back.
There is apparently a thing where you
can,
where you can,
um,
a report when people are hijacking your
image,
squatting your name.
You know what's funny is that when they
switch it over,
they just deleted Joe's Joe Rogan.net
name,
so they just let it free again,
like so he could get a.
and so I grabbed,
I noticed it right away and I grabbed
it,
but I didn't tell John looked at him
like that
motherfucker.
Somebody got my shit.
So I sent an email thing to them,
a message to them saying,
Hey,
I will give you a,
uh,
an autograph DVD and a cd if you give me
that.
I say the play that long.
But I was like,
I know how much you do practical jokes
that was even going to do it.
But it's funny because I don't know if
you looked at the photo,
if you go to [inaudible] dot net now in
the twitter,
if you look at the photo made his head
more tilted so it looked gay or.
So you've been working with this.
It'd be like what?
Uh,
I got it.
It's uh,
May 7th,
May 7th.
I'm in a metropolis in Montreal.
So anyway,
we were talking about having crazy
people in your life and sex and
isolation tanks,
isolation tanks and get well about
having good,
good relationships like the best way to,
to have a good relationship.
You've got to be comfortable with who
the fuck you are,
you know,
and if you've got a lot of issues,
a lot of stuff that's bothering you,
you know that's going to fuck up any
chance you have of communicating well
with other people because as soon as you
get comfortable with another person,
when you first meet someone,
you don't really let them in and you
sort of project who you want to be to
this person and then the person does the
same thing to you.
But after like a few months or few
weeks,
depending on,
you know,
how good your act is.
Most people,
you get to know who the fuck they really
are and what their real issues are.
You know,
after awhile there and they start
yelling at you and they get upset at you
for no reason or something and you start
tuning it all in and going,
oh,
okay,
you're a fucking bananas.
You know,
you've got to not be bananas in order to
get someone who's not banana.
It's like people will do is we'll always
say like,
man,
I'm fucking trying to find a good girl,
Dude.
I'm just tired.
All these bitches.
Meanwhile,
you're a mess bro.
You're a fucking man.
You're a loon.
You hate your Stepdad,
you know you want to fucking beat dude's
up at stoplights,
you know you're a mess.
And unless you stop being a mess,
you're never going to be involved in a
good relationship.
You never got to be able to recognize,
you know,
other people that are fucked up.
Like I've always said that one of the
things about trying to be like super
honest and I try to be literally as
honest as possible,
like it sounds really kind of gay,
but I really do try to very important
things.
One,
I try to be as nice to people as
possible and be as nice as possible.
I wish I could be nice to everybody,
but some people are fucking obsessive
and they don't leave you alone or the
bananas or they're,
they're retarded or their abusive or you
try to take advantage of you if you're
nice and there's some people that you
can't be nice to.
Unfortunately there's some people that
you know what they need fucking years of
therapy and when you run into them,
you,
you don't have the time for that.
So you've got to go through,
leave me the fuck alone,
stop,
you know.
And,
and it's unfortunate you have to do
that,
but sometimes you have to do that.
So I try to be as nice as is humanly
possible to get through my life.
And number two,
I try to be as honest as humanly
possible.
I try to always be honest.
I try to,
uh,
make sure that everything I'm doing,
I'm doing from a place where I can be
honest about it.
And if you can't be honest about it,
for the most part,
it's one thing,
just one thing is being honest.
Another thing is like tmz type shit,
like revealing all sorts of information
about your personal life because people
are creepy and they want to look,
look into it.
That's not honestly,
that's like a revealing thing and I'm
not really into that.
I'm not really into like becoming,
going on a reality show and having
everybody seemed my bathroom,
like what the fuck is that?
That's not honesty,
that's just,
that's just weird voyeuristic shit that
people get,
you know,
obsessed with.
But,
but you know,
what I am into is telling you where I'm
really coming from and what's going on
in my own mind and,
and,
and be comfortable with that to the
point where I am so honest all the time
that I can recognize deception like
right away,
you know,
and I,
I find that to be really true.
Like if you're a really honest person,
when people are full of Shit,
you just fucking spot it.
Like right away.
It's really difficult to lie to an
honest person really hard.
Remember that we did we videos
for awhile after every video,
but I was going and it really,
it's fucking awesome philosophy.
Me and Eddie Bravo would have a
competition.
Who did it?
Best member tried to know I can do
better.
What was that all about?
At least crazy.
Very competitive.
Very competitive,
very competitive.
I guess you have to be when you do that.
Yeah.
Well,
you know,
he grew up in a situation where he had a
Douche bag for a stepfather and his
whole life has been trying to fight
against people that are fucking with
him.
You know what I mean?
So like he'd become,
he became hyper competitive because of
that.
Anyway,
so that's my advice.
And to uh,
that,
that bitch ass dude that's banging Larry
King's wife and running your mouth,
you faggot.
Turn in your man card,
you little bitch of the man.
That's how you're getting by in this
life.
You're getting your money from ratting
out some woman that you fucked on her
husband's bed.
You silly man.
You silly silly man.
And apparently Larry King,
it helped.
This guy had gotten this guy like acting
gigs,
like,
keep your mouth shut,
son.
You know why?
Trying to hurt Larry King.
What are you getting like 10 grand out
of this.
You little faggot.
How much have you gotten?
How much are they going to pay that guy?
He's probably doing it for the fame to
be Spencer Pratt style.
You know there's a sitcoms or it takes
all these people called man carbon.
They try to earn their man card back,
you know,
or as expensive practice guy and they
all live in a house together.
The sprints or pat is a fucking
Brazilian Jiu Jitsu black belt.
There's no man.
Exactly.
I've seen him on the show in black belt
and it's hilarious.
I hate that shit.
I hate that.
Look,
we're talking about him.
That's all he wants.
And He.
Meanwhile I was making a living and
those who have to work at 7:11.
If you watch the show.
Sixteen and pregnant.
No,
I haven't dude.
Apparently Eddie Bravo says,
I must wash this.
I'm to write this down.
Bad Girls Club.
Apparently bad girls club is ridiculous.
Yeah,
I mean it's just like the motto like 16
and pregnant even more or something.
It was that big keeps coming on.
Uh,
whatever.
Um,
so what does the show?
16 and pregnant 16.
The pregnancy
one episode and it's all white trash
kids and they're yelling at their
parents.
Their parents are yelling at them.
I was like,
I don't want it.
It's awful.
It's the worst show ever.
That's like too much info.
That's a perfect example.
We were an Ikea though the other day and
they had like a kid's room,
like it was like a bunk bed and he was
really happy,
but then there was like a place for a
baby and I'm like,
wait,
is this just like,
you know,
a poor person with only one bedroom and
had this shared like sister and baby,
or is this like,
now this girl has a baby and she's like
15.
It was the big bulk of it.
It's just got a crib thing.
That's what I'm saying.
I'm like,
what is Ikea doing doing?
I think they're just trying to maximize
bedroom,
trying to market to them.
This is like,
oh yeah,
this is like for too many people,
Mexicans living in an apartment or
something like that,
you know?
Yeah.
Well,
you know what man,
with this economy being in the shitter
the way it is,
people are stack and more people into
houses together.
I know a person who lives down the
street from me is losing their house,
losing people,
losing their houses,
left and Ryan.
People who,
uh,
have a really high falutin lifestyle and
spend tons of money and you know,
get used to it and get used to trying to
bling bling and then the shit hits the
fan.
I was thinking about moving the other
day.
Just get sick of a place and you just
want to upgrade.
You always feel like you have to upgrade
your shit.
Oh,
it's out.
All my carpet have wood floors
underneath it now.
It looks great.
Now I'm like,
I'm fine.
Yeah,
you just needed a change.
I think,
you know,
when I moved to Colorado that was a good
thing for me to adjust to change
environments.
I think changing is good for your brain.
I think it like refine your brand,
but your brand has to learn this whole
new environment.
I had a whole new friends,
the people I run into,
a Jujitsu,
whole new people.
I was meeting a whole new comedy clubs
where I was working on my stuff.
It was a very interesting to me and made
me fire my brain up.
I think that's a good thing to do if a
shock it once.
The problem is.
The other thing is you build a base
though.
Like I have a base in la.
I have all my friends live in La,
my wife's friends live in La.
You know,
I have my whole system set up where I
buy my dog food.
I have,
you know,
the guy that works on my car.
You know what I mean?
I have all this shit in la where I train
all the dudes that have been training
with for years.
It's like you get like,
you get real comfortable with that
system and it's very convenient and when
you move you gotta like re reconfigure
your whole situation.
The problem is women,
you know,
you're bringing women and then they have
friends like chocolate Dale said.
He goes,
I can go to a sports bar.
I'll never fucking hour.
I've got nine new friends,
Chili because he's a fucking coolest guy
ever.
He's super friendly.
He's like,
yeah,
come on by.
A very cliquey and beers and some guy.
What do you do?
I'm fucking plumber.
Hey,
you know,
I'm,
I'm this,
I'm that and guys can meet guys like
that.
You know,
like I tell the story about the one time
that I hosted a Jack and Jill Strip club
and,
and Rhode Island.
I've told you the story before,
right?
Yes.
It was a male and a woman stripper,
and it was horrific.
There were,
there were both disgusting.
There was like maybe,
maybe six to 10 people in the audience
at most during the whole night's
performance and I had to perform a bunch
of times.
I would go up and do stand up and then
the male stripper would go on.
I'll go up and do standup in.
A female strip would go on and they
would do shifts and they would take some
time off and then I'll go on stage again
and then they would start to show all
over again and the woman would go up and
the guy will go do everyone in the
audience was like these weird people
from this area,
woonsocket,
Rhode Island,
but there was this one dude who was
there who was a construction worker from
New Jersey and he just happened to be in
town because it was a marriage or
something like that or wedding that he
had to go to for when someone's family
and he was bored.
So we've got out of the house to go have
a appear.
There's a bar down the street,
so he goes to this Jack and Jill Strip
club and he was a totally normal dude
and me and him were talking having beers
like what?
He goes,
what the fuck are we witnessing?
Or You at least seen?
And this was like one normal dude in
May.
After first two beers.
It's like I had known this dude for
fucking 10 years,
were just joining one place to pull.
Yeah,
let's fucking play some pool.
So there's a little corn operated pool
table.
Were playing pool,
making fun of the whole situation.
Like I found a friend like for girls.
That's hard to do,
man.
Bitches don't trust each other.
Man.
I learned that from having dogs.
You know,
having pitbulls I had two female pit
bulls and one of them killed the other
one.
They would.
They would fight and I would separate
them and I thought they worked their
shit out because the way dogs work,
the shit out.
His one dog will dominate the other dog
and then you figure out who the Alpha
is.
They have to do that.
They have to figure out who gets to
drink first.
Who gets to eat first?
That's just the wild animal world and
you have to be number one.
That's why you can never let your dog
get away with Shit.
You can never let her get a dog growl at
you.
You can never let your dog do things
they're not supposed to do because you
have to be the Alpha,
especially if you have big dogs.
Well,
this is what doesn't work with females.
Females never accept dominance.
They would always come back and try to
battle it out again and that's what they
did until one of them killed the other
one.
And I think that's how women are with
women.
Men.
I think women can be friends with women
and they have really close friends and
you know,
they go all sex in the city and pal
around together and shit like that.
But it's real difficult for them to make
that kind of a bond to trust another
woman that trust them.
This,
it's,
I think it's easier for dudes,
you know?
Yeah,
I agree.
I,
it seems like that's like the cat fight.
Yeah.
Especially if there's dudes that are
like doing stuff that you like to do,
like comics,
like if I made comics,
I can go to a new town and uh,
you know,
do stand up or there's some local
complex.
I'm fucking meet local comics all the
time.
Next thing you know,
we're out having a beer together.
You know,
we're hanging around.
We have something in common or Jujitsu
guys like there's like fucking 10 dudes
in Jujitsu that are trained with all the
time.
There could totally be good friends of
mine.
They're just dudes that,
especially Jujitsu guys,
because they have good control over the
ego.
You know,
Jujitsu guys into to get good at
Jujitsu,
you have to battle it out all the time
and you have to be real objective.
You can't be delusional at Jujitsu.
You have to really know what your
strengths are,
what your weaknesses are,
and you've got to be able to deal with
tapping out.
You've got to be able to deal with dudes
dominating you because in the beginning
for sure you're going to get dominated.
Everybody gets dominated the beginning.
Nobody,
unless you're just so big that nobody
can touch you.
So I'm 300 pounds,
brock lesnar character,
you know you're going to get tapped out
at the beginning,
so you have to have the kind of ego to
deal with that.
But for,
for women,
I don't know,
I think it's much more difficult.
It was really difficult for my wife,
especially when you have a little baby
and what are you going to meet some
other lady as a baby and how much you
going to have in common with this broad.
Once she's Christian,
she goes all loony toon Janya and wants
to fucking talk about Noah's Ark and
shit.
You know?
Right.
Yeah.
I got some guy fucking cornered me at
the supermarket the other day.
Some do that.
I guess I had met them before,
but I forgot.
You know,
there's some law that you can only or
there's some studies that say that you
can only keep like 150 people that you
know in your head.
And we've seen that.
No,
I haven't seen that.
But I totally believe it because I think
mine's like 10 says,
well let's meet or I just don't care.
There's so many things when,
when like,
you know,
like I'll meet somebody or somebody
tells me something if I don't care about
it.
I just like,
I put that on the coffee table and
that's about to be thrown out,
you know,
putting my deep storage.
I put in my random memory,
you know?
Yeah.
Here it is.
This,
there's a,
I don't know,
working memory.
There's,
there's a,
I'm trying to find it on Google.
I don't want to waste too much time
looking for this,
but 100,
it's apparently you can only remember.
You can only have real relationships
where you know,
150 people were,
you know,
their name and you know,
you'll have a certain amount of space in
your hard drive when it comes to human
beings.
And that to me reinforces my feelings
that human beings are supposed to live
in small tribes.
We're not supposed to live and have a
gigantic fucking tribes of hundreds of
millions of people.
Well,
it's also if you,
if you ever get assignment says you
know,
like you know where you follow the
colors,
but it also is a.
I don't know if it's a.
we're supposed to live in small tribes
as in if I can do.
Simon says,
but right up to the 14th one,
my brain falls off and it's always like
the 14th one.
It's almost like,
that's just my Max,
you know,
like that's my heart is full.
I can't do anything past this 14.
I might be able to train myself to,
to like micromanage how many things I
can remember.
But uh,
it's weird,
like if I pick up a Simon says right
now,
once I hit the 14th one,
I can't do it.
Like,
just turns off.
Almost everybody has a different
threshold for.
Oh,
I'm saying everyone does the same for,
uh,
for names.
It's pretty.
Wouldn't that fall into the same thing
though?
Just maybe memory,
memory.
Well,
I think,
um,
well think about how many words you
know,
you know,
we know thousands of words and words
that we don't even use.
You know,
you can.
I mean,
you know,
some of these serendipitous.
Yeah.
That takes up more of our,
most of our hard drives.
Scenario art take scenario.
People
that just spout out you only use five
percent of your brain.
So some random night,
the only use 10 percent of Israeli
really to you.
Do you even know what the fuck you're
talking about?
Are you just like reciting some shit
that someone told you in high school?
Like this is the year of Glute,
right?
Right.
And that's supposed to be just saying
we'll use two percent of our Ra,
you know,
you don't fucking know.
But uh,
anyway,
this dude that I met at the grocery
store,
I did not remember him.
He said he is from Jujitsu.
So I said,
hey,
what's up man?
How you doing?
So I think it's just going to be one of
those casual.
What's up man,
how you doing things?
And,
and he's like a little taken aback that
I don't remember him.
And then he'll like laugh.
So I was a girl,
awkward socially.
So take care of my,
some shopping.
I'm doing all my shit and then I'm
leaving and when I'm going out to my
car,
he hits me with Joe,
you go to church.
I'm like,
Oh you motherfucker and I've got a car
and you know,
unload my food.
I don't want to get the fuck home and
this dude is like cornered me in the
parking lot,
and so I,
uh,
I say,
no,
I don't.
He said,
are you interested?
And I say,
no,
I'm not.
And he goes,
have you talked to blank?
And I don't want to say who blank is,
but he is a friend of mine.
And uh,
he was saying that this,
this guy.
Has He talked to you about the Lord,
this guy is fucking this guy who we're
talking about this friend of mine,
his fucking bananas.
All right.
Uh,
you know,
nothing wrong with cheating on your
wife,
but this guy like literally was planning
on killing her.
I mean,
he's fucking brilliant.
Yeah,
it's crazy.
He didn't do anything,
let me go away with her and the whole
day.
But this guy who was talking about was
like,
I don't want to say anything other than.
He's probably one of the worst examples
you could ever possibly use.
He just doesn't know the best example
that I've used for religion.
Well,
yeah,
I mean this guy,
he just doesn't know that this guy's
bananas because a lot of people don't
know this guy's bananas,
you know,
but you know,
so I'm like,
come on man,
I don't have time to break all this shit
down for you.
You know,
if it's helping you,
that's all well and good,
but just running up to people and
thinking you're going to save him in the
parking lot because you couldn't get
your shit together and you don't have to
save me.
All right,
I'm pretty fucking happy.
And if you really truly believe that the
only way I'm going to get to go have him
go to heaven as Kirk Cameron style where
you have to fuck in,
you have to accept the Lord.
You ever seen Kirk Cameron go up to like
gang bangers?
You gotta look Google that Shit on
Youtube.
Watch Kirk Cameron's videos where he
goes up to people and uses his fucking
13 year old logic uses like fucking
seventh grade logic on people.
When you google it,
typing,
Kirk Cameron owned,
there's a lot of those because that's
even better.
Then he starts talking to people who
actually read fucked.
He's so.
He's so bananas.
I think Kirk Cameron is almost
definitely gay.
The more I watched them in these videos,
the more I'm like this.
Nothing masculine about this man.
He's very submissive and is desired for
chastity and this desire for,
you know,
for him.
I met him.
I think I would go over the edge and
just tried to kiss him.
No,
no.
Yeah,
yeah.
I pull out my dick starting to look at
it,
you know,
just like go hit the.
I would go to jail for,
you know,
I'm like fuck them.
Just hold them down.
Fucking pulled them down,
jerk off on his chest or something like
that.
See what he does.
I was this time,
no stop.
I,
I used to like him back in the day with
this show and it growing.
But I also thought that tracy golden was
hot.
So I guess I'm just stupid.
Well,
his wife was Super Hot,
right?
Or she is still stills.
Wow.
Oh No.
He's real life.
Real life is super hot.
There's something the matter with that
dude is chasing down the Lord,
you know,
I can understand you wanting to study
what Christianity was.
What to me in my opinion is,
is an ancient philosophy.
You know,
it might be incredibly flawed,
but there's some very good things to it.
There's some very good ideas that love
one another as you would love yourself,
you know,
be,
treat each other as brothers and sisters
and all that stuff is very good,
but it's got a lot of wacky nonsense in
it that makes no fucking sense.
And if you really want to study it,
if that's your thing,
look,
it's just,
there's nothing wrong with people
studying like Greek mythology,
you know,
like getting into like Zeus and Mithra
and all that crap.
That's kind of cool.
It's interesting,
but when you really get into like
Christianity and start thinking that
this is the real stuff,
like this is the what the fuck are you
talking about?
And then you're got to grab other people
and you need to listen to me.
You need to listen to me.
It's all parents though,
you know?
I would never have thought that if my
parents were when I was a kid though.
Some people know though,
again,
some people are born again so that it's
not their kid or it's not their parents.
Yeah.
But those are really hard to be born.
I never learned it growing up and then
going straight into it.
I think it is of your life falls apart.
I think if your life falls apart and all
these people that are into Jesus seem
happy and they seem like they have a
path because that's really what it's all
about,
man.
You know,
you have to have a path and today
people,
if you,
if you think about the way we used to
live,
the way our bodies are programmed to
I mean we're supposed to be living in
fucking huts and caves and shared.
I mean the,
the hardware that we have right now is
basically the same hardware,
the same adrenal system,
the same neuro synapses that connect the
same way as people that lived 100,000
years ago.
If you took a person from 100,000
years ago and sat them in the corner
right there,
he would be unrecognizable.
I mean it would be totally normal.
You wouldn't say like,
what the fuck?
That's a caveman now.
He would look just like us,
but yet 100,000
years ago they had very different needs.
Man.
There was a.
You couldn't.
You had shit.
You had to do.
You had tasks.
Okay.
You had to go out.
You gotta find that fucking food every
day you had a hunt.
That shit down.
That's what it's like a visceral thrill
involved in hunting.
Like hunters will tell you,
if you ever watch like Ted Nugent,
talk about it.
A key makes it very appealing and Brock
Lesnar,
he's got videos with him hunting like
it's a rush he gives.
These guys are rushed to kill the animal
and get their meat and it's not like a a
cruelty rush and they're there.
They want to kill and fucking hurt and
destroy.
No,
it's.
It's a man is supposed to be out there
shooting animals and killing them.
You ever plant food and then eat that
food?
There's something very exciting about
that.
Very,
very rewarding and fulfilling and to a
lot of people.
Their life is filled with nothingness.
There's no task everyday.
It's a show up at work.
Do what you're told.
Do your paperwork,
stare at the clock,
beg for 5:00,
get the fuck Outta here.
Listen to your wife,
bitch.
Have a beer.
Watch law.
Say what the fuck is going on?
Fall Asleep.
Do it all over again.
There's no tax,
there's no real,
there's no real.
So there has to be some meaning to it
all.
So someone comes up to you and says,
Hey man,
I know you feel that way.
I used to feel that too until I met the
Lord.
That emptiness in your life is that you
don't have the Lord.
When really that emptiness in your life
is just you're fucking hardware and it's
just your hardware.
You know?
Do you think about the way we're wired?
We are not wired to deal with this world
that we live in right now.
We are wired to deal with thousands of
years ago,
18,
30 something was when they figured out
the camera.
That means everything before,
less than 200 years ago.
If you want to know what someone looked
like,
someone had a draw
that person for you.
Do you think it how crazy that is?
They had a draw your how many fucking
people can draw.
I mean,
how many?
How many people do we really know from
before?
1,800.
What they really looked like.
It's fucking guesswork.
Unless you were Napoleon Napoleon.
We have hundreds of drawings.
That guy,
we got a pretty good idea what he looked
like.
Abraham Lincoln.
Pretty good idea what he looked like.
You know,
but you don't go way,
way,
way back 500 years ago with the fuck
black people didn't exist back then.
You know,
white people have only existed for a
short amount of time.
You know,
there was a recent study where they
figured out how long white people
around,
I believe it was like $10,000
years or something silly.
Let me see.
I'm going to google that because that's
an important thing.
How long have Caucasians
see?
I think black people came before white
people and I'm sure I'm sure a lot of
people don't believe that you think
black people came from art kind of way,
like using pallets and colors.
It has to go that way,
you know,
so yeah,
you make,
you have,
you can't go that way.
You know,
black turns into white but white,
it's not going to turn in black in color
wise if you're mixing colors.
When did people evolve to be white?
What we do I work for,
uh,
when did people change become white?
Let's see,
why do people come up?
Why did people become what?
Alright,
that's why vitamin D probably you're
saying between 100,000,
50,000
years ago,
lower levels of vitamin vitamin D at
higher latitudes where the sun is less
intense,
caused the lightening effect where
modern humans became who were,
uh,
who began darker skin first migrated
north.
So human beings have been black until
about 50,000
years ago when we started moving around.
And then the climate changed.
That's pretty fucking chain,
can you pretty crazy shit.
So there's banana had tried to convert
me into Jesus,
at least.
At least with Jesus,
you're allowed to fucking draw a picture
of him.
How nutty is the fucking South Park?
Dang.
Did you watch the episode?
Yeah,
both of them.
No,
I couldn't watch it.
It was driving me crazy.
I was so mad at comedy central for
beeping out every.
No.
Go see the first one,
they didn't do anything on the first
one.
The second one because the first one.
It's so annoying though when you see
every time they say Mohammed it beeps.
And then how about when he's in a
fucking the bear suit and it comes out
with Santa Claus and the bear suit,
like did the first episode he was in a u
haul and it's was like,
like legally that's what they thought
that they wouldn't get in trouble.
Right.
So they just drove,
they drove Mohammed around in a u haul.
He just sit there like,
is this okay?
Mohamad bub?
No.
Pendula said something on his twitter
today,
and I'm paraphrasing,
but basically said the measure of a
religion is a how much you,
you're afraid.
You know,
what way you can say about a religion is
how much you are afraid to talk about
them or when you're afraid to talk about
them,
like how crazy they are.
Basically what he's saying.
And Penn is a very staunch atheist and
I've been friends with that guy for a
long time and he doesn't,
he won't even consider the possibility
that there's some sort of an intelligent
life to it all.
He's very scientific,
but,
you know,
unfortunately he's never done any
psychedelic drugs.
And if,
if he had,
he's never done anything.
He's never had a drop of alcohol.
He's never even had a single drug except
for when he's had to have surgery when
they had a drug.
Um,
he like takes it very seriously to be
sober all the time.
We saw well and good,
but I think,
you know,
you can't really understand what's
happening in the psychedelic experience
unless you've had one,
you know,
point is this fucking Mohamad thing,
man.
It's that.
I like how they compared it.
I don't know if they did in the second
episode and the first thing they
compared it to a the Tom cruise suing
anyone that says he's gay.
It's kind of like the Muhammad thing.
You know what?
You're not allowed to talk about him
being gay.
Listen,
I'm going to tell you right now.
Yeah.
You talked about being gay,
being gay all day long at Cox.
If you go online,
there's pictures of me with dicks all
over the place.
That's the golden rule.
The Internet.
Right,
so that a picture of you on the Internet
somewhere.
Someone is photoshop
when you're making love South Park
though.
I was watching this show.
I was watching orgasmic last night.
I don't know if you've ever seen that
one.
It's a movie at Trey Parker wrote and
directed and stuff and where he's a
mormon and he gets into porn,
but that alone is a great movie.
How they're always battling religion and
trey is at least something that it's
just a fucking love.
They're the best.
They're the most prolific there.
Shows the best.
It's the mall to speak to Mike Sense of
humor the most.
It's silly,
but it's spot on and brilliant.
Just the fucking Barbara streisand
dinosaur monster,
you know,
machine thing that they had.
Do you ever see a day?
I don't know.
I think I've told you this before.
There used to be a website called shock
wave.com.
Used to be shocked,
raved.com,
which was a bunch of flash movies and
stuff and they originally paid trey
Parker and Matt Stone.
Some crazy amount of money,
but I saw it.
What was.
It was a show called princess and what
it was is they were paid tons and tons
of money to do and they were like
uncensored.
They were like,
you could do whatever you want,
uncensored.
This is going to be big on the Internet
and we're going to give you like $30,000
an episode or something like that.
And so they hired tray and math to do
the series.
If I have 24 episodes,
they got to the second one turned it in.
We're like,
wow,
this is great.
And they're like,
Whoa,
whoa.
We sit on sensor.
But this is,
this is out of control too far.
If you go online and have it on my
website,
[inaudible] dot com.
Uh,
just google,
uh,
princess,
Trey Parker or princess red band,
you will find it.
And what it is,
is it just,
it's all about this fluffy little dog.
It like a Shitzu and it just sits there
and it starts off.
It's like all about this dog and then
it's just like crazy stuff's going on in
the background that just cute dogs
watching,
like watching two people.
Fuck,
it's watching somebody get murdered.
It's like,
it's like it's a about this cute little
cute little dog watching all this
horrific shit.
And it only got the two episodes and
based,
even though they said they were led to
the meeting they wanted,
they're like,
this too fucked up.
We quit.
No,
you guys keep the money.
You can't.
You can't do this anymore.
It's the best,
best videos I've ever seen in my life.
And I wish Trey Parker and Matt Stone
would finish that because it was one of
the funniest things.
Right?
Ever seen.
Those guys are so crazy.
They're the craziest,
they just take things the deepest,
you know,
like I remember when we saw team
America,
I remember being in a theater,
gone,
I can't believe where they're going with
this.
I can't,
you know,
when,
when the dude starts throwing up and
keeps throwing up,
that's where it's like,
you know,
Oh fucking football field full of puke
and he's laying in the center of it.
I mean they took it to the utmost.
They took it to its total shock humor,
but brilliant shock humor,
you know,
like it's not as funny the second time
around,
like the throw up seen the thrust and
the first time around when you don't
know it's coming.
It's just God damn.
It's funny.
It's like one of the best there.
If they have a movie coming out,
I'm always more excited than anything
else except them in Bora Bora or dam and
Ology like close.
So
I don't know if it's ever going to work
on me anymore.
I wonder what he's doing now.
I wonder if there's like a third movie
because I know that
off.
Maybe if it takes time off,
if he goes to places where people aren't
aware of it,
like if he goes to like the south,
like that's what we try to do before I
try to go to the south.
Well it's almost like the,
like Mike Myers,
it's falling.
It fell in the same category.
I watched,
you know,
like the last gold finger movie or
whatever he did.
He's just playing the same character
over and over again.
And the other day I watched one of my
old favorite movies was.
So I married an ax murderer and I used
to love that movie.
I've watched you the other day.
I wanted to fucking puke and beat people
up because it was so awful.
Like Mike Myers to me as died almost.
They do
his last movie looked like,
like you know those movies where they
have a guy who used to be funny and then
all the sudden,
like in the movie he takes a terrible
turn and now he's not funny anymore.
It's putting out crap.
And the were shaking their heads and
ease and the downward spiral of life.
That last movie where he played the
Indian guy the love.
Yeah.
Grew gold member.
Whatever the fuck.
I love girl.
Yeah.
Watch the ads for that.
You're like,
okay,
what is funny about this?
This is like antifungal.
It's like this is like a guy who forgot
what funny is.
It's just like,
but what's crazy is if you go back as
far as swipe merit and ax murder,
which was way before Austin powers or
any of that stuff,
it destroyed that movie because that was
the same character as all his other
movies.
It was so awful.
It's,
it's man.
Can you imagine like Timpson Wayne's
world worries coming out.
Shrek.
Shrek guy.
Wayne's world was fucking genius.
Him and Dana Carvey were awesome.
I mean when,
when those movies were on the wrong
though.
I mean that.
Those were great,
great fun,
fun movies,
but the new stuff he does like,
I don't even like the Austin powers
movies.
I never got it.
I.
It's not my shit.
Did you hear about the iphone leak?
If you don't know about this iphone,
the iphone four,
the came out and it's like some crazy
ass new iphone with a front facing
camera and well apparently some dude and
this is the store and a lot of people
think that this is all bullshit and hype
and it's just,
you know,
making the uh,
the iphone story bigger.
I personally don't because I don't think
apple would ever release a thing on
purpose,
you know,
and have people find it.
Lot of the companies did this though.
Not a lot of companies a virus.
The viral marketing nowadays that's
being used on the Internet is so
amazingly deep in like you would not
think of the shift that's happening,
right?
Chocolate down the reebok commercial.
Exactly where he's native and all that
stuff.
I mean,
it's ridiculous.
I could almost see this to build hype
with cell phones because if you look at,
there's a website called boy genius
report dot Com and you could totally
tell this guy's in bed or he was in bed
with blackberry at one point.
Like there was times where it was like,
all right,
you got this phone like a year ahead of
anybody else and you already have and
already a video of using it and stuff
like that.
That seems a little fishy that your
friends let you borrow it.
And when it comes out like a year later,
you know,
there's.
And I almost think it's just shifting
the leaked out,
kind of like on the Internet,
you're going to see what people's
reactions are trying to tweak things.
You know,
it's almost like we're the,
you know,
some of them are living,
I'm sure.
So don't believe know about this apple
thing though,
that it seems to me like the dude got
fired.
Didn't get fired.
Yeah.
He got fired.
Police are involved now.
You hear about the Gizmodo God,
they broke down his house.
He broke down his fucking front door,
took all his computers because the
reporter that that recorded,
well,
he got a copy of it.
They paid $5,000
dollars for the,
for the actual phone.
So they paid money for the phone and
apparently apple saying that that's
their stolen property and you're not
supposed to be having that reporting on
it.
So they went to the guy's house who
wrote this whole report,
broke down his house,
took all of his fucking computers to two
servers servers in his house.
That's a super geek.
Yeah.
Well he is a super geek.
I mean the main editor of one of the
biggest tech websites,
not only is he get free shit,
but I'm more interested in is imagine
somebody coming to your house,
taking your computer and took
everything.
That's why it freaks me out or to
because a computer and nothing to do
with the self.
I think nowadays that's one of the most
scariest things ever.
Ever.
Somebody can now come in and take your
diary and put it into their database,
your whole diary.
Never.
Where do you ever think like,
okay,
the cops just came and took my diary.
Now they know everything about me.
Every feeling,
every thing I'm thinking now.
That's what our computers,
our diaries now.
Yeah.
You get all your emails from like a
fucking million years.
So this Guy Bob and iphone and now his
diary is owned by the every photo you've
ever
taken,
all as computers.
Like why do they think that they can
just take your computers?
Is it to get a um,
a,
like a,
a track tracking of the emails to see
like,
you know,
I think it's an open door that if they
can,
they can
pretty much just like searching your
car.
The cops want to search a car
regardless.
Even if they're just trying to pull you
over for a seatbelt,
they want to search a car and see what
else I can find.
But I mean the,
the,
a lot of people are saying that this
warrant was unlawful and that they
shouldn't have.
It's totally online.
La.
Are you sure?
Are you a lawyer?
It's a cell phone.
Somebody bought A cell phone from
another step.
Right.
But they bought a stolen cell phone,
a cell phone that's basically stolen
property.
I mean the guy lost his cell phone,
but it's the property of apple and it's
very sensitive property because it's a
prototype.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I guess you're right.
But I think basically they fucked up in,
in stealing the phone or in buying the
phone.
What they should have done is given the
fucking phone back to apple.
I mean the company doesn't want you
reviewing their shit before it's out
yet.
I mean,
I don't think that's a,
a huge request.
If you know that it's there,
they're shit.
You're doing something illegal.
I think they more fucked up.
Gizmodo,
more fucked up.
Just letting everyone know who the guy
who lost his putting his face on the
websites and everything.
That's fucked up man.
You know that's
do though was going to get busted.
Anyone that was fucking phone anymore.
Yeah.
Really what they should've done it.
They knew all this shit is given back as
god damn phone
I think.
Or the way they should have done is it's
like,
oh shit.
It's just a cell phone.
I would chill the fuck out.
It's got a front facing camera now.
You know how domino's is all going to
sound october.
We're like,
everyone's got it now.
Crush att and t service.
If you think atd service sucks,
a big bag index.
Now wait till that front facing camera
comes out and everyone everywhere is
going to be fucking use streaming while
they're driving the car.
Talking,
sitting in the fucking black guy piece.
I got a feeling
it's good.
It's going to be a million fucking
people doing that all over the.
Of turning it on like I've always said
that that's going to be the end of the
world is when everyone has their own
channel and everyone basically is like a
walking television channel and instead
of like,
hey,
what's your fucking facebook page?
CAn I facebook you?
What's your twitter?
It's going to be what channel is your
life?
You're going to have a fucking helmet on
and it's going to be a front facing
camera that shows you as you're walking
through the world and you know you're
going to have a video camera
broadcasting everything.
Yeah.
That's kind of like what you stream does
and whitening like justin tv does.
Justin tv originally was called
lifecasting,
which was 24 hours a day falling around.
Justin who?
I had a camera filming his whole entire
life.
Do you remember when we were in san
francisco and justin tv was going to
give us a laptop and a backpack.
I was really weird connection.
That was really weird.
So strange with the dude who came to the
show with it.
No,
we're going to hook you all up and then
we'd go to lunch and he goes,
this is the laptop,
this is the camera.
All right.
And then like put it back in is like,
what were we supposed to there?
Was there a.
Was going to get it all to us
and we started making fun of it.
Oh that'S right.
We weren't.
We were like,
what if it cuts out?
This is silly,
this current backpack around like what
am I going to do?
And we decided that it would be
ridiculous and they were like,
didn't want to be like broadcast shows.
I have enough problems with people.
You tubing my shit before it's done at
shows.
Like when you come up with new bits,
you know,
like sometimes when a bit like is out
and it's not a cd,
you know,
that's to me when it's an old bit.
But if I got bits that aren't on,
they haven't been on television have
been seeded annual urge you to have
good,
you know,
like you've seen it.
How have you seen it?
So I also saw youtube clips some asshole
and the audience is videotaping it now
people are saying that like it's old
material.
I'm like god damn,
it isn't even done yet.
It's not done.
You know like you can't.
So like when they were like,
well we want to use stream,
you know,
your,
your whole show mike,
you can't use tree my show because when
the material comes out I want at least
the majority of people you know,
to watching the television show other
than the people that have seen me in the
clubs,
I wanted to be new shit.
I want it to the dvd to be all shit
that's not on another dvd and it's not
going to work that way if there's
fucking these ustream clips.
And justin tv shows eveRywhere and so I
thought the whole thing was too much,
you know,
and it's not that entertaining to like
to,
to broadcast every fucking thing you do.
I mean with this show,
like I think we sit down,
we do it for two hours,
we're Banging out and that's it.
You don't want to just keep having
content where you're watered down what
people,
but you have no personal life.
They used to be a website called gab,
gab.com.
I used to be addicted to,
which was about maybe eight years ago,
was this girl named gabriel gabriel.
And she's an author in New York city and
she livecast herself via webcam where
would like refresh every 10 seconds
because it was when the internet was
new.
Oh,
you know,
now he's like,
that was actually kind of cool back in
the day.
So would have three cameras that would
just refresh every 10 seconds.
But I got addicted to watching it
because it was so weird.
She would come home,
talk to the husband,
would make dinner,
then they would bring the camera into
the bedroom and have sex.
That's the part I liked the most,
so I'll watch them.
Bang,
bang.
Completely naked.
Was this when people couldn't record
things on?
Yeah,
this is way before that,
but it was so addicting and the one day
she just left and it felt like she broke
up with us,
beaten off just right.
Like if you turned it on there in the
middle of stroke,
15 seconds later,
stroke,
they stopped.
Someone stopped answering the phone or
something like that.
Yeah,
I mean there was a show.
Do you remember that movie with William
Baldwin?
I think it was like william,
maybe Sharon Stone or something.
A splinter.
I think it was called.
It was about those people that have
their.
I think that's moving out.
Was there.
Wasn't there a movie where a these
peoples all their whole lives before
mtv,
like somewhat.
Maybe I've got the premise totally
wrong,
but like something like mtv is a perfect
example.
Member ed tv mean that basically
predicted the rise of the kim
kardashians type shows.
I mean basically that's what that show
was like and people in the movie was
like so ridiculous.
The idea that people would just
broadcast their entire lives,
like how ridiculous I look at this.
And in the end the message was that it's
too much.
you know,
the message was that it fucked up this
guy's life.
He had to stop doIng it to get his shit
together.
Totally.
meanwhile,
there,
there's more of those goddamn shows than
ever.
They're real now.
It's funny how many things from the
past,
whatever sliver.
That's it.
Yeah.
It's funny how many things in the past
were um,
the that people predicted or like a real
part of life now that were like
ridiculous back then.
like this idea of mtv doesn't,
that's a real part of our life now.
You know,
I mean,
it makes you wonder about like mad max
and shit like that.
And that's when,
when peak oil comes and people are
fucking,
you know,
driving a bio diesel cars down this
tree.
They made fucking corn fuel out of and
fucking shooting at people trying to get
fresh water.
You know,
I wonder if that really could go down
like that.
I think so.
I totally believe that.
Read that and talk about your tooth.
Oh,
they want to consign missed brian miss
last week's podcast because he was.
Have you ever.
Have you ever chipped a tooth or a
filling?
Fallen out of your mouth and you could
feel the air go inside your tooth and
hit your fillings?
Fall out.
Will you bid a spoon?
Right?
Well,
yeah,
I'm used to eating with plastic spoons,
but uh,
I ran out of plastic spoons so I went
back to real spoons and I forgot and I
always chew on the plastic spoon.
Why do you chew on a plastic spoon?
Like when I'm on,
like on the internet or whatever.
I'm just like,
she wanted,
you know,
like I'll,
I'll eat yogurt and has,
it'd be that kind of like chewy,
but I forgot it wasn't a plastic spirit
inside.
It's like crunch and like,
that's not smart dude.
Be chewing on.
It still hurts.
I have to go back in a month to get a
real thing.
That's,
that's ridiculous,
son.
That's not good.
Um,
what else I want to talk about?
Oh,
some dudes are certainly from noah's
ark.
Is this the same people that found it?
show show one people?
Yeah,
there's a.
is that.
Was that joe show show number one?
Yeah,
there was one that we did from atlanta.
You could find it on the internet if you
could find a red band.com,
right?
Yeah.
Or it's show show google joe show a all
one word
arc.
Yeah.
Joe rogan.
Noah's ark.
But anyway,
there was a dude back.
Dan said that he had found no ark and
now apparently there's a group of
evangelists that claim they've seen
noah's ark.
Have you seen the photos of it?
Now?
It's kind of interesting.
Let's see it.
I'll show it to you.
Stupid.
So you're going to send me photos of a
boat.
I'm supposed to.
I believe it's a big foot lift on this
boat.
Well,
you never know.
Stranger things have happened.
The crazy thing about these ideas of
world floods is that there was no world
communication back then.
So how do you know the flood wasn't
just in your neighborhood,
you know,
and you think that it was a,
you think that it was somewhere else.
I think that it was everywhere around
the world,
like you really don't have any idea.
Damn.
Look at you and you're following 100.
Almost 110.
One.
Oh,
nine,
five,
seven son.
Very nice.
Uh,
uh,
you know,
it's funny.
It's my space.
I logged in the other day and I've been
losing friends like thousands and
thousands at a time.
It's ridiculous.
Everyone's deleted or myspace account.
I'm reallY thinking about maybe doing
it.
I'm thinking of deleting mine too.
I just don't want to remember those
days.
Anyway.
That is my space days.
Yeah,
it's pretty silly,
right?
Yeah.
It's like having a kid that you just
need to cut off strings or something.
I can't find the article.
Oh wow.
I,
I'll look at a picture of a boat.
It's not even a boat.
It's like some would that have found.
The funny thing is,
is one picture that's really clear with
this guy inside out.
It just says this is know as arc.
It's pretty interesting because this guy
is standing inside something
[inaudible].
Yeah.
See,
look at this.
What is that?
This guy claims that that sees inside
noah's ark.
Isn't that a photo from noah's ark
ministries international?
I'll,
I'll throw this link up.
Uh,
if you just google it looks like my face
was arc.
If you just google they found noah's
ark.
You could see it.
This is the noah's ark thing we're
talking about.
Ate that shit.
It's so.
It's so annoying because I have certain
people in my real life that believe all
this shit and so they put it on facebook
and I have to,
like,
it hurts me to read.
It's just start trolling them.
I got trolled.
But the girl that pretended that she
wanted to convert her friend to,
uh,
from uh,
being um,
the girls hindu,
you know,
that video that I put online of her and
adobe friends are trying to convert the
hindu girl and to being christian.
Well apparently it's a giant troll.
This girl scott like,
oh,
it's Brilliant.
It's really good.
Like she totally seemed like it wasn't
over the top at all.
I mean it was like,
it was very much like jesus camp or any
of that stuff that,
you know,
that's real,
you know.
So tell us your kenny,
how much you mean to tell about your
store,
the story about your sItuation with the
religious people that are go wacky on
you about a certain thing in your life.
I'm talking about.
They're talking about that,
but you've got a lot.
You got a lot of religious people in
your life.
Yeah,
I got a lot and I'm doing like the exact
opposite of what they would enjoy to
were combining.
Yeah,
exactly.
Did you,
um,
did you watch the fights this weekend?
No,
I did not.
I didn't even know where to put lots of
the face.
Where was paper review and it was a very
ufc
did it feel like the us exactly what to
ufc.
But it was like that.
I dunno,
I,
I would love to keep doing atlanta doing
commentary for the lighter weights.
I think those guys need more.
They deserve more credit.
They're more action packed or fucking
those fights are crazy and right now
they're like in this like shadow
organization of the ufc.
It's a small organization,
doesn't get nearly as much attention as
the ufc and uh,
I wish we absorbed them,
you know,
I wish we had a.
If it was up to me,
I mean obviously it's not as a lot of
business contracts and all sorts of
jazz,
but it would be the coolest thing in the
world to be able to call those lighter
weight fights.
Man.
Uriah favorite fought jose aldo in the
main event for the featherweight title.
You're my favorite.
Got he got beat up,
got kicked the shit out of his legs.
It's incredible fight.
If you watch it,
it was more incredible live watching it
because,
uh,
this dude just picked your favorite part
man.
He just arrived.
Favor.
I mean,
some people gave him around.
I think.
I don't know what they were thinking
because basically in my opinion,
although that's dominated every single
round and at a certain point in time
just to had them mounted in a crucifix,
just punched him in the face for like a
minute and a half.
It Was ridiculous.
I mean he just completely dominated
favor and favor is a fucking beast,
man.
A beast just couldn't stop the leg
kicks.
Leg checks kept coming,
you know,
all those.
So god damn fast.
Although used to be a real serious
soccer player too.
He played semi professional soccer and
those soccer players,
man,
they have incredible legs I think can
move really good.
Their works really good and they kick
really hard and he's just so good at
moving in and out.
You know,
soccer is all about moving side to side.
Quick moves to deal with the ball and
those guys that are real good at soccer
man,
that really translates well to be able
to kick,
you know,
throwing leg kicks and,
and,
and getting out of the way of leg kicks
and just the ability to spring forward
and spring back.
Soccer's a fucking,
a tremendous,
a place to start,
tremendous base for certain types of
fighting,
especially for like more time.
You know,
you guys say tito ortiz and channel.
We already talked about that.
But you're going to have to go to the
uh,
recording shit son.
You can't be talking about it over and
over.
How loud were those leg kicks?
The thing about leg kicks is the
goldbergs was talking about that it's
not slap.
It's a thump.
The ones that are really hard don't,
they're not as loud because of like say
if you hit someone's thigh with your
open hand like that and slap the skin of
his thought,
it'd be really loud.
But If you hit their thigh with a
baseball bat,
it would be like a midi thump in the
midi.
Thumps are a lot more painful.
What it is,
the shin just digging into the meat of
the leg and it fucking hurts.
Like hell.
It's you.
You really can't appreciate how bad a
leg kick hurts.
Unless someone likes you,
someone good,
you know,
you get like some fucking melvin men
who've type character.
Some are nesto who's type due to slam a
leg kicking your leg.
You realize like,
god damn,
it's so fucking painful and that's what
this guy's move was.
He just kicked his legs out from under
him until he was useless from the second
round out.
He was pretty much useless.
It was.
It was sad.
No,
but mohammed south park thing.
I really liked how the.
The,
the extremeness website kept on getting
hacked.
Did you see that?
Oh,
the islamic islamic.
Yeah.
What was their name?
Radical islam.
They were from New York,
right?
Yeah.
Fucking traitors.
Ridiculous.
The idea that you don't mean that's
taken nutty to a whole new level.
Yeah.
You can't even show our guy in a picture
or will fuck.
not even a drawing,
a stick figure that even look like a
stick figure,
but.
Oh,
you didn't see it?
I didn't see the first episode.
They drama mohamad and it pulled up or a
second.
It was just like a stick figure,
but it was like a circle align and like
some kind of wiggly coming out and it
went like this.
They just showed up like that and that's
muhammad.
It's incredible.
But here we are,
2010 and there's people out there that
really believe that you shouldn't have a
drawing that represents their,
their,
their guy,
their messiah,
their profit.
And the funny thIng is,
is fucking guy.
I said that once and this guy emailed
me,
hey,
dumb ass.
The reason why you're not allowed to,
It's because they don't want.
You're worshiping false idols and
imagery.
Like,
okay,
I'm a dumb ass.
So you think it's okay to kill people
because someone's drawing some fucking
guy that may or may not have even
existed.
Uh,
you know,
you can't.
When you go back a couple of thousand
years was mohammed like 1500 years ago.
When you go back like a thousand years
plus,
man,
who the fuck knows what really happened
is I want to draw mohammed real quick
while you're talking to it.
Managers die.
No,
I want to draw it again.
Have no,
you don't have anythIng to do about
this.
I have no,
no,
no.
Say I could not stop him.
It's just your mom and.
Yes.
This is brian's version of mama.
Does this dispersion.
Muhammad is not sanctioned by ustream?
No,
I think it is sanctioned as they invest
this.
No,
no.
Got it.
Okay.
This is muhammad.
That's incredible.
Yes.
That's very lifelike.
Yes,
but here's muhammad with a mustache just
in case I forgot.
I guess drawing was probably way more
important a couple of hundred years ago
for photos.
How do you think everybody knew how to
draw?
I think people knew how to draw better.
But you think like if someone like
someone raped you,
you had the right?
Yeah,
because like how bad is people's memory?
You know,
how many people had been arrested for
shit because of eye witness reports and
you know,
people make this eyewitness report and
then they arrest someone sand that.
Sam and it turns out they were totally
wrong and then they apologize.
I'm so sorry.
And the person does like fucking 15
years in jail.
You know,
back then.
What the fuck did they do?
What do they do back then?
You know,
they,
they found the stones that look like the
rape.
This stone,
this trade for assembled,
if theY just had a box of stones,
which one looks most like your race?
You know,
I love people that are like really into
ufos and shit and like say they talk
about images that are around like cave
walls.
I've given seen the images on cave
They're like flying saucers and aliens
on the cave walls.
Like no.
Or know those fucking.
How do you know?
Those guys didn't just eat a mess on
mushroom trip.
Their balls off.
Just start drawn loony show.
it comes to them.
Well what if it's like a children's book
for their small kid come from this guy
with free elk.
We don't know what the fuck they're
drawing.
You just found some scribbles on a wall.
If you found some of my drawings,
you'd be like,
what?
That guy looked like a.
There was people that look lIke dicks.
Get that.
You see that hand and that are not that
one little that bolo that.
The drawing pad.
That's some shit found found from my
high school years.
Yeah,
that's awesome.
This is from when I was 15.
It's crazy.
I'll put some scan all this shit in
their online or you are 100 times better
than I.
I was and I did it all the time.
This was like,
this is from when I was a kid.
It is a super cat.
Huh?
Oh shit.
Like some shit that I drew.
I used to draw a lot is loosely used to,
uh,
that's what I really used to wanna be is
a,
an artist for a comic book.
So 1982.
So I guess I was 15,
19,
82.
I was eight years old.
Older than you son.
I love how all your shit's monsters.
Just scared of monsters,
man.
Yeah.
Goldilocks and three bears.
I'm going to have to do something
because I don't really draw anymore.
Sweet.
Don't.
Here's a wolf.
I was always into werewolves.
That's why I was so bummed out that uh,
that benicio del toro movie fucking
sucked because it did fucking act like
it didn't happen.
Is that waterfall ninjitsu like this one
peeinG on the bed.
Pain over the bed,
ping from the bed.
Ping.
It's like describing the bed is like
being on the.
This might be a project that I had to do
for school.
I got in trouble all the time because it
was when I was on the wrestling team,
I drew the wrestling logo for our high
school wrestling when,
um,
when I was as well.
I also drew the logo for our,
um,
our school.
We had like tee shirts for newton,
south red lion.
So I drew the line.
I used to do that too.
I did the worth,
the worthington kilborne official bungee
jumping and shirt,
which is a cardinal bungee jumping.
But uh,
um,
that's another one that's funded from a
picture from.
There's an old uh,
I think it was long.
Chaney junior or no,
I don't remember which one.
Which werewolf moving.
Maybe it was oliver marijuana.
I don't know which one it was.
Oh,
that's bad ass dude.
Look how good it look.
Color.
You're going to color the drew.
But uh,
before here's humpty dumpty.
Humpty dumpty.
The ax murderer.
I drew a lot of.
Should put the other signature book.
Yeah.
I'll do something with conan,
conan the barbarian.
Nancy.
That's amazing.
Some another werewolf I was fucking
obsessed with.
Werewolves,
for whatever fucking gary's.
And that's how I just,
uh,
I've always loved the wolf man werewolf
though,
wasn't like your father and you know,
I think I was an angry kid.
I was always obsessed with the idea that
you could,
uh,
I think it would represented to me was
like,
you know,
that you can be calm and normal and then
some shit happens on just right now.
Maybe that's what I wanted to do.
I wanted to fucking hulk out on people
and turn into a werewolf,
kill motherfuckers.
I don't know when you're an angry kid,
that's never good.
But I,
um,
I w I told me wanting,
wanted to be a comic book artist,
but my high school art teacher was a
douche bag.
He was just so suppressive and annoying
and unhappy and had no joy.
There was no happiness.
This man,
everything was serious.
Like his art was serious and you know,
and he would draw on.
I didn't think he was talented.
He was like,
he would draw like boring shit,
you know,
he would like draw like pears and stuff,
like a bowl of fruit bowl,
always gay faggot,
you know,
I've got a camera.
If I want to see fruit,
I'll take a picture of it.
Let me see.
You got a photo of wolverine fighting
spiderman now shut the fuck up because
that's what I like.
And he was telling me that what I liked
was like Juvenile and then it was like
foolish and that like my car and I was
like,
you're just suppressing what I like,
you know,
I like watching fucking monster movies.
I like reading comic books.
Is there something wrong with that?
It's just entertainment.
I hate when people pretend that they're
entertainment somehow or another is more
valid or more sophisticated just because
it's like serious,
you know,
like people who love serious movies like
[inaudible],
like,
you know,
don't be so serious when it was like
whatever man,
are you learning something when you go
to see like,
like,
you know,
some depressing sean penn movie?
Are you learning something when you go
to see those moments?
And nikki in touch with my emotions,
joe,
it was that river movie,
whatever the fuck river runs through it.
No,
the sean penn won boss Mr.
Rivers or whatever.
But it was like,
you know,
and everybody's like,
it's such an important film.
Like
what?
What?
What's,
what?
Film is important.
Okay.
They're fucking movies man.
You go to a movie and enjoy yourself.
You have a good time.
It takes you someplace.
It gives you some thrills.
You know,
you,
there's a lot of shit you don't know
what's happening.
Things get resolved.
How's this going to.
What's going to go down?
That's all it is.
It's fucking entertainment.
And the idea that your entertainment
because it represents like things that
happen in real life as somehow or
another superior to like superheroes are
monsters.
Like please just.
I had a good art teacher like I.
It's funny because I got.
I'll get seasoned,
he's in class because I would
sleep except for art,
which I straight a pluses took every
class.
but my teacher was cool and like a lot
of my paintings I look back and I'm
like,
wow,
she let me do this.
One was called pool table on acid and
she gave me an a minus and it was just a
pool table with a monster coming out of
it and everything was melting.
Why noT?
I didn't have to draw it.
She didn't make me do it.
My teacher used to say shit to me.
Like,
you know,
like,
well,
you know what?
If you get a job where you have to draw
a baby for a diaper commercial,
I want to see you draw a baby for a
diaper commercial.
And I'm like,
oh man,
why are you fucking draw a baby for a
diaper
commercial?
Like,
is that my future is what I have to look
forward to drawn diaper ads.
Like he was like real,
like my dream was to do comic book
illustrations and he was telling me
basically you need to have skills
because you're not going to reach those
dreams and what if you have a job that's
just you as an illustrator doing boring
stuff where you have to drop boring
stuff.
And I was like,
You fucking buzz kill,
you know,
and this guy was just a dumpy physically
out of shape.
Unhealthy person and he was just
depressed all the time and so I killed
my effectively I,
I went,
I only went for two years to our,
our class,
I believe it was 14 and 15.
I think by the time I went into my
junior year of high school,
I think I said,
fuck that guy.
I'm tired of this is annoying.
So I just drew on my own from then on it
that effectively killed my,
my wanting to uh,
go to school for art.
I was looking at art colleges and shit
and had scholarships lined up and trying
to figure out where to go.
So that's the only thing I had a chance
of getting any sort of scholarship.
Then meanwhile it's just teachers,
you know,
you don't realize what a gigantic
fucking effect having a good or a shitty
teacher can have on.
Yeah.
but don't,
you know,
they're cutting their salaries over and
over again.
I just saw they're cutting it again and
I think teachers should be one of the
most important things ever,
you know,
like up there with doctors.
ThAt's junk.
Canton.
yeah.
It's amazing how we were so short when
it comes shortsighted when it comes to
that.
Yeah.
what is that?
You're raising the child from the
beginning.
That should be the most them
important thing.
It should be huge.
People that can influence your children
and people that say mean shit.
Like I will never forget.
I had a math teacher in high school who
was just fucking boring and the class
was boring and she was this black lady
hood,
a black accent.
Like she would mispronounce words all
the time.
She had terrible grammar and yet she
would like shit all over you if you
didn't understand her,
her,
her math problems and she was in there
doing her math problem and I was bored
and I was like drawing or something.
They usually,
that's what I do in class and we'll draw
my notebooks and stuff like that and she
goes,
she looks up and she sees me not paying
attention.
So she goes,
mr rogan,
would you like to come up here and do
both of these for the class?
And I said,
do you want me to do both of those
problems?
And everybody started fucking and so she
said,
go down to the dean's office right now.
I said,
okaY,
but when I get back I'm going to do both
of those problems.
Mean eveRybody was laughing.
She goes,
go ahead and laugh and mr rogen,
mr welbourne ain't going nowhere.
He's going nowhere in life.
And I'm like,
at least I know how to say both get out
of my classroom.
And she kicked me out of that.
So
that was like the beginning of my time
as a standup comedian because I felt
like I was defending myself.
Like I wasn't doing anything to you.
I'll just sitting there scribbling in my
notebook.
I just wasn't paying attention because I
was bored out of my fucking head and I
had problems with authority but she
just,
you know,
liked to be the,
the lady to call on you if you ain't
paying attention,
you know,
like she went to get mad.
But I mean meanwhile this fucking pitch
could even speak.
Right.
She said both.
Would you like to come up here and do
both?
I will never forget it.
IT's like in my mind it's like a movie
playing out because the anger in my head
that this fucking dummy was trying to
make me look dumb in front of everybody
just because I was scribbling and I
wasn't paying attention to your.
My.
My opinion on math was always like,
okay,
math is very essential,
but don't you have calculators now we do
and isn't that like an endless supply of
batteries?
There is done.
Like I'm done [inaudible].
There's only a finite amount of things
to pay attention to in the day and I
don't give a fuck about these wacky
equations that you're making me solve
and figure out.
I know how to add.
I know how to divide.
I know how to multiply.
Like is it or are we done here?
Right.
Do I have to keep going?
Is this really good that you're,
you're making me be a fucking square peg
and fit into your fucking round hole.
You know?
It's like I'm not.
I don't want to do what you want me to
do.
Like this is nonsense.
It's weird nowadays.
I can't even imaGine going to school
with google
because then I'd be like,
no,
I don't want to learn it.
I can just search it if I need it.
I don't get what.
That was a problem.
I used to watch a lot of documentaries
even when I was a kid and I got in
trouble again.
Like people will say like,
you're a comedian.
Were you a class clown?
Like I was not really class clown.
What I used to do though is draw a lot
of cartoons about our teachers are
gettIng involved in shit.
And we had this one teacher that was
really annoying Mr.
Holman and h o l m a n very serious,
but he was wrong about a lot of shit.
And I was,
you know,
I was fucking 15 years old and uh,
I was uh,
in class and I was again bored out of my
fucking mind.
He had a science class,
but at least science custOmers a little
more interesting.
They started going on about lake erie,
lake erie,
jerry's a dead lake and this and that.
It started talking about all the
pollution that's involved in lake erie,
and I said,
well actually I just saw a documentary
that was on pbs.
It was talking about the resurgence of
lake eerie,
about how leakier they've worked very
hard to filter out the water and they've
done all these different things to cut
down the pollutants and they've seen a
resurgence in the fish population.
And he got all fucking mad at me and I
was like,
have you seen this documentary?
There's no,
this is not true.
And I'm like,
it's not true.
It's on pbs.
I watched it last night.
I'm like,
oh man,
all right.
so you're just like them.
So the next time we're in class,
um,
he had like these things that would pull
down like projection screens and I
pulled the projection screens up and I
drew cartoons of him and then I,
I pulled the projection screens down.
Yeah,
I covered him.
So he went to draw on the chalkboard and
as you pulled the chalkboard up,
there's all these fucking cartoons of
him saying wacky shit.
And he had this thing that he would do.
He would do this,
this crazy thing with his hands.
We would move his hands like this and
then I have this other teacher Mr.
White,
and he was only like five foot two.
So I drew him all the time,
but every time I drew I drew him
standing on something,
standing on a box or still in the other
chair or sitting on a stool and I drew
it just like him.
It's so funny,
dude.
and I had a one in anthropology teacher
who was obsessed with jane goodall and
the monkeys,
you know,
jane goodall lived live with
chimpanzees.
So I drew this one kid who was a
football player who was a nice kid,
but he was always kissing her ass
because he wanted her to like him.
So you get better grades.
So I drew him,
banging her and like if I can look like
her,
it looked like him and I drew him back
at her say,
you know,
she was like,
oh,
give it to me monkeys.
I passed it around the class,
you know,
like I got suspended on two separate
occasions for drawing cartoons.
I got sent home for trying.
That's the only thing I would normally
get in trouble for him.
I did the same things,
but with overhead projectors I would
like penis as there was an indian guy in
our class.
I'd always make fun of his parts because
he had really bad farts and then one
time they pulled the whole class out and
they're like,
all right,
omar has really bad gas because of his
diet and it's not funny and if you guys
make fun of it anymore,
you guys are all going to be in trouble
and I remember this speech,
so of course then I only drew only for
the rest of the year.
I draw this indian guy heart and on
people and stuff like that.
How ridiculous is that you,
you tell them kids not to make fun of
farts because it's not fun.
How disingenuous is that?
You cannot tell someone that farts are
funny.
As soon as you say farts are funny,
I'm not listening to you because you're
not being honest with you.
You can say farts don't smell.
Can you imagine if he loves fire?
It's the people that do this,
like fart porn.
Have you ever seen fart?
Fart porn?
We're dudes.
get their head right and girls' faces
and girls fart in their mouth.
God,
I've got such a hard on now.
We've talked about this before about how
your farts smell awesome,
but other people's foreign military,
your farts smell the bat.
Except once in awhile,
one lets out and you're like ashamed.
I had one the other daY was never not
wanted by myself,
by myself until it was like,
oh,
smell my own farts and enjoyment.
Everybody does that.
I think even girls do that.
They just don't want to admit it.
Girls cut,
but what is that?
I mean,
why?
Why is there an evolution?
I mean,
it's got to be something if everyone
does it,
like what is it?
I think it's like your body sending out
like a spray from mating,
but probably from acclimation.
Literally ridiculous theory.
Knock up and get pregnant is stick your
dick fucking awesome.
I want to make myself what?
No,
but why do you think that people like
their own forks?
Why is that a,
that sketch?
It's like it's it's food that you ate
already,
so this guy says it's called peaker.
The urge to eat,
smell,
eat random things.
I thought,
I think people,
yeah,
it's people that have mineral
deficiencies to the point where they're
the paint dirt and the other day how
weird that would be.
Eating dirt,
just like craving it like,
I need this tO her.
can you imagine?
Well,
you're kidding.
Could easily be wired wrong.
You think about all the different
connections inside people's brains.
Now think of people like my friend john
jacques machado,
my original jujitsu instructor,
he was born without his one hand,
his left hand.
He doesn't have all of his fingers.
His left hand only has like a thumb and
like nubs,
you knoW,
and that's how he was born.
Deficient some.
I mean,
I don't know what it was exactly.
Some sort of a disease,
but he's born without fingers.
If you're born without fingers,
you could be born with crazy connections
in your head that make you love other
people's farts.
You know,
you could be,
you know what I'm saying?
I mean it's possible.
I mean we look at like autism and what
they don't understand about autism,
but some people who have autism can do
crazy things.
Like there's a child that can see a
place like lists look out the window at
a,
at a,
like a city,
and then draw the city and exact detail
like down to the fucking street signs
and down to the alleyways.
I mean,
incredible.
There's,
there's videos of a online doing it.
I mean he can just look at an image of a
place or go to a place and see something
and just completely recreated in his
mind and it's,
he has a version of autism,
you know,
it's like the whole rain man thing.
It's like,
what is that?
Like,
what,
how,
you know,
what the fuCk is going on that you can
see something and record it like exactly
what you and I have no chance.
I mean if I had a drama backyard,
it will be all off and I've been in my
backyard and fucking thousand times.
But if I had to draw it would be all
fucking wanky.
You know,
what the fuck is that?
I know.
It's really weird.
I know a friend that.
Is that a friend's uncle is that I met
him once,
I met him once and he's always like
talking about like how he used to sit on
his mom's shoulders during parades and
stuff like that.
He met me once though and then every
year he can't stop exactly.
Talking about me to her.
Like she's like,
where's brian?
And brian said he was going to the store
one one and like,
like remember everything about me,
he buys me gifts,
you know,
we broke up a long time ago.
She's like duty by guests and,
and he knows everything about you not
stop talking about you,
but then
wow,
so we're doing to fuck you did one in
me.
That's strange man.
I mean it's like the potential of the
human mind,
you know?
Do you think it's because they,
there's obviously something,
some sort of a disconnect socially that
with people that have autism,
do you think it's sort of like one of
those things where people who can't see
can hear incredibly.
You know,
it's like when you were,
you were missing one sense.
Your other senses like supercharged?
Yeah,
I just,
I,
I don't know because sometimes I think
things like that or I think what if he
knows exactly everything that's going on
but his mouth doesn't work.
Kind of like when you're so fucked up
and you're trying to say something.
If it was like,
you can't have your,
you know,
what you're thinking out in maybe.
And I'm like,
that's it.
That's it.
There an affectionate.
That's the thing with them though.
There's a social disconnect and a real
disconnect
where they don't,
they don't express themselves,
they don't smile as much,
don't make eye contact as much as other
kids do,
you know?
but in so doing that and in doing that
they have this incredible focus.
Like I have a friend whose child,
his son has a mild form of asperger's,
was like an autism type of thing and his
son is a jujitsu wizard.
The kids or an assassin.
I mean he's really,
really fucking good.
Like,
like goes at a head to head with like
world champions.
He's like really,
really good.
And one of the reasons why it's really
good is he has this intense ability to
focus on things and you know,
he's not so good socially,
doesn't have a girlfriend,
not so good at like having buddies.
But goddamn you get on the mat with that
motherfucker,
he remembers every move and he's
countering your moves and advancing and
moving forward.
And he taps like really high level black
belts all the time.
You know,
it's like autistic doesn't necessarily
mean super,
super intelligent,
doesn't necessarily mean you know,
some sort of a rain man type genius.
But it has the potential it.
Which makes me think,
I wonder if it's,
you know,
almost like there's so many people that
are autistic dude.
It's like one out of 100 now,
you know,
and it's advancing over the years.
I wonder if it's possible that,
you know,
I mean people say that it's due to
environmental conditions.
It could be due to pollution,
it could be due to diet,
it could be due to the hormones in our
food.
There's a bunch of different theories on
what causes autism.
But if it's happening in much greater
numbers than it ever has before,
and that's debatable as well because
some people say it's not.
There's just more people are diagnosed
as being autistic now because they've
changed the diagnosis.
But that's,
that's under debate as well.
But what if it's sort of a next stage of
evolution would have emotions and
dealing with,
you know,
the way a human beings.
I've always beeN like really emotional
and what if that's not going to be
necessary in the future.
what if that's slowly being phased out
because human beings don't have to use
our fight or flight reflexes and
instincts anymore because you know,
we're not running from saber tooth
tigers and shed.
Basically.
We're just dealing with civilized
society and that society becomes more
and more civilized and as society
becomes more and more modern,
more people are born with this
detachment from emotions.
And one of the reasons why I thought
this is because of amish people and
amish people live their life in a very
traditional old school,
sort of a word.
And it,
it's kind of a fucked up wacky religion.
But you know,
they drove around the horse driven
buggies and they build their own houses
and you know,
and I don't know if
they even use electricity to some of
these women use electricity,
some of them driving a regular car,
some of them have real jobs and they're
amish.
It just depends on what kind of learners
they are.
But,
but the whole premise originally was
that these people lived like a certain
group of people hundreds of years ago.
Well,
they have a much,
much,
much lower.
I'm a history or much,
much lower numbers of autistic children,
much lower.
It might be just something like cell
phones and the signals are cell phones,
beepers and,
and all this shit that started making it
increase orange,
just like splenda,
you know,
it could be something we're not even
thinking about it.
We don't know.
And that's what skip aspartame,
aspartame and shit like that could
easily be.
We don't know the only way to do that.
You know,
there's a lot of theories about,
you know,
um,
people say that a lot of people,
there's a lot of anecdotal evidence
about vaccinations and there's a lot of
people say there's no scientific
connection whatsoever and people always
want to jump on that and you know,
your tinfoil hat.
But this whole thing about
autism,
what people don't realize,
there's thousands of people have been
paid off by the autism court of America
because of a,
I don't remember the exact title of the
court,
but I believe it is autism court,
uh,
not autism core,
excuse me,
vaccination court,
like the vac.
Let me,
let me find the exact number in the
exact,
a theory because I'm one of the
kennedy's,
I think Robert Kennedy jr is a heavily
involved in this shit and a lot of
people have been paid off by vaccine
court because a,
and it's in the thousands of families
because of their,
their children suffering from brain
damage after being vaccinated,
that they had brain swelling and brain
damage and they received sizable a
rewards from the courts.
Now,
if that's really true,
how do we not know that you know you,
you're not damaging other shit with
vaccinations,
especially like heavy duty vaccinations
with through marisol and all that stuff
that's been linked.
I mean the stuff that they've removed
from,
from vaccines,
it's a real heavy debated issue because
people don't want to thank a few people
have had their children vaccinated.
They don't want to think that they've
done anything wrong to their children
and people have children that are
autistic.
They want to blame someone and so they
try to blame the vaccination.
But the bottom line is,
you know,
you're injecting chemicals into your
baby when you're not even supposed to
give kids fucking peanut butter.
You're not even supposed to give babies
peanut butter because they might have a
peanut allergy,
but yet you can shoot them up with all
these fucking chemicals.
you know?
I don't know.
You know,
this whole jenny mccarthy debate.
No,
and then she's running around saying
that vaccinations cause autism to the
kids,
but I have friends that say their kids
were more and we have a friend that we
know that his kid got the measles,
mumps and rubella and then instantly was
different,
like instantly became detached,
got fucking weird and,
and,
and the kid has some serious autism now
whether or not it's connected or whether
or not he had a preexisting condition
that was exacerbated by those
vaccinations.
That's possible as well.
But who the fuck knows what's causing
all this shit?
It could be,
you know,
just the of pollution,
the higher levels of carbon dioxide in
the air.
It could be,
you know,
the preservatives in food.
It could be,
you know,
it could be a bunch of shit,
but it also could be the civilization.
It could be the fact that as
civilization progress is the need to
have all these emotions and the need to,
to exist the way people have always
existed as is morphing.
It's changing.
You know,
we're going to be like fucking aliens.
I mean,
if you think about like all the
depictions of aliens and a science
fiction,
the advanced aliens,
they're always super unemotional.
Take me to your leader,
you know,
it's like that type of shit.
It's like we kind of inherently know
that emotions are sort of holding back
progress and as human beings become
super technical or super,
super technologically evolved,
that eventually we're going to get to a
point where we're not irrational and
emotional,
you know?
And you think about like the shit that
happened with that crazy girl that got
you arrested.
LIke what?
What was that?
It's nutty emotions like chaos and
emotions,
you know,
you think about almost all murder.
Why japanese people never have domestic
violence issues or have any issues to
support this one.
I mean,
I'm,
you know,
but,
but you think about that like when,
when we think about like alien life,
super advanced alien life,
you know,
the guy from the day the earth stood
still was always super stoic and
unemotional and you know,
I mean we kind of inherently know that
that is the future.
That that's where we're headed.
And that's autism.
I mean,
it's kind of a fucked up thing to think,
but I mean maybe all these people like
one out of 100 have autism and the
debate as to whether or not it's been,
you know,
just do,
they've changed the diagnosis.
I don't know if that's the case and I'll
take,
you know,
either it debate as to what is causing
it,
but the only way you know what's causing
it as you take the exact same biological
human being,
you do a bunch of shit to him.
He has autIsm,
you go back in time,
you try it without the shit you see.
If he develops autism,
you'd,
you start removing things.
other than that,
I mean it's just speculation when you're
dealing with these kinds of numbers.
One out of 100.
I mean that's,
these are pretty significant numbers.
You know,
you have a thousand people.
Do you have 100 autistic kids?
You know,
that's not a man.
That's crazy.
Got $100.
it a lot of god damn paper.
Have you ever seen retard porn?
Are there is a retard point?
You're seeing it.
What if they do retard fart porn that
oh,
retard fart porn be awesome.
No,
it's weird because like retard,
like you feel like you're watching
something illegal,
but then you're like,
wait,
this isn't an adult.
But then you're like,
wait,
he doesn't really know.
He's getting fucked with a dildo and his
asshole dude,
I saw something the other day,
so I'm hardcore retard porn where this
girl who was also retarded but shoving a
dildo up his retarded guys asshole and
the girl seemed like more retarded.
But the guy,
I don't know,
it's so weird.
And I started wanting to,
about how was awful.
Don't never watched it.
Don't ever watch it.
So,
you know,
that's the thing about which obviously
we talked about porn,
like who buys porn today?
The problem is like fucking nobody's
porn.
So to make money in porn,
they got to go deep.
Well,
you know,
porn,
it always has these walls that they hit
and they always come out of it because
the bottom line is,
uh,
there's always going to be porn.
You know?
How do you make money though when
there's so much of it already on the
inner,
you know,
it's really amazing how,
uh,
like movies and stuff like that or
having a hard time getting their videos
off the internet.
But if yOu tried to find like a movie,
like if you want to find this as certain
movie,
it was important.
A lot of these websites all work
together like these,
these unicorns and stuff like that.
Like they'll give you a 30,
30 minute,
32nd clip or something like that,
but they're keeping the majority of
their main movies off all these
websites,
which I find really amazing.
What do you mean?
Like a.
If you're trying to find like a jenna
jamison movie to our jenna jamison movie
compared to seeing avatar so you can get
an a bit torrent easily.
Yeah.
Not being know how many porn stars are,
are not on bit torrent,
but really it's not the same as as like
pirate bay,
you know,
porn that harder to find bet you're
wrong.
I bet if you go to newsgroups and shit,
I bet they trade shit at a rapid rate.
I think you're just not
obsessed.
Not there as much though,
is what I'm saying.
I mean you can go to pirate bay has a
lot of porn.
They had porn porn but it's not pirate
parties.
Not about porn though.
Morally about like where's and it's
about movies,
music,
videos,
files about everything.
But it really is about.
But it's not the same percentage of
porn,
like 25 percent of everything on the
internet as porn over.
I'm just saying that the main thing that
porn is getting into the most I guess
nowadays is having personal websites.
So if you find it,
if you have,
if you find a girl like so and so down
the street,
yeah.
You become a member for nine bucks a
month.
She gets hurt or her webcam just sitting
there playing with a bottle,
you know.
So yeah.
That's like the big deal,
right?
His webcam shows for those girls to a
facebook page.
It's like that girl that's on our,
our um,
message board.
Crazy amber,
crazy.
Amber literally makes her living by
doing like live webcam shows,
founders.
He's one of the first girls they ever do
hd video on the internet for porn.
She wrote about it on our website.
Remember she had like a press release
like 60 years ago.
Yeah.
She's a pretty fucking.
She's heavily a tech check associated.
Yeah.
She's,
I don't know what everyone's doing.
It's crazy.
Crazy.
Amber.com
or ambers amateur.
hardcore.com.
Just look up crazy and you'll find her
if you want to find your finer.
She's crazy.
Amber on the rogan board.
Um,
if you don't know what the rogan board
is,
I got a forum that has like,
it's almost like $3 million.
It's up to posts on it.
So pretty wild for him.
Any fucked up news,
anything that's going on,
anything.
It's crazy.
Any new video that came out.
Anything that,
anything.
Bananas is on forums dot joe rogan.net.
The rogan board.
If you get on the board and you sign up
and you could be a member,
anybody can be a member,
but if you're a dickhead,
if you going to retard,
we pink.
You look pink.
Hue is.
There's two forms.
There's one forum that's regular forum,
it's called shit talking one on one and
there's another forum that's called
special ed.
And what special ed is,
is when you are too fucked up,
you need too much attention because too
much trouble.
You start fucking,
you know,
just harassing people and being
annoying,
starting dumb argument,
stupid shit stocker.
I've noticed,
especially with twitter's a lot more
creepy stalkers and I thought there was
a bunch of out there that are fucking
nuts and that you wouldn't ordinarily
let them into your life.
And now because of the internet,
you know,
they get into your life and you've got
to figure out a way to filter them.
You know what I mean?
Look,
sometimes we have this chat here and uh,
I look at the chat and sometimes people
just constant
you saying dumb,
annoying,
stupid shit over and over and over and
over and over again.
But the beautiful thing is you just
click on them and ban them.
You know,
and that's the beautiful thing about
twitter too,
like some people,
well,
twitter,
you stupid shit and all they're trying
to do is get your attention.
That's what's scary is like there's a
few people that they wake up from the
morning to sleep every three minutes
writing a message and you're like,
tHis is what this person is on the
message board.
No,
like on twitter and I,
some of these people really creep me the
fuck.
Well,
it's given them a direct
action.
Two,
it's given some people like something to
do,
something to look forward to.
They get to interact with,
you know all these different human
beings.
Yeah.
Like that little girl that you guys
always talk about.
What are you doing?
Talking.
She fucking has the one sided
conversations.
He's been trying to fuck me for the last
two months.
This fucker.
Dude,
why are you not said one word to her,
but every,
every day.
See your face.
How are we going to pop some fellow she
wants.
I don't see anything wrong with.
It is called,
which is for young lady.
I don't know.
It's funny.
It's like I,
I followed her sometimes and she's like
having full on conversations with jenna
jamison right back and forth and I'm
like,
that's fine.
It goes back and forth with this.
What do you think of the golden
goldman sachs case?
Do you know about that?
Do you go there?
You know what golden sachs is now?
Goldman sachs is a gigantic bank that's
getting sued now by the federal
government is actually looking into
them.
They're going to bring them to court and
they're gonna.
They're gonna.
Try them and figure out how the fuck
they defraud people.
They shorted.
What they did was they sold people a
bunch of,
uh,
they told people to buy things and then
they banked against it.
So they told people that we're shorting
means is like,
say if you decide that,
uh,
you know,
you look at the market and you say,
okay,
this company is going to take a shit.
They're going to fall apart,
but you keep selling that company to
your clients.
You keep telling them,
hey,
you should invest in this company
because this company is a good
investment.
But meanwhile you're shorting,
which means you're betting that that
company is going to fail on the side.
And they made tons of money.
They basically fucked over their
customers and manipulated the whole
system and made fucking hundreds of
billions of dollars for this and there's
this guy matt taibbi,
who's been writing about this in wall
street in a rolling stone magazine,
fascinating and infuriating articles all
about the corruption.
It's involved in wall street and it's
fucking mind blowing that they can still
pull that shit in 2010.
You know,
this is one thing that I sit on stage to
stage this weekend.
I've been talking about this a lot.
Like you know when people talk about,
well you don't understand the economy is
complicated and here's what I don't
understand.
There's the same amount of fucking
people.
Okay.
There's the same amount of shit,
the same amount of metal st,
amount of materials,
the same amount of people buying things.
Where the fuck did all the money go?
What happened?
Well good though the stoCk market
crashed and the housIng market was
inflated and fell upon.
What the fuck are you eating?
Saying what does that mean?
To me that means that the system is
bullshit.
It means the whole system is fucking
nuts.
I think everyone knows that system is
bullshit there.
I don't know why he says it's not that
I'm surprised,
but I'm surprised of is that it keeps
going.
We've talked about this before,
that our system is like our culture,
our system of government is like windows
98 and then the windows 95 was like 100
viruses and we're just throwing patches
at it,
trying to fix things,
trying to work around stuff,
but that's really what it's like.
It's like this ancient fucking stupid
system that doesn't work and it crashes
all the time and it's got all these bugs
and it's filled with corruption,
you know?
And yet still there's,
there's no solutions for it.
Move to an island.
What can you do it?
You can't even move son.
What are you going to do over there for
work?
Going to fucking pick coconuts.
How about you?
Going back to manual.
You have people to talk about how they
hate society the way it is right now.
You would be so fucking happy if you
move to an island.
You had to work for a living to come
back here.
You'd be so happy to go back to wildlife
was just pay 28 percent tax and you
know.
No,
I remember when I was in high school and
how he's on vacation in myrtle beach,
which is the widest trashes the case in
ever,
but I remember talking to this guy and
all he did every day was open up this
little shack that looked like a grass
cut and make margarita is for people and
he just sat there every day that we were
talking.
I was talking to them like,
you did this every day.
He goes,
fuck you.
Like I see the hottest chick that sit
here on the beach and do nothing but
make drinks.
Man.
It's the greatest life ever.
I'm like,
I love this guy.
I was like,
that he makes just enough because you'd
probably.
I mean probably could never make enough
to buy like something huge or anything,
but it gets bought by a private relies
on credit and stuff like that as a life.
To me,
I was like,
oh,
you just pretty much do what you like to
do.
I don't know.
Yeah,
there's an argument for that man.
There's definitely an argument for the
dude that checks out.
I'm just like an expatriate moves to
Costa Rica,
sits on the fucking beach and drinks
margarita is why the world explodes in
the distance.
Yeah,
I mean there's an argument for that.
My dad's about to retire.
He's 60 something just about to retire
this year and I'm like,
I'm like,
aren't you scared that you know you're
not going to have any income coming in
at all and you guys,
it's kind of scary but you're not saved
up so much.
And I'm like,
yeah,
but you could have one hospital thing,
fuck your life up and then now you have
to go back to work like 20 years later
and you're gonna be out of the loop
working at fucking grocery stores,
trying to pay for your wife to buy new
diapers for it,
you know?
And that freaks me the fuck out.
How much does your dad I've saved up,
I mean,
how many years worth money?
I'm not really sure,
but it's probably over a million.
I would imagine.
It's got over a million dollars car.
Yeah.
Yeah,
I think that's what you see.
I don't under.
I will ensure.
Yeah,
yeah.
I noticed but I don't take smart.
Yeah.
But still,
but nowadays a million dollars.
I mean you go to the doctor and you get
fucking chemo,
you're paying like $200,000,
you know,
or something like that.
Definitely make sure you keep up on your
health insurance.
Scary them hit or scared he could
because he could live another 50 years
old.
Sixty two or something like that.
Because your dad going to lift up two
years.
Well,
I mean,
you know what I'm saying?
no,
but he could live 40 years.
What does he want to do?
Like when he retired as you have a thing
that he wants,
he likes,
he's just like me but with the,
they didn't have computers so he does
everything else but like electronics and
building things.
So he will make like a hot tub and his
living room,
you know,
that build his own.
Yeah.
He'll feel like the whole living room
and hot tub just refine,
you know?
Wow.
That's cool.
Things like that that keep.
TheY keep people happy man.
Hobbies and things do.
Maybe he can invent something and sell
it.
Maybe he should concentrate on trying to
do that while he's been trying to break.
Was a perpetual motion for the longest
time.
So he has all these perpetual motion
machines in his basement and you'd go in
there and just magnets with bike bikes,
sickle tires and like.
And he's got like 15 patents.
he builds things all the time.
Let's say that it's like he builds a
computer that gets right on out of your
bathroom,
you know,
and then you're like,
what?
What's radon gas?
Well,
why doesn't he just a co.
I mean that seems like a,
like a really promising avenue to pursue
it.
Is that creative?
Maybe he should just think about that.
Think about retiring and using all this
time to try to come up with some new way
to make income.
Right.
That's what I told him.
He needs to like make something.
Why not?
fuck it,
man.
Little dude,
you know better to take that chance at
60 then 60 days that we're sending was
better to take that chance at 60.
Then they'll take their chance.
When you're fucking,
you're almost dead.
And they're like,
god,
I should have done something
interesting.
You know,
what if he,
what if he makes it and one falls
suddenly starts making a good living off
of something he created and get up at
noon and fucking go to the coffee shop
and,
you know,
check this out,
check this out.
How crazy.
Sometimes things happen in life,
you know,
uh,
they were supposed to come out and visit
me next month and he was going to retire
the following month.
And my stepmom was thinking about
retiring the following month.
And then,
uh,
I broke up with my relationships.
So they decided not to come the
following day after deciding not to
come,
they're getting late.
My step mom's getting laid off.
But because she had like over a week of
vacation time set aside that she'd never
used.
They have to like force some kind of
like year pension plan or whatever the
bottom line is just because she didn't,
they didn't take that vacation.
She gets paid for a year for no reason.
An extra year.
So she would have visited me and bought
that ticket.
She would have been screwed by the
corporate world because I love when the
house.
Do you believe in fate and stuff like
that and like things that happened for a
reason.
Do you believe that you think
everything's kind of set out and you
really can't change it?
It's easy to be cynical.
I love that idea.
But it also seems sometimes like,
it almost seems like life is scripted,
you know,
and in your situation,
I think it seems like at some time in my
situation in my life,
it's sometimes it seems so ridiculous
that it almost seems like we are living
our own movie,
you know,
the,
you know that.
And the more gonzo the fucking news gets
and the more bizarro,
you know,
uh,
our,
our culture gets,
the more,
it seems like a movie,
the more it seems like,
it almost seems fake.
It almost seems like we're living in a
dream,
you know?
And if you look at some of the things
that happen to certain people,
you,
you go,
well,
what's it attributable?
Trivial is it,
is it,
can you attribute it to the fact that
they've lived positive life and so good
things are happening to them and is it
karma?
So it's karma real because that's like
one of the trippiest spiciest of notions
ever.
So is that what's really going on?
Or is it because there's a grand plot to
life?
Is it because life is like a gigantic
mathematical equation and there's like a
set,
there's a set result it's going to
happen no matter what.
That's all working towards that set
result and you getting a certain job and
you meeting a certain person is all part
of the grand plan of the universe.
That's fucking weird.
It is weird.
It's,
it's,
it's you can't say one or the other.
You can't say yes.
I believe in fate and fate is real mean.
You should consider it,
but you also can't say fate's not real.
And you know you decide your own destiny
because I don't know if that's true
either.
You know,
I mean we are a weird combination of
biology,
of life,
experiences of genetics.
You know,
there's,
there's a lot of shit going on,
you know,
how you interpret the life experience,
the people you come in contact with that
help you rethink the way you look at
things.
I mean,
how many people have you ever met that
inspire you and literally change the way
you think about those?
It makes me wonder if I was supposed to
meet and go through this experience and
a lot of times I just want to like,
I felt like that last sound is going on
in the back of it,
you know,
because it just seems like it's just
like that.
Like it's just
a weird,
like quick,
like some shit just seems fake.
I think a lot of it is because you live
in your life the right way or you think
you'll a lot of is you live in real life
positive.
You're not being shitty to anybody.
Well,
karma is a real thing.
Definitely.
I believe karma is or that's why this
fuck that's ratting out larry king's
wife.
He's going to get it.
Shit's gonna hit the fan for you son.
You know he's gonna have nipple camp
certainty.
It's going to get ugly.
I don't know.
I don't know if it's true and I think,
you know,
it's one of those subjects where people
are very polarized on it,
you know,
some people,
uh,
will people will argue vehemently that
their size correct because it's sort of
like,
like a windows versus mac argument,
you know,
it's like a religion versus atheism
argument.
It's like,
you know,
people want to be correct.
They have choose a stance,
they choose a camp that they're in,
you know,
and that's fate is one of the weird
ones.
I'm open to the idea.
There's a fate.
I'm open to the idea that there's,
that life really is like some sort of a
gigantic equation and that it's moving
towards something I don't know.
I trY to,
I try to keep an open mind about all of
that stuff because I think as soon as
you decide that you have the
information,
one way or another,
you're being silly.
Yeah.
Because Then you're going to block off
with and only hear what you want to hear
and then you're,
you're living the right,
right.
I mean,
we have friends that believe in nutty
things and we've had conversations with
these friends that believe in nutty
things and you can tell they are not
even considering the fact that these
nutty things they believe in are in fact
just nutty things,
you know?
I mean,
that's,
that's a disconnect.
There's,
you know,
and you said it best when you said
you're not keeping everything on the
table.
That's rule number one.
Rule number one,
you have to keep up
even when you have 100 percent
everything on the table,
like a positive on the table.
Why even bother taking the table away?
You know,
if something comes up,
it'd be no reason that.
Okay.
Exactly.
We get married to a,
an answer a yes or a no.
A side of.
For or against,
you know,
I mean it's like religion.
It's like anything else.
Human beings are very insecure and you
know,
our life inherently is insecure and
because of that I think we try to,
we try to put things in a box so that we
can deal with them when they're in a
box.
There it is.
We've got labeled.
It's wrapped up.
Okay.
God is not real.
It's in that box.
Let's move on.
Okay.
do we like windows and mac?
I say windows.
Mac os for faggots.
Put it in the box.
We're move on.
Whereas for pc,
getting to this is just for idiots.
Idiots that,
you know.
I don't know.
I think,
uh,
I don't know.
I think we hit two hours.
I think this is good.
We're going to end on a positive note
list.
Gentleman.
Um,
so thank you very much for tuning in.
When you come back next week,
we will have a couch.
We will have better cameras.
We have a new video cameras coming in.
Uh,
the audio that's on this week's itunes
will be,
as we said,
from a big beefed up mp three recorder
and it's supposed to be the best one
that you could buy.
So hopefully that will be the case.
So it will be clean audio on the itunes.
We have two audios to audio versions of
it and uh,
we will continue to evolve it.
If you have any suggestions,
please feel free to twitter it.
Tell us what you like,
what you don't like.
If you Join my forum,
please don't be a douche bag forums dot
joe rogan.net
and if you have any suggesTions there,
feel free to put them in there and we
appreciate it and thanks for tuning in.
Next week we will be sponsored a
officially as of next week by the
flashlight.
We're going to get some flashlights and
we're going to fuck on me,
but the shit out.
I'm going to fuck these,
these record audio of mine.
We can listen to it loud.
You were just going to go.
Okay.
Do it.
Record it.
Record audio.
We're going to meet with a student this
week and um,
and uh,
and get some.
Uh,
so we'Ve a sponsor now,
so we're,
we're fucking professional.
This is a professional show.
God damn it.
But hopefully still just as fun as it
was before.
Again,
thank you very much everybody.
We appreciate the shit out of it.
Thank you for tuning in.
We'll see you next week.
Tuesday as always.
Joe rogan,
twitter red band and my twitter is now
just joe rogan.
it's noT joe rogan.net
anymore.
It's just joe rogan.
Alright later bitches.