Boom, and we're live.
John Jock, Joe Hogan.
I'll pull this up. Pull this up
quite some time, but we made it.
Yeah, we've made it. We made it
happen. People still to this day,
all my friends call me Joe Hogan because
you a, I don't know man. Joe Hogan.
That's a funny Brazilian thing.
You know the Portuguese
translation of ours to H's I think.
I think when we speak English,
you have to use your tongue in a way
that in Portuguese we had just flat out.
But you use Rio, you don't say
heal, right. Do you say heal real?
How that work? Somehow? The,
it's in Portuguese there first to let
us add the strongest one in the word,
but, but Hixon and hoists
and say on, right, it's,
but it's not Rickson but it's
Rio. Yes. How's that work?
I don't know when it becomes,
the name is different than when you
say a city name. Oh really? Yes. Oh,
it's funny. Real. It's
more something for them.
And when you say personal, it becomes
a little, I don't know, Hickson.
So Holly people,
it's an h but it can be an r like a
earth sound with objects and things.
Yes. Or just places I'm
thinking more places in in.
It's funny because in each region in
Brazil is a different accent really.
Well that makes sense.
Kind of like America. Yes.
Each place like by countries that,
because it's the sounds very different,
but it's a beautiful language.
Portuguese has like especially Brazilian
Portuguese. I was like a sing song,
you know, like a flow to
the bus or of a carnivores,
but it's that the way you guys
talk, it's cool. It sounds good.
You know it's one almost
like singing. Yeah.
How many Americans have like put on a
fake Brazilian accent once they started
really getting into Jujitsu.
Must be when I think,
I think in a way when Gigi to
stablish their flag outside Brazil,
it make funny. It's fun
in a way that people,
our goal is to make that area become
more resilient than any other place.
It's not that we're trying
to speak more English,
but we'll make the English become more
Portuguese and almost every student that
I have, maybe probably
because of my accent,
they still listen and speak in very
similar the way we do in every Jujitsu
school. Yeah, well that's a u.
We used to see that in taekwondo.
Two guys would have like fake Korean
accents and in each school the instructor
has a different accent
and different vocabulary,
which even extended more,
it becomes like another
language in digital community.
So Jujitsu is huge in Rio,
but what other parts of Brazil that is
very strange if you stop button and think
about the history of martial arts,
which is something that's always
been very fascinating to me.
Jujitsu's the most fascinating because
until 1993 it very few people understood
how potent Brazilian Jujitsu was.
When when I start understand Jujitsu
and became on the teenager time,
Jujitsu is basically in Brazil has that
amazing Arrow off my uncle Helio and
Carson, the whole first generation of
their family, which Brazil was all over,
[inaudible] was all over
Brazil as a teenager.
Remember the sheets was
basically establish in a very,
um, wealth area in Rio de Janeiro only.
It's basically have all these schools
is to call Gracie schools by the
neighborhood. You have a Gracie, my
tie. You have a Gracie coppa cabin.
I have a than future Gracie Baha.
But everything was almost Gracie school
everywhere and it was wealthy people
only in their welfare of
real wow. Then slowly,
because keep in mind these two have one,
maybe two tournaments. Sports
have you shoots a year. That's it.
We always practice sheets who mainly
at that time for self defense,
we want to get ready for protect ourself
would never had much chances to try in
a tournament cause there's no tournament.
Every training we do was
based in defend yourself.
What year did tournament
start coming about?
By the beginning of the nineties.
I think there's usually two tournaments.
Start catching up more as a
crazy video of your brother.
He gun and uh, Hickson
competing at a tournament once.
I was the biggest tournament of the
year. Three, 300, 300 competitors.
Oh, that's crazy. That was, that was
the biggest, that's the biggest one.
300 thousands and thousand hours.
The big ones is like 5,000 people.
Yeah. Now when this happened,
what year was this with your brother?
I think was in the 80s not
sure which year with something.
I don't think today looking
back is something that um,
I didn't like personally cause
it was no need for that. We,
everybody's to train together and let,
I don't want to find out there was behind
the scenes people involved with the
organization.
They want to something more
of the tournament and they
end up making something
like that happen. Oh,
so you mean because he gun and Hicks in
a trained together having them compete
against each other was
not a good at all? No.
Hickson was teaching us
cause our instructor,
why do you think they wanted to
have him compete against Seguin?
It wasn't even,
this happened on the day of the event
was no planning of having that fight or
anything.
They just made that happen there and
they realize that the promoter of the
tournament, they sponsor a, was talking
to someone involved the promotion.
Hey Man,
I'll give you more money
if it makes something like
that happen in an hour time.
If my instructor tells me I want you to
go and do that, I don't even question,
I just go and do it. Right.
That's the way we were in, in,
in the whole family and uh, all instructs.
And I've got to go and do this even
though I don't like it. It's wrong.
I should not do it. We'll do it.
So what would be wrong about it would be
that you were all training partners and
in fact Hickson was your instructor. So
for one of you to go up against Hixon,
it's just
w I will give you a, the Indian
nineties, early nineties,
we have a cymbal wrestling
tournament in uh, San Diego.
And when we moved to America
was nosy sheets, events at all.
And we are in search of something
similar that we can do to keep the edge.
And we went to some judo tournaments.
We went to wrestling tournaments and
not knowing the rules of anything.
And we ended up in assemble
wrestling tournament.
Sambo for people don't know is a
Russian martial art that wear their judo
jacket, but they were
wrestling shoes and shorts.
It's kind of a mix of
both different rules.
I still don't know exactly the rules,
but here we are and myself and now we
go there and I saw Hickson in that event
and when it comes started,
the final match was me and him on the
final and I back that time where we have
some conflicting side, the
family things that are,
I'll keep that in four, four
walls, but a, we were not,
the relationship wasn't as well as
should be. Then when the referee call me,
it's like, well, I'm not going to
fight my instruct on my, my coach, my,
my hero, my idol. No. Um, and I
told the ref, no, not fighting Nev.
Hexion was like, look at me.
And I think in a good way he knew
of not ever compete against him,
but at the same time he,
he realized that, um,
I would never have done
myself. You can see him, right?
I will fight for him for the
rest of my life. And, and period.
And I think it was the point that, um,
I was able to engage back our family
things together after these days and
showing him that it's all my respect
and our fight for him never against him.
Well there was a time where people were
trying to use the Gracie name and um,
many people were opening up schools
that weren't necessarily really that,
that wasn't their birth name, Gracie,
whereas you guys went a different
direction and use the Machado name and the
Machado name became enormous
too. So there was like,
from what I remember in the 90s when
I first started training with you,
there was a, I started out at
Hickson's place and I only, uh,
trained there one time and then I went
from Hickson's place to Carlston's place
just cause it was closer. I didn't know
any better. I thought Gracie is Gracie.
Oh Carlson, Gracie Hicks. Grades.
I didn't know anything and I was white
belts and I was like, oh another Gracie.
Oh this is like 10 minutes closer
to my house. I'll just go ahead.
That's how it used to be in Brazil and
there on the 80s all gracious schools,
but then when that place went under,
lost that plate, it was on Hawthorne.
That was when v Toward Belfort man,
his UFC debut in 1997 and
that place went under,
I started training with you and when I
started training with you it was like 97
ish. Right? Somewhere around there.
98 somewhere around there. One was,
I think it was right before fear factor.
No though. Seems few years before.
Yeah, a few years before cause fear
factor was 2001 newsradio style. Yes.
I was still on news radio
when I was training with you,
but our member there was like a
co year Machado. Now I'm like,
what are you talking about? I was like,
I didn't understand like oh there's
like Machado's and then there's like two
different, like
the the, the functions. The thing
that happened in that time was this,
my mother older sister,
she's married to Carlos
Gracie senior than me.
He had seven lives color.
His last wife was my mom's sister and
that's, we grew up with the family.
We don't have the same last name, but
I feel like I am and all my brothers,
the same thing.
We represent the grist family the best
way we can forever and now and every then
have a big family. I have cousins
that you relate better than others,
but it's still a family than
no. And back at that time,
two of my brothers were teaching
at the Gracie school in Carson.
Was He going in Carlos? And um,
I think by that time Chuck Norris was
no longer training with Horian at the
Gracie school. They're not sure what
happened and he stopped training.
Then one day, um, some of the,
some technologies noise show
up at our house, at our garage.
We used to teach in our garage in Redondo
beach and we opened the doors and the
look is like, man, that guy
looks like Chuck Norris.
Then this was a him up or this is
Chuck Norris. And we look like what?
And he brought him to train.
He did training a few years back at the
Gracie school. And Blah, blah, blah,
and it's a long store shot.
Then he start training for us
and when he start 24 hours,
we become very good friends. It was
amazing. Like something Brian Away.
He invited us to his house and he's
a great guy, man, amazing person.
It's the hanging out and by the time
I remember he used to make a movie,
one movie a year. He worked
for six months, make a movie
and has six months off.
When we met him, he was six months
off. Literally he trains every day,
but when he trained, he doesn't go
home. We'll have lunch. He hangs out,
go to a movie, then sell it, become
good friends. Then one day he,
after a few months after the train of was,
he invited us to the valley where he
used to live in, in soon and say, look,
I have surprise for you guys.
Then he took us to a shopping center
right off into the believer in,
um, he shows a, have a gift for
you guys and he shows a, uh,
one of the unity's mats,
right? He's like a school.
Then he said, look, this is for
you guys at your school. Wow.
Then we'll look into him like [inaudible]
run on the street and said, check,
we don't think we can afford that is
an underwater, that's my building.
You guys don't have to pay anything.
I just want to make sure I don't have to
drive them one on one at four or five.
You guys, that's a hell of
a drive to Redondo drive.
And he gave the school tours. Wow.
Then it's like what can I tell him more
about this guy that's on the knows and
that's why we have this school in the
valley because he used to live any sooner.
The school was in a scene and then we
start coming here. Then here we are.
You Hogan Tarzana to our
school. Yeah. That's amazing.
Wow. What a great guy. But the point
on that, our conversation was that, um,
our school when we opened our
school, still called college.
Gracie's you too because of our uncle.
Cause when we came in we have the
Gracie school and I remember, uh,
the family's big and everybody
has your sign of story.
Everybody's saying
something about your uncle,
your cousin and we wanna
make sure that this side,
the fem that we were representing
away was Carlos side.
Then um,
a lot of people when the with d the grand
opening check noise were with us doing
this self defense and demonstration and
the grand opened up the school and that
was on Sunday. On Monday.
We're not even ready for the amount
of people that show up at our school.
And we have um, a small place
with the amount of people,
but a lot of people start calling the
other school asking where our schoolwork
cause we're not even on the the
book, the Yellow Book. Yeah,
we are not even on that and people
are calling the other schools,
hey do you know where the
other school is in there?
Create a little situation
back then and we got some uh,
calls from other cousins and they say,
Hey, you guys cannot use the name.
Then for the first time leaving
using the name of our family,
we realized like what? Why not? Cause
you don't have less name, you can use it.
Then for us,
we grew up fighting or the family
doing everything for their family.
We still do nothing change,
but then their suggestion was, yeah,
you can call my child
like all the Gracie name.
My family was this because of Horian? Yes.
Was Beck who was a lawyer and so he was
the one who kind of copyrighted it and
wanted to make it. He was like trying
to sue Carlson at one point. Right,
but do you know the crazy thing was this,
we have one of the students in
and as we learned your shoe too,
the most important thing for me as an
instructor was everybody can learn how to
fight, right?
How can you translate what you learned
in the Mat to implement in your personal
life? That's how we learned your shoes.
The impact as you two has on you
to succeed outside the academy.
I know you can fight,
but can you fight on your life
outside then is a different ball game.
It's a lot bigger and a lot harder and
we have a lot of students that came to us
when we have our garage time that
changed their life in Queens gently.
One of these students happens to be sent
off the biggest lawyer in California
and we have no idea because we ended up
getting sued by one side of the family.
They don't have no money. We turn
to this and say, guys, I'm sorry.
We want to have to leave.
So you thought you were going to
close down the school? Oh yeah.
Then we have this guy, which his
father was very grateful to us show up.
Say, look, I'm these hot shot
lawyer. I can represent you guys.
Like what am I going to pay
now? You guys are ready.
I owe you because my son was saved
by you guys and who's your son?
That his son was 21st for quite some time.
Became very [inaudible] to change his
life around. He was a drug addict.
Now he's one of the best yoga instructors
out there. Jujitsu addict. Yeah.
We go and tell his life and that lawyer
protectors made sure that we stay here.
Fine. What's back then? There was on
the past today, Paul, our families,
we have our difference back
then and it's less now. Oh,
it's nothing. Well, there's
enough for everybody now.
I think everybody
realizes in the beginning,
Jujitsu was so new and so powerful
and that Gracie name was so huge.
Do you remember when Vituro tour? They
used to call Him v [inaudible] Gracie?
Yes. They would call him victor for
some reason it was victor vi, k, t, O,
r, and then it became v tour, like I
was there when they were calling them
Victor Gracie Manda. No,
the amazing thing in the eyes of
fighter and in my generation, Brazil,
everybody wants to be part
of their family. Of course,
everybody wants to feel that you and
that big circle because there's so much
history and it's the name.
August 12 at your birthday, right?
11th August 11th they're going to have
a statue of a Carson Gracie beach in
Copacabana and ribbon me. A
lot of recognitions happen now,
which is you two in special degrees.
Usually it's because anyone that does
usually today you're doing great Sushi
somehow, maybe second generation,
that generation student off this guy who
his instructor was the student and off
they may,
I think everybody should be in and
they're grateful for what their family's
done.
Yes. The fee,
it's the most important family in the
history of martial arts by a long shot
man. It's, it changed. The world,
changed the world, changed the world,
changed my world.
I remember when UFC came out and I watched
it and I had been a Stryker my whole
life and um, I had done a
little wrestling in high school,
but no Jujitsu, no
submissions, don't nothing.
And I watch boys crazy just run
through everybody. And I felt,
I felt so vulnerable. I was like,
oh no, I don't know anything.
I don't know any of this. What the fuck.
This is how I was watching him take guys
down and just strangle him like shit.
And these guys were killers.
They were standup killers and
hoists was just everybody.
[inaudible] when I was in Arizona,
I remember the first one they
show in the paper view. And, uh,
I was in Denver right the first year.
[inaudible] and I was teach a seminar
and I think back those days they got
payment thousand dollars
for the weekend. And,
and I was watching a group of guys and
they were not even sure and I put them on
that. David said, hey,
who wants to make a bet that the skinny
little guy like looked like a dark color
is going to win everything? And
everybody I know. No, that guy. Okay,
put good money in them. Nobody
put the money though. And He,
we are because we knew what you should
do too is we knew that Jujutsu youtube
works and the things usually it's brought
a lot of reality into the martial arts
world. Oh yeah.
We made a lot of enemies that today are
our friends because we showed something
that people refuse to learn
until they have no other choice.
They have no other choice
and no man, we have UFC,
the biggest fighting show in the world.
What they come from came from Horian.
There we go. Came from the streets in
Brazil to the world and Horian Gracie,
who we all owe a huge debt to.
He wanted to prove the
effectiveness of Gracie Jujitsu.
So he established the ultimate fighting
championship and that's where it came
from.
It came from that guy's imagination and
his desire to spread the word of his
family. That's why I choose you to do
for people. Make you believe. Yeah.
Imagine if he did not believe in what he
has and what he learned. Yeah. Will be.
None of us will be a talking today,
probably still doing something else and
maybe not as happy as we actually know.
It's amazing. And the whole stories,
it's hard for people to understand
too that have never practiced it.
How Fun it is. You know, it's, it's an
a so, and it makes your mind the better.
Oh wait,
I was telling some of the students use
Jitsu is a health way for you to be
bullied by someone.
You in a school environment and you
have the high belts playing with their
weapons. Yes. They even, they
out the white belts come in.
It's literally been bullying in a
health way because it's an hour safe
environment. Well it's not bullying
where you're not getting picked on,
but you're getting manhandled. Then
the thing is they get smashed daily.
They come back for next
class. Yes. Next class.
Until soon they're going to start
be able to do the same thing. Yes.
And that little step they
do, they realize like,
well I'm being picked by someone now
I stand by myself and I'm able to,
and he turned the table around.
It's a very healthy way to be picked up
smash every day that if you stay there,
stick there, you're going to use
that. You're going to reverse that.
You get choked pretty soon going to be
choking someone in the round bar going on
by somebody and as I walking up in
the stairs and that's how we grew up.
We go to the schools, we get beat up
like by the older cousins and um, man,
I don't think that's for me. But then
we come back one more time. Yeah,
we'll come back one more
time. Then 40 years later,
you still coming back from one more time.
We'll teaches you not just resilience,
but how important it is to just
keep showing up and it's a,
it's fun. Yeah. That whole thing.
You get choked to go home with a,
how'd that guy choked me? Yeah. I
thought I knew how to defend that.
How did he make me turn in their way that
he gets the choke? Then it intrigued.
Then you keep in in back in
the 80s we had no videos.
We would have to try to memorize and
see how this actually happened. Right.
Is it was a lot more challenging because
you have to try to remake it and not
sure if that's what actually happened
to you. But the amazing thing in,
I remember a lot of times
they're looking around the mats.
I have all my brothers, all my cousins.
It's no way someone in this room with
them will not have the answer for the
question that you have. Right.
And you have so many different views
that is impossible for you not to learn.
And I'll get good in Jujitsu. Yeah.
You have so many amazing fighters
out there knowing more than you know,
then every member, every time I
ask something to the technique,
I get five different answers. Yeah.
And I use the one that works for me.
Well that's what's interesting, right?
I said everyone has a different
approach that Jujitsu is almost like a,
the way people talk, it's
like having conversations.
People use different words and
different styles and, and, and, and,
and the amazing thing is, let's see,
we train and I do well with you
then the train with that guy.
You do well if the guy in
deteriorate, I should be doing well.
If the guy know maybe his game
does not fit with my game,
I might have a lot of difficult
against him, which I shouldn't.
What is the matchup game is
very interesting is nothing
that is guarantee all
that guy's gonna. No it's not right.
And maybe my game is used
yours but not to his,
well that was the most amazing
thing about Hickson, right?
Cause Hickson was the one guy that
everyone said was the best when I grew up.
And I have to say, um, the
privilege watch for me.
I have some guys from Carson school,
there was amazing fighters used to
watch them and I remember one of them.
Our Casio Cardozo for me was phenomenal.
We have definitely heuler
for his size, his weight,
most accomplished, Phil nominal,
all the greatest numbers, man.
What this guy did with for his size
against opponents. People look like that.
No Way. And yes, it is a way. Yeah,
and definitely as you going
heavier, I have my brother Hagen,
which was an amazing fighter.
Choo. And if evidently for me,
my time was Hickson.
It's like you have the era
of Hixon. Yeah, I love them.
They live both fighters, but you,
you in the room decade and Nixon and now
could be you, but he was right there.
Right. You could've been
number number 200 Hickson.
You could've been number one.
Are there anybody else in the amazing
thing you feel like a chameleon? He can,
he can kind of make any
game. You train him.
He can pretend to be you
fighting me or anybody.
It's amazing that aspect,
especially in the teaching process.
What was so good about him.
He used to go to our school,
we have third of the best
guys, all higher belts,
and he tells you, okay, choose how I
want to start. And you choose. Okay.
He is not going to get out. He gets
out and he gets you in the position.
You ask him to start with everyone.
I think the most,
the best thing that he has on his game
that I'm on my view and today understand
that was his defense.
Hmm. No way to get him.
You let your mom take his back, do
whatever you want. You can get him.
He used to start, let guys take
his back with a rear naked choke,
fully locked in black belts. Go
ahead, start from here, stuffing,
defend, get out and get you there. Crazy.
Then messes your mind up like,
Hey, wait a minute. Yeah,
how can he get out? And he gets
me here. Can't get out. You know?
And I think the amazing thing was
his confidence and belief on that.
It makes amazing. Well,
he was unusual in that he was really
into physical fitness as well.
Like Yoga really in the yoga
become incredibly flexible
and strong and really in
the breathing. He,
he had an amazing control of his body
as well as the knowledge of Jujitsu man.
He brought a lot of
elements to shoot that.
I don't think people realize how important
it was as people, so I knew that.
No you did not. He brought
in the breathing aspen, the,
there's your nice guy that makes you
come closer to the nature habitats.
Yeah. Gymnastica naturals
what we're talking about.
It's a style of who invented that
was the man who invented Orlando,
Connie and there was a Brazilian
thing as well. Brazilian guy.
He's still alive in his eighties and you
look at him like how can he do or still
do that and the whole idea is move your
body like the animals to bring back to
us, the animal instinct that we
end up losing by the generations.
You see some of that now
with a Edo port towel.
And a lot of these guys are training
martial artists in these movement,
like movement classes and movement styles.
And a lot of that is very
similar to gymnastic or natural.
Amazing.
But the biggest difference I think
was the concept that he used,
the approach that he used wasn't as just
mechanical the way it is with something
that's sometimes on the exercise you
change the direction of your movements is
not certain Catia, you have to do one,
two, three, four. Now he goes one, two,
[inaudible] four 10 go
back to six. You flow.
And Hexion brought that into Jujitsu.
And I remember a train, he goes, Hey,
get there. Keep, keep moving, keep
moving. Don't stop moving. Keep,
keep the flow of the
technique, you're gonna get it.
And he brought that
movement into the sheets,
which for me made a huge
difference in the way I fight.
How did you fight before that?
Um, we learned the technique.
We do the drills and uh,
it's more like you pause and wait for
somebody to pause in his position when he
came in. Understand that he's,
you learn how to start guiding people
to where you want them to go. Mm.
I'm 20 few.
I want you to go to my left is no
other way for it to go to my right.
I learned how to mold my Biden away.
The only direction you will have
to go is on my left. I know that,
but you don't. Right. Then we go on one
step ahead. Then when you go to my left,
you're gonna put your left hand on
the grounds. That felt right hand.
I know that too. Then I'm two
steps ahead of you. I mean,
when you're trying to defend something,
you already two steps behind because
the defense is I was shorter than the
offense. Your stretch arm.
For me to get your arm,
I have to put my hands and swing my
leg for it. Just bring going back.
It's always short. It's quicker.
That's why when you have
one or two steps ahead,
you don't have the time to defend.
You're blocking off the defense.
I'm already too far
ahead for it to defense.
And that's what I learned with those
movements that he brought into Jujitsu.
You start learning how to guide and
mold yourself to make you go to that
direction. Who was a challenge
to him in the early days?
Cause there was a lot
of great guys, right?
We have a lot of great guys and it's
funny sometimes I soon go to the Internet
and see some of the fights and you
notice that a lot of guys, they,
they can kinda hang out for until
five minutes after five minutes.
And great athletes, they just
done because of that movement.
He keep going constantly keep that rhythm.
People were not able to
keep up with him. Right?
And he's not lifting weights
and a body builder now he's,
and we learn how important for human
needs to be in contact with nature.
Would you imagine yourself not going
for hiking some days in the morning?
Let me, we need that. We
need that energy. You know,
we need to walk without shoes. We need
to be near the mountains, the water.
That's something that make us healthy
and stronger. And that's why you see,
we used to go a lot up in the mountains
and waterfalls and out of the city to
try to get that in a healthy
animal instinct that we had. Yeah.
Where they listen to the birds,
listen to in the middle
La maybe some chaotic,
there are people that are in the
city, they'll go on the mountain,
they're going to get
eaten, eaten by a mountain
lion. It's not even here, the mountain
lion. But if you're walking there,
quite often you understand that you'll,
you'll develop any, still have that, oh,
I heard something there. We're
losing more of that as you Jitsu.
We're trying to bring people
into that environment,
which is something they make
you better off regardless.
Be more aware of yourself.
Exactly. Yeah. More primal.
And um,
then also that's the struggle of Jujitsu
is so much different than what most
people experience on a daily basis where
you're literally trying to stop someone
from choking you. And it's a
friend, like a good friend, like
[inaudible],
but they're trying to choke the shit out
of you and you're trying to stop them
and the amazing thing you're trying
to stop and you don't get mad at him.
Not at all. You don't say thank you
man. You slap hands. And then I say,
how'd you get me? Like, oh you
forgot this. Like Oh God, here we go.
His daddy is the amazing thing.
One student said something like,
do you know why?
If you see two people show friendly
cause they hug each other at the time.
And I don't know for sure. Right? Yeah.
Well there's so much physical
contact that that is true.
There's something to that.
But I think it's the, they,
I contacted talking to Jordan.
I'm in that exchange of
information. It's also humbling,
which I think people need.
I think people have a distorted perception
of what they can do in his life.
And I think sometimes you
need to understand this is
where you are. And when,
one of the beautiful things about
the ranking system of Jujitsu is,
you know when you give someone a purple
belt, you say, hey, this is real.
Y'All ready for this? I've
seen you. I watch you.
I know you know 100% where they are,
they're ready to get a purple belt,
and then it's this feeling like, okay,
the all this showing up
day after day drilling,
after drilling coming
in when I don't want to,
is this paying off and
I've reached a new place.
It sounds like when you promote someone's
a flashback, they'll go back like,
whoa. Yeah, they realize all this time
that are bringing in a very good way.
Suffering going through these it worth
when he ran now feeling much better.
When you gave me my purple belt,
I remember thinking that was probably
one of the happiest moments of my life
because to me purple belt was like a
blue belt was like you just kept showing
up. You kept showing up. You kept
showing up. Now you've got a blue belt,
but a purple belt was like
you could get a black belt.
You just have to keep going. You in the
top of the mountain as a purple belt,
you're right there with the we all
the top guys. There's no way down.
There's just up. You're
right there with all of them.
That was during the fear factor game days.
I was more happy about getting that purple
belt than I was about getting factor
donation some because a, I get a lot
of messages from people like, Oh man,
it's your hook and good than
jogger and you need to go to man.
Come to my school anytime.
Joe Hogan shows up and he's,
he's back now. Training is not about his
power man. He doesn't care.
He wrestles everybody,
anybody and I see him twist the people
around there and the school in east one
and this is, this is real.
Here's one of the hardest
students training partners
that I have and I think one
of the last time I wrestle
him and my Malibu School,
I think we trained maybe for half
an hour or something like that.
I was there for, I don't know,
20 minutes just trying to sweep
Joe and Joe was right there.
I finished the trainers and man,
my legs are sore and I don't,
I don't remember if I did slip him or
not to just stop training after half an
hour and I want people to understand
that it's anybody that I want to trend.
I would never in a refuse,
I never give a bell to anybody unless
they deserve the belt and want to say
deserve is. I don't defer
people from more famous,
less families taught. Now it's
everybody's usually to word is the same.
You have to walk in the same role as
everybody because that's the only way you
actually going to learn
Jujitsu. For Real. Yes,
you're and I don't remember you say no
20 body training get hurt a lot of times.
Don't care. Show up and my neck is here,
my knees there and trainee and
you out there that you listen.
Here's one the strongest,
excuse my language.
Motherfuckers I have in my school training
Jujitsu with and that's why I'm here.
I'm pushing him to get
back and when to show up.
And now that I know where he is, I'm
going to show up here. What's up Joe,
is that as soon as I healed
this, fuck it. It is amazing.
And I want people to know
that a is the real deal.
Another thing that people don't know
is when he was back in the fear factor
time, he had one idea to,
one of the challenge for the
people would be training,
fighting a cage with me and decades, don't
you too? And then they realized that,
Joe, you don't need me. You go
there and do it. Well you're wrong.
You're going to mango. Everybody there.
You don't need anybody to do that.
You went up not happening. And
uh, they decided [inaudible]
that it was too dangerous to
do a person versus a person.
They thought that there was too many
legal implications. Actually. Meanwhile,
they have people ride a fucking
bull. Any sentence? But so the, the,
the challenge was they were going to
have to start with you on the ground,
like in your guard or
with you mounting them.
We had to figure out what it was and
whoever survived the longest, you know,
like the, the,
I told that guy, I said, man, you
don't need me. You can use Joe.
Joe's going to do this same thing and
gonna twist whatever needs to do it has
all the tools for that. That was
funny you say that the point was you,
you can do it. There was
no need for me to do it.
How do you, how,
how you still fairly injury free
after all these years because what's
interesting about you is, you know,
you've been doing jujitsu forever,
but you can still roll
and train with people.
A lot of other guys after
a certain of time, they
really can't roll anymore. They
develop all these back problems,
back problems in particular,
um, neck problems.
I learned Emmy Meulens you too.
Last chance to have to get hurt.
And my point is I'm always under control.
I'm always controlling my opponent and
I know how to avoid certain situations
before the situation actually happened.
Cause a lot of times people go for the
kill but not concerned about them getting
killed.
Sometimes they expose themselves to be
in a bad position and they have to learn.
Sometimes you'll do an onboarding somebody
and somebody put all the weight on
your neck and I see peeping
system in getting there. No,
you go back and give up. Keep the
control. Then you do it again,
but nodding systems, some bad
positions and if then has to do,
how well do you eat?
How well do you sleep?
Do you exercise?
Let me a lot of the things that involve
exercise to be like with weights,
lift weights and run the needle and swing.
You have so many things that
you can do and people say,
oh no debit buys going at the
holidays. Sure we can die tomorrow,
but I want to make sure that time of my
life I'm healthy and I don't see myself
going to Jujitsu school
teaching and not training,
but even Hickson can't train
anymore. Oh no, he's back training.
He's rowing ass. He's really
know when to start rolling again.
I saw one of his students, they
train last week, just one hour. Wow.
I had the injury and again understand
a lot of real bad back problems. Yeah.
As the back and the hip.
A lot of things in a lot of those things
happen more not with [inaudible] with
some of the MMA fights and got
understand back those days.
There's no no protection at all and
throw the child out of the ring and I was
sipping. Yeah, very, very
challenging. No weight class.
I mean he show up as a young age
fighting. Some monsters are dead and said,
man, I don't know how he did
it, but he did it and you know,
showing up and Zulu when he was 18
is a losing sane but still strong.
It was more from that time. Didn't
actually shoot soon. You should.
Should never go a as you
Justin [inaudible] nothing.
[inaudible] then his back training man.
I would love it. It is amazing man.
I don't see myself with years
old not be able to train the new.
You've got a cortisone
shot recently. I, yeah,
I'm not sure what happened and my knee
bugs me and I go there have a little
meniscal tear. I'm still training.
Have a certain position that are,
it's not comfortable, uh,
have the cortisone shot and so far
so good. Not bothering anymore,
not bothering me. You have
a central position that,
but the physical therapy that
I'm doing is being very helpful.
What kinds of stuff are you doing in
lift the weights and I'm every day in a
bike doing things that make your
legs stronger or bike is amazing.
It's so good for the knees.
Knowing packed them in. Yeah.
I think we have everything we
need. Then if I, if I don't have,
I can learn how to do by
end up man sheets is a,
is a lifestyle in general.
Yes. Yeah, it is. And the P,
it's, it's almost like, um,
it's not just a lie.
It's like a philosophy too because there's
a lot of people that they learn how
to deal with life through the struggle
of Jujitsu because the struggle of
training is so much harder than most
of the struggles that you face in your
daily life. It makes you more accustomed
to dealing with uncomfortable position.
I will tell a funny story that why
she's you to this for you? I, my,
my older daughter had some health issues.
I get chew o'clock in the morning,
something like that and uh,
called the doctor and said, look,
you've got to go and get these inhalers.
Something that the pharmacy man,
I was wearing my pajamas driving crazy
to the pharmacy and as I'm walking in and
have a guy walking out and bumped
him, he showed her mind and hey,
son of a ds F-you and I said,
man, shoot turning them one.
When I find them go home, go
chill. Why? Then they got no,
I'm going wait for you. Then he's
outside. I go get the medication.
I put this stuff in and say, man, get
the guy outside. He's no longer there.
Several months later the
same guy show up in my school
and I did not recognize him, but he
keeps staring at me and I approach, hey,
how are you? I betrayed shoots
before. He's like, do you remember me?
Did you train here before? No, I
bumped into you in the pharmacy.
It goes like tank you for now hurting me.
And that goes like, man,
what happened to you that all my father
passed away a day before I was so
depressed. So the point
for me was with Jujitsu,
I can walk away for something like
that. Then I feel sorry for the guy.
You know, I'm not concern. All my
friends are him. No, I'm not afraid.
It's just the fact that I'm
saving him to get hurt today.
He's one of my best friends.
He's my lawyer, my idea friend.
He's been trained as youtube for,
since that time, almost as 20 years.
But I remember that they walk in and the
guy bumped into me. He want to fight.
Wow. And it's like, man, I walk away.
Nah, I just drunk from you, man. Go home.
And less.
That's the difference too, between Jujitsu
and kickboxing. Cause the kickboxing,
you can only hurt somebody. You can't
really like hold onto him and go, hey,
hey, you ever see the [inaudible]?
Do you ever see the video? Yeah.
He was already ocean when you, right.
Ever see the video of Matt Serra,
Matt Serra, uh, was in, uh, an
altercation with some drunk guy in a,
in a bar or a restaurant or something
like that. And Matt matches.
Took the guy down, mounted them,
and was just holding onto his wrist
and he was like, calm down, calm down.
And the employers are like trying to
figure out what to do. He was like,
he's fine, he's fine, calm down.
But you know, Matt didn't hurt him.
He just held onto them and basically just
mounted them and grabbed a hold of his
wrist and was controlling them.
And then when we, she, she too is
a gentle word. Yeah. We
mean that yes. Usually it's,
we'll give you the choice to
choose to hurt someone or not.
Yeah.
And I think why a trainee realize that
that person has something already going
on in their life. Right.
And we choose not to. Yeah.
I mean we grew up in our time and it's
funny with teenagers in those years you
to tournaments and then we go like how
are we gonna test ourself and back into
the 80s in Brazil we have some fun time.
We go to a nightclub and fight breaks
through and here we are practicing our
Jujitsu but not hurting anybody.
And not because we choose
or somebody provoke. No,
we get people coming towards
us cause we always little guys,
we'll never be the biggest
guys in the police.
Then we just make sure like man we
take them down, hold joke somebody out,
but no scratch. And on the end those
people become students of our school.
Right. Because all those little
kids can do that to us. Right.
And that's one way. That's funny.
In the 80s that usually two became even
bigger with some of the altercation on
the street. We convinced the
person that we just fought,
we just choked to come and become our
student cause you didn't hurt them.
Then they're like mad they and they end
up coming and learned that they feel
humiliated, but at least they, they feel
thankful that you didn't injure them.
Uh, for sure. Yeah. And
you know, in a five minute,
I think you should to give it that
sense of control that you have.
You have that,
well, this is the way I
always explained to people.
I say if I'm in a street fight
with someone and they're swinging,
if it's strong person of a strong person,
they're good athlete and they have strong
arms and they're throwing punches at
me. If I get hit, I'm in trouble. No
matter who you are. If you get hit,
you're in trouble. Most likely I won't
get hit if I know how to, how to fight.
And I keep my hands up and I move.
Right. But if I get a hold of you,
you're not doing anything to me.
Like there's a difference between like
someone who's untrained and someone's
trained. Like if a Jujitsu black
belt grabs a person and gets off,
actually gets control of
them. There is no lucky.
You're not gonna luckily submit me,
you know, it's not going to happen,
but you can. Luckily you could hit
someone. It can happen in a street fight.
If someone has a little bit of speed
and they have power and there's a strong
person they can hit you. It's much
more dangerous. That's the only,
and we also want to train,
it was the only opportunity or upon
enhances before we close the distance,
right? That's the danger zone.
And if you think for a second,
a lot of things that we do
on the ground in Jujitsu,
you'd just bring those two
people up in the close.
The distance is the same thing.
And a lot of people today,
they don't do the same.
They tried to fight standing when they
hold different than when you're on the
ground, the way you move your
legs, they way play guard.
It's the same thing when you're standing.
Work on the people's body as a whole,
cause a sweep to make
somebody fall. And, uh,
and we learned that when
we get close to someone,
we make this size not affected as much
eyes could if you have a distance,
do you,
I think that there was a transitionary
period where a lot of Jujitsu guys were
having a hard time cause they were, they
didn't know how to take people down.
And then the wrestlers were learning
how to keep them at distance.
They were learning take down defense
in, in uh, yes and, and that's
the very challenging thing.
But if I'm fighting wrestler,
what are the chances that
he's going to take me down?
It's higher than me actually
taking him down. Right?
And most of the things that
we do in the Jujitsu on the,
what we see in the sports issues today,
we're not gonna use in a real fight,
most as you should to see in a tournament.
We're not going to use that in a fight.
That's the difference from that generation
of the 80s to the generations from
the 90s until today.
It's two different kinds of a Jujitsu.
One is a sport which is very beautiful.
A lot of people did do amazing techniques,
but the rules of the sport had the tenders
to take to another direction and when
you have [inaudible] as the 80s with
practice using a lot of leverage with the
arms patients and when we play Gardendale
eighties is different than we played
today too. They have a lot of
gears wrapping around everything.
They key became a weapon right in our
time. They give us never a weapon.
They give us like almost like a paper
we use a lot. The neck a lot. The elbow.
Well that's what helped you when
you transitioned to No-gi, right?
Well definitely it also because you were
born with no fingers on your left hand.
Man was no d from me until two
days. No difference. Right.
I play exactly the same in both,
right. No difference at all.
But you are all over hooks and under
hooks and and grips around the body and
whereas the guys who transitioned to MMA
and they're all game relied on grabbing
collars and sleeves, those guys
had the harder time for sure. Yeah.
A lot of guys. That's why a lot of
guys that are trying to come in,
they might be good in their top games,
but when they go in their back, yes,
they are kind of a little lost until
I see this guys how to play the game.
Yeah. That's why it's so
important. Impressive.
When you see a big guy
who also has a great back,
great office back like
Fabrizio over knew him.
I think if you'll notice it, if I'm
on the bar of someone and I'm flat,
I'm a target, right? I have to change
the angle. If I don't change the angle,
I'm going to get ground and pound
like we've being seen a lot. Yes,
you're gonna see some more this a black
boundary sheets and then they go like,
oh, it just gets flat on his back.
That means all my weight now is
affecting you. I'm dropping you.
You have to learn that your
leg should be an angle.
This way I'm not able to hit
you there. Your legs on the way.
And that's one thing that very few guys
do it or close the distance or change
the angle, but it can be looking at
him trying to, we'll hold his neck.
He's gonna hit you hard.
Well Eddie figured out a brilliant thing
with rubber guard when with a brilliant
thing with mission control and how
to control from the back of the neck.
He loves the distance
closer to the distance.
He changed a lot of people's games. What?
What that some people
don't want to recognize,
but they have chu is the idea that he
had and I remember him coming up and try
some of the techniques and people, oh
this is crazy. I said, no man, keep going.
This is, you're going to get
some, well I don't think,
not every body can do that because
you have to be a little bit flexible.
But once you learn how to do
it, you save your life. Yeah.
How many guys that when they get a hold
of their foot and keep that close is no
gap or room for the
person on top to hit you.
And as you're trying to move too
much arm suddenly stuck. Yup,
and there we go. Yeah.
Closes the distance.
You can be playing when my arms are
free because I'm going to ground them
pounds. Especially the heavy guys man.
Right. Hit once or twice. That's it.
Yeah.
He figured out some very unique ways
to use his legs and you notice that he
closed the distance or he changed
the angle. Close the distance,
change the angle. Whoever's on top,
you don't have space or
you don't have the angle.
You always in a weird position when they
get a hold of your head and the leg the
way he does.
It's interesting to see the evolution
of Jujitsu from 1993 UFC style to 2019
too. There's so many new techniques.
There's so many new approaches,
but there's some guys like
[inaudible] Gracie for instance,
who just use the basics honed
to raise her sharp edge.
You don't see a lot of crazy baron Bolo,
chokes or wild things from those.
A lot of the like real rock
solid traditional techniques,
guys, he does simple
works all the time. Yes,
whichever simple works.
Are there any things you used to that
require more than three steps you need to
train a lot, but even Hickson, right?
Like Hickson style was the just,
it wasn't anything that
no one knew how to do,
which just he knew how to do it
better than anyone. There we go. He's,
he's the way he moved. Yes, you can
find him. Right and once you find him,
he gets out and get you. He
goes around your back. It's,
it was a middle man triangles. Armbars,
rear naked chokes, normal stuff.
Normal things that everybody knows
how to do. You'll get to his god,
you know you're going to find a back.
Yes. Simple as that. I'm his guy,
I'm gonna fall, follow his back.
He's going to sweep me all.
I'm not going to sweep all he's
going down by me. They may,
it's not much way can feel
safe and today you see a lot of
these usually to have, they
need some pickled transition.
You go phone number one beginning
of the position transition.
Then you have the submission today.
They jump from number one beginning
to the submission is no transition.
The transition now is become muscle
amped over by never seen so many injuries
today in this Jujitsu competition.
Really so many injuries,
shoulder neath, foot, elbow like my
God, what do you think it's from?
Because it's no, you're
missing a lot of that.
Sometimes they finesse to get there.
They have to muscle. Well that's
one of the reasons why I wanted to talk
to you about your longevity because you
are the best guy that I know of
in terms of like you, you are,
I mean if you have a little knee
injury, little meniscus, but that's it.
I've known you forever. You've
never had like a major surgery.
It never had like a major problem and
everybody I know gets hurt. Everybody,
man. I again is the way you train,
the way you control the fight and I think
people can understand is I rather get
you once but I get you. Well
then trying to get it 20 times.
Sometimes people try to go after each
other and the injury will happen.
Right? Cause the clashing. Exactly. If
you have somebody come very tense to me,
I don't play tests back. I tried
to relax more. You relax more,
I'm going to be able
to achieve against you.
I remember when you competed against
Dean lister and he was about 250,000
pounds. Tt was so fucking big.
He was so big. And then,
but you were able to,
there was one of the very big frustration
for me on that event because I
remember was I'm training to be my
weight class below one 70 and that year I
will have a with Marcella Garcia, we'll
have some good names, good gas to fight.
And I was training a lot
for that. And I think, um,
we can a half before the event, um,
Aronia was supposed to fight
the LR, but back in those days,
I think he's called tracked with pride,
did not allow him to fight cause their
concern is an injury happened. Right.
And he's gonna meet me, be
missing the pride fight.
Then they come a week and a half
to offer me death fight and um,
and ended up taking their
fight. But I don't think I,
I train is specific and
focused to fight dean.
And I think that fight
was a process for me.
Dina was a monster but it wasn't a good
fight was not much happening on the
fight. It was mostly he was
concern it to move and I was,
I felt the difference in
the, I was so light and I,
I did not train anybody heavy
cause I was fine on the one seven.
I was just trying to, if people that
way class in lower to get this speech,
be ready for those guys, then
here we are week and a half.
I don't think I was feeling ready
for fight. Somebody this big,
my strategy, I have no strategy back
down. Okay, let's, let's try to move.
But he was very smart, not moving much.
I have evidenced to be worried about
him, grab a hold, get a hold of my foot.
And I think it was 20 minutes, not
much happened on their fight. And um,
and for me it was,
was frustrated not be ready for five
like that as I was training to fight in a
lower class.
I was so ready and I regret not
doing that would be amazing.
But for the other reason,
that movie Aben no problem.
Well, when you did do
Abudabi the first time,
I think it was a wake up call for a
lot of people that you know because of,
you know,
being born with no fingers in your hand
and your approach to Jujitsu being so
over Hook and underhook
powered, you know, you,
you transitioned so smoothly into No-gi
whereas a lot of guys from your era,
they would go and transition
into Nogi and they really,
they were missing so many tools because
they're so used to grabbing the game.
No, what I remember when I got a
call to go at nine and nine and um,
they said they rules would be 10
minutes, five minutes, first five,
nothing counts, right? Then after
five, whatever the rules were,
I don't even know today what the rules
were anyways, what counts on the account,
but then realize, man, the first
five minutes not counts at, let's go.
Right? So if people don't know
what we're saying here, I would,
Dhabi is a very strange rule
set. So for the 10 minute round,
the first five minutes
of it, there's no points.
It doesn't matter what happens if someone
takes him back. If you get mounted,
you get into a triangle, but
you escape. There is no points.
Yeah. And I just go bring
that guy to the ground,
pulled guard right away
and let's go right.
And I think was suppressed for a lot of
people because right from the bat I keep
going all the way. And um, again,
with the transition that I,
for me, I have no transitions.
The same game no-gi right.
And I felt at home, yes.
That's what I do every day. And I felt
a lot of guys not sure how to behave,
but in my mind, the first five
minutes, nothing counts. That's,
it doesn't matter if he mounts
me, take my back or do anything.
Nothing is realistic.
Their whole idea is to make people
actually go after charter. Right.
But when I get there,
I see people waiting,
standing five minutes walking
around, waiting for the five minutes
[inaudible] and then went on one
point opposite. But usually, yeah.
And I said, hell no.
Let's go to the ground,
see if he's better grappling than
me. Good if it's not good as them.
But it was a wake up call for a lot of
people cause they got to see you. Who Do,
who did you fight in that first year?
He fought sock awry, right? Aye. Yeah.
Fought who was a big time MMA
fighter at the time. But I can,
I think they were well known and very
well known and May, may world of it.
They're also known as being really good
grapplers so it was very eyeopening for
people to see you run through,
if I'm not wrong with the first
loss for Sockeye is first loss.
What was fine? I think for me it was,
it's my world and let's see if you're
better grappler good if you're not. Yeah,
we go. Good Fun. Yeah. Yeah.
It was fun and I think was,
it was very good for me too. All Day.
ADCC I was able to be among the
best three guys and that was,
um, for me was a great
accomplishment. Being able to,
to stay up in the top of their game and
fighting the lighter guys that have your
guys and was in special Nokia,
which was something that it
takes for a lot of people,
some kind of adjustment cause they,
they born in the gay world base in their
game on the g and they have actually
some hard time too. And a lot of them
even gave up. Like, I forget it now.
In the early days of Jujitsu, there was a,
a lot of No-gi guys on
the Luta Levi side, right?
There was a v for people don't understand
there's a big rivalry in Rio between
Jujitsu and Luca Libris. Um, a lot of,
a lot of times you have people that come
to our school and they don't fit in,
they and they walk away.
And if find the stood back those days,
those guys were some of
these people that didn't,
did not fit into their Jujitsu schools
and then that creating their own,
no geese school. But
again, understand that.
And in the 80s our generation in
Rio de Janeiro, summertime, man,
it's a 110, 115,
extremely humid and we did
a lot of trainings with
trinity g and after the guest
session, like the top of
the guilt and here we go,
we train ogee since we are white belts,
we've been doing that because the intent,
we're learn how to get
out of our head lock,
how to be in the barn and somebody
trying to slap you. What do you do?
And that was our
training, that generation.
That's why almost everyone from the 80s
is still up to date teaching and making
a great school.
All the jet dead generation still the
longevity on them being do Jujitsu still
out there. A lot of guys that I see
now, especially if their social media,
they all teaching, they all doing
very well. A lot of them too big.
Some of them still in
good shape and teaching.
But at that generation I think is uh,
for me was a golden gold generation
cause he's still out there and the people
that come from that
generation, their students,
they developed such a good Jujitsu
roots is they're still looted liver,
anything anywhere.
I think they still have there but
there's not a rivalry anymore right now.
I don't think today past that time.
And I think that their rivalry was a
need for our generation to stablish.
She,
it was a very effective art and I think
some of the MMA events that happened was
the fight to should,
should they happen on the,
then we're able to bring
that into make into an arena.
And this way only the two guys would be
finding not innocent people get hurt on
the street. And I think ways
of what people don't realize,
there's a lot of those fights could be
happened right on the nightclub or some
people even get killed now lets bring
their fighting to their arena on youtube
guys. Nobody else going to get hurt.
And that's why a lot of those events
happen. No money, no prize money,
not just for pride. There's some videos
of some of them that still exist.
You know, just for pride,
there's no money involved in
any of those fight on the beach.
Who was that on fight? Ugo
Duarte. That's right. He'd go,
Duarte went on to fight and pride.
He fought tank Abbott, right?
Man fought some different
people. And I remember,
I remember that they were so funny because
I'm have a point on the beach in Rio
that is,
it's where most of the shit
where the pretty girls were.
Then all the guys go in there session
the beach, very famous people,
and then everybody goes in that
session and I would keep it here.
The rugal challenge Hexion Luca challenge
Hexion Hooga challenge here is right
here. Every go smack them in
the face then, and he goes like,
no, he didn't say anything.
And I'm right there.
I'm walking right there
and a light shorts there.
My mission where Hixon look
up, look at me and say, hey,
watch my back. Where were
you? I'm the one. Okay,
I'm off the screen now.
Right on, on my left.
You're gonna see me
standing there then. Oh,
he came right. If, if I get up, I can
show you what this fear is. What year?
This man, sometime in the 80s and
didn't know who's filming that.
We have a um, high and Gracie,
he was sitting at someone's shoulders
with our camera. Crazy to try to see.
Oh no man. I was getting so
many bodies. I was getting,
I was getting punched in the head and
back just cause as watching Hickson's but
everybody didn't jump in? No, no, no.
What we did was we made a
circle harms two arms and uh,
and Hickson's the one with the green
shorts, right? Greenstreet yes.
And he had the long hair that they,
which they got grabbed his hair.
It doesn't look like it's hers that well.
Oh No, he is a ponytail there. Really?
Yeah, I have, I knew he had a
ponytail from a advantage of,
see now you see Hickson
mounting him. Oh no, he, he,
he got tired of punching the guy we felt.
And so my mission, him punching
him. Yeah. There we go.
And the guy tap and stop.
Please stop and didn't have it.
He has a group of guys with him.
We want to make sure that
nobody jumped on his back. And,
but the thing is, we have
this in, don't get me wrong,
I'm not telling people to go and do that.
But in that time and that generation,
a lot of those fights that happen in the
street with the need for Jujitsu to be
established the way should be and was
better than two guys finding there.
Then that fight end up in a bind and
that Glenn mucking five people shooting
each other in the, remember
Hexion said that we,
we get together now our first
original Gracie by high school,
then some members of other Jujutsu
to schools and say, look guys,
a Hicks is gonna go, they're gonna make
a circle. Only him and the guy fight.
Nobody else fight. You understand that?
Cause if everybody fights then somebody's
going to get really hurt cause you're
not going to be able to control
anything. We just made a big circle.
We'll hold hands regardless of what
happened. We will not interfere.
It's Hickson and the guy and that's it.
But want to make sure nobody
jumps in then never may say,
you got to watch my back.
And I go like, oh, okay.
Said don't do nothing. I
watched my back and he, we arm,
I was behind him and I'm getting punched,
getting kicked from other people.
But the crazy thing was they happen
and Hexion on his mind said, look,
I'm going to go there, slap him
on the face and he's going to run.
Then we're like, okay. So he goes there,
slept that guy and the guy did not run.
Then we go, Whoa, shit game
on. Then we hold the chart and,
and I think it was, uh,
this happened on Saturday.
Um, Tuesday night ugo went
to Hixson school with,
uh, a lot of people. They're
all carrying weapons.
Hexion wasn't there and they call his
shows up in shorts and he quickly just
slept booboo around.
Somebody called the police later on
and they even should the ceiling, um,
ar 15, whatever, just
boom. And they laughed.
But then was Hickson just smash him
quick cause it was on the cement,
not on the sand. Um,
but then again happened in a way for us
as a pride to prove the point is you to
ease the best staff martial arts. Uh,
we keep going strong and
Ula was alluded lever,
a guy who was a looter liver
respected, real strong,
one of the best guys do today
and they had a grappling style.
It just wasn't as
comprehensive back there.
They were doing a lot of
foot locks already here.
The ones that are doing a lot of foot
locks and they'll get a lot of Hugh hooks
and they have some quality
fighters among of them.
Definitely Eugenio to Dale
or Janita deal and they have,
I ended up fighting one of the guys from
there and now I want to double dom is
there. But as the time goes
by, I think people get older,
can understand and I don't think today
has any conflict or any bad feelings and
they must've adopted a lot of the
Jujitsu techniques to everything was you,
you take the guilt right
today, all training. Grappling.
Okay. What is the definition of grappling
you on the ground fighting then?
It's usually it's what do you think
about this new trend that you're seeing,
like you saw it particularly
coming out of John, Donna,
her and dean lister with the leg
locks like leg locks are so big in,
in Jujitsu competition.
Now when when we learn
Jujitsu in stu today,
we will not learn anything related
to lags until we get our blue belt.
The main reason that behind these were
to be able to let you the help guard
without concern anything just to learn
how to move your hips in sweeps and
hooks. Foot lock is
something very effective,
but if I show you right away,
I might be stopping some of the evolution
of your game or the other person that
you train with that he can learn, which
will make even better. His Foot luck,
right? That's why we hold back
until people get up one year,
two into Jujitsu to learn leg locks,
but today you have the no-gi
everybody such in a hurry.
Then a lot of No-gi schools, the first
thing people wants to learn, hey,
I want to learn hill hook. It's usually
it's with, gee, I want to learn ombre.
They know g wants to
go straight to the leg,
they get people want
to go straight to them.
But I think particularly because of the
success of these leg lockers against
high level competition or know
it's effective is amazing.
I think it's a portion of the game
[inaudible] and you will see
the development of people
that will have defending
that which also will force guys
to pass also beyond the legs only.
But definitely their
work is a very danger.
Let people wrap their legs
around your leg hook you there.
I mean not everybody can get out
of that and if you don't tap,
you're going to get your
knee ripped apart. For sure.
And that's the real problem with leg
locks is that so many guys wind up with
pretty devastating knee
injuries in the 80s the the,
the decision not to have heel
hooks in Jujitsu was for safety.
We do, we did practice, but
the competition does not allow,
you gotta understand that in the
80s if you have a knee problem,
your career is over, right?
There's no surgery that really
would fix it correctly. Right.
Today is different. Yeah.
You understand it's the devolution of
the medical side make possible for you to
put a brand new knee over there.
Yeah. But still to this day,
meniscus tears and cartilage
tears, those are still huge.
I mean without stem cells it's very,
very difficult to fix those
unless you get the wineskin.
Like I had part of my meniscus removed
on my left knee and then you see them in,
you want to train fall Engevity
and your gun understand two is a,
I think some of those things
should be kind of farmers cranium,
a pro league into the Jujitsu world.
Cause a lot of people they get hurt
before even they learn what Jujitsu is.
That's why my only concern is the
danger of all those heel hooks.
[inaudible] leg locks.
Cause if you get somebody who knows he
might have or he might roll to the right
side, even though a lot
of guys do get hurt. Yeah.
But if you hold somebody who doesn't have
much experience in one of those traps,
it's for sure injury. They brought the
wrong way and rip it apart themselves.
Even if you don't squeeze, it's because
they don't know what to do. Right? Yeah,
and my, that's my view off as an
instructor today on my school center.
You're not ready for legs yet,
right? Oh, I go to the nugget.
Don't go to the Nogi Tournament yet.
You have to learn first in
the stand for your own safety.
And also I want them to develop guard.
Cause when we get hired with pool guard,
when you get tired, you lie down to sleep.
You don't sleep standing. You sleep.
When you lie down, when Jujitsu
is the same thing, you get tired,
you're going to pull guard.
And that's one of the ways I see
some of my students in a tournament.
They get tired. He's a top guy.
Send his that pulling guard.
Does that mean he's tired?
He's already once in.
That's why you have to have a good guard
just to survive and rest to be able to
continue.
We surprised though that this no-gi leg
block games are taken off the way it
did.
I think because of the success of have
so many guys doing extremely well in some
of the guys that come from the new ogee
originally doing so well now some of the
guys that come from the
gear world doing No-gi,
they've been finding some
challenges to adjust to that leg.
I think he, in a way,
you have two ways that simplify because
if you get somebody in a footlocker leg
lock there, we go in at the same time.
You complicate cause you see a lot of
scramble now and a lot of injuries as
evidenced the same. People don't want
attack. Then it's a position that you,
some is going to get hurt. Yeah, but I'm,
I'm [inaudible] that development
and devolution of the,
the grappling world and
I think it's amazing.
It's sooner or later somebody is going
to find ways to protect better and better
and better and better that
will force people to move on.
But you seen that I think now with a
lot of the leg lock guys against each
other.
They kind of stalemate and he seen them
winning by rear naked choke or Armbar.
Again, they're not using the leg locks
against each other. They realize like,
man, he knows as much as I do
now. I need more than that. Yeah,
they're using them to sweep or they
use them to set up other things.
They're trying to exploit other holes
like maybe they concentrate too much on
leg block so then they, they're
open to armbars or chokes.
I remember when when I learned in the
beginning and we have foot lock as the
last resource,
let's see him fighting the guy
and I man not able to submit him.
I'm going to foot lock him.
That's how we used to have in the 80s
where your Hail Mary lock is, okay,
this is my deadly weapon. If
everything that I do is not working,
I'm going to foot lock him. Today's
the opposite. My first shot his foot,
lock him all the way. It's not
working. I'm going to choke him. Yeah.
You see so few foot locks in
MMA. It's interesting, right?
You see like so few figure four foot
locks because the danger also for you to
get hit yeah. That sometimes when
you do the foot lock your face,
your arms are both around the land.
You can get a not defending exactly.
What do you think about combat
Jujitsu at his new invention?
Men I think is a way for people to step
up to reality and then this thin and
some guys make a decision to know what
I might be able to go and do MMA too.
But that's the real world.
Yeah. If you find somebody,
that's exactly what's
going to happen. Right.
And making people more aware of, okay,
my Jujitsu for Jujitsu sport only,
this is not gonna work there. Well
for this kind of, as you sheets,
I have now to be aware of
more of my real fight. Yeah.
And I think it will help more devolution
of that sport of Jujitsu to transition
to MMA for people to show
what combat Jujitsu is.
Eddie Bravo invented a way where you do
Jujitsu with slaps on the ground and uh,
you, you would think it's just, Oh, it's
a slap. But no, a palm strike really.
I mean you really can hit someone very,
very hard with your palms. I mean,
I can do that with my hand on a table
and it doesn't hurt my hand at all.
But if I did that with my knuckles it
would really hurt. So they're there.
They can smack the shit
out of each other. We,
we still do that after we train Jujitsu
is to call in Portuguese that top area
second slap each other after
the train. No shirts. Yes.
And we used to train like that in Brazil.
Oh really? Yes. To be ready again.
We have no tournaments. I me
after the train, let's see.
And we stand in front of each
other and open hands and,
and we go slap each other, make sure I
get slapped in the face. But on the end,
the train,
you have marks all over your body and
it still shake your brother's hand.
I love you, but y'all
over mess. Are you still,
you still lift weights? Yes, I do. How
often do you do that? Two days a week.
Two days a week. But I, but I like
to run a lie like outdoors. Yeah.
I run three, four days a week and
usually when you run in trails,
I did try my how now it's
too hot. I don't know.
Unless you go early in the
mornings. I go early in the morning,
very early in the morning. It was,
it was hot this morning when I went.
It's very hot right now,
but I like it there.
I think I want to challenge my body hours
to bring the best off the resistance
cause I,
I think I don't like to go and run
the same street over and over again.
Somehow. Your body rate
again just to that right.
I'm always trying to find
different, the trays. Yes.
This ways I gonna fight you on changes
up and down the whole time. Yeah.
And, but it's something
to [inaudible] dish,
which is my excuse to do all of this.
I want to go and do better or
my students are getting harder.
How can I switch that to
make not their heart, right.
I gotta do a little bit
more than I was doing now.
How do you mix up your weightlifting
training with your Jujitsu training?
Do you do it in the morning and then
train at night or do you do it after you
train?
Right now I'm doing before
teaching to the train.
My intension is when I
show up to the academy,
I'm already tired physically so that
when you do train you can be relaxed.
And just this way, my challenge
is because I'm physically tired,
I make the level of my students higher
cause they have a lot of energy and
they're good too.
It makes more challenge for myself to
train with them cause I don't have,
okay I manage now I have to purely use
the techniques. There's usually two.
The techniques has, must be
on time. I intend to do that,
get their tired to make a good training
for me and that's what I've been doing.
I show up and they don't know and
hey, let's go and train. Then. Uh,
I can tell them, man, I should
rest before train this guy today.
I don't know if he's
getting there good until ty,
everything's at the same time next
week. I'm not going to do that again.
So when you do it, uh, twice a week,
how do you mix it up? Like what,
what kind of training you're doing?
I work on one one day legs and lower
poverty. And that's not the day.
Upper body of hours. Yes. Yeah.
So it's just to make it stronger,
just to keep the joints healthy and
evidently fuel the muscles I think is
important for its like
preventing injuries. Yeah,
that's the main thing. Yeah.
And I'd be using a lot the, I don't
EC stuff. Remember the guy from the,
I don't ag, he sent it to me.
The equipment I'm using that
it's amazing they using that.
It is a recommended issue shoe.
Two guys for Jujitsu regards, it's,
some are going get it man.
It's incredible. Or You
said something to me once,
I'll never forget it. Go.
Never Trust. You're nice to do.
Not Fall out as strong as to get to the,
to the neck. You have to
be very aware of stuff.
Seeing little flashes after
that gets dark. Oh yeah. Yeah.
We go, oh, I'm DC. No, you're
about to go out. My friends
trust your neck. Never
Trust your neck. Yeah.
But at least you could train it safely.
Now with the iron neck there was always
a bunch of different ways where people
trained that were questionable.
Like there's a lot of people that
don't believe in neck bridges.
They said it's actually kind
of dangerous and our neck is,
if you see the spine is so sensitive
you got gotta be careful and work.
Your neck issues you treat on, you
use our heads on the ground base.
Our bottle never.
I think that our neck is again is the
maintenance of having your neck or well
around because that spin,
anything that you do man,
you work every angle of your neck.
Yeah. And I do a very simple exercise.
I have ds attaching to a bar and
go forward and turn sideways there.
She knew the movement. Do
you do the Ray Charles very,
very slowly have that bungee that
keeps more or less nation? Yes.
Yeah, that's right side where man I love
that machine or that piece of training.
It was a a great addition
to all the exercise.
Thanks to the guys cause it's
really, really helpful. Yeah.
I recommend it to everybody. It's just,
and for fighters that get hit in the head,
it's so important to have a
strong neck to resist the impact.
Your socks will be the
muscles around this way.
The muscles take the first hit.
Just like you're talking about building
strength around your joints by lifting
weights and protect actually
the same thing. Exactly.
So are you doing like basic stuff like
curls and dips and very busy going in
difference different than the time
that you're training for competition,
which is inhabited a lot.
Explosions in this way.
Just trying to maintain and everything
else I do. And she's used to,
some days I train pushing
more Sundays or pushing less.
Some days I just train in defense
and they say training. Okay,
I gotta finish everybody today or I got
amount of bar today. You kind of found,
make your training, um, a goal
for your training this way.
Always excited to do it right. You know,
and not having the same thing every day.
Now I select OK to them
when sweep everybody.
Then I pull guard and keep playing guys
my go sweep and some guys I'm very hard
to sweep another day I just went amount.
I can only finish people from the mount
and that mean you kind of make different
goals and I think that
keeps you and again,
my students there, it's usually
just fun. Come on. Sure. It's fun.
You never know what's going
to happen, right? It sells.
I challenge you goes like, oh man.
Then you realize I should sleep two
hours extra. I'm tired now for sure.
If you really want to find out where
your body's at, go train home man.
Why I'm so sore. I don't know. And it's
usually to test you in every level.
Now what about nutrition? I grew up um,
did you follow crazy diet?
I grew up doing the grace of diet with
my uncle Carlos. Could you explain that?
Basically men, the dye to be the
foods that you combined, right?
Some foods. When you make that
combination you're not going to get what?
Expecting from the food and that's
how we learn. I eat a lot of fruits,
lots. I don't drink juices
in where I make my own juice.
That's the only way you can have
a proof that is actual fresh,
fresh and juice. Right. And if
you then very rarely I eat meat,
fish and chicken and a Turkey more
often than red meats. I remember,
I don't remember last time. It's been
awhile, but it's basically fruits.
He's my, I love it.
But Pie in the morning,
cream cheese and honey and late at night,
sometimes watermelon juice in Tapioca.
I don't know if people know what Tapioca
is. Sure, yeah. Tapioca pudding. Yeah.
Not the pudding. You make.
Looks like a Tortilla.
You make that in a pan and it's really
healthy. Yeah, I was show you how to do.
Yeah, it's, it's like a powder.
It's like a brute and they
shredded the roots in 'em and you,
you put in a,
in a pan and as the paint gets hit
it looks like a Tortilla and Dan's,
then you put a cream cheese and it's
thousands times health in any kind of
breads. You've eaten a life. Hmm.
I mean things that are good for your body,
but basically fruits are
my, my main thing. Well,
you're always burning off so
much energy. Let's do the things.
Jujitsu burns off so much energy and if
it ended the lifestyle you have, you,
you burn more than you eat, you're
gonna keep your weight. Four,
I weight the same painful in the
past 10 years, the same weight.
Go up two pounds, go down two pounds,
three pounds, go down five pounds.
You take any supplements
I take. Uh, I take Maca,
tumeric pounder and mixing all those juice
that I make as a more like preventive
things. And if it denti learn,
sometimes I'm going to train
harder tomorrow, I'm going
to eat some carbs today.
The carbs will become a
lot of energy tomorrow.
My training and you basically little
things that you learn. But for me,
the main thing is to stay
healthy. Right? There we go.
I don't remember last time we sick. No,
really? I don't remember this time. Wow.
People have headaches. Why have a
headache many ways or have a headache?
You're not drinking enough water or
you need too much sugar on that mean
something that you're consuming
right now gives you headache.
And what about a post workout recovery?
Do you use sauna or ice bath or
anything, anything like that? Man,
the sound is a must. Yeah, I mean I love
it. I see you put a lot of [inaudible].
It's a must so eliminates so much and
your body's always pure and clean.
I love my apps on South Jacuzzi.
Therefore I dunno an hour and
just forget about life. Yeah,
she was brand new after then you have a
lot of things that you should do as to
keep the longevity of us to be able
to do what we want to do and that stay
healthy. It's a main thing. You
stay hiking, stay close to nature,
brief trying to breathe good
air. It's pretty hot in la, but
yeah, you go up in the mountains,
man. You feel like, Whoa,
it's even in your mind.
You already changed the whole thing of
a then that's basically stay healthy.
I, how can I teach what?
Tell my students to do.
Some people I'm not doing right.
It's like you go to the gym,
have two different coaches, one that
looks healthy and the one that is,
it's pretty big. Which
one are you going to pick?
The one that knows how to
get the way he is. Yeah.
When you see guys that start letting
themselves go and getting big and fat and
it's like, it's very
disappointing. Yes, it is.
I give a hard time to a lot of people
that I know, friends that that goes a man.
It's not what you say is what you've
been doing. Yeah. And now, Oh,
don't do this. Then you're doing what
kind of a tomorrow by an example.
Yeah. People get tired. They
get lazy. Uh, yes, but man,
you,
you chose the wrong job to be lazy
and now you're martial artist.
You can be lazy as a
martial artist right now,
do something to seen in the desk and
don't do nothing then that's I understand.
But uh, you're doing the martial
arts and you get lazy. Now he can't.
You become in a way, an
example for a lot of people.
And that's why I make people do
what you do. Yeah, there's no,
it's not an option. It's not an
option to become [inaudible] at all.
And as soon as I see
someone who is doing that,
who becomes lazy and becomes
fat, I just don't, it's,
it's unfortunate. You know,
it's unfortunate you're
making a mistake. I try,
I try to understand and sometimes
I don't. I said, look man, again,
you chose the wrong line
of work. Yeah, they, me,
you're telling me that you don't like
what you do cause you feel like what you
do, you're not going to be
the way you are right now.
And it's a Juju to working for you now,
which should be working
right now more than ever.
Well that's one of the great
things about you and my brothers.
You've always been a great example and
you've always been a person who leads by
example by the way, the things you say,
but more importantly by
the things you do for sure.
And I know that a lot of in a,
I think we learned through the years
that what you say and what you do will
affect a lot of people out there and
especially now in the social media,
get so many great inputs for people that
I have no idea who they are. Like, oh,
thank you for this. Thank you for that.
Thank you for you to put a good quote
out there. I think those little things,
uh,
have an impact in hours
in a lot of people and a,
I can't forget that and
man, I love what I do.
I never had that job.
They have a works and now I train
Jujitsu and the amazing things,
they give me money to lose you
shit. They pay me to do this.
Like I can't be. Thank you. Then
they know never had it. You,
you have a great life. You
make friends everyday. Yeah.
And now you make friends
every day and you kind of,
I able now to help people just
with something that you say.
Um,
sometimes I have a higher belt students
or even lower belt students that show up
for training. And I learned that
with one store. My uncle told me
he, Uncle Carl is he and he
used to leave it there. And uh,
and uh, back in those days he observed
a lot of things in uh, he has, uh,
it was a time that in braze you have
a lot of cock fighters and he has his
regular rooster. Then he said, man,
I'm going to make him money
if he's rooster. I said, okay,
and I'm going to see how long
the rooster actually fights.
And when I noticed the time, how long
he fights, every time he's fighting,
I'm going to get the
real, the cock fight it,
stop moving him out and the
rooster think he's winning.
He's been doing that for awhile.
Then he realized the rooster can only
stay in the fight for two minutes.
After two minutes he run.
Then he goes to arena and challenge
anybody there with his rooster.
It was not made for fight to fight in one,
therefore one minutes
and they bet the money.
And for one minute the
rooster get beat up,
but fought for one minutes did not run.
Then one minute up he got his rooster.
Give me them. Oh let it fights and
now I said one minute, the point was,
I have guys that come to my school and
they're not having a good day and I can't
tell that by looking to their face and
I'm start training them and I let them
give me a hard time and I go like,
man, what's wrong with you today?
You kicked my butt today and I can see
the change that made than that person.
And I use that to train a lot of
my students. I'll give one example.
Our friend Eddie, when he was, before
he fired Tyler, when he called me in,
he wasn't in the best of his game and
I know his could be an amazing on the
beginning, prohibits anybody to
give him a hard time or anything.
As he started building up. Then towards
the end the say man kick his butt.
He was so good and
confident. After few months,
nobody could even get close to the
nothing to him. Said, man, you ready?
You ready for a fight?
But on the beginning,
this was my way to work out his
psychological to build him up.
He wasn't in the best shape.
He was in training, said no,
you can't train to fish tune
as everybody does what you do.
You're going to find somebody
who doesn't do what you do.
When a train of people that
do what the other guy do.
And here we are in three months,
we've made him a monster and he
did what he did in his fight.
We're using the same idea of my uncle
telling me his story to make you start
believing and towards the end
that other guys, man get him.
Nobody could get even close. Isn't that
funny? How much of it is psychological?
Cause when you're are tired
but you start doing well,
all of a sudden you have energy. It's
all in your mind. And one of the things,
uh, I tried to remember
who said that in uh,
we grew up in the fighting world.
Lauer's seeing summarized will she do in
the war and have a lot of good quotes.
And one of them was, um, whenever we
think you're tired, your opponent is debt.
I was remember that until
today. I remember a yellow belt.
One of my cousins told me
that, man, when you're tired,
you're pointing these dead that keeps
you going. Your opponent is dead,
he's dead and he's, he's
way more tired than you are.
That's the time you have to push
instead of trying to conserve. No.
Now push for what? If you're tired and
he's not. This is, this is the mindset.
Then Jujitsu gives you the tools
but makes you never give up.
You can be tired and we all going to
be tying the fight, that's for sure,
but you not going to give up.
How important do you think it is to do
additional conditioning other than just
taking classes?
If you want to go and participate in a,
in an event that tournament
training, dishes you to train today,
you're going to do well. If
you want to win the tournament,
then you have to do more.
You have to work out.
You have to do your physical because
that hour involves if your mindset,
a lot of people they get nervous
because they feel that already.
Do you ever think that you'll have a
Jujitsu school that also has weights and
cardio equipment and things like that
and maybe even classes to help supplement
Jujitsu training?
I think I'll be a dream school for sure
because a lot of people do not realize
how beneficial that would be
for them in general. Right?
Not only for Jujitsu because
I keep telling people now is put them in
their minds for them to get better and
believe in themselves, but when they do,
those things are challenged themselves.
If you challenge yourself every day,
you're going to bring the
best of you every day.
You should do the same thing every day.
You already know what's going to happen.
I never challenge a shelf. You're going
to bring something better and better.
You're going to grow more inciting
and stop believing so much more.
That capability that you have, that
would be a dream school. I don't know.
Any school that has like
a real comprehensive gym
strength and conditioning gym
attached to a Jujitsu school to school.
I don't know any martial art MMA
places do and they may places. Yeah,
like all those big gyms. Yeah,
but a lot of things like sometimes someone
may ask me and my thought above was
this,
when you go to MMA gym and I
think today the specific for MMA,
I mean they train enough grappling for
MMA. They train enough punching for MMA,
which is amazing, but it's like
you're going to a hospital,
you go, they have a general doctor,
but if you need a specialist and got to
go to the school that is specific for
that purpose striking or she she to
even though now the biggest ones,
Jim's out there, they have
the best instructors of
anything all together. Right,
like American top team, right?
They have, yeah. Ricardo Laborio,
they had the best grappling
culture could have the wrestling,
but not all the schools are like
that. Right. That's a rare one.
It's very challenging because of sometimes
the ego among the instructors shore
who the fight is going
to listen to, right?
You get a lot of Jujitsu fighters and
start training with strike and coach and
the striking coach has them
convinced that they're a Stryker.
And I think the biggest challenge for the
MMA guys is when is the right time for
me to transition from standing to
the ground or the ground to standing.
And that's the ones that find
the right momentum to do that.
They're the ones that are winning.
And I know my uncle Hila said,
man, sooner or later they're going
to get your number. I mean that's,
they made me world very hard for it to
retire it without and when is the right
time to retire? Right? Yeah.
It's hard to figure out for many,
many fighters now, it's
a lot of the things,
maybe money issues or maybe I
didn't want to give up being famous.
A lot of things involve when I
should retire. Like now. Well,
we've been around for a long time and
we've seen a lot of fighters fight long
past where they should have retired.
That's when they can get hurt really bad.
Yeah. And see that's when
the, the injury can be
resting, be with him for a
very long time. Yeah. It's,
does it bother you when you see that?
Like particularly like older fighters
getting knocked out? Man, for me,
I think the people surround
them should be say, hey, yeah,
enough is enough to know.
And um, I hope all of them,
and I think the way these two days,
everyone is able to make good for their
lives with say enough money that they
can live well. Not all
of them are fortunate.
That's why they have to keep
fighting as much as they can.
But it's a very challenging, I think he's,
I'll have to understand his a short
career. You don't have 20 years fighting.
You have to understand is
my body can take this much,
but after a certain point, many in
you can get hurt really bad. Um,
just so everybody knows on the wall,
the studio right there does John Jack
Machado's coral belt right there on that
wall in the studio. It's prominently,
man, you gave me that. I only made,
I only made 10 of those. One of them
was right there. And my brother and I,
all four, I gotta be for a
special person. Joe Hogan. Man,
it's awesome. Well thank
you for everything man.
Thank you for teaching me Jujitsu.
Thank you for being such a great leader
and a role model and just thanks for
being here brother. I really
appreciate you. So Pedro,
thank you for having me here and now
I can. People don't keep asking, hey,
why don't you go to seed, you're
holding your tongue SCG Haggadah time.
And I think it a great
pleasure for me to be here.
Amazing to see the transformation.
And I think in the mixed martial arts
world, in the martial arts world,
how important was to have someone like
you that knows what you're talking about.
Cause I remember the
first few days of UFC, uh,
please UFC understand Joe Hogan was much
bigger than UFC and I think you've see
reach out to a point like that to have
someone like you pushing and you have so
many people that loves you, that
follows you. And the UFC was,
is your device of UFC and now, and don't
get me wrong, those guys out there,
but uh,
when you are talking and you have all
those may fights there is very different
than when you see the
other guys talking about,
because I know the involvement that you
have in a martial arts and the knowledge
that you have. And it's
way too good to be here.
Men in all this specimen years
see the amazing journey to follow.
You see you're getting
bigger and bigger and uh,
be able to sit there from
the beginning is amazing.
Well thank you. And I promise
I'll be training soon.
Soon as his knee feels better, I'll
be back. Um, and uh, in Tarzana,
that's your main school. The Malibu one
unfortunately was affected by the fires,
but Jay is now teaching somewhere
else in the valley. Right.
What was he teaching? I think we,
we have a lot affiliation squares around
here and we have one in Chatswood.
We have one in, that's where J J Basie
goes. He goes there on Fridays. Yeah,
it's the kings. I'll have the
women's combat sports. Yes. Yeah.
And your gym.
The Machado Jujitsu Academy
is in Tarzana. And, uh,
you could find it online.
Yeah, it would be.
I was 27 years and now we're probably
going to be moving around the area for
something that we need more space.
I'm fortunate and fortunate the same.
Fortunately the know it up
[inaudible] to this podcast. Uh,
we see it. Yeah. That's going
to be even more fucking crazy.
Anything that comes out at you. Hogan
gets, I love you again, Porsche. Well,
listen, you have the best fucking school
I've ever been to in the world. And a,
it's a beautiful environment and it's
a brotherhood and sisterhood and that's
one of the best things about it is how,
how much it is like family over there.
It's like everyone who trains with you
has the US utmost respect for you and the
way you are and the way you treat people.
It rubs off on everybody. You really,
genuinely do. Make people a
better person. Thank you, sir.
Now she'll be back soon on the mat. All
right, my brother [inaudible] thank you.
Bye everybody.
[inaudible]
[inaudible].