The joe rogan experience.
Well,
here's the whole thing about the
holistic stuff for me and it's sort of
the,
you know,
the wisdom of the Orient and all that
kind of bullshit.
To me it's like this,
if you don't have a real problem,
then it'll cure whatever your non real
problem is.
If your real problem,
it's just some sort of fatigue that's
based on depression or d or based on
something that's going on emotionally in
your life.
Basically it's living in your head,
but you say,
oh my joints ache and I have trouble
getting out of bed and I give you a
magic pill that has a little bit of
whisker of the cat and it then that'll
work on you.
Now if you got a real problem,
I do a podcast with a guy named Brian.
Brian has a tumor on his brainstem and
he's got a real problem that's a
different problem and he takes
medication that stops the growth of
that.
If that tumor,
it was experimental at the time,
but if that tumor grows,
then he's dead within six months and he
started years old.
So when you have a tumor on the base of
your spine or the top of your spine and
the base,
your brain,
that's an operable whisker of the cat
and the fucking hair,
the newt
is not going to fucking heel that shit
for you
rhino horn for,
right,
right.
No,
that doesn't work.
If you have a real problem,
that's the best combination.
Like the best comparison rather is Rhino
Horn versus Cialis,
right?
One of them,
you know,
only works in your mind and you're like,
Whoa,
I feel more viral.
And the other one gives you a steel rod
and your pants for a solid day.
Right?
You have a choice whether you want to go
with Voodoo or that little blue thing.
Well,
the Rhino Horn should be a strap on
Rhino Horn.
You should get the whole horn.
Forget about grinding it up into a
fucking powder and putting in your
teeth.
Just give me the whole fucking horn.
I'll put,
uh,
I'll put a,
you know,
Bob bicycle inner tube around it.
Wrapper once around the Pauls and nail
over the fucking horn.
Could you imagine
how horrible it would be if men had hard
ons all the time,
like a horn.
It wasn't a biological process that you
had to like engage in your head.
All factors have to be right and
anything that's wrong,
fear,
boner shuts down,
drunk debono shuts down.
All these things happen.
Your bonus shuts down the complex
biological process.
That is the erection.
If we just had a rhino horn and we could
just fuck all the time,
what a wreck it would be on earth.
Everyone would have callous dicks.
We'd have like caked calluses all around
the outsides of our dicks.
Dude.
You know all these places instead of
Manny petty places,
places that would remove the cows is so
you could enjoy pleasure with you dick.
And I'm going to step up your
apocalyptic boner future nightmare
scenario.
I'm going to fucking turn one up to 11
then imagine if there were bone
poachers.
Uh,
and they're like,
Hey,
some guy and uh,
Japan wants to make some soup at a
Rogan's cock cause he thinks it's going
to make his cock harder.
Wow.
Rogan's a virile guy send to the MMA.
So the next thing you know,
you've got to look,
you're looking over your shoulder
because there's some dude and you don't
know if he's a game warden or she's on
your side or their side,
but every time the sun goes down,
you've got to worry about the cock
poachers.
Could you imagine there is no way to
grow your duck could like,
could you imagine if the only way to
grow your Dick would be sucking dicks?
You'd have to run around and suck as
many dicks as possible to get your dick
bigger,
but it didn't work.
So girl,
when you know you pull your pants up,
she'd look at your deck and she would
know for a fact,
wow,
that's a great dick.
But this guy most likely sucked a lot of
Cox to get that Dick so big.
Right.
Well then you'd have to explain that
that's just a sort of born this way.
God's gift.
Your Dad and Grandpa have huge Cox.
They never suck.
Cock.
Maybe when you wouldn't want to protest
that much,
but we'll have to lie about it a little
bit.
I don't know any builders and steroids.
I don't know if the chick would a assume
that,
but it would be an interesting thing to
find out a survey of straight guys,
which is if you could grow your cock by
sucking cock,
would you be in and down for that?
It would be like how much does it grow
too?
Oh yeah.
[inaudible] Holy Shit.
There'd be a long negotiation about
swallowing,
about length,
about our we metric or standard.
Here we go and millimeters.
We going by the inch.
How do we do it?
I always say this and it was,
everyone talks about,
you know your Dick,
your Dick size.
You measure the Dick caddy.
Measure that Dick.
I say this,
it should be standardized.
You measure your cock this way.
You,
you heard it on Joe Rogan's show once
and for all.
Okay.
The official way to do it,
use a cloth measuring tape,
center of the anus,
watts.
Hear me out.
Center of the anus once around the balls
to just pass the tip.
Just pass the test.
That's the official way I measure my
cock and I think it should be a standard
that's um,
that's very generous of you.
That's the way you mess your car.
I've heard these supposed to measure
from the bottom and I think that's
ridiculous.
Nobody knows [inaudible] don't cheat it
back.
Go Center once around the balls just
passed the tip.
Let me ask you another thing,
Joe Cocker related.
Okay.
Tell me down with this.
I,
I've,
I've given this a lot,
a lot of thought,
a lot more thought and then I'm really
comfortable admitting,
but I had this idea where we do a water
displacement test on every guy over 18
your hard cock into a graduated cylinder
filled to the top with water through
just a very thin sheet of like stainless
steel,
lower you down and we literally see how
much water's displaced by year.
Tumescent cock.
Hmm.
Okay.
Now this factors in girth and length and
everything else.
This is so water should be a volume
thing.
This is water displacement.
Okay?
Once we do that,
we do it for every male in America over
the age of 18 you then are issued a
windbreaker.
That windbreaker has your ranking on it,
not how much water you displaced,
not how big your cock is.
But out of,
let's say there's a 100 million males
that are over the age of 18 and the
United States,
what place you come in,
number one,
that'd be a pretty fucking good
windbreaker to have.
Yeah.
You'd also,
anybody was in the top 10 would be
making the fucking rounds on the late
night shows and each year,
you know,
there's two,
three,
5 million guys turning 18 it all has to
be recalibrated every year.
I mean,
you may see getting bigger if you saw a
graph of how big dicks used to be in the
20s and 2000 well,
you know,
just if,
if,
if people are getting better,
I'm sure.
Proportionately we are.
So the point is this,
you may be number one,
but there's always some guy turning 18 I
mean there's a thousand guys just turned
18 the time I said that,
and they're getting tested and there's a
big reveal and for one month everybody's
got to wear that windbreaker wherever
they are.
And you know,
look,
we're going to wear that thing for a
month.
If you're,
that's the rule.
2 million,
999 billion.
It's starting at 100 million.
Yeah.
I mean you can be sure somebody is going
to be last.
Well,
there's three,
150 million,
300 million people in the country,
so 150 million plus minus wrapped,
but then you got to go 18 year old then
after that,
but let's just call it 100 million
people.
Okay.
And for my money,
the number one dude is going to do all
the late night shows.
And the last dude,
he's going to make the rounds to see
that one guy that has the biggest cock
in the world.
Apparently he went to the Tsa,
uh,
like he was wearing sweatpants and they
accused him of trying to smuggle
something.
The guy's got a giant hog.
Yeah.
Apparently it was like all over these,
uh,
news reports and white guy too.
Pasty looking white guy.
Yeah.
I think his name is Jonah Falcon or
something like that.
That's,
that's what I heard.
I think I saw a documentary or
something.
Do you remember in the porn days,
and it's not saying that John Holmes
doesn't have a big Dick.
He definitely has a big Dick.
But remember when we were kids,
we'd watch porn.
If you saw John Holmes,
you'd be like,
holy,
that's a big Dick.
Joanna Falcon.
So sad.
Frisked by TSA by the way,
don't believe it.
Ask me who the vice president is.
I'm like,
ah,
ah fuck man.
I didn't know it's going to be a history
quiz,
but big Cox,
I'm fucking your man.
John Holmes used to have a giant deck
right now that's like pretty standard.
Like there's a lot of those guys with
big giant dicks.
Actually the black ones,
I don't,
well I got a theory about big giant
black dicks.
Thank God,
dovetails nicely into my windbreaker
right there.
I got a theory about that.
Um,
and it,
and it is the following.
First off,
how dare you be?
Smirch a good name of Johnny Wad home.
Cause he did have a big deck.
It was very nice.
Still Big by today's big Dick Stand and
no doubt.
But uh,
as far as black guys having big dicks in
porn,
I think that's a form of porn racism.
Hmm.
And I'll tell you why.
I think if you show up onto a porn set
is a black guy with a medium sized cock
fair to Midland.
You know,
you man,
I got six and a half inches here.
They send you a packet.
They're like,
we don't need black guys were small
cocks willingly black guys with big Cox.
We can take a white guy with a medium
cock,
but we can't take a black guy.
Well,
why bother getting fucked by a black guy
if the guy's got a medium cock?
You see what I'm saying?
I think they're discriminated against.
So I think we think the only huge cock
we've seen is in porn.
It's on black guys.
They won't let average size cocked black
men in an I dream of a future where my
children can watch pornography and see
black guys with medium sized Cox,
you know,
balls deep in a junky coked up blinds
here.
Here.
Yeah.
That's,
that's it.
That's a future.
Yeah.
Okay.