The joe rogan experience.
Do you watch those movies
and shake your head?
I like him.
I just knew I liked science fiction,
you know?
Right.
You know,
so yeah,
I didn't sit there.
I grew up with star wars.
That was my,
when I was nine years
old or some finances.
Yeah.
I'm not having this.
I did,
I did a,
an argument with Neil,
the grass tight,
not an argument,
but a debate with him about lightsabers
ones cause I claimed that they're
physically the in
principle there possible.
Um,
and he was trying to say that they aren't,
but they are what did have to loop back
around cause the light's not continuing
to like the fact that it goes to
a certain distance and pauses.
We don't have a mirror or something,
I guess.
Yeah.
Something that's true to be the end of it.
Right.
That's true.
So it wouldn't,
it'd be a different kind of light.
So the only point was
making is that photons,
particles of light can
bounce off each other.
So we see that in really high energy
experiments in particle accelerators.
We can collide photons together.
So my point was a bit of a
pedantic physicist one but he's,
cause he,
it is true that light can bounce off.
It can hit light but very,
very high energy.
But when they press that
button to a certain distance,
I wasn't,
that's engineering.
I agree with you.
The distance thing,
I agree mass to it.
Right.
So as you're swinging it around,
you wouldn't have the
leverage of a long thing.
So why not make it really long?
Cause it wouldn't be
difficult to swing around.
Like you could stab someone
with a lightsaber a mile away.
That's true.
Well I shoot a laser in it.
Yes.
Like why,
why make it so short?
You have to swing,
you got to be close to
hitting a person with it.
That's a silly,
silly design.
You are picking holes
correctly in the engineering.
Part of my,
the only point I was
making is that physics is,
that we shutting is quite interesting
is it light can bounce off light.
So,
but it would have to do,
it would have to be something that
causes it to stop at the very end.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Which would be,
you're right,
you'd have a merit,
but he wouldn't look cool with it if
there was a no kind of thing within,
which drives me crazy about star
wars is not the light sabers.
It's the lasers when
they're shooting the guns.
So I'm like,
why can I see that when
I can't see bullets?
This is,
we're supposed to be way
faster than a bullet.
Yeah.
Like easy to see this
because it's like George,
you could duck,
you can get out of the way.
Those things,
they really slow.
I'm so angry.
I feel like this is so dumb.
I could go warp speed in this Millennium
Falcon and travel the speed of light,
but for whatever reason,
these lasers are so slowly you
could duck out of the way of them.
That's so dumb.
And he's not only star wars is,
it's everything.
Uh,
the epigenome is quite difficult.
Different.
The epigenome is that the structure
of how the DNA is looped around.
If you look at the chromosome,
you're not seeing the gene Amil.
It really basically saying epigenome and
what w what I think is causing aging is
not that you're losing the DNA structure,
you're not having mutations.
You're actually changing the epigenome,
which is the,
the reader of the genes.
To put another way,
a compact disc,
okay.
Uh,
for the young audience,
uh,
come back.
Discs are little things
we used to put music on.
But anyway,
these are,
these are digital information of course.
And the reason we switched to digital
in the first place is that it's very
copyable and it doesn't wear out.
Whereas a,
a cassette tape,
you know,
people our age know that if you
try to copy that a thousand times,
there's not much left at the end.
So that the compact disc
inflammation is the genome.
The epigenome is the reader of the CD,
that little laser that goes around.
And what I think is causing aging is
not the loss of the digital information,
but it's the reader at the analog pot.
And that's like a cassette
tape that eventually runs out.
So what we,
what's going on really is that your
cells are losing the ability to read the
right genes the way they
did when you were 20.
And that's basically noise,
informational noise
that gathers over time.
Um,
and so what we end up with when we're
80 is a compact disc or DVD that
scratched.
So the reader cannot read the right genes,
the right time,
and the cells become dysfunctional.
Now what we're working on is how do you
Polish that CD or that DVD to get that
information back again?
And if you could do that,
I think that's really the
best way to reset your age.
And I,
we haven't published it yet,
but,
uh,
we're working on ways to
actually reset that genome,
actually get back the information
that we once had when we were 20.
So what is happening to the epigenome
when you're going through those scanners?
Well,
so what we found is the biggest
disruptor of the epigenome is,
uh,
a broken chromosome and DNA break.
And I don't know about scanners,
that's just an abundance of caution.
But an x ray will damage your DNA,
no question.
Um,
even going out in the sun,
we'll do a bit of that.
And we think that the cells reaction to
that break having to unwrap the DNA from
its Chromatin,
we call it,
and uh,
and then rewrap it is what eventually
disrupts the ability to read the right
gene at the right place.
So Dna damage is essentially
a s a little scratch on,
on the DVD.
And that accumulates over time.
A lot of people are not willing to learn
how to do that because they want the
fast track out,
take a drug and pass out.
That is the thing,
right?
They just want a pill.
Yeah.
It's very unfortunate that
those things exist in that,
that that sort of thinking is,
you know,
it's reinforced.
Yeah.
It's encouraged.
In fact,
you know,
all these ads and all these
doctors and different people,
well if you have a hard time sleeping,
I'll just write your prescription.
And then next thing you know,
and I mean you look at the animal world,
like they self medicate,
they'll use clay for
parasites and you know,
dogs leak grass for stomach issues.
And you know that I guess birds now are
putting like nicotine and cigarettes and
their nests cause there's some of
benefit to that and you see animals
self-medicating,
you see our ancestors using
everything from you know,
cannabis to Ceylon cinnamon to you know,
all sorts of different derivatives
for thousands of years.
So it's not like supplementation or self
medication or the or the whole creation
of pharmaceuticals is something that's
unnatural or not acceptable human
activity.
But once you start to use it as a crutch,
I think that's where you
run into issues like once,
once you deny the human body's ability
to be able to heal itself or to be able
to decrease stress on its own,
you begin to rely on
these exogenous chemicals.
I think that's where you
start playing with fire.
The idea that you're
going to be this balance,
chilled out person and
still be a fucking world.
Smasher good luck with that.
I'm the farthest thing
from relaxed and chill.
You know,
I try to learn now,
but,
but when you're training
and when you look,
there's a mindset that's
required to beat the best guys,
and it's not the same mindset
that's required to get good to get,
you could get good and be a chilled out,
relaxed person.
Like say you want to be
a black belt in Jujitsu,
that's totally possible.
You can be really good.
People can go,
Hey,
look at Mike Mann.
Mike has got great triangle.
Watch them raw.
Wow,
he's really good.
But if Mike wants to be the
motherfucker have motherfuckers,
you better be crazy.
You know,
you better be God damn crazy.
You better be like Mike
Tyson when he was young.
Yup.
Be those Michael Jordan's
you're talking about,
they're always thinking about it.
Roy Jones Jr yes.
All of those guys.
You gotta be a fucking crazy person.
Absolutely.
Roy Jones Jr played a professional
basketball game the day of his fight.
Played a guy in a basketball game,
did not have competitive.
Do any.
Just an athlete.
Yeah.
I mean,
I just don't think there's any other way.
I think if you're going to win a race,
you're going to red line
the engine because I just
don't see how you're going to
beat the best guy.
Everybody is trying their best.
This is the thing.
There's so much going on there.
I mean you could have like a really
good coach so you have an advantage.
Technically you could have a really
good group of guys you train with,
so you have an advantage in
the environment that you're
training in and there's
a lot of inspiration.
But if you're not a fucking psychopath,
good luck.
I know my friend Sam Harris was trying
to get you guys to ban Donald Trump.
He was saying if the fall,
your terms of service,
I just did a podcast with
him actually as well.
It should come out today or tomorrow.
He's uh,
he's a,
he's a fascinating guy.
Sam Harris.
I love him to death.
But what he was trying
to do was like saying,
hey,
he's threatening nuclear war.
Like he's saying,
Hey Korea,
my bombs are bigger than your bombs.
Like,
what else does the guy
have to do to get your,
to remove them from the platform?
When you guys saw that,
what,
what was your reaction to that?
Was there an internal discussion about
actually banning the president of United
States?
Well,
so,
so two things there.
One,
it was a context that presidents of this
country have you similar language in
different mediums.
They use it on radio,
use it on television.
It's not just through Twitter.
And even if you were looking at,
you were to look at the
presidency of Obama.
It wasn't exactly the same tone
in this exact same language,
but there were threats
around the same country.
And we have to take that
context into consideration.
So the second thing is that we need the
most controversial aspect of our rules
and our terms of services.
Probably this clause around public
interest in newsworthiness where,
um,
powerful figures are public figures,
might,
uh,
be in violation of our terms of service.
But the tweet itself
is of public interest.
Yes,
there should be a conversation around it.
And that is probably the thing
that people disagree with the most.
Um,
and where we have a
lot of internal debate,
but we also have some pretty hard lines.
If we had a global leader,
including the president of United States,
make a violent threat
against a private individual,
we would take action.
We,
we always have to balance that with like,
is this a,
is this something that the
public has interest in it?
And I,
I believe generally the answer is yes.
It's not going to be in every case,
but generally the answer is yes,
because we should see how our
leaders think and how they act.
Okay.