He's like Metro pcs because I see all
those commercials that they do.
We live right now.
We're live.
We're on the air.
Misha tate were on the air.
I just had to let me take note of the
world was flat.
She didn't know that the man has been
holding us down and fucking with us and
given us bad information that satellites
are bullshit and that the earth doesn't
rely on gravity,
but it uses electromagnetism to make
sure things get stuck.
Where is this coming from?
The world.
The world does a lot of people out there
in the world that are waking up.
Do you know what being woke is?
Are you aware of being woke or you're
not?
You don't know about being woke.
Jamie's woke stay,
woke,
stay.
Well,
you got to stay.
Woke.
Stay woke.
So people think that the earth is flat.
Yes.
You can all use also use wokeness as you
could use it as like a.
You could say like,
I have wokeness.
You know what I'm saying?
Like you just because you're just
because of the UFC bantamweight champion
does not equal your wokeness wokeness
you're woke bullshit.
But the man has been the earth being
round each round or its flattest fuck,
the earth is flat and chem trails or the
government spray in the skies and uh,
there is no gravity.
Here's square and stationary earth.
Was this a new one?
One of the parts of the theory you think
about Kim.
Kim chose a real.
Is that what you're saying?
Well,
I don't know.
I kind of wonder what they are and what
are they?
That's a good question.
The problem is when people take that and
then they go right to conspiracy
question.
I'm not a conspiracy theorist,
but I have questions like I want to know
what they are.
When a jet engine flies through the sky
and the jet engine encounters
condensation in the atmosphere,
it creates an artificial clouds.
It's not an artificial cloud.
It's an actual cloud.
And the cloud is a direct reaction to
the jet engine changing the temperature
of the air in the atmosphere.
It is scientifically proven.
It's repeatable.
They could do it over and over again.
That's why when you see those things in
the sky,
those things exist.
When the jet engines passed through the
condensation and it changes the
temperature and then they slowly fade
away or not depending upon how much
moisture is in the atmosphere.
Some places do it and other ones don't.
Well,
because some planes are at different
altitudes and some point,
you know how clouds exist in some
places,
but they don't exist in other places.
There's people,
well maybe there's no connotation.
Vegas.
I was like,
there's flights coming in all the time
and you watch a steady stream coming in
and none of them have it,
but then like the little like,
I don't know,
they're like small.
I don't know if they're small planes are
not commercial planes.
The little ones.
Those are the ones that make all the
chem trails,
so I'm like,
does that.
Well,
they chem trails.
I don't even know if I'm technically
saying it right now.
I don't know what they are.
What do they call them?
They call them contract.
That's the real.
The real like if you ask a scientist,
they calm cantrell's.
If you ask conspiracy conspiracy,
people that call him chem trails because
they think they're spraying chemicals in
the air,
this is something that I had to like
deeply study for this show that I did.
Cultural questions about this for a long
time.
I've heard so many.
I've heard obviously most of the
conspiracy part of it,
everybody hears about it.
Everybody here is.
I've heard that they're trying to like
control the weather with it somehow by
putting gas.
Part of the problem is that they are
trying to control the weather in
different parts of the world.
They spray,
they do what's called cloud seeding,
but cloud seeding is very different than
what you're seeing when you see these
artificial clouds with cloud seeding is
they'll spray a certain type of chemical
into in into the atmosphere that will
create rain and they do it in Abu Dhabi.
Abu Dhabi,
they actually do it every every week.
They do it once,
so they've done it like 52 times a year
and it makes rain.
Yeah.
That's been going on for a long time,
but that's very different than these
artificial clouds that are being created
by jets.
That's just a side effect for you
though.
Like the artificial travel,
artificial jets or the rain?
Rain.
Well it's silver.
Iodine I think and some other stuff that
they find like find a breathe in and
stuff.
Yeah,
I'm sure it's not any better than jet
fuel.
It's burning in your sky above your
child.
That's the real problem.
Yeah,
and the gas drive in here and all that
gets people that live near airplanes or
airports rather.
They have a significantly higher rate of
lung infections and lung diseases and
lung disorders like adjusting like how
far.
Now I'm thinking about how far I live
from the Vegas airport.
It takes me like 20 minutes to get
there.
Fifteen minutes.
Is that too close?
I'll be okay.
Well I think we're all fucked.
Yeah,
we're all fucked.
We're all breathing and under the same
flat.
Exactly.
Under the same flat earth.
Well that's one of the problems with the
whole chem trail theory.
Like don't they live down here too?
They're spraying this guy's like,
what are they trying to do and the
either the ideas there is either weather
modification or that they're trying to
change our behavior that some people
think it's their change.
Like it's,
it's something to do with crops too or
something and they're trying to.
I don't know,
the growing crops in Vegas,
I don't think they grow shit in Vegas.
Tumble weeds,
they probably got it now.
It's probably a lot of pot grown in
vegas probably is.
It used to be so illegal,
like if you went to vegas you have to be
like really careful about having weed,
but now when you drive around they have
these giant weed Dr.
Bill Boards and show.
It's really weird.
It's like
the call one 800 hot babe on one side
and then Dr.
Weed on the other side.
That's a weird place to live,
isn't it?
It is,
but it's,
it's.
I feel like Vegas is kind of what you
make it is whatever you make it.
Like if you want to go down to the strip
and be crazy and be wild and hang out
with all the hooligans that are there
for the weekend,
you can,
but if not,
just live in your little house and go
hike the red rocks and go down to the
lake.
It's pretty barren.
Pretty Ugly Lake.
Honestly.
It came from Washington state,
so I'm used to a lot of greenery.
It's beautiful there and we've got the
San Juan islands and you could go whale
watching and she's gorgeous,
but it reminds me too much.
We have a national rain forest up there
too.
It's beautiful.
Yeah.
I'm a big fan of Washington state.
The rain can fuck with your head,
right?
Yeah.
I couldn't.
I lived there for.
I mean I was 18 before I moved to the
eastern side,
which is very different.
A lot of people don't know this,
so the mountain range divide sustain
half and on the east side,
east side of Washington,
that's super dry.
It's like deserty,
like there's actually tumbleweeds and
sand dunes and all that.
It's completely different.
On the other side of Washington and
moisture comes in from the ocean,
hits the mountains,
rolls back over rains like double duty
on the west side.
And the east side of wash of Washington
is really dry year from spokane,
right?
No,
I'm from Tacoma,
Tacoma,
Compton.
To call it people call it.
That's hilarious.
Yeah.
Yeah,
it is.
It's pretty ghetto.
But I lived on the edge.
It's really big actually.
It's um,
I think if I'm not mistaken,
I should probably know this things,
but I don't pay attention to a lot of
things.
You'll probably find out,
I don't know,
a lot of statistics and stuff.
I'm kind of like,
well it was fly by the seat of my pants,
like whatever's going on.
It's cool.
But I think it's,
it's one of the biggest circumvents the
whitest cities,
like not most populated but like most
area in Washington anyway,
so on.
I live on the very outskirts like near
Puyallup.
So I grew up on like five acres and like
I had some land,
it wasn't like in the heart of it,
but it's a pretty cool place.
So going from there to live in Vegas,
but I guess like as a professional
fighter,
your days are probably so filled with
training and recovery and being like,
how much time do you have actually have
to even be in the city that you're in?
Like none.
None.
I'm in camp really not much.
Maybe on the weekends sometimes.
That's what's nice about it too is you
can go down there and just enjoy comedy
show.
I mean you come through often,
like a lot of acts come through.
Kevin Hart comes through a lot of
musicians,
a lot of concerts.
So it's nice because everyone comes to
you essentially.
You don't have to go travel and see
anyone.
So if you want to just set the cup down
for a minute and take a break from the
chain gang or would it go ride the,
the,
you know,
the big ferris wheel that they have
there,
the on the link,
they want to go ride that or do
whatever,
you know.
Um,
it's nice because there's always so much
going on as long as you stay outside of
it like Henderson or something like
that.
I live in mountains edge.
Um,
so yeah,
for the most part I don't ever even see
this trip unless I'm driving by it.
Like to go visit the UFC offices or
something like that.
Well it's a good place to live as a
professional fighter.
Right?
Because there's a lot of gyms there.
There's a lot of great training there.
This across the board strength and
conditioning and Thai boxing.
One is the home of the UFC so it's nice
to not because there's a lot of
extracurricular things that I get to
take part of because I'm,
I'm local.
I could do a lot more charity things and
with the boys and girls club and you
know,
just going in,
you know,
being a part of the year.
See,
I guess I get to,
I get to do more things.
Yeah.
No,
your life is very different right now
that it was a year ago.
It is.
How crazy is that?
Yeah.
You a year ago you were talking about
like not doing this anymore.
You will.
I've got to figure out what I'm doing
right now.
You're the fucking world champ.
Fricking
one 80.
Yeah.
My,
my career in life,
we couldn't have been different a year
ago than it is now,
you know,
strangers that,
how that can just in an instant,
you just never know.
What does that feel like?
It's like when you wake up in the
morning,
so you have to go to the belts
for real.
I'm happy.
It's um,
it's enlightening.
It's fun.
It's great to be the champ.
I,
I love it.
Honestly.
It's a completely different thing.
It,
yeah.
You know,
a year ago I was so frustrated because,
you know,
when I lost her onto the last time,
I knew I had a lot,
a long road you to,
to work my way back up.
But I thought I had done that and when I
beat Jessica,
I,
it was announced.
It's like,
you know,
this is going to be then the number one
contender eliminator fight.
And then afterwards they were like,
yes it is.
You're going to fight Ronda.
Then I felt like the carpet was kind of
just pulled out from under my feet
because they were like,
just kidding holly.
Holly's fighting.
And they announced it without telling
me.
So that's why I was so upset.
I was like,
I don't take that shit lightly.
Like I was training my ass off already.
I had already reached out to um,
a girl in France,
I can't say her name right.
I think it's like Jeffery,
I don't know some French name,
but she beat Ronda and judo.
So I had already been making plans with
her to train with her and fire over here
and choose changing things.
Then I was like,
I felt like such an ass,
like I feel like an idiot,
like I look like an idiot because here
the announcement was made and I didn't
even know.
So I was kind of upset about that.
But you know,
we talked about and we smoothed things
over and,
and I took it personally at the time,
but I don't think it was meant
personally and it was a business
decision and I understand that,
that at the end of the day that's what
it was and it all worked out.
So
the UFC is in a weird position because
they're both a promoter and sort of a
sanctioning body.
And that's really rare and matter of
fact,
I can't think of any other sport where
that exists.
Yeah.
You know,
they have just this ability to decide
like they'll,
they'll just decide like this person
gets a show.
Like the whole conor mcgregor situation
is a perfect example of that.
Like all of a sudden if he had beat nate
diaz or if he had beaten dos Anjos dos
Anjos didn't get injured and he beat
beat Dosantos you fucking know for sure
they were going to have him fight Robbie
lawler.
Yeah,
for sure.
And they were just going to like,
figure out a way to do something with
145 Palm Tata.
And why wouldn't they do it if there are
business people,
because that's where the money is.
I mean it would have been if he had beat
dos Anjos and then went on and fought
Robbie lawler,
Jesus Christ.
When you talk about like a $5 million
paper view by event,
they'd have to do it.
It would be insane.
But if that was like a sanctioning body,
like you've seen it before in like
boxing,
like someone won't take a mandatory
challenger and they get stripped even
when they just won the title,
it happens all the time.
Like we're a phyto would just win the
title and then they have this mandatory
challenger who nobody knows go fuck that
fight.
I'm going to go fight Canelo Alvarez,
I'm going to fight this guy or that guy.
And then he gets stripped.
Like because there's like five different
sanctioning bodies.
Like boxing is way more of a mess.
So there's like pros and cons to doing
it the way the UFC does it.
But from my point of view of someone
like you,
it's probably much more frustrated.
I don't
know what to expect.
Like you get curve
balls all the time in the UFC.
Don't know what to expect,
you know,
like a lot of people were so pissed off
at me for,
for the Holly Holm,
not having the rematch right away.
But it's like,
it's not,
it's not my choice,
you know,
they have over you because they think
that I like turned it down or I should
have went in there like guns a blazing
for holly and like put myself out on my
shield.
Like,
no,
we have to have the holly rematch.
You guys,
you don't understand.
But um,
you know,
they call me up.
I'm like,
Amanda,
July ninth.
I'm like,
okay,
fuck.
Do you say no?
No you don't.
You can't say no.
So they come up with you like I'm in.
Yeah.
And now you know,
it's like,
dude,
relax.
Most people don't get immediate
rematches in their career.
Like unless you are conor mcgregor or
Rhonda or you know,
someone that's really got a presence,
you don't get an immediate rematch.
Like I didn't when I went back and
strikeforce when,
when I lost to Ronda,
I didn't get into media.
I've never gotten immediate rematch.
My career.
I would have loved to immediately
rematch cat when I lost to her.
But you don't get it.
Sometimes you got to work your way back
up and you know,
hope for the best.
But we will,
I'm sure it will fight each other again.
She's fighting a Valentino Oshun Shanko
now you're going to be in Chicago,
right?
It's going to be on the rumble.
Johnson Glover to sharer card,
which yeah,
that's going to be crazy.
It is.
And they're both South Pas and Stryker's
is going to be interesting.
Tough shit too.
Dog.
So interesting.
She's very like physically strong.
Like the way she fights.
She's very physical.
I think.
I feel like they are kind of both.
I was just watching her fight with
Amanda again.
I think I only got through like the
route and a half before I had to go
because I was doing the Fox Fox show the
other day and we weren't,
we announced the fight with holly.
That's why I was watching.
She shouldn't Genco and um,
she seems like a counter striker too
though.
I was wondering when you get to people
who are counter strikers but elite
strikers,
what happens?
Well,
holly is much more of a kicker and holly
also is like much more fleet of foot so
it's going to be interesting.
But holly's not weak either.
She's very physically strong,
super strong,
it's going to be an interesting and
that's a really good fight.
And for shift Chenko it's super
important.
You know,
she's had a couple pretty good fights in
the UFC,
but like this is the big one is like the
map.
Is it headlining?
Yeah.
So it'd be a big one.
Is that the main event?
So I think that's the same card as
rumble.
Johnson and clover.
I can't imagine that.
That wouldn't be the main event,
but I don't know.
It might be on Fox Fox one.
That's going to be a big job.
It's a,
it's an awesome card period that
Chicago.
Chicago's awesome.
I love Chicago.
Oh my God.
My favorite cities in the world.
Have you ever had molly's cupcakes?
You're going to say molly,
are you really into the cupcakes?
Like you have this nickname cupcake.
Is that real?
What's weird?
So recently,
probably the last month I've been
working with a new sports doctor Dr
Edwards and he's changing my diet,
which is great.
So I've been eating more of a high fat
diet,
Ketogenic Diet and I've been staying
away from a lot of sugars and stuff and
I feel really good.
So I haven't been mowing down the
cupcakes recently.
But um,
in the past I've been known to put down,
you know,
a couple
in the moment you said Ketogenic,
there's thousands of people listening to
this podcast.
And like,
no,
not again because it comes up so often
because I've been doing it for five
months.
I've been eating nothing but that,
that's how we eat,
right.
It's lost like 10 pounds.
Yeah.
Brian's lost so much weight on this
diet.
Like his camp before,
that was a struggle to get the weight
down because it's really big for 1:35,
he gets up to like one 65,
you know,
he can get up to one 70 ish.
Yeah.
Remember when he was making the cut the
first time?
Yeah.
It was hot.
Hard and.
But this one you switched to that,
you know,
with a little bit of carbs.
Obviously if you're an athlete you have
to have some carbs.
Sure.
Do.
Strictly fats and what not,
but anyways,
weight has flown off.
He's way ahead of schedule.
He's doing really good.
So we're pumped about that and I mean
shitloads of fats to and staying lean
and healthy and I feel good.
So like,
do you do what,
what protocol you're following?
Like is it's like 60 percent fat,
30 percent protein,
10 percent carbs.
Like do you need.
No,
I'm not that scientific about it.
I kind of just listen to my body and I
just eat what I feel.
I feel like I've been doing it so long
that I just kind of have a natural
sense.
It's like if I'm hungry then I just
choose to eat something that's more fat
based than something that's the sugary
or our carby like what kind of foods are
you gravitating towards?
So recently I've been so stoked about
liver Mousse,
like yeah,
yeah,
they're delicious.
So if you go to whole foods and you are
the cheese section,
they have these little packages of Moose
liver and they have different flavors
and I got like a truffled one.
I think I ate almost the whole thing in
one sitting,
but they're not that big.
I mean they're like,
you know,
but I mean it's kind of a lot of fat in
the liver is really,
really good for you.
It's got like vitamin D and tons of
vitamin C I guess more than carrots.
Like liver has crazy amounts of vitamin
C,
so it's like a super food.
And my doctor told me,
I'm like,
oh,
whatever.
I tend to like foods more when I know
they're good for me to something like
mentally in my brain just tells me this
is good for you.
You'd like it really
well,
I guess if you train as much as you do,
that does totally make sense.
Yeah.
And beets,
beets,
beets are grade for it.
Yeah.
Beet juice.
Oh yeah.
That sounds fantastic for your beet
juice.
Also,
it mimics things like,
um,
the endurance properties of things like,
a certain mushrooms if you take beats
like rick or rich roll,
who is a endurance athlete,
was saying that,
uh,
he found like significant advantages in
taking beet juice and that like blending
beats and like a Kale shake or something
along those lines really gave him like
an extra boost in training.
Yeah.
This is a little company called love
beets.
I don't know if they're little.
They could be big love beets.
You see a lot of,
a lot of them.
I'm at the whole foods too.
They have like the canopies and um,
how was doing UFC embedded in.
I had beats on my salad and then they
reached out to me like,
oh,
we saw she had beats on her salad.
We want to send her out some beet juice.
Like maybe it was,
maybe it was,
maybe she was having libido actually was
love beets.
And they sent me out this.
Oh man,
this shit is delicious.
It's so good.
And they're the one that's um,
beats and ginger.
They've that,
oh my God,
it's to die for.
I love it.
Anytime you can get like powerful
natural nutrients like and they come in
last two gen kind of like,
I kinda got on that,
that glass drinking out of glass instead
of plastic.
I kind of got on that train a little
bit.
I don't know if you're around that yet.
It's definitely smart.
I mean plastic for sure can leach some
chemical taste it sometimes in the water
and I'm like if I feel like if I can
taste it and our body's made up so much
of water anyways,
so I think with a better water you put
in your body,
it makes more sense.
Right?
For sure.
Well the real issue I think is when
people leave bottles of water,
plastic bottles in their car and they
heat up,
we'll think about how they get
transported.
It's not like they're in a cooler.
Very good point,
you know?
I mean,
you drink,
I'm cold.
If it's cold,
you don't taste the plastic as much so
you,
they sell it to you cold,
he put it in the fridge and you drink
your water bottle.
And you don't really taste it as much,
but if you let it get to room
temperature,
just buying it from the story,
probably you'll taste the plastic.
I wonder if anybody's ever done any
studies where they've taken to arrowhead
water,
Fiji water from the shelf and just test
it and see how much.
Yeah,
that shit is in the actual water itself.
Yeah.
I wonder too,
but I just.
The fact that I can taste it sometimes,
like I think I'll go with glass like
more natural.
It's better for you,
right?
For sure.
So do you eat?
Do you eat a lot of Avocados?
Mct Oil,
coq 100 percent mct oils I put,
I've been digging this or you a tumeric
and curcumin.
Curcumin,
the Dr Rhonda Patrick Show.
Oh my gosh,
you blew my mind.
I've listened that episode like five
times and I still have to go back over
the fine tooth comb and write notes.
I just downloaded the second ones.
I've listened to the first one like five
times.
So I figured I think I got enough of the
information.
Finally.
She's so freaking smart.
And then now I downloaded the one before
the last one,
so I'm about to listen to that one.
Probably on the flight home.
She spooky.
Smart.
Yeah.
So she was talking about all that and my
sports doctors is in complete agreement.
So anyways,
I don't know where I was going with
that.
What did you ask about eating?
Oh,
coconut oil,
um,
curcumin or turmeric and ginger.
I make like a tea in the morning and I
that I like blended up.
So it's frothy and delicious.
Speaking of not eating a lot of sugar
though.
We did.
Um,
I did use on a UFC tonight last night
and then we did tough talks and the kid
Kahleel we had a cupcake eating contest.
Oh No.
Oh my God.
I was wrecked for the rest of last night
because I haven't been eating sugar mad,
you know,
I'm competitive so I'm just going down
these cupcakes.
So they,
they gave me like smaller ones for the
weight class discrepancy.
So yeah,
like,
I know,
but you know what actually it was kind
of a disadvantage that appeal more of
them spend time trying to peel them out.
So I,
I,
I think I ate four and then my sofic is
to shut and it was like,
Eh,
like no more swelling,
another bite.
So I shoved three more in my mouth and
just like held them in the last sense
because I was like shoving them in my
mouth.
So I think it was seven,
but I spit three of them out.
No.
When you say your soft biggest shock,
was it like you couldn't swap,
did you have milk?
I did have milk but there was just too
much.
There wasn't room for milk in my mouth
anymore.
It was just all cupcake.
It was like,
it was hilarious.
The videos on my facebook page if you're
interested in watching,
it was pretty disgusting actually.
What did you feel like after it was
over?
I felt terrible,
honestly.
Like I was like shaking.
I was like,
oh.
It was like,
I feel like I kind of had a gut ache was
like this is a really good,
bad idea.
Isn't that weird that you could have
eaten those things like a year ago?
No problem.
And then I just now for many cupcakes
and I'm feeling like garbage.
I was on the Diet for a long time and
then I had a cheeseburger and a malt.
I got a big ass chocolate malt and I
was.
It was a huge.
It was like that big.
It was all sugar gets you.
I was wrecked.
I laid down on the couch.
It is when you just get used to it.
That's the problem.
And when you're used to it,
your body's seems like,
ah,
this is nothing.
So when people,
oh,
here you are,
who you are eating a cupcake.
My mouth is watch and I'm throwing.
They're counting down.
I'm like,
Oh God.
It's so gross.
Disgusting.
It's terrible.
Like the referee outfit on.
I couldn't.
I have three cupcakes in my mouth.
I know my lips are literally bursting.
Like,
see if this was fear factor we would
have made you swallow it and open your
mouth.
That's the only way accounts would have.
Speaking of fear factor,
I always wanted to do that show.
I used to watch it all the time to talk
to you out of it.
I could eat that disgusting stuff.
You think you could.
I think I could.
Well,
you could probably eat some of it.
I eat some of it.
Really as I asked you,
what was the most disgusting thing that
they made some money.
You think blended stuff is the worst,
like blended bugs and stuff.
When did pancreas and different.
Disgusting like blended the spleens and
there was some and you know what's
really interesting is one of the ways we
made things more disgusting was
expensive cheese.
Like if you go to,
what's it called?
A formal ga for Azure.
Cheesy story,
but go ahead and tell me.
They will go to the Beverly Hills store
that sells like super expensive,
like Primo French cheese and it smells
like donkey Dick.
It's so bad.
You open up the top of it and you go,
what in the fuck is wrong with French
people?
That's my.
That's my disgusting stinky cheese
story.
It was in France the first time I went
to Paris.
It was over Valentine's Day and Brian
and I were on this really beautiful
dinner boat thing and you know,
they bring out all this food and we're
getting for grandma and like whatever,
and they bring out cheese.
I'm a cheese lover.
I love cheese.
I could never give up cheese.
It's the one that I would,
I would venture to say,
you know,
well especially now for
sure I'd picked cheese over cupcakes if
I had to cut something out of my diet by
buy cupcakes.
Like I'm eating,
I'm sticking with the cheese anyways.
They bring this cheese on,
there's three of them.
One is fine.
The other ones like it's a little
stinky,
but I think I'll try.
The other one smelled like a rotting
carcass.
I kid you not,
I believe you.
It smelled like someone ran over
roadkill and then they like.
Then they served it up like two weeks
later after it had been like an
extremely soft.
People eat.
I'm like,
what's wrong?
I was like getting away.
I wouldn't touch with a 10 foot pole was
in beverly hills where we used to send
the people that worked for fear factor
to buy it and they would walk by this
place and they open the door and you'd
be like,
what in the fuck?
And meanwhile people are paying a lot of
money for this thing that if it smelled
anything like that,
small,
like I might've struggled to eat it.
I've been with the same stuff.
I mean I don't know what it was called.
I would have to call my friend,
just plugged my notes.
I like to think I'd be able to eat
anything.
Is it?
I Dunno.
Well you're pretty mentally tough.
That's the thing.
I could get through it and was over.
You probably blank out of your mind that
deals with that and just go into the
zone,
throw it in and then you're like,
am I good?
Yeah.
Then he'd run over to the garbage pail.
That's what happened.
I saw more people throw up and probably
I would say like if you like look at me
and like maybe catch cafeteria lunch
ladies.
We've probably seen the most people
throw up in the world.
Oh,
I bet.
I've seen.
I saw how fucking people throw up every
week.
I saw people throw it.
I became completely immune to throw up.
You I think would be more gross than the
blended stuff.
I feel like as long as there was enough
liquid to be able to just swallow it,
I think I get through it,
but I think it would be hard for me as
the like crunchy bugs,
dirt easy really well for me because
just like anything.
Yeah,
but it's not the taste,
the texture,
the sound,
the sound of it.
Like the shell crunching and then like
the guts exploding.
I don't know.
We were just talking like this is
disgusting topic,
but that's like my.
That's like that.
Or the big old caterpillar's like where
they pop in your mouth.
Like hearing something like that I think
is what would get me to eat a tomato
horn worm.
That wasn't the best tasting thing in
the world.
That one popped in my mind.
Those things.
I think that would be a little hard for
me,
but it's nothing like that.
Gum,
remember that gum used to have the
squirt center.
It's good for your breath.
You remember that stuff?
Yes.
They still have that stuff.
I'm sure they do.
That gum is like tomato horn worm.
You pop it except it doesn't taste good
when squirts.
Tastes like,
but it does.
It's like neutral.
That would be a struggle for me.
That's just my thing.
I don't know.
That's my thing is like anticipating the
pop or the crunch telling you you would
just do it.
I'm telling you nothing.
The bugs or nothing.
I was in Mexico recently and they were
served crickets.
The crickets.
So like,
like it was a snack that they left in a
hotel like fried crickets.
I don't know.
I guess if I could do it at my own pace
and I like they were cooked crickets.
I'd probably try one own peers and
staff.
The thing is,
what would be the thing that you only
have a certain time or one where they
stuck with those spiders with like super
long,
long legs and it was like trying to
crawl out of the person's mouth while
they were eating it and like that was
just like,
oh my God,
that would be a African cave dwelling
spider.
I ain't one of those two really.
I eat a lot of shit.
He's alive.
He always threw it in there.
Chewed up.
Can I bite you?
They tried really felt like a little
pinch her on my lip but serious.
But I am death.
You just mounted down and I'm like,
I got down on those cupcakes.
You imagine being a force,
bartered some fucking gag for a TV show
and someone's going to eat,
you know.
But um,
yeah.
The most bugs don't taste like anything.
I bet the ones that are really bad or
poisonous,
they probably would fuck with you.
Like if you had a black widow probably
tastes like shit.
Nobody ever had like a live snake or
anything like that?
No.
Well we can't give any of the animals.
We had,
we did,
we did do some stuff with snakes.
It was really interesting what people
would get upset about and what people
wouldn't get upset about like p,
the Peta would,
they would get really upset if we did
things with rats or things with rodents.
Particularly problematic,
but people didn't get upset about things
with bugs.
Like there's a really clear hierarchy
that people have with life and people
just don't seem to get that upset about
bugs,
but like certain animals take almost
feel bad.
If I was to eat a live bug,
part of me would feel bad.
I don't know.
What about lobster and throw lobster and
a pot.
I feel bad about that too.
Oh yeah.
I prefer to just kill it real quick
first and then I'm fine with it.
Yeah,
I think they're meant to be eaten.
I'm fine.
Like with Hyundai doesn't bother me,
but the,
the idea of them may be experiencing
extrusion,
eat amount of pain before,
like just just like seven in the head
real quick and then it's done.
It's dead.
You killed it humanely and then eat it.
No problem.
Care about that.
But they say the lobsters can't feel
pain,
but I say bullshit bullshit too.
How do you know you're not a lobster?
Have you ever been lot?
No.
So I just say err on the side of
caution.
Just kill it.
First used to go crabbing up in the San
Juan Islands.
We'd catch fresh dungeness crabs.
Cook it within like an hour that they
taste so much better that way.
It's incredible isn't.
Yeah.
Brian can't eat seafood to save his life
at all.
Like he can't,
cannot stomach it.
Like you can't eat anything out of the
water.
Anything.
Even like seaweed,
anything psychological?
Sure.
I think part of it's psychology.
He just doesn't like it at all.
He thinks it tastes disgusting.
Like the taste of the ocean.
Like you get a lot in fish skin or like
seaweed,
like anything that tastes resembles the
flavor of the ocean.
Something watery.
He hates it.
Is He from Washington state too?
So it was it like an overdose of fish
because everybody's up there eating fish
all the time.
No,
because he lived on the.
He lived in central Washington area.
Right on the other side of the
mountains,
so it's a little more like grainy and
dry and a little bit farther away from
the water.
But um,
he ate dungeness crab.
This was going to get back to,
is that,
that will have a crab that we caught
that day and killed it and boiled and we
had this sweet butter to debit.
Well,
yeah,
actually.
Like he ate it and was like,
yeah,
it was pretty good.
Those was the only seafood thing he's
ever eaten in his life that was swarming
crabs on the seafloor.
Why?
Oh my God.
Is that real?
Thousands and thousands of crabs.
You can even see the floor off the coast
of Panama says,
Holy Shit.
What kind of crabs are these?
Red,
red crabs?
And they just covering the floor like
sand.
That's insane.
They didn't.
When I think of when I read this,
they said they didn't know what it was.
They thought it was just the moving sand
on the ground until they got to put
light on it.
Then they saw that it was crabs.
Wow.
Are the little tiny crabs,
is that what it is?
They look like they'd be pretty big
crabs are the cleanup crew.
Crabs and lobster.
It's interesting how good they taste
when you consider what they do.
They just basically eat rotten things
that like sharks leave behind other fish
leave behind.
And I mean they're just the cleanup
crew.
Yeah.
Were,
were like,
got to be grass fed beef,
but we can eat,
we can eat shit eating now.
That's so crazy that brian doesn't eat
any seafood because I would imagine that
especially considering that he cuts
through so much weight,
like that would be like a good source of
lean protein fish.
His friends wanted to mess with them one
time and he had like,
he's at a restaurant and one of them had
had salmon.
Brian's like one of those guys like does
he want to look like if you're eating
seafood,
does he want it?
He doesn't want to look.
Yeah,
he does.
He just so like so grossed out about it.
And um,
so he got up to go to the bathroom and I
guess I wasn't there.
I wasn't dating but this,
this was a long time ago,
I guess they picked up a piece of the
salmon and rubbed it all over the rib of
his cup of milk and he smelled it and
then threw it like he went to take a sip
and he almost just see,
just like lost it because he's.
Yeah,
he smelled it and I don't know.
Did someone like force feed them a fish
when he was a little kid or something?
Oh,
I kinda wonder if something traumatic
had to have happened.
Bravo's got a weird thing like that.
Onions,
I'd give them onions.
He'll fucking freak out.
What if they're cooked?
I don't think he can even eat them
cooked.
Really?
Yeah.
Apparently he had a douchebag for
Stepdad.
His stepdad used to make meat.
So Vj and the uneasiness of each day to
this day,
like just freaking the fuck out of can
of onions.
Like everything on with that.
Um,
with chocolate flavor things.
What's,
yeah,
what about cupcakes?
No chocolate cupcakes really?
Now I don't like,
um,
I don't like chocolate.
I don't like chocolate ice cream I don't
like,
but I like milk chocolate,
dark chocolate.
No,
I'm okay with this.
As long as it's not anything chocolate
flavor,
it has to be real chocolate.
Just,
it can't be anything.
It's such a weird thing.
But the thing is I was really sick when
I was a little girl was like five or six
years old.
I had a,
like,
I almost died.
I went to the hospital,
I had to get a spinal tap because all my
veins had collapsed.
I was so,
yeah,
I got really,
really sick.
What was it?
I
had rye,
Rye Syndrome.
I don't know what that is.
I don't remember exactly the details
about why you liked the bread.
I don't know.
We never really quick.
It's bad.
That was killed.
You have chicken pox and then I had a
form of hepatitis hepatitis B.
that's what I had all three at the same
time because my immune system was down
from the chicken pox and then I caught
that and then I kinda have to add and
um,
yeah.
So,
so my parents took me obviously to the
hospital and they couldn't,
they,
I had a phobia of needles for awhile
too.
They got an ivy and me barely.
And um,
you know,
how like they're supposed to leave the
ivy and you.
And then they changed the tubing will
the stupid nurse pulled it out and all
my veins were so collapsed they couldn't
get a needle in anymore.
So they would come in.
I was just passed out.
They would come in on the hour almost
every hour on the hour and I would wake
up to like 10 or 15 people holding me
down.
It felt like 10 or 15.
I was five.
It was probably like three people,
but I just see lights and see will
holding me down and they'd be trying to
stick needles in the top of my hand in
my ankles and the tops of my feet behind
my knees like that.
And they hold me down trying to get
fluids in me because I couldn't keep
anything down.
And so finally it was so bad that they
told my mom to like call it if she's
religious,
I call her pastor and like have him
come.
And like they were like,
yeah,
like she's gonna,
you know,
so they brought me in to give me a
spinal tap and my God,
it was the most painful thing I've ever
experienced in my life because he take
fluid out and epidurals,
like I hear really painful too,
but it's an injection as opposed to like
removing the fluid,
which is more painful.
I don't know.
I remember feeling the most excruciating
pain in my life and then passing out.
I was so weak anyways.
It was pretty terrible.
I,
it was back to the chocolate part of it
before I went to the hospital,
I was running such a bad fever and I was
throwing up and my mom thought,
you know,
let's give her ice cream.
And she had like some Neapolitan ice
cream downstairs and she was like,
they're really cheap.
Crap.
We didn't.
I didn't grow up in,
you know,
with a lot of money or anything like
that.
We struggled.
So it was like the cheap fake
strawberry,
the cheap vanilla in the really shitty
cheap chocolate and I tried to eat some
of those,
the strawberry and the vanilla and I
fell asleep and I woke up and I was
really hungry and really thirsty and I
went and the all the chocolate had
melted so it was like a super bowl of
warm ice cream and I took try to take a
bite of it because it's just a little
kid and I lost my shit.
I puked everywhere and to this day it
ruined it for me,
like ruined anything chocolate flavored.
What I can do,
like dark chocolate,
a real chart but has to be quality.
So if somebody brings you like a
superbowl neapolitan ice cream right now
and it just.
Yeah,
it's.
it is mentally fucked me forever.
Look at the definition,
Jamie.
Pull that back up again.
Please.
Look at the definition of rise.
Disease.
I mean it's,
look at this,
a rare but serious condition that causes
swelling in the liver and the brain
liver damage perfectly.
They said it was permanent.
I don't know.
Most often affects children and
teenagers recovering from a viral
infection most commonly the flu or
chicken.
That's amazing.
I've never heard no that.
I never looked at it,
but I knew that I had some liver damage.
They actually told me to.
It's been linked to this.
So you have this use caution when giving
aspirin to children and teenagers and
that's exactly when.
That's.
That's why.
Yeah,
that's why that happened because my mom
told me she called.
She called the hospital and ask them
like,
my daughter has chickenpox,
what should I,
what should I give them,
give her whatever,
and they're like,
oh,
just give her aspirin,
you know,
give her some aspirin to help her with
that.
And that's what caused that.
And then it was just bad.
It was really,
really bad.
It was so weird that it's connected to
aspirin.
I wonder what the fuck.
The fact,
I didn't even know that actually,
but I just know that like that I had
that in,
that had liver damage.
They actually told me that I would
probably never be able to excel as an
athlete because of that,
because of your liver damage because of
the liver and like,
I don't know if maybe that's why I'm
like,
so maybe just show up and maybe I
shouldn't blame,
blame my,
like my,
my lack of,
uh,
of,
of paying attention to situations and
knowledge of things.
I can never remember people's names.
Maybe I will say I get punched in the
head for living.
Maybe it was that like brain damage and
liver damage,
all those things can be great.
But if anybody said that you would never
make it as an athlete told me like,
yeah,
the.
Yeah,
exactly.
Right.
The doctors were like,
yeah,
she's probably going to always have an,
you know,
an issue as an athlete to like to excel
now.
Have you ever got like a liver toxology
toxology no examination or something
like that?
No,
I never had.
It seems like it'd be a good idea to do.
My mom always told me she's like,
you should do a visualization of your
liver healing itself.
So you said you had to like envision my
liver,
like growing moms?
Yeah,
it was.
she was.
She never totally visually than anything
else,
but I remember that now this is bringing
back memories.
She's like,
you should try to,
you know,
think about your liver being healthy.
I don't know if it helps.
We use now a lot.
Visualization.
Absolutely beneficial means the mind has
also to weird properties that we don't
totally understand.
That's why placebo effects work.
We don't know why they work,
but it does work.
It's statistically proven that if you
have a positive attitude and you believe
something can help you,
it can help you.
But the problem with that is people use
that as like an excuse for charlatans
like psychics and palm readers and Tarot
card readers and healers.
Healers are a big one.
There was a guy that was working with a
bunch of UFC fighters back in the day
that people would call like the witch
doctor and this guy was like doing all
these things.
Do you remember George St Pierre?
Um,
not,
not do remember,
obviously.
But do you remember George St Pierre?
They had this thing that these do with
him when they would like rub his back
and rub his sternum,
they had never understood that it was
just shit that this guy had talked these
people into doing like a bunch of
fighters.
Like even fucking randy couture was
going to this guy.
Yeah,
and the guy turned out to be a total Ho.
I met him and I just felt like right
away because I'm so used to hoaxers.
I'm so used to being around bullshit
artists and examining them as soon as
you started talking about the Meridians
of the body and this and that,
and I was like,
Oh,
you're full of shit.
You're full of shit.
And you got deeper into these people.
You're,
you're rubbing on them and you're
opening up their chakras.
Old fucking for sure.
You are
people that do the funny like ci videos,
I feel like it's like a cold almost
sometimes there's people in there like,
you know,
I can make someone flip over by just
doing this or like whatever.
They do the weirdest things and the
people that that they convinced to,
like it takes two to do that obviously
because it's not real.
So the person doing it and the person
getting the move or whatever done to you
have to have know that person has to
agree to do it and then it's always so
funny to me when you see them get
approached by someone who doesn't
believe in that at all and they're like,
they're like,
okay,
do you have to me like,
okay.
And they really,
they really think that it's gonna work
and the person's just standing there and
I'm like,
no,
it's not working.
They're like,
Oh you know it's going to work.
They think is going to work,
but given the bullshit artists thinks
it's going to work or you ever see the
guy that was like trying to chop a shop
was,
I'm not a pint of almost a pineapple,
but a coconut try to shop,
but like his hand,
he was trying to set a world record.
You guys should pull that video up.
It's what his hand was.
It bare hand.
He's like a karate guy.
He'll be like,
chopped the boards.
I think it might have to break a coconut
with your hand.
No,
and it was funny because he had like a
news crew there and he had like 20
coconut set out on like this,
this bar,
and he starts just hacking at one
hacking at one hack.
Anyone?
Yes.
And,
and it's like,
well you watch the video.
It's hilarious.
I'm going to have.
I'm like,
guy think that this would work.
He's one of these guys.
I'm telling you.
You got a karate outfit on and look at
it as a metal bar underneath that.
So watch when he misses.
Oh No,
no,
no.
He misses,
but yeah.
Oh,
fail.
He does this.
Oh my God.
He hits the fucking.
Oh,
fail.
Fail.
Oh my God.
He hits them
like his hands hurting.
Yeah,
for sure.
He had to pull away that he doesn't want
to do it again.
He doesn't want to,
but he's like,
I got to.
And he's like,
okay.
No,
she stepped in.
Thank God.
Why was he thinking that that would
work?
Wouldn't you practice that before you
got on television,
but you imagine thinking that you would
karate chop a fucking coconut open.
How about just hit the earth in and wake
up people in China?
That's what I was saying.
No.
So yes,
the mind is a very powerful thing where
there's a gang of videos of these guys
that are doing those key things on
people and then their students fall to
the ground and start twitching and
there's a great one with this guy in
Harlem had this,
uh,
like Kung Fu school and he had all these
students and he,
he's like doing all this like literally
like Dragon Ball z type shit on them.
Like they would have followed the ground
and start twitching and spasming and
it's like really shitty acting.
But they are into it.
I think when you're in a cult like that.
And that's what a lot of those martial
arts are.
There are a cult and I think almost all
traditional martial arts have like
attributes which can be beneficial,
like the discipline and desire to please
your Sensei or your,
your Sabam name or whatever you wanna
call them is like it's intense and you
know,
yes sir,
and they bow and all this stuff and they
really believed that their instructor
cannot do any harm.
There's a lot of good in that because it
makes you have this really intense
desire to succeed and this intense
belief in yourself,
but it's not realistic obviously and a
lot of traditional martial arts and
until the UFC came around,
we didn't really know how unrealistic it
was.
Yeah.
Well if you remember like Pat Smith when
he fought that Ninja guy and like UFC
one or two.
I think it was UFC too.
I don't remember which one it was,
but he fought some guy and this guy was
doing these like in the.
You remember they used to have the video
of the guy training before the fight and
the guy was like throwing all these
techniques around a flip and people on
the ground grabbing her neck and fucking
karate chop at the top of their head and
they fall to the ground and the UFC has
come along way in a short amount of
time.
Right?
I mean think about like football from 93
and then football in 2016 and kind of
looks like football.
Still the same,
but the UFC in 93,
like,
look at it,
it's like it's chaos,
but Pat Smith was like a real fighter.
This is the guy.
Look at it.
I just kept charging that Pat Smith and
tried to.
I don't know why I clinched up his name
and math got on top of him and he just
dropped elbows on them and smash this
poor dudes head open.
It was awful,
but that's 12 to six years.
We're still allowed.
Then 12 slash six is the dumbest fucking
rule.
Oh,
here's this guy.
Look at this and this is the best part
about it.
Pat Smith walks off and the fight is not
done because he's a kind man for walking
off because the referee is saying the
fight still going on because.
Yeah,
yeah,
because it's park.
Yeah.
That guy got smashed,
but what's this guy's name again?
Oh No.
We don't even need to bring up this poor
guy's name,
but he probably thought it was big John
Mccarthy.
All lean and healthy looking.
He probably thought that it was real.
He probably thought that what he,
what he was doing was real and he didn't
know until he got in there with a guy
like Pat Smith that what he was doing
was just some malarkey.
So Mall Strip mall malarkey.
There's a lot of that out there still to
this day.
It's amazing.
It's kind of makes you wonder sometimes
as the world that we live in,
it's like,
well,
it's that same.
It's the mind,
like the belief in what you can do when
you can't do it can benefit you,
but it can also fuck you up.
Like he can benefit you if you're
talking about your own health,
like if you really believe that
something's healing you,
it can heal you,
but there's like physical limitations,
you know,
like if you believe that Melvin manhoef
can kick you in the liver and nothing's
going to happen,
guess what?
That's not true.
You can chop cooking.
Oh,
that guy.
There's so many of those people though.
So that was weird.
First podcast I ever listened to of
yours was a guy talking about a cult
that he had been involved in.
I can't remember his name either,
but it was like,
it was really fascinating.
He's talked about his story and how they
basically took him in and you remember.
Oh yeah,
Steve Hassan.
Yeah,
he's actually a,
um,
a cult.
Is that how you say his last name?
H S h a s s n
and fascinating man.
He's actually a really warped as mine.
Like that.
He really got into believing that his
family was against him and like now that
he's removed from it,
he's like,
I was totally
my mind manipulated.
Yeah.
He's in the moon and he was in the
moonies that's where,
that's what he joined up with.
Yeah.
That's A.
It's a weird store because that guy now
works to help people get out of cults.
Well,
he should go help some of these c's
height.
Gee People.
I know you've,
I'm sure you've seen the one with the
old Asian man who fights the young
karate guy.
Have you ever seen that one?
This guy,
they show him with his students and he's
doing all this stuff and they go flying
across the room and their body twitches
and he decides to have an actual no
rules fight with his young Turkish guy
and this guy just fucks him up,
grabbed his shirt and beats his face in
and high kicks.
Um,
and it's so brutal because the man looks
like he's like in his late sixties.
Yeah.
It looks pretty old and not stout.
And it's not like,
you know,
a healthy old 60 either.
He looks like he's got a little potbelly
and this dude just beat the piss out of
him.
And a got like a beating like that from
a young strong guy who's much bigger
than him to the guy looked like much
stronger than him.
Like that's not something that old guy
is going to recover from.
A key might be fucked forever from this.
That's terrible.
In his mind,
he thought that he was going to fucking
Kung Fu this dude.
Do you believe it?
Like have you ever researched much about
hypnosis and how I've been hypnotized?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Vinny shoreman and it.
Well Vinny shoreman.
I don't know if you know who he is.
He works with a lot of fighters.
He worked with Joe Schilling.
He's worked with a lot of MMA fighters
and he does what he calls himself a mind
trainer.
And what he does is he can talk to you
and put you in a state of mind.
It's a very weird thing,
like it's not what people think it is.
It's not like take off your pants and my
dick gets down like that.
Like you're,
you're aware kind of.
But it's like an altered state of
consciousness.
It's almost like he puts you in like a.
it's like you're under a drug or
something.
So.
So I,
I just recorded a podcast.
I just started my own podcast.
And what is it?
How do people find it?
Mutated?
Misha tate.
Show the fuck out of here.
What'd you come up with that name or.
No?
Starting to think about that one a lot.
How about the cupcake?
Our right,
like I'm getting our.
Yeah.
Um,
so I,
I sat down with Mark [inaudible] who
does a comedy hypnosis show 10 years on
the Strip and absolutely fascinating
when you think about the conscious mind
and the subconscious mind and how the
conscious mind really is kind of the
tip,
just the tip of the iceberg,
but there's so much more beneath it and
your subconscious mind is we're talking
about how the power of mind and he says,
you kind of go in and out of hypnosis
states all the time.
Like when you're driving and you start
daydreaming or you're,
you know,
you're sitting,
you just kind of space out.
You're not really looking at whatever
you're looking at anymore.
You're in,
you're in a daydream or at night,
you know,
that's kind of a state of an awake
hypnosis and that you can kind of go in
and out of those yourself you do all the
time during the day,
but a hypnotists can kind of guide you
into that and then plant certain good
seeds,
you know,
I guess are bad seeds if they wanted to,
you know.
But I always thought of that too,
like a Kooky guy that was going to make
you do dumb shit while you don't know
what you're doing.
But that was fascinating to me because
he talks about how he helps people who
have phobias.
For instance,
someone who has a phobia of a dog.
He's like,
so fear is like one dog,
this dog bit you and your child,
you're scared of that dog phobia is this
dog bit you and you're scared of all
dogs.
Now some people are so terrified they
get these phobias.
They can't even leave their house.
Like they're so scared of the neighbor's
dog walking by and going to jump out of
anywhere and bite them.
So they're crippled by these fears.
And he could put them in a hypnotic
state and kind of go back and remove
that fear essentially.
That makes sense.
I mean,
I think that there's a,
as he said,
there's a bunch of layers to the mind,
but I think that one of the most
fascinating aspects of it is when they
do those comedy hypnotism shows,
those comedy hypnotism shows are 100
percent real.
Like I've seen them live.
Like there was a guy named Frank Santos
was a big comedy hypnotist.
Guy In Boston and his son still does it.
Frank Santos Junior.
But Frank Santos would do this show
weekly show it stitches and all these
comedians.
We would come from like all over the
town to watch this because we couldn't
believe it.
We were like,
how the fuck is he doing this?
And he would get people and he would
know when they were under and when they
were an under.
Like you would know when people are
faking it,
when they weren't.
He would get them off the stage when
they're faking it.
But the people that we're really under,
you could see.
They just were baffled.
And I,
and he couldn't explain why it would
work on some people and why it wouldn't
work on others.
He didn't really know.
Yeah.
I asked mark the same question because
he,
he'll invite as many people that want to
volunteer out of the audience as you
want.
So he'll get 30 plus people up there and
he'll just pick people off as they are,
aren't into it.
But he has people doing the craziest
funny things,
you know?
Yeah.
And it's so funny.
It's bizarre because you're like,
how are all these people in on this?
Well they're not.
They really do like this.
The Frank Santos used to have this
person.
This is like in the eighties,
back when Madonna was hot.
Like if you said you're going to have
sex with Madonna now guys would go,
Hey,
what the fuck?
That looks good for her age.
For her age.
That's the big part though.
Yeah,
right.
She still looks great.
I mean,
no,
but everyone knows even if she looks
great,
everyone knows that pitches like 60,
like,
you know,
like I say bitch with all due respect
this piano like a bad bitch,
bad ass bad.
But um,
but you would watch him like he would
talk someone into believing that they
were having sex and Madonna and these
guys have the orgasm in their pants.
So like you'd see them go,
like he would tell them and you know,
and now you're going to come in your
pants and you'd see the guy go,
oh,
when you're watching it,
you're watching.
You'd be like,
what in the fuck is this real?
You almost want to go,
jude,
I want to see your underwear.
Let's
say it.
Yeah.
I want to see if it worked.
It was,
I can see the proof in the pudding,
but frank tried to explain to us he had
worked with people where it would help
people quit smoking and things along
those lines.
But until Vinny shoreman did it to me,
I really,
I had no idea.
I was like,
I still haven't been hypnotized by fema
to try it.
It's going to be in the United States.
I'll connect you guys together.
You would like it because he's used to
working with fighters and he's.
He's great about like setting a mindset.
I think Ian Mccall worked with them too,
but he's great about putting you in a
certain state of mind and working on
various aspects of like maybe your
performance or or your attitudes.
Yeah.
It's interesting.
Well that's all about staying woke.
Stay woke.
He's woke you.
I want some net achieve wokeness.
Super,
super important to achieve wokeness.
Yeah,
I mean the mind is a really fascinating
thing and I think that especially for
fighters,
I would have to say that it's just one
of the most important aspects of your
ability to perform.
Like physically is one thing,
but the ability to like you're inside
the cage,
the pin goes into the gate.
Are you ready?
Let's get it on.
I mean that is the craziest moment in
all sports.
There's no moment like that where you.
I mean think about like a basketball
player,
basketball players.
Even if there's a lot of pressure for a
three point shot,
if you miss that three point shot,
you're going to get another shot
somewhere in the game.
Someone's going to hand you the ball.
Luckily,
or if not someone's gonna hang up all
tomorrow or someone will hand you the
ball next week,
but if you say,
if you fight,
you know,
between team sports and individual
sports too,
for sure.
I mean it's like when you lose,
sometimes it's not unless you.
The kicker on the football team and like
you literally cost them but it.
But it's still like a,
you know,
it's still a team sport.
Your team,
your team obviously didn't get you far
enough to where you had to rely on that
kick,
but you go inside the cages is just you.
It's not just you,
it's just you involved in the most
humbling,
dangerous,
extreme version of a contest between two
human beings.
You can get outside of sword fighting,
you know,
outside of fighting to the death.
There's nothing is extreme as a cage
fight.
When you guys,
I have to laugh when people say like
that.
We're scared to fight someone,
you know,
like people were like,
oh,
you're scared to fight holly again.
Like you can't listen to those people.
Scared is not a relative.
Like it's not a term that I feel like
fighters really.
We don't,
we don't have scared the way normal
people have scared,
you know?
Yeah.
Like a normal person would be scared to,
to,
to get off their couch and go to the
gym,
you know,
to spar something like that's what we
do.
Like we live like what most people would
shit their pants
and you would have to be a fool to not
know that it's a dangerous fight.
So it's not a matter of not being aware
of the danger,
but it's a matter of managing the
consequences are like,
I think you did a fantastic job with the
holly fight,
like literally you did in that fight
other than the fifth round,
which is the most amazing part of it.
But you did everything.
Like when we were about like what you
have to do to beat her.
I'm like,
she's got to stay on the outside.
She could have very her rhythm and she's
got let holly come to her like she,
she can't rush in because you rush into
holly.
It's like Russian into Machida are
rushing to anybody who's a great counter
striker and you saw the Rhonda fight.
Ronda just came bulldog and honor and
tried to out bulldogger and you just.
You can't do that with holly.
She's too fast.
Footwork to her,
her striking is so precise.
Her,
her counters are so clean
movements,
very hard to read.
Like it's very unpredictable.
I remember what a couple times I tried
to maybe come forward and get her to get
to the fence and I couldn't tell whether
she was going to jet out to the right of
the left.
Like usually like two steps back left
and I was like,
ah,
you know,
like I couldn't even tell like she had
gave no indication of which way she was
going to go.
Yeah.
Well you just did a fantastic job of
varying.
Your approach to your speed was
different.
Like you,
you,
you did a lot of fainting,
you varied things up a lot and you could
tell like she was like almost like
waiting for these moments to happen when
you're going to come forward and then
you wouldn't come forward and then it
becomes like a test of patience,
like who's going to get outside of their
comfort zone,
who's going to take chances?
Who's gonna who's gonna engage.
Yeah.
And she also has that weird stance to
was she kinda halfway stands like a
boxer and halfway stands like a karate
person.
She throws like a lot of side kicks on
the front leg techniques.
Yeah,
she,
she's,
she's a tricky one,
but we put together a really good game
plan.
I was happy with that.
Yeah,
you did.
I was happy,
but it was a fifth round.
Fifth round was crazy.
God,
when you grabbed a hold of her and then
eventually got her back and got her to
the ground.
It was so crazy because every aspect of,
from your initial entrance to the
takedown to getting her back,
there was nothing.
One hundred percent about it.
It was all touch and go.
It was all scramble.
It wasn't like you had complete total
control over like maybe like Damien Maia
versus Rick Story.
Like he daymond my gets rick stories
back.
He's got them locked up and then he
anaconda asm and squeezes them and then
it gets them.
It wasn't like that.
It was like you were fighting for your
fucking life and you knew there was no
time.
There was no time.
You were likely down by like at least
one round and you were headed into the
fifth and final round and maybe if you
won that round you could have got the
decision,
but fuck,
you're fighting the champ.
Yeah.
Who knows?
Who knows what's gonna Happen?
You take our back and then when she
tries to shake you off the top and you
hang in there and you hang in there and
you see what you like.
And I watched them like,
oh my God,
she's going to go out.
And when she went out and you climbed
off her and she was unconscious like,
Holy Shit,
Holy Shit.
What a moment.
That was incredible.
It was incredible.
It was one of the best moments in all of
women's championship fighting as far as
like like an extreme,
extremely dramatic moment where like
you're,
you're trying to accomplish something.
She's fighting tooth and claw.
Neither one of you are exhausted,
so it's not like anyone's like
physically compromised.
It's just a fucking mad scramble between
two killers and you get her and got her
back and then you get back and you sink
the choke and she's trying to fucking
shake you off and you hung in there and
when she rolled and you're on top of her
and you,
you,
you hung onto it and you realize like,
oh my God,
she's going out.
And she is.
She didn't even tap.
She was throwing punches in the air
while you were choking her unconscious.
I kept thinking
to myself,
I'm like,
when is she going to tap?
It didn't in my,
in that instinctual moment.
I'm so used to,
in training you get people in a choke,
you know they tap.
So I'm waiting for that tap and I'm
like,
God,
like when is this girl going to tap?
Like I know I've got her.
What does she mean to,
you know,
tap on it and then,
then I felt her,
I saw her from my peripherals,
kind of do,
do something.
I wasn't quite sure if she was tapping
or what she was doing until I watched
the video later and then I felt him pull
me off and I'm like,
that's the feeling that we fight for is
that feeling that,
that feeling of like I did it,
I established my dominance,
you know,
it's,
uh,
you know,
as a prideful sport in some ways,
it's hand to hand combat with someone
else.
It's like,
you know,
I,
I did it tonight.
I was better
to be prideful because otherwise there's
just certain sacrifices in certain fires
that you're not going to walk through.
Like you have to have every fucking
motivation.
You have to be Zen,
but you also have to have an ego.
There has to be so many things going on
for you to achieve that highest level of
greatness.
Again,
on a tight rope,
you know,
people that are just like that perfect
balance.
You know,
I'm walking between buildings that are,
you know,
hundreds of stories high or you know,
and then it's like,
it's,
it's Kinda like that.
I mean,
you have to have the perfect balance and
everything has to meet perfectly and
that moment,
including the training camp,
not overtraining.
Did you ever hear that video that the
video is not that good?
But the audio is,
is awesome.
It's between the fourth and fifth round
and it's my corners,
what they're telling me between fourth
and fifth round.
It's such an emotional video for me.
When I watched it,
it makes me relive that moment.
And Brian came in there and essentially
he was like,
Misha,
you've got to get after you got it.
You have got to put your chin down.
And Mike Tyson,
this chick.
And that basically means just get after
her,
like,
get,
get in there,
get after it,
take the risk,
risk getting knocked out,
go for broke.
And um,
it goes,
you know,
plays into the round and basically
you're just telling me fucking Mike
Tyson her like get after her bulldog or
do whatever you've got to do.
Is that because you're running out of
time,
and I remember in that fifth round still
trying to get out of that,
that mindset of like,
I to find the perfect opportunity.
I have to be patient because the whole
training camp was,
you know,
patient but persistent patient but
persistent.
No one run into anything because you,
you know,
you'll get caught,
you get knocked out,
you'll get need,
you'll get kicked,
you'll get punched.
So don't do that,
but you've got to look for the,
the opening when it's the right timing,
it's all about timing.
And after I took her down in that second
round and I just beat her up that round,
she was so.
I'm so cautious in the third and fourth
and so perfect,
you know,
her game plan was perfect to,
to beat me,
to stay just far enough out of the range
and keep me from not wanting to come in.
I couldn't find in a perfect opening.
It couldn't get in on anything.
There wasn't mistakes that she was
making.
And then in the fifth round I just
decided,
you know,
going to have to,
you're gonna have to take the chance of
getting knocked out.
This is,
this is what it's boiling down to.
Now you've got like three minutes left
on the clock and now it's do or die.
It's either you go in there,
you,
you go for it,
you do Russian,
she catches you,
you get knocked out,
you know,
you gave it everything you got or you
don't make something happen.
When have finished the fight,
the question was really like whether the
second round was a 10,
eight round on all three judges score
cards.
It was,
yeah,
I was watching it.
That's what the judges said.
Well it should have been but.
But what I'm.
What I meant was the question watching.
It was like I want like when we were,
when you were headed into the fifth
round with my question was,
was I wonder if she got a ten eight
round for that second round.
Because if she did then this is like,
this is even fight.
So what's happening right now?
Like what?
How the judge is looking at it going
into the fifth round.
It was even.
Yeah,
it was tied.
That's crazy.
That was such a crazy moment.
Does another time.
The Indian,
the postcode interview where almost
cried like a bitch.
I get so emotional.
Yeah,
it was,
it was incredible.
Well,
it's so hard to explain to someone when
you're there and you,
you,
you get to see someone like you who's
worked so hard for something for so
long,
you know.
So when I said to you like,
how does that sound?
Like,
what does it sound like?
You're the new women's bantamweight
champion of the world.
Like what does that sound?
And you were just so overwhelmed.
It was so crazy.
Like just to be right next to you while
you were saying that and you said when
you said,
I'm waiting for you to say that for so
long.
It was crazy.
It was crazy moment craze.
Yeah,
because I,
you know,
what's crazy about the mind and the
power of it.
I've,
I had visualized that moment so many
times that I felt like I was confused in
that it was hard for me to distinguish
that that was the real moment
I would,
I would imagine it was so.
It was so surreal.
I would imagine that to this day it
probably seems fake cats.
Really Weird.
Yeah.
Sometimes I have to go back and be like,
man,
that really did.
It really happened.
It really happened right there.
Oh,
it's pumped,
Jay.
Thank you guys.
So excited.
If you had like,
if ours were real,
you know,
like fucking.
If you had ci it was coming off your
body for sure.
The whole,
the whole state of fallen over in bed,
shaking papers,
cups flying through the air and carpet
would rip.
Okay.
That's gracious.
Yeah.
That was the best one.
Best moments in my life for sure.
I can only imagine.
I mean anyone that watches that sport,
that moment when you choked her out and
in the whole exchange of the.
Well,
even like the really the whole fight
because fight is like.
I mean in a weird way.
I mean we call this martial arts and
there's a lot of people that have a
problem with that,
but in my mind that there is an art to
what you guys did in that fight and even
what holly did because up until that
fifth round mean like you said,
especially the third and fourth.
She was what she wanted to do.
She was shoes and there was a display
going on.
There was a,
there was a performance going on on top
of this being a competition to watch it.
I,
someone's sitting there watching it and
calling it.
I mean this is a work of art and to have
it in that way which is such a masterful
performance was such a masterpiece
moment and that to me is like one of the
best moments in mma because it's such a
fucking hard thing to achieve to become
a champion.
And for someone like you had tried and
tried again.
He won the title in strikeforce and
you're trying and trying again and
trying to make this happen and you know,
you think you're getting boxed out and
then the Rhonda fight didn't happen
after you beat Jessica.
Hi.
And then all of a sudden you have this
opportunity and they comes to together
in one of the most powerful ways we've
ever seen inside the octagon.
It was amazing.
Well,
thank you.
That was a,
that was quite a great narration of
everything that's had to happen to make
this country,
you know,
and it,
it's uh,
it's crazy because it was 10 years,
the same month,
10 years,
the like the month,
um,
that I had had my first fight.
Wow.
It's been 10 years.
Yeah.
So it's crazy because you think 10 years
ago there wasn't even a women's ever
made was a joke.
Like it was.
I mean,
to me it wasn't obviously,
but to most people it was a spectacle at
best.
Something they kind of threw on the card
is kind of like,
ah Ha,
you know,
watch the chicks fight.
You know,
hopefully it'll pop out,
you know,
because they didn't respect us as
athletes.
You know?
That's,
that's what we,
that's,
that's the,
that's the honest truth.
That's the uphill battle that it was
like nobody took it seriously.
We didn't make any money.
We were fighting for bread crumbs at
best and kept you going during those
times.
The Passion,
as Cliche as it sounds,
I'm just the desire to want to be
fulfilled and I felt like that was the
most fulfilling thing in my life.
It wasn't college.
It wasn't,
it wasn't.
There was nothing else that was
fulfilling.
But what is it about fighting that
attracted you to it when there wasn't
any clear future because you were in it
at a time.
Think
about the future.
Too much early on now.
I didn't think about it as something
that was,
this needs to be lucrative for me.
This needs to be,
you know,
coming to some of it was I was probably
three years into my career before I even
thought that I could maybe like actually
possibly make a living at this,
so it was just something that I was
doing to feel alive.
Wow.
Yeah.
It was just something that I was doing
to,
to make me feel accomplished.
It,
you can't put a price on how something
makes you feel,
you know,
a memory and experience happiness.
You know,
those emotions.
people say like the day that they got
married,
the day that they had their kid,
the day you,
those are like mile markers in people's
lives.
Like I guess if you ask someone on their
deathbed,
what were the moments that made you feel
alive?
Like what did your life amount to what,
what was that?
Those key markers in your life?
And all of my fights have been markers
in my life that's more than most people
can say.
You know,
so I guess it was such a sense of
fulfillment and now the fact that it was
so hard,
it was,
it was so hard and so many people were
so against me.
I think that made me really determined
to.
Because a lot of people,
my Grandpa,
my dad,
my grandpa was really,
he was chauvinistic to be quite honest.
He was not,
he was embarrassed that his
granddaughter was a fighter and he would
give my dad a hard time all the time,
like,
why you let your daughter do that?
And he's like,
don't let her do anything.
She just,
she's her own person.
I'm not proud of it,
but my grandpa,
he's not.
But he,
um,
had a big change of heart when I,
when I actually lost my title too,
when I won my title against Marley's
spoon and,
you know,
he really became obviously big fan,
he's very proud of you.
I'm talking to my neighbors about you.
He's like,
I was wrong.
And I lost my fight to Rhonda,
right.
Be Right when he got diagnosed with
cancer.
And um,
that's eventually what passed away.
Um,
so I went straight from that fight down
to see him,
to see how he was doing and my dad was
down there visiting.
He lives in Florida so very,
very far away.
And I told them,
I was like,
Grandpa,
I'm really sorry that I didn't win this,
you know,
when it makes me emotional.
I was like,
I'm sorry I didn't win this fight for
you.
And he's like,
it doesn't matter,
you know?
And I think that's the last fight that
he ever saw unfortunately.
But,
you know,
he's like,
Hey,
you had a lot of heart and so proud of
you.
So yeah.
Were you attracted to other extreme
sports when you were younger?
No,
because I wasn't raised that way.
I wasn't raised with like extreme
sports,
like,
um,
yeah,
my dad's still saw me as even segregate
me,
I wouldn't say,
but he,
he saw me as a,
you know,
it was a little girl,
like he didn't take me four wheeling or
um,
you know,
riding dirt bikes or anything like that.
He took me down hill,
not downhill mountain biking,
but it kind of turned into that.
We rode for miles out to a lake with my,
with my little brother and a friend of
his.
And then um,
I remember I was riding back and there
was like big rocks and boulders and my
dad and his buddy have have had downhill
mountain bikes may for I'm writing like
a little street bikes,
but they're,
they're expecting that I'm just going to
be able to,
like,
I'll just carry down the hill or
whatever.
I try to bomb down the same rock hill.
Them I eat shit like bad each and I
still have scars on my elbow actually
hear from,
from when I,
uh,
when I fell and I just got up and my dad
says,
this is like one of the moments I
realize you were different.
He's like,
you just popped up and you're like,
frustrated was off.
He got back on your bike,
bombed down the rest of the hill and be
all of us home.
Like,
you're just crazy.
He's like,
I never saw anything like that.
I thought you're right that we were
gonna have to like,
you know,
call,
call medical help.
And I thought [inaudible],
he's like,
you ate at heart,
and it was like,
so it was just something that was just
in you,
I guess just deal.
I don't know.
My mom always told me,
and this something I realized when I was
talking to mark hypnosis,
he's telling me about how much children
can be affected by people who are
negative in their life with people who
can,
you know,
you're never gonna amount to anything
and how that can affect the subconscious
mind.
You know,
having a dad who's like,
you suck,
you're terrible.
You're never gonna be,
you know,
you're never gonna be anything.
How that can create crippling ripple
effects that,
that translate on all the way through
the rest of that person's life.
And I said,
well,
what if it's the opposite?
Like what if you had a parent that was
telling you that you're amazing all the
time,
that you could do whatever you want and
they really true heartedly believe in
you.
He's like,
Oh yeah,
that can,
that can be amazing.
You know?
Amazing too.
And it made me start thinking because my
mom and I,
we've had a really rough relationship
the past three,
four years or so,
maybe,
maybe longer.
It's been a struggle.
We're,
it's getting better,
but I will give her a ton of credit that
as,
as a single mom for part of my life
growing up and even not single,
she,
she never made me feel like I wasn't
capable of doing anything.
If I,
if,
if anything,
she always made me feel like I could be
and do whatever I want and I could be
the best at it.
Like most people when I would go five,
six,
seven,
eight years old and I want to be an
astronaut.
Like every little kid,
they're like,
yeah,
you know,
Oh,
on my grandpa was the first one to be
like,
that's not realistic.
You're not going to be,
you know,
not going to be.
Actually my mom was like,
no,
you will just like,
you will,
like,
if that's what you want to do,
that you will.
It's like,
she's like Misha,
whatever you want to do,
you will be the best at it.
Well,
I think it's probably good to have both.
It's probably good to have someone who
wholeheartedly believes in you and
someone else who's like doubting you.
Sort of like a little motivation to
prove them wrong.
The other person rise.
I,
I feed off of that.
I love proving people wrong.
Love it.
You're a very even tempered person,
which is very unusual for a fighter.
You're very feminine,
but you're also very flat and very
relaxed.
You're very like,
this is Meesha.
Like this is how you are like it was
when you were on the ultimate fighter
with Rhonda.
It was when it was highlighted the most
because she's so manic.
She gets so hot and it's one of the
reasons why people love her so much.
She gets so fucking crazy and she's so
competitive and angry that like when you
guys did that wall climbing thing and
that she's like,
fuck you,
and she's giving you the finger.
Like you're just like you just your
level the election,
but how has that.
When,
when did would.
Was that your whole life you're like
that?
Or is that something you learned how to
do?
Pretty easy going my whole life.
The thing is I don't like to be stressed
out and I don't like to be pissed off
and I don't like to not be happy,
so I do everything within my power to
not be stressed out.
Like I can be about to miss a flight or
has something.
And I'm like,
well what can I do now?
You know,
I'm just like,
it's sometimes it's a bad thing because
they don't plan ahead enough or I'm not
really good with time management because
I don't want to be.
I don't ever want to rush.
So even if I'm late to something I don't
like to rush,
you know?
And it just,
sometimes that's a bad thing.
I'm not the most organized person
because I'm so relaxed about everything.
Then I'm like,
no,
my taxes,
I'll do those later,
you know,
like that kind of thing.
It sounds like a great recipe for life
though.
Is It on both ends?
No one does it this way.
Seems good.
Yeah.
You know,
I,
I save save all my tension and stuff I
guess for when I get inside the cage,
but I like to be relaxed.
I just like to be shown.
I don't like to be pissed off.
I don't like to be stressed out.
Like what a miserable life.
I feel like,
you know,
some people are just angry all the time.
Like,
like they're like perma scrooge,
you know,
just all the time angry.
I'm like,
do you not even realize how bad your
life must suck?
Like what if,
if you just looked at things
differently,
you'd have a way better life.
I'm like,
I never want to be that person.
I remember Mike Tyson when he was in his
prime and they asked him about something
and he was talking about being angry.
He's like,
I'm angry all the time.
I'm angry at my dog.
I'm angry at everybody.
I'm angry.
The mailman just get the fuck out of my
way.
Like when he was in his prime,
he was just a ball of fury,
you know,
he was just this wrecking machine,
which is like a lot of people associate
that with being a championship level
fighter,
like almost like you have to have a
certain level of discontent,
you have to have a certain level of
anger to motivate you.
But with you,
I think if you could look at like a
person's graph,
like a sound graph of how they speak
their whole life.
Mine would be all over the fucking
place,
going up and down and be all crazy and.
But Yours,
I feel like it'd be like this like flat
up in little tiny ups and downs,
like very minor ripples,
like,
you know,
like a little bit of like a flat lake
where the water comes in a little bit,
but it's nothing fucking crazy.
There's no tidal waves.
No.
No chaos,
no tsunamis,
but you're just flat and steady.
I try to be,
not always,
I'm still a woman,
but that's usual for a fighter,
right?
This flat level sort of way.
And I say flat.
It almost sounds like a pejorative and I
don't mean it that way.
I mean like a Zen,
like you have a very zen thing going on.
Yeah.
And that's,
yeah,
I used to have issues with anxiety a
little bit when I was in high school and
I would like have my track meets and
something and I would have anxiety
attacks.
I actually have a problem with it and I
guess I've always been a very open
minded person and I always asked myself
questions whenever there's something
wrong with myself or you know,
an issue that I'm having.
I asked myself why am I having that,
you know,
and then,
and then it comes full circle and I was
able to answer those questions in and
then I have never suffered from anxiety
since I.
So I kind of put myself in a zen state
of mind early on in my career because I
hated it so much.
It's like you don't want to live having
anxiety issues.
Like why do I have that?
Why?
What am I afraid of?
You know,
it's like,
well,
I'm not,
I'm not afraid enough to where I'm not
going to do it,
so let's just not make it a big,
not make it something I don't like.
Obviously I do like it.
That's why I'm doing track.
Obviously.
I like MMA.
That's what I'm doing it.
I don't want to make it something I
hate.
don't enjoy because it's not.
So that's not why I do this.
I do this because I love it,
so let's not make it something I hate
ever.
I try not to.
That's a very rational approach though.
It's very unusual for people.
Yeah.
Like there's nothing in this life,
like if I want to do it,
that fear is going to stop me.
Fears are realistic thing.
It happens.
Yeah.
It's scary to get into the cage.
It's scary to think about losing weight
and I've tasted the most bitter losses
you could ever dream of and it's
devastating.
It's crushing.
That's the most scary thing.
It's not getting beat up.
It's not breaking your nose or breaking
my orbital bone or letting my arm gets
snapped in half.
That's not the scary part about fighting
and what I do.
The scary part is not being adequate
enough,
not being good enough that you're 100
percent wasn't good enough.
That's scary.
That's really scary.
And um,
I've had that.
I've had to face that point blank right
in the face many times before.
And it's the hardest thing to do.
Bar none.
It's the hardest thing to look at
yourself and be like,
I didn't,
I wasn't enough.
No one else can be responsible for that.
I fucked up.
I didn't do it.
I have to own this and to come back from
something like that and think that you
can still,
you can still get it back or you can
still do it again or you could still get
better.
You can learn from that.
That's,
that's also the challenging part of it,
you know,
and that's something that I've,
I've had to,
to get to this point,
I've had to get over those situations
where I thought that my world had ended.
You know,
my second last or Rhonda was the most
devastating.
The first loss was devastating.
The second loss was a,
like,
it was horrible.
I thought my world was,
was coming to an end and you know,
and nobody cared about my family and
friends,
but the rest of world,
they don't care.
I don't give a shit.
They don't care about second place.
They don't care,
you know.
And um,
they're mean.
People are harsh.
They're mean on social media.
You have to get thick skin quick.
Nobody teaches you how to deal with that
either.
There's no mma,
social media,
101 or like you don't,
you just sink or swim,
you figure it out or you don't either
bothers you or doesn't,
you know,
either you yell back at everyone or you
don't.
You know,
like when you're in the first generation
that's ever had to deal with.
Yeah.
So there's never been anybody in the
last 10 years.
Is it new occurrence and they don't
teach you how to,
how to deal with it or how to not let it
affect you emotionally?
No one knows.
I mean,
this is a total new field learning
experience,
especially for someone who does what you
do,
which is the most exposed an athlete
ever gets ever like if you lose a tennis
match and the world says,
hey,
you fucking suck at tennis or whatever
bitch move on with your life.
But if you're like,
you know,
Rhonda beat you again,
you fucking dumb hoe.
And you're like,
oh my God,
I can't believe this.
People so goddamn mean.
And it's fighting.
It's like the most primal thing.
So everyone,
what other sport or sports always buyout
boiled down to and they don't like
another person is
fighting.
That's like the most primal way to deal
with something.
So once your sport is fighting,
people like feel like
that more justification to talk shit,
even though they're just like,
Gosh,
I have to laugh because Jon Jones and
Daniel Cormier,
when we were in New York,
they opened up the questions to the
audience.
I big mistake because these little
pipsqueaks they got on the microphone.
Or like,
I'm so Daniel Cormier,
I just want to say I have a really
important question for you.
How is it going to feel when Jon Jones
kicks your ass again?
You know,
and I'm just like,
you idiot.
Like if you were,
you wouldn't have the balls to say that
if it was just you and Daniel in this
room and no one was going to know the
outcome of what happened after you said
that.
Well,
the fact that people feel so safe that
they can,
can do that killer like Daniel cormier
and then they did the same thing to John
Jones.
Did you ever see what they did?
The Rashad Evans,
Rashad Evans,
was that the photo signing and this guy
comes up to him with a picture of,
you know,
there's an iconic photo of when Leo
knocked him out or he's like kind of
crumpled up against the cage and this
kid,
this little skinny kid with a smile on
his face wanted Rashad to sign that and
we shot a crumple it up and threw it
out.
I'm and looked at him like,
are you out of your fucking mind?
Like,
do you know what I could do to you right
now?
Like he tried to hurt my feelings and
try to make me feel bad trying to punk
me in front of people while you have a
camera on me because you're filming it,
like your friends are filming this
reaction to you sticking just his
callousness and also just being
oblivious,
like oblivious to like,
why would you want to do that?
Why would you want to say that to John?
I don't get it.
Why is he so dummies grow up watching
pro wrestling and they,
they don't understand that this is real.
Like you,
like you say hello,
how's it going to feel to get your ass
kicked again?
What started that?
Like they were expecting like some
fucking fake thing.
It's like he's just oblivious to the
idea that you're hurting someone's
feelings for no reason and you can also
get caught up in it emotionally.
Like,
you know,
people get caught up.
Like I watched conor Mcgregor's social
media after Nate Diaz beat him and Holy
Shit I was,
I was saying to my friends,
I'm like,
I hope he stays off line for a few days.
Just don't go anywhere near a computer
for like a solid week.
Oh yeah.
Because it's just the cons,
the concept of the world.
Just the deluge twice for it.
Oh,
they love it and they hate their own
lives is the thing is that nobody wins
in our sport forever.
Like so.
You're always.
You're going to have to face that at
some point.
It's one of the most exciting things
about it is that it's so volatile.
Like the Chris Weidman,
Luke rockhold fight to me is like a
perfect example that I often.
I see Chris Weidman training or watch
videos of him training.
I'm like,
what is going on in his mind right now?
Because Weidman was so dominant and you
even in that fight,
incredibly competitive and he throws one
kick.
One crazy.
We'll kick one ill advised we'll kick
rockhold takes him down and smashes him
and I just wonder like,
how much does that kick haunt him?
How much does that haunt him?
Like how might what?
What is going on in his mind?
Well,
here's a guy who destroys Anderson
Silva.
Beats the fuck out of Leo Machida.
Vito Belfort smashes him in the first
round,
you know,
you watch his fights and you just go,
okay,
like,
what is this rockhold fight going to
play off like,
and then when rockhold beat them and
beat them down the way he did and
destroys him,
like,
oh,
we have a changing of the guard here.
Like these moments,
these pivotal moments of like,
your whole life changes you go from
being Chris Weidman,
UFC middleweight champion of the world,
one of the best fighters in the planet
to Chris Weidman,
former UFC middleweight champion of the
world now hoping he gets a shot at his
title in a rematch and now that he's got
it and it's going to happen soon.
It's like,
whoa.
That the drama and the buildup,
like I can't imagine being him right
now,
like the tension that he's under right
now and the pressure and what,
uh,
how much emotional connection he has
towards this attempt to win his title
back and how intense it's going to be
once they get in there.
Yeah.
And they're really starting to not like
each other.
The last time I was here for Fox,
I think it was about a month or so ago,
they were,
um,
they were there and there was some
tension.
Of course they were in studio and you
could tell Chris was just a,
he was not,
he was,
you know,
he's pissed.
He's not happy with the situation and
Luke rockhold is kind of like,
you know,
he's happy,
he's got the belt and he was kind of
boasting it around a little bit and he's
kind of ribbing Chris,
you could tell like trying to get under
his skin a little bit and Chris is like,
you know,
you could just tell he was like upset,
like they were kind of friendly
before that,
which is weird.
Yeah.
They were friendly before that,
like for a long time,
like there's photos of the two of them
together,
smiling and not anymore.
Well,
when a guy beats you down like that,
like,
and you lose your title the way Weidman
did.
Yeah.
But Brock holds fucking good.
He's fucking good.
I saw holly,
um,
once instance a fight and I was really
actually kind of nervous about it
because I was like,
she was,
um,
at the Jones osp fight.
Those just happened.
And um,
we were both of the VIP party and my
friend Heather Clark used to train
heather.
Joe Clark actually fighting this weekend
in Rotterdam.
Anyways,
she was like,
you should go and talk to him.
I was like,
yeah,
I want to.
I just,
I don't want to come off.
Like,
how,
what do I say?
Bitch?
What do you say to someone that you
just,
you took the dog,
say hi.
That's what I did,
you know,
I just went up and was like,
how are you?
And she like,
she came out and she was like,
no,
I'm just really bombed it in and get
that rematch.
I'm like,
I know.
I was like,
don't worry.
well,
we'll see each other a future.
She's like,
yeah.
I hope so.
I hope you still have it.
Just like,
you know,
I wanna I wanna see you again in future.
I'm like,
yeah,
I totally get it.
I've been in her shoes before.
I know how bad that sucks and she wants
that back,
but we were friendly,
but it's
using her.
Both of you are so nice.
Like holly is one of the nicest people.
Nice.
She's such a sweetheart.
Meticulously Nice.
If you didn't know she was a fighter,
you'd be like no fucking way.
And then he finishes a 19 time world
boxing champion.
Be like,
what the fuck are you talking about?
How's that possible?
How's that?
Nice killer.
Some tomfoolery.
It just doesn't make any sense.
She doesn't fit the mold either.
Like both of you guys are really
interesting representatives of MMA and
great representatives because you break
that mold.
You know
her manager though?
Oh yeah.
Who is he?
I don't know.
I don't even know if I've ever met him
in person.
I probably haven't.
Maybe I have.
If I did,
it wasn't memorable.
Anyways.
Um,
I guess he went,
like Dana went down.
So Dana,
Dana told me this.
Dana went down to albuquerque before
this fight ever came together of her and
I.
Right.
And he said,
look,
you guys need to wait for Rhonda.
Trust me,
that's the big money fight.
That's a fight.
You want to wait for him?
He went down there.
He told me this,
my face.
He went down there to tell them don't
fight me.
Should take like they didn't want to
give me.
The UC did not want that fight to
happen.
They wanted the rematch should be the
first fight and holly's manager told him
we want me should tay.
And Dana said he threw up his hands and
was like,
are you fucking kidding me?
He's like,
she's been the baddest,
you know other than Rhonda for years
now,
and you want to take her lightly.
You think you're just going to walk
there.
He's like,
yeah,
we got this.
Like she's going to be a tune up fight.
Who's her manager?
I don't even know his name.
Okay,
I know these idiot.
But then he told Dana that,
that they,
that they thought that I was going to be
a tuneup,
fight.
Well
for get crazy.
People get crazy.
Look,
look right.
As people go crazy too.
Everybody gets crazy.
People get crazy.
Like why did Rhonda charge after?
Why?
Why did she try to stand with,
with holly like that and charge after
it?
That's not the right attempt.
Right.
But she did a page,
so page was also at that VIP party and
Paige and I have spoken with were
friendly,
don't know her that well,
but anyway,
she felt the need.
She came up to shit,
Nisha,
Nisha.
She's like,
I have to tell you this experience I had
with Rhonda and I'm like,
Oh,
what?
And she's like,
well we're at a reebok deal just
recently.
And um,
she,
she's like,
we were at a shoot and she's like,
I was trying to find her so we could get
a picture and the reebok people were
like,
don't ask Rhonda for a picture.
And she's like,
why?
She's like,
just don't do,
just stay away from Rhonda.
Don't ask her for a picture.
She's like,
okay.
And I guess Rhonda came later that day
and like seek her out and there's like
cussed her out.
Like they've never really had a
conversation either.
She's like,
I don't know Rhonda,
like,
you know,
other than hi bye.
That's it.
Like I guess she came up,
it came up,
I was like,
fuck you,
you fairweather bitch,
how dare you cross me ball washlet cross
you,
what are you talking about?
And she's like,
you congratulated Holly Holm for beating
me,
so fuck you,
you fucking fairweather 115 pounds.
I was just like,
went off on page and page game he told
me and I was like,
honey,
welcome to my world.
She's like,
oh my God.
I'm glad that I saw this side of her.
So I know,
you know,
I'm like,
well.
And she's like,
you know,
because I didn't understand.
She's like,
I told Rhonda like,
I'm sorry if I offended you but you're
not allowed to congratulate whoever I
want.
And um,
she's like,
because,
you know,
I congratulate a rosen.
I'm a unit.
When she beat me,
I was like,
congratulations,
you whoop my ass was a bad
ass performance.
And she's like,
you know,
I just simply told holly,
congratulations once again,
like,
it wasn't anything,
you know,
anti Rhonda,
but Rhonda gets just ripped her nuon
wow.
Like you have to be on team Rhonda for
life.
Yeah,
I guess I've never been on team Rhonda,
some all or none.
No,
that was crazy.
I mean,
people love both ways.
It's interesting like people love your
way,
but people also love like shit talking,
you know,
people love Nate Diaz for that and
people love,
they love the drama,
but they also love someone like you a
hugger.
I'm somewhere in the middle though
because I get a lot of flack for
no my mouth like,
so you just can't go.
I say what I'm thinking and I'm,
I'm pretty transparent and sometimes
people think that,
you know,
I get a lot of flack,
oh you're fake or this.
And I'm like,
not really like,
just because,
you know,
I'm like,
I'll say like I'm a fan of Connor,
I am.
I like his fighting style and his antics
at first were kind of like,
wait,
who is this guy?
What is it?
You know?
And then I'm like,
man,
props to him.
He's done amazing things like good for
him and he's done really good things for
our sport.
But when you didn't show up to film that
commercial,
like I'm not,
you know,
I'll be honest like yeah,
I kind of rubbed me the wrong way
because people are like,
oh,
he does so much more media than you guys
do.
Yeah,
I'd probably does.
You know,
they probably does.
I do a lot.
He probably does more.
I agree.
But I don't have a private jet flying
out to pick me up and bring me back and
fly 20 people in my crew with me too.
He does more.
So he gets more when they bring them to
Vegas,
they put them up in a penthouse,
you know,
they make sure he has everything that he
needs.
I don't get that,
you know,
that I'm,
that's fine.
You know,
he's earned that.
He's in that spot.
No problem with that.
But I think three months out from a
fight camp,
you know,
you have a private jet coming to pick
you up with.
You can bring one of your teammates.
You could probably work out on the jet
if you want to,
on the way there because it's yours,
it's private.
Do whatever you want.
Right.
You could probably hit mental agenda.
You could totally,
you know,
I mean,
you're three months out and you don't
want to show for your media obligations.
Like I don't really understand that.
I don't like it just,
I don't know.
I guess I'm trying to figure it out,
but the only issue that I had and it,
it doesn't bother me.
Like if he didn't want to do it,
that's his own thing.
The thing is,
is that I showed up the day to film the
commercial and I had two segments I was
supposed to film and that's all that was
on my schedule.
And then they asked me.
They're like,
can you please help us out because
Connor's not here and uh,
we don't know what we're doing for this
third segment of the commercial that was
supposed to be conor and nate.
So can you please come back later that
day and film that segment Muslim,
that was during my practice time.
So I had to come back and you know,
I did it.
So it was a company woman,
but like it was just frustrating because
it's like Dang,
you know,
if I had known about this,
I could have planned my training
otherwise,
but now I kind of have to like scramble
to get my second workout in and then it
affected me.
So yeah,
his decision did.
And it probably is actually,
you know,
I haven't made any more money in the
sport yet because of Connor.
A lot of people like to like,
oh,
you must have got a bigger payday
because I last,
I'm like,
no,
because I wasn't the champion so I
didn't get any more of like get any
paper views.
I get any more money and now he's like
not on this fight card.
So I'm like,
you know,
but it's whatever,
it's,
it's connors deal and uh,
I,
I don't hate connor,
but I'm going to say how I feel,
you know?
And I would say it if he was sitting
here too.
I'm like,
dude,
why did you do that?
You probably,
I feel like there's a bunch of issues
here and we are the only way to really
get a firm understanding of it is to sit
down with everyone involved and say what
was communicated your manager?
Did he know what the,
what the appearance schedule was going
to be like?
Did you guys agree to this?
Did you understand what you were getting
into when you were fighting?
Maybe it's a misunderstanding,
you know,
who knows?
It's hard to say,
but it's the way he went about it was
ridiculous.
Like saying I'm retired,
thanks for the cheese.
And then saying I'm not retired.
And then saying I'm glad the UFC decided
to give the fans what they want and be,
I'm going to be on UFC 200 numbers.
Like what?
And so like what he's doing is he's kind
of like using the media to try to get
this thing to pass through,
but he doesn't understand Dana and
Lorenzo and frank,
like that's never going to work.
Like you're,
you're either in or you're not in like.
And they're like real clear about that.
They have to set a precedent.
So like if you say fuck you,
I'm not doing media that kind of go oh
well okay fuck you,
you're not fighting,
but hold on,
I'm conor mcgregor where the UFC,
this is what it is.
My name is Doris,
don't make many more
and we might lose millions of dollars
because you're not on UFC 200.
Yeah,
well he,
he,
he had put,
they put 10 million ended up promoting
this Saturday 10 million and he's like
we're way over budget,
you know.
So that's why I was like you've got to
show up and do you know that's how
connor was made is through that stuff.
So now like at what point do you get to
decide that you don't have to do that
anymore?
Like if that's what made you who you are
like I mean don't,
you kind of have to like,
does that make sense what I'm saying?
I mean at what point do you get to
decide like when you don't have to like,
like I use the machine and now like I
don't,
I just want to hop off now that I'm
here.
I don't know.
Do you kind of have to keep it the same
boys?
I think so,
but there is also like a fine line,
right?
Like you can do too much.
Like when I was watching the Jose Aldo
media tour when they were going all
around the world,
I'm like,
okay,
I understand that you want to promote
this fight.
Yeah,
but how much of this is helping the
actual fight itself and then how much of
it is just conor mcgregor constantly
talking Shit at press conferences and
grabbing the belt and all that.
That mean that's really kind of selling
the fight.
Was that.
I don't know.
They did a lot of it,
but apparently connor was sick.
Like he was like,
I'm just constantly fighting off a cold
is really hard to get in shape.
Really hard to train because every week
you know you're traveling from here to
there and they already here.
It's just you're constantly getting
beaten down and you know what it's like
if I give you ever.
Have you ever flown into Brazil and
fought?
No.
I fall in there for fight cards though.
What is the furthest you've ever had a
flight of fight?
Japan?
Japan.
So that's an interesting one because
it's a long flight,
like 16 hours,
right?
What is it like?
Like,
like adjusting and then competing?
I try to
started adjusting my schedule at home,
like black and white windows a little
bit or you know,
like to,
to make the timeframe but you'd never
get fully adjusted.
But the,
my mind frame is like when,
when push comes to shove,
when fight time comes,
whether it's two in the morning,
my time or not like I'm going to be game
so I would just look at it that way but
it's not fun.
Like I remember three weeks out from my
fight with Retina Chi,
which I didn't even want to.
I didn't want to do that fight because
she was so unknown.
She was undefeated.
I'm going over there to fight on a newly
blooming fight pass and I was like,
this is like,
feels like it does nothing for me.
And like if she wins it,
springboards her,
you know,
then she'll be 17 and no shove a judo
background.
They're going to want to make that fight
for,
for her and Rhonda.
I know that's what they're trying to do
is they're trying to use,
you know,
business use me as that springboard.
It's like I don't really want to use but
I did it but three weeks before the
fight they had me fly to Japan to do
some promotional stuff and I was flying
longer than I was even on the ground and
they said like ticket sales went up and
everything was really good.
But yeah,
that was exhausting.
So I do,
I understand that before.
Yeah,
that's hard.
Really hard.
Ramping it up three weeks in super hard
and after my fight with holly I got to
spend a little time in Australia and
then I went straight from Australia to
New York.
Spent a day there,
did a full day of media,
went to Connecticut to espn,
what to Toronto,
did a full day media and it's just like,
it's non stop from like you start your
first interview at eight in the morning
so you have to pick up at like seven and
you go until seven at night and even
while you're driving to the next place
they'll have you on the phone.
Was with the,
with the,
with uh,
you know,
with a radio interview,
I mean there's no break.
It's all,
it's,
it's pretty intense.
It's pretty crazy.
It's pretty exhausting.
So I get it.
I've been in those shoes before.
But um,
you know,
it's,
I don't know,
maybe there's more extended research.
Maybe he was hurt or something.
Maybe you didn't want people to see like
maybe I don't know,
like what if there's even something like
that.
Like what if he had hurt himself or
something and he didn't want nate to
know.
Yeah.
Who knows?
I don't know.
And it's also,
he also had to realize there was a lot
of work that needed to be done to beat
nate.
Yeah.
Like he's hitting eight with some of his
best shots and nate was fine with it and
it was a real problem.
That's more what it was,
is that he was just obsessed with
beating nay and I,
I get that too.
I don't take that away from him for a
minute.
Like he wanted to stay home and.
Or he was in Iceland I guess training
and he wants to train to be nate.
I get it.
Totally get it.
Yeah,
I get it too.
It seems like the only way also I felt
like.
But then again he could have brought us
whole gym with him,
you know?
Sure.
We could have tried.
I mean it was going to be a difficult
time just trying to find the moments to
train and to stay in shape.
And then obviously being exhausted from
flying and all that jazz
turnaround too.
You know,
like as far as.
Well I don't think he was supposed to be
there more than like two days.
I
honestly think he's better off not doing
it.
I honestly think he's better off like
sequestering himself for a few months,
like really focusing on what went wrong,
how to correct it and can you correct
it?
I mean,
do you like when it comes to the ground
game,
what I saw on the ground,
I was like,
boy,
this is a long road.
Like you've got a long road to beat.
A guy like nate,
he's so much further along in,
in and ground and pound Jujitsu,
positioning everything.
When I was watching nate beat them up on
the ground and choke him,
I was like,
whoa.
That happened quick.
This is not like Weidman and rockhold
was a prolonged beating before rockhold
eventually stopped him the next round.
Yeah,
but with why with nate and connor wasn't
that prolonged.
It happened pretty quickly and when you
see that you go,
Ooh,
this is going to be.
There's a lot to overcome.
It's not unsurmountable takes.
A lot of times the skill sets,
they don't just.
They don't come overnight.
You don't.
He can pick up your cardio pretty quick.
You can do a lot of things.
You can't,
you can't build a skill set any faster
than it's going to go through your
muscle memory and being Rep.
you've got to put thousands of reps in
and there's no way around it.
There's no way.
There's no way to fast forward through
that.
There's no way to cut the corner.
There's no right.
You can't just repetition,
repetition,
repetition would also.
It highlights all the various eccentric
aspects of your training that people are
like,
hmm,
is this what makes connor great?
And you know,
and then,
you know,
nate calling it touch button,
the park,
like the dude,
all these cartwheels and stuff.
Then video is so funny.
Hilarious.
Oh my God.
I was dying laughing.
Clarius.
So when this all,
you know he's doing all these work with
this movement guy,
but then you see what happens when it
actually comes to fighting skills and
you go,
oh,
maybe this is not the way to do it
because like I've talked to a lot of
people that were like this stuff that
he's doing his utter horse shit like
this.
Doing cartwheels and being obsessed with
movement.
Here's the movements you need to be
worried about.
Okay.
Moving your feet,
throwing kicks and punches.
Take down defense and Jujitsu on the
ground.
That's it.
You know,
understanding takedowns yourself,
taking people down if you must,
trip sweeps,
all that stuff.
But all this cart wheels and what this
guy was explaining to me,
and I want to name any names because
they're prominent guy.
He was like,
you have to understand that there's a
limited amount of energy you have in
your time training and you are not
perfect at all of these other aspects of
mma.
So if you are not perfect all these
other aspects of,
uh,
may you have to say,
okay,
how much.
Yeah,
how much of this stuff is going to help
me?
Will a guy like George St Pierre,
he looked at gymnastics and he was like,
you know what's going to help me because
I can be stronger physically and there's
no better way.
I think like as far as like manipulating
your body than gymnastics,
like doing the rings and developing a
perception.
Yeah,
you're learning how to manipulate your
body and all kinds of contorted
positions being upside down and
understanding where you are
when you're upside down and where you're
going to be with the momentum you have.
You have to calculate that your mouth is
doing constant algorithms and math
equations essentially when you're
fighting to weight distribution where we
are,
especially when you tie up with someone
else and you have to feel their way and
you have to manipulate it in a way to
get it where you want,
whether it's against the cage or whether
it's on the ground,
your body is using a equation.
You know your mind is equating,
how much force do I need to make this
happen?
How little forest?
Like what if I go the opposite direction
because they're pushing into me.
There's all these different things that
you have to over.
There's no other way to do it.
Then then a trial and error process and
over and over and over and over again.
Yeah,
and you look at someone who's like
really good at one aspect of MMA,
like Yoel Romero who is just a
ridiculous wrestler,
and you go,
okay,
look how much touch button the park.
Is that guy doing cartwheels?
Is he doing?
Is he tumbling?
No,
but I bet you he does 100 double eggs a
day at least.
Well,
he's doing all kinds of legs and then
100 body locks.
Then,
you know,
connor lost.
Everybody's like,
this is what we need.
We need a movement coach.
I need to move in,
coach,
you know,
and it still might.
I mean as
George St Pierre,
it has massive benefits to get that kind
of coordination.
Physical strength.
Do you like about connor though?
Is like um,
his balance is impeccable and that could
be part of that and like he is never
over himself,
at least with the striking part of it in
the ground is a completely different
thing.
But when he's in striking range and it's
just his body,
his eye hand coordination is incredible.
And his balance,
like he's never too far over a punch.
He's never too far back.
He's always centered,
he's always centered,
he throws a kick,
he never gets,
you know,
you see people kick and they miss and
they kinda like stumbled like their
weights off balance or,
or they kick and even land and even when
they put their foot down it's kind of
like,
it's not a good landing,
you know,
like I'm not like the world's best
kicker,
but when I watched conor do it,
it's like he kicks or push kicks and
sticks it.
He is like a,
like a,
a gymnast in the sense,
you know,
the flip and then they want to just
boom,
stick it like.
And he's really,
really good at that sense.
Maybe that's where the movement does
benefit.
I think.
So then he never is over himself in his
weight distribution but isn't the case
whenever someone loses though,
everyone always second guess is what
they were doing.
Even if what they were doing was getting
them to be like 16 and no,
totally undefeated world champion.
When you'd make a mistake or something
goes wrong or something goes right for
your opponent,
we should probably say immediately
people start questioning everything you
did.
Yeah,
definitely all the time.
I mean it happened with me when,
you know,
when I lost to Toronto,
that guy,
you got to change this,
you gotta change everything,
but as long as you're winning people
like,
yeah,
keep doing what you're doing and it's
working,
and then he loses it,
like change everything.
It's like,
Jeez,
that was quick.
Well,
that's also the Rhonda criticism in the
Holly Holm fight.
Everybody was like looking at her like a
dominating Betco.
Heyo would stand up,
you know,
I'm beating
Sarah Mcmahon and the way she did Alexis
Davis beating her down the way she did
and go,
we'll look.
Rhonda obviously is getting so good at
striking,
so just such an elite athlete that she
can do what she's doing to anybody and
then her trainer saying that she could
go box women professionals and knock
them out and so you get this thing in
your head that you can do what you have
been doing and then you fight someone
like holly and you go,
Oh,
well,
okay.
Yeah,
there's a leather sole.
There's so many levels.
I mean,
it's one of the more fascinating things
about martial arts is that there are so
many levels.
Yeah.
And there's never.
It's never ending.
Never ending story really is,
right?
Yeah.
Is this a song that I ever just goes on?
Um,
no,
it's,
it's literally,
it's you never injected when you think
you have it all figured out.
Boom.
There goes the curve ball.
I think that's what's addicting about
this sport though.
Like it's safe to say it's like a drug.
It's,
it's addicting.
I think adversity in some weird way.
I'm definitely addicted to that.
I like it when things seem
insurmountable or their look too hard or
other people don't believe that I can do
it.
That's such a weird quality because most
people have the opposite.
Most people are like,
I like it when I know I can take a nap.
I liked it.
I like it when that couch looks soft and
I'm gonna walk over there and plop
myself down.
I'll let you know.
And you're like,
I'm going to run up that fucking
mountain with no air.
See how I see how long I could go before
I pass out.
Weird quality.
Yeah.
Um,
I don't know.
It is weird,
but I like it.
I Dunno like that about myself because I
know anytime I ever get into a hard
situation about,
about anything,
it's like I can get through it.
I've,
I've seen worse,
you know.
Well you definitely have proven that.
There's no doubt about it.
You know,
and you've proven it inside the octagon
just leading up to this fight.
Obviously he proved it in this fight,
but you proved it leading up to this
fight.
Like the Sara Mcmann fight I think was
one of your most impressive fights
because you got her down and you were me
and she's a fucking silver medalist in
the Olympics and you were dominating the
top position.
You out scrambled or you stayed on top
of her and beat her down and I was like,
that is it does it.
Big victory.
Heavy top game.
You do.
We should grapple sometime.
Okay.
Well I'm scared now.
Girls say we should grapple sometimes.
Yeah.
But always gets odd.
Weird,
quick.
No,
I'm sure you do.
I'm sure,
yeah,
but um,
it comes to wrestling and I think just
experience and knowing,
you know,
wrestling can translate.
A lot of sports can translate well into
two mix.
Marsha,
I happen to think wrestling is one of
the best translations,
you know,
as opposed to like someone typically
boxers coming into the sport don't
typically transition as well.
Kickboxers,
you know,
because they have so much more to learn.
I feel like the fundamentals of
wrestling kind of the,
they,
they encompass a lot of what you need in
mma and if you are the better wrestler
you can decide do I want to stay on the
feeder?
I want to take it to the ground.
It dictates what dictates.
So with that said,
um,
I think I learned how to use the pieces
that work for wrestling and MMA and take
out the ones that don't because there's
a lot of stuff in the wrestling or any
other sport that you're going to bring
over the doesn't work from because I'm
amazed the sport of its own.
And I think maybe like Mcmahon Ha,
like she's such an elite level wrestler
that she's so ingrained with just
wrestle,
wrestle that it's hard sometimes with
the more elite you are at something to
like water it down again,
essentially.
That's kind of what you have to do that
you have to take pieces out for mixed
martial arts.
There's some things that you don't want
to do because Oh,
you got choked.
If you do that,
you know,
like when you're in wrestling,
the last thing you want to do is be on
your back.
So you turn over you and you arch out,
you lift your neck.
It's like,
Oh man,
if you try to do that,
you try to stand up the way that you
wouldn't.
A wrestling match,
you're going to get choked,
can't do that.
You've got to keep your Chin tucked and
then you've got to hand fight.
So there's things that you have to
relearn.
And I think when you're such an elite
elitist at something,
sometimes it's hard to relearn those.
That's very good point.
And I think you could also use that same
point where you're talking about
strikers learning takedown defense and
that like a lot of strikers like to
stand up really straight and you know,
as soon as they get involved in
exchanges with people,
they fall into their old striking ways.
And that's when a got like George St
Pierre who was so good at being
unpredictable.
Like you never knew if he was going to
take you down if he's going to stand for
one of the most flawless fighters.
When you say as far as like a game by
sticking a game plan and being
disciplined and we're getting emotional.
Never getting away from the game plan.
Well in his prime,
you look at during his run and no one
keeps her run up forever.
But during his run,
I mean he beat everybody.
They put in front of him and he fought
in some incredible fights where he
fought some really,
really dangerous difficult guys and
manage his way through the water to
victory.
And that's all you could ever expect
from a champion.
And people will say like,
oh well here's some of the sites were
boring,
or he played safety first.
Like Jesus Christ,
he fought the killers of the killers and
he had five rounds and in during those
five rounds,
you know,
Carlos Condit head kicks him and drops
him.
Matt Serra knocked him out and won the
title.
He's had adversity like,
but he beat everybody.
You can't ask for more.
Like what do you think would happen if
he just,
there's this mentality that some fans
want where they want a guy who wants a
bite down his mouthpiece and just swing
away and like come on seven and hope for
the best.
That's so retarded.
Like that's not what martial arts are
about.
Not One hundred percent people.
People sometimes tend to enjoy the
excitement of amateur fights more
because they're more chaotic.
Like people don't know what they're
doing.
So it's just like stick to two people in
there that Kinda know how to throw
punches and maybe Kinda know how to
wrestle and they just go balls to the
wall because that's like,
that's all that they know that they're
confident in.
Just go as hard as you can.
It's also like a really good debate
between two very articulate and very
intelligent people.
No one is going to get the real upper
hand real quick.
There's gonna be points and
counterpoints is going to go back and
forth.
Both guys going to be very well
prepared.
Both women are going to be very well
You're not going to get like a very
clear winner right away unless something
crazy happens.
Like Aldo in Mcgregor,
like all those just so mad at Mcgregor
from all this fucking shit talking he's
been doing for months and months and
months that he just runs at them and
gets clipped crazy.
For a guy like Aldo,
that's gotta be maddening.
You hold the title for nine fucking
years or however long you held it.
I think it was in second.
Oh my God.
I mean any scene,
although do that.
He was so emotionally charged.
Yeah.
He was very upset and that just goes to
show how much the mind is a powerful
thing.
It's like if you.
If if you,
if you think you can or think you can't,
you're right.
Either way,
it's,
it's really derived from your,
your mind,
you know,
and,
and you can have all the skills in the
world if you don't believe you can do it
or,
or whatever.
You don't have the confidence in your
mind,
you won't just interesting.
Or if someone puts a seed in there and
like,
like connor,
I just think that he was so good at the
mental warfare and you know,
Josie never had to deal with that.
Never.
That was the thing.
It was like
he was all respect.
Everyone that he fought,
shook his hand,
respected him.
I realized he's this killer.
I mean,
and he was the reigning featherweight
champion for as long as there was a
featherweight champion.
He was the first,
the original.
He held that title for longer than
anybody and was flawless.
I mean he had some amazing fights,
but he started this show,
like some chinks in his armor or towards
the end,
like the second fight that he had with
Chad Mendez.
Like it's shit like that was a real war
and real grueling fight.
Whereas,
you know,
the first fight with Mendez,
he just looks insane.
It looked tremendous and stop Mendez
quick,
so I think nobody rides for free.
They train so hard in Brazil to.
They're insane.
No doubt God no.
And yellow in particular.
Yeah,
they go to war.
There's a good saying about training.
I'm smarter and not harder sometimes are
working,
you know,
usually it's working,
but same thing goes for training.
Overtraining is a big thing in this.
Yeah.
I'm glad you brought that up because I
wanted to talk to you about that because
you had mentioned that in the hallway
fight he had made sure,
you know,
we were training for a five round fight
in particular.
How do you make sure that you are in
peak performance level but you're not
overtraining?
Like who?
Who Designs your program?
Well,
you know,
I think a lot of it depends on athlete
input.
Does someone can design a program,
but if you show up one day and you're
supposed to be pushing sleds,
you know,
or do something heavy and hard and
you're like,
I'm exhausted.
Then they're like,
okay,
we need to dial back your feedback.
Your heart rate.
Yeah.
I wear like a polar heart rate monitor,
I take it in the morning when you wake
up and all the HRV and see where I'm at.
And that's really helpful.
The heart rate variable.
Okay.
So basically it tells you how,
how your heart is recovering.
So when you first wake up in the
morning,
um,
from my understanding,
the more like the more that your heart
is kind of like irregular,
maybe for a better sense of terms means
that it's responding to things like
quickly if it's kind of sluggish and
it's Kinda like not really,
not really reading that kind of quick
reaction,
then it's not,
then you're tired,
your body is still broken down.
It's not recovered though,
you're,
you're kind of looking for that
irregular kind of Bouncy,
you know,
I don't know if it's a rhythm,
but there's something that the,
the hrv reads,
not just the heart rate but something
about the heart in it and it reads it.
The heart rate variable and I'm tells
you whether you're actually recovered or
not.
And who goes over this stuff with you?
Do you have a?
Um,
no,
not really.
My sports doctor,
I'll go over it with him.
You know,
you're basically calling the shots.
Yeah,
and it's,
it's really easy to read.
It's either green,
orange or red,
like if you're in the red,
don't kill yourself that day.
Like it tells you it's,
it's,
you know,
it's very simple.
Anyone can do it.
A wake up in the morning and if your
heart rate variables in the red,
that means like there should be a
relatively easy day either a rest day or
relatively easy and maybe should go for
a nice run,
like just let your body recover because
if you don't realize you don't get
stronger while you're training,
you don't get stronger while you're
lifting weights,
you're actually damaging your body.
You're actually going backwards.
You get stronger when you're resting,
recovering from the work.
And that's what,
that's.
That's literally what it is,
is when you're resting,
after you've worked out hard and after
you tore everything apart.
I mean if you work out 24 slash seven,
there's no chance to repair and heal and
grow and get stronger.
So you know,
it,
it just goes back to that,
that science and that balance of when to
push hard and when to,
when to not push hard.
And I think that our sport typically has
a lot of really tough people who don't
like to ever think,
you know,
they're just in that work hard mentality
because we're fighters.
We're like the toughest people,
but a lot of times they don't stop and
think like,
it doesn't matter how tough you are.
Like science is science buddy,
you know,
it's,
it doesn't matter.
You're going,
I'm just going to work out harder.
I'm going to push through it.
I'm gonna spar hard today even though I
feel like crap.
Like,
I mean there's something we said maybe
for mental toughness,
I guess,
you know,
you're going to go in there and you're
going to push through it.
There's times for that.
But,
um,
I don't question my mental toughness.
So I just listen to my body.
You know,
I don't,
I'm not at a point in my career where I
have anything to prove as far as like
how tough I am.
Skins and Misha,
my coaches always tell me like,
we're not,
we don't need to approve how tough you
are.
Me Should we already know that?
So let's just,
uh,
if you don't feel like sparring today
was tomorrow.
Well that's one of the things
that I think really does trip up a lot
of fighters is that they're so tough and
they figure out how to push through
injuries to figure out how to force
themselves through situations,
but then they get these,
these damage to their joints are damaged
to their back or.
And a lot of it comes from not recognize
the difference between an actual injury
and pain.
Just a little bit of discomfort and pain
is normal.
It's constant.
It's never going to go away.
Everybody who does martial arts
experiences that,
but for someone like Cain Velasquez,
it almost becomes like a detriment
because he's such a fucking gorilla and
he just knows how to push through
everything that he blows everything out.
He blows his shoulder out and then he
blows the other shoulder around.
He his knees out.
It blows back out.
I mean,
he's,
in my opinion,
when he was at his best,
he's the greatest of all time is between
him and fader.
Those are the two possible heavyweights
and the fate or one always has to have
an asterick because he was fighting in
pride and it was,
you know,
the steroid era,
you could do whatever the fuck you want.
Not saying even that he was on it,
but who the fuck knows,
but that,
I don't think the guys that he fought,
even though he looked amazing against
them,
I don't think Hong Man Choi is at the
same level as like junior dos Santos
when junior dos Santos was at his best
when,
when cain fought them.
It's so hard to.
And I think even junior dos Santos was
overtrained for one of their fights and
you know,
they talked about it like they had
measured his,
um,
his,
creatine levels in his blood and he was,
he was,
he just hadn't recovered correctly.
Yep.
That,
that's so common.
It's a big part of it.
It's very being so tough because you see
people go in,
whether it's a three round fight or a
five round fight,
sometimes you'll see people gas out like
a round and a half around it and you're
like,
oh,
they must not a train hard.
No,
it's probably the.
They trained too hard.
Yeah,
that's probably what it is.
They're probably still beat up
sometimes.
Like I will go like fight week and I'll
be in the workout,
you know the mat room that they have in
the hotel and sometimes I'll see these
guys in there and they're just going.
I mean they are going,
they're hitting mitts.
They're just ripping the big take downs
and they're just blowing it all out.
I'm just like thinking,
dude,
it's fight week calmed down and the hard
work should have already all been done.
Like this week is about recovery and
usually it's like people not like
foreigners that are still in that
mindset of like know they're a little
bit more old school mentality.
I feel like some of those gyms still
haven't caught up to the.
The idea that it's not always about how
hard you go.
Well,
Matt Hughes told me that he used to
train hard up until the day of the
fight.
They just trained hard and he's like
always trained hard and you know,
yeah,
fucking work though.
Worked for him.
Well,
you know,
but he was,
he was a high level athlete for a long
time and he knew how to,
how to harness what and you know,
it's not saying that it can't,
that it can't work,
but I still think that there's something
to be said about preserving the
longevity of your career.
You might not be able to do that as long
you know.
Well,
with a guy like Matt Hughes,
it's so hard to,
to say that now because he was such a
pioneer.
I mean he was at the early,
early days of the UFC and it was one of
the great champions and one of the
greatest champions ever.
And when you look at his title run and
his reign of 170 pound division,
like during his heyday,
he had to say like this guy,
like he's sort of paved the way and a
lot of ways,
especially for a wrestler that developed
some really good submission skills.
I mean he's got some excellent
submission victories,
including that arm bar that he submitted
George St Pierre with mean he had some
really good submission skills for a
wrestler.
Yeah,
he's incredible.
Is that it was time a little bit,
you know,
definitely ahead of his time.
And you know,
an an important pioneer.
If you look at the overall game like
these,
there's these moments where a person
emerges and they go,
okay,
we haven't seen one of those guys
before.
Like Yoyo Rodriguez is a perfect
example.
Like this fucking guy.
I watched that guy fight and I go,
Jesus Christ,
like here's a new thing.
Here's a guy who's like this elite
taekwondo guy who knows how to do
everything else too.
But he throws these taekwondo kicks,
like a normal person throws a jab.
He just,
they're a part of his arsenal.
He's throwing,
jumping,
roundhouse kicks and we'll kicks and
he's,
he's doing shit that like,
you gotta you gotta get ready for this
because this guy's going to do this
every round and this is a totally
different type of engaging a.
you've got to be aware of things coming
from all these crazy angles and they're
coming fast.
These wheeled kicks and the jumping
roundhouse kick did hit a feely with
like,
Holy Shit.
That was crazy.
Fucking crazy.
And he's,
he's one of these new guys.
It's like he's got so much skill.
We used to train with philly.
Did you?
Sacramento were a part of the team Alpha
male and it was funny like he,
he's come such a long way like he,
he used to have for some reason he had
like a house arrest thing on his ankle,
like the bad things,
you know,
train with it on.
He had to trim it that.
But he did not want to train.
So I guess he got permission to go to
the gym and I don't know what it was,
you know,
what it was for.
But it's a funny story because it's
like,
I just remember him back then and he was
just still like,
you know,
it was still relatively new to the game
and now you know,
he's doing well and then obviously his
last loss.
Well he zigged and zagged and that's
just what happens in the game.
Yeah.
He got caught and he also fought a guy
who was one of the elite of the elite
right now at 1:45.
He's unpredictable.
So wild.
Yeah.
He and his fucking ground game is really
good to hear.
Can do everything.
Yeah.
Okay.
Something mad he is signed.
I knew he was something but feeling
something to.
He's a tough fucking kid and I thought
that was going to be a great fight like
this.
I'm really interested to see how feeling
navigates the kicks because that's the
big thing.
Is he going to try to kick with this
guy?
Is he going to try to like.
Maybe I'm just like,
bear down like did you,
do you watch Gloria at all?
A little bit.
Did you see Raymond Daniels and Joseph
Valvoline?
Valvoline.
He is a traditional Moy Thai style
fighter and he just just kept his hands
up high and just chop the legs and
chopped them down and eventually knocked
them out with a head kick,
but Raymond Daniels is this wild
motherfucker,
throws,
jumping,
spinning,
threesixty,
turning sidekicks to your face and all
this wild shit.
And he was a point karate champion who
eventually got into kickboxing and he's
so wild with his kicks.
Just he hit this guy with a touch front
leg side kick and then spun in the air
and hit them with a spinning back kick
to the face where people like that who
can recreate that style to get someone
like him.
You'd have to get a karate or that.
It's like it's all you can get,
you know?
Well,
it's people that don't understand that
there's,
there's some skills that these
traditional martial artists have like a
traditional,
like a lot of karate guys and a lot of
talk window guys in particular.
There's some things that they can do
with their legs.
The average person just can't do.
And if that karate guy or that taekwondo
guy like a year Rodriguez,
learns wrestling,
learns Jujitsu,
and learns kickboxing,
and has all that shit at a really elite
black belt level,
you're fucked.
Someone a good friend of yours.
It can do weird things with his legs.
Eddie Bravo.
Oh yeah.
Lowered guy is like,
he's like gumby.
Well he's been stretching his legs like
that.
Like,
like religiously for Jack.
He not that flexible like growing up
now.
He just keeps doing it.
Did Eddie,
when you watch TV with Eddie,
Eddie will never wear shoes.
He doesn't wear shoes.
Just puts his fucking feet everywhere
and it kind of freaks people out.
But Eddie will sit there and he'll just
like be like stretching himself up.
So He'd be sitting watching TV and he'll
be ready to get to,
but he'll be like sitting there and
it'll hold it and he can do that without
like pulling on it.
Like he doesn't have to have arms that
pull his legs in these positions so he
could just tuck his legs in the places
and all of a sudden you're like locked
up in a Gogo plot.
And you don't even know how the fuck he
got his leg there.
I know I grappled with him once years
ago.
He was like retarded.
Really tricky.
But he's like,
dude,
you're like grappling with the dude.
Is that feel good or that.
Yeah,
that's always a compliment.
As long as people don't say,
I look like a dude,
I can grapple.
I could do it all day long.
And that's never,
you know,
never an issue.
I dread the day when like I love it when
people were like,
oh,
you don't look like a fighter.
I'm like,
good,
that's good.
Because like,
it really dread the day when people
like,
man,
you look like a fighter.
Like,
oh whoops.
Went too far.
I,
I pushed the edge of the envelope and I
didn't come out on the winning side.
The grapple like a dude is isn't okay.
Like,
yeah,
you make out like a dude that's not yet.
How do you know?
Is this conversation going back?
Well,
there is a definite difference between
watching some women grapple and what
some women can do it in.
This got to be some benefits to like
being a woman when it comes to
grappling.
There is sometimes like,
yeah,
oh,
rappel some guys and I don't realize
it's much different to be like,
man,
you are so flexible or like you've got,
you know,
your ankles.
Like I try to log and it was like most
guys would attack,
but he was like,
you were fine.
I was like,
I,
you know,
I don't know.
Have you ever seen this thing that
ballerinas used?
And this is a,
I think it's a new device,
but it's like you slide your foot into
like this.
It seems like a rubber sheath has like
this,
a flat board and they just like this
rubber sheath and you slide your foot
into and that do these exercises
with your foot.
And somebody put it up on one of the
Jujitsu pages that I follow on
instagram.
And they were like,
this is the best way to prevent foot
locks.
Like literally it just strengthens it,
strengthens it,
and stretches it to the point where if
somebody gets you into like a,
um,
a footlocker and they're pushing down
like a toehold in there as they're
pushing down on your foot,
it's the hyper extending of the ankle if
it gets you to tap because you're like,
oh,
I think someone's going to tear and the
people tap and this gets your foot into
this flexible position where you've kind
of strengthen and make it so flexible
that you can't get tapped in certain
ways.
You never tried.
You haven't Jamie's odors.
Huh?
That looks similar.
That's similar as pro arch.
Is that what's it's called?
That looks like it's making it like
where your feet are like.
So yeah,
like the arch of the Ballerina foot.
That's probably like strengthening.
Huh?
To be able to stand on that.
What does that.
You weren't.
Birkenstocks is brutal.
The feet feet are so nasty,
so bad.
It's like,
Oh,
I thought my feet were bad news girl who
is a ballerina,
and she had to have her feet fixed
because her,
her toes,
she had smashed her toes for so long,
like doing like point and trying to
stand on their toes that she had to get,
like she had these scars over the top of
her feet where she had to get her toes,
like realigned and deter ligaments
repaired.
Valets,
a hard hard support from,
from my understanding,
like I don't think they get enough
credit.
They also have to starve themselves.
You have to be one.
Did you see that swan movie?
Was it black?
Yeah,
freaky.
It was insane.
Oh yeah.
It's not a woman's empowering sort of
activity.
Yeah.
I posted a picture of me with a scale of
the day,
like weighing myself.
People like 1:47,
they're like freaking out about it or
whatever.
I'm like,
yeah,
wait,
you know,
almost 150 pounds.
But they're like,
I feel like that's good that not,
you know,
it goes to show you don't have to be a
hundred pounds or 110 pounds to look
good or be beautiful or whatever.
And I'm like,
yeah,
I don't,
I'm not ashamed of what I way at all,
like at all at all.
I don't care.
I get weigh a hundred 60 pounds as long
as I look good and feel good.
Like,
you know,
people were just kind of surprised that
I guess women have numbers in their head
that you don't want to go over.
Yeah.
Thirty five is like the peak.
Don't get bigger than this.
Yeah,
I think it used to be like 1:10.
My mom's best friend growing up,
she was um,
she was Vietnamese and they had,
they had a rule where she's having to
me,
so the Vietnamese side of her family,
so she was a little bit bigger bone.
Gorgeous,
beautiful.
Like exotic green eyes,
dark black hair like halfway to me is
really,
really pretty.
And um,
her family was so hard on her because
she weighed over a hundred pounds,
like you were supposed to be under.
You're supposed to be 99 or less because
they're all super tiny,
but she was half,
so her aunt,
she got her half of her White Dad's side
and she was like on nine or something
and was like,
Yo,
you lose weight,
Lynn.
Lynn,
you lose weight.
You too heavy.
Too heavy.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Oh yeah.
And she had just,
she got eating disorders and stuff like
that.
And like later,
because she was so just mortified that
she weighed more,
you know,
they didn't want her to weigh over 100.
Oh,
that's so crazy.
The number crazy number on things.
Numbers.
Yeah.
It doesn't matter to me.
How do you look if you look good,
what does it,
what difference does it make?
Like obviously being a fighter,
you're going to be denser.
I mean,
how anybody wouldn't understand that a
woman like you,
what do you like?
Five,
seven,
five,
six,
145 pounds.
You're going to have a ton of muscle.
I mean,
you have to,
if you're doing all the grappling,
you're doing what kind of strength and
conditioning program and you on,
um,
I go usually like two,
three days a week and I go to this place
called phase one sports and they work
with a lot of athletes that were the
boxers and football players and things
like that.
So I do like the most that I really do
for like actual lifting weights is
probably power cleans or like hang
cleans.
I go,
you know,
flip the bar that's I think really good
explosive movement for um,
like for wrestling and things like that.
Um,
I do sled pushing and do a lot of body
weight stuff,
a lot of footwork and you know,
um,
we kind of mix cardio and weight so
we'll do like,
he'll like do one set of the workout
that's strength based.
So it's like anaerobic.
And then we'll run sprints.
So kind of like to simulate a fight.
Like you're going through a,
a combination and it's anaerobic,
you throwing five,
six punches and you're doing that
without oxygen.
Anaerobic.
And then you do something where,
you know,
you circle away and you move or
something that's a robotic,
you know,
are you coming for the take down?
That's kind of an anaerobic movement.
And then so it simulates the fight.
So we do a lot of,
um,
I don't know,
it's not really anything super rocket
science,
I don't think.
But I like it.
It works for me.
She's done a strength and conditioning
program.
I love strength and conditioning and I'm
in high school and stuff.
I lifted a lot of weights.
I get criticized a lot actually in high
school because I was pretty buff in high
school and I wrestled and criticized
when girls or boys actually guys mostly
I think the girls were kind of scared of
me even though I was never
confrontational.
I never really fought people.
It was like pretty nice everyone.
But I'm like,
I don't know,
the girls are probably like,
if they knew,
if they would mess with me,
I probably would have wrecked them.
You know what?
I was just kinda like passive.
I was a people watcher and uh,
yeah,
like the guys were like,
man,
stop lifting.
MEESHA getting to buff.
Like maybe you need to lift more.
Were you wrestling in high school?
I wrestled in high school.
What was that like?
That was hard,
man.
It was actually the first half of my
season was terrible.
But you wrestling dudes.
Are you wrestling girls?
Primarily guys.
That's ridiculous.
I was the only consistent female on my
team for four years.
What the fuck motivated you to go do
that?
I'm just like wrestling dudes.
Yeah.
No,
actually that was that.
Like I said,
it was terrible.
Like my first day.
My Gosh.
Well I'll get to why I did it.
I did it because I can't play
basketball.
That was really the reason why I didn't
do it.
Did you want to play basketball?
No,
I hate basketball.
Well that's probably why he can't play
basketball because I bet if you wanted
to play basketball you figured out how
to get really good at basketball.
So don't,
don't say you can't play basketball.
It would have been a long road man.
I couldn't it ever tell you.
It's taken a long time as if MMA isn't a
long road,
but it's way more fun.
What does it mean crazy though,
that the odds of you getting famous as a
female basketball player or nonexistent?
Yeah,
there was like,
I mean the NBA still exists,
right?
Name one famous NBA player named one.
Go ahead.
Ready Go.
You can't do it.
But female fighters at the time,
it was ridiculous.
If you're in high school and said one
day I'm going to be a female cage
fighter.
People like it was crazy bitch.
Get away from her.
She never fucking mind.
Meanwhile you're famous.
He was just barely coming out.
I was like,
so I know it's crazy.
Um,
so I decided to do it out of default
because I want to do,
to do a sport,
but I was really reluctant to play
basketball or even try.
Didn't like,
it just didn't appeal to me.
You didn't click can't dribble the ball.
He did.
I don't shoot well,
like I didn't pee a couple times.
I'm like,
this is not the sport for me.
I can't jump very high.
Like everything is just like not I'm not
made to play basketball.
And so I went out for wrestling and I
was like,
yeah,
I guess I'll try this.
And uh,
we didn't tell my dad at first either
because he would have probably been
mortified.
He was mortified when we told him,
but it was too late by then already I
was already in.
It was,
I think my mom thought I was going to
quit.
So she tried to hide it from him for
like two,
three weeks or so,
like thinking,
oh,
she's probably going like this,
but I love the girls were on the team
with you.
One other girl that was my best friend,
Sharon,
and it was actually her idea.
I never probably would have thought of
it.
We were an honors English class,
will smarty pants and she looks at me
and she's like,
you know,
everything,
you want to do a sport but I don't want
to play basketball either.
You want to go out for wrestling.
I like wrestling and I always taught
wrestling was so weird.
Like in middle school as a kid I'm like,
what are they doing?
Like these boys in these tight suits
like rolling around.
This is a weird um,
so I had this like distaste for
wrestling,
but it's kind of like,
well,
it's better than basketball probably.
Yeah,
sure.
Let's try it.
Yeah,
that's how.
I mean it's nothing against the
basketball,
but I just,
I just can't.
I don't know.
How did you know that you liked it?
Wrestling?
Yeah.
Well the first day I got my ass kicked
bad.
Like I left with like Matt Burns all
over my body and my face,
like I didn't know what I was doing.
They tried to get me to quit.
They didn't want the girl,
they did not want us there.
And so they meaning the teammates,
teammates and the coaches.
Really?
Yeah,
the coach.
Yeah.
The coach was kind of an ass,
like he was only there for one year.
He actually ended up getting,
he had of getting fired.
But anyways,
um,
yeah,
they did not want us there.
So I think they thought like,
if we make this as
hard on them as possible,
they'll just quit because that's like,
you know,
I think they had a couple years before,
like a girl come out and like they
didn't,
they never lost,
like they never made it past the two
weeks.
So I think I kind of felt that and I was
like,
you just wait for us.
I was like,
I'm going to prove you wrong.
I'm going to stick around,
I'm going to do this.
And I was like,
and as sure as hell no,
I can't get any worse.
It was like,
so the law of diminishing returns says
I'm bound to get better.
And um,
yeah,
I kept coming back every day and it was
the hardest thing that I've ever done.
I think that's why I liked it so much.
It was fucking hard,
really,
really hard.
And they did a lot of conditioning,
a lot of,
you know,
but I loved,
I didn't mind that at all.
Like I love that stuff.
I love working,
I love conditioning,
I love pushing myself.
The part that was the most challenging
was the actual wrestling because they
didn't want to teach us anything.
They didn't teach me anything.
I remember they put me in there with a
guy who placed third in state and he
just wrecked me.
I was like,
can you at least show me a double ad?
I don't know anything.
I don't know how to do any of this
stuff.
Like,
can you show me?
They're like,
just a body.
Yeah.
They're like,
no,
just go wrestle and you just embarrassed
me.
What a Shitty fucking wrestling coach.
Yeah.
Well,
I don't know.
They didn't want us there.
Was that the first time that you knew
about yourself though,
that you liked to overcome adversity
like that,
that you could do liked difficult
challenges?
Looking back on it?
I think so because I didn't realize how
tough I was until I got through like a
wrestling season.
I'm like,
holy crap.
That was really hard.
Brutal for people who've never done
anything difficult to is probably like
the first.
Most people don't say when you start out
with a big team and half the people drop
like flies really quickly,
a couple of kind of dwindle out and
you're left with like a few that are
really there to do it.
And especially with me being so
terrible,
like I lost.
Um,
I mean I probably lost about every match
that you're,
I'd never wrestled before and I was
competing against guys.
Um,
I can't remember exactly.
Uh,
I think I'd be a girl like later in the
season,
my first year and I lost my very first
wrestling match was actually against
another female,
which was rare and it lost by points,
but she was like a senior,
so it was whatever.
I just tried to know.
I got pinned.
That's a lie.
I remember I got Penn,
she was a senior,
it was like second round and I didn't,
I just didn't know very much,
you know.
And uh,
then I went on it.
Actually my senior year I ended up
wrestling varsity.
Whoa.
Yeah,
that's crazy.
So you went through freshmen,
sophomore,
junior,
and senior year.
Yeah.
All four years.
Four years.
You wrestled?
Yeah.
That's amazing.
I loved it.
Won't go live for it.
That's crazy.
Yeah.
And the senior year you were a varsity
wrestler.
What in the fuck what?
Wait,
this is the hilarious part.
Okay.
So.
So I was good but I wasn't male varsity
good.
You know,
I love wrestling.
I worked hard.
I came early,
I stayed late,
I did all that.
But um,
I wasn't that level right.
But,
but the thing was is that we didn't have
152 pounder.
We had to one $45.
So I wrestled 1:45.
I didn't know how to cut weight so it's
just what I was walking at at the time.
I was heavier and heavier in high school
than I am now and I didn't know anything
about diet.
I didn't know anything about anything.
I thought what I joe,
this is how stupid I was.
I thought that when I had to make wait
the next day that I needed to eat the
most low calorie foods,
so I would go like get the jar of salsa
which has had or I don't know how many
thousands of milligrams of sodium,
which is going to help you hold water.
I didn't know.
It's like,
oh,
it's five calories per serving,
let me eat this whole thing.
And then like,
I'm sure it was like a balloon the next
day.
Like it's no wonder like I couldn't cut
any way like nobody,
nobody taught me anything about cutting
wakes up to eat,
throw garbage bag on and run around,
you know.
And so anyways,
um,
there was two,
1:45
pounders,
no 1:52
pounders.
So what they would do is basically I was
the sacrificial lamb.
We would both weigh in at 1:45
for varsity and they would decide which
opponent was more likely for the guy,
our guy teammate to beat.
And they would match him up so that we
could get a win and they would put me
with the tougher opponent.
So that our guy that had a chance at
winning could win because they were like
the new.
Either way I probably wasn't able to win
and get.
I mean these are,
these are tough guys.
Like I've been wrestling for years.
They'd been wrestling their whole life.
Right.
And they're cutting weight.
So half the time I'm wrestling 1:50,
two pound men.
Like I'm weighing in at 1:45
on Vr,
on the Varsity team and just getting,
you know.
Oh my gosh.
Did you beat any dudes?
I did,
but not in Varsity varsity guys.
But I beat some other guys.
I made him cry,
I made a few guys quit.
It would always get back to our school.
It would always get back to our school
to like,
Oh yeah,
that guy you beat last week.
He quit the team.
Yeah.
I would come back to our school because
obviously there was a,
you know,
a rival school or whatever.
But somehow it would get back to it.
Yeah.
Like I guess he quit the team.
I wonder how much that.
I don't know.
I don't.
I didn't care.
Wound care.
I didn't care,
of course.
I mean you can't.
No,
we're not gonna make it.
Yeah.
You gotta keep going one time.
Do you know what a Saturday night right?
Is?
Sure.
Yeah.
Can you explain it to people?
It's the most brilliant.
So it's basically,
I'll tell you a story.
I got by like a hundred 50,
two pounds state placer.
I weighed in at 1:45.
I remember he wrestled for White River
and he went out and just bulldoze me
right over and Saturday night ride pin
me and like 18 seconds.
I mean he crushed me but it's the most
embarrassing and do like it's a last,
like if you're a girl in high school,
that's the last way that you want them
to on.
So basically they,
they lay like straight on top of you in
like a starfish position and they wrap
your arm both of your arms with their
arms and wrap your legs with your legs
so that you can't,
you're just starfish out on your back.
And like I was like,
what an asshole.
Like you know,
he did it on purpose.
Well why does that?
But if it was effective,
why is that more embarrassing?
Just because your legs are all spread
out
and it looks like a sexual position kind
of,
you know,
because they're like right on top of
you.
Stomach to stomach,
chest to chest pain.
The Groin.
Here it is.
Yeah.
That,
that's.
Yeah,
that's close.
Well,
that's amount.
Someone mounting grape vining someone.
Oh,
it's not really pulling up the one go
down again.
The black and white one,
right?
Uh,
yeah,
there's,
that's kind of like basically I'm sort
of.
But he's kind of doing more of an
Armbar.
So just imagine if you had thing amount
with a double bond.
So it's just kind of,
you know what I mean?
It was just like demoralizing.
No,
I get it,
damn it.
And it was so fast.
But usually actually I didn't get pinned
on Varsity so it was so flexible because
back to that,
like people couldn't turn me over.
Even the varsity guys like I would.
That was my survival technique was like
my shoulders were so flexible that if
like in,
in high school wrestling you can't go
past was potentially dangerous.
You're not allowed to like dislocate
someone's shoulders,
so it's like they would try to turn me
on my shoulder,
my arm,
it be going,
going,
and they were like,
you can't go past that or you're going
to dislocate your arm,
you know?
So it was like,
that was my,
my Hail Mary.
It was like I'm really flexible and I'm
super tough and I would just,
would not let.
I would have let my arm dislocate for
sure.
I was not going to let him turn me.
That's totally fine.
Interesting things about wrestling,
isn't it?
This is like there's some things that
you would do in a fight that you're not
allowed to do.
Well,
it's collegiate wrestling,
so it's um,
there's different styles.
There's collegiate,
which is more safe for schools.
Yeah.
Because our kids.
And then you get into freestyle
wrestling,
which you can throw people in slam and
collegiate.
You have to kind of set them down.
You're not allowed to just like pick
someone in the article,
boom,
throw them.
You have to kind of put them down.
But even just freestyle.
I remember when Mark Schultz fought in
the Olympics and rip that guy's arm
apart,
got them into Kamora and sort of tossed
them with the oranges.
He yanked his arm backwards.
Yeah,
I mean he,
he got disqualified for that.
Which we're in the UFC would be an
amazing move.
Yeah.
Well I guess it's a different mindset.
I guess they think of wrestling is
wrestling and fighting is fighting.
It's different.
It is,
but it's like it's effective grappling
like the use of your body against their
body.
It's interesting in that way.
It's right.
Think for wrestling.
I don't know if you're supposed to use
like joint manipulation.
I think maybe that's the difference.
It's supposed to be like that.
You can control their body with your
weight on top of them.
Not necessarily like contort their joint
in the wrong direction so that you know,
that's Jujitsu.
Jujitsu comes in.
Do you remember when Matt Hughes Fought
Ricardo Almeida and choked them out,
but with like a front headlock?
Yeah.
Which is a move that is actually using a
wrestling all the time.
That was a fascinating.
Some wrestlers have adapted more of that
stuff too,
and then they put that in there more
than one start putting some pressure on
the throat and folding people over it
and they try to get a little bit
who's so fucking strong when he gets a
hold of you in that position and he's.
Yeah,
he's pushing against your.
Your arm and it's pending against your
neck and then he's squeezing your neck
on the other side.
He's choking you out.
Let's just like a head and arm choke,
but in a reverse position.
Yeah,
it's pretty good.
Yeah.
I was amazed when I saw that fight that
he did that,
that he was able to choke out Ricardo
Tomato who's a Jujitsu black belt,
but Maura may since then that no one
else has been able to do it.
Have you wrestled?
Did you refresh?
I wrestled in high school.
Wrestle in high school one year.
Yeah.
It's hard.
The other ones,
taekwondo,
so it was both.
Yeah.
I just decided to tag window was easier.
I liked that and I like kicking people.
It was like the biggest things,
isn't it?
I was,
well it was also that I had to do it at
school,
so it was like I had to stay at school,
which I fucking hated and I was just a
Zombie like after us,
so sore.
I remember like we used to do the
sprints upstairs and shit and carry each
other across the football field and I
was so fucking sore.
I just remember thinking like a bark
used to do like what they call the gut
busters I think because it literally
makes me want to vomit.
I was doing both at the same time too.
I was doing taekwondo and wrestling at
the same time.
I just had determined I wish I could've
done more extra curricular like school
activities besides just what was offered
by the school.
That was one thing is like we were so we
struggled a lot financially growing up.
We didn't grow up in a privileged
household by any means and they couldn't
afford.
My parents couldn't afford to put me
into gymnastics at a time,
you know,
but I'm glad because I think that for
it,
that's what I wanted to do.
I actually wanted to do gymnastics
instead of wrestling,
but they're like,
you know,
we just,
it's too,
too much and,
but I'm glad that I didn't come from
super privileged because it just gives
me a whole different perspective.
Sure.
You appreciate what you've earned,
I'm sure.
When did you start striking?
When did you do any sort of striking
martial arts?
Nineteen.
I was 19.
When did you start out with?
Um,
I think it was just kickboxing.
Yeah,
just normal,
like learning to throw kicks and normal,
you know,
it was kickboxing for mma.
I never did any,
like,
just straight anything.
It was always about,
it was always about mma and obviously I
wrestled.
So the goal was always to grab people
and get them to the ground.
Right.
So yeah,
I started with kickboxing,
learning how to throw basic kicks,
learning how to throw basic punches,
but like,
but before my first fight,
I think I had like maybe four weeks of
striking,
which is like nothing.
Nothing that's crazy.
It was crazy.
Well,
in those situations where I had a buddy
of mine who was a Jujitsu black belt,
really high level Jujitsu guy and he's
taken an mma fight and we had a
conversation about it before and uh,
I was going,
well,
how much striking are you doing?
And he's like once a week or get
together and do this.
I'm like,
Holy Shit.
listen,
do you know what you can do to guys on
the ground?
Well,
someone can do that.
Do you standing up and evolve?
That guy has to do
is keep you from getting a hold of him
and your Foxville like you have to.
You have to be understanding that like
there's a difference in the consequences
as well because the consequences of
being in there with like a dangerous
striker or one wrong move and you get
clipped with something and you wake up.
It's just,
it's such a different thing.
But so many people that are really good
at one thing,
they think all I have to do is do my one
thing and they won't be able to stop me.
Right?
Well,
I went into my first fight,
kind of ignorance is bliss,
to not,
not thinking like,
you know,
if I can't do this because I just didn't
know how devastating it could be to get
like kneed in the face now up in
Washington state,
they don't allow amateurs like to throw
a full on,
nice the face.
I don't know,
they don't allow it like an amateur
fighting I think in California and stuff
like that to like now there's more
regulations and they don't allow it just
because a lot of times and amateurs are
still learning and just such a brutal
blow,
right.
The need of the face like we are.
I mean that's a hard.
There is no protection.
It straight like kneebone and that's
pretty brutal.
Um,
my first fight,
oh my gosh,
you know,
I went out there,
I wrestled her.
I pretty much just all that's all that I
knew.
I don't even think I threw a punch on
the ground.
Like,
I took her down like the easiest I've
ever take her down and I think I forgot
that I could punch because I was just,
that's all I knew is wrestling.
So just wrestled her the whole time.
And then the second round I came out and
threw a once you went to and I try to
grab a hold of her and she put me in a
Thai clinch.
So her and her husband own the,
uh,
like,
owned a Thai school up in Canada.
So she was like really good striker,
no wrestling or really much grappling a
little bit and I didn't know what it
was.
I didn't even know what a Thai clinch
was,
as much less how to defend it.
So she just starts kneeing my face off
and the only thing I can think to do is
shoot.
So I'm just shooting into knees,
is it Bam,
Bam,
Bam.
And they're like,
one of them caught my nose is clean on,
busted it flattened my nose.
And um,
that was in such shock.
And she,
you know,
because is the first time I've been hit
really,
like you don't,
you know,
you don't take blows to the face in
wrestling.
So I'm just like,
Whoa,
what is going on here,
what am I doing?
And she kind of like pushes me down like
because I'm so shooting,
but I kinda like slump out of the,
uh,
you know,
off of the legs a little bit.
I'm a little bit stunned obviously.
And she spins around and takes my bag.
She tried to choke me and I just,
I remember I had this epiphany moment.
It was like the world stopped,
you know,
and she's still trying to like fight me
and beat me up.
But I remember she tried to choke me and
I had my hands like this and it's such a
vivid moment because how I got this
star,
this is how I started my career.
It was my first fight ever.
And I'm watching this pool of blood and
there's a steady stream,
like not even dripping,
like it's just pouring out of my nose
and this pool of blood is getting bigger
and bigger and bigger.
And she's still trying to choke me and
punched me and I'm thinking like,
this bitch,
that's
exactly what the hell.
No.
And I got pissed.
I got pissed.
I lost my temper and the fight.
I started bucking her off and that's
when the fight,
it really came out of me because before
that I was just,
I was so wrestling.
I was like,
you know,
competing.
That's when the fighter came out.
I got fucking pissed.
I was pissed.
Not only that,
my nose was broken.
Not only that I got hit,
but that she had my back.
That was like,
that was what pissed me off.
Like the rest was kind of like,
Eh,
you know,
but I was the wrestler.
Fuck you,
like get off my back like you're the
striker,
you're not allowed to be there.
So I like started bugging her and she
fell down into the guard position and I
stood up above her and I reached to the
ceiling as high as I could and I just
started raining down punches from the
standing position.
And the lead is going everywhere.
Like she soaked in it.
I've got it all over me,
I'm just bleeding like a stuck pig
everywhere and I remember her face Kinda
like wincing,
like trying to weather the storm and
that's the how the second round ended
and then I went back to my corner and
like I'm the head,
the head coach was like,
we can't let you go back out for the
third round because your nose is just so
like we don't know how bad it is.
And I was super bummed because that was
the turning point in the fight for me.
That's when it actually became a fight
and I was like I really wanted to go
back out in the third round and just
whip this girl's ass.
So you lost the fight but you learned a
lot about yourself?
Yeah,
the ton.
And I had to go home.
That's bringing this back full circle.
This is where my,
my very chauvinistic grandpa at the
time,
but you know,
was kind of sexy super old school.
Like he was like,
you know,
women do this and men do that.
Women don't do this.
So you're not allowed to do that.
And what are you doing?
I had to come home.
Oh my God,
that was the most dreadful drive I ever
had because my nose was literally like
three times this size.
I had no definition between my,
the bridge of my nose and my cheekbones.
Like it just went straight out.
It was flat like a lion and then it just
went straight up to my cheek bones.
That's how bad it was.
I mean it got broken bat and then over
like the next night,
like I could barely even open my eyes
and I had two giant black raccoon eyes.
So it was like,
there's no hiding it.
Like you get to look your grandpa
straight in the face and he's like,
risk.
I told you,
you know,
and you're just like,
oh yeah,
oh man.
He was just like that,
you know,
he just wouldn't like would not lay off
of it was,
this is why you shouldn't be doing this.
This is absurd.
This is ridiculous.
This is embarrassing.
And my dad's just like,
you know,
he's so embarrassed.
Like he was just.
Yeah,
he was embarrassed.
And I'm in the back of my mind,
I know that I can't say anything at the
moment,
but in the back of my mind I was
thinking,
I'm not done.
I've got to do this again.
Like in the back of my mind I was
thinking because everyone was like,
well good.
She good thing she got that out of her
system.
Like she'll,
she'll surely never do that again.
Thank God she got this.
She learned her lesson early and I was
thinking,
I was like,
I can't,
I've got
to get back in.
They're going to prove that I can do
better than that was like,
it was too embarrassing.
I'd have to face every one that was
telling me like I shouldn't be doing
that.
And you know what everyone says to you
like before you like,
but at least back then everyone would
say to me,
don't break your nose.
That was like my pre,
like good luck,
you know,
like people say like,
oh,
go kill it.
That meaning break a leg,
you know,
people like the other way,
like,
well,
you know,
good luck in your fight.
Don't break your nose.
Fuck,
no,
you know,
it was so embarrassing.
I think I missed like a week of call,
a week of classes too because I had done
it over like a break so I had like,
I dunno it,
like winter break or something and then
I,
I missed like a week because it was
still so bad.
Did you have to get it fixed?
No,
I probably should have.
It's still not fixed,
but you can feel it.
It's like you can fill the
disassociated.
My septum is like,
it's not very well to be honest about
the right side.
Like I can barely.
And this is a good day.
Have you ever had thought about having
it fixed?
Yeah,
I have,
but um,
yeah,
hopefully one of these days I just did
it recently.
Helped him a lot.
Yeah.
Yeah,
I did it.
I didn't do it till I was 39 my whole
life.
I had a fucked up now.
Oh,
that's amazing.
Sound really nasally now to listen to
myself.
Like I'll probably go back and listen to
podcasts.
Like God,
I sound nasally.
I used to be just like you.
I'll be like,
one side was like three quarters closed.
The other side was totally useless.
I had no breathing out of my nose.
It was just all fucked up in there.
But now it's like,
yeah,
and then.
But yeah.
That's nice.
I'm jealous.
Wait a rabbit and Joe,
but you could get it fixed.
Yeah.
But then I was wondering like,
don't they have to like shave it down?
They're like,
no,
it's inside.
Straighten it.
It's like open up the like they opened
it up but then it makes it a little bit
weaker or something to get broken again.
No,
I don't think so.
You know,
I think we'll,
they shaved down the turbinates.
The inside,
like there's these bumps inside your
nose that hinders the opening or the
opening smaller.
They shaved that down,
they cut out the inside.
That's all calcified too for me,
which is like cauliflower,
cauliflower ear.
You get that in your nose as well.
I feel like I'm asking for it to get
broken again though.
As soon as I fix it.
Like it says like it's gonna get broken
again probably anyway.
Right.
If you keep fighting,
but I think that like at least you have
more of an opportunity to breathe and
your cardio will definitely improve.
That's what they have heard about cardio
already.
If you breathe out of your nose,
I'm sure it would help you in a lot of
ways.
I have to look into it.
Yeah,
I mean,
so like when I was a kid,
um,
I went to a doctor like when I was 19 or
20 and I had a real problem with it and
the doctor said,
look,
unless you stop fighting,
you need to just deal with this and then
once you're done competing then do it.
And I just left it alone but that snore
really bad and I want to take yoga
class.
I couldn't breathe out of my nose and
finally I just bit the bullet.
But after I did it,
I made a youtube video about it because
I'm like,
oh my God,
all these people saying that.
It was like really bad.
Like fuck.
It's nothing,
it's nothing.
The iteration was nothing.
What did they like to do?
Put you under?
Yeah,
but when it's over,
like everybody's like,
oh my God,
it's so awful.
You're miserable.
Break your nose.
They definitely get in there.
They like break it and reset it though.
Anything.
Now it's broken up here like you could
feel like it's all.
Where was.
I broke it when I was five was the first
time I broke it.
I broke it.
Who knows how many times after that,
but the inside was where it was all
fucked up.
It was just.
And he said it was one of the worst
you've ever seen.
He's like,
boy,
this thing has been broken a lot.
Said I don't know how many times you
broke and I'm like,
I don't know either,
but I mean a.
compare my nose though to like vandelay.
You remember when Vandelay vandelays one
of those guys where if you look at
vandelays first fight everything.
Yep.
So he had to get his.
He does Nick Diaz,
Nick Diaz,
bone shaved down and he had scar tissue
removed.
But with Vandelay,
he probably had that done too,
but he had a bunch of scar tissue
removed because he had so much scar
tissue that his eyes were drooping like
severely and his nose was flat.
I mean just flatten.
There was nothing left.
So he had a piece of cartilage removed
from his rib and then they redid his
nose and he had his nose made big so
that he could breathe out of it better.
Like he like had the license while he
was still fighting.
Oh yeah.
Do you remember when he fought in the
UFC?
He looked one way.
I fought chuck and then like he,
he looked like a completely different
person.
I didn't even notice the nose because I
was so focused on like the bone
structure.
Like I feel like that maybe he had a lot
done.
Yeah,
he's crazy too.
I've traded as Jim before madman.
He's like,
all all Alec tries to kill people.
Yeah.
No,
he finds there.
There's no sparring with vandelay
fighting.
Yeah.
I've talked to people that spar with
them and they were like,
what in the fuck?
He just kills people.
Like no mercy.
Like give me mark mark,
that's just.
Well that was like more of a Russian
accent.
That's not what he sounds like it,
but it was like mean like that.
I'm here to fight and there we go.
Just making really mean until like,
like he's chewing through his training
partners.
That's what it was like.
That guy got fucked over.
He really did.
I was so upset with when they tried to
give him a lifetime ban and you know
what,
what they did was really wrong and sent
him on his tail tailspin.
Then he sent a bunch of crazy shit about
the UFC and it's like that.
The whole thing made me really sad
because they were trying to make an
example out of him.
But look,
that guy never failed a drug test.
I don't know who the fuck knows what he
was doing.
He definitely did some shit,
especially in pride for 100 percent.
I mean when he fought cro cop,
he was 218 pounds,
you know,
that's not from creatine.
He did some shit 100 percent right,
but back then you were allowed to do
whatever you want in the UFC.
He never pissed hot.
He never got caught.
So to have this one time where he ran
away from a drug test and to say that
he's banned for life,
so ridiculous.
It was just a total abuse of power and a
really callous abuse by these people
that are a part of the commission
because they are responsible for this
guy's livelihood and they just decided
to treat him as an example and not
respect him as a pioneer of the sport.
What my thought is you should treat him
as if he pissed hot.
Look you randomly from a test,
guess what?
You're automatically pits and hot.
So it would be like nine months and
instead they said life.
And I'm like,
that is crazy.
You can't take away a man's livelihood.
No.
He would've been better if he.
Yeah,
like if he would've pissed hot
technically yes,
but much better.
Yeah,
much better.
If you had been back fighting already,
he'd be already scheduled right now in
the UFC.
He probably be still in the UFC and
still fighting and now I guess he's
going to fight for Bella tour and he's
got a fight overseas because they
reduced to suspension to like,
I think they gave him a couple of years
or something like that or maybe even
less,
but the time,
a fight career that I can,
especially when you're 38 as it is,
we want to see 38.
He's got to be right.
Thirty seven,
38.
It's um,
it's so weird too because the trt thing,
which was around for quite a few years
and you saw the rejuvenation of Vituro
and Dan Henderson,
these guys that were on trt,
that all of a sudden started doing
really well again and just,
it's such a gray area like.
And then that's,
that gets removed and then like a,
everybody's got to go back to your
normal hormone secretion.
Like,
oh,
what do you,
how do you feel about the band?
I don't like it.
Yeah,
I don't.
Well,
I don't like weigh ins.
This is,
this is what I feel like.
I feel like we have to move away from
this weight cutting thing because
there's a difference between this sport
in any sport other than boxing and I
think that the head trauma aspect of it
makes wayans 24 hours a day.
Extremely problematic.
When we understand the science of
rehydrating,
the brain can take as much as 70 plus
hours,
so that to me says that we're doing a
bad thing.
We were doing this silly thing and we're
letting fighters compete.
Compromise.
I think if someone like you and someone
like holly,
you are a similar size.
I think you guys should make an
agreement and the UFC should say,
okay,
look,
Neesha,
what do you weigh right now?
You wait like 1:46
when you're in peak condition.
What do you weigh?
A One?
40 three.
Holly,
are you cool with 1:43?
Yeah.
Okay.
Well let's just way you guys during camp
will weigh you guys sporadically and
we'll give you a couple of pounds to
play with because realistically the
difference between a 143 pound person
and 145 pound person is nothing.
It's just,
it's,
it's not,
it's not enough,
and as long as no one's dehydrated.
Let's take hydration level.
Interesting concept though,
but think about this for minute
wrestling week classes typically
are typically about five pounds apart,
so you get into the bigger ones.
So in theory five pounds makes a big
difference if when you're talking about
manipulating someone else's weight
because you're five pounds less,
but they're five pounds more,
so it's almost like if you think about a
double,
like in my mind it's almost like a
double five pounds can be a lot if
there's a lot of wrestling striking.
I don't think it's doesn't mean
anything.
Jujitsu maybe not as much,
but maybe getting someone to the ground
or being able to sweep someone.
I mean the commander sound like a lot.
It depends how.
Yeah,
it depends how big you are.
Five pounds to a 300 pound person isn't
that much?
Five pounds to 100.
15 pound version is a lot.
It's a bigger percentage of their body
weight.
That's a big point.
Like when you're talking about like a
straw weight or something like that.
That's a great point.
And I think actually I think holly walks
around like someone 60 something.
Does she,
she's pretty big girl.
Well I just feel like she is.
Yeah,
you could tell she,
I really feel like there's gotta be a
better way to organize weight classes
and I just don't know if forcing someone
like holly to compromise your body to
get down to 1:35
and then rehydrate up to like 1:50
or whatever she does
came into to the whole play because of
like bedding me,
like back in the day,
that's what they would like.
Want to show off the fighters and get
people to bet on him.
Like who do you think's gonna win.
So it was kind of like more of a showing
than really like a way in like look how
big this guy is.
He weighs this much and look how big
this one.
Which one do you think's gonna win?
And they would get people to bet and
that's Kinda how wins came about the day
before.
Try to try to get people interested in
the fights instead of to both the
fighters.
Yeah.
Well,
it's their shirts off and get them on a
scale and show how,
you know,
we'll,
the size difference or whatever,
you know.
So it didn't.
They used to do the day of the fight.
I don't know,
maybe.
I'm not sure about boxing.
It was the day of the fight.
Yeah.
I'm pretty sure though that that's like
where that kind of came in and then I
think they started making more weight
classes and that's how it got got like
more specific,
like you have to be a certain way and I
understand that you want to wait,
you want people to be within a certain
weight of each other,
but then the problem is like you can't,
there's no way to really monitor that,
you know,
like some people blow up but tween their
camps and other people don't,
you know.
And how do you.
Yeah,
like you said,
how do you really regularly,
like what if,
what if I said,
you know,
I walk around at 1:47
and holly's like,
well,
you know,
I walk around at one 62.
Then you're like,
well then you can't fight each other.
But it's like,
she's like,
well,
when I die it and I do this and it come
down,
I can make the same weight as as Misha.
It's like,
how much does she cut though that she
cut way more than you?
Or does she lower her body?
Was sure she lowers the body way.
I'm going to guess and say she probably
cuts from about one to 50 what I could
be wrong.
See,
then you're only dealing with a few
different pounds,
right?
Like would you say you're like 1:46,
one seven.
You're dealing with three pounds.
Yeah.
So that's not,
that's not bad,
but that's not cutting weight.
It's not
dehydrating.
I think we need to measure the amount of
hydration that's in the body.
Then what you do is what they instilled
in the wrestling programs in high
schools essentially they way you.
But you also have to pee into a cup and
you have to be a certain amount hydrated
and then they tell you you can't go
below a certain weight because that
would mean you're dehydrating yourself.
That's,
that's definitely a smart scale.
And then like also you have to test the
hydration of your urine and so you'd be
able,
I mean that would be really the only way
to ensure people are not dehydrating
themselves to make a weight.
Otherwise you do have to be the same way
though.
I mean to be,
to be fair,
to have 135 pound title,
it'd be 135 pounds.
Like you know,
it should probably be a diet thing more
than a dehydration thing.
I just think that also would,
it's just,
it's such a dangerous sport already.
And to add this extremely dangerous
weight cutting aspect to it.
Like the guy in Brazil who died last
year from weight cutting.
Yeah.
That can happen.
And it's happened in high school
wrestling.
It's in college wrestling and it's
happened in mma a few times now.
It's not a good thing.
No,
it's not.
And the ivy ban from my understanding is
it's kind of silly because they,
they say like,
well,
you know,
because it can mask like a.
was it epo
or something?
They can mask certain type.
You have to talk to Novitsky,
but it can mask certain types of
performance.
So from my understanding,
what I understand is that cyclist use to
use it like right before they knew that
the person was going to come and test
them,
they would hyperhydrate their blood so
that it would look like it was a normal,
like a normal consistency or whatever
level.
Yeah.
He crit levels that they would be d hi.
You know,
high.
Oh hyperhydrate.
It's,
there wouldn't be as much when they
would draw it,
but the thing is,
is in our sport where first of all were
monitored for at least probably three
hours before a fight.
We're taking the venue in it and a
commissioner does not leave our side at
all.
There's no way to like cheat.
There's no,
you're not going to ivy up for,
you know,
real quick,
10 minutes.
I'm like,
no,
like they're in the bathroom with you.
You're completely monitored.
And I feel like maybe if they were going
to abandon,
maybe they could do under like a
medical.
Like if you need an Ivy afterwards and
you have to go to the hospital and get
one administered or something like there
could be a way around it because the
thing about cyclists and other sports
that they banned it and then they just
transferred it over to mma.
It doesn't add up because we do cut
weight,
you know that I agree with that.
It makes sense or not taking that into
account.
The only thing that I would say is that
what they're doing by the ban is keeping
their checking plastics,
that plastic residue that comes from the
tubes into your body.
And that could be from blood doping.
So blood doping could be one way that
you could have an advantage in illegal
advantage over your opponent.
And they could eliminate blood doping by
eliminating ivs because this,
um,
the,
the small trace amount of plastics that
show up in your blood from use of an ivy
in the bag and the,
the,
the tube and all that stuff.
You could use
that with blood and gain an endurance
advantage over your opponent.
You're saying by by using the ivy and
putting like injecting like an epo is
that you're saying by blood,
by putting blood like blood doping,
you know,
blood doping,
you take blood out of your body your way
in and then once you weigh in,
when they reintroduce that blood back in
your body have much more blood because
your body's replenish the blood that was
missing.
Now you all of a sudden have a massive
endurance advantage.
That's what epo replicates.
What epo replicates is what they were
getting by just blood doping.
That's what blood doping.
It's just pulling blood out of your
body,
storing it in,
and then you put your own blood.
Yes.
You never heard of this?
Well,
I've heard of evo,
but I thought it was like,
well,
that's what EPO is.
Epo is a drug that stimulates your body
to like you were at a high altitude.
I knew about that,
but I didn't think about like taking
your own blood out and putting it back
in.
You just have too much blood.
Yes,
you would have too much blood,
but temporarily it gives you a big
endurance advantage.
Eventually your body brings your blood
back to baseline,
but that's what he was doing with epo is
doing,
is accelerating the amount of red blood
cells of your body produces.
What blood doping is doing is
reintroducing blood that you pulled out.
Once your body's replenished that
missing blood,
now you're throwing even more blood in
there.
It's probably actually safer than the
EPO.
Epo can cause strokes and a epo is,
is tricky stuff.
But yeah,
it's uh,
it's also a drug that,
you know,
a lot of fighters have gotten caught
for.
Well I thought because I didn't think
about that,
but I thought epo.
Is that like you can tell when it's,
I guess like the color of the blood or
something or a little bit different when
it's.
Or when you have epo in your system.
Like they can tell if it's fake.
Well,
they didn't use to be able to test for
it,
but now they can't.
Now they can.
But I think the two issues with the ivy,
the main one is the masking of other
performance enhancing drugs,
but another one is the possibility of
using these bags and these tubes to add
additional blood to your body.
So,
but I've also been told that that can be
worked around with a glass syringe and
with a glass container for the blood or
or ivy fluid.
So I don't know if that's true either.
So weird.
Well,
this is going to be a lot of moves and
countermoves Novitsky was saying that
they figured out a way to make
testosterone out of animals.
They're taking testosterone from
animals.
It's indistinguishable from the bio
testosterone that your actual body
produces versus like the stuff they make
now,
which they make in some sort of a
laboratory environment with wild yams.
That's how they.
That's how they make testosterone with
the yams.
That's one of the reasons why a carbon
isotope test can differentiate between
exogenous testosterone and testosterone.
This naturally produced by the body.
That's crazy.
It's fucking nuts.
Know what I mean?
You're,
you're dealing with this massive,
massive sport that's just so crazy that
there's.
And we have to tell you it's there's the
edges that you gain,
I mean the edge that you got to think
about all the strength and conditioning
that you did,
all the crazy drills you did,
it all came down to that moment in the
fifth round where you knew you had to
take holly down and in that battle,
which was so touch and go like it was
like she was countering.
You were dragging her down.
It was a struggle.
Any little edge,
any little edge there is the difference
between you walking away the new champ
and you losing a decision.
I mean any little edge there.
And that's where it comes down to people
and that's where people get fucking
shady as fuck,
right?
Fuck.
That's got to be the hardest feeling in
the world though,
to know that the reason why you did when
it wouldn't be satisfying camper,
he can't now or if it is then it's just
like why?
Why,
why would you do?
Why would you do a sport like that?
Like I dunno.
I think sometimes people do it because
they think other people are doing it
too.
Like I remember Fitch,
I had a conversation with Fitch wants
and he was like,
um,
I would never do anything.
This is back when testosterone was legal
and he was like,
I wouldn't do anything until I'm done.
He goes,
once I'm done fighting is.
Yeah,
I would definitely take hormone
replacement therapy when I'm older and
all this chance.
But right now he was,
I would want to know that I did
everything I did by myself.
But then Fitch pissed hot now.
Then he got caught,
you know,
he was fighting Paul Horace and
everybody knows Paul might very drawn a
little something,
you know.
And so I think maybe it was one of those
things where he's like,
look,
this is not a level playing field.
I'm not gonna,
I'm not gonna Cheat Myself while this
guy is doing something.
And that's the problem was like,
you know,
everyone says cheating.
Then you either have to or there's gotta
be a way to combat it.
And that's the asterix on the pride
days.
You know,
that's the one thing you have to look at
it.
You gotta go man,
amazing times.
But who knows what the fuck everybody
was doing,
who knows what everybody was on 100
percent.
Yeah,
it's really interesting and it's really
interesting that this sport is so,
it's,
it's so popular now and there's so much
riding on it that it really sort of
highlights all of this,
these moving and pushing of the
boundaries and trying to achieve an
edge,
you know,
how much can you achieve through
supplementation,
like natural things,
quarter's eps mushrooms and be 12 and
natural supplements.
And how much can you achieve through
that?
And how close does it get to illegal
means?
Yeah.
I don't know.
I think when money gets involved it
always changes things.
State politics changed a lot of changes
a lot,
so people are willing to do whatever
they can to get that win and get that
paycheck.
I guess some people,
not everyone,
but how do you have a plan for how long
you want to do this?
You know,
I used to,
I used to think I had a plan.
That plan went out the window.
I just,
I turned 29.
I just turned 29 last August.
And um,
I still feel pretty damn good,
like,
you know,
it's weird that I feel that,
technically I've been doing this for 10
years,
but I still feel like I have so much to
learn and so much to offer and I feel
like I'm learning so quickly.
Like man,
you know,
I talked about the law of diminishing
return,
all that I don't feel like that applies
to me for some reason.
Like I still feel like I'm just evolving
so quickly and so rapidly,
especially with my striking because it
wasn't something I ever focused on
before,
is that it sounds weird.
Like I didn't focus on it.
You start folks.
Got,
I started focusing on it more right
before I fought Ronda focusing on it.
But I'm,
I moved my camp to Las Vegas like
halfway through that training camp,
which was,
it needed to happen,
but it was bad timing in that I'm just,
I'm getting like a couple of new coaches
and we don't have the lingo down yet.
And it's like a language you learned
between your coaches and we didn't have
that.
So there was definitely some hiccups.
But,
um,
after that,
you know,
I won firefights and won a title,
so I think I definitely made the right
move,
just maybe the timing was bad,
but I started focusing on it,
you know,
six weeks before that camp.
And then since then I've been working
with my coach,
Jimmy Gifford,
um,
you know,
and he's helped me tremendously and
focused more on my strength and
conditioning actually making a regiment
and doing,
doing all the things that I guess you're
supposed to do as a professional athlete
because before what I was doing just was
kind of,
I was a little bit ignorant and I worked
hard but worked harder,
not smarter kind of a thing.
Now I have people back,
we have a nutritionist,
I was sports Dr.
have a strength coach,
I have a striking coach,
have a to mma coaches and wrestling
coach and they've got it all like.
And I feel like I finally figured it
out.
Finally,
have a good gym where I'm at and
everything too.
So.
Well,
that's where it all comes together,
right?
Is when your dedication matches your
talent,
matches your focus and your desire.
And it all comes together.
And now as a champion,
do you feel like do,
do,
do you have more confidence now being a
champion?
Do you feel different?
Like do you feel like a fucking did it
100 percent,
but I belong here.
It's one thing to believe you can and
it's another to know you can,
you know,
believing you can.
I mean that's important.
That's crucial.
You have to believe.
But it's entirely different once you
know,
you're like,
and now I know not,
not only do I know,
but everyone else knows too,
you know,
that's a different feeling.
It's a whole different animal.
It's a whole different ballgame.
Like I,
something's changed inside me that I
can't explain some things just
different.
And um,
felt like I hit a new level.
You feel very satisfied.
I am saying this,
I can tell
super confident,
super satisfied,
super confident.
I was still hungry or I still feel like
I have a lot to accomplish,
you know,
I have,
I think I have a really tough match.
And Amanda definitely do.
She's mad at Nunez is no joke.
No,
she's dangerous job.
I remember.
Did you watch her fight with Julia Budd?
Strikeforce,
but she knocked her out with that one
punch and Julie Bud was the bigger,
stronger girl and a striker.
She knocked out.
I mean,
she's got one punch knockout power.
She showed up against a good man.
You know,
she,
she beat.
She'd be down.
Sarah Mcmahon.
She beat her down.
She hit her so hard.
That just made her on it quit.
And then she climbed on her back and
choked her out.
Like,
man,
she's good.
She's well dangerous.
He's very dangerous.
You know?
I think that she might have an issue
with cardio if I was going to pick out,
pick out something that might be
something you maybe she's not as
efficient in the cage,
but she's.
We are working to change that.
No,
she knows this is a five round fight.
I can't.
I can't rely on someone getting tired.
That's never a good game plan.
Like,
okay,
I'm just going to try to stay out of
harm's way until she gets tired.
Like,
well,
she seems to explode and fights and then
drain the gas tank.
She's trying to stop people and if it
doesn't work out that way,
she has a little bit of an issue ever
wins or something or first round
finishes.
She's a monster.
Yeah.
Very,
very strong striker.
Did very physically strong person.
She's kind of like a brown or black belt
in Jujitsu and a brown or a black belt
in judo.
Yep.
Very well rounded.
Yeah.
There's not that many girls in our
division that are that well rounded.
Um,
so she doesn't have a lot of holes in
her game besides,
besides a seeming to hit a wall
sometimes in a fight and yeah,
with her as one of the things that I
said about holly and the Rhonda fight,
it's like you look at how accomplished
holly is outside of the UFC and you wait
until the moment which you could put it
all together inside the octagon and she
might put it all together inside the
octagon when the moment is the biggest,
when she has to rise to the occasion.
That might,
when you push her back against the wall,
it might be when you see her at her best
and it turned out to be exactly that and
someone like Amanda,
she's going to realize like this is the
time,
this is the opportunity to put it all
together.
Can't half ass a thing in training thing
with nutrition thing with your mind.
She has to show up 100 percent focused
and so for someone like you,
you have to look at her like her
potential
and look at all of all the girl would
beat Sara Mcmann.
That's the one that I'm training,
you know,
and even better than that girl because
we have to assume she's evolved.
That's the best.
I think I've seen her look so I have to
assume like she's going to be better
than that even.
Do you have goals
as far as like what you want to do with
the title?
How long do you want to hold it?
Do you have any thoughts in mind of like
must be opponents like is getting Rhonda
back in the auction?
Yeah,
that's important.
I need that.
Like that has to happen.
That's very important to me and I have
Amanda had of me,
I do not want to look pastor because you
think that would be a huge mistake.
It's not one that I want to make as a
veteran in my career.
That would be a rookie move.
Um,
but you know,
in the back of my mind,
of course,
like the fight with Ronda is something I
want to happen and you don't know when
it will happen.
It could be anticipated for November.
I've heard that be tossed around in the
UFC that she's planning on coming back
and maybe it might be Madison Square
Garden.
That would be great.
I want to focus on that.
I want to focus on Amanda,
but I know in the back of my mind and I
want,
I want that fight.
Like I want that to happen.
I think it's so important to me and my
career to go and beat Ronda and prove
everyone else.
Like I've been an underdog in most of my
fights.
I had been the person that people have
always counted out in my entire career,
my entire life.
Most people are telling me,
you can't,
you couldn't,
you shouldn't,
you wouldn't,
and I'm,
you know,
that's,
I'm fine with that.
I'm perfectly fine with that.
I am at the best point in my career and
Rhonda is at the worst.
You know,
she's going through what I've already
been through time and time again and I
have built myself back up from that
point.
Time and time again.
I know that I can do that.
I'm confident in that.
Here I am standing the strongest that
I've ever stood and I've already been
through that.
I've already been head kicked and
knocked out.
That happened to me before,
like I picked myself up,
but pull myself up by my bootstraps,
but one foot back in front of the other
and worked.
Got My strike first world title.
I lost the Toronto pick myself back up,
but one phone interview the other got
back on the horse,
fought,
fought.
Ronda Rousey was devastated,
crushed,
thought my world was just falling down
around me.
Coming to an end,
pack up.
We're going to put one foot in from the
other guy back on the horse,
and now here I am,
the world champion.
You know,
I know that I'm tough.
I know that I have what it takes to beat
Ronda.
Many people don't believe that.
That's okay.
I've been in this position before.
Many most people didn't think I was
going to beat holly.
Most people don't think holly was gonna.
Beat.
Ronda doesn't matter to me what other
people think.
It matters what I believe and what I
know and I'm the question mark is how is
Rhonda going to come back from this?
I know what I've been hearing from
Rhonda in the media and the press.
She's been a little quiet lately,
but before that it wasn't what I would
have expected to hear from someone who
really wants to come back and he was
really,
really a fighter at the core.
She's a great athlete.
She's a great fighter.
She's accomplished a lot of things.
Credit where credit's due,
you know,
I give her a round of applause for
everything she's been able to
accomplish.
I'll tell you what,
every time I've ever lost in my career,
I went bananas to get back in their
ballistic.
I was like,
I have to like right now,
just like holly was like,
they're like,
when do you want to fight again?
Just like tomorrow.
I meesha.
Now.
That's what you want to hear.
When someone has a devastating loss,
they want to get back in there right now
and face that person right now or or
someone else,
just get that loss of the record.
Erase it.
When I lost the cat Zingano,
I freaked out.
I called Sean Shelby and I was like,
get me another fight right now.
He was like,
your noses even heal.
I don't give a fuck.
I want to.
I want to fight.
I want it now.
I want to know when it's coming up like
right now or I'm going to freak out.
I don't know what to tell you,
but I'm going to lose my shit if I don't
have like a fight on the horizon,
lose it.
And then I hear Rhonda,
like I'm going to take a year off and
I'm gonna.
You know,
I'm going to do this.
I'm like,
that just doesn't sound like someone who
really wants this anymore.
And I think that fight might've broke
her.
I could be wrong,
but I think something inside of her is
different than it was before.
Um,
maybe she's not broken,
but it's different
because how much do you think of factor
is how much of a factor do you think
success is in the park in terms of she's
doing movies.
She's,
she was a darling always late night
television shows and everybody wanted to
hang out with us doing these commercials
with,
you know,
seth rogen on television,
like how much of a factor is on?
Well,
she asked security,
now she has job security outside the
UFC.
Sushi doesn't really need that anymore.
And I think maybe that's also something
on her mind is like,
does she really want this?
Because winning is awesome.
It's great.
It's easy.
It's like when you win,
everybody loves you.
Everybody supports you.
Everybody's there.
Everybody's on your train.
When you lose fucking sucks.
It sucks.
And only the people that really love
your still really,
really there for you.
Everyone else was just like,
Eh,
whatever the loser,
and then you have the social media,
you know,
White Knights that come out and want to
tell you what a piece of shit you are
and how you're never gonna accomplish
anything and you'll never win another
fight and you might as well just quit
and retire,
blah,
blah blah.
So those people and you have to make a
choice,
you know,
and my choice is always been the to do,
to,
to keep fighting,
you know,
to add.
It just don't.
I don't recognize.
There's a lot of things I recognize in
Ronda that I can,
I can recognize her greatness,
I can recognize her championship,
I can recognize things I don't identify
with that I don't identify with.
Sitting on that last for a year,
I cannot understand it.
If it was me,
it would have eaten me alive inside and
out to.
I couldn't have done it.
I couldn't be making a movie.
I couldn't be doing that.
I would,
it would just.
But does she?
I don't think she has a choice.
I think if you have movie contracts,
I think you have to fulfill them.
How do you,
I dunno,
does Conrad have to show up for.
But showing up for press conferences is
one thing,
but I don't think,
I think she could have.
She could have fought because they,
they said they had anticipated for her
to come back at UFC 200.
They wanted that and they and,
and Dana said she could've but should,
she?
She could have but should she.
Well I think that could have and should,
she was because she had to do a movie
for three months,
so like doing the movie for three months
would have taken three months outside of
her camp.
And you've done a movie before.
You know what it's like you're on the
set all day.
It's 16 hour days.
It's long and grueling.
You don't have time to train,
but after a loss like that,
I think you really have to have enough
time to actually focus and then on top
of that to getting,
getting flatlined like that.
Like you have to have some time to
recover.
Recover your head.
Yeah,
absolutely.
I just don't know if a year that would.
I'm just saying that would crush me.
I wouldn't be able to do what she's
doing right now.
I wouldn't physically be able to like to
deal with that for years.
And if I had to,
I think it would eat me alive.
Like I think I'd be so depressed and so
I'm sure it's eating her alive
too.
But how do you sit on it for a year
then?
How do you do that?
Do what you gotta do.
Can't.
I couldn't.
Well,
you know,
it's all speculation.
We only,
we don't know until she comes back.
But the other thing too is like,
no,
she's like,
you know,
she had her,
you're going to her downs or her really,
really low,
which I empathize with.
I've been there,
um,
you know,
but then she said,
I was thinking about,
you know,
these all these negative thoughts.
And,
and um,
then I looked up on the hill and she
said this on the Ellen show.
I looked up and I saw Travis Brown and I
realized,
you know,
I've got to stick around to have his
babies and I thought like what?
What went through my mind is like I
gotta get back and get my title back.
I gotta get back and win a fight like
it.
It just seemed like her mindset was
different than what I would expect a
fighter's mindset to be.
Does that make sense at all?
But I'm trying.
What I'm saying is like,
it didn't seem like her motivation was
to fight and win again.
It was.
There was other things.
Now I'm not saying she's not going to
come back and be great or come back and
fight.
Not Questioning that and questioning
where her true motivation is coming from
because I think while she was winning,
it was so awesome.
Like she's like,
well,
yeah,
I want to keep doing this course.
I want to keep it,
keep them crushing girls.
I'm demolishing them.
I'm a star.
All these great things are coming now.
She already has that.
She's already making movies.
She already has millions of millions of
dollars.
Is Her true motivation?
Was it just,
you know,
keeping that undefeated streak because
she talked about that so much,
you know,
I will retire undefeated w and then she,
she even said like,
I don't know,
I'm questioning what am I doing now?
Like,
you know,
now I'm not going to ever retire
undefeated.
So what is my,
you know,
maybe I'm meant for this.
Maybe I met,
she doesn't really know that was her
identity was like to be undefeated in
this sport.
So if,
if that's not the goal anymore,
I just don't know.
Like I feel like I sent something off,
I send something is not right in her
mindset and I think she's going to come
back and I think she's going to fight
anything.
She'll fight hard,
but I just don't know if she still has
it after a brutal loss like that,
you know,
if she's still hungry enough.
Those are fighting words.
Restate.
Is she $100?
That's the question.
What you're doing right now is you're
throwing up the bat signal,
right?
Yeah.
Well that's how I feel I'm going to down
now.
I get a lot of shit because people are
like,
oh,
you know,
he,
that's not what I,
I don't,
I don't apologize for anything that I
say unless I really say it's something
that was,
that I didn't mean to say that was
hurtful to someone and I'm like,
oh,
I fucked up.
But honestly,
if it's my opinion is my opinion,
if you don't like it,
I'm not.
I'm not gonna apologize for my opinion.
Don't apologize for anything that I have
to say about the way I feel about
Rhonda,
the way I feel about any,
any of these situations,
you know,
so I've just,
I'm going to be as transparent.
I don't think you're saying anything
disrespectful either and I don't think
you,
I think as a champion and that's what
you are,
you,
you're analyzing someone's mindset and
you're totally entitled to that.
Yeah.
And I have a lot of respect for Rhonda
was an athlete.
You know,
a lot of guys think you'll ever be
friends after all said and done.
Never.
I don't think so.
No.
I think she thinks that I've done so
many things and like she,
I don't think she would ever.
I think she blames me for things that I
didn't even do.
So that mean how do you even get around
that?
Right.
You know,
like I heard when you guys did your
interview,
she said something like that I called a
promotion and like tried to get crispy
or like mess with him before his fight
or something like that.
That I guess he,
I guess he was contracted to another
promotion and he wasn't supposed to be
while he was on the ultimate fighter.
And I guess that that Dana,
I received a call and then they thought
that I,
she thought that I did that.
I'm like,
first of,
first of all,
like I didn't even know he signed to
another organization at all and if you
know that can be was,
it didn't even,
wouldn't have even crossed my mind.
Like I'm too,
like you said,
I'm too easy going to even think of
something like that.
And I'm not malicious by any means.
I have nothing against Krispy.
Oh.
But I think she thought that I tried to
like mess with him,
like I called the promoter of whatever
organization,
little small contract,
don't even know how I would have known
that.
How would you even know that?
How do you know?
But this is the same girl that ripped
page for,
for congratulating holly.
Like she has her way of thinking and
she's going to hate me until the day she
dies and I'm okay with that.
That's fine.
We don't need to be friends.
That's okay.
You know,
I'm perfectly fine with that.
All right.
Yeah.
Well listen,
congratulations and everything.
What you did not Holly Holm fight was
fucking amazing.
It's awesome.
Thank you.
And I think you're a great
representative for women's martial arts,
for martial arts,
period.
But as a champion,
I think you were a great representative.
Just your personality,
the way you carry yourself is very
admirable and I think you're a great
role model for people that are coming up
and looking at what a champion behaves
like.
I appreciate it,
Joe Words.
Thanks for being on the podcast too.
Thanks for hanging out and for finally
having fun anytime.
Bother you enough to get me on here.
People bother me cause it's not that I
can do.
I only have so much time.
Thank you very much.
All right folks.
We'll be back Friday with Ian Edwards.
See you then.