Hello Freak bitches on.
People definitely want to fight.
I can't live in with fight fighter.
I'm not either.
Some people think that you're supposed
to.
That's how a relationship is supposed to
be.
If you're not fighting the years somehow
or another,
you don't care about each other because
if you care you get upset.
So very weird sort of dynamic.
The man woman relationship dynamic of
things that people think you shouldn't,
shouldn't expect the way people behave
or don't behave the way they talk to you
or don't talk to you like it's very,
you know,
it's weird.
It's as if it's all the same.
If any friendship is the same.
Yeah,
don't let,
don't let people be mean to you.
Don't let them fucking beat you down.
You'll shit at you.
But some people like if you grow up in a
home that fights all the time,
you get used to that and then you.
It's not a big deal.
Like she,
this girl,
would she fight,
scream and yell at him and like as soon
as it was,
it was done,
she'd be fine.
Just like say I have some coffee and
just sit there and I'd be shaking like,
oh my God,
why did she say like,
I'm not good with that kind of attention
that at all?
Yeah.
I used to date this girl would get
really mad,
really mad and want to fight.
And then once,
once there was some sort of resolution
should immediately turned docile.
It was very odd thought she'd be
aggressive to start some sort of
altercation,
but you could calm the altercation down,
shut it down.
But you had an almost shut it down by
just saying or you're not going to do
this.
I'm not going to talk like this.
Like this child.
Yeah.
And I was young.
So I had,
I needed to learn like how to talk to
people or how to manage situations.
Like sometimes like something's
happening between two people,
like,
uh,
you're,
you're upset about something.
And instead of thinking about how you're
conveying your thought to them,
all you think of is what you want to
happen.
You know,
I want you to shut the fuck up.
I know.
Even though you want someone to shut the
fuck up,
the problem is when you say that you're
not really thinking about communicating
with them,
like through their eyes wants anyone to
say shut the fuck up,
but we say because we want people to
shut the fuck up and you can't deal with
it.
I'm not.
Yeah.
Is there a point you don't want?
You don't care what their needs are,
you just stop.
Well,
it's.
Well it's also like when people want
people to do things so they want people
that are.
There's,
there's the,
the mindset of you wanting a result.
You want someone to behave a certain way
instead of thinking about them as like
your equal.
I can just another human being and
instead of thinking like I have to get
what I want.
Like what is it that you want?
Okay,
what happened here?
Like why are we to pass?
I find like impasse getting older,
that thing that I'm more aware of your.
It's a big part of not thinking about
you all the time.
You're always thinking,
especially when you're young and you're
like coming up and you're doing.
It's just me,
me,
because you're just trying to survive.
You're trying to figure.
You don't even know what you want.
When you shut that part down and think
about the person across from you.
It opens up the whole world,
but it's a difficult thing to learn when
it's also when you're young,
the camera industry just done.
Just tell other uses.
Last time you saw like a straight up
camera.
Well,
you'd have to be like a guy who was a
photographer like Jamie.
Then you carry those goofy bricks
because you want to press checks and you
know what he's doing.
It's just take a picture of the church
all the time.
Just cleared the lighting.
Let me just fix your hair.
Your hair's.
But even that just loved that.
They loved to pose.
Sure she did.
They go because I see them all the time.
They just go on like little photo shoot
dates with girls too and two,
three,
four,
five,
10 times and there's taking pictures of
each other.
They don't need to hire the photographer
anymore.
I've seen that man.
I was at a restaurant in these two
bitches.
Just kept doing that back and forth with
each other.
I was like,
ladies,
enjoy your meal.
Right?
And they were like,
no,
like this,
like this.
Hold on with phones.
Yeah.
This is the.
I'm about to take a selfie face.
Ready?
There's a thing that girls do with their
neck that they only do when they're
about to take a selfie.
This is it.
Ready?
Just Dab that weird neck.
Boom.
It's like they're like,
Shit.
This is weird cell phone.
You don't ever do that.
And the other time,
except for when you're looking at your
phone,
just trying to sell you nothing is
nothing is more awkward scene.
So someone tried to take a selfie.
You ever seen that mom at the playground
where they're trying to take selfies?
She takes 40 something.
Selfies.
You still like dispatch smile as what
you look like.
Okay.
You just roll with it doesn't always
look great.
You don't need to tricking people but
filters
how they do it because this weird
chicken movement,
chicken ads,
chicken and chicken and that's where it
comes from.
Chickens be crazy.
It's not where it comes from,
but it belongs in it.
True.
It's in the same night.
Yeah.
Umbrella.
But that's a real chicken head.
Yeah.
I mean this is really.
This is.
Trust me,
I've chickens.
This is the fucking chicken.
This is.
That's what they do,
man.
There's nothing more awkward seeing
someone's trying to take fucking
selfies.
So embarrassing.
This is definitely more awkward.
Shit.
It's more awkward if your friend is
taking and you're a guy.
You're standing there like,
hold up bro.
Hold on Bro.
Oh my God.
Like this.
It's so weird.
What do you think?
Like this year was okay and she kicked
you out,
Bro.
Your guy and you're poking your ass out.
Okay.
How many guys take pictures?
Like the hero?
I'm going to look mysterious.
Thinking about this book.
I'm writing
as out
so awkward.
Man.