The Joe Rogan experience,
Joe Rogan podcast by night.
Thanks for having me,
man.
I really appreciate it.
I'm glad you're here,
Jim.
Yeah,
you've got a very interesting setup and
I've talked to quite a few people work
with you and your unconventional ways
and uh,
he just,
he got a great reputation,
just so you know.
Yeah.
Hey,
thank you so convinced of this time,
tiffany scientific.
Well,
that reverse hyper,
that machine that you create.
I've talked about that 100 times on my
podcast.
Get that thing has done wonders for my
back and uh,
it's just,
uh,
a genius product.
You're good.
It's a,
it's a genius product.
How did you invent that?
I broke my lower back in 1973.
You invented that thing in 73 while I
started to exercise.
It's actually about 74 started,
but I brought my daughter back in
[inaudible] 73 and I was on crutches for
10 months and no one was helping me,
so I just come out,
you know,
I'd do back extensions where you hook
your ankles and raise your upper body,
but that would kill my back.
So I thought,
well,
if I did it in reverse,
so I jumped up on a platform,
dropped my legs,
raise them up,
pumped up my back,
didn't hurt,
and that's how,
that was the beginning stages of it.
And then years later we've always been a
private gym.
We're not open to the public,
so it was never out in the public.
And then I finally made a machine years
later and got my first patent in 1994.
How is it that no one knows about that
thing?
I mean,
how is it that it's not a gigantic
success?
Uh,
well we were actually,
should we sell over a little bit over
$100 a month?
100 machines a month?
Well,
I hope I've sold some of them for you
and you have.
I want to thank you for that.
And that's the way you know,
is like sex once you have you gotta you
gotTa keep it.
Yeah.
I don't remember how I heard about it.
I don't remember who initially told me
about it,
but I was having some disc issues and
they all want to cut you open man.
If you go to doctors,
they all want to fuse disks and cut you
open and there's all this talk and I was
like,
wow,
there's gotta be another way.
So then I started research and stuff and
I don't remember how I came upon the
reverse hyper,
but I remember as soon as I saw it,
I went,
wow,
that's a genius idea because you're
just.
The idea is right that when you're
getting a bulging disk is because things
are getting compressed.
So just pull them apart.
Right?
We've got another machine that belt
squat machine we usually for grappling,
we actually fight in there and it's
just,
it's not a reverse every bit to traction
device as well,
so we do an enormous amount of work and
at the same time as the restoration.
So what is the other one called?
It's called a belt squat machine.
A bell squat puts you in a platform with
a belt around your waist with maybe 100,
200,
300 pounds,
and then we grapple or or we spar or it
could do anything.
We actually lift weights and we use an
enormous amount of wage.
May Two thousand pounds in it,
but why?
It's building up your glutes and all the
old lower,
lower body is tractioning out your
spine.
And it's um,
but the restoration street medicine next
day you don't even know you worked out,
but you've done thousands of pounds of
work and that's why I've got the world's
strongest soon.
Wow.
So you started out as a power lifter.
Shadows apparently started limping.
Lifting I was 14 and then I went to my
first time meeting 1966 and salt guys is
really built.
Never went back to Olympic lifting
again.
And then a power lifted all my life.
Made top 10 for 34 years.
That's why I'm so beat up.
And uh,
but uh,
I love the sport.
I love the strength and power also loves
if it's,
if it's in time or weights,
I love it.
You know,
something you can measure,
you know,
it's,
it's good to be a.
I like to work with football because I,
I'd average three tents off,
12 linemen going in the nfl some when
the NFL,
some didn't.
So you just never know.
But I like,
I like just basic things to statistics,
you know,
how strong are you,
how fast are,
you know,
for the person who doesn't understand
this,
what is difference between power lifting
and Olympic lifting,
power lifting,
you've been squat and dead lift and
Olympic lifting a clean jerk and snatch
part of the things that absolute
strength,
sport law the way could be very,
very slow,
uh,
and Olympic lifting because I could to
clean,
you have four,
you have two poles,
front squat and a jerk,
whatever your weakest at touch,
what you're limited at.
But that's a speed strength sport.
And that means velocity.
Speed.
Strength is intermediate philosophy.
My sport had slow velocity and then if
you jump,
that's explosive.
I'm explosive power and that's measured
in past philosophies but didn't want to
build explosive power.
You Gen and how'd you get involved with
work when fighters,
because I know you work with Matt Brown
and you worked with a bunch of guys.
Well,
not bunch.
Kevin Randleman.
Kevin Brown started Kevin Randleman and
a tree.
Kevin has experimented.
First off,
I thought I was afraid I was going to
hurt the guy.
It's not that you can't hurt these guys
know they ever hurt me and then.
But that's how it started.
It was fun.
And uh,
back when Kevin,
you know,
when it was champion and one was,
you probably know when he was probably
around 2000.
Um,
yeah,
it was somewhere in that range,
somewhere around there.
He was the UFC heavyweight champ.
I know.
I'm trying to get,
um,
you know,
his buddy.
I'm Mark Coleman down here and I'd never
get marked down here.
I went to his house twice.
I thought he's going to kick my ass.
I got it all psyched up and he starts
staring me down to rock it back and
forth and I don't really shit.
And then I tried to calm me down to get
the hell out of there.
And then he said he wanted to talk to
him again about a month ago.
My Guy.
So I go back up there.
Same thing happened and then I asked
Kevin,
I said,
why you wanted to come down?
And he said,
well,
he said he'd have to train.
I trained optimally.
I don't train on smartsheet optimally,
you only need to have a bunch of stuff
out in the first round.
He trained everything optimally,
not minimal,
not maximal.
It's optimal.
So when you take a guy like Kevin random
and like a stud athlete like that,
like how would you assess like what
optimum is for a guy like that,
but that's when he was the first guy I
ever had.
And you know what a freak he was on men.
So I'm Tom,
which a lot of guys right now and I mean
Kevin was used freak.
You saw Kevin?
Yeah.
So uh,
we do a lot of sled work,
upper body,
lower body and a lot of the dumbbells
for time like him and I,
he,
he is so upset.
One time we tie,
they did a 107 reps with 75 pound
dumbbells in five minutes on a stability
ball and he tied me.
Wow.
We both did 107 reps and he was highly
upset.
He's one of the best athletes ever in
the sport.
Oh no kidding.
Super Explosive.
Did he win the UFC heavyweight title?
I know he fought boss Rutan and I think
he lost the title to Bas rutten office.
It was a real controversial decision
because boss was hitting them off his
back.
He broke boxes,
knows that,
right?
I'm sure.
Yeah,
and those breaks are pretty common
habit.
Almost every fight.
Yeah.
At least some sort of bright.
Almost every fighter has like some kind
of a DD deviated septum.
What you see in our fighting is down.
Mark was probably champion UFC champ,
but fighting is changed now.
You know,
you know that every week you're there.
I'm only at home and in my recliner
watching it,
so it's so much more sophisticated.
I love MMA because it's highly
technical.
A lot of people,
you'll hear people boots still when they
get on the ground.
I love the ground game.
I love that.
Thank you.
Have to think.
Oh,
it's definitely very technical.
Well,
what's interesting too is that there's
all these different approaches to
strength and conditioning and that's one
of the reasons why I wanted to talk to
you because one of the things that I had
seen was matt working out with you and
your guys and he was doing all kinds of
crazy stuff.
Like when you devise a plan,
like for an athlete,
like a Matte Brown or someone like that,
like what do you do?
You work with them first and try to
figure out what they're capable of and
then think about what their style is
like.
Obviously you're gonna have a different,
a different need if you're a striker
versus grappler.
Well one thing we do,
we try to get them where they're
conditioned to do five minute rounds and
recovering.
One minute.
When I worked everything was five
minutes and minute recovery.
Some guys had went through eight rounds.
A lot of guys I was able to do that.
I mean pretty good fighters,
you know,
13,
13 wins and and pro fights,
stuff like that.
So just whatever recovery I want to
maximize the amount of work it can do it
five minutes and then be able to cover
in one minute and do it again
repeatedly.
That's all I ever did.
Work on five minute intervals.
So did you work with guys,
use heart rate monitors and how did you
decide what to have done?
Any of that?
Really never now my print now John
Sattler,
he's got Shitty Chi Jujitsu.
He's basically started almost ready to
first MMA school in America if you think
about because he was judo,
Jujitsu Samba,
but also striking and he started in 1995
and he does everything by heart rate
where we do take by percentages,
uh,
like said we trained by a range of
velocity,
speed,
strength training and 75 to 85 percent.
He would do heart rates like that.
And like if you and I would grapple
with,
we could talk to each other for a half
hour,
that'd be optimal.
You know,
me and you can talk while we're doing
it.
That's an optimal heart rate that,
that way.
So he kept track of heart rates,
basically how we do a percentage of one
rep Max.
So meaning that it's optimal if you
could still talk while you're doing the
extra train optimally you knew you're
not like,
you know,
that's how I would be in here.
No.
So,
but if you're going to fight,
like if you're in a fight and it's a
very high paced fight,
it's very likely that you're going to
achieve much higher of heart rate would
be much more exhausted.
But see,
that would be up to much how we train
our speed.
Dave,
I to today for squatting and deadlifting
is optimized.
They do a 25 squats at one way and two
for speed strength acceleration into 20
deadlifts and then the other days Max
effort.
And that's what you're talking about,
what you go all out and around someone's
pushing,
you know,
they're trying to take you out.
So you've got to fight back.
So it would say it always changes.
You can't do the same thing.
It's called the law of accommodation few
night.
Uh,
if you and I grappled at the same rate
all the time,
I would actually catch up to you,
you know,
so you'd have to be able to maximize
your potential and run me into dirt.
So that's why you got to have few
different days,
you know,
you can't just do the same type of work
all the time.
I think that's where a lot of projects
go wrong.
They get wordy pages up too much.
You see that before fighters,
fighters cover up.
And uh,
you know,
I,
I'm gonna Watch fights all my life from
Roberto Duran to Mohammed Ali.
I've watched him.
I'm sure you've got to be a big fight
fan and you just see how some people get
in a scheduled amount of work per
randomly and that's when you beat them.
Take them out,
you know,
another word,
I'm gonna.
Make you go at my pace,
not you go,
in my opinion,
I'm gonna.
Go call your patient will make you feel
it.
Mine.
So varying the intensity of the training
varying how you do your training.
You think that's very important,
very important.
Hence the change those zone.
So does it have to change all the time
because the body just adapts and gets
efficient?
Try that as well as ask about it.
In Law of accommodation is you adapt to
a training loader stimulus and if you
don't change it,
you get no better.
You actually go backwards so you can
actually got to change these stimulus.
Tom Does a lot of stuff of war barrels.
We push we're bells around for half a
mile running sometimes heavier weight
walking,
get into belts.
Clot is very grueling.
And then just a maximal strength.
Went to simple things like deadlifts,
good mornings.
We do a lot of stuff holding the bars in
their elbows come has to do a lot of
that because almost like,
you know,
grappling,
pumbling and then uh,
other times,
you know,
you got to do quick stuff.
So quicker page stuff.
So,
you know,
it does how fights are their number one
pace.
Now,
how do you create a schedule like say if
you're working with a guy and you,
you,
you know,
we don't believe in schedule,
you don't believe in it.
Now,
even my guys,
I had the strongest gym in the world,
spoke about 140 all time world records
at breakfast and time can verify at
breakfast in the morning at 6:00,
6:30.
We decide what we're going to do that
day because he drinks majored in time.
It's not measured in weight.
It's measured in time.
Talking about velocities and so we just
pick an exercise like for you.
If we did a real low box squat,
didn't takes longer than squatting.
Eight hundred pounds.
Your gun squad a hundred pounds.
You know you choked me out after a
while.
I'm gonna tap.
All right.
Or if we run after awhile,
I'm going to run out of oxygen and I'm
going to quit.
Say thank for strength,
economic strain,
so long,
so long as you strained at least that
length of time or longer,
you're going to break a classical lift
and squat venture debt with.
I'm not totally sure I understand what
you're saying.
I'm like,
why do you have different?
You have.
When you grapple,
you're going to have different
opponents,
big ones,
small ones,
fast and slow ones left hand,
right hand,
right,
and so you,
you,
so you adapt to all different
situations.
We,
that's what we do.
As long as our training is harder than a
contest,
we're going to break records.
I took a gentleman not long ago,
a 800 pound squat at one 65 top of the
world right now,
1880 total top of the world,
I promise the one year old world record
in less than a year,
each quarter,
80 pound world record until of 2008.
And we just got systematically,
we run everything in ways three for
speed.
We work on speed,
strength,
exhilaration and we.
So he goes,
uh,
is basically 75,
80,
85 percent.
And then on the fourth week we way back
and start over.
We changed the bar so that way by
changing a safety squat bar,
if you know what that is,
or even a front squat,
we changed them link to the spine.
Um,
you know,
without really,
you only got one of the spine,
but we do it systematically by using
different bars so you,
your brain has to now think differently
because it's got a bar from where it
sits on top of your back.
Your lower back is different.
So it has adopted that every three
weeks.
So by changing bars and changing is like
the type of workouts you do,
it forces your body to adapt all sorts
of different loads or all sorts of
different ways of standing.
All sorts of different outputs.
We change.
Your leverage is constantly changing
leverage and where the bar has to keep
going the same,
you know,
like your car.
I talk about this all the time,
you know,
if you look at your car,
a normal car,
it will shifts at 2,500 rpm.
So every time it shifts gears,
well that's optimal horsepower for that
car.
And so we traded it to a certain
percentage of the bar.
Speed is optimal for postal power.
Or if we want,
you know,
it's 30,
40 percent.
I'm like,
well,
I'm want to take you down and I'd work
on 30 slash 40 percent,
wait til one a muscle you,
I've worked with 75 to 85 percent wage,
so it'd be strength speed,
and if I had to really grind you out,
that's why we got to make you stronger,
you know,
how strong grapplers are.
And uh,
so we work on all,
all different philosophies and string
inside of one week and in where instead
of doing high reputations,
I'm like a person Icu,
let's say your lower back is susceptible
to injury.
You might have 600 pound legs and,
but only 450 pound lower back.
So we work a individual muscle groups,
single joint activity like reverse hyper
works your low back hamstrings and
spinal rectors,
right?
We got a special machine of works to
hamstrings.
Uh,
we got all these different apparatuses
that were different parts of your body.
So we don't have any Muslim bounces like
MMA if you've got no stand up,
I'm going to stand up with you.
We've got no grappling.
I'm going to take you,
you know,
so wherever you said we work on all
these witnesses have balances,
so we have constant balance of our
strengths and abilities and we're
capacity
and so because you don't have a schedule
and because you decide what you're going
to do that day,
do you just kind of assess like how your
athletes are performing and what they,
what they're capable of doing given the
each individual day.
We have records on all kinds of things
like penn dead lifts or box deadlifts or
some kind of squatters,
some kind of bench.
They break the entire gym.
Now there's only maybe 15,
maybe 15 guys.
It was a private gym,
but you break the record over 90 percent
of the time you're in,
you're out.
So why'd you decide to have a private
gym?
Like how come?
How come you don't open the same
commercial gyms?
I can't stand to be around people that
don't know if you're a real fire.
You don't want to be around a bunch of
facts,
right?
I mean I can't stand.
I can't stand to go into commercial gym.
Can't stand it.
I just got out,
I'll leave in five minutes because
they're not working out hard enough,
not worry,
not hard data on what the hell they're
doing,
you know,
looking in the mirrors,
looking girls and shit like that.
I like to ask,
but,
but um,
uh,
gym I want to work out,
then I'll go look at that.
So you just decided to set up this year.
We should do like a little tour of the
gym at the end of the iron sharpens
iron,
you know that,
right?
So if you're one with the,
you develop a limp.
So don't hang around people like this.
And how long have you had this gym for?
Well,
I've,
I've had a gym.
I started training by myself.
I had a top toe in the world,
1973 for a while until I brought my
back.
But I've,
you know,
I've had a gym book would training
partners since 1976.
She got my first part in 19 six.
It's always been private.
Is it my basement?
I went to my garage and we had to start
getting bigger and bigger and bigger is
not better,
but we had to get bigger because we
started to attract a lot of people that
were good.
I mean they're selected to come here
like anybody else in English,
so they just pay a membership fee or
something.
I pay everything.
You pay everything.
How do you keep this place running?
This business right here.
Oh,
selling books and videos.
Machines.
I don't know.
We got um,
got like 11 or 13 patents I've paid my
money comes from royalties from putting
my name on different companies.
That's really interesting.
So it's like almost the gym itself
doesn't bring any profit.
It's just reputation.
Probably 50 grand a year.
Wow.
When you say 500 years,
did gym costs me 55,000 a year.
Wow.
But it's one of the most respected
places in the world.
Science and most famous gym.
There's no sign you don't need a song?
Yeah.
We're pulling in here.
Like where the fuck is this?
Twice.
That's what you like.
Yeah.
Wow.
That's interesting.
Well that's,
that's about as hardcore as it gets.
And it's how it would choke him into
lovelace because a lot of people like
who the fuck is,
they're not that old.
Back in the day,
you still power lift yourself and.
No,
no.
I had to quit five years ago.
I mean I kept up my neck,
gave out when I was 63.
I did at 7:30.
Squatting to meet 500.
Five bench six 75 to 70 when you're 63?
Yeah.
Wow.
My neck just gave out wide.
Starting to pass out all the time zone.
You start passing out all the time
because of my neck.
Like what's going on and to compress
this.
What?
Yeah,
totally.
It's the basically from my mid back,
from my deck to my mid back is like
locked up all just from carrying heavy
weight,
heavy squats and heavier.
I was squatting for 10 when I was 14
years old for 10.
At 14 to 16 to content support.
Keen at 1:40.
Wow.
It hold new.
60.
I'll be 69 in two weeks.
But.
So how old were you when you were saying
that you lifted all that weight?
The law,
the most recent 63,
63 and that's when you done,
you're like,
that's enough.
I was passing out and you know,
I couldn't pass out and I came off a
platform and I expect for him was
described good.
It was 7:35 and he said No.
I said,
what was wrong?
He said,
you pass out.
I mean,
I didn't know.
Then I was on Queer Street,
I noticed as real dark covered.
So when I went I made it through.
That meant I needed to get an 1885 total
is actually 37th in the world that year.
Wow.
And then,
uh,
I mean I thought I could actually tell
what 2000 pounds if I,
I was doing training which was squatting
the age,
but,
but because it needs context,
you were geared,
it takes longer to get up and down.
Just caused me to pass out.
Now.
Have you ever thought about inventing
something that would strengthen the rest
of respond the same way you did the
reverse hyper?
I wish because I've got two devices.
It definitely worked for the lower spine
that I,
I need something from upper right now.
Um,
I just went through a series of stem
cell.
I don't know what you got.
You get stem cell stem cell in my knee,
both hips and my shoulder and.
Right and I just yesterday had platelet
injections in my knee and my hip.
You got to go back next week,
but I'm not,
I get nerve blocks in my neck,
you know,
I'd love to get my neck well,
but I think my also got kicked in my
leg,
uh,
by a kid.
A fight or a small one.
One 35 and he screwed up by.
Nice.
So that didn't help me any.
Why did he kick you in the leg?
But I told him to kick me in the head.
She didn't kick me,
don't kick me in and he kicked me to
nene.
Torn muscle in basically must be,
or a hamstring right above my knee.
Will you guys sparring or something?
Yeah.
Oh,
okay.
Yeah.
I'm just stupid.
Like dude.
So he's still spar?
No,
no,
no.
I keep.
I can barely get around now.
I had a fracture is called 13 guy hit me
in a hipaa baseball,
13,
10,
broken jaw and broken hand by 18.
You know,
you didn't have him in me back then.
Have you thought about inventing
something that would have strengthened
the cervical spine and linkedin?
Know I got on a boat of things I just
said we're gonna.
We're going to introduce the machine.
October 21st going to absolutely change
of strength training as world knows.
It's called a static dynamic of Elbert.
It will change.
The world is static dynamic developer.
What is that going to do?
Well,
it's like if I hold elbow and a get
pressure on your arm and go in,
I have a machine that's going to hold
you like throw a punch.
Hold it,
let it go.
Buy Button.
Hm?
I'm not sure.
I'm just watching you.
You do a a judo.
You ever see judo toss where a guy,
they'll tell you in crash pad,
like one for.
Well,
we'll hold you down while the other guy
tries to throw.
Then the guy,
let's go.
Yes.
Same thing.
Just like that.
What?
I mean,
I have a machine that could do that.
Oh,
interesting.
So you could pull like as hard as you
can and can't budge.
Me and I released zooming.
Is it possible to develop something like
a reverse hyper that works on some sort
of a neck brace?
Like a similar type of movement?
We've done reverse hypers with NEC
harnesses.
Yeah.
Where you're working in the top of your
spine to the very bottom of your spine.
Hm.
Now how would that.
So you would do the reverse hyper with
which to people are just listening to
this.
What a reverse hyper is,
is like say a table.
If you put your upper body on a table
and your lower body was suspended
underneath the table,
like hanging underneath the table,
you would attach your ankles to this
harness.
That's like a leg curl attachment and
you lift your legs up straight and then
when you let your legs down it's pulling
on your spine.
So it's active
pressure.
Right?
And what would you do with your neck?
I've put it,
we use it,
but put a neck,
arm or song.
So when you're down,
when,
when you raised that,
when you raise your feet,
we also read your upper body and then so
when we do have to use at neck harness,
you're working the very top of your
spine right up to the atlas all the way
down to six.
So
would it be a neck harness?
Like with weights on it?
Yes.
Okay.
So just like a regular neck harness,
like where you hang your weights down
and you do it.
Yeah.
So when you pick up your feet,
you pick up your head as well.
You,
you rub it down,
back and forth.
That's interesting.
Huh?
That seems like a great idea.
Thanks Joe.
Yeah,
I bet you do.
Well,
you mean as soon as I saw that reverse
hyper machine,
I was like,
well how come this isn't used constantly
because it totally makes sense.
It's Trenton's the back and a very
strange way.
Like I brought in a bunch of people that
have had back issues and they just try
it once and then go,
whoa.
I'm like,
yeah,
why the fuck is this thing?
Not Everywhere.
It's marketing.
You know Tom Barry here.
Does one marketing,
but you know,
we're just starting and I never tried to
market.
I didn't care.
I didn't care about my business,
cared about my gym now he cared about my
gym on my life.
It's one of the most,
it's one of the most common injuries for
people who lift weights or for people
who grapple,
like I know a lot of fighters who have
either have had diskectomy where they
take a chunk out of your disk or they're
getting disc replacements.
Now a lot of guys are getting
displacements because it develops a
pretty new technology in Europe where
they have these articulating titanium
disks and they just cut out all the
gelatinous substance between the discs
and they put this articulating
mechanical disc in there and guys were
getting great relief and they're able to
start fighting again.
I know rick story has to have them in
his neck.
Um,
uh,
quite a few guys have had these things
done where there their back was just too
fucked up and they just couldn't do
anything.
It's another actually replacing disks.
Yeah,
that's what happened to me.
But with you,
they wanted a fuse.
You right.
I had two doctors,
2005 but would not pregnant on me.
She says she dangerous.
That was 11 years ago.
Why too dangerous?
I don't know.
Is that Ohio state do you sent me to,
to,
to search into Ohio state and he
wouldn't operate on me.
And you wonder why it was because I was
taking,
I was living on Nyquil and tylenol pm.
So it was too dangerous because you were
taking so many pain pills?
No,
they said it was at that time there,
the procedures they had,
they thought it was more dangerous not
to operate on me then leave me alone.
But I mean they weren't going through
me.
I've been trached.
I've had chest tubes.
I have a thoracic outlet.
What do my doctor here in town?
Outlet threat cutlets with.
A lot of people have open heart surgery.
So you can't put your hands over your
head anymore.
Um,
I went to my doctor.
He had me put my hand over my head and
raise my head and my pulse stopped
because it basically goes in and touch
his carotid artery.
Why it stopped my.
Yes,
so when you would raise your hands over
your head,
it would compress your carotid artery.
What's causing it to do that?
Because it would push whatever is doing
and would just cut the oxygen.
See if I.
If you want to tap me out and just puts
her head backwards and I'll go to sleep
for you.
Sounds like head backwards anymore.
Powerlifting sounds fucking terrible for
you.
Like you know,
if you had grappled guys,
wait one second.
You all your life.
I grabbed hold of guys away to 2,920.
Well not exactly what it's like,
right?
Yeah.
You know when you want to unlimited turn
tournament and you get some 285 pound
monster on your hands.
Same thing to get bigger and bigger.
It's A.
You're burning the candle at both ends.
So you know the weights each Sheila,
but you don't sound like you have any
regrets whatsoever.
I don't regret if I hadn't been beat up
and all my life.
I've never learned what I learned.
You know,
people make fun of me is.
Oh,
you broke your back in 70 through your
broker math.
Well,
you know,
I have no bicep.
Tore my bicep off.
$70 towards this and off a knotted up
right here.
That's where the bicep ties into your
forum.
So both your biceps had been torn off
and it never stopped me.
I told this and I'll totally.
And they told me I was done six months
later,
won a national championship.
Third biggest total estimate.
Pulled that.
Let me see what that looks like again.
So it's gone.
It's gone.
You have no bicep?
No right here.
So that's insane.
So you don't do curls it very few curls.
Curls don't matter for us.
Curls for the girls,
Sandra.
It's all extensions.
Extension.
Wow.
But that's how I learned.
You know,
how you going to learn.
So when you tour it,
you didn't even think about getting
surgery to get a return.
I went to three surgeons to set
operating one second.
You don't care what it looks like,
don't operate.
And I said I'm not operating.
Wow.
No,
I said six months.
So they are made to third highest over,
made my way clients and then you had to
fuck up the other one I don't believe or
not,
but I told them my patella tendon and
half,
I'd never done curls like you said.
Yeah.
Richard enhance many catheters over
here.
So I,
uh,
I was doing curls and then talking about
freaking payslip and Jim,
I'm so bored I couldn't hardly do
anything.
So you were so bored because he tore
your mortality.
Say,
well let me try these curls and then you
want to blow in your bicep.
I Petroleum,
I took Patel.
I was never going to let the kid because
I was 43 at that point and I'd done
about everything that I was going to do
a.
and then,
uh,
so like four years later I had a kid who
was training me these world record
holder at 20 years old in the bank,
seven,
28.
And I told him,
I says,
Kenny.
I said,
man,
I've got my retirement is caught seven
for you ever been seven again.
He said,
old man,
you don't interrupt several pounds on
your back again.
I brought me every time I write a seven
eights and nines I squat,
I have a second biggest squat in the
world at 50 years old,
at the fourth biggest total assist
because brought it up
to you like,
hey,
you run your.
Run your mouth.
You know,
the good thing was he made me.
He made me do that,
but he never did break at bench record,
so I'm always thankful for.
I'm very motivated by anything and get a
highly motivated person.
Now you've also been real open about
steroids,
which I think is very commendable
because it's one of those things in the
world of power lifting the world of
bodybuilding and even in the world of
fighting,
it's a dirty,
dark secret that people like to keep to
themselves,
but your grandpa can take it.
Yeah,
yeah.
Right.
Yeah.
I,
I believe in my,
in my opinion,
there should be.
You should pass the physical.
No one has the right to tell you what to
do in this world.
When it comes time to die on the one
that's got a di,
someone's time for me to live letting me
lead to life.
I want to live,
but what do you think in terms of the
problem with a lot of people have the
problem,
the problem they see with using steroids
in sports is it's going to force young
people to use steroids to be able to
compete with the people that are using
them and do it anyhow.
Yeah.
But if everybody's forced to be cleaned
and they don't like what we're doing now
with the UFC,
you were like the Usada the,
the people that have stepped in and Jeff
Novitsky running that program.
The guy who caught Lance Armstrong.
Well actually,
Lance Armstrong was never caught,
right?
He passed.
He passed 25 tests for seven years in a
row.
I never was tested.
See,
it's not against the rules to take
drugs.
It's against the rules.
You get caught taking drugs.
That's a fucking loophole.
You got a good doctor.
You're on the craft or not.
Not.
So that's why there should be no,
uh,
Tyson period said an even playing field
stop the drug test.
I'd say the same thing.
Not Old Barn was seeing my testosterone.
That's true.
I mean,
when I was a kid,
even if I was born today,
I would be in prison.
You're not telling me to teach all
these,
you know,
some of those fighters have got way more
testosterone than another fighter.
That's true.
Not Born at same amount.
So the only thing you could,
why not train?
You got a better.
If you got a better,
uh,
you know,
if you could kick my ass because you do
Jujitsu and shit and I don't do any,
but that don't mean you're tougher than
me.
I just means you got a better coach in
So are you cheating me?
That's a good point.
But if two guys do have the same coaches
and they do have similar body types and
one guy's taking steroids,
he's going to have an advantage.
Right?
But isn't at pharmaceutical.
What are you looking at?
Watch TV every five minutes.
You go to a drug commercial one.
Every year I'll be 69.
Let's take all the god,
I'm 68.
I'll be 600 to let's take all the health
medication off.
Six to eight year olds.
I'll be the only one left on her.
I don't have any ailments.
Tom will tell you my problem is they go
to the doctor does note some Romaine.
There's nothing wrong with me.
I just beat the crap out of myself
physically.
I don't have high blood pressure,
high cholesterol,
I don't have anything and so let's just
take all the drugs away.
But all the old 68 year old guys off is
well.
Well be the only one lit for a guy like
all the old women.
Well,
for a guy like you who's not competing,
and was he one of the arguments for
fighting is that steroids allow you to
do more damage to your opponent and that
that is one of the reasons why steroids
should be illegal is because you can
train harder,
you have more endurance and not just
steroids,
but things like epo and bunch of other
stuff.
You'll have more energy in a fight.
You could possibly land more blows,
possibly wind up beating someone that
you wouldn't be able to beat and do
damage to them.
So it's different a lot of ways,
but why?
Why wouldn't person take us force for
him,
you know,
is called PDDS performance enhancing
drugs.
Why wouldn't you do that in sports?
Well,
his.
Because they would think of it as
cheating.
Well,
who does?
a lot of people don't know how many guys
are cry their eyes out,
but get caught.
Then he cried like bitches and a lie.
Right?
Baseball players,
they don't.
They never took drugs.
You get caught in a car like bitches.
That's what I don't like.
Just tell them.
I'll tell you,
I'll never read the Bible,
but see the billboards on the freeway
says,
I shall not lie.
Just quit line and come out and say I'd
take droids you know the NFL.
Why would you be in this for like the
NFL?
You know,
what drugs do is for recovery.
That's all it is.
You know,
you take.
I can give my strongest people I've ever
seen doing.
I've seen guys take board drugs than
anyone I've ever had much.
Really?
Yeah.
Jugs up make you strong.
You're born that way.
You're born Fascia,
born slow.
You're born with an attitude or you're
not.
Well,
that's the big misconception about
steroids,
right?
Is that they make you bigger.
The work makes you bigger,
is to recovery,
cause you to recover,
to do more workouts.
Right?
So everyone doesn't want to do workouts.
How did the people,
you know,
save you want to be an MMA fighter,
intimidated in a cage one time and never
get by.
Coleman told me,
Mark said he had a million restaurants
when he had hammer house here.
Soon as they got onboard one time,
but he never came back.
But there's,
there's a mild benefit to taking
testosterone,
a bunch of other stuff without doing any
physical work.
But almost all of it is in the fact that
you could put in or
work and you recover far quicker than
the average person.
Yeah.
But see that way if everyone took it,
you're not cheating.
You know,
you don't,
you gotTa,
you got a corvette,
you don't have to put high test cats in.
Don't you think that like it also for
young guys,
you can fuck up your endocrine system
and fucks up your body's production
testosterone.
So what?
So that's what hcg sport,
you got to spark doc,
you take her.
Everybody takes hcg because your muscles
shrink up because if you take roids,
you take tests,
you're taking more in mother nature told
you so you're not measuring cup,
but there are morons anyhow because you
took act,
you're nuts.
Wouldn't drink up HCG.
What does that stand for in tropic
hormone?
It raises all your home men's vendors
and sports there.
You cannot.
There's no sportsmanship in sports.
It mean you were still fight in
front of a big crowd.
Half the crowd will want me to knock you
out.
And the other half the crowd would want
you to knock me out.
Is that sportsmanship?
Well,
that's just people.
Sportsmanship is supposed to be the
athletes competing without cheating.
I mean if,
if,
if there was a pill that you could take
that made you invulnerable,
gave you like a God pill and you took
anyone into a fight and the other guy
thought he was fighting a man,
but you're,
you're invulnerable.
No one can hurt you.
You can't be hurt and you don't get
tired,
which you have superhuman strength.
That's a good point.
With share Roy still be legal or illegal
type point.
Well,
it would be better than steroids.
It would.
It would be like a superstar Roy,
but I mean,
wouldn't you think that that would be
cheating?
No,
no,
but we'll then nobody can beat anybody.
You just beat the fuck out of each other
and nothing would ever happen.
But in the hills right here,
it all starts up in your brain,
man.
See,
I kind of could see how you can make
that argument with other sports,
but fighting.
I mean fighting is about fighting.
Is problem solving with dire physical
consequences.
I mean that's what it is and if you can
minimize those consequences through
drugs,
a lot of people would think that would
be cheating.
I look at this,
I look at the Diaz brothers.
I'm guessing they got a lot of
testosterone.
I don't know who in the hell their dad
was,
but he must have a lot of testosterone.
Well,
it's interesting.
Those guys eat Vegan for the most part
thing.
Nate eats fish and eggs to.
I don't even know if Nicki's fish it
might have in the past,
but I don't think he does anymore.
I think he's pretty much Vegan,
which most people that eat vegan have
lower testosterone because the substrate
for developing testosterone is fats is
like cholesterol and fans and one of the
most important.
It's.
It's like when people get on ketogenetic
diets,
one of the more interesting things that
happens when they consume a large amount
of fats and saturated fats and
cholesterol is that their testosterone
goes way up to high cholesterol diet.
Yes.
So I don't.
I don't necessarily know if those guys
have high testosterone.
What they do have is high endurance
endurance is through the roof,
but a lot of that is because they
participate in triathlons,
a lot of endurance running endurance,
swimming,
biking,
things along those lines.
So it's.
You still have to have the brain thought
to go kick someone's ass.
Right,
but don't you think that Ronda Rousey
has that brain thought to.
She doesn't have any testosterone but
makes.
She has some but not a lot.
You know what I mean?
But more than other girls have,
but not more than about Cyborg.
Well,
that's a little different.
Well see that's the argument for
steroids right there.
That's the argument because she actually
has been caught,
but she's actually tested positive and
she's passionate test now,
right?
Yes.
But you know as well as I do that when a
woman takes male hormones for a long
period of time,
even if they get off of them,
there's benefits that they keep forever.
Same thing with men.
Yes.
And just because you're passing the drug
test,
I won't say who,
but I trained the top international shot
putter.
He could go off and apart and eight days
pass a drug test,
IOC said.
I will say say that's it.
It's only eight days.
You can get onto the Nana par se
antibodies,
one of the quickest ones to get
off of.
Right?
Yeah.
So I mean you.
I mean how I forget to take stuff for
eight days.
So the benefits unquestionably are
permanent or at least some of them are.
What I think about,
you know,
what you're looking at.
You're looking at a fight and career as
you see it in an envelope and then when
that day that tough part retires,
you forget about it,
but what about the years later after a
fighter's career,
if he was on antibiotics,
he would survive the fighting years and
be able to continue with his older years
like me.
So what you're saying is that listening?
Well,
longevity post career,
I totally understand that.
A lot of fighters believed that as well,
like testosterone replacement,
growth hormone therapy for guys who have
retired,
but while they're competing themselves,
they don't want to do anything because
they don't want to think that the reason
why they accomplish those goals because
they were taking drugs.
I could shoot tons of Roy and so much
that I think will make them kick my ass.
It's not gonna make them kick their ass,
but there's no question that some
fighters fight better when they're
taking steroids.
How about just a nutritionist?
Let's just cut out the nutritionist.
Yeah,
but the nutritionist.
Look,
look,
everybody knows how to eat healthy.
I mean,
if you're eating healthy and you're
training hard,
but one guy's taking steroids and one
guy's not,
there's a giant advantage with the guy
was taking steroids.
I just know too many people take
steroids and then the passenger test.
That's all I'm trying to say.
Right.
Well that bring up any names.
I understand and I know you're not,
but that's one of the reasons why the
UFC is instituted this incredibly
invasive.
You sought a policy where they don't
wake you up at 6:30 in the morning.
Well,
how'd you like that?
Watching piss in a cup.
I don't like it exactly,
but that's the only way to catch people.
I just.
I'll never go into a drug test.
I don't think the NFL,
she had drug tests intro.
I think there's a good argument there.
First of all,
it's a good argument for baseball
because baseball,
no one's getting hurt in the NFL.
You could make the argument that you're
able to hurt guys more and then that
damages them and it shortens their
career,
but.
But baseball does no argument,
in my opinion.
Baseball's boring as fuck.
And if,
I mean some people like it,
I get it,
but what I'm saying is like if you got a
drug that lets you hit more balls over
the fence,
take that.
That's the only thing interesting about.
So how do you let that sport get away
with it?
You know what I'm saying?
Why not make it legal for all,
you know,
like baseball's a funny thing.
You know,
if you hit less than 50 home runs,
I guess your drug free,
but you start hitting 51 year old roy
dry.
It seemed like as what this core.
And he talked about the base,
the steroid here [inaudible] we're
taking a drug to 19 sixties who they
trying the kid where they.
Yeah,
in St Louis,
you know,
a football team.
Um,
you know,
the raiders.
Uh,
I've heard stories where I think it's
documented on espn.
Never gone in and had the ball tabs on
the training table.
Alright,
well,
you know what I say to the raiders or
the baseball team,
the oral,
the um,
the aes athletics.
What was like,
if they're in the same town,
you sign these 200 and sexual
wondergirls room section about the
girls.
What if no one has it?
They knew football players were taking
it in in Oakland,
but why wasn't,
why wouldn't the baseball player if you
taken it right down the street.
The other problem was what do you think
that people were thinking of steroids as
being,
uh,
like that kind of power being a crucial
aspect of baseball.
But I think what it was.
Sure.
But baseball is more of a skill game,
don't you think?
Did anyone ever tests Mickey Mantle?
Roger Maris,
Hank Aaron,
you think Hank Aaron was doing steroids.
They had steroids back then.
Shirts 19,
39.
But where people were athletes taking
them?
No,
exactly.
Yes.
That's what I'm trying to say.
Get the football team was taking it.
Why wouldn't a principal.
So we'll get these fortunate result
geeks.
Anyhow,
they interviewed the goddamn thing in
her life,
but they're also a hypocritical and they
got these ideas and they're popping on
air.
Probably taken a,
you know,
a testosterone therapy as it is.
I was that apparently one time and his
doctors are big fat guy and he's talking
about how bad boy josh does listen to
them and then like for instance,
what's a patch on here?
He says,
well,
that's a testosterone patch.
What kind of thinking is that?
It's a true story.
Well,
there's a lot of hypocritical.
Thank you.
When it comes to that stuff for sure.
It's just,
it's,
it's an interesting debate and a lot of
people think that you should be able to
do whatever you want,
like the pride days during the pride
days,
which in my opinion are some of the most
exciting all time,
mixed martial arts fights.
Those guys did whatever the fuck they
wanted and the Japanese literally told
them like in their contract we will not
test you for steroids.
They told them that
hell at horse racing.
Dog Racing.
Yeah.
But everybody that's okay.
And he just worry about that.
Well,
echo poise,
poise is equity.
It's got a horse in the fucking title.
Yeah.
I mean,
and that's something that people take
and it's a hormone for steroids,
for,
for horses now.
So you don't think there's anything
negative with.
There's obviously got to be some
drawbacks of steroids,
right?
I went on antibiotics 19 January 1970,
1970,
1970.
And uh,
so what was this?
Two Thousand 16?
Yeah,
I'd never been off.
You never been off in 46 years.
That's insane.
Just stay on them.
I try no cycle in that.
Go off to tell everybody you're off.
I get sad.
I go out there and tell the truth.
I don't lie to people get upset at you
that you're so honest about it.
I don't give a damn of the upset of
course,
but I'm just curious if you ever come up
at the council of self respect and I
give him hell about these geeks.
They're not doing crap.
They suck when they were kids.
They suck when you're middle age and
they suck when you're old.
That's how I look at our day in prison.
I'll be on Roy John Little country road.
You wouldn't be putting our world
wouldn't be in shape us in the day if
they had some nuts,
but if they had not stayed,
wouldn't need steroids.
Right?
Because then let's say some aggression,
some aggression.
Yeah,
so my friend was a psychologist and he
would test people in prisons,
rapists and murderers.
He said he had tested some,
had 25 times the rate testosterone's
normal man does 25 one time.
That's why I say,
you know,
it wasn't even possible.
Well why are they out there raping
people and why they killing people with
no,
no remorse because he got an enormous
amount.
He said that he saw.
That's why they probably did it.
He didn't,
you know,
if you can't do that stuff,
he realized that.
But he thought that's why they will be
on a course to do stuff like that.
It was just absolutely crazy.
You take a look at elephant.
These elephants a well they call it when
they.
It just ease.
I'll test house on route,
killing each other and knock it down.
Villagers and everything.
So the world needs more of that.
Well,
I think it needs more because of the
look at the.
You know what,
when I was a kid,
just 10 percent gay.
Now they say there's 34,
34 percent,
four percent fluxes that.
But college is good.
I believe it.
Boy Bands.
There's no ways.
Thirty four percent.
Four percent.
Oh Man.
Okay.
Well I'm sure some would test out.
Terrific.
I look at Jeffrey Dahmer and he's out
there killing people.
Well,
he was gay too.
Yeah,
that's it.
But I don't think.
I don't necessarily think that's a
testosterone thing.
Right?
That's a sociopath psychopath thing.
Who knows?
I will say that.
Well,
I don't think.
I'm not talking about the gay part.
The other part we're eating people.
Yeah.
Yes.
I mean that.
But that's.
But that's not a good argument for
testosterone if you're seeing the
prisoners and rapists and murderers have
a lot of it.
So everybody has got a lot of opinions
about Roy's,
but I've seen probably a thousand people
on Roy's over the years.
Right?
Okay.
No,
maybe more.
Right?
That's right.
The ones who took the most drugs were
not always the strongest to strong guys.
Didn't take that much and uh,
a lot of them.
And then,
and the lesser guys take a ton of shit,
but he just can't necessarily.
That's not what strong.
Well,
isn't there also a point of diminishing
returns where like taking too much of it
throws your body out of balance to the
point where he's not going to recover
correctly because your body's constantly
dealing with this and it makes you
crazy.
Right?
He can't concentrate.
Yeah.
That's a,
that's a real problem that people don't
want to admit it.
The roid rage isn't a real thing.
I've seen it.
It's real.
It's 100 percent real.
I don't think there's such thing.
Roid rage.
You don't think so?
No.
Well you said it makes you crazy.
Yeah.
But I don't seem to have a little guys.
You know,
there's plenty of fighters would fight a
300 pound guy because it was just crazy
because you're crazy.
You know,
it's not causing on roids are fucking
crazy.
Right.
But when people are taking too much
steroids and it makes you crazy,
a little guy's not going to jump on a
big guy and get his ass.
Great.
You know,
because of Roy Price,
he'll do it because he's.
He was born that way to do it.
There's two kinds of people praying
predator.
You'll find out which one you want to.
Real quick,
your prayer Predator.
Lou,
you're in this like very insulated world
and a lot of ways,
right?
Because you're constantly around these
savages.
You're constantly around dudes that are
just fucking lifting and crazy
heavyweights.
Very manly men.
A lot of guys are doing steroids.
A lot of guys lifting weights like
that's your world.
Like this is the.
These are the types of people that you
surround yourself with.
A lot of people that are listening to
this right now,
like,
this guy's fucking crazy.
Who's this guy with no biceps and been
on steroids for 40 years?
Like,
this guy's a maniac.
I Dunno.
I mean I,
I was born to do something and I did it.
I,
I've never strayed from the way I've
done one thing.
I'm going to go to the day I die.
I'm not going to quit what I do
everyday.
I've got to try and make me better or
someone else better.
That's what I do.
That's the only thing I've ever done and
I never quit it.
Well,
for you,
for a guy,
if he was in my gym,
I would find a way to you to make you a
better graph here.
I believe you.
I believe you would just my job.
I believe you would now being 68 years
old if it wasn't for all your
debilitating injuries that you've gotten
from lifting crazy amounts of weight.
You look great.
You look very healthy,
like,
like very healthy.
Like you have energy,
you're very,
you know,
you're,
you're on top.
You're on the ball.
When,
when I'm talking to you like,
do you attribute a lot of that to take
the steroids that it gives you that
energy?
We'll enter testosterone.
I mean,
Lord,
I'm not saying I might be dead,
but I mean I wouldn't be sitting here.
You wouldn't be talking to me.
You wouldn't know who illusion is what.
I mean,
I broke my back in [inaudible] 73.
I had no training partners.
I was on crutches for 10 months.
Everyday I get down in my basement.
I looked at a mirror ahead,
Amir and an am radio and in that mirror
and said,
how am I going to get better?
What I gotTa do everyday?
I've never to this day.
I mean I can't go until.
I mean you just can't pass out.
He killed me in to God's witness,
so that's what got me out of my sport,
but he was listening to this and here's
that pounding on the roof.
That's Ohio rain folks,
metal ceiling and the roof.
So it's nice for us in California.
We don't get any rain ever.
So nice to be down here.
Get some rain.
So what stuff do you take?
I mean,
right now?
Yeah,
just testosterone,
testosterone.
What have you taken normally when I've
been trained,
but take a donabell capitalists,
you know,
I just did tests.
You talked about that composer like that
component.
What about human growth hormone?
Orange waste of time doesn't work.
It's a waste of time.
Yeah.
How so?
Well,
you know I took is human growth before
HIV came out and kidnappers called Chris
Corman of ride.
That's the stuff that came out of
people's brains.
They took out a pituitary glands,
right?
That's right.
Well then when it made sense not growth
hormones,
they never made some enemies.
Somatomedin triggers not a trope in
wishes,
growth or some matter meeting.
What does it about to meeting triggers?
Growth Hormone.
And if you don't have,
they never made synthetic.
Some atomy.
I mean people take growth hormone and
how many people,
you know,
take growth hormone.
If you take hormone,
you have to eat around a guy your size,
you'd probably have to do seven,
seven,
8,000 calories a day.
Is that blood sugar attacks one after
another?
You don't.
People don't do that.
Why?
Because it doesn't work and it knocked
body fat off.
You see people losing body fat and no,
it's a joke.
It's a more um,
what's the word?
Placebo effect in anything.
So you don't think it helps people
recover from things?
Anything?
I took tons of it.
I've been prescribed it.
I have a fake shorter fake shoulder.
Yeah.
What's going on with shoulder?
I had to have a shoulder replacement.
Wow,
okay.
If pros had a frozen shoulder,
had to replace this one and then um,
uh,
so I got tons of growth for them and it
didn't go through him or not,
I just gave it away as waste.
Wow.
Dr [inaudible] study you.
It seems like everything wrong.
Fake children really.
And what,
what and what a exercise benchers you
bench press over 500 or the fake
shoulder to doctors.
I did 24 reps,
100 pound dumbbells with 2,400 pound
dumbbells.
Jesus Christ.
That's insane.
It's in the mind.
So you're saying it's all in the mind,
you know,
there's a book a fighter's got.
Remember his name is called pain don't
matter.
It don't matter to me.
I'm so freaking used to paint.
It don't matter,
but it's a fake shoulder.
Like I don't mean are they,
are you supposed to be able to lift that
kind of weight in a fake shoulder?
Like did doctors tell you,
be able to go
back to training?
I had it done by the doctor.
His name is Dr Bianchi was the Cleveland
Brown searching at the time and he
basically gave me no instruction.
I left the hospital that day,
I recovery and uh,
never I did my own therapy to give you
no instructions already knew.
He literally,
it was new at the time.
He kind of wanted to see if it would
hold up my,
my,
my buddy march was a strength coach with
the browns.
He said this guy is crazy,
you know,
so he wanted to find out this thing
would hold up and it must have held up
because I mean,
you know,
and it's still okay now,
man.
Wow.
Score and you see this,
you don't believe me?
Oh,
I believe you.
Yeah.
Wow.
PCB did stuff.
And so when you got your soldiers
shoulder replacement,
how long did you wait before you started
lifting?
Heavy benching?
I started pinching in one week,
started to branch to come one week.
That's so crazy.
How much will you benching one week?
Not a broomstick,
but in,
um,
in three months I benched 300.
That's so crazy.
That's crazy.
Well,
in that case,
I got to think steroids helped your
recovery.
I try.
Well,
that's one of the best things for it,
right?
Is recovering for injury.
And that's one of the best argument is
send it to athletes and nuts too.
You just can't sit around the doctor.
Take him for eight weeks.
That's why.
Don't go to doctors out of being a leg
becomes a quacks.
Surgeons,
that's all they know.
They don't know nothing.
They were experts on everything.
So I don't know this Dr.
well that's one of the best arguments
for steroids is post-injury recovery,
right?
It was for.
It was for concentration camp victims in
World War II.
Nineteen 39 antibiotics came up for
concentration camp.
They tried them to.
People come out of concentration camp,
prisoner of war.
That's what they make.
Antibody was first thing they made him
for.
Well it's really good for people that
are wasting diseases.
Same thing if you're in the prison of
war camp and give you some sort of
vitality back.
Yeah.
So when when you see guys that get
injured and you see them try to do
things without steroids,
like especially injury,
like injury recovery,
I think that's one of the best arguments
that like maybe when an athlete blows
his knee out or something like that and
get surgery,
they really should be allowed to use
that.
Do you think are in America professional
athletes?
All tone was in her at least 100 times
more.
There's a couple million older men
taking testosterone replacement.
So that's my art met.
Why would you not let an athlete?
What is the difference?
And that's what I just said,
but I don't care if you don't.
If you don't want to take,
I'm fine with me a damn.
You don't wanna eat a protein shake.
You don't eat right?
I don't care.
Well when it comes to eating right,
like what kind of.
What kind of Diet do you subscribe?
I really don't describe.
I eat eggs and meat in the morning and I
ate pretty good.
You know what I mean?
A lot of chicken and rice.
I'm not entered a good food.
I've seen people real clean.
They have no aggression,
so like a lot of bodybuilders super
clean.
It seems like I have no aggression and
you know,
if you're like what I outside the
throwing punches or kicks,
it's the same.
It's a fight.
You gotta fight these big white jeep.
You guys stay on Dad,
you gotta lift it and then you got to do
it over and over and over.
Just like,
you know,
11,
10 to aggression now.
Do you think that that's the lack of
cholesterol in the Diet?
Lack of fat?
It may be because I've just seen them.
I mean,
you know,
I've been around too many people.
Bodybuilder also.
They were the one that had the side
effects.
You'd get around.
They of the guys that have no facial
hair and uh,
you know,
or nobody here.
It seems like those were the ones that
I've noticed over the years and has no
side effects.
A little bit of drugs will give them
side effects and other people,
you know,
you always talk about taking stuff for a
to come out.
I've never taken anything like God darn
life.
I've never needed anything for Gyno,
for one made a real tough looking guy.
He'd never had any problem taking raw
because they're already got
testosterone.
It's not a.
it's not something new to their system,
but guys get guy.
No,
it's just because they have a ridiculous
amount of testosterone in your body.
Starts producing estrogen,
high estrogen anyhow.
Oh,
so you think it's just.
Exactly.
Because I've seen guys with big,
thick beard,
rough kind of guys.
You don't have no problem.
You don't have a problem.
I'm just telling you what to.
Right?
No,
I get it in lab.
I'm only telling you what I've seen in
my,
in through my many years,
what I've seen guys,
the guys that get whacked out on drugs
where the guys are very,
uh,
you know,
I'm not Finland,
Finland,
but almost kind of
when,
when the person who doesn't power lift
or people are unaware of the sport and
they,
they think of a bodybuilder doing the
same kind of things that have gotten,
like you would do,
that's what they think.
Oh yeah.
But that's not the case.
What is the big difference between
bodybuilders?
There's a high purpose,
high reputations in the eat different.
They take other things different to get
very big and then we don't want to get
big.
We're just like,
we wanted to stay in the smallest weight
class we can and get as strong as it
was,
the same big Ang strong,
strong,
strong.
So we just want to be strong,
so everything we do is not to build
larger muscles.
Like I've worked with track people,
mostly girls.
We don't want to put 10 pounds of
bodyweight,
almost 10 pounds of extra weight that it
had to overcome gravity rundown down
track.
Right?
So we keep keep your body weight to a
minimum.
The muscle mass,
we just want to make it strong.
You don't have to get bigger to be
stolen.
That's confusing to a lot of people
because a lot of people think of big
muscles meaning stronger and that's the
only way to get stronger.
But I've seen some people in power
lifting competitions.
It just lift insane amounts of weight
and they're not that big trunk.
Well how is that possible?
But muscle type,
you know,
you're always talking about you.
I've always mentioned you a few times.
You talk about like a wooly and says,
oh my muscular.
He runs out of gas real quick.
Who?
Tyrone?
Tyron Woodley.
Yeah.
He has the same.
Got a pretty pretty much the same amount
of muscle mass.
He just has very fast twitch muscle guy.
You,
you're not about to.
Endurance may have board slow twitch
muscle and then so that guy,
that's why he can fight five rounds and
tyrone were to start to wear out
somewhere in the second round.
Well,
it's also because a guy like tyron is
capable of putting out so much energy,
like the way he can attack guys and move
so fast.
It's like having a 500 horsepower engine
versus having a 400 horsepower.
One's going to just use.
Yeah.
Well just fashion.
She got sprinters and marathon runners
and it looked totally different.
Yeah,
and so when someone looks at a
bodybuilder and they see this guy just
covered in muscles,
they assume that guy will be able to
lift a ton of weights,
but for the most part those guys can't
live nearly as much weight as a garlic.
You can know that that's crazy to people
like that doesn't even make sense.
Well,
like a lot of things are crazy.
People do don't aren't in and know what
we're mentioning.
What about the anabolic stimulus?
Does it frustrate you that this lack of
understanding the general public has
about this stuff?
Absolutely.
Yo you ever.
You ever look at the Olympics?
We look at our weight lifters,
Olympic weight lifters.
We don't go to the Olympics.
We never did hope to never get any
Olympic.
Never tend to worsen,
so if there's ever been.
They said our Olympic weight lifting
team is pretty bad.
We can't get the guy on the 18th.
All right,
and they're just not very good.
You look at our women's gymnastics
people,
they're extremely strong.
Ain't a blurb out of the water.
You Go China.
There are male weight lifters and female
archery ministry muscular and they
killed everybody that your gym's look
pathetic these because they're all in
different systems.
She didn't know who they are.
You got better coaches and and better
systems that take stuff so well.
American doesn't have good Olympic power
lifters,
Olympic weight lifters,
lifters.
We rule the world power of Jews in this
country.
American witnesses are not very good.
They're not know terrible.
Really?
No,
I did not know that.
There was one girl what got a bronzy
Olympic one girl got a bronze.
We in,
in my sport,
there's 12 male way classes.
Uh,
we hold seven of the total records my
Jim Holtz to and in women there's 10
week classes.
America holds nine of the 10 and my Jim
holds five.
I have the strongest male power lifter
ever lived.
Period.
And the best and the strongest female it
will bury St Jim.
Now what about shit like those strongest
men contests?
Oh,
well her strongest guys.
But that's a different thing entirely as
well.
It's another defense.
Like boxing is different than intimate.
Yeah.
More,
you know,
more ties different in boxing.
You know what I mean?
You never said I'm going to say it in a
more Thai guy that's going to win a
world boxing championship and vice
versa.
But I think it has
happened.
Ty was what the fuck is his name?
Oh,
there was a kid though.
I mean,
the gold medal is thought Thailand
packet.
I think you shouldn't have your key.
Might've been a one time champions on.
Right?
Oh,
Chris Algieri.
Yeah.
He was a kickboxing champion.
Time to work out.
What's the fuck is his name?
I forget his name,
but there was the guy that.
He's the guy that John Claude van Damme
was always supposed to fight.
John Claude van Damme pretends is going
to have a fight.
It's going to have a kickboxing fight
with this is Thai guy and.
But that guy won a world title as a boy
tie fighter and as a boxer.
But that's pretty rare.
But I agree with you,
but now like what would be the
difference?
See like if you see like if you had a
guy come to you that wanted to win,
like a strongest man competition,
that seems like something that will be
right up your alley because you're so
good at preparing fighters and
understanding the different demands of
different sports.
My friend in Finland's name Chicago,
he's got poor guys in that gym over 900
and they're all strong man and he does.
He trains of Straw man.
Alright,
I'm not into that,
but he told Tom and I had one thing in
each sprint with barrels,
thousand pounds on willpower.
We do a lot of willpower work and also
to carry heavy yoke.
So that's two of the primary.
Thank you.
Get them to be strong men.
What's a yoke?
A Yoga thing,
putting me back in your walk around with
it.
Like if you walk around,
we do an enormous amount of walking with
bars with a badge and change hanging
off.
So it's unstable because that's what you
have to be.
You got to be stable and unstable
environment.
So they walk a half a mile of stuff
like,
I don't know about it.
He gets his strong.
Is that why you like wheelbarrows?
Because it's almost like a dead lift
that you've got to kind of walk with it.
Like I'm going to price you will get
more type fired at.
Doj thought that really helped us up is
um,
is plum colored clinch.
Yeah,
that makes sense.
Um,
so did you come up with the idea of
using wheelbarrows for nine,
1990 and it's just something that looked
to you like a good unstable platform
that builds up your ministry ministry,
building up your back and grip,
you know,
you've got to have a grip.
So,
you know,
you guys got great grips anyhow,
but it builds up grip and it builds up
all your muscles and your walking.
See My,
you know,
a lot of guys do strength and
conditioning.
I believe it's got to be combined.
You don't have that much time because
fighting is a treatment and skill.
You need all your.
I mean the world's strongest man.
Hate the damn the MMA champion now.
So I believe you got to strength and
conditioning st time.
That's why we do so much outside
walking.
We're doing heavy objects walking.
So we're conditioning and strength
training.
Do you pay any attention to Marius
[inaudible]?
Oh sure.
He knows what he's doing now.
He's fighting MMA.
Oh,
I knew he did.
I didn't know he's still doing it by
lifting strong man and went to that.
Yeah.
He's um,
he's,
he hasn't given up.
He's been doing it for quite a long time
now and he's actually beaten so pretty
good guys at this point.
He knocked out halls,
Gracie,
and the first round he,
um,
he lost it.
Tim Silvia.
But that's a fight that he never should
have taken.
But you know,
Tim Silvia is big giant former UFC
heavyweight champion,
but you know,
you see tim,
Tim's got like a lot of body fat on him.
He is not like the most gifted athlete
in terms of like,
like randleman is like a freak athlete.
He was when he was alive.
Recipes.
Who's a great guy.
I love Kevin,
but he was probably one of the biggest
natural genetic freaks I've ever seen.
Tim's not that Tim's just hard work and
dedication and just toughness and he
beat the fuck out of Mary's [inaudible].
It's kind of funny when you see the two
of them together.
I might've saw that fight.
Yeah,
he might've have,
but he started out.
He started out kickboxing.
Denise,
before we even went into a,
I think he kicked box when he was a kid,
puts an asking,
did he?
Maybe it was a boxer,
boxer,
okay.
Boy,
do you not believe it when you see him
hit the pads and he was starting out.
It was like,
yeah.
It's like almost like,
you know,
he's weighing himself down,
like throwing weights all over his body
and trying to move himself.
It wasn't,
but my point being he's actually
transition is become a legitimate
professional mma fighter who's beaten
some guys.
He's not.
Not Bad.
I mean he's not.
No one's gonna say he's a threat to the
UFC heavyweight title least at this
point in time,
but it's interesting to me because he
still 300 plus pounds.
He's still a massive,
massive guy and he's fighting.
All these events are all places where I
don't think they test them too,
which is interesting too.
Tim.
Sylvia,
when he was at his best,
when he won the title against Ricoh
Rodriguez was on some shit,
but he was a.
He looked so different back then.
He didn't look like a
doughy sort of heavy guy over his best
example.
Ubereats?
Yeah.
When when overeem came to the UFC,
when he fought brock lesnar and you
know,
it was kind of the wild west of testing
back then all you had to do was pass the
post test.
That's it.
That's all you have to do.
Which was,
you know,
like you were saying,
if you take an avant,
they just get off it for eight days.
You're clean,
you know,
but the facts were obviously still
there.
Exactly.
Yeah.
I mean and has always been the drug of
choice for collegiate wrestlers,
you know,
way back years ago because the fact it
gets out of your system so quickly
because he keeps your body weight down.
You want the demurrage really
bodybuilding,
they take drugs that you know that on
low calorie diets he can maintain muscle
mass.
He touched the Princeton I think was the
only one kind of antibiotics.
Why isn't bodybuilder look like I do and
was part.
You know why they look different if
we're taking the same drugs?
Because it totally is totally different.
You.
Yeah.
That's one of the orientations.
Totally different.
One of the big dirty secrets about Vegan
bodybuilders,
like almost all Vegan bodybuilders are
taking something and the reason being is
because of the fact they're not getting
enough cholesterol,
they're not getting enough saturated fat
in their diet and so your body just does
not want to produce that kind of muscle
mass.
So those kind of guys are almost all
taking something in order to put that
kind of mass onto their body.
You know,
say we are trained to Olympic gold medal
spreaders.
Alright.
I've trained all kinds of people and so
it's not like you just been around power
lifting.
Everyone I know,
you know,
there's a rate like,
we will get back to the drug tests.
You ever think about the Olympics?
People were records that the drug at the
Olympics.
What records of her breaking world
records drug free.
Why do you need drug testing?
Maybe one of your callers calling me up
telling me that one.
Well,
because they're passing the drug.
well they're also catching them from
previous years.
Now you hear about the,
uh,
the Russians,
those two guys from 2008,
they got their gold medals pulled from
them.
Just bullshit is bullshit.
It's bullshit because you think other
people were doing it too,
of course.
But Russia has a very sophisticated
anti-doping program in America.
Divergence now let's say that America I
don't think is so blatant about their
endorsement of drugs.
I think America kind of knows about it
and,
but they can't come out and say it or
come out and
if you're overseas,
the pain just went to them.
What place you got?
They don't care.
How do you don't think they care?
No.
Course.
Not Overseas.
No,
because it's,
it's,
it's done by the state uses.
It's done by the state.
And that what the problem was that
Russia was guilty because it was state
funded drug administration.
Okay.
What do I mean?
They're doing the same thing happens.
Report.
Well,
not just that rush is killing the
scientists.
All the scientists know about it.
A good giant percentage of those guys
had been shot in the fucking heck we've
been reading about that.
Oh,
they're dropping
like flies.
Yeah,
all these guys,
because once Russia got in trouble,
they were,
they were in danger of being eliminated
from the Rio Olympic Games.
You know about that,
right?
Yeah.
Well,
no,
they didn't.
They,
they allowed them in.
Now there was no way that they don't
forget how many people.
A couple hundred Russians did not go.
Oh really?
And you know.
Yeah.
And a girl here in America,
it's a high jumper I think,
or a pole vaulter which tested 33 times
in three years.
That's bullshit.
It's total bullshit.
I had victor content on my podcast,
you know,
he has the ball co guys.
I know who he is.
Yeah.
He pushed all the roysher ever and then
he's a drug test her.
Well now he's okay.
He's performed here for Peace Now.
The.
Exactly.
Yeah.
Um,
he's,
he's an interesting case,
right?
Because he was a guy that had developed
a designer steroid that was
undetectable,
which they still have.
They still have those,
how they break and world records and not
bucking the drug test.
You know,
I was born at night joe,
but it wasn't born last night.
See,
I was.
And,
uh,
I like to believe that people are just,
it's just hard work.
And folks who,
uh,
believe in that,
do you think it would be better if
everybody just came clean and everybody
just did whatever they wanted to do?
Exactly.
I really did.
I think or know why is your dad,
why?
Why possibly is your father on going to
the ancient clinic and taking
testosterone growth hormone?
It was that damn bad that you hit.
Your Dad wouldn't be going there.
There's a couple million people I know.
You're just that guy.
There's probably over 2 million people
doing it annually.
Why are they doing?
That's a good point.
It certainly helps you.
It makes you and your brain function
every.
Everything's better.
It really,
your drive,
your muscle,
your muscle.
You've got more muscle.
He got better bone density.
You got better sex drive and get better
dry period.
But I mean,
mine is never changed.
That's my whole freaking problem.
My brain's never changed since I was
like 16.
So your brain's still functioned the
same way.
I think a lot of that
face never get around a person.
And you just look,
here we go.
We're going to kick your fucking ass
because I don't know why they just can't
my camera.
I just want to punch him out.
I can do that.
Do you think that's road rage?
Not really.
Bridge.
This was when I was born.
I was that way when I was 10 years old
and I'm that way now.
I just teach sometime.
Does it go?
I want to.
And you know,
it's weird because I can get around.
Old Man is no threat or nothing.
Me,
I'll go,
I want to punch this guy in the face.
I'm serious.
I know it sounds,
but then I go,
I can't do that.
I know I can't do that,
but I'm going home because.
Because there him and chuck is bitches
gonna Choke your ass.
I'm not,
but I don't think it's enough in my
brain and say,
no,
you're going to go to jail if you do
that.
But that's how I've never changed right
now.
I don't know if I'd say sometimes I
think,
Gee,
I wish I changed.
It'd be a little bit mellow.
Like I'm supposed to be.
Well,
a lot of 68 year old guys,
they're,
they're slowing down and they don't have
a lot of zest for life.
GRANDPA turns into grandma.
Yeah,
it does happen,
right?
Yeah,
that's right.
You say I kinda weird too that you can
go to like any kind of a nutrition store
vitamin store and this shelves are
filled with muscle builders and
recovery.
This growth hormone,
that and fake test house rooms.
Yeah.
Well,
and a lot of them turn out to be
steroids,
but then he'd go to use against all.
Well it is against the law,
but you sign it has a page and when we
had no Wicki on the podcast,
and this is when I found out about this,
I was blown away because they have list.
What was it like?
It was over a thousand more than a
thousand different products that have
tesco have steroids in them that people
are buying under the guise of just being
some natural muscle builder or you go.
So there's probably thousands of people
on here in America and city year against
taking drugs,
but you're taking drugs,
right?
Well,
there's certainly a lot of people that,
well,
you know,
there's a lot of people that have taken
drugs and they don't want to admit
they're taking drugs,
like people want a drug free America,
but they want to drink beer and they
want to drink coffee and they want to
smoke cigarettes.
All these things for trunks.
Right?
Yeah.
I've said that you'll go to a football
game,
like a house steak.
You got to,
you got 100,000 drunk take,
you know,
up and smoking cigarettes,
watching 22 athletes on the field that
are clean.
That didn't make any sense.
I can't drive him out the parking lot.
Do you think that leave even for high
school athletes that like steroids are a
good idea?
I think when you're able to vote you
out,
build you anything you want at 18 years
old,
God,
if you could drink,
why couldn't you take roids if you're,
you know,
I mean,
I still believe it should be the draft.
I think that's what's wrong with America
today.
There's no draft,
there's not enough people that have a
father figure in his country and I think
if they went in the army,
you eventually have a father figure.
I was.
Ios actually was a bought 10 or 12 years
old.
I tend to block during summer vacation
and then during school,
the guy who picked me up and I actually
knock holes out these that thing.
There's called a knockout.
I will knock out these blocks and
putting the word take out.
What's a block tender?
What does that blog tenure?
I carried block and mixed mortar cement
block.
Twelve years old,
12 years old.
I started working at 12 years old,
I guess.
Social Security card.
Twelve years old.
That's right.
Wow.
That's how I grew up and I,
I grew up by if I want to make money,
I got to work.
No,
I had nothing.
And uh,
you know,
uh,
my,
my parents had money,
but the party there were party animals
and so I didn't get nothing.
I bought everything I've ever done since
I was 14 years old.
No one's ever given me nothing.
People,
you know,
with these guys day,
I pay him to lift,
you know,
if they make a world record or get on
our board down there to get money.
I never,
I would never take any money.
I never took nothing.
He's guys get protein,
they get free gear.
I took nothing.
I own anybody,
anything.
And when I die I won't owe anybody
So you think that way by saying that the
draft exists,
like forcing people into the military
force to them to serve would at least
give them some discipline and give them,
like make them understand what hard work
really is.
Caucasian and discipline,
you know,
what's going on with the police force,
in America today.
It's just a lack of,
it's just a lack of common sense and I
mean authority.
They don't have,
you know,
represent authority.
I,
I grew up,
uh,
I remember was I used to play baseball.
I can help people to story.
I was like 12 years old and we played
this game.
If you hit a ball out the yard,
you're out.
But if you had inside,
he already got the second score.
You got to score to run and it was just
you against me with a neutral pitcher
and I slid into second base.
I was 12 years old and my neighbor was a
high school senior.
I,
I'm memory probably like 220 pounds and
then he gets up and he said,
you're out.
And I said,
I'm safe.
And he slapped the hard as he can slap
me and he goes,
you're out.
I was out.
I couldn't kick his attitude.
I grew up a pecking order.
No one knows what a pecking order is and
number to picking nowhere you over,
but is that good for society to have
that kind of a pecking order?
We wouldn't be ran over by all these
countries right now if we had a pecking
order.
Every look at the picking order now
they're all,
you know,
you go to school because you got
bullied.
You know,
I got kicked out of school in first
grade.
Okay.
Not for a day.
I got kicked out for the first grade.
A kid stole my shoe.
I won't tell my dad said,
hey,
this guy stole my shoes on their side to
Columbus here on east side,
and he says,
well,
I'll tell you what he said,
if you tell me that tomorrow,
a basic to basically said,
if you told me that one will kick your
ass.
So I go to school kit tristate Mushu.
I punch and get in a fight with them and
teach it,
breaks it up.
I ended up punching the teacher.
They take me down to the principal's
office and the.
And they said,
you're kicking me out of school.
So my mom says,
for how long is it?
We're kicking him out of school.
I'm going to first grade.
So we moved across town over here on the
west side of Columbus.
You know,
we'll say Barbara,
but he wouldn't let me at school.
I had to set it on a freaking year.
I didn't start school at seven years
old.
Wow.
From Punch the teacher.
All right.
What kind of teacher can't take a six
year old punch?
I have exactly.
It's basically back then that seems
ridiculous.
But I.
But I still think that.
But you know,
no one has any,
there's no trades in America,
you know that they're talking about this
now knowing you don't have any
tradesman.
If they went in the army at least two
years,
you can get a couple of years of college
free education and something gets
something from the government instead of
a handout from the government.
Well,
some people think that it would be that
mandatory military service would be good
because then they would realize the
consequences of war that would really
understand it.
Like Israel does,
like Israel,
everybody has mandatory military service
and their patriotism is at a very high
level because of that,
because they realize that they're all
connected in this giant army.
When the army goes toward that literally
is them.
I believe the same thing.
I just think it would change.
Think I can say this country so sick.
You know,
your,
your kids are older and they got these
things because your kids building well,
you know,
I'd rather be the bully then to be
bullied.
I bullied everybody I kid could and the
bigger people bullied me.
That's just the way.
Is that good though?
I know my role in society,
but wasn't a little bitch and acted like
I run my mouth to you and you touched
me.
You know what I mean?
I go call the cops.
Right?
You beat my ass.
Fuck that guy beat my ass up.
That's just the way it goes.
I mean,
I've got 13 teeth.
Okay.
How are you thinking?
That's why I got 13 from running my
mouth.
Oh,
and I don't have no regrets.
No regrets.
It taught me lessons.
Was that the only way to learn lessons
though?
I think it's a damn good for you.
I think it's a good one.
You can't think you're something that
you're not.
You just have to grow.
That is a problem.
I just know what you really are.
That's all that matters.
Well,
I think a lot of people think there's
something other than what they really
are because they're not tested because
they're not the.
You know how many people in this life go
through difficult physical struggles on
a regular basis?
It's one of the main things that human
being,
especially men,
one of the main thing that men lack in
life is very difficult physical
struggles that tests your character.
Exactly right,
but being a bully doesn't test your
character or somebody that be bullied.
What's all UFC fighters in the cage?
Well,
once they get in there,
but that's competition.
I know.
I mean,
I know they're great guys outside the
cage.
Matt Brown,
you know,
they're all nuts.
This Greg Guy,
I get crazy looking eyes real quick and
she's got crazy eyes.
You Fuck with Matt Brown?
That's a big mistake.
I mean that's a real.
That's a test.
And you got to be tested.
Yeah.
And you know what?
It don't get sad old thing.
You don't mark,
you get knocked down.
Can you get back up?
Got Back up to million times.
I'd never don't give a damn.
I mean honestly,
it don't matter.
You know,
like I always said like Canva,
if Kevin will beat my ass.
Well,
so what?
He beat a 100 other people.
I'm just.
That long list would be be my ass.
What?
I feel bad.
No,
it can't be.
Feel honored.
I got Kevin relevant,
kicked my ass.
Well that's because you could overcome
that kind of shit.
You've been through shit like that
before.
You understand what it's like to have a
bad moment in life and it's not going to
wreck you.
Brush yourself off.
Yeah.
That's the problem with people.
When your children get bullied and they
send them some kind of cool because
you're bullied and my father sent me
because I got bullied,
I'd blow my brains out.
Do you have kids?
No,
I knew I should've never had kids on
eradication.
Wow.
How'd you.
How'd you manage to get through without
knocking up one check.
My wife didn't want to have kids and I
didn't want to have kids and she grew up
pretty poor and like four or five
brothers.
Your mom raise your cut.
Your Dad got killed in a car wreck it
too.
And I never want a kitchen.
I mean my life's for.
Okay.
I don't have time for kids.
I wouldn't have time to be a good
father.
I knew that.
So why would I have kids?
Well,
that's a very rational way of looking at
it.
I've been married 43 years and I'm as
you do that because of daylight,
that's a smart way looking at do you
have like when you,
when you look at your life,
I mean at 68 years old,
you've accomplished so much,
has this great reputation in,
in power lifting and you know,
just in,
in helping people and athletes,
especially in mma.
I mean when I talk about you to the MMA
fighters,
you know,
you,
you have a fantastic reputation.
I mean,
people just go.
They just nod their head and like,
that guy's the shit.
You know,
he knows his stuff.
Do you have goals at this point
in your life?
Yeah,
I should've got goals because we got to
keep a couple of products.
I want to get out before I die.
You know,
I've gotten mechanical reverse hyper.
Did she talk about it?
She'd be an hospitals over the world and
mechanical one,
so it does it without you lifting
weights is put you,
stands you up and it will put you in
place.
It can move your legs back and forth.
You get well then would assisted in it,
you could read,
it would have resistance,
so for someone who's like maybe two a
week to actually lift the weights up,
like if you couldn't move your legs,
visitors you'd like,
I can move your leg.
You say okay,
that's it.
Okay,
Then week after week until we finally
get that full range of motion,
once we gained full range of motion,
then we could put a resistance to
mechanical resistance for you picking up
two pound,
three pound or whatever,
but.
But it's static dynamic developer.
I'm coming out was going to
revolutionize the strength training for
every sport.
Well,
I'm interested to see that.
Do you.
Do you have that here?
No,
we've got it on film.
We can a little bit on film,
but when you feel that you would not
believe it.
Yeah,
I'm very curious.
I'm very curious to see what that's like
and I got one more book on writing a
book right now and then I'm pretty much
done with discussing the editor and have
it track and field a track now.
Feel just track for sprinting and
distance and just about developing
strength for helping strengthen reducing
injuries.
There's so many injuries now.
What about an MMA,
a dessert.
Do you think there's a way to reduce
injuries and MMA through powerless?
Too much.
Really?
Yeah.
I think he's far but too much problem.
Then,
uh,
I used to talk to guys way back in the
[inaudible] campus.
Big that guy because it was 95 percent
of fight.
He would go there.
He was a kate one fire and he said,
and I think you've got to slow that down
because you're,
you know,
they say in boxing fights,
don't get you.
It's as foreign.
Yes.
So that someone was firing,
working on skill and work on your skill.
Was this thing.
They say that because that's the trend.
Now,
Donald Cowboy cerrone,
who's never looked any better than he
does right now,
and he's on a tear.
He said he stopped sparring.
He doesn't spar.
Says all I do is do drills.
He goes,
I already know how to fight or know I'm
tough.
He goes on,
don't waste myself in a gym.
We have the greatest squatters bar ever
in the history of the sport,
and we don't squat.
We settled on boxes.
We don't do regular squats.
What do you mean?
We sit down a bunch of just sitting on a
chair.
We will and then stand back up.
I taught were you training to.
We go to a contest,
then you got to do a squat.
We don't do any regular debit with a
rope,
a bar,
and real weights.
None.
And our top,
our top five average is 890 and
10 is eight.
Sixty six.
So you,
what do you do if you don't do regular
dead lifts?
We do bands over the bar in power racks.
We use two or three different bands over
the bar,
meaning elastic band
instead of my edge,
220 pounds of attention.
Like if you picked up,
you know,
200 on the bottom,
you stand up,
it's 4:40,
right?
Okay.
Or we got stronger boundaries.
Oh,
did you have to kind of bands and,
and uh,
we just do a lot.
Stuff like that.
So what that means to people that are
listening to this,
when you have these elastic bands on the
bar,
that makes it more difficult when you
get up to the top of the range of
motion.
That's the same with chains to it.
Better?
Yeah,
changed.
It's called accommodating resistance,
but it builds a tremendous acceleration
in these.
A lot of band camp treat mentioned
acceleration to very bottom because you
knew you had at the outrun the bands.
Right?
Right.
So yeah,
you have to outrun the bands and then
when you get to the top it becomes more
difficult.
So you when you have just a regular
deadlift or a regular squat with it
doesn't have any of those bands at the
end you have more horsepower.
Exactly.
Huh.
So you don't do any regular squats or
any regular deadlifts and you think that
that helps you out.
That preserves athletes as well.
Greatest.
Squatters your greatest male female
pilot.
We had a number one,
number two,
greatest quality of all time and I've
got a one 65 I think have become.
He's going to be the great squatter bolt
on or thinking about 950,
five pounds of one 69,
955 pounds at 165.
That's insane.
Dot eight nine.
He did that easy.
That's incredible.
And keep him out of jail.
Oh,
it was crazy.
And a little bit.
How weird.
Wow.
Let's just say he's.
We'll just say straight down.
Yeah.
Well,
I would imagine.
I mean it's not the case with almost
everybody who's like at the very top
levels of anything.
Normally people only give you normal
results.
Whew.
That's a good quote.
That needs to be a meme as normal people
only give you normal results.
I don't need normal people.
Yeah.
That's an interesting way of looking at
it.
Well,
I mean that's what I was saying before
that you're kind of insulated because
you're in this world of savages,
you know,
in your attitude about things like,
this is not an attitude that most people
have in 2016.
Everybody's worried about everybody's
feelings.
Everybody's worried about being
sensitive.
You know that this is the time of toxic
masculinity.
People worried about masculinity.
Strange,
right?
Forgot like you.
Isn't it strange I'm going to do.
I think the world is screwed up and
you know,
I,
um,
had told Tom to buy all these books and
the straw man back in 1900 and they all
look like mma fighters today.
Men Don't look like at today like I did
back then.
No loan before roids.
They looked like gamers loaded to the
gills and there wasn't a road back.
He was probably,
food was better.
Maybe,
I don't know,
but they all had attitude and everybody
will kick your ass.
So I just,
I don't know that I can send to warrants
to soft man.
It's got to be hard.
You can have an easy life because once
things get hard,
you're screwed.
I see that in my sport.
I watched guys will accelerate them so
fast and it gets hard to quit.
We like in a fight.
I'm done.
I just quit tap.
I am,
I'm Outta here.
You know,
punch me in the face.
Well done.
I'm done with.
That drives me insane because work
hundreds of hours to get these guys
super,
super strong and then they quit,
but doesn't that make you appreciate a
guy like a matte brown or someone like
who is like a legitimate check from that
I respect for all finders.
I mean,
you know,
any fire.
Okay.
What level?
But they get into UFC cage.
I got loud,
respectful,
but in 2016 does have rare type of
person.
Right?
In this ever softening world,
don't you think that's why MMA is so
popular?
Because everybody wants to be that,
but they don't want to go through that
work.
It's also the recognize how unique it
is.
They recognize.
I mean there's a lot of people that I'm
friends with like MMA that they don't
have those qualities themselves,
so they appreciate them and other
people.
That's exactly what I'm saying.
Yeah.
I've always admired fight.
I'm a huge boxing fan,
like triple g and guys like that.
Me Too.
You know?
So Roman Gonzales' classical boxers,
man,
I'd like to classic because uh,
you know,
you go try to do it.
It's not easy to do at no works insane.
Oh yeah,
and everybody thinks it's a brutal.
Even boxing.
I was a brutal sport and they think in
the maze.
I don't want to think that,
but there's a lot of so much technique.
There's more technique than anyone would
ever really imagined.
Ridiculous.
You know another thing that fighters are
getting into a lot lately as yoga.
That's a.
that's a big one.
Did you ever mess with that?
But.
No,
I haven't,
but I probably should.
I know Matt was doing yoga,
right?
Hot Yoga.
We got to subtract girls to do the hot
yoga.
They say it's really,
really good.
Well,
it's a great thing for your back.
That's one of the reasons why I brought
it up.
It's amazing for like lengthening your
spine.
There's certain decompression exercises
that you do in Yoga where you.
You grabbed the bottom of your heels
from underneath and you're pulling and
straighten your legs out.
You literally feel your back on like
pop,
pop.
Like I do it all the time and I can feel
my back,
especially in the middle.
I feel it's separating and it makes it a
little pop,
almost like you're getting adjusted by a
chiropractor.
Is that something that you would
recommend to your athletes?
Is that something you might think about?
If it's not an advantage,
a disadvantage,
anything of a person I want them to do
now.
What about,
uh,
other kinds of therapy,
like a cold therapy,
ice bass,
cryotherapy,
things like that.
Prolotherapy,
stem cell,
platelet injections.
If you could think of it.
I've done it.
I wouldn't even get it.
I don't want your cat and your readers
to hear everything I've done because
they would probably have me locked in.
Like what have you done that would have
you locked up?
I've used our stint and strict nine
injections.
What?
Strychnine arsenic.
Strychnine or arsenic and strychnine.
Right.
Why would they inject you with poison?
Because it raises your red
blood cell count.
I've used nitroglycerin.
Nitroglycerin cream because you know,
in a stimulating blood flow and me start
your heart up.
Right?
And I use it because I broke my back and
I didn't want to admit I broke my back a
second time.
So I use it,
I told my friend who was a professor at
Ohio state that says,
don't go nowhere.
Well,
we'll see what his does.
I mean,
I was raised and being for three hours,
it felt like you were hit me in the head
every,
every heartbeat just hit me in a temple.
And um,
so,
but I've done it all.
There's nothing I haven't tried.
I did electric statement,
I think it was called a microwave.
It lengthens out the muscles.
I'm Tom did it for what?
Fifteen seconds?
I did for 96 minutes.
What does it do?
It lengthens out the muscles literally
straighten out your leg right off the
ground is electrocuting you.
And uh,
for six minute segments.
And I did 96 minutes.
So it's electrical muscular stimulation.
It lengthens it.
Yes.
And I should never done it because I
think I've got too many injuries,
you know,
and it basically tore.
It popped my,
uh,
my hips and my shoulders out,
his uncle.
What if my hip don't?
Six hour right here,
my hipbone crazy here.
Your whole body's like a walking medical
encyclopedia.
You know when you got to try it right
now,
I guess road warrior say desperate men
do desperate things now.
I'm very desperate.
Hold from what's.
What's worked the best for you?
Did stem cells work out well for you?
While I'm finding out because what has
been about three weeks against stem cell
in both hips and my knee and my
shoulder.
And what's wrong with your hips?
Oh,
there's some squatting ride.
Just beating the crap out of myself.
It was all torn out.
I'm shorten real wide.
So all your parents are here for
fighting,
so it's just all wear and tear.
And do you feel any different?
So I think it's starting to work.
See,
I wasn't allowed to take anti
inflammatories.
I've been on an antiinflammatory.
Nike's 1991 because uh,
I didn't really die.
See when I tore my knee off,
I'm allergic to anesthesia so I went
back in the beginning is fine.
Yeah.
So I went back in and gave me a shot to
sort of calm me down for surgery,
to take the wires out of my knees,
out of my knee and it put me to sleep.
He gave me on stages and they're getting
trached why?
Like I'm jumping around.
There's ticket chest tubes in me.
And that really,
that's how I got the rest of that.
They several,
my intercostal nerves,
they severed your intercostal nerve had
at lh,
five to five or six doctors telling me
that's exactly what they did.
Only a chest tubes in me.
So at that point,
91.
Um,
and,
and I'm going to tell you about my gym
and this is why the trade partners I
had,
I did step in 50.
No one's ever done.
And this is how,
because I was in intensive care for
about four days and I was in house with
three more days and I got a,
I didn't need a trake I could talk
because I trained a.
So they take my throat shut.
He got ahold of this big.
I got stitches in my side.
They take me out of the hospital to the
gym as well.
Tuesday.
But then suddenly I go to the gym and I
go,
I'll walk on crutches.
He got money,
you know,
they find out and is you're maxing out,
motherfucker,
and I says,
what?
They laid me down,
I've been street 55.
Who are they?
Who's their trading partners?
They're out of their fucking minds.
Exactly.
They tried to kill me,
tried to kill him,
and that's what you got to have.
You've got to have people like that.
They drove me to the point that when
they told me that if I,
if they told me they kicked me,
I'm old jump.
I didn't do it.
Just tell me male the man.
That's just so ridiculous.
What a training.
That is so ridiculous.
Well,
I understand your attitude now.
You know,
if you don't have an attitude,
you don't have anything.
I've had some great results with stem
cells.
Stem cells are probably going to help
you quite a bit.
You ever neck?
No.
Oh,
okay.
I just had it in my shoulder.
I had it in my knee and my hip.
But uh,
the big one was my shoulder man,
my shoulder,
my hip.
Was this a minor soreness and I was
saying like do it preventative.
And it definitely had an impact on it.
My knee highs have an on and off pain
for years.
And my knee completely cured that up in
my shoulder.
It healed it like nothing I've ever done
in my life.
Wow.
Yeah.
Well I got for the break of needing
shoulder surgery to no pain at all.
Well this shoulder it gives out of place
every freaking day.
And they got to put my.
I separated my shoulder and say I got a
big guy,
puts it in everyday.
So I'm hoping every day I could be put
in everyday.
What pops it out.
Just strange.
I mean just strained the ligaments,
tendons,
I think over the years.
So it's not even anything you're doing
physically,
like not,
not even lifting weights.
It constant wear and tear,
you know,
I mean it's just like playing pro
football,
you know what I mean?
But I'd done this for all those years.
I mean,
you know,
I mean I was in,
I was a nightmare record in 1971.
Wow.
And then um,
so then,
uh,
2000,
three or four,
whatever the eye and where it was,
2000,
five percent,
top 10.
Wow.
So do you do any exercise at all?
Now?
Trained this smaller crap.
But when he goes to bed,
I'd like to walk on tires.
I do belt squads.
I had to quit because my knee was so
bad,
but I want to get back where I can
deadlift.
I love the deadlift,
the deadlift.
You don't just kick your ass.
I mean if you can live you can still
fight if someone attacks me.
Right,
right,
right.
Which is quite possible because the way
you talk in his podcasts,
get any a woman's ass eddie.
Wow.
That's amazing.
Strong words.
So like what,
like when you lift weights today,
like you,
you lift in Max,
are you maxing out or just getting some
exercise?
Because I been squatting and dead lift,
just,
you know,
top dog squad right on,
in my,
almost my first meet.
I mean when the neck,
if you're going to pass out,
you just have to,
you know,
comes a time.
You just got stuff.
Now when you're talking about doing the
reverse hyper with that neck,
a neck harness on,
does that help you?
We actually do a bunch more supreme,
a severe thing.
We do neck,
neck deadlifts,
out of my belt squat machine with a neck
harness.
What's a neck deadlift?
So you put up a net carbs on his machine
and he squad over.
You just stand up.
Oh,
so you're doing your deadlifts and just
with your neck,
how much weight are you doing that with
a on that machine where the machine
weights?
I've done about 40 pounds.
Looks at the whole lot.
Yeah,
40 pounds a lot to be hanging off of
your neck.
Yeah.
Plus that.
Plus the cage.
One hundred 95 pounds.
Ninety five pounds.
Are you still doing that?
Yeah,
it seems to make me feel better.
It makes you feel better.
It makes your neck feel better.
Yeah.
That's interesting because that would be
like counterintuitive.
A lot of people would think that a lot
of people think you shouldn't lift any
weights with your name,
your neck.
Like I talked to Kelly,
started about it,
you know that eight way neck machine,
you know that thing he says,
don't ever do that.
It's bad for your neck.
And then I've talked to other people who
are athletes who were fighters,
so it's one of the best things you could
do for your neck.
You got to in the NFL,
the problem,
they don't train their nickname or mira
big.
Everybody's neck was Russell.
He was real big.
What do you play?
Football.
You don't see that anymore.
It they neck is a the two most bomber of
a piece of jewelry back in your neck.
No one trains them because they're
afraid to write.
Well there.
That's what I keep hearing that it's bad
for your neck to lift weights with it,
which seems so weird because it's not
bad for your lower back to do dead
lifts.
It's not bad for your lower back to do
like reverse hypers or Roman chair
setups,
ups or anything like that.
And I think a guy called Paul and strong
assumed never lived way back in the
fifties,
but he thought the neck was,
was the most neglected muscles.
And it shouldn't be the most used muscle
cars.
What happens to us,
we have bad necks because if you don't
do anything,
we'll get bad neck.
So do you think it's,
it's a real issue with grapplers,
like grapplers almost always get served
cervical herniations.
Do you think that a lot of that could be
prevented if you just strengthened up
your neck?
Yeah.
Well,
you know my print John Sader,
I mean to this day,
67,
he gets out and does neck bridges for
five minutes and does $500 dollars
qualities in 6,500 Hindus squats in a
row at time.
That's insane.
He,
that's what he does,
that he gets out of bed.
He does it every day,
five minutes at neck bridge and $500
course.
That's amazing that I could do them in a
row and I could do $200.
No,
my fucking legs turned a rubber.
I've got to step up my game.
500.
Wow.
And how old is he?
I'd say 62 years.
Sixty three busy on the shit.
I don't know.
You don't know?
You don't ask him.
Don't talk to older guys.
Talk to about other bds to coach for
seven years.
Oh,
okay.
That's.
Well that's a big one for grappling a
lot.
A lot of old school grad course in
particular.
Love the Hindus Quans.
But that's amazing that they can still
do neck bridges and everything like
that.
And he's at that age.
I mean he's a black belt in judo,
Samo Jujitsu,
black belt in Japanese.
More time.
He still trains.
He trains all the time.
Wow,
that's amazing.
He just had some miniature.
He's but he's back now,
but I think he can roll around a little
bit.
So.
Wow.
Hip Surgeries and a replacement or
whatever.
That's another real common one.
Mark Coleman's got a hip replaced.
Two.
So common,
a hip replacement.
Um,
everything else lasted.
Hm.
That's interesting.
Way Pass everybody.
Well,
what they're hoping now is that through
the use of stem cells that your body's
going to be able to regenerate tissue
and a lot of areas where it couldn't
before and that's going to prevent a lot
of replacements and a lot of surgeries
and a lot of things.
They think that sometime in the future
that stem cell based therapies are going
to eliminate a giant percentage of
surgeries that people have.
That's why I didn't know.
I hope so too.
I'm curious is if anybody's a canary in
the coal mine to you will find that only
time I get.
Well I want to live.
I want,
I want deadly.
I'm going to beat.
And so you just want to deadlift till
you drop.
Yeah,
that's what I do.
I don't know.
Anything else?
Well,
is there anything else you want to say
to all the people listening out here
and.
No,
just no,
just good luck and don't be afraid to
try,
you know,
keep trying and never give up.
People give up man and give up and no
one should give up.
Well listen man,
you are a very unique character and I
really appreciate you taking the time to
sit down with me and do this and uh,
I been wanting to talk to you for a long
time and thank you so much for making
that machine because that machine has
helped me so much.
It built so much strength in my lower
back and gave me so much relief from a
lower back issues that I had.
I have one in my studio before I do the
podcast will tell you I do that fucking
thing all the time.
And anybody who's got a lower back
problem,
I go,
come on,
come on back and I show them it and I'm
like this thing,
get it.
Put it in your garage.
You need one of these.
Yep.
Great.
Well Matt,
I really appreciate you coming here.
Really appreciate it.
Thank you very much.
Thank you sir.
So,
uh,
we're gonna take out,
check out your gym,
go for a little tour of the gym,
will make a little video of that.
And uh,
thanks man.