Okay,
sorry,
sorry.
Just a lot of people have to communicate
with.
You already started.
Joe,
here we go.
You'd already,
but did you really go?
Hold on.
Here we go.
This is how slow type you dirty bitches
and you know what I type so bad is
because I don't want to admit that I
need glasses.
I need reading glasses.
I've old man eyes.
No http and people say Joe,
do you write all that crazy lines before
the actual.
Yeah,
to do them all myself.
I'm like a pro sneakers.
Oh my God.
Sneakers reference.
That's great.
How did you bust that out for me?
You do have a lot going for you.
We're going to get to that reference
wise.
Do you have any flashlights at your
house?
Amy?
Dude,
this is the commercial he's.
He's easing into it.
Have zero flashlights.
Are you guys promoting flashlights or
flashlights?
Oh,
that's nice.
Well,
it's one of our sponsors.
Very embarrassing situation.
Yeah,
that's a totally different group ever.
Craving of pocket pussy like a.
well,
the tug and pull method and the
flashlight where you put you take the
actual flashlight out of it and it's
like this big fleshy thing and you tuck
it inside of you and then you pull it
out slowly and it feels really good.
It's kind of like anal beads for your
vagina and it's the second use of the
fleshlight,
but you want to make sure you don't take
the whole thing in there because it
could probably get stuck telling me
less.
Fascinating.
Tell me amy schumer
being silly.
Goose.
We have two commercials.
This what we do.
One of them was for the flashlight.
That really is a sponsor for our
podcast.
We have one here.
I'd like to know.
I'm sorry.
I would have brought you one if I
thought you were curious.
There was a gift bags.
Should I should start hooking that up?
Right,
right.
I had a boyfriend and she'd get together
if like I'd be into him getting that and
I was like,
I don't see how that would benefit me at
all.
Oh,
why would you?
Maybe.
So you could watch them.
Fuck something else.
So
crazy.
I was like,
I'm cool.
You could do it.
Maybe he can just fuck that thing and
you spit on him.
Maybe that's what he's looking for.
That's what he wanted.
Yeah.
He going to make more time for us or
what's that phrase?
While he's doing it like that kind of a
dude,
but I will never know minded that you
never know.
I tried to find out.
Anyway,
if you go to Joe Rogan.net,
click on the link for the fleshlight,
entering the code name Brogan.
You will get 15 percent off the number
one sex toy for men and our sponsor
forever.
From the beginning of the podcast when
we were scrubs,
when we like,
if this is like we've come so far,
but we have a room.
We have an actual space now with
cameras,
but from the beginning of the podcast,
these guys were with us when nobody was
watching,
reading,
listening,
whatever.
So they remain.
They remain.
Our pumps are our sponsor.
They're cool and it's a good product.
It sounds embarrassing.
Yeah,
it's a good product.
I don't love it.
I like it.
It's a good inanimate object,
but I don't feel love for it.
Don't be creepy.
I wish you were twilight zone.
I feel like it's possible.
I those real dolls know.
Have you seen those where they have
communities of real dolls dudes like get
their real
dolls together and hey man,
my girl a girl though.
She didn't know that happened but
I made fun of it on my website once and
I'm in a blog and then some guy emailed
me his reality and as to why he has the.
Oh yeah,
it was really sad or the best.
Well it could've been,
it could've been troll.
Could have been in trouble,
but it didn't seem like it was.
He was one of the guys that was in the
community that was a.
I was making fun of him because they had
all the dolls and their dressing them
and shit and I'm like,
Hey,
what the fuck are you.
You guys are crazy.
And they were,
well then a lot of these guys are either
disfigured or something really wrong
with them and so it is very sad.
It's a fucking what I should.
He rolled the dice with fucking a
disfigured guy.
Some something like one little thing
fucked up,
but what if he had a lot of things like
that.
He can't be like all out,
like he's to be like one charming,
like a weird board or something
somewhere.
Do something extra.
I think it has to be something missing.
A limb is gone that way.
Like everyone thinks I'm so nice and,
and I'll be kind of like grossed out
while we're fucking but up.
But like get into it.
I think.
Hm.
Would the gross style part the benefit
you?
I like that.
I like watching porn like that.
Like where I'm like,
would this make me puke?
Like what I throw up on this dude.
So I now,
this is how I'm finding my target demo.
I just like,
if you're disfigured,
you want to make me puke?
Yeah.
Come on down to the funny bone,
blah,
blah.
Amy Schumer,
you crazy.
We're still doing commercials.
Blue tonight doesn't seem like it,
right?
Yeah.
The cameras or anything of the flow.
That's the beautiful thing of the flow
of this show.
We're also sponsored by [inaudible] Dot
Com,
o n n I t,
makers of Alpha brain,
the cognitive enhancement supplement
that I show you right here.
Vitamins for your dome.
She saw you take pills.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
You take them for real.
Yeah.
It gives you like,
it's not like as a prominent is like say
adderall or something like that,
but it would,
it would,
it does,
is it enhances the way your brain
functions.
Anybody's interested in at Google,
the Google,
the word nootropics.
That's the best way to get information
on it and try a bunch of different stuff
out before you ever even think about
buying Alpha brain research.
Nootropics getting,
get involved in looking at what it is.
It's,
there's a bunch of studies about it,
you know,
a lot of them were done on people with
Alzheimer's.
Um,
you know,
people whose brains weren't functioning
until Wednesday morning and it helped
them.
Various companies have a nootropic
formulas.
Don't necessarily go out and buy Alpha
brain,
but I'm telling you that we use it and
then it's awesome.
I like it.
And if you don't like it,
you order it and it doesn't work for
you,
you don't even have to return it.
You get 100 percent money back
guarantee.
We try to make it as easy as possible
for your first order.
Can I have more than that?
Because some people stole
it or something.
Dragons came.
Brian,
what was the story again?
How did it go?
It dragon's cave.
It was a troll who came over the
mountain with a battleaxe and came into
town and took all the Algebra and then
put it on Ebay or something.
No,
no,
Joe.
You took my Alpha brain the other day.
And so I noticed I didn't tell anybody.
He just gives it to me.
Any launders sells on Ebay.
It's been him the whole time.
Uh,
yeah man.
That's my new theory.
I'm make like three bucks every time.
It's an awesome deal.
Anyway,
we also have a bunch of different cool
supplements that are available.
All of them that I find to be effective.
If I didn't think they were effective,
I wouldn't promote them.
One hundred percent.
That's the truth.
Get into it,
check it out.
If you want to try alpha brain,
go to Joe Rogan.net,
click on the Alpha brain link and during
the code name Brogan,
and you get 10 percent off all orders,
not just the first one is money orders
in the future.
All right,
benches,
Amy Schumer's start the music now.
The podcast officially begins.
Joe Rogan podcast all day does a very
mild version of the song.
They're like,
you weren't trying to hurt amy Schumer's
protecting,
protecting.
I think that was.
I think that's exactly what he's doing
because you find her cube.
I didn't want to start over.
You love her.
You love her already.
Looking at you already adjusting your
behavior back.
That's some serious respect is usually a
blows your fucking eardrums out.
Silly and it's needed and then he gets
silly with the fade out,
you know,
because he fades it out the entire wall.
Wall Wall Wall.
Go on for like minutes,
but not with you.
He's trying to be like really
unobtrusive and really sweet and
collages of pictures together.
You're making him the best.
You making them the best.
Brian,
he can be a job for real.
If it wasn't for you here,
I think you're making Brian the best.
Brian,
he can possibly a better version of you,
for real.
Bring out the best in you.
Don't run away from this trend to troll.
Marry Yo.
I'm not trying to troll you.
Women don't do that.
That's one of the things that he's
playing a practical joke on me right
now.
Guys.
This is going to sound totally
ridiculous,
but you know how guys will sometimes get
divorced and the woman will get half a
guy shit and then people will say,
Oh man,
that's fucked up that she never told a
joke or she never,
you know,
made one point.
You know,
how the fuck did she get half his money?
But the combination of people sometimes
sometimes a woman will come into your
life and she's such a bad ass bitch and
you want to impress her so much.
You will be a better person.
Well,
I think the flip side of that is I think
what,
what chicks do not me know when you
start dating somebody,
like I'll just like,
I'm the.
I'm like super cool new girl.
Just sweep the crazy end of the rug for
a couple months.
I'm like,
you don't need to see this.
You don't need to meet my mom,
who I'm becoming.
And then,
uh,
you know,
the truth comes out eventually,
but I think you're like the best version
of yourself at first and then you can't
help.
But that's why I always tell the guys,
you should be the you who you're
pretending to be when you're trying to
get laid.
If you do that day,
that day,
that guy,
be that guy.
It is possible to be that guy.
It's fucking hard to decide and work on.
It might be the you that you pretend to
be when you're trying to get laid.
I think vitamin D or something,
you got to do squats,
deadlifts,
watch doesn't give you a kettle bells,
Sean,
big fucking heavy ones.
50 pounders,
70 pounders.
You've got to really work the spine and
the core,
all that is part of it.
You gotta keep your core engaged.
For sure.
My inner core.
So I think that Amy Schumer is like your
Muse,
is what I'm saying.
You know that she's hilarious.
You know that she's talented as fuck,
so when you're around her,
you've got like this guy,
crazy respect because you're also
physically attracted to her.
Like there's a lot going on here.
This is the best thing.
You feel the same way.
There's a lot going on here,
Brian.
This is.
It's not bad,
but I know that's true.
It is so ridiculous.
I know what I want to do.
I'll get you pictures of you in the
woods near my house where the outline
is.
Oh,
let's go out near the near my house
because there's been four mount line
sightings sightings.
The attacks are usually on dogs and a
lot of rabbits get fucked up and the
occasional deer,
if they catch a deer,
they'll basically fuck up anything.
So they try to avoid people as much as
possible,
so it's really weird that they've seen
for or at least one four times in the
course of it might be the same one.
Most likely you ever watched.
I survived and the mountain lion one's
really fucked me up.
Just like they scalp you,
they're horrific.
They're so dangerous.
You don't even have any idea of how
strong they are when you see one.
There was one when I was in Colorado,
they had a stuffed one like this.
They have this crazy,
a wildlife exhibit place where,
uh,
there,
there was this guy taking care of like
all these different tigers that were
from zoos and all.
So it was like a big,
huge area filled with big cats,
but they had a stuffed mountain lion and
it was like 200 pounds,
a hundred 50,
200 pounds.
But it's,
when you look at the dimensions,
that's what it freaks you out.
You see the width of its paws.
It's wrist is like twice the size of a
man's.
There are enormous risks.
And then you look at the bones of the
pause and you look at the fucking head,
all of it designed to fuck shit up.
Big Cat as big as a person.
This is essentially what it is.
It's a big man,
but it's a cat.
Two hundred pounds.
Fucking the one I saw and I survived.
The woman was trying to save.
Her husband had the and she was jamming
a pen into the mountain lions and it
wasn't even reacting.
It was just like,
what?
Jesus fucking Christ.
Yeah.
You'd have to break that thing.
Are you scared to be outside of your
house?
I pack heat.
You know what I do when I go outside.
Some of the Times I go outside to take a
leak just to put my mark around the
house.
That's not weird.
In my underwear with a gun in my
underwear.
Just tucked the gun in my underwear.
See I just pooping little coffee cans
inside my house and then they just put
them.
We should have more secrets for me to
start now.
It'll just be a job.
I don't really walk around.
I'm just fucking around,
but I did when I was hiking in Colorado.
I did always use to bring on just for
that very reason just for the mountain
lion reason.
Most likely it never happens,
but fuck.
If it does happen,
wouldn't it be nice to do it?
Shoot that count,
those posters that say like,
just make yourself bigger,
but you got to do something wild killer
is looking at you.
I'm going to throw my friend at the
mountain lion and I'll go get help or
playing dead me.
Just push the south park.
When the actors had to save the world
record,
it was just human shield.
Oh,
well,
mountain lions eating your asshole.
You remember that?
That thing we talked about a while back
where I said if you ever get attacked by
a lion,
I would take like a piece of paper and
try to throw it.
Like if it was a real cat and you were
like,
Oh,
you're stupid,
but somebody posted this amazing
documentary of this guy and you've
actually seen it before where he gets
really close to dig this.
These,
this line is male lion and this girl
lion and he's holding a toilet paper
roll and the whole time he's just
holding it like in his right hand and
then like at the cat starts coming up to
him.
He's just like,
like about the throat,
the toilet paper roll and the cat just
kind of like,
looks over to the right and like,
like just like jerking off the cat right
now.
Just kinda know.
But then at one point like he got really
close and the,
the,
the guy who was going to use that to
throw it in the opposite direction,
he said that that would be like his only
chance to survive.
It was that little toilet paper.
Oh my God.
If I could find the video,
I'll try to find out if anyone knows
what I'm talking about.
If I was to distract him with toilet.
But yeah.
Yeah.
I,
we have to watch this video.
I hope somebody tweets me because you'll
freak out.
Wow.
Because they've never seen anything like
it before.
It's because then their instincts and
their instincts are still a cat.
Like where live you throw anything out
of cat,
you know?
It will be like,
what the fuck's that?
We should kill all caps.
I love my cats and everything,
but I know the only reason why I love
them is because of the size difference.
You know,
I'm way bigger than him.
She wanted to fuck around.
If she wanted to fuck around and try to
kill me,
I could snap her neck.
Do you know what I'm saying?
Makes you love something.
Well,
no.
That's why she loves me.
I'm big enough,
but if the roles were reversed,
my cat would eat me.
Yeah,
for sure.
Should have cats.
I don't.
They're like abusive relationship is
totally.
When they need something they're like,
hey,
it's me.
And then when they're like,
fuck off.
You can't have a cat and a pet mouse.
You just can't have it.
Do you have.
Can't have it a pet mouse?
Yeah.
No,
I do have cats.
I have two cats.
What are their names?
You don't need to know.
I'm interested in personal,
creepy shit with my.
Here's that video.
Sure.
SPAZZ and Oliver not touching it.
Oh,
this is insane.
As he faces the kingdom,
just an ordinary.
Oh my God,
this guy's so that he's going to throw
it at his head.
It creates a diverse look at that thing.
None of them have guns either.
Let's look at this shit.
Look at the size of this thing.
I don't know what you're saying.
You're talking.
It gets intense.
Oh my God.
For the audio listeners is a bear versus
a line man.
Big Man with A.
Yeah.
You got some questionable life choices
when you've got a ponytail.
Anyway,
it is a bear verse.
Oh my God.
Look at the size of this thing.
It gets intense here for a second.
Jesus Christ.
It doesn't even need this creepy music
like it's just intense.
That is a big killer.
A big wild killer flips its tail around
sign that he was.
My potential danger remains both
threatening with that line or that dude.
I think I'll take my chances.
Oh my God,
this is terrifying.
Can you imagine that?
Look at the size of its arms.
Just look at that thing.
It's beautiful.
It's horrifying.
At the same time,
the idea of that thing,
looking at you,
my 600 pound fucking monster,
that just kills things every day in
Africa at Jesus fucking Christ.
The second line,
second line,
the back of,
Oh my God,
this guy's alone with the two of them.
This guy in Narnia beyond the limits.
Oh my God,
he is fucking up here.
This is where it gets fucked up.
Crazy,
right here.
Didn't seem scared.
Is he just that cool?
Stoned?
Yeah.
They put my bags and he's on meds.
Just dropped him in a field or a good
luck.
Here's a ball of paper.
Look at that thing like,
God,
this is like a fucking werewolf movie.
Oh my God.
This insane.
It's walking away.
Oh my God.
And then that is it.
I walked away.
Jesus Christ.
That's terrifying.
But yeah,
so my paper theory is totally legit.
Wow.
Brian read bids theory.
So if you're getting attacked by a
tiger,
get some paper,
crinkle in the ball and then it right
before it attacks you,
just like you're going to throw it.
It's um,
is it the big,
the emotion of it?
Like you're throwing something white and
they don't know what the fuck it is.
Fuck.
I think it's just a hack into the brain
of a cat or a feline that for some
whatever reason,
they they that crinkly noise that,
that ball,
that what's the in your hand type thing?
It doesn't know what it is,
so it's just spazzes out like,
what the fuck this.
So lucky cats are stupid as fuck.
I was so lucky.
Toilet paper distracts them.
Oh,
that was scary.
That was one of those things.
We need those shitty blurry youtube
style video who still absolutely
terrifying.
There's got to be an hd version of that.
Oh yeah man,
man.
Versus wild pride.
A male lion and it's off the road.
Is it the animal planet?
So it was like an animal planet DVD
that's available.
Yeah man.
Versus what it says,
man vs wild pride and I don't know if
that's reverses wild prod Jesus Christ.
I want to know that guys deal with that
dude who's taken.
Well,
you know,
he's another one of those dudes.
Those wild.
I'm going to get close to animal dudes
that have been popping up a lot lately.
We should really say rest in peace if he
is dead because he's probably as.
That looks like an old video and he's
doing that kind of shit.
He's probably not even alive anymore.
He was on his last leg
I think.
I guess Steve Irwin Sorta started that
all off,
you know,
because he was like real wild animals.
The crocodile hunter dude.
He would get like right up to him and
you know.
And what was the one with the black
bear?
What was that movie?
Oh,
grizzly man.
It was a brown bear was.
Yeah,
the brown bears are the big ones.
Have Black bears out that dangerous
black bears are.
They don't really attack people as much
or kill people as much.
It's the bigger bears and brown bears.
Yeah.
He was that dude who lives in Alaska and
they said that he was essentially death
by bear.
I mean he suicided himself.
He wanted to do that as suicide by bear.
He just stayed late,
you know,
that's supposed to be there.
The bears that are awake are super
dangerous because they can't kill
anything.
So you're not fat enough to hibernate,
you know?
And so they'll,
they'll eat anything.
They eat babies,
they were eating babies,
so he caught the meeting babies and uh,
he's still stuck around for a girl.
I always think about his girlfriend.
Yeah,
absolutely.
She died after she tried to help him.
Apparently the video is,
there was a cap over the camera,
but the audio is there of the whole
event and it's like six minutes long.
Yeah.
Because he only played like the very
beginning of that,
right?
No,
they didn't play any of the audio of the
attack.
The in the,
in the movie,
his ex wife or his ex girlfriend,
whatever it is,
is listening to it.
She's listening to the audio and she's
the one who decides at her and Werner
Herzog,
the,
the guy who's director,
they decided not to release it,
but it's a long audio too.
It's like,
bears don't kill you.
They just eat
and eventually you die.
It's a completely different deal than a
cat.
You're way better off getting killed by
cats.
Cats,
cats kill you.
Well,
they kill you.
The first thing I'm going to do is grab
a hold of your neck.
And they gonna kill you.
That's their instinct.
Harris just hold you and start eating.
Was there any proof that the wife of
that bear dude didn't have a penis,
right?
Those,
yes.
She was a real woman.
She was sad,
you know,
some,
some women get roped up with guys and
they can't find a man.
So they find some guys doesn't want to
believe that he's gay.
So he's living in the woods with bears
and shit.
He was crazy obviously getting,
you know,
I mean like as gay as you can get.
And I think,
you know,
for some dudes the,
the desire to stay in the closet is so
strong.
It leads to be so fucking crazy.
They're willing to go live with,
you know,
and he had this whole thing always
protecting.
I'm protecting these bears.
Does the forest department want to help
them now?
Does that.
Sheriff Department went to help them now
the wildlife you fuck you,
you motherfucker.
And he was like yelling and screaming at
the camera and point at them and then he
would
like,
like reconstitute himself,
clean himself up,
get back in and do it again.
And do another take on it.
He did it.
Dick
Probably.
I think that would have certainly helped
him.
I think he was eight and he had this
crazy thing where he was like walking,
holding the camera,
talking about if he was just gay,
if I was gay,
so I could just go to.
Yes.
Yeah,
I could do it.
You know,
you go to a rest stop.
But oh well not gay.
It's just,
it was the most obvious.
I'm gay,
like cry for help.
It was really sad.
It was sad because that's.
It's fucked up that it's fucked up to
dudes.
Get stuck in that closet situation,
man.
You know,
that's a terrible place to be.
To pretend your whole life to be one
thing when you really.
You could just say you another and
everybody will still love you.
You know?
It's like you don't have to like.
I know.
I know dudes that are in the closet
today.
Tommy Thompson.
Bird growing thought we weren't going to
talk about that on the air.
Dick,
dare you.
Oh,
we'll edit it.
I think we're doing it live on ustream
right now.
Fuckhead,
how dare you fucking.
Oh yeah,
they don't really fuck.
They just start to fuck and they come
prematurely all over each other.
They were actually becomes burden and
Tom Fucking,
they're so hot for each other in the
idea of them fucking.
It's so hot.
They never.
They never get it inside.
No.
They just come close to the.
They're trying to be less.
Hey,
just so that they could have gay sex.
There's so gay.
They can't even actually consummate.
No,
no.
They just,
they just,
they just start twitching and coming on
themselves.
Great to think about.
I'm like
picturing bird's family,
like what?
His family is totally down.
Don't worry anybody's cool.
The coolest burt's kid.
You got to know what the fuck is up.
This craziness in the world.
They're ready for anything.
It's probably best for him that they
running the house.
Could you imagine if he were in the
house?
You know,
it's crazy.
I could just picture those girls.
Making them dress up for a tea party.
Of course.
I'm sure he does.
All that stuff works.
You have to do all this stuff when you
have kids.
Bert Kreischer,
he's uh,
another one of those dudes that I think
the Internet is perfect for,
you know,
like people get to see the.
No,
when you get your hero,
like when he's on podcasts,
you know,
you get,
you get the total,
you know,
when he's not stuck on,
like if he's,
if he's doing let him or something,
he's always hilarious.
But he stuck to like seven minutes.
He can get to really know them.
The experience to Albert Christchurch
brands.
Amy Schumer,
how long have you been doing comedy?
Seven and a half years.
You,
uh,
you did that Charlie Sheen Bros.
And that's when I really,
uh,
that's when I found out about you.
I've heArd your name before.
People say you really funny.
I don't want to pull your head up.
I don't want to,
to go.
Uh,
you know,
guys always.
Every now and then someone will have
this conversation when you see like a
really funny check,
you know,
like,
oh,
there's another one.
So because you know how it is with
comedy,
you know,
there's lIke I'd say dudes,
it's hard enough to do comedy,
to be a dude,
but to be a woman just to,
to get over this societal boundary of
you being the one talking,
I think it's way more difficult for a
woman.
I think it's weighed more difficult for
men,
especially meatheads and insecure guys
to accept the fact that a woman's
onstage talking and then your subject
matter is obviously going to be more
not,
I wouldn't say more restrictive,
but it's more difficult for you to get
out certain things,
especially sexual stuff and you know,
and,
and certain things about judgments and,
and politics because people are
reluctant to take the opinion of a
woman.
A lot of people are,
it's way harder I think for a chIck to,
to make it and be a standup.
So when you see a bad motherfucker come
along like yourself,
you know,
I always get,
I'm always very impressed because um,
I know that it's harder for a woman to
do than a man.
And when I heard john and charlie sheen
row,
so I was like,
holy shit,
this chicken is fucking funny.
You had some really funny lines.
I was like,
oh shit.
You know,
I generally a like a lot of times
roasts.
I go,
oh,
okay.
You're just being mean.
You're being mean to each other.
And sometimes it's funny and sometimes
it's just,
whoa,
this is like some weird,
creepy
shit that guy's been storing about this
dude.
You know It's gross,
right?
The way you did it was awesome.
And the fucking exchange.
You've got him with Mike Tyson.
Can we play that?
We got to play that.
If we can,
if we could find it.
If brian could find it,
he'll put it up.
Because it was so funny.
Mike tyson was trying to go back and
forth with you and you just handled him.
You handled
Mike Tyson.
Mike tyson used to beat a boxer.
It was really fun.
It was like when I watched that,
that was like in retrospect,
I was like,
jesus,
that just happened.
Like I just like,
man,
he just manhandled Mike Tyson in a
verbal,
in the white girl bubble enough still to
be like,
he won't come over here like I'm going
to be a.
But it was like afterwards,
I was like,
holy shit,
you shouldn't assume that.
Take a joke.
I mean he's away calmer version of Mike
Tyson and he was back in his fighting
days,
but what?
But he's a scary guy.
Was still like,
yeah,
there were some uncomfortable moments
still where you like Pretend to be like
he was gonna hit someone and you're
like,
that's not funny to anybody,
but you will.
They'll laugh at it.
That's the problem.
If he has least fake punches at people,
people will laugh to out of uncomfort
and no one's going to be like a,
you know what michael,
that makes me uncomfortable crossing a
line mind.
But you know,
you used to be a professional fighter,
right?
I'd like to talk about my boundaries.
He's like,
yeah,
you just have to be like,
oh,
that was awesome.
I'm going to leave a couple minutes
early.
Let them grab your dick.
He grabbed my dick the whole night.
You gotta let them,
as long as he's not squeezing it,
squeezing it,
and then you might want to call them
nothing but now.
But uh,
that was like,
afterwards I was like,
I can't believe that just happened,
but he did a great job.
I think he did even better than what
they made it look like.
The wrIters are all kind of sweating if
he was going to be able to deliver.
But I thought he like nailed it.
Yeah.
Well,
what did you think that he was going to
be able to do?
You just thought,
well,
I,
I didn't know the writers who had been
working with him were kind of like,
oh,
we hope he was like the wild card.
Like he might just bug out,
like say be completely incoherent
because they had like a concept for him
that he was going to speak really
intelligently and spout poetry and you
know,
and uh,
but he did a great job.
Well,
he used,
that's what he mean.
He was like a weird sort of a,
a kind of almost like a ghetto
philosopher when he was a young guy
because he would like mess up words and
stuff,
but he would quote you all sorts of
crazy things like he was,
he's a scholar on boxing history,
you know,
and when he was a young guy,
he wasn't a,
an inarticulate guy,
you know,
I mean,
I don't know how much has changed,
but there's an inevitable decline in
your ability to function after getting
punched you in the head.
Yeah.
It's inevitable.
There's a certain amount,
you know,
certain amount you eat and no one wants
to admit that or accept that,
but then that is a fact.
To be totally honest,
I felt the only sort of remorse I felt
that night was,
was for him because it was like,
he's for sure brain damaged and it felt
like,
oh,
I think you fucking had to do what you
had to do,
girl with crocodiles and you poked in
the eyes and ran.
He didn't see me coming.
Yeah.
Did you have,
you found a brian?
they're all a bunch of fake ones.
Oh really?
Yeah,
like like it's just like,
like screenshots and.
Oh,
it been like copyright.
Some comedy central comedy central is.
Well,
why woUld you want to have a bunch of
people watch it and see how funny those
roasts are?
Yeah,
pull those clips down.
Fucking body spray or the site.
Is it because they want to sell more
dvds?
Is that what it is?
They want you to add stuff,
but they probably have a month somewhere
on their website,
deep under commercial,
so there's.
It's so archaic that we're thinking it's
so dumb.
They don't understand that.
Yeah.
The more people that would watch those
videos,
the more people would watch those
roasts.
It's that simple.
If 100 million people watched the video,
I'm like,
oh my god,
this is awesome.
And then another roast is coming on.
Boom,
they're gonna.
Want to watch it,
right?
It's this weird thinking that you don't
want it.
Anything good to be available for free
online.
You fucking silly assholes.
How much do you spend spend in
advertising?
They have fucking tied all of the
commercials,
all over sitcoms,
and yet they're not willing to let
things be free online.
Do you not undErstand?
That's the same thing and this one,
you don't have to pay for the crazy ass
holes right here.
Here is a clip.
Have a it,
so be sure.
Yeah.
Where are you?
Turn girls were just making out with
each other.
It was what?
What are you doing?
That is.
Hold on.
that's you having the other podcast
going on in the background.
That was sam tripoli's voice
that hurts everybody's feelings.
Her saying,
no,
this is every week.
It's impossible for him to not do this.
Brian,
just be where everything's wonky.
Every audio clip,
it's.
It's part of the charm of the show.
You to accept it.
It's perfect in its imperfection.
They are nice dress sweet lady.
One of the waitresses of the seller made
that really?
Oh wow.
That's cool.
She's a
no,
I'm asking.
I couldn't understand a fucking word.
He said your voice sounds like a girl
crying.
Every time you speak.
Do you give yourself an erection?
hey mike,
here's something you'll never hear.
Great tattoo.
Oh shit.
You have a lower back tattoo on your
face then don't know whether to be
scared of it or finish on it.
Look at that face.
It's so.
It's so dark and wrinkly and constantly
getting pounded.
It's like patrice,
his grandmother's asshole after a gospel
brunch.
I'm just assuming she raised you.
Does that make you feel bad knowledge
producers dead?
No.
He was proud of me.
He was my.
He was my good friend.
I love patrice and I wanted larry.
I wanted him to think I did a good job
and I know he did.
We hung out a like at the after party
and was like,
he was proud of me,
you know,
you did a good job.
the trees.
So you know,
like it doesn't matter what,
do whatever.
Patrice,
when I heard he was going to be on the
day,
so I was like,
oh shit.
That kicked me into the next gear.
I was like,
that's cool.
Oh I,
yeah,
he's one of my favorite comics.
I was like,
shit,
I can't phone in even a second.
He'll be like,
he'll call bullshit.
He'll call bullshit on everything and
anything.
Yeah,
it was fun.
It was fun.
Yeah.
It's just.
But no,
I didn't feel bad about anything but
that,
uh,
that fucking launched.
You write that comedy central thing as
far as airports and I got a corporate
gig,
like,
you know,
it must be,
you must be getting a lot more standard
work now.
Now I'm getting more on the road.
I'd probably make a like maybe twice
what I was making on the road before,
but I think that's great.
Yeah,
totally,
totally.
Look at that one video.
Isn't it amazing?
It still doesn't seem worth it.
No.
I mean good.
But just being on the road like I'm
like,
it.
No.
Oh,
you know what you gotta do what you
bring your friends.
You.
That's what I'm doing now.
I bring a ari shaffir or joey diaz are
terrible.
Hey,
I love it.
Yeah.
No,
it makes such a difference.
It's a night and day.
It goes from being a chore to being a
great fun.
But what I also realized,
I've always stayed in the shittiest
hotels,
you know,
but now now seeing a nice hotel,
the road is a whole different
experience.
It was like he didn't want to touch the
sheets and paired with some assholes
that they'll be headlining comedy.
Kind of just say no to condos.
Like that's the only time I use that.
I'm a girl on the road.
I'm like hotel rooms.
I had,
I've seen comedy condos.
It not,
not hotel rooms,
but in comedy condos where they don't
have doors on the rooms with dudes.
Yeah.
Like I've,
I've put in my time on the road.
It a dark days.
Yeah.
Comedy store.
No,
that's the darkest condo in the earth.
Oh,
I've heard of condo.
More uncomfortable post-coital moments
have occurred.
Tablet where you walk in,
you feel the uncomfort of,
of roads,
stank road hacks and whatever.
Poor,
lonely fuck allows those road hacks to
stick their dick inside of them.
And crabs,
ness.
Oh god.
I can say never again.
No comedy condos.
That's my friend.
I bring my friend with me now.
The next one is phoenix.
Phoenix was a dark line to the tempe,
tempe improv.
That was joey diaz.
His haunt back in the dark days of joey
diaz.
He would pull the fucking Shades closed.
You wouldn't even hear him.
You couldn't call him.
He wouldn't answer his pager.
There was nothing going on with joey
diaz for hours come out to do this show.
Look like a vampire look alike.
bela lugosi.
Yeah,
I've been furious.
I,
I've been in condos where the,
I heard the feature at getting fucked
and I was laying there.
They were getting fucked.
I was like trying to save you.
You heard him reading some hurt,
hurting,
getting fucked while you were getting a
guy or a girl.
Guy.
Girl.
Guy was the feature.
Was fucking like a girl.
one of the waitresses to be specific
where they allowed all the things that
were they allowed.
I was like,
yeah,
I,
I gave them my blessings.
Enjoy you guys.
Go for it.
Did you guys like my new opener?
Oh,
nevermind.
Yeah,
it was awful.
And then,
um,
it was,
it loud was,
it was loud.
I felt like it was his way of saying
like,
I'm the headliner.
That's hilarious.
You felt like that?
I did.
I mean that could have been winter.
So funny,
like even just a guy getting laid will
be like a message.
I felt like he was sending me a message
trying to get laid.
That is the.
Why would you assume that the thing that
men want more than anything else in life
is to get laid.
Why would you assume that him getting
laid would be anything other than maybe
getting laid little
comics?
Egos are bigger than their cox for sure.
For sure.
I think it would be more like waitress.
No one under any circumstances would
have wanted to bang this girl.
Oh.
I think it would be more like,
hey,
I'm being loud because I want you to
know that if you want to join us,
you can be a little of that.
Second of all you.
You say that,
but the guy was fucking guy and I'm sure
he wasn't the first seeing even though
she was not a virgin.
Yeah.
Even though like you would say girls
like not really pretty.
Just willing for a lot of guys better
than masturbation were pathetic,
pathetic creatures.
I don't know.
Oh yeah.
You don't understand what it's like to
have a dIck.
I don't know.
I talked to um,
talked to chaz bono because she's
starting to make sense now during
shooting up the testosterone.
She's totally making sense these days.
Yes.
She can like really talk about that shit
now.
What's fascinating because she really
has gone from both extremes where he.
No,
no.
I mean talking about like,
what's,
what's annoying and,
and then the sexual urges that come on
because of testosterone.
Men go blank.
They get sad.
They don't get to know what's going on,
but I don't know,
like I've dated guys and I've been the
one in a couple of relationships where I
was always initiating sex.
Oh no,
I feel like it's a super charged on my
own.
Yeah.
I don't have a dick,
so I'm not like,
it's not brushing up against stuff by
accident.
I'm getting excited,
but uh,
but I don't know.
Uh,
I dunno.
I feel driven by sex.
Do you think you're driven by success?
Like to get sex?
No.
No,
no,
I'm not driven by success.
I feel like sexually driven like a lot
of the time.
Right.
What I was saying is that if a guy like
is,
is getting laid,
most likely that's just getting laid
like comes razor you would,
but you would think that they were
trying to send a message to you.
I'm the headliner
loud.
He was like very.
Everything he did that weekend was
really annoying.
Like he was trying to,
he would like take his coffee on stage
and do a lot of crowd work and just.
And then you'd be like,
stick around,
you're going to enjoy amy.
Like it was like so annoying
that.
I don't know.
I thought that was an extension of those
things.
Doing a lot of crowd work.
Like when you're not a headliner.
Oh,
I'm sorry.
I thought you said he was the headliner,
the headliner.
Oh,
I was confused because I thought you
were saying by him being loud,
it was his way of saying I'm the head.
no,
like he was saying like I should be
headlines.
Oh,
trying to alpha me.
Always total miscommunication.
Oh,
I would see that.
I could totally see how like middle
acts,
whatever.
Yeah,
yeah.
No,
I was,
I was headlining and he was all weekend
trying to assert himself like in the
green room.
Changing shit.
Please make sense.
I don't have the energy.
I'm just like,
you know,
you're just like trying to feel good and
be positive and whatever on the road.
And then
so he would like try to put on the tv
what he wanted to watch.
Like if you were watching.
Yeah,
he'd be like big base,
some baseball game.
I was just like,
oh,
oh really?
Yeah.
And I don't want to get into like a.
Yeah,
into an ego battle.
Yeah.
Drive fucking will
dude.
Something like working for women,
that's for sure.
Yeah.
And especially like ego saying
I try to be sensitive to that shit
though.
Know I just want to be treated like you
would treat.
But I,
I definitely get treated differently,
uh,
expectation wise on the road.
But like,
because I'm a girl,
they'll think there's some expectation,
like not necessarily that I'm going to
hook up with them,
but that I'm a girl so they'll come in
the green room.
Like this past weekend this guy was
talking to me like,
uh,
just letting me know like,
hi,
I'm from here and did it and I was like
[inaudible] [inaudible],
like why would you do that to intel?
Would you do,
would you come in the greenroom and
trying to like paint your picture and
give me your bio and
he's,
how is he doing this?
You say you feel like when a guy does
this,
he does this,
he doesn't like respect to would a male
comic,
like I would like to be treated like a
like you would treat the headlining
comic while I'm on the road.
Right.
But they treat me like a,
like a girl and,
and guys are confused like how they
usually are with chicks.
That's what,
how they treat me.
But I think I should be treated like I'm
the headliner that weekend,
just speaking to me like I'm working
with you rather than like throwing me
anything
and you're not even trying to like
dominate them.
You just don't try to dominate you.
You don't want them just getting weird.
Yeah.
I just want them to treat me like
normally and like they would treat any
comedian
because there's some comics who won't
even share a green room with,
wIth the,
the middle and the opening act.
Like they'll,
it might get to that point just because
of how much like bullshit.
We've had problems in the past with guys
that we didn't know when we did that
maximum comedy tour.
I remember we kicked that guy out in
boston.
There was just super douchey talking
shit about everybody while they're on
stage.
Talking shit about me got really,
really drunk.
He was just a creepy ass hole.
And he was uh,
you know,
we,
we did,
we had like,
I know I don't remember what town was it
in boston,
but it might not have been boston.
It seems like it would be.
It adds up.
It might not have been though,
I don't
remember because I don't remember the
guy's name,
but it was one of those things where
there was in each town,
they had a different opener.
A local guy would come up and most of
them were fucking really good.
Thompson was hilarious.
That's why I met tom.
He,
he,
uh,
opened up in phoenix.
Anyway,
this dude just got hammered and it was
just.
And I said to brian,
I think I said to you,
I said,
this is the last time I'm going to work
with somebody.
I don't know.
It's not worth it.
You should just bring some sorenson
friends too.
Um,
I'm not rolling like that.
We can be,
but it's like,
you know,
but you know,
you can work out deals with clubs,
especially with amy schumer.
You need a god damn podcast.
That's what you need.
Yeah,
you do.
That's what you need.
This is the number one promotional tool
for a standup comic because they're
really going to get to know you.
How else besides this kind of format,
how the fuck else is anybody get to
totally get to know you exactly.
Um,
I just want,
I think I just want people to get to
know me that I want to get to know me
really well.
What about your standup?
My standup is becoming more and more me,
but it's just sort of an amplified
version that whatever truth I want to
get out there.
So no,
you're.
I mean that's not true.
You're right.
Like I do want to shows and stuff.
Right.
You know,
just sort of to promote the comedy as
well,
right?
Yeah.
So,
but,
but in terms of people really knowing me
and like my personal shit.
No,
they don't have to know your porsche.
You reveal what you want to be.
I know what you're talking about.
Like I get what you're saying,
weird.
The national enquirer type shit,
like
personal life or if you're one of those
weird purple that offers up every little
single detail.
No,
I understand what you were saying.
Yeah.
That,
that would make sense.
I feel like really intimidated by the,
like all this technology should here and
like I don't even know how I would the
first step of starting to talk to that
guy to ever see brian again.
Are you living in New York city?
Yeah.
How often are you in la?
Uh,
almost never.
Oh really?
You need to move to la.
You got to move on here.
Check this out.
70 five degrees I live is whether space
your yard.
You don't want a yard and dogs and
puppies.
You know what if I like had a dude that
I loved and like we had a rabbit farm
and I'm here in blue by,
you know,
Olivia Newton,
john or linda ronstadt,
whatever.
Yeah.
I'm hearing in the background while
you're telling me that I don't know the
songs,
but uh,
that sounds good.
Linda ronstadt?
No,
I don't know.
Blue by you.
Beautiful song bro.
Yeah.
I just,
I would live here in linda ronstadt,
blue bayou for her because I want to
hear the story.
I want to hear your.
You're going to belittle my dreams right
now.
I'm not.
Just want a little background around
music to your dreams.
So cold blooded.
Do you have it,
brian?
Yeah.
Just hit it real quick and I want you to
tell me a horrible person who wants to
tell me what the right relationship
would be that would make you want to.
Don't fuck with man.
Stop
crying.
Please don't fuck with my dreams right
now.
look at.
This is a beautiful voice,
but it's a little sad since I left my
baby behind.
Oh,
I know this song.
It's so sad.
Very sad.
So tell me.
I just want a guy who listens.
There's a huge rod knows when to tell me
to shut the fuck up.
and when?
Tell me that my mom's account so far.
I'm like,
what you're saying?
Can you get that camera out of my face
or you fried?
Fuck.
Oh my god.
Wait,
I thought it was like blue bayou on.
Okay.
I thought you were saying blue by you.
Uh,
yeah.
I don't.
I don't want to do this anymore.
Yeah,
it's dark star.
What is the law?
Oh,
was the last time you ever stayed in los
angeles?
A couple months coming on your for a
couple of months,
like if I've,
I'm working on something.
But you find it is because your friends
are all back east or moved here.
Oh,
they did?
I don't have any friends in New York
really?
Well I have like two friends,
but that's.
What is it that you love so much about
New York?
I don't know.
Okay.
I think pose.
Is that what I sound like brian?
Really fucking that you might be the
worst impression that's ever walked the
face of the earth from wilson.
I'm the next bank kellyanne though.
Listen to my amy schumer.
It's fucking on point.
It's like hearing myself.
Um,
I,
uh,
so what is it?
Excuse me.
Brian.
Don't mock right.
Wonderful.
and talented guest just because she's
clearly too much for you to handle you
at the beginning of the show.
She was making you a better person.
You've gone through a full relationship
cycle and now you've become the bitter
guy at the end of every relationship
that mocks his girlfriend and she's
packing her shit.
I just don't get New York.
I'm sorry.
I just don't get all right.
I need that moment.
Seems like the scariest moment in a
relationship where you're packing up and
he's mocking you.
You know?
He's like saying like mocking shit
boxes,
would you?
Well this is happening right now.
This is that moment.
You've got a full relationship cycle.
And brian's like,
okay,
you're leaving.
Okay.
He's like,
yeah,
well I just have a fucking problem with
people like New York.
You know,
it's always the beginning in the first
match.
You if you were like stressful.
I really love New York.
it's pretty amazing times square.
How do you fuck with that?
Now he's like,
totally over me.
He's like,
fuck New York,
whatever.
You guys have gone through a full
relationship cycle.
brian kinda let the girl like New York,
bro.
I don't see why you're so creepy.
But yeah,
like I like it there,
you know,
because I feel like people in
la,
a lot of them are playing at an identity
a whereas people in New York,
like if there's like an old rich mean
jewish chick on the upper east side,
like that's really who she is.
Right?
People here like buy an outfit and
they're like,
this is who I like,
you know,
not everybody,
uh,
my best friends live out here.
Uh,
and they're not like that,
but
I don't really know what you're saying.
They'll do.
The vast majority of people that you
encounter,
the higher percentage of them are more
fucked up.
And I'm like,
yeah.
And I'm like angry going into any
restaurant.
Like everyone's looking around and
everybody.
It's just a totally different vibe.
I don't think it's all of the people.
It's just like,
look,
you know,
when I say about cops,
like most cops are cool as fuck I,
the,
the cops that I run into.
Most cops are good guys that are working
on really tough job,
but there's a certaIn percentage,
whatever it is,
one or two percent,
10 percent.
And will you make the number up where
they're just fucking cunts.
They're just constant.
But there would be concept.
They were construction workers.
They would be counted if they worked at
the grocery store.
They just shitty human beings.
So you think the percentage for la is.
Well,
it's because of the fact that this is a
magnet for people that want showbiz,
fame,
what it is.
I mean,
I can tell many people that come here
with a pr,
not a real dream,
but like,
well I wish,
you know,
and it's like they don't do anything
about it.
right.
But they came here initially to become
famous.
You,
you'll meet them at flower stores,
you'll meet them in this,
this women people
like I don't like those people.
And I,
and I,
I have like a weird,
um,
my,
like,
what I want from this stuff is I'm
confused by it because getting
recognized and all that stuff is not.
I haven't experienced it as being fun.
I like,
I've gotten upgraded.
Sometimes there's perks,
but I like anonymity in New York.
No one gives a shit if you are the most
famous person.
I feel like you can ride around the
subway and people generally leave you
alone.
I'm jew because nobody gives a shit
there.
I don't know,
I just like it more there.
So you think people give a shit?
They're less than they give a shit here.
That's what I do,
so that's what you want more people who
just don't give a shit about famous.
Yeah.
Or about seeing someone famous or.
And it's weird because it's like I want
to reach as many people as I can.
Like that's the goal,
but I don't like.
I'm like,
I don't like,
hey,
you're
right.
I see what you're saying,
but you're going to get that anywhere.
You're going to get that in New York
city.
You're going to get that anywhere.
It feels like he become.
I hear what you're saying.
Yeah.
Well if you,
if you've lived there for a long time
and the one thing that I definitely got
when I first came here,
I was going to totally move back to New
York after my first sitcom was canceled
because I didn't like the vibe out here
at all and I was.
It was my first time ever working with
actors ever in my whole life.
I did this really bad sitcom on fox
called hardball was written by these two
guys that were brilliant writers.
They work for the simpsons and married
with children,
but then fox got ahold of their sitcoms
just to stuck cox in phase shot sockets.
Fucked
his ears.
It just really,
it was like when the,
the,
the brilliant vision that they had Jeff
Martin and kevin curran where the guys,
the brilliant vision that they had,
it became like a,
just this thing that had been fucked to
death.
It was covered in combo,
like a glazed donut,
sodomized.
I always tell everybody this is because
no one can believe how bad it was.
These guys,
first of all,
the guys who originally wrote it,
we were really funny,
really funny guys.
And the pilot was funny.
It could have been funny.
It could have been a decent show,
but when they gave it to some guy who
used to work on,
um,
coach and he was like,
you know,
one of those.
And then I,
I know those fucking robot shows where
it's like you could just plug it into
your computer.
Yeah.
And it would be it real easy to make
that show.
And one of the lines was,
I was on a desk with this girl and I
like,
we're about to have sex,
and the,
the coach opens up the door and uh,
uh,
I go,
do you mind?
And he goes,
yes,
I mind,
that's,
that's my daughter.
You're attempting to,
that's my desk.
You're attempting to defile.
It's what he says.
And I say,
I'm not defiling the desk,
I'm defiling her.
That was actually a line.
And they were like,
approved.
That was like,
yes.
Done.
Moving onto the next line.
That was,
we actually said that with the cameras
on,
you know,
that's how bad the show had gotten.
It was,
it was death.
So I,
I was ready to pack up.
I fucked up and got a lease because I
thought this was going to go.
Yeah.
So I had a lease for a year and I still
had an apartment in New York,
but I was like,
what the fuck am I going to do now?
And I just like leave this spot on here.
And then I wound up doing another sitcom
afterwards,
but I was ready to go and it was my,
my thing was just dealing with actors.
It was just dealing with the.
Did they're delusional.
I really liked New York actors.
Well all of them though,
you know,
I mean I'm sure if you.
It's like my comps and everything else.
Most actors I think are fine,
but it might be like 30 percent of them
that you just fucking can't communicate.
But I've found that it was the same
essentially in new yorkers.
It wasn't a,
I just think,
well it's the,
they're,
they're hitting the hive.
The way girls dress for auditions is
different.
Like I always look like shit.
I looked like newly homeless.
I walk in the room they like are looking
at me like is she unit parked cars and
they're all like perfectly flawless.
A dress cool.
And I get to be like nonthreatening
girl.
They all talked to in the waiting room.
But in New York it's like I look like
the other girl,
they all talk to you and when everyone
asks me questions like,
do you know where the bathroom is?
I think they think I'm weird.
The level of like cap beauty up here is
very,
very hard.
Like when you go to nice places and you
see girls and they'll have perfect tows
and expensive shoes and expensive bags
or they look famous.
Glow.
Yeah.
Um,
yeah.
There's a lot of girls in la that are
hot as fuck that look like that.
Like that.
And that's one of the things,
the commodity of like,
you know,
if you're.
All you're selling is what you look
like.
Good.
Fucking luck.
Good luck out here because that's worth
a nickel.
And we age.
Yeah,
it's 10 years ready.
It hard.
You met her a year selling need that
guy.
That's why have you frozen your eggs
here?
Yeah,
my eggs are frozen.
All of them.
Not all of them.
You got to save a few for live rounds.
It's too late.
I'll follow them out.
Which is the idea is that in case you
know,
you wait too long and then your boxes
dry.
Yeah.
You know,
this way you'll have to move up your
eggs.
What's.
No,
there's no eggs left.
They all fall out,
fall out of your body.
You still got to suck them out early and
freeze.
Hold on,
let me write this down.
Do you guys,
did you know that you're productive and
nice from joe and brian?
Do you know the girl ethical terms?
Like suck out those eggs.
do you know girls out here?
I actually store their body fat also,
uh,
to be used later as physicians in their
face.
Yeah.
Like,
no,
don't do anything with your lips ever.
Yeah.
It's unfortunate that someone trick
girls into fucking with their lips the
same way they did with their tents
because the tents worked because guys
really don't care what a guy,
what a girl has faked it.
So even though we know that there's like
a bag of water under the skin that's
making them pop out like that was so
fucking stupid,
but any,
any movement and change the direction of
this shape better.
It's like a egyptian hieroglyph thing.
It's like for whatever it is,
it's the shape of the woman's body,
even though you know it's horseshit,
but that is out the door with the lips.
When it comes to the lips though,
we don't like that.
Well,
you can't apply the same principles to
tits as you can to lips.
And that's what they try to do.
They tried to make the lips crazy and
puffed up thinking I'm just going to go
with it the way they go with tits.
But they didn't.
They went,
whoa,
whoa.
This is lips.
You can't do lips the way you do tits.
Tits on crazy and outrageous.
And guys,
I eat what's up like that you're doing,
but you get all fish face on dudes and
they get creeped out.
There's something about the lips.
Yeah.
I saw a chicken the gym the other day.
She was blow drying her hair.
She was like,
not elderly,
but she's getting up there and she
clearly had implants and they were,
they had like the,
you know,
the ellis diversity of her skin wasn't
holding up,
so the implants that kind of fallen,
so her nipples were up top and it,
I was just,
I couldn't,
I couldn't stop looking.
I was just like.
And she was just blow drying her hair
like naked.
Oh,
maybe it was her way of warning.
Maybe girls would just like to take on
rugged lesbians and it's like a,
like a fad and the only way to find
them,
it's just going to let those rocks hang
out in the bathroom.
YeAh,
just a girl just looks like she's had a
hard life and she's,
you know,
that's like a guy just fetishize.
People are in a weird shit.
That's true.
Maybe there's some lesbians that are
only into running into girls that have
had hard lives and so like,
you know,
their tits are all fucked up scars and
shit and they look at you like what's
up?
And the next thing you know you're
eating,
you're eating box in the handicap stall.
Proceed.
No arms.
Okay.
No arms,
horrible implants like rock implants.
I don't know,
I wouldn't want anything fake on
anybody.
This is a weird thing that dogs not just
became accepted but fucking shot up.
But I've seen girls that have got them,
like they,
they,
um,
they had babies and then their boobies
got all dehydrated.
You know,
they became pancake boobies and then
they got their breast implants and they
felt better.
Yeah,
I mean,
whatever.
It's,
it's no,
that does make it look better.
I know.
It's stupid.
It doesn't seem like it should make
sense,
but it totally works.
It's a trick.
It's like the dumbest magic trick of all
time.
What's on my shirt?
I can't know what's under there.
It's a bag of water.
Yes.
But meanwhile I'm like,
ooh,
I like big cars.
Big real titties to a man.
Just that's the shape of it that is on a
mud flap,
you know,
gets our testicles to tingle.
It doesn't have to be actually real.
it's like a symbol.
It's so.
It's so iconic and the man's mind.
This is the man's mind.
This isn't just your mind like from
talking to people like guys.
By the way,
first of all,
there's no way I could know if it's an
everybody's,
but it sounds like you've talked to
other people about.
Well,
do I think that's why fake tits work?
That's.
That's why I mean that shape the
hourglass shape of a woman,
there's a reason why that is like an
iconic shape.
the hour glass shape.
Whereas for a man,
I mean women like guys with nice bodies,
but there there's no like shape that you
could put up that represents a man's
body to a woman.
I think every woman is really as a
different taste in men,
men's bodies,
but I think for dudes it's pretty
classic hourglass big tits shape.
That'S on the back.
waifs though.
Those guys are broken.
They're broken.
They have broken balls or one of them
doesn't work.
Right?
What if it was suicide?
I want to hear that.
Of course,
the chick that was his that's on sports
illustrated like I love her body.
Like kate upton.
Upton.
Kate upton is a hero on our message
board.
She's hot as fuck.
Whenever there's a thread on the message
board for one of our podcast,
if the podcast goes astray and the
subject of the podcast become something
that they're not interested in at all,
it didn't start posting kate upton
pictures.
It's all kate upton.
It's hilarious.
It's really funny.
So if like a guest like says something
stupid or they don't want to listen to
them anymore,
it just becomes a photo festival.
Fuck she is.
She's not.
She's got she's meat.
I don't like skinny girls.
I mean I like I'm.
We can be friends,
but I'm saying I'm.
I don't find that attractive.
Right.
Everybody's different.
Some chicks like black guys,
right?
Right.
A lot of black guys like fat white
girls,
right?
A lot.
A lot of white guys,
like chinese girls,
like everybody's allowed to.
You're allowed to look like your wife's
whatever you want.
I saw something today that reminded me
of one thing I definitely don't like,
and that's flat assets.
Man's flat man asks,
would you see what I think saw?
I saw somebody
stocking something at a store that I was
at and I just sat there and saw her,
but the lInens and things.
Wait a minute,
did you see someone who was on there
balcony who was naked?
Who paparazzi took photographs off?
No.
Okay.
Because at ariadne from the ufc,
paparazzi took photographs of her.
Yeah.
they were on her balcony and she was on
her balcony naked and they were like,
you know,
from a long way away wIth a high powered
lens and they took pictures of her naked
and put them all over the series.
Yeah.
What made you,
why?
How did that come up at it?
Some guys were saying that she had.
Oh,
her buttocks with less than impressive.
She's a beautiful girl,
but you know,
look,
guys have to realize there's a big
difference between what girls ask
normally looks like and a girl's ass
looks like when she's posing for photos,
when chicks are just walking around,
like dudes like naked.
They don't even know that people are
watching.
Harassing pucker their assets is fine.
This was actually imagine a 12 year old
boys asked,
who is this person,
this person that was,
uh,
a stocking something at the store.
Was that in her?
I just had to sit there and listen to
what you just said.
This person that was stocking something
at the store.
What do you,
what are you saying her?
I thought it was a young boy stocking
it.
That's how bad her as well.
So I sat there and just kept on staring
at.
There was no ass at all.
Like,
you know what you're talking about.
Just a woman.
Random woman's just like trying to bring
you your latte.
This chicken starbucks?
No,
he's talking about someone who's in the
audience and someone is buying something
at starbucks right now I'm talking about
employee stock.
Oh jesus.
Brian.
I've said it four times.
I know you said stop.
I thought you said stalking.
You knew what I meant.
I didn't know you meant stocking item.
I'm just like.
I'm like,
what Is he talking about?
The employee was stalking someone.
What the fuck?
And you're watching him stock them and
they have a flat ass went.
What kind of crazy conversation that was
listed,
it was like one of those
spanish things where you know,
you say the wrong word and they want to
shoot,
you know,
no brand.
No,
no,
but if you know what I'm saying,
you think you know the language.
Use the word correctly.
This led to one of those.
Those fucking.
Yeah,
that was bang castello first.
first.
This person has a small ass.
Yeah,
it was.
It was.
Not only was it flat,
it was like one of those indented
assets,
but it was so small at this chicken
that,
that right there.
I,
I don't know if I can date her because
to me it looks like a deformations.
Like I see her and I'm like,
this would hurt
me less if I haven't seen your ass,
but I've seen.
Yeah.
Oh my.
My ass is horrible.
Everyone's a critic.
No matter what asked is horrific.
Yeah.
there's no way he should be talking
about anybody's ass ever.
maybe that's why he's so upset because
he.
It's something that he sees himself,
sees me.
It's like A mirror.
It's like man in the mirror.
Michael jackson
it.
That is what it is by you.
Just.
We learned a lot about ourselves today.
I've been told by many of my ex
girlfriends here do our podcasts on a
permanent basis.
Please.
Yeah,
you should.
You can live in a studio.
we can make you famous for real.
You're a monster.
You're hilarious.
I'm going to move here.
You guys were throwing It out as a
hypothetical.
That's fine.
I'm not throwing it out as a
hypothetical.
Totally.
Sarah will have you on every week.
You got a couch,
you got a bathroom for number one,
so you can do through number two spots
at the ice house everyday.
I think you know what?
Every radio show that's ever existed,
they always try to stick a woman on the
show that goes,
oh,
we need to balance it out.
We're going to balance it out.
Men,
men resistant like opie and anthony,
call them holes like it's like a radio
host that.
Those guys were awesome.
They're right.
They're right,
but you are different.
You.
You actually would bring.
Oh,
funny female perspective to a podcast.
You should totally be doing one thing.
I know what you mean though.
It's like,
okay,
let's find the least unbearable girl.
I hope she knows when to not.
It's usually she's hot and you know
she's sassy.
You know she can hang with the guys and
we could call and we could call it your
step.
Mom's house.
Is that like an inside Joke?
his wife chris.
We have one called your mom's house.
Totally a joke.
He just include me in all jokes from now
on.
I'm moving out here.
You guys.
That's all it took.
Listen,
you don't want to be sold on the weather
and shit.
You Could always use medical marijuana,
medical marijuana,
and you got to have your own podcast
show.
What have you been in the stores yet?
I've never been into the store and we're
going to take you right after we leave
here.
We're going to take you right into a
medical marijuana Store.
As soon as we leave here.
We'll take you right to by the way to
this is we know the guy who makes this.
You don't even have to worry about
terrorism.
we know the guy who actually grows it.
She can't say maybe my,
maybe my weed.
We don't have to worry about this week
because this week is 100 percent not
created by bad people.
Thank you.
You guys are such good.
Whoa.
Am I supposed to do it off camera?
I'll put on my face on camera though.
It's really bad for your career.
what was it?
Amy schumer.
Do you want to join the desk squad?
That sounds good.
All right,
so your step mom's house is going to be
natasha leggiero.
Now that's another inside joke I used to
date natasha and then they broke up and
I love her.
I love him more though.
You know what I'm saying?
He's a free man.
Know him,
but if He could pay my billS.
I don't know.
he could help you a little because I'm
willing.
I'm willing.
I just heard natasha on a adam corolla.
It was really funny.
She's very funny and that dunkin and her
are cool with.
Yeah,
they're going to be fresh.
I don't feel like you have to pick team
right away.
Like they're gonna be friends right
away.
Totally amicable.
I think it's great because they're both
adults.
You fucking child still feelings for
somebody you don't want is you want to
fuck them again.
Yeah.
You want to fuck them again,
so just don't see them.
Especially when you haven't seen him in
awhile.
Yeah,
we got a problem.
Yeah.
You know what?
The human body is a strange fucking
thing.
you know,
when you,
when you had moments with someone and
then all of a sudden you're in front of
them again.
And especiallY when no one's around,
you know,
if you like,
you,
uh,
just for whatever strange reason,
just run into them somewhere and all of
a sudden you're standing face to face
and you want to give him a hug.
And so then you do.
And then the other thing,
now what's up?
We broke up for a reason,
but the chemicals in your body or like,
why does my penis starts going?
We used to fuck her.
Right?
We could do it again.
Remember,
this was fun,
right?
I thought it was right,
yeah.
And then if you just keep,
keep doing that over and over again,
you'll never get out of relationships.
So my thing is don't talk.
Don't be at the same place.
I've had buddies that will break up with
the same girl six,
seven times because they will always get
together and
just fucking is so good.
Then they just feels like home and
you're happy to not be fucking a
stranger.
You've got to be fucking the stranger.
And then on top of it it's,
well,
it's nOt even that.
It's this weird thing that happens when
you break up and then you make up.
Like the makeup
was like,
it's reallY intense,
especially if you're convinced that
you're never going to make up.
Like if you have insulted each other,
I said crazy shit to each other,
you know?
And then people get in like patterns
like,
and you can recognIze those patterns
when you start dating someone because
they'll try to pull that shit on you.
You know,
they'll look,
you insult you and they'll say something
creepy to you and you're like,
whoa,
what the fuck is this?
It came out of nowhere.
What came out of nowhere because that's
just how they rock it.
like every relay,
every relationship they get in,
it's like starts off real good,
get real close to each other and then
get fucking nasty with each other and
then
cover and then recover and I only had
one relationship where we got nasty to
each other.
Since then it's been pretty smooth
sailing in and out.
That is the worst.
There's no darker feeling than someone
who you used to like tell I love you and
used to make out with them and use the,
you know,
if you have sex with them and then all
of a sudden you like elena and each
other and angry words and they're saying
insulting shit to you take back.
You're lIke,
whoa,
I only had one like that.
It's been since then.
I don't.
I refuse to participate in that shit.
No,
I haven't had a relationship like that
since I was in my twenties and when I
went to the last one that did happen,
I,
I clearly remember saying,
all right,
this is never going to happen again.
I can never allow myself to get in this
of a situation where we're,
every time I'm around this person,
there's some sort of like an argument or
debate or jockeying for position,
you know,
there's a weird jockeying of power.
Sometimes it goes on in some
combinations of relationships.
You know,
it's like you,
maybe you,
your,
your confidence triggers the weirdest
parts of some guy,
you know.
Have you ever had that happen where
like,
the guy is probably pretty cool with a
lot of people,
but then he gets her up.
Think like you being a comic and being
smart and quick like those two.
That's,
that must be like issues with some
dudes.
Um,
guys who aren't comics.
Have you date guys?
Weren't comic's comic really fucked up.
Huh?
Tom?
Too fucked up.
No,
I was saying to brian like,
I,
I don't make statements like that.
I'd love to thank like.
I'll never date a comic fan.
I dunno.
It's like it's nice to be with somebody
who speaks your language.
That does help.
But do you want to date someone as
fucked up as you really don't think I've
met him.
It's just seems like,
it seems like you always have to follow
you,
fuck with somebody you work with,
you're going to pay in the end comedy
clubs.
It's like working at a place,
doing your,
you know,
your onstage doing your shit and you're
like kind of doing,
you're not persona but whatever,
like she do on stage and then.
But then like seeing somebodY that makes
you so vulnerable and you can't,
you can't like,
you know,
in good conscience.
Keep up that facade when you're like,
you know,
you just want to go home and cry.
Sucks.
I've only dated one like abusive,
crazy,
crazy asshole and yeah,
I really,
I was like,
I'll never do this again.
I never did.
But we brought it up.
Was it your first black guy?
I've yet to go to the dark side.
my new year's resolution though,
I feel like the,
I,
I hope that I fuck a black guy
this year because my professional,
but it's just like,
I don't know,
I feel racist that I've never been with
a black guy.
Like why hAven't I?
Well,
I asked my therapist,
I'm like,
does that make me racist?
And she's like,
no,
but I think she was just trying to make
you feel.
There's this guy that joe wants you to
hook you up with.
His name is rampage.
He's a really nice favorite video chain
while you fucked,
but you could probably.
We're a chest protector and you'd be
fine.
For me,
that's what I want.
I want like a brother,
like I want to feel his ankle bracelet
when we're fucking.
We need like a ton of lube,
but just for his elbows.
Coconut lotion.
I think it's hobos dark girl.
Chance you went down weirdo lane.
I went down racist land.
I'm not.
No,
I don't.
I like,
I really did make that as my new year's
resolution,
but I don't.
I don't know if it's going to happen.
Yeah,
I know people that are comics and only
day complex and it never works out.
it's just like not a good idea.
It's like high school.
You're at the same shows every night.
Well,
not only that,
I think it's better in life and in my
opinion,
to experience things from when,
when you're close with someone,
whether they're friends or whether
they're coworkers,
whatever,
when you,
when you're really close with someone
you're experiencing life,
when you communicate with them
through a different perspective in a
completely different perspective.
So if you're dating someone that has
like a completely different set of
interests in a completely different set
of desires and like someone who sees
life from,
you know,
a totally different viewpoint than a
performer.
Like you're going to get your,
you'll,
it'll,
I think it will broaden your
perspective.
I think you'll get,
I think when you date people that are
outside of your line of show business or
even any line of work,
I would think if you're,
you know,
you're limited.
Yeah.
If you're like a ceo and you're only
date ceo checks and you'd get together
and have some ceo sex,
what kind of line are you staying on?
They started to feel very incestuous,
like just talking about like hear what
quinton's said tonight,
like right after time.
We fucked today before the laughter died
and I was just like,
whoa,
this is too close to home.
Like when does the work stop and the so
no,
but right now when I'm talking what one
of the greatest comedy cds of all time,
fucking unbelievable.
We couldn't help it.
Fuck,
we're so psyched.
And folks who don't know if you don't
know this,
is this a cd?
When dice clay was at dice clay by the
way,
wants to do the podcast and I got his
number.
I want to call.
He doesn't have a cell phone and he
doesn't have a voice mail at home.
He just has a phone.
If you call him,
you either get me.
Oh,
you're getting me.
No,
it doesn't.
It doesn't have an answering machine if
he doesn't answer the phone.
That's it.
I love it.
And when he was huge,
when he was at the top of the heap,
he put out a cd,
two cd recording,
a double album of him bombing.
He went to.
You went to danger fields completely
unannounced and you've gotta understand
folks wouldn't.
When this was happening.
When dice put the cd out,
dice was feeling comes dice clay was the
biggest,
most explosive standup comedian of all
time.
I always say that there was no guy who
had more success and he doesn't get a
lot of credit because it was like really
juvenile for several for whatever
reason.
For some people it's like not good.
I'll tell you what,
I fucking love dice clay,
especially when I was a kid,
when I was with my girlfriend when I
was,
when we were like 19,
18,
19,
and we're listening to a cassette of
andrew dice clay.
We were fucking howling laughing waY
before I ever thought I would ever do
stand up comedy,
but I remember thinking,
this guy is fucking hilarious.
He just was going for every single
fucking thing going for us.
He's a fucking genius.
And norton security guy,
kenny,
you know?
sure,
sure.
Be dices guy and the stories that he
tells us even more,
he's fucking crazy.
So this is what he does.
He's the.
He's on top of the world.
He goes to danger fields to shows up and
he does an album with him with no
material at all.
He just went up
and just talk shit for like two hours.
Ruined every audience member,
blocked people.
Maybe there were like four people left
to be in,
I don't know,
crazy.
It was a complete cd of non comedy and
he sold it and there were still some
funny moments.
There was a guy named,
there's a guy named Mike Donovan who was
boston legend and when I was coming up,
he was one of the guys that I really
admired and he was crying,
laughing,
counting dice,
doing nixon while he was eating the
girl's ass.
He's like,
he's like,
I'll do mixing in that ass is nixon
impression,
and Mike Donovan was crying tears for
fears in the back room of the comedy
connection,
crying,
tears recounting it,
talking about how great that cd is.
Especially for a comic,
for any up and coming comic.
Man,
you must get the day the laughter died.
You must get that
start and you will want the crowd to
like you and then you get a healthy like
hatred of the crowd and then an
indifference creeps in,
but that's where I am now.
Just total indifference.
It's like ugly guys and girls,
ugly guys and girls have this thing
where they,
they love the girl,
but the girl doesn't love them back.
So every time they see an ugly,
a pretty girl,
they have this feeling of pain inside of
them that,
that connection with rejection.
So it's not that the crowd is terrible,
it's just in the beginning we're all
terrible.
So we grow to hate the crowd because so
many times they punished us
for the truth,
and then we love them,
but it's not satisfying enough.
Well,
we have to get good enough to be better
than them to sort of guide them along.
Right?
BuT.
And then they're listening to my comedy
journey.
No,
I think,
you know,
I honestly believe that there's a lot of
comics that develop this sort of hate
for their audience and it's really
strange and I think the only thing that
makes sense is they connect it with bad
feelings.
They connect their audience with some
reflection of how they've put out their
own energy and their own personality and
how people responded to that and then
their own material,
you know,
when,
if they've had bad sad or if they've had
like,
you know,
bad things happen in the crowd and they
associate that,
that bad feeling with everyone that
comes to see them.
And so they developed.
I've met a lot of old guys that had been
in the business for a long time and like
I don't give a fuck with these people.
One or I'm going to feed them what I do.
They like it or they don't like it and
the show is over.
All right folks,
get the fuck outta here.
And they really do develop that sort of
defense mechanism.
Um,
I try to be exactly the opposite.
I try to,
I,
I buy now,
I have like,
when I do shows,
people come out that know me,
like it's there,
it's my crowd.
So what?
It's my crowd.
It's like,
it's way easier.
It's just like,
no,
we're just going to have fun,
you know,
I feel like very open when I go out
there and like,
just like when I meet someone like in
life,
I give them the benefit of the doubt and
uh,
and I'm,
I'm into it but it.
But I don't,
I feel like I don't need anYthing from
them right now where I am.
I'm not like,
I'm not like pleased,
laugh or please like me and I'm not
like,
I don't know.
I don't feel scared at all.
Youth as a,
as an intelligent person,
when you were involved in this sort of a
bizarre line of work,
there's,
there's self analysis that comes along
with creating new material and a lot of
times you start looking at this weird
relationship that you have to this
strange group of people.
Like I'm seeking their approval and then
I'm doing this and I'm changing who I
am.
You know?
And there's,
there's a weird,
like there's a,
there's a weird thing that goes back and
forth when you're an intelligent person
and you're analyzing anything where you
sort of insisting on the approval of
Mass amounts of people,
which is what your comedy is totally
more so than like music.
Yeah.
BuT like,
okay,
but before you were saying about being a
chick and uh,
that it might limit the subject matter.
You Can talk about that.
I did want to say limit what I said is,
makes it more difficult.
I think I'm more impressed when a chick
can skirt the issues of sex or politics
or,
or any,
any position of authority or,
or,
or someone who makes sense.
Yeah.
Because guys don't want to hear a girl
makes sense that they haven't figured
out.
That makes total sense.
But that's what I feel like I've been
doing like onstage about sex stuff.
I'm talking about the,
like the girl,
the female experience and not for the
sake of shock and not for the sake of
I'm making anybody uncomfortable or you
know,
trying to belittle or alienate the
dudes.
It's not like that.
I,
and I think that I've found a way to
like make it acceptable for people to
digest.
I bet you have your smart,
you can do it.
It's not impossible,
but it is,
it's more difficult
but,
but in that way,
what I'm my reason for saying that,
I was like,
so I'm paying attention to the
experience of the audience is having,
like if they're not laughing and not
with me,
I'm not going to be like,
well,
I don't care.
This is the path I'm on.
I'm fed by that and I really react to
it,
but I just don't feel like,
like,
uh,
you know,
I just,
I don't know where I used to.
If a joke didn't work,
I would sorta just tap dance to the next
one and be like,
maybe this will.
And that just,
you know,
that I think just from bombing so hard,
so many times the fear leaves you
because he was lived out all your fears
on stage.
Yeah.
The moments of deep bombing
right now people are like kate upton,
but it's true the bump bombing moments
or clarity moments.
But I think that that's where people
develop the,
uh,
the bad relationship with the audience.
I think that's,
it's like a guy with an ugly dude with
pretty girls just so used to getting
rejected that you folk these bitches
will,
you always lose,
will go to a strip club.
Yeah.
I think that's it.
It's a natural thing for people.
I loved your,
uh,
one of the videos that were,
are you or how you dealt with,
uh,
that the,
female heckler,
um,
you,
uh,
you were like,
I'm not,
you just like really explained the truth
to her.
Like,
I'm not,
I think you were like,
I'm not your boyfriend or like,
I'm not trying to fuck
you.
Like you.
I'm not gonna act like what you're
saying is interesting.
Not,
not that those were your words,
but I learned.
But I learned from that.
I was like,
oh,
like the absolute truth is like the
funniest shit.
Like you,
you didn't like insult her whatever.
You were just like,
here's the situation I didn't have.
I was like,
you're not fascinating to me.
Like there's an.
I'm not going to pretend like you're
interesting.
Like the guys that want to bang you,
like just shut up.
I had a woman in vegas a couple of weeks
ago that was in vegas to the one I think
you're thinking of.
Which vegas?
They just go the deepest.
Is it usually on meth or eCstasy or
something?
Last advil there on flying.
Flying knows what the fuck they're doing
in vegas.
There was a girl last time were there.
She stood up for like 10 minutes for 10
minutes.
She was like standing up in the
audience.
Why I destroyed her.
Totally exaggerating on the 10 minutes,
two minutes.
She was just going to the bathroom.
But no,
she was standing up for a long time
screaming and yelling at me.
She was just crazy.
She was just pretty.
And uh,
you know,
and she just thought for whatever reason
she just couldn't be running this room.
I think they're just confused.
She's into coyote ugly too.
Anytime she thought she could just stand
up and start a revolution.
Starts flair bar tending
about
somebody play devil went down to the.
Yeah.
Do a little bit of this in the audience
that night,
joe.
Or it's riverdale
saying,
you're like,
that's not what I'm here.
For whatever reason,
she just really,
really wanted to be the center of
attention.
So it's just caused this massive
commotion.
Talk to them like I talked that I like,
I would talk to a toddler.
I'll be like,
do you feel like you need attention
right now?
Yes.
That's important.
Like,
do you need it to be from me?
Or maybe the people you're With at your
table could maybe.
Where does,
what led you to this deficit?
Can you check this?
So looking at this one thing of
behavior,
what is the,
what is the catalyst which started this
sauce with his childhood molestation?
Let's talk about your dad.
Leave you somewhere and never come and
get you.
Or what can we do right now by dogs?
Or I'll just like,
I'll move the mic and I'll just say
like,
don't talk to me anymore.
And I just go back.
It's like,
because I think the way that it is a
struggle also for me is I go on stage,
I look like very amish,
uh,
like I look not threatening and I think
people react even no matter what age
they are.
Like I'm a substitute teacher.
Here we go.
Mrs randle's not here like America.
I look like an american dollar pie.
I like apple pie.
You'd have like the best tasting apple
pie time step,
right?
If I looked at her and I said,
that bitch is by,
we've got some awesome album and I go up
and I'm like,
my posts either
that.
So
they think it's like,
you know,
step teachers swipe to sort of assert my
authority right away and be like,
this is how this is this,
this house is going to go,
you know,
that's hot though.
I mean that.
I bet.
I think I would have imagined that the
guys would be or like scared
of this guy.
I don't know.
I don't,
I don't get hit on very often.
Or like if I get hit on it,
it'll be a guy coming up after the show
who will listen to my stuff and I do a
lot of stuff up being like easy.
So they'll,
I've had a guy come up and he just like,
assume that they're like going home with
me.
LIke I've,
I've had a guy come up and be like,
hey,
so I'm a marine.
And like I drove two hours to get here.
So I'm just saying,
yeah,
it's safe and a knife.
I'm like,
okay,
like thank you for signing the cd.
And I'm like,
okay,
thanks.
And he's like,
whoa,
where are we going?
And I'm like,
oh no,
like you're a stranger.
Like where are we going?
Yeah.
Or,
But no chicks,
chicks just as much as guys aren't our
handsy with me and are like,
let's go somewhere.
Where's the next location for jesus
christ?
Do they want to party with you or do
they want to have sex with you?
What would this church.
I hope both.
I can only hope both girls want to hang
out,
but they're all like.
And if it's like a couple,
they'll be like,
I don't hog amy,
I want eat,
you know,
and they're like,
the girls are pansy.
Cause you know,
they feel like,
I'm sure everybody feels like they're
your friend,
they know you,
they want you to like them and they want
you to know that they get it.
They get so funny.
So yeah.
So a guy.
Yeah,
definitely.
I have to,
like,
I did the show at foxwoods and this guy
was like,
can I,
can I take a picture where I'm
pretending like I'm,
I'm gonna grab your boobs.
And I was like,
whoa.
no,
um,
but let's take a normal picture.
And he wrote on facebook.
He was like,
that comment.
She left me and I wrote back to him and
I was like,
like that's the only time I ever have or
ever will write back to anyone who
writes something rude to me.
I like,
I like black,
I like the block button on twitter,
I'm happy.
But uh,
that guy,
I was like,
why did you feel like that was okay?
Like I said,
let's take another picture and usually
go.
Just thought you'd be like,
limb vanilla would have done it,
and I'm just like,
I'm on the road by myself.
Usually like I want some inbred fucking
weirdo to be like,
oops,
sorry.
I grabbed them by accident
pretending to grab your tits.
How fucking crazy.
It's weird.
I'm just like,
no,
I don't want that.
I grabbed him.
He just picked me up for a picture.
I had a guy asked me if he could pick me
up.
I want to feel safe.
Can I carry you?
What did you want to do?
It kind of carry you in the picture.
The fuck out of here,
Man.
Why would you want to carry me?
That's so weird.
Oh,
it was so weird.
It was a big guy too.
I was like,
hey,
you're like lefT to fight for that
position,
so let's come up with something else
here.
We get to the point where you're
actually carrying me.
We're going to have to.
We're fighting you crazy asshole.
Trying to pick me up.
we'll have no boundary here.
And then what?
Next thing you know,
it's never enough.
It's never enough,
so he's another was the average person
would never ask.
They could pick you up and carry you
over.
Ask.
Don't usually,
if it's an artist first time you've ever
met them,
even though you know that they're a
person that you've seen on television or
on a band or whatever,
you have just met them.
You crazy ass.
All three seconds of facetime with you
in,
uh,
in sacramento.
This chick got thrown out of a show
because she was talking and drunk and
loud and she got up one at the
punchline.
This is the shit.
And she was like,
amy,
are you going to let them do it like
you're a stranger bitch?
Like she thought I was going to be no
barbara or whatever.
I was like,
yeah,
get her outta here.
Crazy drunk asshole shit.
You're going to let them.
I always wonder too,
when people go off in the audience,
so occasionally I will always wonder
what are they on,
you know,
in this day and age I always wonder
about like,
what kind of weird prescription shit are
they drinking?
At the same time,
because some people did a complete
disconnect from reality,
absolute utter disconnect from
we are,
it'll be like,
they're not trying to be mean,
they're trying to,
like,
they think they're helping
and they'll even tell you afterwards I
helped you.
I hope that show.
He went great.
We were playing off of each other,
right?
No,
uh,
I had a guy,
the punchline atlanta over new year's.
He was like yelling and he was like,
I said something like,
like,
I'm not a lesbian.
I mean I've caught a finger but I'm not.
And so.
And he's like,
yes you are,
you've,
you'll fuck anybody.
And I,
and he and I don't think he was trying
to lash out.
I think he was trying to be like,
I know your whatever.
Right.
But uh,
but then everybody's like,
woo.
And they put the lights on and it's like
they wanted me to like,
trash this guy and uh,
so I did know,
but you know,
it's lights on him.
They put the lights on in the crowd so
that you could see him there.
Yeah.
Oh wow.
Did you ever ask them to do that?
I don't think so.
They put the video online.
It's not good.
Wait a minute.
Wait.
Why did they do that?
That's their solution.
Turn the lights on here.
You can see him now.
He's the victim.
You can go after him and I don't want to
do that.
I want to do like my,
my jokes that I'm working on.
You know,
that is rather not have the interaction
at all.
Yeah.
That is a problem.
You know,
especially when it becomes really funny
too.
Then the crowd thinks it's a really good
thing that had happened than someone
else.
Favorite part that they enjoy that look
with the trash,
that fucking idiot.
So I could see how the club would be
like,
oh,
this'll be fun,
but there's other clubs that won't even
allow it to get to that.
I love those clubs like gotham,
gotham polices that they don't fuck
around that.
Places are all ex cops running that
fucking savages.
TheY grabbed you guys alone.
They are where they're waiting to
pounce.
Those guys are professional,
New York.
Amy's.
No.
All right.
Well,
have a signal the other animals,
they don't fuck around there waiting to
hurt someone.
Those guys are beautiful places.
Perfect.
It's perfection.
Now you have to go there.
Why are we like no?
You know,
I love god.
I love god and that's where I started.
What,
what the hell aM I doing in New York?
Not doing that,
brian.
What am I doing?
I remember haTton theater,
the manhattan theater.
Fancy pants.
Fancy on the bitch.
Ain't no shit
Moving on up.
Well,
I love doing clubs just as much.
But uh,
yeah,
I think more someTimes even,
but to do both,
right?
It's when you can't do five shows or
can't do like a whole weekend,
you know,
like thursday,
friday,
saturday,
sunday.
And if I can't do that,
uh,
I have to do like a theater.
I don't want,
you know,
I get bummed out if I can only do like
one show at a town,
only 200 seats or something like that.
but those are the best shows,
right?
Don't you think?
200,
10 days because then I might fill it.
You'll listen.
I'm telling you,
if you had a podcast,
he'd be packing clubs everywhere.
I've heard you stand up.
You're fucking hilarious.
Hilarious doing.
Stand up as you are rose.
Thank you.
You'd be killing them.
Oh my god.
A podcast.
Yeah.
I'm tony.
Could step.
This is my podcast.
I wouldn't know the first thing to say.
I'd be just start talking.
Start talking shit.
Or come on out.
You could be the hole on our show.
We could introduce you.
You could totally be my homie schubert,
aka the.
That's squat.
Whole valentine's day.
Yes.
So beautiful.
What's beautiful?
Because you're here.
Thank you.
Bounce so well.
There's a fake butthole in that table.
By the way.
We're right in front of you.
You amy.
There's the little brown thing.
No,
the little rubber thing right there.
Oh,
this isn't.
It's thanks for telling me to fake
asshole.
Like I would be concerned that this was
perhaps a real asshole just had wandered
away from it.
So this is an african americans asshole.
Is it just because of february or switch
out the asshole when we do some porn
star podcast here and when girls have a
gaping asshole,
they use that to like plug it during the
day.
So they're assholes.
Just not like mouth breathers.
Shut the phone,
you know,
because sometimes if they get it doesn't
smell right.
You're not tricking me with this.
You just making this up be crazy.
Asshole.
Have you seen this asshole?
No,
I have not.
May I please?
Thank you.
Enjoy.
Silly.
Please enjoy.
Do you know will sasso joe?
He's a very strange,
very strange that someone would want to
have in your hand.
Yeah,
I guess.
I guess when dudes just sit around
finger and go,
that could be her ass be somebody's.
First of all,
I would brush,
brush up against her.
Barely
just letting my fingers.
Just let her know I'm here saying what's
up?
You want to back up?
You can it up.
You feel a little pressure?
Is that your booty hole pressures?
If you had the feeling to just back up
and just.
Everybody's different.
You put your finger on some girl's
asshole.
So then they clamped down and go,
whoa,
asshole.
Every.
Almost every guys.
Well,
wouldn't you rather that than a guy back
on grab that second thing?
I think so,
yeah.
You don't want a guy who's like super
good.
That's how I feel today.
When you get older.
When I get older,
I'm going to see be fisting any dude
that will let me.
The stoke.
The fires were old speed board or
whatever.
I can in his ass.
Little brown assholes.
Disturbing.
It might not be a total.
I mean it's what I mean total.
I don't know.
I mean that's a black asshole blast.
Just a really tan person too.
It's not necessarily black.
No one's.
That
chick that I pulled it out of was a.
It was a black.
Well thanks brian.
He didn't pull this out of some girl.
It was not an actual real doll play
hole.
It's a real dolls,
but holding version of a real downer.
But isn't,
isn't a real dog.
You can fuck.
It's butthole.
Yeah.
You can pick different attachments in
it.
Oh,
you can.
But this skin is what the real dollars
may not have.
Yeah,
that's not as good as flashlight.
No,
it's not.
It has a patent technology,
joe
the market.
Oh,
way better.
Yeah.
Fleshlight feels way closer to vagina.
Yeah,
absolutely.
Pretty good.
Close.
That's why you get you buy any kind of
fake vagina as a guy and it's like,
it's a joke.
It's like fucking a barbie doll chunk.
Like that data piece where they make
barbie dolls out of like the carpet in a
certain way.
That's what it.
It feels like.
Can you make the fleshlight tighter if
you want?
Yeah,
it was pretty tight.
It just stretches around your dick.
Yeah.
Okay.
Do you know what I mean?
So for the most part,
most people are
imagine.
Maybe,
maybe not.
Oh,
thank you everyone.
We meet me.
Wow.
This is great.
Very touchy subject with men and women.
Oh yeah.
The asshole.
China's something taken over.
Some artificial shit for,
for years.
Dudes.
How to live with girls riding equipment
and stick and sedans inside of their
bodies.
And now it's your turn.
Now it's finally you're the men sexual
revolution.
Turn around right now.
I wasn't scared of all that shit.
I've never dealt with any of that.
I mean I've had a vibrator,
but how do you feel about this crazy
rick santorum,
asshole.
Not to like skew your judgement in any
way you thought.
Maybe I'd be like,
whoa,
whoa.
I love santorum now.
Apparently like he's not even into birth
control.
He thinks that women shouldn't have
birth control and that the states should
be able to decide whether that was my
way of saying you're pulling out and
putting it all over his wife's stomach.
Yes.
Because you thInk he's a tech guy or do
you think.
I don't believe that he feels like that.
He believes anything that he's saying.
You feel like he's just completely to
plan a game,
don't.
what do you think it could be gay.
He just go straight to fat.
Yeah.
When I went over.
So it's really religious bears.
When someone's super,
super religious and they want to lie,
like
they want to either challenge gay
marrIage or control gay or whenever they
want to get real freaky with like
controlling sex and morality issues like
that.
I almost always go gay with them.
Almost always one are uncovered as being
wildly gay.
Yeah.
It sounds like a crazy thing to say.
Like,
you know joe rogan,
you're an asshole for saying that.
No,
I'm not.
You know why I'll tell you why because
I'm not saying that you shouldn't be
religious.
I'm not saying that.
I know a lot of people were all that is
super benefited them,
especially people that have had
substance abuse issues.
You cannot say that christianity or
religion and having a good church and a
good association of community
association to that belong to.
That's religious and false religious
tenants that it couldn't help.
They're like,
yeah,
but for,
you know,
for a lot of people they're just too
fucking stupid.
Yeah.
It gives somebody hope and it helps them
out.
I'm like,
god,
do it,
but,
but if it's just because you're
borderline retarded and somebody told
you to believe it and you do,
then I guess I don't really know what
I'm saying.
What do you saying?
I don't know.
I just think,
um,
I don't want to blame the pot,
but uh,
I just like don't even really remember
what we're talking.
Do you like the breadsticks and salad at
olive garden?
Brian?
You had to.
Is that what we were talking about when
you're there you are talking about black
eyes.
Oh yeah.
You guys.
I'll tell you later.
Personal threeway mind stump right
there.
We were driving and we were following
you.
You will that we.
Yeah,
because there was a brIef moment where
I,
w,
you know,
as you having a conversation,
it's sorta like you tossing a ball back
and forth to each other.
I took them off.
You have the ball and I completely
forgot what I was saying.
When I gave you the ball in the sewer,
you,
you sort of threw the ball back to me
and I am like,
I'm not sure you can have it again.
And then you said,
I don't know what we're talking about.
Just like,
damn,
I should have kept that ball and I
wasn't paying attention.
Yeah.
Brian's like watching reruns of stanford
and you don't want to be the koby bryant
of podcasts.
You want to push the ball off as much as
possible.
It's very important.
Yeah.
It's a beautiful moments.
Rape joke.
I'm gonna.
Opt out.
Do I love you?
I love you.
Move here.
Come on.
We're going to be besties.
I stopped doing my rape joke.
I can't do it anymore.
People were getting mad in the audience
that had been raped.
Yeah.
You should not be.
That's not a funny thing to talk about.
It's like murdering babies is not fun to
talk about either.
Yeah.
They don't have to tell you.
I beg to differ
subjects.
I just.
I can't.
I can't find a way to make cancer funny,
but everything else I think is pretty
well.
It depends.
It depends on who's getting raped when
dudes are getting raped.
It's hilarious.
That's great.
Especially assholes.
What a bad rape.
I mean men are getting raped by other
meaner men.
Song sister,
right?
For that reason.
That was the rape.
I was like,
yes.
Laska rape show on television was odd.
They don't make them like based and
that's a different way of owning a guy
raping them.
That's a whole other level raping
someone when you're in a cage together,
like they just
impose themselves on you so much that
they sexually impose themselves on and
they make you suck their dick.
Oh,
they not in your mouth.
They didn't even.
They just wanted to show you that they
could do that.
Few.
Imagine how horrific that must be.
The [inaudible].
The moment you become a fiction,
it's what you want it to happen,
but what if you.
You have to got beats the fuck out of
you.
The best way to not get the fuck beat
out of you is to suck as deck.
Let them fucking yes.
Not going to take that much tIme out of
your day.
Tibet and rape ceremonies.
Yeah.
Your tie you to a stick and a bunch of
guys that raped free tibet means betting
that up.
I'm getting that bumper sticker meeting.
Meeting adjourned.
He's actually
and saying a tibetan.
I'm a vulture,
vulture funeral funeral where they tie
you.
You're dead body to a stake and then the
vultures come down and eat you.
It's fucking wild and watches like your
family members,
your family in.
a lot of times the voltage will leave
the head on last,
so a lot of the photos of you see it.
It's just like a skeleton,
like almost at exactly from disneyland
and then a person's real head attached
to extend.
Not only the high level guys,
the high level guys take it to the next
level and they bring haMmers and then
they smash up the head and they smash up
the bones and then they step back again.
The vultures come back and they'll
acTually devour the smashed up bones.
That's when you're taking a deep.
That's when you're taking it super deep.
When you're hitting your friend's head
open with a fucking hammer and they
opened them up to at knives.
They're like,
open the meet up to get the vultures to
start.
I was actually talking to this mom.
I'm on the phone with my mom and now
he's telling her about why didn't my
suspicious that you're telling a lie?
No.
I said,
I will call.
I will call her,
I'll call her right now live if you
don't believe me,
but no,
I swear to god I was driving over
telling her about this and then she's
like,
you know,
this is like the most disturbing thing
my mom's ever heard in her life because
she doesn't have like internet as much
as people,
you know,
so like I'm telling her this and she's
like,
I have to sit down.
Really just the idea of tolerance you
did today on the way here.
Oh,
you should tell her to fucking go to the
link to make it go to the line and then
just email it to her.
Hey mom,
this is new place.
I'm thinking about moving into.
We're back.
What do you think?
And she'll just look at that length.
She sounds like a real bitch.
I think she's spotting.
Say that while you're wearing your
cougar mentor.
I could sent it.
Cool to you.
Do you remember the cougar in,
in austin?
Austin,
Texas.
Uh,
you know,
the accidental cougar?
Oh yeah,
yeah.
Do you want to tell that story?
No,
I think we've told a million times,
but pretty much are you,
are you talking about the strip club?
Yeah,
the one when you didn't know.
So there is this waitress that was
really flirty with me at the strip club
and I was blackout drunk and you're
like,
he wants me to get jealous.
Yeah,
yeah.
Well he is,
you know,
she wasn't enough and don't worry about
it,
but she was pretty high.
She was pretty hot though.
And so she was like being really flirty,
like massaging my back and everything
like that and I was just wasted.
And then she stopped massaging my back
and I'm just fucked up.
And then suddenly this other waitress
comes up to me or a stripper or I don't
know who it was or just an older lady.
She was a patron,
a patron.
I was just like an old lady that he hung
out at strip clubs,
you know,
like creepy older ladies.
They smoke cigarettes and I don't know,
like face of an ugly angel.
And uh,
and she,
I thought that was this girl tried to
kiss me on the cheek or something like
that.
And I thought it was that hot waitress
and I just closed my eyes and just
started like frenching her and then
joe's recording it on his phone.
And then,
I don't know,
it was this way before.
You could record things in your.
No you do because I recorded it on a,
on a,
on a camera camera camera.
He recorded on the camera and then then,
um,
a whatever.
I like backed out and notice it wasn't
hurting everyone that was around me look
like a ghost.
LIke everyone was just like,
why does it go?
What?
It was like,
it was october and brian was happy as a
pig in shit.
He was sitting back with his arms
stretched pie.
I'm drunk,
stoned as fuck.
He's just oblivious to the world.
And he had this huge smile on his face
and then the waitress comes over and she
was really cute and brian said something
funny.
He laughed and he clapped his hands
together and we were all having a good
time.
And brian kicks back and he's literally,
he's so hammered and like fucking
nickelback is playing really loud.
His head is leaning Back and the girl
comes over and kisses his cheek and
she's a fucking old biker lady.
Like an old roast.
She had short chyna,
golden girls.
the older one that was the.
The cougar.
She was wearing a vance.
Blanche blanche.
She seems like the cutest one.
anyway,
so she was.
She was.
She was like late,
late fifties,
right when you say late,
late,
late fifties.
Old biker lady sits down next to brian.
Cuddles with them,
rubs up agaInst him.
He like puts his hand on her.
She kisses his neck,
he turns to her and it's like watching a
deer get hit by a train.
Oh my god.
It was horrendous when she stuck out her
weathered cigarette,
great tongue.
It was like a fucking appendage and in
the movie predator it was like something
you expect come out of it's mouth.
She was tongue and brian and oh,
it's so nasty.
And wHatever tattoos that she had on her
head long been ballooned by the mother
time.
TaSmanian devil shooting a basketball or
something.
Oh,
they were making out.
They were making out and I'm filming
this,
I'm filming it,
and I'm going,
look,
what
the fuck is brian?
So the video is like,
look,
look what the fuck his brains doing.
Hear me.
You know?
It's like,
yeah,
and then the next day I'm like,
dude,
did you get that video?
And goes,
dude,
I deleted it for you.
We watched it.
I knew that it was too good and it was
going to get out.
I knew it was devastating.
It would have been devastated.
I would love to see no today.
I agree.
But eight years ago,
whenever the fuck it was,
I,
I say you weren't really ready for that
yet.
I would love to.
It would have been devastated.
I had that on my fucking mind.
You'd wake up and shit,
your pants and cold sweats.
You just wake up thinking about it.
JusT shit your pants.
Oh,
that woman was horrific.
That would be so awesome to have seen in
the shining.
When jack nicholas says,
making out with the woman at all.
So it turns into an old lady out,
oh,
that's what it was like,
huh?
That's sad that you did little buddy,
you know I love.
You know I want to.
I want to see.
I didn't want to see it again.
I went almost reenact it,
live with it.
I felt bad.
Everybody was going to attack you.
I'm on a cougar hunt show.
You're just here to protect him.
She was a snuffaluffagus rocker chick
trying to ruin my game with the cougar,
but there's somewhere out there.
There's someone who wants to suck her
feet.
Yeah.
There's some dude who wants to suck
those.
DrIed out.
Old fucking calloused heart and cracked
feet.
He wants to suck on them.
There's somebody out there,
man.
hey man.
Pretty nice.
Was that like,
was that like hispanic or like bread?
Like southern southern guy.
So awful.
Have you seen the book of mormon?
Do you go to like plays and stuff like
that?
Is it.
Is it just amazing?
It's coming here to los angeles.
Finally,
for folks who don't know,
it's the matt stone and trey parker.
A musical.
Awesome.
It's coming to los angeles.
I think so how the fuck those guys have
time to do that?
Man,
that's ridiculous.
There's some people that like put out
like the workload is just.
It's.
So
you're one of those 85,
you're like jamaican.
No,
these easy jobs.
Everything I have,
I figured out a way to just to fake it
crest on,
on crest secret.
Super manly,
rugged fucking fucking fucking.
Just everything I do.
It's super easy.
It's all like skating through.
I Mean comedy is the only thing that's
difficult because you have to write
material,
but then once you got it down,
once you have your set down,
it's super easy.
You know that they're really.
The only difficult thing about comedy is
writing new stuff
on the shit that the travel,
but that's just.
I'm telling you,
your travel will be so much different if
you had a podcast and bring your friends
just hanging out in California,
smoke a lot of weed and just do shows
here locally.
Do podcasts.
Yeah,
come on,
get in there,
girl.
This is a scene in the movie we decided
that fucking New York,
New York can suck it and you throw all
your stuff in a bag and that's what I'm
saying right before you leave New York
and he kicked the door.
Shut up,
listen your plane.
Next thing you landed like in the movie
snatch you.
Remember when the dude has to fly back
and forth from london to New York.
I'm so mad.
I got some fucking diamond deal that's
going on and pop.
Sammy the pretty women,
but like in reverse,
so like a month from now I'll just be
like a hooker pants list straight.
Like,
no,
I don't need money.
I don't need money or the greyhound
station is,
but it really.
I'm like,
okay,
can I have some money to the street in
my underpants?
Just state your brown.
When I first joined to New York,
I'm not going to start shitting myself,
brian,
jesus christ.
I'm just not.
I don't have a job.
I remember when I first got to New York,
there was an area of New York,
uh,
jimmy norton would know where it is.
He'd be able to share it.
I'm sure he knows where it moved to.
He probably does.
There's an area that was like near the
shipyards and shit.
It was like a real creepy area and you
drive through and there was hookers
everywhere.
It was like night of the booker.
It was 42nd.
Although seattle,
seattle,
again inside jokes.
This motherfucker with the inside jokes
there was.
It was so bizarre because it was like,
like it was only shipyards and hookers
everywhere.
It was a dream.
Really weird village.
People are actually there that that's
that.
That's a real place.
There's a lot of people that have never
experienced that.
They don't know if there's spots where
they.
There was all these,
they've decided hookers or just going to
amsterdam,
like on a streets in new orleans is the
scariest place like that that I've for
hookers really from what I've seen and I
went to college in baltimore,
like I saw some,
some shit for sure,
but new orleans I saw the scariest shit
I've ever seen with hookers and stuff.
I would've never thought that baltimore
was like a hardcore sort of a place like
the wire.
The wire is real.
Are you going to New York?
I grew up in New York and as in the city
constantly.
Nothing ever happened in Baltimore.
I got robbed every way imaginable.
My car held up at gunpoint.
Our apartments.
Christ like.
Yeah,
it's fucking.
It was nuts there.
I don't know if it's better now,
but I love baltimore,
but it's.
You don't want to go to central booking.
Yeah.
Baltimore.
They used to have a comedy club there.
You start in improv.
Do you remember doing.
Oh,
speaking of that.
Oh shit.
He's in baltimore this sunday.
I think it's called the comedy factor.
Yeah,
I remember that.
I just remembered that.
Yes,
We're a Washington dc ass.
I was just saying like,
don't go to baltimore and like,
fuck,
I'm going there this sunday and shot at
and don't forget this.
You want to see my comedic?
Yeah,
stylings.
Oh yeah,
so you're going to be wearing baltimore
the sunday.
I think it's called the comedy factory
at.
Is that the old improv?
It's like,
right.
If it's not in the actual spaces right
next to it,
that's where the improv used to be.
Yeah,
because I know the power plant,
so yeah,
that was a fun last spot.
That was fun.
That was coming up when I was in school
and we were just little horrors one
around there.
That's what it seems like.
It's a block away from gay street,
which is like the strip club porn.
That was fun.
Fun place to go to college for sure.
That's where a boy,
john rollo is.
Shout out to john rollo.
Listens to the podcast.
He's from baltimore.
We got john rollo to weird accent that
baltimore accent.
so fucking.
It's sort of city,
but it's sorta country.
It's not cute.
It ain't cute.
Do you think it's bad?
Just kidding.
Please come out sunday.
Everything you do is art.
Everything you do is our miracle.
Come out sunday.
My elbow support me.
Do you have an album?
Yeah.
How can people get it?
Itunes,
itunes.
It's called cutting.
Cutting.
Oh,
nice.
I love the album cover.
I might buy right now,
but that.
Okay.
How about.
What's that about?
Buy my album,
the album covers.
Awesome.
What is it?
It's her baking cupcakes and she has a
black guy.
She's dressed up like,
oh,
this is the one where the lady didn't
want to do the makeup.
She didn't want to do that.
Wow.
Because she thought that you're.
You're making fun of violence?
I think so,
but like that's my favorite thing to do.
Like my sister and I used to go to
rangers games and I would wear it brace
and I'd put two black eyes on her and
people be like,
what happened?
I'd be like,
oh,
we got into sewing with each other.
It's awesome people.
One time we saw jon hamm,
like,
oh,
we forgot that we had fucked ourselves
up and he was staring at us.
We were like,
john,
he was into our shit and then we're,
we're all your feet the fuck up.
Yeah.
We get worse and worse.
Every game.
Like we would try if we got our hands in
crutches and we would do anything.
We just thought it was so fucking funny.
People were horrified by us.
Is that okay?
Got you into stand up comedy,
like just be a joker like that.
I think so.
I've been a dick,
had my whole life.
I've been a worthless dick my whole
life.
I always had saturday detention.
Did you have that?
You know,
like the breakfast club shit?
Yeah,
it was me and all the kids that didn't
speak english.
I didn't have,
we didn't have saturday detention and
regular detention all the time.
Yeah.
Did you,
did you make it snow like from your
dandruff onto a picture?
Do.
I don't know.
Andrew fund to a picture.
You dirty tickets.
I'm not going to move here anymore.
That I was talking about the fiscal
february that you know,
we were there on saturday.
Important to you and nobody else.
I have no idea what a fucking alisha,
alisha,
alisha for.
Yeah.
You remember she used to like,
she was the of your hair and make it
snow.
Uh,
because of our direction.
It was like go as disturbing thing for
that movie.
That was the dandruff.
Like I think she.
Yeah.
And it was a joke that was snowing on a
house that she drew or something.
Oh,
I'll show you that.
That part,
I don't remember that.
I don't think that was important plot
point.
I don't know if I actually watched that
whole movie all the way through.
Yeah,
that's one of those movies I probably
watched like 20 minutes and then shut it
off and then went back and watched the
other 20 minutes.
Another time.
I probably never finished it.
you don't,
you don't like those movies?
I don't know.
It's never ended them.
They used to frustrate me when I was a
kid when I was a kid,
when those movies were coming out.
All those 16 candles is a very weird
time in my life because I,
I would get annoyed at any,
any like feel good.
Like I,
if I saw where it was going,
I couldn't enjoy it.
I had to like,
I,
I couldn't enjoy any sort of a horse
shit.
Sort of
happy ending any kind of movement it was
concocted.
Those movies had some really dark shit
though,
I'm sure.
Really?
Yeah.
The guy,
the guy that was right.
but I mean like I just,
if you saw like the happy ending coming
at you,
if I saw any,
if I just felt like it was written,
I felt like I was just like really
super,
super critical to the writing.
Yeah,
I could,
I wouldn'T,
wouldn't even leave and enjoyed like
comic book movies
back then.
But that movie is like a.
And you're the nerd and you're the,
you know,
it was very.
Yeah,
it was really like,
yeah,
this is the bad boy.
The bad boy.
Like in that movie,
his dad was like putting cigarettes out
on him and it was.
Right.
Well That's.
Yeah,
that is really talented girl.
Molly ringwald was like,
yeah,
like I remember thinking it was really
dark out.
She was kind of vilified just for having
tits.
Like she was doing something to
everybody just by having boobs.
Oh,
here's,
maybe if I saw it again,
it just showed him like.
But I was,
I just remember.
So I,
I had really like super critical taste
back then.
It was a what?
Yeah.
What did you like?
Why would.
I was very critical about myself at this
point in my life and so I was really
critical about like everything I saw on
tv and the movies.
It was just a weird time for me.
I was like,
oh,
the movie fucking sucks.
Were you like a comedy nerd?
Nick did you know
I became a comedian before that.
I was the only.
I was a richard pryor nerd,
you know,
we'd listen to richard pryor tapes.
So my girlfriend.
Yeah.
But then,
uh,
I,
I really started doing it because I'm
friends talked me into it and because
somebody described to me sam kennison,
the first sam kinison bid that I ever
heard was done for me by a girl in 19
year old girl
I know worked with,
you know,
I don't know why I know this story,
but I do know the story.
I should've just pretended like I didn't
know.
I probably told him on the podcast.
So you must have told him on the toilet.
Sorry,
brian.
I,
we did.
Yeah.
Even hearing in the parking lot.
She was.
So,
it was.
So it was such a funny bit that this
girl wasn't even a comedian,
did the bit in the parking lot.
I was like,
wow man,
I wish I could come up with something
that funny that was like,
she did it enough justice that you fell
in love with him just through her
quoting.
Yeah.
She acted it out and she was hot.
It was really ridiculous because she's
lying on her stomach in the parking lot
and she's like,
oh,
you mean life keeps fucking in the ass
dad.
Oh.
And I was like,
wow.
And he's like a short fat guy that's
doing this.
She's like,
he's wearing an overcoat.
It's hilarious.
I was like,
wow,
I got to check that guy out.
Like she's making me laugh by doing an
impression of the guy,
you know,
that's when you know your shit's good.
Did the girl was pretty good.
She was super cool.
I probably couldn't do kinison isn't
any,
just especially that one.
Blinding can try and help me in the
parking lot.
She was just so,
such a preposterous scene.
She's talking about getting fucked in
the ass.
Being a corpse is a for folks who don't
know what the bid is.
Kennison had a joke about homosexual
necrophilia tax that we're paying for a
couple hours undisturbed with the
freshest male corpses.
They had been arrested for it.
So he had this whole bit about the guy
being on a slab like,
oh,
well I guess that's it.
Now I'm dead.
I'm going to go be with jesus.
And then he starts rocking back and
forth like,
hey,
it feels like that in my ass.
You mean live keeps rocking the house
even after you're dead.
So fucking great bits.
This girl's doing this on her stomach in
the parking lot.
And I'm like,
oh my god,
this is hilarious.
She nailed it.
So I wonder where she is now.
Was probably married bunch of kids.
Her pussy is dragging on the floor.
Just I can still do the.
Oh god.
That was when I worked at that health
club.
That was a,
a really important moment for me is
that,
uh,
when I was like 18,
19 years old,
I worked at the boston athletic club.
I got to see bobby or did you know he is
famous hockey player.
I'd never seen anybody that had had like
more than 10 knee surgeries.
I'd never seen like a professional
athlete whose knees had been destroyed
and I got to watch this guy like walk
around.
He's a,
he's a legend in like boston legendary
hockey player,
like one of the greatest hockey players
of all time and the poor guy could
barely walk.
And I remember thinking like,
fuck man,
that can.
you have to think about that when you're
18 years old,
you're spry and you're all fucking
bouncing around like a little rabbit.
You don't think that like your,
your legs can get so fucked up that you
could be like one of the greatest hockey
players of all time and still you've
taken so much damage and so many
surgeries that you know,
you're hobbling along and agony
everywhere you go.
Wow.
Dark shit.
It's weird.
I just,
I was talking to this guy plays football
and I was like,
you'll probably like,
don't you?
I,
I was like,
don't you guys
die young?
And he was like,
yeah,
yeah.
Well,
and I was like,
I regretted it after I said it,
but I just,
it was a really legit question.
Like,
like you just,
you have a choice,
like there's enough research and with
internet and stuff,
you know now like you are,
you are really fucking yourself up.
It's so weird.
Yeah,
that's a tough gig.
You know,
any,
any guy that chooses to use his body for
any sport,
you know,
anything.
We try to Make a living just off your
body or like a ballerina athletic
environment or like fuck yourself.
how many,
how many guys get to be baryshnikov?
How many dudes are like,
I am going to be the next punished.
Meanwhile these bins are against
thousands of them and no one gives a
fuck.
It's like,
who's going to be the next lance
armstrong?
Guess what?
Nobody knows about that.
Go go into that fucking bike racing.
Trying to get famous were like,
hey asshole,
we don't need to ride bikes.
Okay.
I just got a cortisone shot in my hip.
I like running,
like I run,
run,
and I just,
all of a sudden my body was like,
no,
stop,
stop.
One second.
You know,
that's just a pain thing.
That's the.
You,
you're still injured.
Yeah,
I know.
I know because I started running again
for like three days.
I ran like,
like I used to and uh,
and it came,
the pain came back,
like I hadn't even gotten the shot and
then I haven't run since then.
So it's been,
it hasn't hurt me.
Were you having the paints in your ship?
Yeah.
Ran under the lake.
it's a muscle in my hip.
Oh,
it's a muscle in your short muscle.
Yeah.
I went and got x rays and a bit scary
shit.
I know people who have had hip
replacements.
That's fucking dark.
No,
the x rays looked totally fine,
But he was like,
do you want to shadow cortisone?
I was like,
okay.
And uh,
I was so excited that my hips didn't
hurt.
It still doesn't.
So I just,
it doesn't hurt now.
But,
uh,
when I was running again,
it did.
What if you have to get an iron hip?
That'd be crazy because I'm not getting
a hip replacement or a hip.
You know what they do?
they saw off the end of your bone where
your socket is.
They literally saw it off and then they
screw this fucking spike that goes deep,
deep,
like a foot into the bone with an
artificial.
I don't know if it's a foot.
It's about it.
My.
I didn't measure it.
Don't get crazy on the internet,
but they screw this fucking long pipe
into the bone and then it's an
artificial hip socket that's on the top
and sometimes it doesn't line up so
good.
Like one leg might be just slightly
bigger than the other leg because of it
and when you're walking you have this
little fucking hits to your stroke that
you'll never get away with.
Like you'll never walk normal for the
rest of your life unless you want them
to open you up and resize it again.
But I'm going to get out of here and
officials bomber and
that's just the,
you know,
they're going to be able to develop
artificial everything in the future.
They.
They made a titanium bone for a woman
who had some sort of bone cancer and she
lost her jaw and they created her a
titanium jaw and apparently it functions
just like the regular jaw that's better
than her old inserted in place.
It's slightly heavier than the old job
fuck is going on.
Oh,
that's actually a person's jaw that
they've all added a safe environment.
This is not a safe place.
You have somewhere.
You have to go,
don't you?
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
You made me laugh so hard.
It was super cool and I want you to do
it as many times as you can.
Whenever you're in town,
please call me and let's fucking do this
all.
Do you ever moved to la for real?
Brian has a whole network of these
podcasts called the data.
Whenever you want one,
we'll put you on immediately and when we
put you on immediately,
I'm telling you everything will change
everything,
which I'll fuck you.
Oh,
your clubs club dates will change.
Medical marijuana license.
We'll get.
We'll get you a card board.
Hilarious.
thank you very much.
Really,
really cool.
Having you on your.
Awesome.
See it panned out.
Ladies and gentlemen,
like I knew it would.
This podcast was brought to you by
flashlight.
The flashlight.
It is.
If you go to joe rogan.net,
click on the link for the flashlight and
entering the code name road.
You know the fucking drill.
Why don't have to say at the beginning
and the end,
maybe you tuned in halfway and he didn't
hear the first.
You Heard it.
I'm being rude.
I'm being rude,
and we were also brought to you by
[inaudible] dot com,
o n n I t.com.
Makers of alpha brain and read the code
name rogan.
Get yourself 10 percent off.
Try the shroom tech sport.
If you're an athlete,
shroom,
tech,
immune and the new mood.
A five hdp enhancement,
something that you shouldn't take if
you're on antidepressants.
All right,
we'd love your dirty bitches.
Will see as soon as we got a lot of
people coming up in the show.
Uh,
sam harris has coming up.
Be real from cypress hills coming up.
Greg fitzsimmons is coming up my power
from boston.
We started out together back in the day.
All right.
That's it by everybody.
We love you,
right?
See you soon.
He,
huh?
Huh?