Try My day,
Joe Rogan podcast by night all day.
People love both ways.
It's interesting like people love your
way,
but people also love like shit talking
[inaudible] people love Nate Diaz for
that.
And people love,
they love the drama,
but they also love someone like you walk
up to holly and hug her.
Yeah.
Middle though,
because I get a lot of flack for,
you know,
my mouth like,
so you just can't get it.
I say what I'm thinking and I'm,
I'm pretty transparent and sometimes
people think that,
you know,
I get a lot of flag,
oh,
you're fake or this.
And I'm like,
not really,
like,
just because,
you know,
I'm like,
I'll say this like I'm a fan of connor.
I am,
I like his fighting style.
And I,
I,
you know,
his antics at first were kind of like,
wait,
who is this guy?
What is it?
You know?
And then I'm like,
man,
props to him.
He's done amazing things like good for
him and he's done really good things for
our sport.
But when you didn't show up to film that
commercial,
like I'm not getting,
you know,
I'll be honest,
like yeah,
I kind of rubbed me the wrong way
because um,
people are like,
oh,
he does so much more media than you guys
do.
Yeah,
it probably does.
You know,
he probably does.
I do a lot.
He probably does more.
I agree.
But I don't have a private jet flying
out to pick me up and bring me back and
fly 20 people in my crew with me too.
He does more.
So he gets more when they bring them to
Vegas,
they put them up in a penthouse,
you know,
they make sure he has everything that he
needs.
I don't get that.
You don't know.
That's fine.
You know,
he's earned that.
He's in that spot.
No problem with that.
But I think three months out from a
fight camp,
you know,
you have a private jet coming to pick
you up with.
You can bring 20 of your teammates.
You could probably work out on the jet
if you want to on the way there because
it's yours,
it's private.
Do whatever you want.
Right.
You could probably hit mitts on a jet.
Yeah,
you could totally,
you know what I mean?
You're three months out and you don't
want to show for your media obligations.
Like I don't really understand that.
I don't like it just,
I don't know.
I guess I'm trying to figure it out,
but the only issue that I had and it,
it doesn't bother me.
Like if he didn't want to do it,
that's his own thing.
The thing is,
is that I showed up the day to film the
commercial and I had two segments I was
supposed to film and that's all it was
on my schedule.
And then they asked me like,
they were like,
can you please help us out because
Connor's not here and uh,
we don't know what we're doing for this
third segment of the commercial that was
supposed to be conor and nate.
So can you please come back later that
day and film that segment.
And also with that was during my
practice time,
so I had to come back and you know,
I did it.
So it was a company woman,
but like it was just frustrating because
it's like Dang,
you know,
if I had known about this,
I could've planned my training
otherwise,
but now I kind of have to like scramble
to get my second workout in and then it
affected me.
So yeah,
his decision did,
and it probably is actually,
you know,
I haven't made any more money in the
sport yet because of Connor.
A lot of people like to like,
oh you must have got a bigger payday.
Cause I'll ask them like,
no,
cause I wasn't the champion so I didn't
get any more of like and get any paper
views.
I didn't get any more money.
And now he's like not on this fight
card.
So I'm like,
you know,
but it's where ever,
it's,
it's connors deal and,
uh,
I,
I don't hate connor,
but I going to say how I feel,
you know?
And I would say it if he was sitting
here to be like,
dude,
why did you do that?
You'd probably,
well,
I,
I feel like there's a bunch of issues
here and we know,
and the only way to really get a firm
understanding of it is to sit down with
everyone involved and say what was
communicated your manager,
did he know what the,
what the appearance schedule was going
to be like,
did you guys agree to this?
Did you understand what you were getting
into when you're fighting?
Maybe it's a misunderstanding,
you know,
who knows?
It's hard to say,
but it's the way he went about it was
ridiculous.
Like saying,
I'm retired,
thanks for the cheese.
And then saying I'm not retired.
And then saying,
ah,
I'm glad the UFC decided to give the
fans what they want and be a,
I'm going to be on UFC 200 numbers.
Like what?
And so like what he's doing is he's kind
of like using the media to try to get
this thing to pass through,
but he doesn't understand Dana and
Lorenzo and frank,
like that's never going to work.
Like you're you,
you're either in or you're not in.
Right.
And they're like real clear about that.
They have to set a precedent.
So like if you say fuck you,
I'm not doing media.
And they kind of go,
oh well,
okay,
fuck you.
You're not fighting.
Yeah,
but hold on,
I'm conor mcgregor where the UFC,
yeah,
this is what it is.
Made my new stars.
They'll make many more.
Right.
And we might lose millions of dollars
because you're not on UFC 200
yeah,
well he,
he,
he had put,
they put 10 million ended up promoting
this Saturday tonight and he's like,
we're way over budget.
You know?
So that's why he's was like,
you've got to show up and do you know
that's how connor was made.
Yes.
It's true.
That stuff.
So now like at what point do you get to
decide that you don't have to do that
anymore?
Like if that's what made you who you are
like I mean don't you kind of have to
like,
does that make sense what I'm saying
here?
I mean at what point do you get to
decide like when you don't have to like
I use the machine and now like I don't,
I just want to hop off now that I'm
here,
you know,
and like,
I don't know.
So you kind of have to keep it the same
boys?
I think so.
But there,
there is also like a fine line,
right?
Like you can do too much.
Like when I was watching the Josie Aldo
media tour,
when they were going all around the
world,
I'm like,
okay,
I understand that you want to promote
this fight.
Yeah.
But how much of this is helping the
actual fight itself?
How much of it is just conor mcgregor
constantly talking Shit at press
conferences and grabbing the belt and
all that?
That,
I mean that's really kind of what
selling the fight was that,
I don't know.
I did a lot of it,
but apparently connor was sick.
Like he was like,
I'm just constantly fighting off a cold.
It's really hard to get in shape,
really hard to train because every week,
you know,
you're traveling from here to there and
there to here.
It's just,
you're constantly getting beaten down
and you know what it's like if I give
you up.
Have you ever flown to Brazil and
fought?
No.
I fall in there for fight cards though.
What is the,
um,
the furthest you've ever had a flight of
fight?
Japan.
So that's an interesting one.
Cause that's a long flight.
It's like 16 hours,
right?
Yeah.
What does it,
uh,
like,
like adjusting and then competing?
Um,
I try to start adjusting my schedule at
home,
like blacking out my windows a little
bit or you know,
like to,
to make the timeframe,
but you've never get fully adjusted.
But the,
my mind frame is like when,
when push comes to shove,
when fight time comes,
well that's two in the morning,
my time or not like I'm going to be,
so I would just look at it that way.
But it's not fun.
Like,
I remember three weeks out from my fight
with written to Chi,
which I didn't even want to,
I didn't want to do that fight because
she was so unknown.
She was undefeated.
I'm going over there to like fight on a
newly blooming fight pass.
And I was like,
this is like,
feels like it does nothing for me.
And like,
and if she wins it,
springboards her,
you know,
then she'll be 17 to know,
shove a judo background,
they're going to want to make that fight
for,
for her.
And Rhonda,
I know that's what they're trying to do
is they're trying to use,
you know,
business use me as that springboard and
was like I don't really want to spend,
I did it.
But three weeks before the fight they
had me fly to Japan to do some
promotional stuff and I was flying
longer than I was even on the ground.
And they said like ticket sales went up
and everything was really good.
But yeah,
that was exhausting.
So I do,
I understand that.
Yeah,
that's hard.
Really hard.
You're peaking right really hard.
Ramping it up three weeks
for hard.
And after my fight with the holly,
like I got to spend a little time in
Australia and then I went straight from
Australia to New York.
Spent a day there,
did a full day of media,
went to Connecticut to espn,
went to Toronto,
did a full day meeting.
And it's just like,
it's non stop from like you start your
first interview at eight in the morning,
so you'll pick up at like seven and you
go until seven at night and even while
you're driving to the next place they'll
have you on the phone.
Was with the,
with the,
you know,
with the radio interview,
I mean there's no break.
It's all,
it's,
it's pretty intense.
It's pretty crazy.
It's pretty exhausting site.
I get it.
And I have been in those shoes before,
but um,
you know,
it's,
I don't know,
maybe there's more extended research.
Maybe he was hurt or something.
Maybe you didn't want people to see like
maybe,
I don't know.
Like what if there's even something like
that.
Like,
what if he had like hurt himself or
something and he didn't want like nate
to know.
Yeah.
Who knows?
I Dunno.
And it's also,
he also had to realize there was a lot
of work that needed to be done to beat
nate.
Yeah.
Like he's hit nate with some of his best
shots and nate was fine with it and it
was a real problem.
That's more what it was,
is that he was just obsessed with
beating nay.
And I,
I get that too.
I don't take that away from him for a
minute.
Like he wanted to stay home and he was
in Iceland I guess training and he wants
to train to be nate.
I get it.
Totally get it.
Yeah,
I get it too.
It seems like the only way also I felt
like,
but then again he could have brought his
whole gym with him,
you know,
I mean it was going to be a difficult
time just trying to find,
uh,
the,
the moments to train and do,
stay in shape and then obviously being
exhausted from flying and all that jazz
quick turnaround too.
You know,
like as far as like,
I don't think he was supposed to be
there more than like two days.
I honestly think he's better off not
doing it.
I honestly think he's better off like
sequestering himself for a few months.
Like really focusing on what went wrong,
how to correct it and can you correct
it?
Yeah.
I mean do you like when it comes to the
ground game,
what I saw on the ground,
I was like,
boy this is a long road.
Like you've got a long road to beat.
A guy like nate,
he's so much further along in,
in,
in ground and pound Jujitsu,
positioning everything.
When I was watching nate beat him up on
the ground and choke him,
I was like,
Whoa,
that happened quick.
This is not like a,
like Weidman and rockhold was a
prolonged beating before rockhold
eventually stopped him the next round.
Yeah.
But with why with nate and connor wasn't
that prolonged.
It happened pretty quickly.
And when you see that you go,
Ooh,
like this is going to be,
this is a lot to overcome.
It's not an unsurmountable build that
those skill sets,
they don't just,
they don't come overnight.
You don't,
he can pick up your cardio pretty quick.
You can do a lot of things.
We can't,
you can't build a skill set any faster
than it's going to go into your muscle
memory and being your effort.
You've got to put thousands of reps in
and there's no way around it.
There's no way.
There's no way to fast forward through
that.
There's no way to cut the corner.
There's no,
there's nothing.
You can't just repetition,
repetition,
repetition would also,
it highlights all the various eccentric
aspects of your training that people are
like,
hmm,
is this what makes connor great?
And you know,
and then you know nate calling it touch
button,
the park,
like they do it,
all these cartwheels and stuff.
Then video is so funny.
Hilarious.
My God I was dying laughing areas.
So when this all,
you know he's doing all these,
this work with this movement guy.
But then you see what happens when it
actually comes to fighting skills and
you go oh maybe this is not the way to
do it.
Cause like I've talked to a lot of
people that were like this stuff that
he's doing his utter horse shit like
this,
doing cartwheels and being obsessed with
movement.
Here's the movements you need to be
worried about.
Okay,
moving your feet,
throwing kicks and punches,
take down defense and Jujitsu on the
ground.
That's it.
You know,
understanding takedowns yourself,
taking people down if you must trip
sweeps,
all that stuff.
But all this cartwheels and what this
guy was explaining to me and I want to
name any names cause he's a prominent
guy,
he was like you have to understand that
there's a limited amount of energy you
have in your time training and you are
not perfect at all these other aspects
of mma.
So if you are not perfect,
all these other aspects of him that you
have to say,
okay how much?
Yeah,
how much of this stuff is going to help
me?
Well a guy like George Saint Pierre,
he looked at gymnastics and he was like,
you know what's going to help me if I
can be stronger physically and there's
no better way.
I think like as far as like manipulating
your body.
Then gymnastics,
like doing the rings and developing.
Yeah.
You're learning how to manipulate your
body and all kinds of contorted
positions.
Being upside down and understanding
where you are.
When you're upside down,
you're going to be with the momentum you
have.
You have to calculate that your math is
doing constant algorithms and math
equations.
Essentially.
When you're fighting to weight
distribution,
where are we at?
Especially when you tie up with someone
else,
then you have to feel their weight and
you have to manipulate it in a way to
get it where you want.
Whether it's against the cage or whether
it's on the ground.
Your body is using
a equation.
Yeah.
You know,
your mind is equating,
how much force do I need to make this
happen?
How little force?
Like what if I go the opposite direction
because they're pushing into me.
There's all these different things that
you have to over.
There's no other way to do it then than
a trial and error process and over and
over and over and over again.
Yeah.
Look at someone who's like really good
at one aspect of it.
I may like Yoel Romero who's just a
ridiculous wrestler and you go,
okay,
look how much touch button the park.
Is that guy doing?
You know,
how many cartwheels is he doing?
Is he tumbling?
No,
but I bet you he does a hundred double
eggs a day.
Oh yeah,
it'll least,
well he's doing all kinds of eggs and
then a hundred body locks.
Then you know,
connor lost,
everybody was like,
this is what we need.
We need a movement coach.
I need a movement coach.
You know,
and it still might,
I mean as we said with George Saint
Pierre,
it,
it has massive benefits to get that kind
of coordination.
Physical strength.
Do you like about connor though is like,
um,
his balance is impeccable and that could
be part of that.
And like he's never over himself,
at least with the striking part of it.
And you know,
the ground is a completely different
thing,
but when he's in striking range in his,
just his body,
his eye hand coordination is incredible.
And his balance.
Like he's never too far over a punch.
He's never too far back.
He's always centered,
is always centered.
He throws a kick,
he never gets,
you know,
you see people kick and they miss and
they kind of like stumble like their
weights off balance or,
or they kick and even land and even when
they put their foot down,
it's kind of like,
it's not a good landing.
You know,
like I,
I'm not like the world's best kicker,
but when I watched conor do it,
it's like he kicks or push kicks and
sticks it.
He is like,
uh,
like a a gymnast in the sense,
you know,
they do those flip and then they want to
just boom,
stick it like,
and he's really,
really good at that.
Maybe that's where the movement does
benefit,
I think.
So that he never is over himself and his
weight distribution,
isn't it the case that whenever someone
loses though everyone always second
guesses what they were doing.
Even if what they were doing was getting
them to be like 16 to know.
Totally undefeated world champion.
When you'd make a mistake or something
goes wrong or something goes right for
your opponent,
we should probably say immediately
people start questioning everything you
did.
Yeah,
definitely.
All the time it happened with me even,
you know,
when I lost to Toronto,
that guy,
you got to change this,
you gotta change everything.
But as long as you're winning people
like,
yeah,
keep doing what you're doing,
it's working.
And then he lose and like change
everything.
It's like,
Geez,
that was quick.
It's
also the Rhonda criticism in the Holly
Holm fight.
Everybody was like looking at her like a
dominating vechicle.
Heyo would stand up.
You know,
I'm beating Sarah McMahon the way she
did.
Alexis Davis beating her down the way
she did and go,
well look,
Rhonda obviously is getting so good at
striking.
She's just such an elite athlete that
she can do what she's doing to anybody.
And then her trainer saying that she
could go box women professionals and
knock them out.
And so you get this thing in your head
that you can do,
you have been doing.
Yeah.
And then you fight someone like holly
and you go,
Oh,
well,
okay,
yeah.
This is where there's,
so,
there's so many levels.
I mean,
it's one of the more fascinating things
about martial arts is that there are so
many levels.
Yeah.
There's never,
it's never ending.
Never ending story really is,
right.
Yeah.
[inaudible] okay.