Boom.
We're alive.
Fresh from the trenches.
Joe Schilling in the motherfucking
house.
It's up.
Joe.
How are you brother?
I'm doing,
I'm doing pretty well.
He chatting with people.
Are you doing let snapchat then the kids
had a snapchat you to the world,
these wacky kids and their snapchat.
I tried snapchat the other day cause my
little daughter loves it.
God Damn,
Dude.
All my names are taken.
My name's taken powerful.
Jrs taken Joe Rogan experience has taken
everything.
He's fucking creeps.
That's so weird.
Give it up.
You freaks.
Give my name back where those,
yeah.
Well we gotta do,
I was late to the game.
What is the big deal with snapchat?
Why is everybody like that?
Uh,
I don't know.
That's a,
it's really blown up lately.
When it first came out years ago,
it was like,
I had a little different connotation to
it.
It was like,
you know,
the pictures deleted in like five
seconds.
It was like,
you're sexting APP.
Yeah.
Fucking Dick Pics and shit.
But uh,
but nobody deletes those.
They just make a screenshot.
Yeah.
They,
it'll tell you,
hey,
he's just screenshot to dude.
You're a stuff.
They're like,
no,
that's that horrible feeling in the
bottom of your gut.
No,
I don't know.
You've got problems with your sending
Dick pics anyway.
Understand the less the girl wants dead
pecs and then you've got to send them,
I guess.
Yeah.
I don't know.
If you talk to people that are in the
Dick pic game,
that's how you got to send pictures to
get pictures.
Uh,
cause girls feel vulnerable.
If they're just telling you,
sending you pictures,
they're posting and you're not sending
anything back.
They feel like this mother fucker has me
here.
This is bullshit.
There's no trust in this relationship.
Even if they don't want them,
they just want a picture.
You know,
sometimes you gotta be vulnerable for
these girls,
allegedly.
One of my next part,
this is where we're starting Dick pics.
What was it?
There's no rhyme or reason to any of
these damn damn thing,
you know?
So,
uh,
like I said,
definitely Joe Rogan's Dick pic game is
very strong.
It's still is shaky.
It's all over the road.
But my fucking phone,
I give my phone to my six year old.
It's filled with snapchat,
pictures of her face,
switching in with Kimbo slices,
face all the pictures I have on my
phone.
She goes through all my photos and finds
pictures that she wants us swap faces
with kids,
these wacky kids these days.
So,
uh,
like I said,
man,
fresh out of the trenches,
man.
You A,
you had a crazy war.
No.
Yeah,
this weekend.
That was wild.
Yeah,
man,
that was a,
that was something wasn't it?
It was fucking something,
something that was for sure.
Like we were saying before the podcast
started you,
you were really fighting emotional.
You were,
you were worked up,
you know,
you'd already fought him before and you
know,
you wanted to get back at him.
And it was,
uh,
it was kind of obvious in a way.
You were fighting.
You were,
you were really putting a lot of
pressure on him.
Yeah.
I didn't really feel that way at the
time.
They said I wasn't aware of it.
You know what I mean?
I was just in there doing me and uh,
yeah,
there's a lot of pressure,
a lot of,
you know,
it was,
um,
yeah,
I'm wondering,
I wanted to,
I want to knock them out.
I want to do,
I set things right.
I think,
uh,
being the,
told and,
and kind of carried as the face of a
belts or kickboxing and there's a lot of
pressure on my shoulders at night and a
lot of,
uh,
you know,
one of,
one of the big shot and I wanted to make
an exciting fight and I think I did
that,
you know,
definitely did that kill or be killed
like you know,
and for Spike TV's perspective,
I'm sure we killed it on the ratings.
And my job was to carry the ratings
because I was white.
I was the first fight from the,
uh,
the main card and uh,
he said it was a never a boring moment,
you know,
it wasn't boring.
It was fucking wild.
Um,
is that,
does that,
that's a weird like fine line.
You have to cross some sometimes between
like,
which I should ask you when,
how do you make the distinction of
whether or not you should fight smart or
fight exciting?
Do you make that distinction or do you
just go,
can't stop crazy and fucking charge at
it?
I mean,
yeah,
I,
uh,
I guess there was like a tournament in
other,
it'd be more,
more,
uh,
pressure to,
to fight a little smarter or whatever.
But,
you know,
I,
I take pride in the way that I fight and
I'm,
I think that,
uh,
when you turn on a fight,
you want to see a guy like me.
You know what I mean?
Guys that complain about,
uh,
you know,
people that make boring fights and score
points,
floyd mayweather.
You know what I mean?
I want to see the,
uh,
I want to see somebody.
If I like me,
I want to see a worrier.
Go out there and put it all on one line
and go out on the shield.
Yeah.
That's,
uh,
that's something that promoters always
hope that a guy fights like that.
They always hope that a guy goes out
there charging out guns blazing,
you know?
But most people don't.
Yeah.
Well I mean
hindsight,
it didn't work out that all of a sudden.
But uh,
you know,
it has worked out in the past a lot more
often than that.
You know,
there's a lot of people on the Internet.
Oh,
fucking Internet these days right now.
Vertel you didn't get online after the
fight.
Did you try to stay off for awhile?
It's just a,
it's hard to stay offline too,
so it's a little hard to see if,
uh,
is there anything I could get out of it?
Nope.
Well you could get a lot of technique
advice from keyboard warriors.
I'm sure they have some,
a strategy advice for you.
Yeah.
Everybody has everybody.
Uh,
everybody is an expert,
you know?
Yeah,
everybody's an expert.
But you know,
that's just the thing.
It's one of those things where people
don't really earn their opinion or their
right to express her opinion.
Everybody just has one.
Now they have an avenue to express.
So you have to separate,
what does that expression,
the wheat from the shaft?
Is that what it is?
I've never figured out what the fuck
chef is.
Hmm.
You know what that is?
I talked to Vinnie the day after the
shoreman vinny shoreman and uh,
he had ever made a really good point
about it.
I was like,
God,
these fucking guys online,
like,
he's like,
it's easy to say like ignore him.
It's easy to say,
you know that,
sorry,
some jerk off kid in their parents'
basement.
But I'm not personally religious,
but you know,
he used it as an example.
He's like,
you know,
Jesus Christ was
like the greatest person ever.
Right?
Like the greatest,
you know,
water into wine,
heal the sick,
give mine all that shit.
The people still killed him,
you know,
make,
it doesn't matter how good you are,
what you do,
there's always going to be some fucking
asshole who talk shit and does,
you know what I mean?
And that was a interesting little
perspective that seemed to work out for
me.
Like,
who cares what these people think?
It doesn't matter what you do,
they're going to fucking hate you.
If everyone was perfect,
he wouldn't appreciate perfect people.
If everybody was awesome and really cool
and easy to talk to and friendly and
like you wouldn't,
it's not going to happen.
It's too hard.
It's too hard to have your shit together
and there's too many variables that have
to happen in your childhood.
I think.
You know,
like everything either has to go really
good or really bad.
What you appreciate,
things that are really good so you'd
gravitate towards that.
It's one or the other,
but it's just human beings.
Just a project with no directions.
It's like we're a super complicated
computer and no one has a fucking
guidebook.
No one knows exactly how to work it.
No one knows exactly what's the end.
Everything's happening in real time.
And the words you say they,
especially when you say something
online,
like you might just be in a crazy mood
and you know,
you might just,
uh,
you just tweet at Jamie,
Hey Jamie,
how about you go fuck yourself.
You fucking piece of shit for no reason.
You might just want to get a reaction
that please don't do that to Jamie
folks.
But you know,
people do stuff like that and they don't
even know why they're doing it.
They just,
they're doing it to get a reaction or
they doing it because they're upset and
they're like,
why is this fucking Joe Schilling guy on
tv,
this piece of shit?
Fuck you.
Excuse us.
Miserable people.
But if they met you,
they'd be like,
hey man,
a big fan of sure.
Uber for sure.
They call you fight your real voice.
I'll get like a message.
Like I said,
I was,
I was in a bad mood.
I said something really bad about you a
couple of months ago online.
I'm really sorry.
Can you unblock me now?
I'm like,
no,
you're a fucking asshole.
Yeah,
real fucking asshole.
You live by the sword,
die by the sword kids and said if you
get blocked,
he stay blocked.
Zero tolerance policy.
Zero tolerance.
Got to be a real piece of shit to get
blocked.
And even if you're a real piece of shit,
one day you might snap out of it,
but you're going to have to change your
twitter name.
You'd have to start fresh.
Yeah,
it's a new,
you think about it that way.
You're a neutral.
But I think you know,
if someone is upset at you because they
don't like,
you know,
a painting that you did or they don't
like a song that you made,
that's one thing.
But a fight is so emotional and so
personal and it's so the consequences
are,
it's so much different than any other
endeavor.
Even if you lose a game,
Lebron James,
you fucking suck.
There's two.
It's just the game.
The ball didn't go in the net.
Who gives a fuck?
You know,
in a fight it's salt.
It's the highest consequences possible.
It's,
there's no higher consequences other
than war.
There's no higher consequences as far as
like how it feels to lose or what it
feels like to,
to hear people talk shit about you,
about your performance.
It's just that,
and that's one of the reasons why they
do it.
Like they know.
I know it sucks.
And they know it's not them.
I have a theory about that,
man.
I think one of the reasons why people
attack people,
like when,
when something goes wrong in their life,
like a charlie sheen thing or something
like that is that they,
they know that that could happen to
them,
but it's not happening to them right
now.
So they feel like,
well fuck him,
then go after him.
You know,
they have this,
they,
this vault,
they understand that they would be
equally vulnerable and they feel that
that little opening and they just dead.
It can't help it.
It's like a fucking scab.
They count,
they want to pick at it.
Eh,
that's interesting.
I just think they're just pieces of shit
that to me just do this a fucking piece
of shit.
And they're just haters.
Like you're just,
you've never done anything with your
life.
You know,
you're not willing to take those risks.
And then when you see somebody else
taking those risks and then it doesn't
work out,
they're like,
oh,
fucking told you.
So,
you know,
they just,
did you ever send people and they're
just sad and miserable people?
Definitely,
yeah.
This death thing,
that's definitely true.
Did you ever see that Hbo a,
was it 24,
seven with floyd mayweather while he's
eating a cheeseburger with friend and
some guy,
uh,
some fucking fat doughy cunt is a
yelling at him.
How he's afraid to fight Manny Pacquiao
like you're talking to arguably the best
boxer that's ever lived,
ever.
Pretty.
Pretty arguable.
They pretty,
pretty good argument.
49 and oh,
but really it's only been rocked maybe
twice in his whole fucking career.
You might think of styles boring,
but the fucking guy has done it.
I mean he just did it and he's talking
to some dough,
a shithead,
some flapping jod dumb cunt who's giving
him a hard time about fighting manny
Pacquiao,
who he then went and shut out a couple
months later.
Yeah,
but it's those people that aren't doing
anything,
those are the ones that are going to
yell something like that out.
Those people that they,
they don't,
they don't have anything to gain or to
lose.
And like I bought the mini Petco,
take a box of paper view of that same
fat daily piece of Shabba bought the
paper view and as a flood mayweather fan
and probably about the tmt tee shirt and
hat and rocks is tap out fucking shit.
You know,
same guy.
Yeah,
he probably has it on a loop on
facebook.
Him,
he tells everybody.
Did you see that 24 seven I was on,
did you see that Shit fucking called
them all?
Yo,
I called him out fucking let me.
Well Floyd would slap him in the mouth
to make them drink as pes.
Yeah.
Wait,
now we just gave him another moment.
Hello off.
Off.
There you go.
It's not going to listen to your
attention buddy.
Have Internet connection.
He doesn't pay his bill.
But I think that that's just,
you know,
there's this,
this broad range of people.
There's going to be winners and it's
going to be losers and there's going to
be people to take risks is going to be
people that don't ever take risks and
they just,
they live their life.
This sad,
muted except experience with no risks,
no fun and no rewards.
They just never,
they never get to shine,
you know,
and a guy like,
I mean you fucking take some big ask
risks with your life and you have some
big shining moments,
you know,
like the,
the fourth round Kale of Simon Marcus,
you know,
like you don't get those moments and
less,
sometimes those moments are turned on
you.
It's just,
there's no other way.
Like the way you do it.
There's no other way.
I mean,
sometimes you're the hammer,
sometimes you're the nail.
I am proud as hell of,
you know what I mean?
Like having this conversation like two
or three days ago of it wouldn't been a
little rough conversation,
but now I'm like looking at it like I'm
going to be remembered as that guy that
always brought it up and you're not
going to on my name is going to go down
when I'm dead and gone.
They're going to remember what I've done
for the sport of kickboxing and I didn't
take a lot of pride in that.
And when you turn on the Joe Schilling
fight,
kill or be killed,
like I'm,
I'm going to fucking try and knock his
head off and I'm going to get caught
again in the future and I'm going to
have some huge fucking ups and I'm okay
with that.
And uh,
you know,
I've been knocked out three times.
I wasn't knocked out cold in this fight
and it was unconscious.
Even for a second.
They just stopped the fight.
I've been knocked out three times.
The number 95 fights.
I've done more than I ever dreamed I
would in the sport.
That's a lot of fucking fight.
And my kids are super proud of their
dad's a superhero.
My mom is super proud.
Those what I've done.
Um,
I'm okay with that.
That's a great attitude.
And if you have that attitude and you
know,
you press forward with that attitude,
you know,
I know that you don't like losing,
but if you can deal with it,
it makes all the other stuff so much
easier because you can get right back on
the horse,
you know,
and you've done that already.
You have the experience of getting back
on the horse.
I mean,
I got hit by a shot and got drops in the
fight,
got stopped.
I've had knee surgeries arose out for a
year and had to come back from it.
And I've had a,
you know,
really,
really hard things to overcome and I
don't plan on,
I'm not a good loser and I don't play
them on ever becoming a good one.
You know,
you show me a good loser,
I'll show you a loser.
Now the,
the fight,
I mean he,
he hit you with a,
a beautiful spinning back fist,
but it's not,
it wasn't necessarily like legal,
right,
because he hit you with a forearm.
Like what does it Bella to our rules.
You can't throw elbows,
you can't throw forums is,
that's,
isn't that kind of weird because you
could fucking Shin kick someone in the
head.
Yeah.
Well,
I think it's,
it's uh,
I s k rule is the,
was the ruling body that does the for
both blower glory and for a belter and
the rules,
meaning that talk about,
you know,
you can,
you can clinch and knee,
but it has to be active.
And if you are active and you were
effective in the let it go for five
seconds.
If you're holding it all,
if you're just clenching to hold,
they want to be the five seconds,
they'll break it.
It's one of the rules they explained.
Uh,
you know,
when you throw spending back fist,
it has to be the glove.
They hit you or they stick,
they start taking a point where you
start warning cause it's a illegal shot.
Now I was a professional muy Thai
fighter of elbows and everything else.
So I'm never gonna say that,
you know.
Um,
did he plan on throwing that spinning
back fists?
I don't think so.
Did he have a fucking clue where he was
when he threw it?
And I'm not really,
I'm pretty sure it was rock.
There was no fucking fucking threw it
and hit me with it.
And you know that shit happens.
But is it,
was that technically illegal shot?
No,
but you know I'm not going to get
tested.
Yeah.
It's,
it kind of should be illegal though,
right?
I mean don't you think if you can hit
someone with your Shin,
you should be able to hit someone with
your forearm.
I mean,
I don't like these.
I agree with that.
Yeah.
I don't like these rules.
I don't,
I think they,
they came up with these rules for k one
k one had this idea like used to be no
back spinning back fist.
If you watched the old kid one fights
one the only rule they like say come out
and touch clothes,
come out and swinging or whatever.
And I was like no,
spinning back fist.
That's so crazy.
Cause he always from spinning backwards
but we could throw a wheel kicks.
Yeah.
That doesn't make any cat.
You know the rule set is I believe
designed for a certain style of fighter
or entertainment.
Same thing with the clinch.
Yeah.
So that's the,
those are the rules that they want.
Yeah.
They're not big on elbows in Japan
because pride didn't allow elbows
either,
which is crazy cause they allowed stomps
and soccer kicks but they didn't allow
elbows on the ground.
So k one came up with that rule set.
And the idea behind it I guess was to
make the fights more entertaining
because you wouldn't be able to clinch
and you would have to,
you'd be forced to fight it out,
right?
Yeah,
exactly.
What came did was pretty God damn
amazing.
I mean they really took this sport that,
and I think you know Dana white had a
really good point.
We were talking about this once when I
was trying to get him to buy k one and I
was like look man,
these guys they're going under like he
got like kickboxing,
like this high level kickbox and whether
its glory or it's showtime or any of
these big organizations.
When you look at the like the high level
talent and kickboxing,
that to me is some of the most exciting
shit to watch and all combat sports.
When I watch a fight,
like,
like your fight this past weekend or
like you're the tournament or the Simon
Marcus fight or you fight with
[inaudible].
These are crazy chaotic fights.
I mean that's what people love,
I think potentially the most about mma.
Obviously,
you know,
I'm a big fan of Jujitsu as well and I
love when fights go to the ground and I
love when guys win by submission.
But man,
I mean you want to talk about just pure
excitement.
Kickboxing is one of the most exciting
sports on the planet.
But Dana White's point was it got fucked
in America by that Goddamn PKA karate
that used to be on espn where you would
watch these guys throw these bullshit
ass fake kicks where they had to get in
like x amount of kicks per round.
So they would like throw these flippy
fake stupid kicks and then they would
have just really shitty sloppy boxing
and oh man,
there's some really good fucking boxers
though.
There was,
I think the reason they like it started
from like,
uh,
he was like,
what the seventies eighties.
It was when you were martial arts was
like the thing is Kung Fu Billy Jack
and,
and Shit,
you know.
Well they had some Rick Rufus,
rufus was a bad motherfucker.
Alex lessio was yeah.
Fucker.
Oh yeah.
Um,
there was some,
you know Don the Dragon Wilson was a bad
motherfucker.
Yeah.
But so they had these,
there's karate guys and there are other
martial arts guys general and they're
building this,
trying to make this is full thing.
And there was all these boxes that were
going there and just beating the fuck
out of everybody's,
they're like,
okay,
okay.
Okay.
You have to throw seven kicks before you
can feel you have to throw seven kicks
per round.
Just even keep it from turning into just
straight boxing matches and you watch
them in,
they'll go out there and the big one,
two,
three,
four,
five,
six,
seven.
Why,
why,
why?
I mean they're bad mother fucking boxes.
So like there was some really good,
um,
uh,
some really good guys.
There were some really good guys back
then.
It did go overseas and competed,
you know,
worldwide.
Yeah.
There was somebody,
yeah.
But there was also a lot of like sloppy
shit.
Oh,
it was a lot of sloppy shit too.
But if you look at the level that you're
seeing now today in high level
kickboxing in comparison to them,
like the Nikki holds skins and a,
you know,
Joel Valine Fellini and the Raymond
Daniels and you,
and it's no,
no comparison.
The level is so high today.
It's much higher today and I feel like
the public,
it's just for whatever reason,
they haven't tuned into it yet.
To me it's like the most exciting thing
that most people don't know about.
I mean,
did you watch the might might've been,
yeah,
I did like that.
I thought that that was an interesting
way to do it.
Have a cage in a ring right by each
other.
Yeah,
the,
the set up of the ring in the cages.
You know,
coker really likes it be for the fans
that are there that they can watch both
at the same time.
You know,
I think the seating arrangements get
weird or not,
but from a marketing perspective,
to get what exactly we were talking
about America,
to pay attention to kickboxing so that
we can build this sport.
You got all these people that tuned in
to watch rampage.
Yeah.
Matriarchs for his fight.
You got people that weren't wanting to
watch the,
uh,
the title fight that was going on.
All of those in [inaudible],
Michael Chandler,
Chandler's fight.
Awesome.
Oh man,
dude,
he looked Felix smoking.
Um,
all of those people that tuned in,
Bella terra showed high level
kickboxing.
You know what I mean?
Like that's,
that's a,
a genius way to market it and to get it
out there.
And then,
um,
you know,
I was the first flight on the kickboxing
cards to try to keep those fans,
those ratings going or whatnot.
And your boy,
Kevin Ross look sensational to great
look.
Fucking great.
Yeah,
it's a,
it's Kerri Melendez.
Carrie mullins has fight was fucking
awesome.
Absolutely.
I'm excited to bell towards doing it.
I'm excited.
Spike TV's doing it.
I'm excited that they're putting on
kickboxing.
I just,
uh,
I just wonder what's,
what's missing?
Like you know,
the UFC needed the ultimate fighter
before the ultimate fighter.
Nobody,
nobody had a fucking clue as to what MMA
was.
They really didn't know.
It was just a few people that hurting
UFC from the old days and the hoists
gracie days and the vast majority of the
public was kind of out of the loop and
then they put on the ultimate fighter
and you know,
it was sort of the,
the prime of reality tv back then and
that fight between forrest griffin and
Stephan Bonner,
which was such a wild ass fight that
sort of made mma.
I mean it really did.
It made the UFC and ballot or needs
something like that they need,
what if those two played it safe that
night?
It's a good point.
What would we be here,
Joe?
It's a good point.
Where would we be jobs?
Good point.
I'd probably be in Texas now doing stand
up.
Yeah.
I probably would have never worked for
the,
you probably would have went under.
Yeah,
man.
I mean keyboard warriors were telling
forrest griffin how sloppy he looked at
night and Stephan Bonner was,
it showed or whenever the fuck they
would say,
you know,
what does a chode does anybody know
know?
Is that a real thing?
Um,
you know what they like to call people
today?
I've known as a cook.
I cook a cock.
That's a big thing.
I said,
well,
you know what it is.
It's like the kids on the unit that have
found a new insult.
It was like cock has only been around
for like,
yeah,
okay.
See You k.
Yeah,
well it comes from a cuckold which is
like a guy who likes watching his wife
get fucked by other men,
usually manlier men and uh,
how the correct term,
Joey,
how do you know that?
I'm online.
I frequented the Internet starts to cut,
cut,
cut.
Cold.
Right.
Am I correct me if I'm wrong,
Jamie,
but I believe that's what it's about.
You know,
who would know of wish Jim Norton was
here.
He could explain this to us in its
entirety,
but there is a whole genre of porn based
her on around like really nerdy white
guys who have like this smoking hot wife
that's not satisfied.
And some guys like shut the fuck up and
sit down.
I'm gonna fuck your wife in front of
you.
Oh No.
And they cry and some of them they made
the,
they make the husband suck their dick.
That happens too.
Well yeah that's a cook.
Now the husband is stuck state cause the
cook comes in as much of,
that guy's a stud guy who comes in and
smashes it.
But I don't know if she's just stud.
If he lets the guy suck his deck,
that's just weird.
That's where it goes deep.
You know there's like a spectrum.
Even at cock porn keeping cock porn has
a,
there's a lot of variables they have to
take into consideration.
But I see people calling people cox all
the time.
Like when they're,
you know,
you're calling another man at cook.
Yeah.
As an insult.
What does that say about you and the
porn that you watched it,
you know,
that is,
that just says you frequent like reddit
or something or you're on twitter all
the time.
I mean,
I don't think it says anything about it.
I just think it's a new thing to call
someone to hurt their feelings.
You know,
like there's no other,
there's no equivalent word.
Like it's a new,
it's a new sort of like a classification
of someone to call someone to cook.
You fucking cook.
Yeah.
You cock well On.
I'm just,
I have to start calling people that
don't do it.
If we just promoted it to the world is
now kind of thing before it now it's
going to be fucking Holy Shit.
No,
they've been doing it forever.
They're going to call people like
Hashtag powerful cook.
Oh,
you just started something now.
Man just made a big mistake.
You know when I noticed it a lot when a
Kurt Kurt Metzger,
Ooh,
he's a writer for Amy Schumer show.
He's funny.
Standup comedian.
Very funny guy.
And,
uh,
he was one of the writers for Amy
Schumer's show when she was getting
accused of plagiarism and all this stuff
was going on and I was seeing all these
people calling them a cook.
And I was like,
what is this?
And then I noticed it was like
everywhere.
People call people cooks.
Like everyone's a cook.
Cook.
It's a just a phase.
I hope so.
There you go.
So if someone calls you a cook now,
you know,
I'd be like,
what am I a chicken?
Fuck is that I don't get it.
Cluck.
Now I will get it.
Yeah,
the Internet.
I don't know all of my,
all the haters.
Now we're going to,
could we call me a cook?
You think?
I don't think it'll work.
It doesn't work if you don't like
actually watching your wife get gorilla
fucked by some greater.
First of all,
you got to find a dude.
Fuck your wife day.
You can't kick his ass.
That's not,
it's not like a regular guy,
Joe Schilling.
So this is a different sort of scenario.
A real caucus.
Supposed to be like a feeble person who
lets,
I'm a fucking Lawrence Taylor type dude.
Come into his bedroom and fuck the shit
out of his little white wife.
Uh,
there's visual for it.
Yeah.
There you go.
That kind of a thing.
You know,
let's Tuck won't work on me.
I'm not,
but they'll try it on you anyway.
It's a,
I mean,
I wonder if we've run out of insults.
I mean it's just cause it's coq one that
using it so often,
even when it's not,
it's not really applicable and they're
doing it because it's a new one.
Like we got a new one just like,
it's not like this makes sense.
Let me call him a faggot.
This makes sense.
Let me call him a pussy.
No,
it's like we've got this world,
it's just throw it around until,
it's almost like they found a new word
and they just throw in and around until
it's useless and we're promoting it or
were they useless quick right now,
which just reporters here.
Joe Schilling was just talking about the
world.
You and I are,
we're essentially journalists.
Yeah.
We're current events journalists,
we're trying and might,
there might be some old folks right now
that it may be,
you know,
not in the same social groups is us.
Maybe they live in Iowa or something
like that.
And uh,
they just trying to dip their toe into
the rest of the world.
Like what,
what are these kids talking about these
days?
Let me see.
A what a comedian and a kickboxer have
to say about the world.
And then they find out about Cox and
then,
uh,
you know,
their wife later is going through their
google search.
She finds cock,
what the hell is it called?
Fuck is a cook.
And then she starts looking up cook and
she finds Kuk porn and that she gets
excited and she thinks my man wants,
I'll God,
Oh fuck me in front of him.
I know what I'm gonna do.
I'm gonna set some shit up.
And then she,
uh,
goes on craigslist,
find some dude and she thinks she's
fulfilling a fantasy.
Try Spice up the relationship and
suicide,
murder,
suicide man.
Suicide probably,
right?
Yeah.
It's hard to come back from that one.
Depends on how far in that far out in
the sticks we're talking about.
Yeah.
I think now with the Internet,
I don't think there really is a sticks
anymore.
I think even in the sticks,
they still get all the data.
If you have a connection to the internet
and you can research stuff,
all the weirdness of the world will find
its way into your brain.
There's no hiding anymore.
You can't hide from the cooks anymore.
Yeah.
It used to be like you could live in
like some weird town in Kentucky and you
would never find out about the,
the golf people or the furries or any of
the weird shit out there.
But now you find out,
cause play the fuck's gonna find out
about cause play in West Virginia,
you know,
to fuck his play.
We don't know what that is.
What planet am I on them too busy train,
know anything about this shit.
Too busy hanging out in downtown La
represent and d t la son.
That's so our buddy magnus walker lives
the uh,
Porsche guy.
You ever seen his videos drives all
around downtown La and classic
Porsche's.
He was actually right.
His spot,
his loft or whatever is right next to
where the first location of the yard.
My Gym.
I was running real.
No Shit.
So you're in the heart of it man.
What do you like about downtown La?
Um,
right now I like it cause it's,
it's uh,
it's close to the gym and uh,
it's close to my kid's house and it's,
it's convenient.
It's close to Hollywood.
It's like 15 minutes from Hollywood.
It's,
it's kind of right in the middle of
everything.
Yeah,
it's funky too.
Now it's downtown La is kind of
morphing,
right?
Yeah,
it's getting,
it's getting different.
They used to be like a very art,
you know,
art arts,
like arts district and like younger
crowds,
not,
not too expensive now it's like super
high end expensive,
like the property on this blowing up.
It's crazy how it's blowing up.
We were actually a listed on a place to
do down there though.
Like there's like five bars downtown.
That's it.
Yeah.
It's not like,
I don't know.
I don't really enjoy it for like
nightlife stuff,
some nice restaurants and know what it
is.
I think people are craving something
like that and they,
and they,
they see something happen.
Like it's happening,
it's happening,
it's happening right here.
Let's,
let's start building those type buying
up.
And they're hoping that it becomes like
a New York,
you know,
cause de la doesn't have,
doesn't have one.
No,
it doesn't have like a place where
anybody walks.
Yup.
Well La is like people say live in La
but you live in burbank or Glenn Miller.
There's like 50 cities that have about
this big of downtown as downtown La.
So yeah,
it's like La County.
If you live in La county,
you live in la,
but la itself,
La proper,
it's,
there's no way to walk.
It was like melrose street could kind of
walk on melrose.
Good luck.
Cross one of those streets people
fucking run you over while the texting,
doing meth.
You know,
there's some cool spots downtown and it
was a complete,
no doubt that I like downtown La.
Jamie and I talked about putting a
studio up in what we,
yeah,
well the,
I think what we might do,
you know we're going to set up a another
place around here,
but we were talking about doing a place.
I'm one of those pen houses.
I don't know it was a apartment.
Buildings Cause get an apartment.
I'm like a top floor with a woman's
crazy views.
Right.
I just think that would enhance a
podcast.
Yeah.
We were sitting here in behind us with
some fucking sick view of the city,
especially at night picture Joe.
I love that was out there telling the
other and the other room.
It's in the other room.
All right,
I'll go get it.
It's cool.
You still smoking?
That picture has you smoking?
You quit for a little while back.
I go back and forth.
I think a cat quit that shit dude.
I know you got to smell good.
It is no benefit.
Zero except the,
I don't give a fuck factor.
When would you say is something about
when you decide I'm going to smoke a
cigarette right now?
Clearly.
I don't give a fuck about my health.
I don't give a fuck about the future.
I don't give a fuck about cancer.
I don't give a fuck.
This is an,
I know this is an,
I don't give a fuck moment that I guess
there's some escape in that.
There's some fun in that.
And then you get the chemicals from the
cigarette that you craving the nicotine
feeling a calmness that comes with it,
that washes over it.
You'd need a cigarette right now.
Feel it making me want one accident.
But you're a professional athlete man.
Yeah,
I am.
I can't be doing that.
Try vaping.
Try Sucking on those robot dixit
everybody's got a,
yeah,
have a great sponsor who come up with
that stuff.
I tried it.
You know a firebrand America.
Awesome,
powerful firebrand America.
It's that good of the really good.
It's really good.
They take really good care of me.
So do they have like one of those big
fat ones that looked like a cigarette
box?
They have a whole bunch of those
different kinds of,
what is the deal with all the mod?
I Dunno,
a mod.
It's called them on this guy,
the kid thing,
Cox and mods cook.
Some months.
Furries I'm starting to cook is not
going to catch on.
I still look at it.
I get it.
Cook,
which is called the Guy Cock your cock
sucker.
Fucking nope,
nope,
nope.
You fucking cook.
Yeah,
they like it.
It's a new word.
It's exciting to use.
Let them use it.
The people haven't had a new word to
call people and so long and they're
trying to take away so many of them.
It used to be when I was a kid,
you can call a kid a Faggot,
you know?
Now you gay bashing.
Yeah,
but back then it had nothing to do with
being gay,
but it's too late.
It's connected to that.
It's really hard to use.
Retard.
It's hard to use.
No today.
You know,
even though it's not even a
classification for mental illness is
nothing to do with down syndrome.
Like retarded means slow growth,
like slow to catch on.
It is literally the perfect word to use
for retards when someone's a retard,
like calling them a retard is a perfect
word.
Like you would never say that about
someone who has a disease or someone who
has down syndrome.
Right.
But if someone's like the won'ts,
trump wins what people took it over.
That's what retarded.
That's a retard.
Right.
Fucking recharge.
It's the right word.
It's the word.
These goddamn language police
motherfuckers,
they've type sensitive,
sensitive punch.
Cox fucking sensitive.
Cucs they've traded debt catch up.
Maybe I do like it.
It's fucking,
we need a new card.
I'm happy it's a resident that actually
works in the description.
Right.
It's weak little bitch that would let
some other man fuck his wife.
Oh,
don't call him a retard.
Exactly.
We need to be more sensitive about the
way we communicate both.
They're really trying to do is just
control people.
It's a trying to,
it's the pussification.
Yes.
The God damn of America in America.
That's like the whole world.
The whole world.
Fucking pussification of everybody.
Oh yeah.
Well it's,
and it's also not being honest about
what the fuck's going on.
You know,
like when something happens we have to
be real sensitive to who we insult post
post like attacks.
Like with his shit that was going on in
Germany where all these women were
getting raped during New Year's eve cut
cause of all these Islamic refugees that
they had come in from Syria.
I mean it's just,
that's just the way it is.
Your,
your,
your people are coming from a completely
different culture in their culture.
Women are much more suppressed.
They come over to this country,
Germany where women or Western eyes,
they're free and they're wearing skirts
and their tits or hanging out and w
they're dressed normal and to getting
attacked.
And so what is the fucking mayor of,
was it Berlin?
Tell them,
stay away from men and dress different,
stay an arm's length away from men and
dress more conservatively.
Like literally this fucking,
these people are so sensitive and
worried that they're going to hurt
someone's feelings or they're going to
be called Islamophobic or racist in some
way,
that they're,
they're telling women who've done
nothing wrong,
that they should dress differently
because they've unfortunately let these
people in from another culture that
think about things differently.
Yeah.
Bunch of cooks.
Fucking cooks sensitive dazzle.
The mayor of Berlin or wherever it was,
it was a woman.
Was it Berlin?
I remember the city was,
but that's a woman,
so it's even more confusing.
But boy did she get fucking raked over
the coals online.
People are getting tired of it.
The pendulum swings both ways.
You know,
it swings towards ultra sensitivity and
then people get sick of that and they
go,
what the fuck?
And then they go hard the other way.
I think that's one the reasons why trump
is the republican nominee.
I think Caitlyn Jenner is responsible
for a lot of it.
I think people saw that and they're
like,
what the fuck?
They just like,
why?
What are you doing?
What are,
what does this 62 year old man now he's
a woman.
Call me kate on the cover of Vanity
Fair.
Got To be naked on the cover of sports
illustrated.
And then she wasn't like athlete of the
year.
So Fuck Outta here.
Get the fuck out of it.
She one woman of the year.
Yeah.
Woman of the year.
She a woman for a week.
She wins women of the year.
Just shows you men can do everything
including could when women in the year
we,
this cock Jamie pulled up the fucking
definition.
Is this an urban dictionary is a better
definition I think than the one you
gave.
Oh.
How dare you?
A demasculated millennial liberal male
who often speaks of white privilege and
modern feminism blames white men for all
of the world's problems.
Hmm.
It's the new definition there,
but it now I like,
I like this though.
There it goes chat again with the
megaphone telling everyone that he's a
Vegan.
What a cook.
Okay.
I liked that.
I liked that a lot.
But um,
look up cock hold,
but cock hold is different.
It's a different,
uh,
short for conservative.
What they fucking till word cock is most
commonly used on twitter to describe
anti white males while it was originally
formed with the original meaning of
Kack.
Kack hold the use of the word cock does
not necessarily denote a sexual
connotation.
Wow.
It's morphing.
The language is evolving before our
eyes.
Cox do not care about Islamic countries
throwing gays off buildings or hanging
them as much as the cake Baker who is
Christian and weren't served gay wedding
customers.
Oh,
that's interesting.
Coxe.
Give a free pass to anyone who
criticized them for fear of looking
racist or homophobic.
We'll still have that lady in Germany is
a cook.
The word originated from white
nationalists vocabulary,
but it's still widely used by all.
Okay.
But that,
so,
but they took cock hold and turned it
into this new thing go to.
But what is cut the definition for Koc
hole.
So this has nothing to do with guys'
wives getting banged by Chris.
She does to me.
It's still real to me,
dammit.
I was also like an official definition
that I'm like a an old dictionary from
old English.
Oh it means a man.
His wife was unfaithful cut cold,
which is yeah,
to make a cuckold of so if you,
okay,
that's uh,
that's how Norton I think described it
to me like a man.
If your,
if your wife is out banging other dudes
and you know about it but you don't say
anything,
you become a hold.
But there's also like cock hold porn
where it's like I said the guys there
while like sobbing in the corner while
his wife gets grilled.
Fucked.
Interesting.
The world is evolving.
Beautiful.
So it's still open,
open season then for use cook anyway you
want,
because it hit like five definitions.
I still have a fucking clue what that
means.
Yeah.
I mean a bunch of cooks,
cooks.
I liked that one definition though that
the,
the Vegan gets on the megaphone.
It's usually a Vegan who's been a Vegan
for like a month two.
All right.
Those are my favorite fucking Cox boy.
How do you pull out of this and have a
normal conversation?
Where do we go from here,
jo?
Where did we go?
So,
um,
tell me what it's like working with
Scott Coker and what a,
this whole,
I mean you are the face of Bella tore
kickboxing there.
They're really promoting you hard like
the belt or kickboxing logo has your,
your image,
you know,
you was it like you throwing a knee I
think,
is it I think or you throwing a punch
or,
or is it an elbow something,
but it's,
you're seeing like so many of these
Bella tore kickboxing promos that have
your face on it.
Yeah.
It's a good feeling.
You know,
Scott Coker is a big fan of kickboxing.
Yes,
he is.
Um,
yeah,
he's,
he's really pushing it.
I think the Viacom and spike sports are
really pushing it.
They really get behind and they're
trying to promote the sport and you
know,
I'm blessed that I'm a big part of that
and they're trying to do that for me.
Scott and
Belterra general,
it was just always treated me really,
really well.
Really well.
They need to bail on that name.
Bella terra,
you hate it,
hate it,
hate it.
There you go.
So you're throwing an elbow.
I'm right.
Oh,
Bella toward kickbox and leave that
brother.
Oh cause I am called POW.
You know the elbow torque.
Yeah.
That's even weirder.
You're throwing an elbow and you're not
allowed to elbow.
Yeah.
What the fuck?
It just shows how ridiculous it is.
Why don't they just do Moitai well,
I mean like I watched lion fight.
They,
they're just doing straight Moy Tai and
it seems pretty popular,
although it's on access TV.
And I think the uh,
the k one model,
um,
worked really well.
I think that,
you know what I mean?
Why Change?
It obviously worked for so long.
Um,
because the other stuff works.
Like if you're going to strike,
if you just going to do striking,
why not throw elbows?
I mean,
why not throw knees and the clinch?
Why not be able to click clinch and
sweep?
Why not be able to do all the things
that make [inaudible] special?
Why not take off him and made gloves
went not stomp on his face?
Why not?
Do you know what I mean?
I want to say everything can change.
That's right.
Bare knuckle,
bare knuckled tiger.
You're going to bring those?
I had to bring it up.
Does anybody bald?
I know in Thailand they're still,
like I saw Sam Chai had a fight recently
where they were wearing,
I'm just essentially hand wraps.
Yeah,
but the paint thick hand wraps.
That's like a rope.
Yeah.
Bounded fist matches a Thai fight.
They still do that every,
every couple hour long.
What's the benefit of that?
Because it looks like it's still a lot
of padding it.
I think it's more about the Thai culture
and that was like the,
the Siam Warrior days when they were
going to war,
they had that kind of thing and the
Hmong con that they were,
when they walked off of the thing,
we would work,
they would wear that around.
They wouldn't take that off like they
are now.
They would pull it down when they wear
it around their neck,
like a necklace when they would fight
and go to war.
Really?
But it's still the same thing.
It's like a cloth that's been blessed.
It might be your,
your mother shirt or something like
special and you're taking that with you
to bottle.
You would never take that off.
And years and years ago,
no shit.
When did they start taking it off?
Somebody's got to be big deal choked
with it probably.
I mean I know that was a boy.
Barron is a traditional martial arts
style of Moitai.
Before it became a sport,
it was more Brown.
That's where you see like Tony,
John and those guys.
Oh run up you and dropped elbows and
like the war,
um,
style of Thai was [inaudible] which is
what those bounded fix things are.
It's more about like giving a,
showing their culture.
I think it's interest proud of when we
tie in Thailand.
That's their national sport.
Well they should be,
I mean they figured out the best way to
take care of someone's legs.
I mean they really did figure out the
best way to leg kick.
They figured out the best way to throw
elbows in the clinch.
I mean it's,
it's so many excellent things came at
him with tyler yet.
It's interesting that this one country,
I mean sit,
pretend Thailand didn't exist.
It's a very small country.
If Thailand didn't exist,
like literally all of combat striking
would be very different.
Right.
One of the most influential countries
ever.
If you really take into consideration
like there what they've contributed to
overall combat sports.
Thailand is one of the most influential
countries ever next to Brazil.
But I guess Japan because that's the
first and foremost because the Japanese
even taught Jujitsu to Elio,
Gracie and Carlos Gracie,
and then it became Brazilian Jujitsu.
But Brazil is responsible for a massive
amount of evolution of submission
fighting.
But other than that you got I guess
western wrestling,
you know,
but,
but that's Russia.
That's a lot of countries.
We did start talking about wrestling and
then you got boxing,
which was,
yeah,
martial arts is not used as
predominantly in mma.
So like mma makes the sport,
you know,
you're,
you're talking about Brazil and what
it's done for,
for the sport.
Well that's the sports style of it,
you know.
But like cook food was,
was a huge martial art from China and
judo and karate.
And you know,
before there was guns and bombs and,
and uh,
cucs everywhere,
there was weird,
it was like vikings who had fucking
swords that like when across the globe
and fucking raped and pillaged and
dominated people and you know,
humans millions a year.
I remember many years ago it was,
you know,
they were animals and killing people and
going to war and there were all of these
countries made up,
you know,
Samurais and made up their own style or
whatever.
But like I think Burma,
which is like right next to Thailand has
like Burmese boxing,
which is very similar to Cambodia,
has tire it's own version of those
things,
you know?
Yeah,
yeah.
There was a Bondo,
you know,
which is a from,
that's from Burma too,
right?
Yep.
But no kickbox some amazing that the
style that the ties use as far as the
clinching the knees in a clinch and the
kicks and elbows in the clinch in and
leg kicks.
Like they,
they really revolutionized stand up
striking certainly in MMA.
I'm sure one of the most important
aspects of mma.
And you know,
some guys just become so proficient at
it.
It's,
it's,
it's interesting when you watch pure
Thai boxing,
like,
like a yachts and Cli or like really
high level Thai guys.
You Watch it,
you're like,
wow,
this is like a totally different way of
doing it.
Like they have a very specific style
type of style and you watch the let you
see the high level guys come over and
fight in the U S it's really interesting
how successful they are.
Hmm.
Oh yeah.
Unlike San shy,
you know,
it was a,
has a very exciting style on a very
different style.
He uses a lot of Meu Baran techniques
that,
you know,
the Cartwheel Kit,
cause I'm with Veronica,
you know,
so he's uh,
his,
uh,
you know,
in Thailand there's the culture of Muay
Thai and the level is so unbelievably
high that uh,
that's the,
the evolvement,
you know,
has really involved.
Yeah.
Um,
Sanchez really light on his feet too.
It's interesting watch fight because
he's
not like,
you know,
we think of a,
like a tie fighters being like light
with the front leg,
what kind of plodding forward.
But Sanchez like very light on his feet.
Like real good footwork,
moves around a lot,
a lot,
a lot.
I like a lot of,
um,
faints and a lot of like Mr Racks and,
and I'm very,
very fast,
very fast kicker too.
Interesting.
Like there's so many good guys now that
have come over from Thailand,
young guys to look Joe,
not a want,
you know,
it's um,
it's really good time to watch just even
straight Moy Tai.
Yeah.
I mean he got guys with 200 fights that
were trained by guys from,
with 200 fights that were trained by
guys with 200 fights.
There were towns guys by 200 fights,
you know,
so it's uh,
and they start when they're seven years
old and that's just their way of life
and their culture and their,
you know,
we tie is like in their blood and then
their DNA and their,
uh,
you know,
I have 95 cents a mile now.
90 fights,
nick.
Man,
it's a lot of fights.
I'm like,
that ain't shit.
That was like a 15 year old in Thailand
for a boxer.
That's crazy.
Right?
Find a boxer has 90 fights and it's
pretty rare.
Well,
I mean like he had like 150 images.
Did he really?
Yeah.
What is the most,
anybody's ever had an mma I think is
Travis Fulton.
I think Travis Fulton as like full 300
fights.
I think he has 300 fights.
Yeah,
Jeremy Horn I think at 200 or close to
it.
That was,
I thought I saw Jeremy Horn fighting
this janky little fucking card once in
a,
somewhere in California.
I forget where we want some Indian
casino or something like that where you
weren't allowed to,
you weren't allowed to punch you a lot
of slap slap to the face,
but you will have to kick to the face.
And it was just,
it was like when mma was illegal,
like pink creation.
Yeah.
When MMA was illegal there was like a
bunch of loopholes that they were
exploiting cause you couldn't fight mma
in California for a long time.
So they came up with all sorts of
different ways of doing it though.
They call,
you have to throw seven kicks before
they didn't have that.
But they had slaps like that was a,
that was another thing that existed in
Japan.
The early days,
the pancreas style,
which is real.
It's real weird to watch now boss route.
The guys figured out how to insulate it
though he hacked it because he threw
palms like punches where everybody else
was throwing bitch slaps.
Bas rutten was knocking guys out with
palm strikes cause he was throwing like
palm upper cuts and palm hooks.
He figured out how to hack it.
Yeah.
That crazy fucker is he fucking kicked
the lever.
That lever cake.
Yeah.
He's uh,
he's another guy who paid the price
physically his uh,
his craziness and his,
his madness in his pursuit because he
just,
he would talk about,
I mean talked about on the podcast,
he would just shoot cortisone into his
joints and his shins and just numb
everything up and lie to Cain.
He shoot lidacain into his shins and so
they cannot lie to keynes,
a numbing agent.
Novacane right.
It's like the gay cousin of cocaine.
Hmm.
It doesn't get you high,
but it just leaves me numb and confused.
I can't cousin.
Okay.
Yeah,
I got it.
I had lot of cane in my nose wants,
uh,
when I had my nose operating on.
And uh,
it's a,
it's interesting like it makes you like,
you feel weak and disoriented,
but you're not,
you're not drugged up.
You're like,
something's wrong with me.
I got to,
I can't,
like I could drive,
I could walk,
I could talk to people,
but I'm like,
I'm just not.
So he would inject it into the Shin so
it wouldn't because he was injured his,
because he wouldn't feel it when he
kicked it.
I'd have to ask boss again,
get the full story.
But I know a in checked in cortisone
into all of his joints,
just rectum is no cartilage in any of
his joints.
His knees are completely shot.
It's all bone on bone.
He was actually going to get them
resurfaced.
You ever seen when someone gets it
resurfaced?
My friend Steve Graham had his knee
done.
I'll show you a picture of you.
You're going to get grossed out.
He was,
uh,
he was on the Olympic ski team.
Yeah.
Why am I fucking am in so much?
He was on the US ski team,
I should say.
I don't know,
he wasn't any Olympics,
but he was um,
a top flight skier and had upwards of 20
operations on his knee.
Yeah.
I'm not exaggerating.
And this is what his needs look like
now.
The resurface the inside of his knee
because he was bone on bone,
so they put steel caps over the joints.
So the way his Tibia and fibula
intersect with each other.
And then I'm assuming that like they
don't rust or no,
it's stainless steel slide over each
other.
Speak.
And that white shit is like a artificial
meniscus,
like artificial padding in between the
steel.
How's it work?
Is it good?
If he's happy,
it's all good.
It's all right.
You know,
I mean,
he's a crazy fucker.
He's in pain all the time,
but he's just one of those dudes
[inaudible] some people just not a suck
it up.
Would you have done to your knee?
Uh,
I tore my MCL,
my MCL,
like detached from my Shin and then that
allowed my knee and I tore my acl and
half and then I partially tore my lcl.
So it was,
it was like four 10 ins and your whole
journey,
like two of them were completely torn
and then one of them was pretty fucking
close to being completely joint.
Wow.
What happened there?
I took a fight on short notice and I'm
in Vegas.
I did 40 a Chinese guy and uh,
he's like the sand chow.
I don't even know what Sanchez was.
They were like,
they told me the rules for like five
minutes before the fight in the back of
backstage,
I was throwing it,
went to throw a knee.
And as I was like standing on one foot,
as I was standing on one foot throwing
the knee,
he'd kicked right under my,
my knee.
And it shifted so hard that it just
ripped my blow everything out.
Oh,
wow.
And then,
uh,
be in the savage that I am,
I,
uh,
took the eight countenance stood up and
I was like,
I tried to fight anyway and I'm like,
oh,
he's going to kick my leg.
So I'm like,
oh,
I know what I'm going to do.
So as he runs to kick my leg,
I jumped over it like Aha.
But I landed on the one that went out
again.
And then,
uh,
I don't know if it wasn't completely
torn at that point.
It definitely was after that,
so,
but uh,
yeah,
I did that.
And then that same fight I had,
um,
my other knee ended up getting like a
quarter size piece of cartilage torn out
and was floating around in the joint.
It was,
it was a rough fight.
It was a rough thousand dollars back
then.
Joe Thousand Bottles and bucks.
He's out for a year.
God Damn.
But I'm going out.
So it was out for a year and a,
when I came back I just went on a terror
and that goes on at home.
I went on my belt and when like I don't
tend to know,
I think after that immediately after,
no.
What kind of surgery did they do to do
cadavers and cadavers and a scope?
I don't even have that.
You can't even tell if you look up my
name,
his name was,
gosh,
that's amazing.
Doctor Maura and a Orange City of
Warren's to do an amazing job.
And uh,
he fought with the insurance company.
For me it was,
they didn't want to do the cadaver
thing.
They wanted to like what they do is
they'll actually cut a sliver out of
your hamster tele or your hamstring
tendon,
which is the big fat 10 in that goes
down to the front of your knee.
I had that done and it would cut a
sliver out of that.
Take that piece,
put it in your acl and then wait for
that to scar over.
And I'm like,
so I already have a weak knee.
You're going to fucking take the one of
the only tendons I have left and make
that one week again.
I didn't go for it.
So we did the cadaver thing,
which is crazy.
It's like a dead body Barton obviously.
And then I guess once they put it in
your body,
like mutates it and they're like,
takes a while to get soft again and then
you,
your body will take it out as its own.
Well,
your body,
it acts as a scaffolding.
It's not like the cadaver itself is,
stays in your body,
your body uses the tissue that the
cadaver graft is on to sort of
peripherally pro proliferate with its
own cells.
So uh,
that's why they use an achilles tendon
because it's larger.
I had that done in my right knee.
It was way quicker recovery.
The left knee,
I had bolt acl done the left knee,
I did the Patella thing like way back
in,
I think it was 1993 or four.
So it was back in the day,
they didn't do the cadaver back then.
They only did the Patella tendon graft
or they did even worse.
The hamstring,
which is a real bad one cause then your
hamstring has to recover and they take
just take a chunk out of your hamstring
and then just fucking bolted into place.
I think that has to the same thing.
Your body has to proliferate it with
cells and you know,
it has to make,
you got to make sure that blood supplies
working and so it's a lot of work.
No,
they can do like prp and all this cool
stuff.
You were talking about that Orange Shit.
Last one is here.
Oh,
now they're doing stem cell treatments
for a lot of people.
I know Daniel Cormier,
I had that done.
He was really close to get knee,
had some stem cells in it and heals
right up.
It was right up.
It's just amazing.
They can take what they're,
they're finding with stem cells is that
it can take on the form,
especially if they're doing it from
women's,
um,
uh,
placenta,
like a woman who gets a sterian section.
We'll take a young girl who's getting it
says hereon section.
They take her placenta and they take the
stem cells out of that and then they can
inject it into various areas of your
body and it can become anything.
It can be good but tendon,
it can become a ligament.
It could repair torn muscles.
It's really interesting what they're
able to do,
but there's also some danger apparently,
especially if you go to Mexico.
Some,
uh,
some dude went to a bunch of different
places.
I think he went to like six different
places to get stem cells cause he had a
back problem.
And um,
he started growing some weird tumor in
his back that was like pressing on his
spine and when they cut the tumor out,
they realized it was not his tissue,
that it was like someone else's tissue
was growing in his body.
Like somebody like whoever's stem cell.
Yeah.
He's like trying to get like a uterus.
You got a uterus is laying around.
I mean since I was off of that and
they're like,
oh yeah,
give him that fucking tumor we took out
of the guide stem cell.
Right.
Other work,
the fund can say,
well if you're going to Russia or Mexico
oil and cut off often in there.
I mean I don't,
I'm obviously not a doctor so I don't,
I don't know exactly what they did in
these other countries that uh,
they're,
they're trying to pass off as stem cells
mean.
Who knows what the fuck they injected
this guy with.
But it used to be you'd have to go to
foreign countries to get stem cell
treatments cause you know,
they weren't exactly sure.
It was eight apparently helped this guy
once and then it started to go away.
Like whatever benefits he was getting
started going away.
And then he's like,
I'm just going to go on a fucking mad
tear all across the world and get stem
cells,
third world stem cells towards believe
it didn't work out for him.
I don't know.
It's fucked.
They,
they,
they cut like a fucking,
like a cod out of his back and then
they've probably to fix that,
they gave him like American stem cells
and everything's good.
I think he's done anything.
Homeboys toast and he's,
he's definitely saying,
uh,
I think his quote was,
don't go in the future.
I would advise people strongly not to go
with anecdotal evidence,
solid advice right there.
But um,
you know,
and don't help me a lot.
My shoulder,
my shoulder was pretty fucked and I got
stem cells and it's fucking fantastic
now.
Yeah,
it feels great.
So he gets a little sore sometimes after
a hard workout,
but just ice it up and it's good to go.
Like all the strength is hundred
percent.
It's,
it's uh,
they're,
they're doing it a lot on pro athletes
now.
There's a lot of athletes that are
getting it done.
Whereas,
um,
you know,
there's very little way to get certain
areas to heal without taking me just
massive amounts of time off or surgery,
you know.
But when you're talking about like
you're kind of injury,
I mean that's just par for the right
with
your business.
I mean,
yeah.
uh,
everything that live in my own,
all my joints hurt.
My elbows are sort of shit right now.
My,
uh,
uncle's herb man,
which of course my chest still hurts
from that last man standing tournament
that I had a couple of years ago.
My neck gets a chest hurts.
You had to pick a broken sternum,
right?
Yeah.
Well,
I don't know what I said.
It was like,
uh,
did you ever get an Mri?
I got an MRI,
did injections.
I did all kinds of stuff that they have
this,
I still have this,
uh,
I have a,
I guess like a Hematoma that's in
between the rib cartilage or something
and it swells out all the time.
It's still swollen.
And he was like a golf ball right there.
Oh,
she might,
if I,
it would get so bad that it would swell
up like a fucking tennis ball and then
that would pinch off all the nerves
running down my arm.
No.
Terrific.
Be All fucked up.
And the only way to fix that,
it's probably to open you up like a
fish.
I,
I'm not that out.
Hope it doesn't come back.
Be Proofing on the daily,
he's a,
is that what you taken?
Yup,
pretty much all the time.
You know what man,
I had a friend or I have a friend,
um,
who's a ultra marathon runner and he was
taking Ibuprofen every morning and he
was also taking it at night.
You're taking 800 milligrams in the
morning,
800 milligrams at night.
And then I had this woman on who's a,
a doctor,
doctor,
Rhonda Patrick.
She's a clinical researcher.
And she was talking about the dangers of
nonsteroidal antiinflammatories.
They cause high blood pressure.
They can cause strokes and some people,
especially when you're using them on a
daily basis,
she's like,
there was a lot of people that are using
nonsteroidal anti inflammatories and it
actually,
there's,
there's a fucked up loop that's going
on.
This is the loop.
When you take nonsteroidal anti
inflammatories,
it actually causes,
it causes inflammation because it fucks
with the gut flora in your body,
especially if you take it on a regular
basis,
which in turns causes inflammation,
which you're taking nonsteroidal anti
inflammatories to deal with the
inflammation.
So the,
the pills that you're taking a deal with
joint pains sometimes are causing joint
pain.
And that's what my friend Cam Haynes,
he was,
he was running a half a marathon every
day.
He still is running.
He's cause he's gearing up for this,
uh,
big foot 200.
That's in August.
He's going to run 200 miles in 48 hours.
He ran 24 hours.
Uh,
last weekend he ran 102 miles to gear up
for it too,
but he got off the Ibuprofen after that
podcast and he goes,
I've never felt better.
He goes,
it's amazing.
He's all the aches and pains that I was
taking Ibuprofen for.
They all went away.
And so,
so what does it take for them?
It's not taking shit.
He's not taking shit.
It is eating healthy.
He saw his eating healthy.
Ah,
fuck.
Fuck how bad you eat.
Uh,
not that bad.
Not that bad.
Come on Joe,
you already there.
Could we just stop with the cigarettes?
I tell you this because I love you man.
I'm just trying to help you out.
Not only that,
but I have a,
um,
officially of lily.
I have a,
uh,
a food prep sponsor that could be really
good.
I saw that on your instagram that looked
super healthy.
You get all those pre prep meals.
That makes it easy.
Huh?
It's so good.
So it's a hot sauce.
All I need,
45 minute,
45,
and the microwave and a nice,
so you get it like every week you get
up.
I go,
oh my fight camps he gives me like a,
every week I would go and pick them up.
That's how do people get Ahold of this
guy?
Where like is it a website one?
Uh,
get a hold of him through my instagram
or on instagram.
It's a chef roble chef route the meal
plan,
man,
look up the the meal plan man for all
the meal plan,
man,
chef rob will the meal plan,
man.
Yeah,
there's a lot of those guys.
A lot of MMA fighters have those little
sponsors that that do that guy that
makes a big difference.
So good.
Healthy foods.
So fucking important.
It's like [inaudible] of course.
But you really are what?
Cheat man.
I mean it's like,
it sounds so cliche.
We don't think about it because food
tastes good and if I have,
what's it going to hurt if I have a
fucking cookie?
Your body's made out of everything you
put in it.
If you eat cookies all the time,
you fuck you become a cookie.
He become the product of all the
bullshit,
non nutritional food that you stuff and
your fat face.
Yeah,
he's got a like grass fed beef and bison
and fucking all the good stuff.
So it's good.
Nice.
That's nice.
Do you take supplements?
You take like vitamins,
everything on the on it sends me.
So that's been good.
I'm addicted to off of right now.
Like if I don't take off her brain,
I'm just like,
why am I so dumb today?
It's like a counselor you'd be on here.
So I never used to take it before
workouts,
but now I take it before workouts.
I've found that it's easy cause I was
thinking,
well that doesn't have anything to do
like mental energy,
but it has a,
it has a lot to do,
especially when you're fatigued,
like mental energy.
Like I find that my workouts have more
energy.
When I take Alpha brain and I take
shroom tech together,
I stack them and a Abra said that's what
like all the pro athletes are doing,
like football players and shit.
They stack them up.
It was all,
there's a lot of good stuff today that
you could find that,
that,
that really does help you.
Um,
uh,
non,
or rather essential fatty acids are a
big one that's like,
I think that's almost not negotiable.
I think you need essential fatty acids.
I think you need fish oils at giant
Sabal,
man.
I think it's so important.
So important for your joints.
It's important for your brain's
important for the development of a
healthy muscle so that the official,
it makes a big difference to me.
And then also anti-inflammation stuff
like crew,
curcumin,
I guess you say it.
That's anything which is a,
comes from tumeric.
That's a big one.
Tube.
Yeah.
You know all these natural
anti-inflammatories that are not bad for
you.
Yeah.
I could see the gut flora problem with
the,
from Ibuprofen.
It's a big deal.
Stomach's always fucked up.
Yeah man.
It's bad for taking Ibuprofen about 600
milligrams twice a day for dude.
It's like,
I remember he got to stop.
Can we get you to stop?
Can I get you to stop all these things?
Is it possible?
Can I help you?
Sure.
Man.
They might have body stop hurting you
fucking do it.
Well,
how much time do you have off now
between fights?
I got,
I probably got some time now,
probably three or four months I think.
So.
Do you have anything scheduled or you
do?
I think my next one's to September and
I'm hungry,
I think.
Oh,
okay.
So they have something that this getting
this a military event as well.
Oh,
so Bella towards going international?
Yes sir.
How many international events that they
had?
I know they had a London one.
Right.
Um,
they hadn't lend one.
They had the,
their first belt where kickboxing event
was in Italy.
Uh,
part of it that was Italy.
I still a couple months ago.
Then they have hungry and then again in
December is a Florence,
so.
Oh,
nice.
Cool.
Yeah.
Gloria had fights all over the,
all over the world,
but I was always like the American guy,
so it was always like a la carte or the
American cards.
Right.
It's really cool that a Delaware is
going to have me see in the world a
little bit.
That's beautiful.
You had like a falling out with glory,
Huh?
Yeah,
we uh,
we just went our separate ways,
you know.
But you were saying that they were
taught,
they were telling the commentators to
talk shit about you.
Um,
is that a speculation or is that I
don't,
I hm.
Can't talk about it.
I think it was asked nicely not to talk
about anymore.
What did you say?
You know,
what did you think?
Watching my fight with Gloria.
Did you think the commentators were,
but it was your opinion on the date.
It's seat commentating.
He's interesting because,
uh,
being uh,
someone who's done it before,
there are things that you see on
television when you're watching it.
Honestly,
the best view in the house is your
house.
Cause the best view when you're watching
fights because when you're watching
kickboxing or whether you're watching
mma,
when you're watching on television,
you're seeing it like inside the cage
and inside the ring and you've seen it
from the right angle.
Like there's a lot of times when I'm
watching a fight,
first of all,
I have the best seat in the house.
You can't get any better.
I'm touching the actual ground that the
people are fighting on.
It's in front of me.
There's a table and then right in front
of that I could reach out,
but I can touch the cage.
Okay.
So he can't get any closer.
I miss a lot of shit and I may watch it.
Is there a screen for you to watch?
Two screens,
but I like to watch the fight.
I want to watch the actual fight and
win.
The fight is playing in front of me.
It's like I'm looking up and then I'm
looking down at the screen.
I'm looking up and then when we get down
the screen,
and sometimes I have to do commentary
when I'm down in the screen,
but I want to watch the actual action
playing out.
And when that is going on,
sometimes you don't see everything,
but I feel like there's some subtleties
that you see when you're looking at a
guy.
There's some things that you see in
movement where your brain,
yeah,
I got to think that all the years of
watching martial arts and doing martial
arts,
my brain's chunked a bunch of
information and I s I see certain traits
and I see trends and I see things and
you see them when you're actually
looking at the person's body better than
you do if you're looking at a monitor,
a video representation of it.
But like there's sometimes the refs in
the way,
and I don't see what's going on like
the,
the refs here and there right behind the
RAF and so I might miss something or
their back is to me and they get hit
with an upper cut.
You don't see what they get hit with.
There's a lot of times you miss a few
things.
So that taking that into consideration,
I know that these guys were sitting
ringside and they're watching it through
the ropes and they're seeing it live and
sometimes you don't catch anything.
But I did think that the commentary was
a little one sided and I did think that
they,
there was a lot of things that you were
doing that they weren't either picking
up on or they weren't giving you credit
for.
And uh,
it all fairness you told me about that
before I saw the fight,
you know,
and so I saw the fight and I was
watching.
I was like,
wow,
that is,
this is,
um,
it's interesting way there.
They're talking about this fight.
You were right.
Like it was,
I mean you,
you put it in my head then I watched it,
but I tried to be as objective as
possible.
But yeah,
I didn't think they were giving you
credit for a lot of the shit you were
doing.
Yeah.
I just thought that,
um,
the way that I've a few
that is possible,
man,
no one's ever done that in the UFC.
No one's ever come up to me and said,
hey,
hype this guy up or hey,
talk shit about this guy.
It's never happened ever.
But that's the UFC I could tough.
I definitely see it possibly happening
in other organizations.
If you felt that,
I just thought that,
uh,
the way that I was talked about in
general had changed dramatically of
when,
uh,
in the last couple of fights,
that was what was weird.
Earl Hawaiian,
he came up to me and said the same thing
last time I saw him was like,
well they serve,
talked about you really different now
maybe hearing really had an inside mall,
maybe at a mole inside fucking Gloria as
well.
But you know,
it is what it is.
You know,
Gloria,
I do,
I was doing a lot for this sport,
um,
in this country and worldwide.
I,
you know,
they certainly are.
I wish them the best.
Yeah,
I and I do too.
I'm a big fan,
but you know,
they were doing weird shit like on your
bio instead of all your accomplishments,
95 professional fights,
all that.
No,
it was like kicked out of his house and
he was 17 fucking loser,
you know,
a forced to go to four different high
schools.
Everybody hated him.
His feet smell.
It was like,
I was like,
is like a rap sheet.
Yeah,
they were definitely painting you out to
be.
But that's also in their defense.
I mean,
they're trying to develop personalities
for people tuned into,
you know,
here's this guy who comes out with
fucking prison pants on with la on them.
You know,
it's,
I guess,
I mean I wouldn't to live well,
I develop or promote the fact that he
was the first American to ever win a
global combat tournament or a three time
world champion or holds the record for
the fastest knockout of the down sports.
You know,
why promoting those accomplishments.
No,
that's not important.
I want to know how many times you kicked
out of school.
Yeah.
How old when you were so old you were
when your,
when your mom kicked you out of that
family home and yeah.
Yeah.
That's what I want to hear about odd
jobs that you worked on your tough man
contest.
Well,
in um,
bell tours,
not defense,
but in,
in,
um,
to their credit they did a great job
with that piece they did on you.
Yeah.
I really,
that was a,
I was really proud of that.
You know,
it was cool to,
uh,
you know,
when you're in it,
you don't really realize what you've,
you've actually done.
But um,
you know what we've,
what I think I've,
I've been a part of for can't stop with,
can't stop crazy for the sport and the
growth in the sport here in this country
from lion fight to glory to now belts or
kickboxing and being where I am.
Um,
the weight is on my shoulders,
so to speak,
with pushing this new brand and showing
Kyla we'll kickboxing into the world,
putting on exciting
fights is,
uh,
you know,
was proud it was,
which is why we got to get you off the
fucking Ibuprofen and get you off the
cigarettes.
Trust me.
The cigarettes.
Yeah.
The ibuprofen is like a necessity.
No,
no,
no.
You think it's a necessity.
You think it's a necessity?
I'm telling you,
I think that there's a real possibility
that the inflammation that's being
caused by taking this stuff and fucking
with your gut flora is actually making
your joints hurt even more than they
would have normally.
I think it's very possible.
I think a lemon,
did you,
do you have the a on it?
Total gut health?
Are you taking night yet?
I don't know.
Probiotics.
It's a new,
it's a new of the Krill oil.
Okay.
Something that's different.
That's good too.
That's a essential fatty acids.
It's essentially,
it's a more potent form of fish oil or
more bioavailable.
Have a really good bioavailable form I
should say.
Cause even regular official is
excellent.
Um,
but this total gut health is different.
Probiotics and enzymes that is really
good for digesting food,
the enzymes and also absorbing nutrients
through your food with the enzymes.
But the probiotic aspect of it is very
important.
I've been big on probiotics lately.
I eat a lot of Kimchi,
you know.
Do you like that stuff like spicy Korean
cabbage?
I love that shit.
I eat a lot of that.
I eat a lot of raw sauerkraut,
been eaten a lot of that.
I drink a lot of Kombucha.
That's good too.
That's real good.
Yeah,
I love that stuff.
I love that gts,
Kombucha,
the stuff that you have to have a an ID
to buy cause it's,
yeah,
we have that shit to here,
Jamie.
We have some pasta out,
two bottles from me and Joe Schilling.
Um,
but this stuff is more than one half of
1% alcohol.
So you have to have a license,
a driver's license.
He has to show your 21 to drink
Kombucha,
which is predictable.
It's stupid.
And I also buy this stuff at Erewhon.
That's a,
you take a shot of it every day.
It's like super fucking fermented
cabbage with Cayenne pepper in it.
It's like,
whoa.
He would take his like raw,
but it's super good.
How was it Joe Wa and I'm Keifer.
I've been drinking a lot of key for our
drink.
A big glass of the out a day.
Yeah.
Goats milk.
I take goat's milk keifer.
She's like a super powerful form of like
Acidophilus,
like coat cultures.
But what I've found over the last year,
year and a half from,
Oh yeah,
look at that thing.
It's like we're drinking beers here.
This is my favorite flavor.
This is a gingerade what it is,
it's what's called,
yeah.
Gingerade gingerade organic raw gts
class.
You got to get the classic,
the classic has the Black Label,
the black labels to let you know it's
fucking dangerous.
So one half of 1% less alcohol.
Cheers.
Cheers Buddy.
I love this stuff.
But anyway,
gut health,
probiotics,
just fucking,
it's everything man.
So important,
so important.
Your immune system.
So important for everything.
So even though your mood,
they think your personality is partially
shaped by your thoughts before.
That's great too.
Yeah.
And uh,
you know,
just five htp folks.
I mean that's what it is.
Five htp.
But you know,
a new moon has um,
l Tryptofan also which converts to five
htp,
which converts the Serotonin.
So you get sort of a time release
method,
a time release effect,
but all that stuff is very good for your
brain.
There's other,
all the building blocks for human neuro
transmitters.
That's what Alpha brain is.
That's a new moon is,
but new mood specifically,
uh,
as the building blocks for Sarah telling
him,
right.
All that stuff's legit.
They even tell people that are on Ssri
is to not take five htp,
um,
serotonin uptake re and habitaters
antidepressants.
You know,
things like,
I guess he tell him not to take it
because then you can get what's called
Serotonin Syndrome or your body has too
much serotonin in it and sort of like a,
when guys are on steroids and they get
bitched,
it's same thing.
It's like your body is like,
what is all this fucking Serotonin doing
it here?
It's creates an imbalance.
They just,
they just don't work with each other.
Well,
a Neil Brennan friend of mine who's a
comic was the first guy that I ever met.
It was on a five htp and then when he
got on Ssri,
they told him to get off the five htp
and like,
you're taking this too much going on
here.
Also the antidepressants,
that's what they do is they create
serotonin.
I do.
Well,
it helps.
It,
it,
it helps your body establish a better
mood.
And I don't know exactly what the Mac,
it's been described to me,
but I can't really,
uh,
recite it off memory.
But,
um,
Serotonin and obviously is a big factor
in the way you feel growing up and
taking things like new mood.
You know,
especially like athletes,
like you,
fighters,
you're constantly draining yourself.
I mean you are just,
I mean I've seen your workouts dude,
you just fucking empty it all out and
your body's just like boom,
it's done.
And then you have to regear up so your
body has to produce everything again.
Your endocrine system is taxed,
everything is taxed and you have to get
all the right food in it.
That's why fucking with any of that,
like taking the Ibuprofen,
fucking cigarettes,
shitty food,
all that stuff is like,
it has a massive effect on someone who
does something that you do.
Like you need every edge you can get.
Man.
You know,
you're in a,
you're in the craziest business that you
can be when it comes to professional
athletics.
You're in the combat sports business
here in the business and arguably the
craziest of the combat sports cause it's
all just throwing bones,
man.
There's no wrestling,
there's no take,
there's no fucking lay in pray.
There's no hump.
And someone on the ground and holding
them down and no getting him in the
head.
You can't do any of that.
You got to throw bones,
you know,
that's a,
it's a wild way to make a living.
You need to all the advantages,
all of them.
I know you were working with a nic curse
on for awhile,
you're going to do that again.
I didn't work with him this last year.
It was like with Brovana coffin and it
was just really busy.
And um,
you know,
my,
uh,
lately I've been,
you know,
four week notice.
My camps have been really short for both
my last two fights,
so I just hadn't had a chance to work
with I like,
I think two or three times for this,
uh,
this last fight.
But yeah,
the guys,
the guy's amazing.
I can't say enough good things about
him.
Yeah,
he's a bad motherfucker.
An awesome fucking awesome.
He never so much too,
just so different.
You know,
like when I used to train and do like
strength conditioning and working on my
own and stuff,
it was like by how hard you worked and
every day it was,
you know,
I've never had a session with,
with nick where I left and I was like,
oh fuck.
Like they were always hard and difficult
but like I never,
they were never like breaking me down,
you know,
the results and the level of the
increase every week was like really,
really noticeable and impressive.
Yeah.
That's the intelligent approach and
that's the approach that a lot of
trainers are using now is they're giving
you enough work so that your body
improves and recovers,
but not so much that your body can't
improve.
So this old stupid idea that a lot of us
have,
and I used the APP just work,
get out of there like you fucking,
you can barely walk.
You got to leave it all in the gym,
but that's not,
that doesn't give you a chance to
recover.
Right.
And then like rest days,
like,
um,
you know,
not killed.
We used to just crush myself on Monday
and then the rest of the week I'd be
dragging ass trying to make it by
Friday.
Rolled around and was like,
now your last three workouts a the week
weren't that productive.
You know what I mean?
Well,
I've been really into that a lot lately
because I started listening to Wa Pavel
Tatsu lean.
He's the guy that brought kettle bells
to America.
It's this bad ass Russian dude.
And He,
um,
has some really interesting ideas about
strength and conditioning.
And one of the things that he said that
I think is most important is that the
way you're training,
especially training with kettle bells in
particular,
what you,
what you're trying to do is you're
trying to give your body work so that
your body feels like,
like,
um,
it can,
it can recover.
And you slowly build upon these things
and think of them as a skill.
Like he's like,
strength is a skill and you're not
trying to leave yourself completely
exhausted and blown out and all your
joints are fried and all your muscles
are just rubber.
Like you're trying to what he calls
grease the groove,
which means like slowly build this up
and do it.
Like instead instead of sets of like 25
wraps,
like crossfit style.
He's like everything more than five reps
is bullshit.
is bodybuilding.
He's like,
you should be doing like heavyweight
five reps and if you can do 10 reps,
do five like you don't need to do,
you don't need to work to failure.
He doesn't believe in working to
failure.
I'm doing a bad job of explaining,
uh,
his philosophies,
but tim,
Tim Ferriss had two podcasts with them
where you could listen to it.
It's,
I'll,
I'll send them to you.
They're excellent.
I think that's kind of similar to like
the way nick least,
the way that I see nick's training,
it's like trying to send a neurological
signal to my body to grow or to change
it,
to move.
I don't need to like destroy it to do
that.
I don't need a breakdown my muscle and
it has to rebuild itself.
I need to,
it's like a altitude training.
When you go to high altitude,
your body has picks up a signal that I,
there's not enough oxygen in this air.
I need to make more red blood cells so
your body sends a neuron neurological
signal to create red blood cells from
your blue mirror or whatever.
It's your body's like a computer and
just trying to get,
okay,
I want my,
I want to be a little faster,
I want to be a little whatever and I'm
doing enough work to send that signal to
make my body adapt.
You know what I mean?
As opposed to I want to be faster so I'm
going to just destroy my legs until he
can't walk for a week and then it's
going to build back faster.
You know what I mean?
A sense.
It does work.
It does.
Obviously it doesn't work good.
It doesn't work the right way.
The right way to do it really is to
like,
and I've,
I've been getting great results with
pebbles methods with doing lighter or
not lighter weights,
but lower reps,
lower wraps in like if I could do eight
or nine reps,
I do five,
I do five and I ended there and like
when I'm done,
I feel good.
Like I'm done with my workout.
I know I put in,
you know,
45 minutes or more of hard work,
but I don't feel like broken down.
Whereas before when I was like sort of
structuring it off of my own ideas,
I would just have these fucking brutal
workouts where I just,
everything was to failure.
Everything is right.
Ah,
great.
And then when it was over,
I just felt like a Zombie for the rest
of the day.
Yeah.
And then now your serotonin levels,
by the time you're three days in,
I'm like,
fuck,
I need some new move because I don't
feel like I want to do this shit anymore
and you're not going to perform as well
and you're not gonna you know,
it's a caffeine big thing.
Yeah.
I was chugging 20 ounce starbucks like
they were nothing.
I go to sleep,
I can take a 20 ounce Dar Bucket Watch.
That shit doesn't work anyway at work.
Yeah,
you can,
you can get to the point where your body
is just,
it doesn't matter.
Stimulants,
whatever.
You're just,
you're just toast.
Yeah.
It's,
it's,
there's a lot of science to,
uh,
athletics to sports training with
athletes today that just didn't exist 10
20 years ago and take advantage of that
heating water right,
is drink lots of water,
eat lots of red meat that your,
that was your,
that was your supplement base,
you know?
Yeah.
Nobody knew shit.
I mean,
eight,
nine.
Well,
yeah.
Nobody knew anything about like,
what's,
what's the proper way to,
to eat?
When should you eat?
You eat five times a day.
Should g there was this warrior diet
craze where people were like,
the only eat one meal a day because
that's what a road warrior did.
They would only eat once a day.
And like,
um,
you're not a warrior.
You're not a viking.
Like you're not a fucking barbarian.
Like,
look,
you got a frigerator.
It's right there.
How have some neat you fuck like it's,
it's weird because it's fucking fuck you
fuck cock.
You got damn cukor he had a fucking
stake.
You need to come up with our own insult.
Come up with a name that you can call
certain types of people.
Well we'll work on that.
That's for time.
But it's interesting that like
nutritional advice that people would
give you just 10 years ago isn't valid
anymore.
Oh yeah.
You know the,
the ideas of a absorption of certain
fats and essential fatty acids that they
had,
especially plant based stuff just a few
years ago.
They're realizing like,
yeah,
this stuff exists in these platforms,
but it's not as bio available as it is
in an animal forms.
And this is what really recent stuff.
I like the Food Pyramid Shit.
Yeah.
Like that.
Like it's just,
I was talking about that,
I guess margarine and butter,
that's better.
And I can't believe it's not butter,
but now it's not about,
you know,
it's march,
it's fucking terrible for you.
It's plastic.
It's one molecule away from plastic.
That's what they were telling people to
do.
You know the Food Pyramid said that you
should have like 300 grams of
carbohydrate today.
Yeah.
You supposed to eat bread and pasta and
now they're saying,
no,
no.
Dot.
I was reading and then like you get,
Oh yeah,
stupid cancer.
Like,
oh they have you cut out all of the shit
that they've been telling you since
you're a child.
You're supposed to have,
which the food pyramid was based around
the economy.
They want,
they need people to buy it,
to buy the fucking oats and grains that
we grow here.
You know what I mean?
Either.
There's a lot of that.
I mean there's certainly 300 must have
a,
must have some influence,
especially with corn subsidies and all
that jazz.
Man,
did you ever see that movie king corn?
No.
Cheers dude.
Watch that documentary.
It's crazy.
It's about how much corn,
wheat and how much,
how corn is subsidized.
Have they paid people to grow corn?
Like the government pays farmers to grow
corn?
If the government didn't subsidize corn
production,
this company corn agricultural like
would fucking collapse.
Like there's so many of these people
that are reliant,
these agricultural farms that are
growing corn reliant on government
subsidies in order to stay afloat.
It's weird and corns and everything.
Corn,
I was having beef jerky other day and
uh,
my wife was reading the ingredients and
she goes,
didn't know this has corn in it.
I don't know why.
Corn Syrup is one protein.
Everything right?
Corn,
protein,
corn,
protein in fucking beef jerky.
It's fucking corn heads.
That's a new one.
Corn,
corn,
corn head fucking,
no,
it's not,
it's not going to work.
But corn,
protein in beef Jerky,
beef.
The protein that you would think would
be in the,
yeah,
I'm sure again,
well it must have something to do with
the flavoring or something to do with
the sauce that they,
you know,
they marinate them and Teriyaki or
whatever the fuck they do when they make
it.
But there was corn protein in beef
jerky.
How much is beef jerky?
You've seen it all now in jail.
I have seen it all too.
So,
um,
so what's the plan now when you,
when you come off of a fight like that?
What'd he do?
He just chillax for a little bit and
just,
yeah,
I had two back to back fights anyway.
And uh,
and I'm looking forward to,
I was a little time off for relaxing a
little bit,
getting my mind wrapped around what
happened,
why it happened,
where I go from there.
And do you move around your training
camps at all?
Do you bring in new trainers?
Do you ever go to places and spend a
little bit of time working with someone
different?
I'm numb.
I'm sure I'll be up in stockton,
a Latin hoping an acre ready for his
fight with conor now and then,
um,
yeah,
it's always good to work with those
guys.
And uh,
I want to get some boxing rounds in with
Richard Perez when I'm up there.
So Nice.
Um,
not a lot,
you know.
Uh,
I try to,
you know,
my,
I think my team is really solid and,
and uh,
I think that's where I need to be.
I was at American top team is a little
before when the sock,
he got nine mail the first time it was
an American top team working on my
wrestling and stuff.
And then was,
it was,
it was a cool experience.
I don't think it was the best experience
from just being away from my sports
system of my coaches and my team.
And I don't think,
I think that was a mistake to to jump
ship,
so to speak and go train someplace else.
Yeah.
It seems to me that there's a lot of
comforts of home that help relax you and
just being in the,
in the same environment all the time.
It's probably real good for you in terms
of like your comfort level recovery and
being in your own home.
Yeah.
And I think just your coaches and being
with somebody that's you for 10 years
and he knows what you're thinking,
you know what he thinks,
he knows how you are,
what you need to hear,
how hard to work,
do things like that,
you know?
Right.
Knows when you're tired,
when you're off,
you have a good understanding of you.
Yeah.
And I think I liked the fact that you've
gone away from the MMA and decided to go
straight back to kickboxing cause you
know what do you 32 now?
Yup.
Yeah.
I mean it's just like,
it's not,
you're so good at kickboxing.
It's such a,
you know,
it's such an emerging sport too.
And with this opportunity with Bella
tour too,
I think it's a really good idea because
like learning all the wrestling and
learning all the fucking submissions and
take down defense and all that stuff,
just,
it's a whole nother experience.
A whole nother like journey to get on.
Yup.
It's a,
and it's,
I think it's too late for that.
It'd be like if I went into a boxing
career now,
you know what I mean?
You just,
you can,
you can throw and you can take some
shots,
but like you don't have 150 amateur
boxing fights,
you know what I mean?
You're not going to catch up.
Right.
And your body is programmed to do
certain things already.
Like you brought your body's program for
certain distances.
Like you buy like kick him.
Oh he can't kick him.
That's what my problem is with him.
It was the,
my,
my body has been programmed that when
we're in,
when we get close to marina and I
clench,
so to speak,
I pull you into the clinch.
I get to that.
Well,
when I do that [inaudible] pull you
right.
Like you're taken out and I'm like,
it's,
it's so hard for me to think the push
away,
right.
We need to stop this because everything
I've done for the last 17 years of my
life has been like,
yeah,
yeah.
No,
you worked with a w.
What is your trainer's name again?
That Japanese dude mark tomorrow.
He seems like a really interesting guy.
He's a real cool dude.
And you've been with him for a long
time,
Huh?
Yeah,
like a 10 years,
11 years background.
Uh,
he's done almost every martial art I
think.
And um,
he kind of like,
oh,
I didn't,
he did a kito for awhile and the guy was
like,
you know,
you have to go out and be like this.
It's like,
oh,
what if I had I do this?
Like,
no,
no.
It has to be like that.
He's like,
oh,
fuck this bullshit.
But he,
uh,
you know,
did boxing and kickboxing.
He was one of the first,
uh,
promoters here in California for Moy Tai
when they used to have the old shows
that Hollywood park was what promotions
I like to meet.
That guy seems like a very wise guy.
Very knowledgeable guy.
He's good.
He's real good dude.
Real good dude.
But have you had much experience besides
American top team working with different
kickboxing trainers or is there anybody
that you would really enjoy working
with?
Um,
no,
I haven't had a lot of experience
outside of working with,
um,
at Att,
many,
many att.
It was mostly,
I just words in my wrestling,
wrestling,
um,
have more to the whole lot of other
kickboxing a trainers.
Do you think there's benefit in that and
trying out,
uh,
you know,
different Pete,
just having some sessions with some
different people just to see if you pick
up a few things.
Oh,
absolutely.
You're like a rob came in or something
like that.
Yeah,
I know rob came in.
He's a buddy of mine,
but we haven't worked together again.
God,
you got to work with them.
Yeah,
absolutely.
Yeah.
I mean a antony hard docks around here
too.
You ever trained with him?
I'll set it up.
Yeah.
Smart Guy.
He's another guy I think probably help
you.
It knows a lot of shit.
I just think um,
you know,
for a guy like you at your level,
like any little variables that you could
pick up from any of these guys,
it's probably a good thing.
So much,
so much good knowledge.
And Southern California in particular is
such an amazing place for just all
martial arts.
I mean,
we're like in one of them that,
I mean as far as the United States,
this is one of the Meccas uh,
Henry Hill.
Yeah.
Love to work with them.
Oh fuck yeah.
We see each other at the fights of know
each other well,
but um,
great guy.
Never had an opportunity to work with
them.
He's done the wonder here a lot.
Actually.
I think he's being in northern
California quite a bit because he was at
Aka for awhile.
I think.
What's he doing up there?
I'm not sure.
I think that he was working with Luke
for the last fight and I think that,
uh,
think he might be moving out this way.
Oh really?
When I heard that.
Interesting.
I don't know how long that blacks
Lillian's is,
is doing.
Yeah.
Isn't going under it.
I've got a business or something.
Didn't the owner just declare bankruptcy
or something along those lines?
I think that's what I,
that's not good.
I don't know.
Cause he owned that owner owned Jocko
willink too.
If it's one point.
Yeah.
I think,
I dunno.
I don't know enough about this study and
probably talk about it.
I don't either.
I don't know.
I mean,
uh,
I know Dan Lambert very well,
the guy who owns American top team and
that's as legit as it gets.
He's the best.
So such a great dude.
I love that guy.
I mean like a superstar when I was
there.
Dan Lambert is awesome.
No,
he is a fucking amazing dude.
And so important for the growth and
development of MMA.
I mean what he's done with American top
team and putting together this world
class facility,
by the way,
spending millions of dollars to do it.
Just throwing money at that and having
guys take advantage of that.
And he had guys rip him off.
He had a lot,
a lot of like really shitty things
happen a lot.
And then when the black zillions came
around,
a lot of guys bailed because that guy
paid him.
He paid people like,
come on over to me,
I'll give you money.
And you know,
he just sort of poached a bunch of
people allegedly according to Dan tells
the story.
So who knows?
Who knows what the fuck happened.
But at the end of the day,
guy like Dan Lambert,
super important.
You need like these like wealthy
benefactors who take these chances and
put together these facilities.
But in my opinion,
no one's done it like Dan has.
Did it handle a new facility out there?
I saw him in some,
some pictures online.
It looks crazy.
Crazy.
It's got apartments.
Yeah,
a huge where's building going on now is
a lot of people are building dorms.
Yeah.
Their camps down,
which makes a lot of senses.
So many guys are bouncing around to
sure.
You know,
they come from out of town to go train
and at Greg Jackson's a building one
like that.
And uh,
yeah,
Greg Jack Cowboy said he has a bad
motherfucker.
Ransoming calloway.
Good Cowboy.
Look Against Code Tag.
Holy Shit.
Screaming at the TV.
He looked fucking awesome.
Sensational.
At one 70.
He looks God damn sensational.
I mean that it's like everything came
together at one 70 and coat.
He's a beast man.
Nope.
Nobody's ever worked coty over the way.
Cowboy did.
And he's he coattails father like two oh
five before too.
Right?
Cause at first he was saying that,
uh,
at one 70,
the guy who was also like a one 55 are
coming up,
but it was like a new way.
Right?
Who's this first?
Oh,
cowboys.
Yeah.
Big Dude.
That was that other cowboy dude.
Yeah.
Um,
but that guy is big.
He's a big fella.
He was bigger than cowboy boots.
Cowboy.
I caught him in the triangle,
but he just looked great.
But like Kofi haven body,
like one 85 and then he started,
his first fight was at two oh five he
dropped Tito Ortiz.
This is way back in the day.
It's when Tito was a light heavyweight
champ I believe.
And I think Tito was either champ or in
the,
I mean it was,
Tito was in his prime and he lost to
Tito at light heavyweight and then went
down to one 85 fought Anderson Silva.
I was doing very well,
very smart fight.
He fought a very smart fight against
Anderson where he was like making
Anderson lead in Anderson is really a
counter guy and he was just sort of
laying back and Anderson didn't like it
and he doesn't,
the Anderson does not like it when he
had like a weird knee popped or
something and then he blew out.
Yeah.
Were like lifted his leg up to throw a
kick and his knee just buckled and
shaped in on him and shit happens
sometimes it's,
Oh yeah,
weird freak shit like that happens a lot
in this sport.
Well sure.
And there's also like injuries that you
get in like the second and third round
that you don't even know what goals,
you know,
you felt your knee pop,
you're not exactly sure what it is and
you're still standing on and everything
seems fine.
And then you throw a kick and it just
gives out.
There's that,
you know,
but the point is [inaudible] he's a
stud.
He said,
tough fucking guy.
And to have cowboy work,
I'm like that.
I was like,
Woo.
Ninja looked fucking aussie like
terminator that night.
Like he looks like,
yeah,
it looked like a world,
but going to happy for me.
Legit world champion.
Yeah.
I hope he can keep that together.
I really do.
I think one 70 I think these guys that
are fucking dumb,
depleting themselves so badly to cut
weight.
I think that's going to be a thing of
the past.
I really do.
I think people gotta realize like,
this is not the benefit that you get in
that is,
it's negligible cowboys weighing like
one 76 somewhere around that and he's
cutting just a little
bit of weight and making one 70 easy.
Yeah.
I think he was like four or five pounds
off when he came for zero.
We sparked a couple of weeks before the
fight and he was like 14 days out and he
was like five pounds like you'd be out
to eat where even when everyone nice
shit drinking a beer.
He's so fucking ridiculous.
What that eight drinks beer up until the
day of the weigh ins.
That can't be good.
Right?
Why?
Well,
a little bit of beer is probably okay.
Well boss route and said that.
He said he used to drink beer.
He said,
I drink beer every night.
I drink a little bit of beer.
I have a,
I don't get fucking drunk.
You drink a little beer when you're in
camp?
Yeah,
I drink a little beer when I'm in camp
after the weigh in.
Not ever immediately after the way I am,
but I'm at and when I'm all fed and
rehydrated and feeling good,
I'll have a beer.
It's part of mine.
I like to be relaxed,
you know,
I want to not relax like all I'm going
to get doing shots,
you know what I mean?
About the cowboy and I were talking
about that too.
It's like they have made the fight week,
so stressful now for everyone.
And then you get so like mentally just
stressed out and you can't do this,
you can't do that.
And you got to do these interviews.
And like fight week used to be our whole
camp.
You know,
when I first started it was you want to
fight on Saturday and it's like Monday
and like,
okay,
I'm training all week and then you
following on Saturday,
you know?
And uh,
you know,
I think that,
uh,
well what's so stressful about it,
the interviews,
the press,
the interview is that the,
if you know,
I try not to think about the fight,
you know,
cowboy the same way as we get a little
get along well with and stuff like,
um,
if you sat at home and didn't eat,
you know,
and you're already tired and you sat at
home,
the only thing that you can think of is
on Saturday night,
this guy's gonna try and kill me and
blah,
blah.
And it's like it eats you up and they
stresses you the fuck out.
Right.
You know what I mean?
As opposed to like go in and see a movie
and relaxing,
you know?
And when,
when the thoughts of the fight come up
and your head,
you purposely ignore them,
push them aside.
Yeah.
If they're not helpful,
you know what I mean?
There's something I can't change.
You know what I mean?
I don't over analyze,
you know?
Right.
So watch my fight my is a million times
before I bought it.
Now it's like I'll watch them fight and
maybe once or twice and see if there's
anything that jumps out at me that it
looked like he does this sometimes.
But other than that turned out to
overanalyze it and make it in there.
Just do it now.
That's,
that's a smart way to do it because it's
like you're doing all the work anyway.
You're doing all the work in the gym.
You're prepared.
Like the mindset needs time off too,
just like the body does.
Absolutely.
And you've,
you know,
is cowboy drink and a beard or fight
week.
And it changed the,
what is body,
what he's done to train for the last 12
years of his life.
He's not going to perform because you're
like,
I don't think so.
I think being relaxed and being
confident and comfortable and then
getting in there and handling business
at night,
people start,
well fuck,
is that sound?
I don't like that.
That's what people are saying.
I know what the fucking cock,
so fuck is going on here man.
Um,
you,
you did some work with vinny shoreman,
you know,
I've had on the podcast,
great guy.
And uh,
before that Vinnie's uh,
he calls himself a mental coach.
She does hypnosis,
but he calls himself a mental coach.
And before that I was like,
all right,
well what's the deal with this
hypnotism?
Is this,
this is shit legit.
And then he put me under,
I had them do it and I was like,
oh,
should I woke up?
My pants were gone.
I got to have him do timeline therapy on
it.
What is that?
Timeline therapy is like a,
it's like a hypnosis state,
but you're basically,
you know,
like a timeline and a book.
There's Jesus born whatever,
World War One,
World War II.
And he kind of like,
did you,
did you feel like you floated up at all
when you're under?
No.
Didn't feel like I floated but I felt
like I went inward more.
Okay.
I felt like it almost felt like I was on
a drug.
So this one
you almost like you pull back,
like you pull back and you'll go up and
go be out of,
that probably sounds so weird to people
that don't get it,
but fuck them,
you go like straight up,
back into the sky.
Right.
So you're like almost,
it feels like you're floating to me.
Like,
like I know what it feels like to fly
based off of that.
And you go up,
up,
up and you're looking at your life and
like a timeline and it will be like,
think about a time when you,
you know,
as far back as you could possibly
remember and you will tap into some shit
from like a Jew childhood that you
didn't even know that you even
remembered.
You know what I mean?
And,
uh,
some really some really far out stuff
and it will change a lot of things.
If you think about it,
like everything that's ever happened to
your whole life isn't you've ever seen
thought,
heard is where did that information go?
Like it didn't fall out of your head.
I mean,
it's there,
you just can't access it anymore and
you'd have a hard time accessing it.
And with these hypnosis things,
you have opportunity to still tap into
that or get better at tapping into them
accessing that information.
So what did you get out of it?
Uh,
I remember I said I forgive my dad.
Yeah,
49.
Um,
I hated my dad's guts,
like hated him.
My Dad did some really shitty things to
me when a,
and I hated him.
I hated him.
And uh,
vinny,
um,
one day when he's say,
I want to try this time on Thailand
therapy on you if you want to,
if you're into it.
And I'm like,
yeah.
And be like,
where's it going to do?
He's like,
I don't know.
We're just going to see if you'd like
this thing.
I had no clue.
It was going to do.
And,
uh,
had me think of all these times of my
life and when I felt really proud,
when I felt really afraid,
when I felt really scared,
when I felt really strong,
when I felt really all these emotions.
And,
uh,
it was probably about 45 minutes and
every single one of the emotions was
some other time with my dad.
It was weird.
And,
uh,
when we got done with the session,
like I couldn't even tap into that
hatred that I had from my dad anymore
and I fucking hated him.
When I found out he had cancer,
I was like,
I don't give a shit and fucking,
you know,
and,
uh,
after that session,
like I,
I didn't have that anger anymore and I
couldn't even find it,
you know.
And I used to be able to like look in
the mirror and think about my dad and my
eyes.
We are ready to be so fucking mad.
You know,
I used to fight when I was,
uh,
I used to do a lot of things that were
based off of
like shoving up my dad's ass.
Like,
I want to show him not necessarily
fighting the person,
like not pretending it's my dad,
but it was more like I'm going to,
you know,
I had a lot of motivation from my dad
and uh,
yeah.
When,
when the session was over,
I had,
I couldn't even tap into that.
I was able to go and I decided to go and
start a new relationship with my dad and
it wasn't like I forgive you but say
you're sorry.
You know,
I'm still,
it was like I just didn't give a fuck
anymore that like,
it wasn't worth it.
And,
um,
people that really knew me really well
could just see me differently.
Like there was like this chip that I
carried around on my shoulder that
wasn't there anymore.
It was nuts.
That's,
that's an interesting thing.
Um,
the idea of timeline therapy,
the idea of thinking about your life and
being able to separate yourself,
like who you are right now,
and go back and look at all these
moments in your life and what they meant
to you and how you're carrying that
around today.
That'd be very valuable to people.
Yup.
It's uh,
it's,
uh,
you know,
he does all kinds of stuff.
You have a phobia,
you know,
if you're afraid of fucking spiders or
whatever,
he can do shit with you and get rid of a
phobia.
Yup.
Hypnotize you.
I don't know how he doesn't,
if that's him,
but like he can hypnotize you and have
you get rid of that phobia.
Like where you were not afraid of those
things anymore.
Yeah.
I don't,
I wish I had a recording of what he was
doing,
you know,
like what he said and the way send back
over and a couple of weeks.
Yeah.
He just sent me an email.
I've got to get back to the,
he's got a podcast he's going to called
the mind diet.
Oh really?
Yeah,
he's great.
I'm a big fan of Benny's.
I just,
as a person,
I really enjoy them and he's a very
good,
uh,
Moitai commentator to,
yeah.
Really knows her shit.
What's he doing?
He was doing its glory,
right?
No infusion now.
Okay.
What was he do you do?
It's showtime.
Yeah,
it was,
it showtime,
showtime.
Fusion.
Just k one,
I can a day.
It's glory.
Glory.
I've met,
it's showtime.
Showtime.
They ended up being gone.
Yeah.
Why?
How the fuck did kickboxing becomes so
goddamn big in Europe?
I mean,
it's so huge in other parts of the
world.
Yeah.
Especially Holland.
Uh,
they just,
uh,
they got,
they had the right people promoting it
and k one with most of those guys work
from most of the management guys.
Four k one were Dutch and their fighters
were Dutch.
And then,
I don't know,
I think we're wearing,
when the US was blowing up with him and
man,
they were there were still on the
kickboxing training.
That's why we ain't got held back.
I think.
Well,
it's amazing when you look at cage
fighters ruined it for us.
God dammit.
What's in the back though?
If you look at all the different people
that are super high level kickboxers it
came from this one really small country
in Holland is not very big at all.
But you've got rob came in,
you've got Ernesto hoost.
I mean,
it is just like this incredible hot bed
of super high level kickboxing talent.
I mean,
uh,
Ramon,
Ramon dekkers.
I mean,
Geez,
you can go on and on and on and can keep
going about all the high level talent
that came out of Holland and to this
day,
you know Badr Hari five gyms.
Yeah,
maybe not even five.
It was like three or four,
like major gyms and they just haul it
competed all the time.
And it was the blue up.
Yeah.
What's going on with that butter?
How are you,
dude?
That guy's always breaking people's legs
and nightclubs and knocking people out.
He's fucking crazy motherfucker.
Right?
He's angry as fuck.
Why is he so angry?
I Dunno.
I never met the guy.
I was over to meet him some day,
you know,
that's a,
it's one of the few people left on my
bucket list of people that haven't met
his butter.
Hurry.
Oh,
I would be a super fan boy if I met
butter.
And then you took a photo with somebody
and you were saying it was on your
instagram.
You're saying there's only one more
left?
Yeah.
Who was that was chuckling.
I saw him at a club here and all they
wouldn't not long ago.
And I was like one minute left and that
Mike Tyson,
I've met a chocolate though.
You know,
there's been a lot of people that uh,
I've had the honor of meeting and yeah,
that was a big one.
And I was like,
oh,
I don't want to be a fanboy of,
I like this.
Yeah.
It's hard not to be a fan boy.
That was like my hero when I was a kid
is Badr Hari and jail.
What does he doing now?
Z?
There's talking about getting them in
Gloria.
I think they were trying to,
but uh,
I don't know.
He's so God damn crazy.
Like there's a video of him.
Some guy was working in at the front
desk of a hotel and I don't know what
the fuck he said,
but bothered it and like it,
so we went behind the counter and
smacked him in his head it was security
camera footage.
I hope the guy said something and,
and it's not the butter hard,
he's just a bully because let these guys
are fucking bullies,
you know?
Yeah,
I hope so too.
I mean it's laughable.
Luxembourg verhoeven on or higher
superfight rumors are true.
Oh Shit.
Yeah,
that's,
that's a bad mother fucker.
Rico Verhoeven is a bad motherfucker.
I'm very impressed with that guy.
You want to talk about that big athletic
heavyweight with sick endurance and just
worldclass kickboxing skill and fucking
big.
That dude is enormous.
Not a small guy.
That guy is fucking huge.
Yeah,
he's huge.
He's just a giant giant man.
He's a giant man,
giant and like really good endurance for
a big guy.
He pushes a great paint.
Really good boxing.
He was like part of a Tyson fury is a
camp for Klitschko was he really?
Isn't that interesting?
There's a gypsy world heavyweight
champion.
A lot of this guy's a gypsy gypsy.
Is that a bad word or traveler I guess
is the better one traveler.
That's what I like to call it.
Pikey hiking the same.
The pikeys bad.
I think pikey is like not that's a
derogatory term.
Sorry folks.
Sorry.
It's fucking language.
Play travelers like travelers.
There is a tricky one because in some
places the Eskimo is a,
is an insult.
But in like Alaska,
they don't have a problem with Eskimo.
Like the people that live in certain
parts of Alaska,
apparently they,
that's what they call them.
So they like it.
It's Omni issue.
Depends is totally geographical.
Who else would be,
uh,
an Eskimo outside of Alaska in you?
It's in you.
It's a,
they live a different parts of the
world.
Uh,
Canada,
I think in Canada,
Eskimo may be a,
an insult because they're not from
Alaska.
I just think they're the same people,
but they just prefer a different name
maybe.
Well,
I like the people in Canada.
They call themselves a,
the natives call them cells.
First nations.
Hmm.
Yeah.
The,
you can't,
you can't call them.
Indians are not Indians.
So it's like,
it's essentially the same kind of
people.
They're just in a different spot.
It's all fucking weird,
man.
It's all weird.
But yeah,
you gotta be careful.
Travelers calm.
A traveler traveler,
I think is there.
He's a funny guy though.
He fucked with Vladimir Klitschkos head.
He really fucked with his head.
He's a funny motherfucker.
He's funny.
Very funny.
Hilarious.
It's terrible sanger though.
Tell him to stop singing.
Go.
But they're having this a heavyweight
title and getting to go to the family is
a trailer.
Are they really?
That makes sense.
And uh,
who else?
Uh,
over cross?
He's another one.
Really.
Wow.
Tough fuckers,
but makes sense.
Theory does like interviews from inside
his trailer.
He's like,
does he really?
I just saw one the other day.
He still has a trailer still as a world
champion.
Yup.
He's living in a trailer.
Yep.
Whoa.
The traveler.
Hmm.
It's proud of is,
do you think he keeps the house too?
I don't know.
I have no idea.
Yeah.
I don't think,
I don't think being a traveler from what
might know about,
well I don't really fuck do I know,
but I don't think that there,
it's about the money thing because I
think a lot of those people have,
have,
uh,
have money in flashy stuff and whatever.
It's just like their way of life.
Oh,
really?
You had to be able to pick up and go
everyone.
So they just don't want to have roots.
They liked to be able to just have the,
what they call him caravans.
I saw them and he snatch.
That's my favorite movie of all time.
Favorite movie of all time.
I could fucking recite that entire
movie.
There he is.
Yeah.
Tyson fury is fucking enormous.
Heavyweight boxer can't even stand up in
his trailer.
He's too tall for his own trailer.
And that's where you actually get of in.
Hey,
if I can get out of it.
Yeah.
That be like tags that Brad Pitt movie.
That was a good fucking moving.
Such a good movie.
I had no idea those people talk.
This is just train Jackson before that
movie.
And then I got stuck watching these
movies are these uh,
videos on youtube.
What?
These travelers are challenging each
other.
He ever watched those I fucking love has
the best.
Oh,
you're a fucking piece of Shite,
Jackie.
What?
The kids,
the kids.
All the kids are still good.
Yeah.
Fucking hang me.
The flood.
Yeah,
I'm going to plug you good.
Yeah.
But they had these fucking bare knuckle
fights,
man.
And they have no rounds.
They have some weird rules and they're
all fight with their fucking jeans on.
Yeah.
They have like their own court system
and like that's if you have a dispute,
that's why it's somewhat like food
dispute and then the fight over it and
like when you know it's settled,
when it's settled,
it's settled.
We'll have like a fucking,
like a file full on fucking fight.
And that's like,
that's the law.
Like okay,
he won.
He wins.
Like keep that.
He's,
you know what I mean?
Yeah.
It's crazy.
But it's just interesting to watch it
all play out on youtube because you
might have heard about all this stuff
before or you hear about in stories and
legends,
but I think our age is the first age
that's ever had a chance to wash these
guys.
Challenge each other.
Huh?
I'm calling you out your fucking bag of
shade and there's a ton of them online.
They're really interesting to watch
because you,
you're getting a peek into like a very,
um,
uh,
very sensitive culture sensitive in that
like there's not,
they don't have,
there's not like a lot of history behind
it in terms of uh,
you know,
like a documented culture and they could
go away like that.
That's something that might not be here
a hundred years from now.
Like we might be watching a type of
people or a group of people that are
living a certain way that,
you know,
things might change and the next hundred
years and they might integrate back into
society like these fucking people,
the halls one already knows about and
you're going round the first round is
telling people you're the case.
What?
I'm going to Burger King.
How are you the Kenyan fuck off second.
I'm going to fight in your whole life.
Oh,
neat
challenge there.
There's one like little bit to Jerry,
which I left
this fucking guy
two young kids in is so fucking funny.
Oh my God.
Red Wine.
You're yet the hallmark knows who's
talking to me out.
I just think it's so interesting to see
all this stuff on youtube because like
we have like a view into this culture
that we just never,
you never would have gotten this before.
You would have heard,
you know,
Patio Brian called out mickey fuck face
and they met in the swamps and duked it
out.
But,
but see in this,
and again,
I mean,
you know,
I would like them to be able to keep
their way of life and all that.
I'm not saying that they shouldn't be
able to do this,
but I'm saying that it's possible that
that might not be there in 50 years.
I these people,
they don't really have us,
they don't have a country,
they don't have a city.
So it's,
it's kind of delicate.
Their existence is fairly delicate.
It's not like you're talking about
people like,
oh these are guys that live in Detroit
and Detroit always had this sort of like
a gypsy community.
No,
no,
they,
they fucking travel around and a lot of
places we travel,
people don't want them there.
I have friends who are from London and
they had a house that is in some suburb,
I don't know what they call it in
England,
I don't think they call it a suburb in
the country.
They had this house and these travelers
moved next to their house.
There was like a lot next to their
house.
They just set up shop party till fucking
four o'clock in the morning through
garbage in the street and nobody could
do shit.
They're all scared to say anything.
Everyone's scared to say anything and
you can't like he,
there's no laws.
Like there's no law against what they're
doing.
Cause there's like,
you can't discriminate against these,
these travelers.
So it's this weird situation where
people are trying to sell their houses.
Nobody wants to buy it.
Property values crashed and these proper
English people that I'm friends with,
we're trying to explain the terrors of
these people move in next door and I'm
chuckling,
oh your second house on a,
what are you going to do?
These people just move next door and
they're fucking party.
And what can you do though?
Good challenge him if I fucking win.
You've got to move.
Exactly.
How do you listen?
You hear me?
Y'All fucking Babish Scheid I'm going to
kick you out of my neck and my God,
my snooty neighborhood.
Yeah.
The uh,
they just set up shop and started
partying and people like what in the
fuck q magine if you like one of those
pinkies out teetotaller type English
people who are super proper and these
motherfuckers moved next door started
bloodying each other up having bonfires.
It's,
I don't know,
there's something about the way they
live is fun.
I like something about it.
I'm glad they were around.
Yeah.
That's exciting.
Yeah,
I think so too.
Yeah.
Let them be them with them.
Live their lives.
I mean,
sorry,
sorry if you're there in your house.
I'm sorry.
Two Yard.
But yeah,
I'm sorry if they fucked up your house.
Yeah.
But,
but it's kind of fun there around.
Awesome.
I hope they win in the greater picture
of civilization.
It's an interesting,
it's an interesting element.
And on that note,
I want to wrap this up.
Sure.
Anything else?
Um,
no,
not the haters,
but no tall and nice people out there.
Shout outs to all the fans.
Oh,
shout outs,
all the fans,
you know,
uh,
never a boring fight and I'll be back
and uh,
I will come back from this like I always
have.
I'm never going to turn off tuition only
fine.
You got a great fucking attitude,
dude.
You had a great attitude,
even through losses.
And I think people do appreciate that
and I definitely appreciate the fact
that you,
you fight the way you do.
I got to tell you about this from
machine though.
Um,
it's called a frog or have you heard of
this?
A frogger.
It's called a frog.
Frogger.
It's a,
this a machine they sent him.
He just sent it to my gym.
It's a,
uh,
it's on wheels.
It's like a full body movement.
It's designed for,
um,
like other marketing and stuff.
Football players.
And it's like a fuck can you,
can you look it up?
I don't even know how to explain the
Shin and what are you doing?
It's like you're on wheels and you can
only do it in place or you can do it.
Uh,
you could actually raise people in it.
And it's a,
I'm telling you,
it's like a good to find it.
You raise people that you can race in
it.
If I can show you this,
can you find you find it Jamie?
Nope.
Do you know the company that makes it?
I had to.
We're going to get this information.
We're really done well in this whole
flux on wheels.
Like I'm playing charades.
It's a,
it's a frog,
but it's not.
It's a frogger.
A football players use it.
MMM.
Okay.
I'm looking at this thing.
Oh,
this is crazy.
It's like Nielsen Spans here.
Feet is like,
oh my God.
It's like doing a burpee.
Is Jamie sign this thing ever working?
Jamie,
find this.
What is the name of the link or what is
the name of that thing?
It's what I'm looking at folks.
It's like sort of like a super advanced
version of an AB wheel,
but you have one on your feet and
washing your hands and you're pushing
forward with the one on your hands where
it's like a almost like a cart and then
you're pulling the AB wheel that's
connected to your feet forward and
pushing frog fitness.
I just pulled it up cause you kind of
looked like a frog while you're doing
it.
Here it is frog fitness,
fill out one of our forms or click here
to head to our new website.
So they sent me two of these to the gym
for me to try out and I was like Oh that
looks like fun.
This is like,
you know,
you'd be like a burpee and you like
almost immediate exhaustion like that.
Yeah that thing is one of the hardest
workouts I've ever had and they're
marketing it for like a lot of the NFL
training camps are getting it cause it's
like the same position for right for
football,
but it's a,
it's a beast of a thing.
So that would make sense that it would
be really good for wrestling too.
Then,
yeah,
the new evolution in fitness.
Okay.
So it's got resistance bands.
So you push the forward cart and the
resistance bands,
uh,
are resisting you as you push forward
and then you pull your legs forward.
Wow.
This looks fucking bad ass.
It works every part of your body.
And it was like immediate exhaustion.
Like wow.
It's like nothing else I've ever used
before.
It's fucking awesome.
But no,
Kenny man.
And do you feel any benefit of this when
you're a sparring or when you're
training or,
I used it for like cardio,
I even used it.
Um,
and you can read,
you can set it so that you can,
you'd be in one place,
you know,
so that you're not going anywhere.
You know,
it seems like you would get up really
hard workouts to it.
But I'll do that with my altitude
machine cause it just zaps you get so
fucking tired so fast.
So I try to do that even at high
altitude.
Okay.
So this girl was using it to do like
cleans and presses and she's doing like
rose with it.
So the wheel also acts as resistance
with the bands.
Yeah.
You can put like a 160 pounds in the
thing or something.
It's something else.
It's nuts.
Wow.
Okay.
So you use fat or bands and then it
makes more resistance as you push
forward is just the guy who invented it.
He looks like a frog.
Sorry Buddy.
Not in a bad way.
Frogs are awesome.
Frogs get your high if you're like,
um,
so this,
this one right here.
Like that guy's got it fully loaded up.
Oh Wow.
Look at that.
That is interesting.
Map.
Okay.
So you could put a bunch.
There's a bunch of different ways to use
that thing.
Hmm.
Wow.
I like it must give you a fucking hell
of a core workout.
How it's,
it's,
it's hard to,
it's fucking terrible.
It's fun,
but I fucking hate it and like,
I hate it.
It's exhausting.
Exhausting.
What is your strength and conditioning
when you're not working with curse on
like what do you do?
Do you just mostly concentrate on fight
preparation,
like pad work,
sparring,
bag work,
things along those lines?
I'm not working with Kirsten and I run,
I'll do a lot of sprints,
would be allowed to bought us.
And then,
um,
mostly explained to bottle that people
don't want to bother 50th,
the interval thing.
It's eight rounds of 15 seconds of work
or 20 seconds of work and 10 seconds of
rest.
And when you're doing is you're going as
fast and as hard as you can for 20
seconds,
getting your heart rate as high as
possible and then immediately went,
20 seconds is up,
you have 10 seconds of rest.
So you're training your,
your heart rate to get used to spiking
and they come back down in your,
you're training your,
it can increase your,
uh,
your vo two Max,
like incredibly.
And to bought us is like really a big
part of my,
my cardio sessions.
Yeah.
It's an amazing protocol that was
invented that I don't know who invented
it.
So it'd be a four minute round total,
eight times of eight of 20 seconds.
Right.
But it sort of goes along the same lines
of what we're talking about with nick
curse on is doing or what a pebble Tatsu
lead is doing.
It's not about massive amounts of work.
It's amount doing it smart and doing it
the right way.
So these 22nd sprint and he's ten second
brakes,
man,
what a massive impact it has on your
cardio.
And he can do that with anything.
You'd be on a,
you could be running,
you could be happy,
even hit pads with it,
you know,
do a bag work,
hard as you can for 20 seconds.
And then 10 seconds off.
You think about that sort of hellified
is anyway,
have a 22nd bursts and you're like 10
seconds and getting your shit together
and the 22nd bursts.
I do that a lot.
And then,
uh,
lately I've been doing a lot more just
pad work and speed work and I'm using a
double end bag a lot,
you know,
I'm trying to get,
um,
for a long time I was trying to be,
very physical and very,
my outworking the other person and being
like more aggressive and I'm trying to
get more to,
to uh,
speed and technique,
you know,
then they tried to outwork people.
There's definitely,
there's definitely a smart move.
Yeah,
definitely a smart way to go.
And it was exactly what I did last
Friday night,
but then,
uh,
Jason Wellness Wellness Day at the time
of four,
it was like a really good example of
that.
And that was a very good example of
Yeah.
And wellness is a dangerous
motherfucker.
That guy's very dangerous.
He hits hard.
He's a,
he's a real threat.
That was a real good fight.
Nope.
Yeah.
So,
uh,
all right brother.
Well,
um,
oh,
let me shut up one more.
Kinetic.
Sorry Buddy.
Uh,
clean addict motor sports and Long
Beach.
They,
uh,
you see my instagram,
they gave me a Ferrari and a feeling of
is that real?
Yeah.
They gave me a fry for like a week until
the fight and then,
uh,
give it back,
went to the,
went to the fight and then I got a brand
new zero six outside right now.
Really?
They're just letting you borrow cars,
you know,
they gave me cars to a drive so I don't
have to buy whatever.
And you know their favor.
The high end car lot.
They have a fucking super nice cars.
You can rent them.
You can buy on me.
Can we?
Or Yeah.
Kinetic motorsports.
All right.
Powerful motor sports.
Anybody gives you a Ferrari
there on my good side.
Get that fucking thing.
Oh Shit.
What was,
which one was that?
It's a four or five.
Eight Italia.
What a beautiful car.
Looks so good.
Look at the design of that thing.
So good Joe.
It's just so spectacular.
It's like a car from the future.
Like when you were a kid,
you thought about a car in the future.
That's what you like.
And then I had a fucking Ferrari
Testarossa poster on my wall is child's,
you know what I mean?
Like this is a talk about bucket list
shit.
Yeah,
right there when that,
when that infocus piece came out and
they texted it to me,
um,
I was driving in the Ferrari just
fucking when I,
when they gave me that,
it was like a good two hours where I was
just like,
ah,
I'm losing my shit.
Right.
But I'm driving in the Ferrari and I get
a text and uh,
it was,
uh,
the boats were social media team sends
me in that video and I'm watching this
video of how far I've come and what I've
done for the sport and that can't stop
crazy and focus piece in the driver's
seat of Ferrari.
It was a good feeling.
That's ridiculous.
Dana White's the same way when he was a
kid and he was in love with Testa.
Rossa like everybody was at watched
Miami Vice.
So he had one made,
he had one done up with a custom
interior to real stereo.
Apparently that's like a big no,
no.
Like people don't want to fuck with the
original insides of the Ferrari.
He's like,
fuck you.
He had done up,
but he was like,
I finally got a test.
Terosa those big lines on the side,
you know.
And that was the car where kids,
fuck.
Yeah.
All right.
Joe Schilling,
uh,
one eight,
seven on twitter.
Uh,
Joe Schilling on Instagram,
which Joe underscores shilling on
instagram and snapchat.
Snapchat,
Joe Dash Schilling.
Hey,
whoever's got my name on snapchat,
give it up.
Come on,
I'll get on snapchat.
I'll give you a shout out.
Who does that anyway?
Like who does that and who are these
people that have other people as their
profile picture and use other people's
name?
Like,
give me a break.
All right.
Thanks brother.
Appreciate it man.
And uh,
that US know.
Next fight we'll have you back on again
for sure.
And pump that up and let everybody know
about it.
Always a pleasure,
Joe.
Always pleasure.
See you too,
my brother.
Thank you very much.
All right,
we'll be back tomorrow,
folks.
Thank you very much.
Bye.