Jamie bam,
motherfucker,
and we're live with filthy skills by the
way,
if people wondering what filthy skills
is,
this is a hilarious story because I just
saw you wearing.
I ran into you in salt lake.
I didn't know I was.
I was going to be there by the way.
Cameron Hanes,
my friend,
but winter.
Oh my camera here.
Wildlife conservationist to ultra
marathon runner.
Ultimate Badass.
I was.
I'm in Salt Lake skiing with my family
at the same time.
Was it called the great western is a
Western hunting exposition.
Conservation Exposition,
something like that.
Which I really want to just drag some of
the,
the biggest,
diehard vegans were the most.
The angry ones just let them loose there
and go wander around.
They'd go there,
they'd go bonkers.
They'd run into walls and probably,
you know,
pee themselves.
It's,
it's all just skulls and shit and mounts
and the cool stuff and places you can go
to shoot your own food.
But uh,
you were wearing this filthy skill.
Shirts.
I'm like,
what?
What is filthy skills?
And I've been seeing it on your
instagram.
What is filthy skills?
This is hilarious.
So some guy sent you this and we'll put
it up on the screen so you can see it on
the youtube.
Some guy sent this,
which is a a fuck.
This is a photo.
The youtube comment with this guy have
Yada Jamie.
Whereas some guy said to you,
here it is.
Fuck you for destroying our world with
your filthy hunting skill.
You're filthy hunting skill.
Why don't you kill yourself instead to
reduce the population dumb ass.
First of all,
the spelling on this is atrocious.
I.
It's almost like he got his dog to write
that forum.
Yeah.
F K space letter.
You space for district got destroying,
right?
Yeah.
World,
that's a tough word.
Yeah.
He's like,
he's.
He's weird.
He's like populations,
good faculties,
good.
But your.
He does.
You are people that do.
You are.
What do you do with all that extra time
that you spend,
say between like why?
Oh you,
what do you do with,
you know,
you don't have to spend that time now
working those fingers.
Very efficient.
Now you're filthy hunting skills.
So you saw that and were like,
hey,
there's a couple of things I thought I
did not know I had the power to destroy
the world.
I am more powerful than I than I ever
knew.
That's impressive,
isn't it?
I said,
hey,
I have filthy honeys.
I thought that was sort of like a
compliment,
you know?
So it's hence the shirt.
There's a,
there's such a disconnect going on this
world right now.
We were talking about this today while
we're practicing.
It seems like there's some sort of a
culture war.
There's a movement of people right now,
there's this whole eat what you kill
movement and a lot of people are
rejecting the idea of factory farming
and rejecting the idea of a buying
process.
Food and buying cows that are locked up
in pens and treated like a commodity
rather than like a living animal.
Right.
And going out into the woods and hunting
and getting their own food and
connecting to this sort of primal
existence and self sufficient self
sufficient.
So what I like about it,
I don't,
I don't rely on anybody to feed my
family and a lot of people love that,
but then there's this group of people
that are completely disconnected from
the way the wild works that are very
angry about all this.
And so there's some bizarre
conversations I've been having with some
very well meaning very intelligent
people.
They're very nice people.
And this is,
this is the,
this is where there's a big
misconception here like I got,
I got into it with a gang of people
recently and I wish you even say I got
into it because I've kind of given up on
insulting people online because I don't
get anything out of it.
Right?
I get it.
If you don't like it,
you don't like me.
I get it.
I liked me,
I liked me.
I'm a nice guy.
I mean if you meet,
if you meet me and you communicate with
me,
Nice.
Even if we disagree,
I guarantee we're going to have a
pleasant conversation.
I'm a nice person,
right?
So when someone insults me or says nasty
shit or it makes a nasty video about me,
I don't watch it.
I'm not going to.
When people want you to respond,
Why would I?
I don't have enough time.
I don't know enough time to spend with
the people I love.
I don't have time to hang out with you.
What am I going to have 15 extra minutes
to watch a video and then make my own
video and I don't have time for this
world.
This life is short.
Okay?
So I get that people are upset,
but the core,
the core message that everybody's
getting out,
there's one of two messages.
One message is you should never eat
animals at all and then we should live
this idyllic existence where everyone
lives off nuts and twigs and shit and
vegetables and that's all you eat.
Pine cones.
You can.
That's fine.
You can do that.
But then there's the other that use port
and I support that.
The best way to live in this modern
world is to go out and get your own meat
problem with that.
Of course,
this is a real problem.
Everybody can't do that.
There's not enough wildlife,
there's not enough time and,
and I don't think that we,
we think everybody should do that.
No,
that our point is,
and I think people like us is you don't
have to do it,
but don't condemn it.
Yeah,
don't condemn it because we,
I mean as you said in my intro,
conservationist hunters are conservation
is we're the one that's paying the money
for habitat for all these biologists to
tell us exactly how many animals are out
there.
They got boots on the ground and they're
out there with the animals doing the
number of surveys.
I'm figuring out harvest harvest numbers
to try to achieve carrying capacity.
The guys online who think that grizzly
bears are almost extinct and like,
how could you kill a bear?
You know,
they want to kill me because I killed a
bear in Alaska that they probably have
no clue how many bear running around
Alaska,
but somehow
they know that I shouldn't have killed
it.
They don't know how many are there.
They don't know what the bear with the
bear population,
where I killed two brown bear,
which are grizzly bear and a black bear.
They don't know that those bears need to
be controlled.
Otherwise they decimate the Moose
population.
It's,
it's all about Moose,
everything.
And part of that balance is humans.
So people always say,
well,
animals will take care of themselves.
You know,
they've always,
you know,
it's worked out,
predators kill Blah Blah,
blah.
We're just interfering.
Well,
yeah,
we're interfering also because of your
house,
you know,
we're taking habitat so we can't let the
animals sorted out because we're the
ones encroaching on habitat.
So we are in that process.
We are at the top of the food chain.
We require habitat to.
They require habitat.
So there's a balance.
It's all part of the equation.
It
is.
And this balance is,
there's some parts of it that are set in
place before you and I were born and
before a lot of these people that are
arguing everybody before everybody was
arguing about this has been born.
The cities were already in place long
time ago.
Um,
the food chain has already been in
place,
the market chain has been in place as
far as like getting food to
supermarkets.
Most of the supermarkets that are in
existence were there long before you and
I started shopping at them and that's,
that's a part of this equation of human
beings.
The,
another part of the equation of human
beings is what you're talking about with
predators.
And this is one of the things that I had
a discussion about what the guys who I
really like and there's some
misconception I didn't like these guys,
the guys that made that movie cowspiracy
Oh right.
They're very good guys.
They're very smart guys.
They're,
they're,
they're vegans.
They became vegans while factory
farming.
Well,
it's a lot about factory farming and a
lot of it is about the amount of waste
methane,
uh,
that gets into the atmosphere because of
factory farming.
Um,
the,
the actual waste as far as their,
their shit,
the cows shit.
And what would the amount of devastation
that does to our environment and how
much actual land these animals need to
graze in order to feed them.
These are really complicated numbers and
disputed.
They went with the extreme on one end
and there's some other people I'm having
tomorrow.
Doug,
during my friend from Minnesota,
Minnesota,
Wisconsin.
My,
my buddy from,
um,
he's uh,
from the Steve Show mediator.
He has that a large a ranch out in,
um,
uh,
what the name of this you hunted out
there and I'm trying to figure the name
of the town is.
He's a very weird small town.
Anyway,
he's in Wisconsin and this really cool
area where it's the,
um,
you know,
they have a,
it's called the driftless area where the
glaciers missed,
so it's all hilly and gorgeous and
beautiful and that's where he lives.
He pays his cows out there and he's
going to come in and give his
perspective on a lot of this stuff is
right.
Um,
but they,
they had this really strange idea about
wolves and the strength that I had to
correct them.
And this idea about,
you know,
that we've hunted the wolves to near
extinction and now the reintroduction p
and won't haunt them again.
And you really have to stop that.
I'm like,
man,
you gotta this is wolves are fucking
cool and this is one of the things that
I said these guys,
nobody wants to eliminate wolves,
but throughout human history,
long before we were around,
people have had a problem with wolves
and there's a reason for that.
All the big bad wolf stories,
all the Little Red Riding Hood,
all that Shit.
It's because wolves are fucking
terrifying.
They are very,
very dangerous and I brought up the
whole world war one incident with the
Germans and the Russians had a fucking
cease fire because so many of them were
getting killed by wolves.
They made an agreement.
They're like,
look,
obviously we got a real problem that's
bigger than us,
like 10 people.
Let's stop killing each other for a
little while and Kelly's fucking wolves,
and they killed the wolves and then went
back to killing each other.
It's a crazy story.
That is.
And then there's the other story from
the 14 hundreds in Paris were wolves
killed more than 40 people in Paris.
The city of Paris was overrun with
bulbs.
That's insane.
Wolves are killing machines and you have
to keep their populations down and if
you don't,
you run into huge problems.
People bring up.
There's this video that people bring up
all the time.
How wolves changed rivers.
Um,
and it's a fascinating video.
We played it on here before.
The problem with that video is the guy
who made that video is fucking nuts.
Okay.
And he is a romantic to the extreme and
the idea of introducing keystone
predators into these areas where they
haven't been before.
His idea was that wolves are making
things better for all these other
animals by getting rid of the,
but they're not.
They're decimating the elk population.
And there was a thing written by
scientists disputing all of his claims
that were in that video.
So then I want to like,
what's this guy's deal about?
So I listened to this NPR podcast on
him.
This mother fucker wants to bring lions
back to Europe.
He was,
he's like,
there's parts of the UK that are empty
and we could reintroduce lions and
hyenas,
but pitcher,
Yada,
Yada.
A good idea.
I'm to bring you case not that big.
You're going to bring violence like
actual African lions and his ideas that
they found these,
these fossils of these lions that
existed there thousands of years ago,
so then it'd be back.
He wants to reintroduce them.
Well,
people have,
by the way,
this guy was suicidal and depressed,
like to the extreme ready to kill
himself and then decided to what he
calls rewilding.
He reintroduced himself to the wild,
started experiencing while and fell in
love with wildlife and nature and that's
what pulled him up out of this.
And now it's his mission.
Hey,
I'm in love with wildlife and nature to
mystically,
but realistically.
Yeah.
Well it's.
I do want to say one thing because we've
talked about factory farming and you
know,
the downside of it.
We're not lumping ranchers,
regular ranchers that
raise cattle.
I mean,
my family is a cattle ranching family in
eastern Oregon,
so I'm not talking about,
you know,
cows that are out with enough pasture
out there and then,
and then being killed,
taken mark and kill.
We're talking about that.
Animals that don't leave the cage,
that are standing in their own feces and
just never move and never have a life
and then have a bullet shot through
their head in their debt.
You know,
we're talking the,
that extreme.
That's not everybody.
I have a lot of respect for farmers and
ranchers and uh,
I mean,
so we don't want to lump everybody into
the ranches.
Are All factory farmers?
No,
they're certainly not.
And one of the things that I noticed
when I was in Montana when I first went
hunting with Rinella,
we went through the Missouri breaks and
there was all these cows wandering
around and I was like,
what is the deal with this?
Well,
those cows literally wander free on
public land they have.
And this is what this Oregon nutty shit
is about.
And within Nevada nutty shit was about
with all these crazy ranchers that want
to fucking take over the government.
Lincoln.
Yeah,
that's not good.
But the,
what do they call it?
[inaudible].
That's my favorite by far.
We don't even know.
We never found out who came up with that
description.
Someone was claiming that someone on the
podcast came up with that description,
but when we were in Montana,
we.
That's when I first got introduced to
this.
They,
they.
These animals are literally roam free
and wild.
They sleep outside,
they eat outside,
they wander through and then they're
corralled and when they're brought to
slaughter then their corralled and so
for the majority of their life they live
off the land.
Almost like an elk.
Yeah,
like a wild animal essentially.
Yeah.
Big Step there.
Someone's someone's property.
Some people have a hard time with that.
They have a hard time with the idea of
property,
of an animal being property and I get
that too,
man.
Another thing I've watched recently was
this penn and teller from that.
You ever see that show bullshit?
No,
it's a great show.
'Em that they used to do on showtime,
but one of them they did was on pita and
the Animal Liberation Organization or
whatever the fuck are heard of that
foundation for free except Holy Shit,
violent arsonists burning down buildings
was spray painting,
Vegan power and these.
I mean just like the nutty as shit,
but they don't think that people should
have pets.
They don't think,
and here's one of the best parts about
it.
One of the women that was in this
program who works for Peta was also a
diabetic.
This is where you got a buckle yourself
in because there's only one way you get
that diabetes medicine.
It's from animals,
so it's an animal product,
and so she was saying that she didn't
think that she was a hypocrite because
that product saves her life so she could
save more animals.
Well,
guess what?
Fuck face.
That's what hunting is.
Exactly.
That sort of hunting is exactly.
I mean if you,
if you go out,
you hunt a wolf and I'm not,
I'm not into hunting wolves,
but if they have to control their
population like that,
not in a hunting,
anything.
I don't meet somebody.
Somebody is got to kill them.
Somebody's got to do it and they're
doing it by the way there.
And also,
here's another thing about
California,
California mountain lions are a giant
issue.
There's an article that I posted up
recently.
Pull it up,
Jamie,
that someone.
Someone sent me yesterday,
they did this like you cannot hunt
mountain lions in California.
There's a reason for it is not here.
It's not logical.
It's all based on people who are animal
lovers who got into a position of power
or voted this in.
Well,
there's the study they're finding
because they killed these mountain lions
when they start moving into
neighborhoods and killing pets and it's
super common.
They've killed.
What's the number of mountain lions
they've killed this year because it's.
It's crazy.
Okay.
Here with a 170 107 mountain lions were
killed last year legally by the
government,
so that's 107 mountain lions and people
didn't get tagged for,
which means that's money that didn't go
into the state coffers.
Then it didn't go to conservation.
It's just money.
It's.
It works.
The opposite state is paying.
Exactly.
Yeah.
State is paying for going into the hole.
They're going in the hole.
Instead of going into the profit margin,
which would they normally did in the
black and red.
I'm colorblind matter.
So they analyze these mountain lions and
they found it.
Mostly what they're eating is pets.
They're.
They're eating fucking.
Only five percent had eaten deer.
Right?
Well,
they're going to go with the easiest
target.
Yeah,
but that seems sane.
Only five.
Granted,
a lot of these animals,
they're there.
They're killing their already problem
animals.
Well,
in what happens with lions are so
territorial,
so the younger lions come up and the
more dominant lions have their area,
so the younger ones are forced to go
somewhere else.
They can't really cross.
So they go somewhere else.
What's left is cities and neighborhoods
and residential and that's where the
pets are.
So I mean those are probably juvenile
lions mostly and down in there and it's
just a matter of time before a little
kid gets snatched or whatever and people
don't want to talk about that or think
about that.
But that's the reality of it.
They're just predators.
They're killers.
They're going for the easiest target
right now.
That's a dogs and cats,
but they don't care.
They don't care.
They're not hugging each other and
crying like we've seen billboards of
that either.
We're going to get into that in a
moment,
but I think this is what I'm trying to
get at.
Um,
this is where I think there's a dispute
and a misconception in the misconception
is that hunters are all these evil
people that want to hunt these animals
to kill them so they can put them on
their wall.
Almost all of the money that goes to
fish and game fish and wildlife
management organizations that protect
wetlands,
that protect public lands for,
for camping and for,
for people to use and people to enjoy
and go hike the money to support those
comes from hunting.
Yeah.
People hate that.
They hate it.
But by far,
by far,
the amount of money that comes from
conservation comes from hunting by far
for the amount of money goes for
conservation,
for the animals,
for habitat
restoration.
You know,
that show we were just at in Utah,
um,
they had a mule deer tag that was
auctioned off.
They give for an antelope island tagged.
They give two tags.
One is in the drawing,
so you have very small chance of getting
it because there's huge bucks.
Whereas antelope island,
I don't know,
Utah,
I'm not sure exactly where it is.
There isn't an actual island.
I don't know.
I don't know if it's just a place they
call antelope island or if it's an
actual island.
Jamiel find out he is a state park.
Yeah,
it's,
I knew it was a park,
but I didn't know if it's an actual
island or not.
Um,
uh,
but anyway,
so one is a drawing.
There it is.
So it's,
is that the Great Salt Lake there?
Yeah.
So it's a,
you see that as set out into the great
salt lake and it's not,
it's not a detached island or doesn't
look like it was just a long peninsula.
Yeah.
So it's a peninsula they call antelope
island and that's,
there's huge bucks and I think they're
sheep.
They're also.
But the bucks are what draw the draw the
money.
So they auctioned one off and it went
for $410,000 for one deer tag and that
most of that money,
90 percent 10 percent goes to a to
funding the auction and doing all the
things that's required there.
Ninety percent of that 400,
$10,000 goes right to habitat
restoration on the island.
I'm building a water water sources,
enhancing those re relocating animals
off that peninsula there because the
genetics,
our genetics are so good to and the
bucks are big and the sheep are big,
so they're really relocate those
superior genetics throughout Utah.
So then you might not draw that tag or
you might not have $410,000,
but those genetics are spread throughout
Utah.
So they're spread in areas where general
hunters have the access to.
And uh,
it's just,
it's all positive.
It's all positive for the state park.
And you know,
anti hunters will say,
well,
if you really cared about the animals,
you just,
you know,
do the 400,
$10,000 and not go hunting.
Well,
it is true.
What is it an anti hunter do that?
Well,
here's,
here's a part of the problem.
There's a,
there's a bunch of problems with,
with all these discussions.
And a big part of it is that the people
that are arguing against the hunting,
they,
they don't regularly go into the wild,
into these habitats,
in these environments and see how
brutally hard they are for these animals
to survive anyway.
It's not like if you kill a buck that
buck live to be five years old,
you might be taking a year off it's
life.
That's right.
No,
there's,
there's no.
There's no 100 year old deer out there.
That was the long,
long great life.
And this is the idea of one of the parts
of hunting that actually aids in
conservation is when you get a mature
buck and you harvest that mature buck,
you are allowing the younger deer to
breed where they might not have gotten
the opportunity.
And you're also in a lot of cases,
saving their lives because they get
killed and fights with older deer,
like a lot of die
from fights.
People find them all the time.
They literally stab each other to death.
They don't have those antlers to look
cool.
No,
they don't have those therapists.
They slam into each other.
That's what they do.
Same with elk.
Yeah.
I mean when you and I were in Colorado
was one of the coolest fucking things we
saw is when.
Remember when we went down in near that
little creek area when there was,
there was like a huge herd of 20 elk
together and those elk were duking it
out and slamming into each other.
Oh,
that sounds amazing.
Well,
here's another thing that I don't think
antennas realize.
You know,
you go out for an extended period and
the killing,
the actual killing is such a small part
of the hunt,
you know?
I mean it's those experiences.
Like when we saw those bulls fighting
and we saw,
I think there were seven bowls and
there's one nice bowl at 3:50 class
bowl.
He was a herd bull,
but their satellite bowls spread
throughout on the APP.
He's,
he kept him pushed out and they were
jostling around and we were there.
We didn't kill anything,
but the experience of that night was one
I'll never forget.
We had a bull sneak in behind us to 15
yards and a nice bowl.
A bowl that would have been a great
bullet for you to kill and it didn't
happen,
but it was just like the adrenaline of
that experience.
I mean,
he was right there behind the bush.
right there.
So close screaming,
but nothing died.
No it.
But we are predators.
We were predators.
They were prey and that's,
that's life.
That's life in the mountains,
right?
That's how it works.
Even if we didn't have a bow,
even if we weren't there to kill
anything,
if we just had calls,
so we were just calling them in,
it would have been an amazing experience
because when you were there with
essentially as wild and animal as you're
ever going to get.
I mean North American elk is a 1000
pound,
gigantic wild animal with a tree growing
out of its head and it's living the way
it's lived for thousands of years and
you know,
you as a person who lives in Oregon and
me as a person who lives in California,
we travel into their land.
We we hike in to where they're at and we
experience this wild existence that they
live in and we don't want to stop that.
We're not trying to kill them off.
We want more of them.
We the NS is the idea of killing a
mature one.
Would you want to take out an animal
that does not have much time left and
you help the rest of the animals survive
because of that.
You,
you make it so that the younger bulls
have a chance to thrive and breed.
Otherwise they're pushing out.
They're pushed out and they're not doing
anything and,
but,
but I will say one thing.
So you said even if we wouldn't have had
weapons,
it was still had been been amazing,
but to me it would have been different.
Yes,
it would have been different because if
I'm just an observer internally,
I feel a lot different.
I only,
I feel like I'm a Predator when I have a
weapon,
so I don't know if I could,
if I would have worked as hard,
if I would have cared as much if we were
just observing,
you know what I mean?
Because if you remember that we snuck
down,
we're sneaking or I mean we're on our
butts,
kind of scooting down in the two bowls,
were jostling around right there,
kind of sparring a little bit and we had
a small window through the brush and I
was like,
you are right,
right here.
As looking at Mike,
I said,
can you see that window?
Do you see that window?
We can get that Arrow through.
It was just that in the intensity of
that moment.
So you're a predator,
that's your pray.
How can you ethically kill it?
That's alert.
All the all it comes down to.
I mean that's why we're there.
To me,
that's everything.
You know,
it says that crunch time moment.
Well there's one of the most ridiculous
things that you see when I look at your
instagram or even my instagram,
if I rarely post a picture of a data
animal just because of that.
I'll post fish all day long and nobody
gives a shit.
Nobody gives a fuck about fish.
It's hilarious.
The,
the hierarchy,
we'll fish.
They're not alive.
Are they?
Here they are.
I believe they are.
But,
um,
if you post a picture of an elk or God
forbid a bear,
people lose their fucking minds.
And one of the things that people love
to say is if it's an original thought,
it's one of those things that did not.
They usually say,
yeah,
you're such a big moon.
How about you do that without a weapon?
I love that without what hunter has ever
killed anything in the history of MMA.
That's what hunters are.
Shit,
tell me a hunter.
Even a caveman that ever killed without
a weapon of some sort.
What are they talking about?
They're not talking about anything.
They're just talking.
They're just trying to demean you.
And I go to their fucking page and one
of them,
uh,
this guy was feeding his animals meet.
And I'm like,
that shit come from a meat tree.
He's like,
this guy was shitting all over you.
And then I go to his page,
he's got dogs,
he's got dogs.
And he's feeding them me.
I'm like,
Oh man,
there's some fucking convenient thinking
going on here.
It's,
it's so strange how many people have
these convenient patterns of thought
where they're self righteous.
They take the moral high ground,
not look,
I the only person that has any say,
the only person that has a leg to stand
on is a person who's a Vegan who doesn't
eat any,
any animal products,
okay.
That's a small percentage of the
population,
but if they want to criticize it there
and they have an argument,
they have a very small leg to stand on.
Holy ground.
When you have a conversation with them,
that's when that argument kind of falls
apart.
It does because,
okay,
v,
if they're hardcore Vegan,
fine,
but are they growing their own
vegetables?
Very few because if they're not,
they still are responsible for animals
dying.
If you've ever driven by,
if you've ever been into farmland and
say a field has been harvested once the
field is harvested,
you'll notice buzzards flying around
that field.
You know why?
Because there's a bunch of dead animals
out there.
There's rabbits that were killed during
the harvest.
There's mice,
there's all so fonds.
What it is a big problem with grouse,
whatever.
I mean those,
you know,
the combines or whatever they're using
there is just tearing everything up and
think animals are dying so you can,
unless you're growing your own
vegetables,
unless you're doing it yourself Vegan,
you're responsible for animals dying.
If your house isn't made of wood because
it's made of wood,
there's timber harvest it.
And when that timber was harvested,
animals die.
So I mean,
well they're also their habitats
displays.
So people,
well I think with their ideas,
they want to do the least harm possible.
Okay.
But a lot of them already came from a
background where they eat meat.
Like I had this one guy was fucking
arguing with me wanting to argue with me
and giving me all this grief.
And then he admits that he was a
mediator just seven months ago.
It's been a Vegan for seven months.
He's fucking 40.
So for 39 years and three months,
this motherfucker,
five months,
whatever it was is my math.
So this guy for all these were very
quick though.
Your math is very quick,
but my point is Sarah dead hunter.
Come on,
man.
You can't see that seven months ago you
were a fucking Vegan and you're shitting
out are you were you were a mediator.
You're shitting all over these people
saying it's a.
it's a moral high ground.
They elevate themselves.
There are a bunch of the red.
They're above us because we're redneck
hunters.
Right?
Same thing.
I had this kid,
he looked like he was maybe younger
twenties,
but he's,
I mean he's a very passionate about his
stance on what's right and what's wrong
and so I went to his page,
same as you.
I see a bunch of hot dogs on there and I
was like,
dude,
enjoy those hot dogs,
but before you judge me or condemn me,
why don't you live a little,
you're 20 years old,
what the hell do you know about
anything?
And all of a sudden you know what's
right and wrong,
and he's like,
he says,
I'm going to have an answer for this or
Karma or some crazy thing.
I'm like,
what do you know?
You haven't even lived yet?
Well,
not only that,
hot dogs are probably the worst.
It is one of the worst.
I mean that is ground assholes and cow
digs.
The probably one of the worst things you
could fucking eat too filled with
nitrites and nitrates and whatever's bad
for you.
I understand that they're trying to work
it out for themselves and working it out
for themselves.
A lot of times people want to condemn
people that are living a lifestyle
that's outside of their.
They decide,
hey,
I'm going to live this small carbon
footprint lifestyle where I'm going to
be humane and ethical and I'm going to
be cruelty free,
Hashtag cruelty free and I'm going to go
on it.
That's like Hashtag cruelty free.
It's like they want to tell you half of
them have fucking Vegan and their names,
which is hilarious of Vegan.
This Vegan,
that healthy,
happy Vegan fucking Vegan flowerchild
everyone's.
But it's a part of their name.
Like it's,
it's a big part of their identity and it
becomes,
it becomes like a cult and I don't mean
it like,
you know,
you have to fucking initiation and pay
dues,
but I mean it's like you're a part of a
gang and it's.
People have a tendency to do that.
Good or bad.
They have a tendency.
Hunters have a tendency to do it.
People will fucking use windows,
have a tendency to do it,
but I don't like apple.
One fucking windows and apple.
You're a piece of shit.
But.
But hunters don't have the hate that
these anti hunting vegans have.
They don't,
they don't.
I mean,
hunters don't go to their pages and who
cares?
Live your life.
Yeah,
know I get where their thought process.
They think they're doing the right
thing,
doing the right thing and there's a lot.
This is not another thing I want to
point out and I went on this twitter
page,
a discussion the other day.
I went on this rant.
I don't hate vegans have vegans that are
friends.
It's not as.
I don't know.
I'm not lumping everybody in.
You know this.
There's a small percentage of people
that are assholes that are arrogant and
outspoken and really aggressive and mean
and shitting,
and where's the cruelty free.
They're like,
why are you being cruel to other people
that are like,
look around with tolerance.
Go outside and drive for 20 minutes and
I guarantee you you're going to pass 30,
40 places that have dead animals in
them.
Every fucking supermarket you pass by
every fast food place,
every restaurant,
every gas station that's slim.
Jim's at the fucking counter or all of
that is animal.
So you.
For you to find a hunter,
the one person that you could point to
that probably kills animals in the most
ethical and humane way possible and
contribute and pastries to be,
to play part of the conservation.
Rolling.
Yeah.
You know,
and people hear these podcasts,
oh,
you fucking go to justify what you're
doing.
If you have to justify it,
there's something wrong.
No,
it's the arguments or tiresome.
There's a guy that's coming on next
week,
his name is,
uh,
how do you say his name?
Tovar.
How do you.
So really to Varsa ruling there.
That's,
that sounds so really,
he's an author and a guy that used to be
a Vegan who's not a hunter.
Right.
And panties will be bunched.
They will get sandy and tweets will be
tweeted.
Good.
It's gonna get crazy,
but I,
I just think that podcast like this and
conversations like this with a guy like
you,
like I think what you do is the best way
to do it.
I mean,
I've said this time and time again,
what you do is the best way to do it
because what you're doing,
first of all,
it's the most difficult way to do it and
you prepare your body for it in a very
fucking grueling fashion.
We worked out before we got here and you
work out every day and one of the
reasons why you work out every day,
it's fucking going through the mountains
is hard as shit.
It is.
It is hard,
man.
I never knew until I went with Rinella
the first time we went up to the
Missouri breaks.
We're climbing the mountains for seven
hours a day.
I was like,
oh,
okay.
This is fucking.
This is not going to the gym and getting
on the elliptical machine.
This is fucking constant and it's all
day and if you're packing shit,
you have to be strong.
You have to be physically strong to do.
I mean,
you remember in Colorado and we were
roughing it up that Ridge.
You know we're at the bottom of the
canyon.
Heard a bull bugling is the bull you
killed?
Yeah.
This dude takes off like a fucking
mountain goat.
I'm in pretty God damn good shape.
And I'm like.
And he's like,
don't even breathe in as fuck.
He gets to the top of the bat.
That's how you saw the bowl is at the
top of the mountain that you spotted it,
but know that that the sun was going
down and we had a lot of elements going.
I can tell the bull wasn't as good bull
just by his bugle and we'd been huffing
it down.
They're done trying to get on a bowl.
That was beautiful and we never could
get eyes on him.
But then I heard what sounded like a
mature bull and the sun going down and
that's why you train.
Right,
exactly.
That's exact situation.
You're coming out of a hole,
you're climbing,
you know,
9,000 feet.
The air is thin there and it's a race
against time essentially.
But I mean,
we made it work.
Yeah,
you don't,
you,
you are able to close the distance in a
much more efficient way because of all
your training.
And uh,
that was a good example of.
Another good example of it was the
packout.
I mean we're packing a lot of fucking
weight.
Yeah,
right.
This asshole has to fucking elk quarters
in his backpack.
So it's like 180 pounds.
And how much is that heavy?
I Dunno.
Heavy Shit.
And you basically have me on your back
and you're walking a mile with this,
you know,
and there's one,
there's a photo.
Why have I,
I'm sure I have some photos of us from,
from this very trip that we're talking
about.
We're packing these things out.
But the point is what you're doing to
acquire when you have an elk steak and
you sit down with this,
and I had this conversation with Remy
Warren about it where it's like,
it's almost like a religious experience.
He's like,
this is a precious piece of meat.
I've gone into the Wilderness vested,
I've harvested this animal and I have a
precious piece of meat.
And he goes and I treat it almost like a
baby,
like I sees in this and I cook it
perfectly and this is.
He has this intensely intimate
connection and I do with the animal that
we killed that animal that you and I
killed when I eat that thing.
I think of our time together.
I think of how difficult the hunt is.
I think of how crazy the environment is,
how beautiful the experiences.
Oh,
you're so much more to it than going
into a store and buying a squash.
Right?
You know,
and this is what people need or
understanding of state,
even beyond what buying a steak shore,
but buying even a Vegan or a vegetarian,
but your,
your vegetables,
you're disconnected from these
vegetables for the most part.
Most people are.
Yeah.
There is an intense connection with the
food that you eat.
Even if you grow it yourself,
like my wife gardens and I do as well
and she does it more than I do,
but we'll have salad from something that
we grew in our garden.
It's awesome man.
It's awesome.
Like we're chopping tomatoes that we
planted those seeds and we fertilize the
ground.
We watered it and it came up.
We pick the tomato,
now we're slicing into it and it's a
process process and that's where the
hunt,
that's where the hunt where the training
and the preparation and the reverence
for the animal and the harvest and the
animal and the care of the meet and get
to your house and you put it in your
freezer and then you thought and you put
that whole process is right.
I'll agree with remy.
There is reverence to and it means so
much and for a hunter for and I think,
you know,
as just being a provider and just being
like,
oh,
we say self self sufficient and doing it
is hard.
It's a lot easier to go to the store and
say,
Hey,
here's some of my money.
Could I have that meat?
Thank you.
Yay.
Somebody else did all,
all the stuff we
just talked about.
Somebody else did that with no reverence
and I'm eating it with no reverence,
you know?
So to do it on your own is.
I mean it's,
it's why it's what I trained.
It's what I prepare for every day and
it's a,
it just means so much.
Well,
it's
enriching in a very strange way that I
never experienced in my life until I
started hunting.
I'd never had this kind of connection
with my food except for me be going
fishing,
you know.
Um,
this,
uh,
last summer I took my kids to Hawaii and
my kids love fishing with my little
girls.
Love it.
It's fun because you know they can put a
line in the water and when they catch
something and then we're cooking it and
eating it later,
they're like,
we caught this and they keep saying
like,
mommy,
we caught this fish that you're eating.
Like there's like a primal connection to
this thing,
but other than that I had never
experienced this sort of primal
connection to your food and all that
nonsense aside.
Like there's a difference between a fish
and a mammal that just is totally,
and there's a.
there's a big difference.
She.
The reverence that you have for,
in my opinion,
the most majestic of animals that you
hunt,
which is elk.
I think it's the most majestic.
They're,
they're,
they're mythical creatures,
man.
Crazy
elk.
Sheep.
Sheep are up there,
you know where they live and the
regalness,
but elk is a god just because they're so
iconic throughout the west.
You know,
a big bull elk is just what
you know when you envisioned the West
envision mounds.
You think of a big bull elk and then you
say,
I'm going to hunt this with my bow.
It's intense.
It's fucking hard to do two and a
goddamn.
You forget me.
Addicted to this shit.
It's a real problem.
I'll text him every now and then like
I'm in the middle of doing something.
I'm like,
I wish I was bow hunting.
I swear to God.
This is boring.
I'd rather even just shooting.
We shot it.
A rubber target today.
It was awesome.
I have a rubber elk.
It sets up my hill and we did a little a
facetime video.
We were out there doing it,
but just shooting it.
That rubber is cool now.
No,
that's what I was saying.
You can take anybody.
You can take the coolest person you
know.
Just think,
just sit here and think who?
Who's the coolest person I know?
Or who is the coolest girl?
I know.
You take that person,
you put a bow in their hand and you get
them shooting a bow.
They're cooler.
No,
that's my.
Yeah.
I mean shooting a bow makes you more of
a bad ass.
I prefer
girls that don't like to hunt that way.
They don't want to come with me now.
I don't want him to have.
They don't complain while they're up
there and they don't want them to hunt.
I just wonder if shoot a bow does screw
up my high.
No,
I'm kidding.
I like cism now in hunting.
Does it exist?
It does next on Oprah?
No,
I'm Dr drew.
He would love that.
It would get me on there and just
crucifying would lie and he would get a
bunch of girls who don't know anything
about hunting to yell at you but have a
lot of.
Did a lot of big opinions.
He,
when we got back from Brazil,
it was right when this whole cecil the
lion shit was going down and these
people to have a hunter onto yell at
essentially and I was telling you don't
do it and the first time you didn't do
it,
I got you to leave.
I was in the green room.
I was,
I was in the green room and again her
hair and makeup and it just like wasn't
feeling good.
Yeah.
I'm glad you talked to me.
I'm glad we have association.
So I left but then I,
I did go on.
Yes,
you did go on later.
But it was after the smoke had settled a
little bit and you went on with a
conversation about ethical acquisition
of meat and you know Dr. True eats meat.
So yeah,
a lot of those people on that show eat
meat.
Yeah.
It's just bizarre.
It's a bizarre conversation.
I mean that show,
whatever they show is around because
controversy so well.
One of the font can hilarious things in
the show was the woman who was saying
that the reason why there's not so many
grizzlies just because we've killed off
all their predators.
Right.
That means dinosaurs by the way.
Saber Tooth Tigers,
Grizzly,
Jesus Christ.
Have you ever seen a grizzly lady?
Nothing.
Eating them up.
Other grizzlies are pretty much the top
of the food chain and I think,
well we are,
but they're not really on the same page
that we think we are.
They think they are.
So there's a little bit of a conflict
there.
There's a huge conflict.
I mean,
essentially it's like two different
kingdoms.
Yeah.
There on the top of the food chain and
the wild kingdom,
we can get them in their world,
but we gotta get the fuck out as quick
as we can.
We can only exist in their world for a
couple weeks at the most.
And then we're like,
okay,
we got to get back to a,
an actual bed and I need to take some
vitamins.
Right now it's a,
I dunno,
it's well,
according to a,
um,
the woman from,
God damn on my brain is foggy.
Did after working out.
What's her name from um,
like blows your [inaudible] Akins.
Sue aiken said that she saw a bunch of
wolves run down a young grizzly kill it.
Oh,
she said the young grizzly was coming
out of its den and when they come out of
their den they're kind of weak and
these,
these wolves knew it.
So they chased after it and they were
biting its legs and then chasing down
and it happened like a fucking 100 yards
from her house.
$100 for my house.
It sounds like she lives in La here,
right?
Yeah.
This lady is so bad.
Yeah,
she's intense.
She's the most gangster woman on the
planet.
She really is.
She's.
I have massive respect for her.
She's just so cool too.
She came in and she's.
It's not like she's like some weird
loner who hates people.
She loves people,
but she prefers to live in one of the
harshest climates on the planet.
Two hundred miles above the arctic
circle.
That's awesome.
Just so bad ass.
How much tougher she is in probably 99
percent of the men that live here in la.
She's tougher than me.
Tell you that.
This is what this lady did.
She got attacked by a bear.
Bear tore her apart.
Okay.
Broke her leg.
Broke her hip,
cracked her skull.
She,
they,
she had to crawl back to her house.
The bear was just fucking her up because
she was in its territory.
This is bare mauled her right.
She,
she managed to live.
She got back to her house.
She was stuck for days where she
couldn't walk.
Her leg was broken.
She was stuck.
She couldn't get to the phone.
Okay.
She couldn't lift herself up.
She had a way for someone to find her.
So these people,
founders like,
I think it was seven days later,
she got healed up,
went back,
shot that bear and ate it.
There you go.
That bitch is so gangster bitch with all
due respect.
That is amazing.
She's so gangster.
Well,
let,
let me expand on something before I get
people hating me for a women bowhunters.
I love you.
I,
uh,
I actually folks,
we are a little bit.
I love that women hunt.
I love that.
I do too.
I do.
I mean I want it.
I'm taking Dana Lesh a bowhunting for
bear this year.
So I mean,
I,
I don't have.
And I want it,
you know,
me and eva had been talking about
getting together for hunt.
So just all joking around.
I do like,
I do just like people shooting bows.
Even.
Yes.
If you can envision this,
if Obama shot a bow,
I'd probably think he was cooler and
that,
that is amazing.
That is amazing.
Shocky you should say
eve is too,
by the way.
She's the daughter of Jim shockey who's
been on this show who's an amazing,
fascinating guy who has a show,
even if you don't like hunting,
there's an amazing show called uncharted
and it's.
It's barely about hunting.
It's really about different cultures and
this guy goes to all these discount.
Jim shockey is as cool and interesting
as it gets.
He is just a fascinating,
fascinating guy and he travels to these
remote places in the middle of a Russia
and he went to Afghanistan and he's he.
He went to Africa to this remote village
that has a massive problem with
crocodiles and it was an incredible
show.
It's an hour long show.
I mean,
it could be on the discovery channel.
It could be on a,
on HBO,
could be on anything.
It just so happens.
It's on.
Is it on the outdoorsman?
Is Channel outdoor channel,
outdoor channel and this guy goes to
this place and you're seeing these
people,
like half the people in the village had
been mauled.
I mean,
people are missing arms.
They're missing legs.
Their faces have been cut open because
they're getting killed by crocodiles
left and right,
and while he was there filming a woman
got taken by a crocodile.
They've set up these sort of rudimentary
fences that they put in place to keep
the crocodiles out of these area where
these people gather water and you know,
and he's there with these other hunters
where they're trying to take out once a
crocodile apparently starts eating
people,
but you got to kill it because got a
taste for it.
Well,
they got a taste for it and they realize
how easy it is.
Like a wildebeest can fuck up a
crocodile a little bit,
you know,
you throw a kick at it and break his
jaw.
I mean the crocodile is incredibly tough
and durable animal,
but a wildebeest is a tough scrap.
It's a big animal and you know,
like a water buffalo,
that's a scrap.
It's a big animal to work for that.
It might not work out a person.
God Man,
we're made out of Jello,
Jello and popsicle sticks.
Nothing.
Well,
and I hunted crocodile.
I mean really they are.
They're tough.
Where'd you hung crocodile in Africa?
In Tanzania.
I wanted to kill one.
And so to get within range of a you have
to build a blind and they come up,
you know,
their eyes are just above the water and
for a bow you have like two bumps.
They got a bump above the eye and one
back here you have to be like right
below that are writing between.
You're shooting at about a fifty cent
piece size.
You have to break them because if you
hit them in the lungs,
they're in the water and then they sink.
You don't get them.
So if you're going to hunter crocodile
with a bow,
it has to be brain shot.
Drop them.
So to do that you have to get them up
off the shore,
right.
And uh,
could never happen.
Built a blind,
had the Beta.
It was just like so hard to do that.
But uh,
one of the guys I was with killed one
with a,
with a rifle and we ate it.
And the meat is amazing.
Well,
it's supposed to be the highest protein
meat you can get,
like alligator and crocodile is supposed
to be one ounce per ounce,
one of the highest in protein content.
Amazing.
Yeah,
I mean it was,
it was so good too.
But uh,
yeah,
they,
they are,
they're smart.
They're tough.
I don't think they're smart.
I think they're stupid as fuck.
Well,
try to kill him.
I just think they know how to not get
killed.
Like they have a couple of calculations
they make in their brand.
Is that a person you know?
Fuck this dude.
Okay.
The brain is very small.
I'll give you that because it's a small
target,
but if you're trying to hunt them,
you're going to think they're smart.
If you're going to do a crossword puzzle
with them,
probably not that smart.
Fascinating though,
man.
I won't want us.
I want,
wouldn't give a shout out.
Not only to Jim shockey because he is
the ultimate savage love gym,
but in Love Eva,
but their son,
brandon brandon is the mastermind behind
the shooting of that show,
right?
He,
you know,
as far as
filming and the production value.
And what you see on tv that's brand
shockey amazing.
And he is,
I think he could film like the,
the Best Hollywood movie you've ever
seen.
He could do that.
He has that talent and right now he's
doing it on the outdoor channel.
So that's,
if nothing else,
go and watch his work.
Yeah.
On that show.
And the notion uncharted,
uncharted,
which is amazing.
And the new show,
Carter's wars war,
Carter's war is all about this guy who's
combating against poaching in Africa and
it's all about stopping poachers from
killing rhinos and elephants and all
these different animals that they're
killing in Africa.
And uh,
so it's not really a hunting show as
much as it's just a pure conservation
show about a guy who's trying to stop
poaching in Africa.
And it's,
it's amazing and gritty and incredibly
well documented and shot and just man
the,
the world of Africa.
If you want to watch a documentary,
and I've mentioned this before to
people,
so I'm sorry if you heard it before,
but um,
our friend Louis Theroux who's been on
the show before,
who's an amazing documentary,
a documentary guy,
documentarian from the UK did a show on
these hunting in Africa,
which is very different from what you
did in Africa.
What you did in Africa.
You went to the actual wild who Africa,
not a high fence operation,
but these hunting ranches that they have
set up in Africa.
It's such a catch 22.
It's such A.
There's so much contradiction going on
because on one hand these animals are
trapped in this.
It's usually enormous,
like several thousand Acre area.
It can be where they're trapped in these
areas and they're hunted and the people
call it a can hunt and a lot of people
that have a lot of hate for it,
but on the other hand,
the animals that they're hunting have
never been healthier and higher numbers
and a lot of them were on the verge of
extinction until they started
implementing these high fence
operations.
And it goes back to the same thing we
were talking about,
the money for conservation,
the real money that these people are
getting in Africa is coming from
hunting.
That's what's paying for these animals
to survive because so many people are
going over there to hunt and people say,
well,
animals have value exists.
The key.
And that's so fucking weird concept for
people.
If an animal doesn't have value,
it's probably going to be extinct.
Yeah,
I mean that's how.
That's.
That's why.
That's why hunter's care.
That's why conservation is care because
the animal is valuable.
Whether it's right,
wrong or indifferent.
When there's value.
People care and people have an
understanding today that they didn't
have this several hundred years ago.
Like when people look at the gigantic
mounds of buffalo skulls,
that's a perfect example.
Why you need conservation.
You can't just have people run out and
kill these animals that have value with
no consequence or with no monitoring of
the herd populations and health.
That's when you get these horrific mass
extinction events like what happened
with the buffalo and the buffalo were
basically brought to the verge of
extinction.
Now they're in healthy populations to
the point where you can actually,
in some places you can hunt wild ones.
The same thing could be,
say,
a set of elk.
The Rocky Mountain Elk Foundation has
done an amazing job of repopulating
areas with elk where they were at one
point in time,
completely eradicated.
Well,
did you know that when you tuck elk deer
Turkey,
when you talk about there's more of
those species now than there's ever
been.
Is that true with elk?
Because I know it is with white tail
deer.
There's more white tail deer today then
when Columbus landed,
but I don't know if that's the case with
elk because there's more places where
they don't exist.
I think like most of the area where like
Steven Rinella did a whole show on this
recently,
but most of the area where elk used to
be,
they're not,
but in the areas where they are,
they're in healthy populations.
I'm on Jamie.
Can you look this up?
Yeah,
look this up.
Look it up about that populations
because I'm almost positive.
There's more now.
See Elk are and probably rinella would
dallas.
So maybe you know,
if he's been on the show,
but elk are there,
plains animals originally they're pushed
into the mountains because the planes,
that's where we live.
We live where there's water and in the
valleys,
that's where humans setup their cities
and that's,
you know,
to get user rivers and we need water.
So they have been pushed and now they're
mountain animals.
But now there's elk where there hasn't
been out before Pennsylvania,
Kentucky and places like that.
So maybe they're,
maybe they're more places than they've
ever been,
but I'm almost,
I'm almost certain there's even more
elk,
but whatever the case,
I don't even think there are more places
than they've ever been.
I think it's the ones that are there are
in healthier populations in the used to
be I think,
but I think elk are a lot like a buffalo
in that there's one point in time,
like hundreds of years ago,
they were just shooting the shit out of
them.
They're almost eradicated.
Oh right.
I know now they're,
they're bounced back and they're healthy
everywhere.
And where'd that money come from?
Cameron hanes.
I want to say hunter.
Yes.
Rocky Mountain Elk Foundation that
they've done a fantastic job and then
they,
they've done,
they've been on the forefront of
protecting habitat,
so that's,
I know they've been over 6 million acres
protected,
I think maybe close to 7 million now or
maybe even over.
I haven't kept track recently,
but that's 7 million acres that can
never be used for anything else other
than habitat for animals.
And that's not just elk,
that's deer to elk numbers across six
dates.
How do we look in there?
See,
this is across states,
but I think,
um,
maybe we could keep looking.
Can we see that in American elk
populations dwindled to less than
100,000 by the early 19 nineties now.
And that's insane.
And now in 2009 grew to 1 million.
Thirty $1,000.
That's incredible.
So the 19 nineties,
that's insane.
It was down to 100,000 in the 19
nineties.
Wow.
That's terrifying.
But that's,
that's the verge of extinction in our
lifetime.
Not just in our lifetime,
but in when we were both men.
Yeah.
So during that time,
totally.
No,
that can't be right.
Is it?
No.
The early 19,
now that's got to be 18 nineties whereas
this hasn't it see the lessons of the
last word of the first paragraph
by 1984 there was an estimated 715,000
elk in North America.
No Fred above there.
The last word of the first paragraph.
Fortunately a toto toto American that
less than $100,000 in a 100,000 in the
early 19 nineties.
So that,
that can't be 19 nineties is it?
It's an incorrect.
That's what he's saying.
But yeah it might be,
it might be a miss.
I think that's
yeah.
Cause cause cause it says in 1984
84,
there's 750.
So went all the way back right?
Yeah.
That must be a typo.
But anyway,
so,
so that's what dom typo whose,
whose fucking go go.
What does it say?
Go Hunt seat.
I don't necessarily trust a lot of these
hunting sites for things like that.
Like that's A.
I trust him when they support the point.
I'm trying to fuck up.
That's a giant fuck ups.
I did email that site.
Somebody who's listening,
please email that site and let us know
fixed.
I think it's supposed to be 18 nineties
and I would say,
and I would say less than 100,000 and
now it's over a million.
So that's,
that's where I get that.
The point that I was making,
but I think before people colonized the
west,
I think they were everywhere.
I think that's what,
that's what Rinella was saying.
Maybe.
So I think what he was saying was that
they're not in 90 percent of the places
they used to be in,
but the,
the places they're in,
it's like thriving.
They're thriving.
Yeah.
And this is,
this is a really important point when it
comes to,
like we were talking about grizzly
bears,
like people say,
look,
the grizzly bears are almost extinct in
Santa Monica.
Yes,
you're right.
They're almost extinct in California.
They only live in California,
but not a ton in California to Alaska.
They're fucking everywhere.
And there's a lot of um,
folks in Alaska which is twice the size
of Texas.
It's a goddamn enormous state.
And they are,
they are big and there's a lot of them,
right?
And they decimate herds of Caribou elk
and they estimate that something around
like where John and Jen live in Alberta,
more than 50 percent of the Moose are
killed at birth by bears.
That's where the bears,
they follow.
So a cow moose is pregnant,
it's going to drop,
drop the calf.
Right?
And so bears will know that Moose is
pregnant.
No,
she's going to be dropping a calf.
They follow her as soon as she drops a
calf right there,
kill it and eat it.
That's how.
That's how they get hurt.
They just follow the Moose around.
Not even then,
a lot of times they're pulling it out of
the cow's body.
Right?
I mean that's how
it.
They're brutal.
I mean,
life in the wild.
It's not a fairy tale out there.
Real deal.
It's life and death.
And so they're doing,
they're just going to kill.
They're going to kill.
That's all they care about.
Throwing a kill.
Eat.
That's how they survive.
So there's nothing wrong with that.
No,
I'm not.
They do.
I'm not going to judge them.
But uh,
yeah,
so where I was,
I was in um,
in 16 in Alaska and you can see a
nonresident can kill to brown bear,
which are basically salmon fed,
grizzly,
grizzly bear and three black bear,
so he can go up there and kill five
bear,
which I wanted to do,
but don't think that I'm blood thirsty.
Thank that.
I,
I want to help the most and I like the
bear meat.
So,
um,
I didn't do it,
but I mean that's what killed three.
I killed three.
But that gives you an example of how
many,
how many bears are our.
And this is by biologists who are paid
and who have went to school and with who
have studied the carrying capacity of
the land and how many animals they
determined this.
This isn't,
this isn't hunters determining this,
this is Alaska fish and game.
So that's where I have a problem with
the people who are,
who think they know better than people
who this is their passion,
this is what they care about.
They have boots on the ground,
they're doing it.
They're,
they're setting the bag limits.
So you don't know if you don't live
there and study this and this has been
your life mission.
You don't know more than them so.
Well their wildlife biologist and by the
way,
if those populations aren't kept at a
healthy level,
they send in people that they pay to
kill these animals and this is an
important factor and this is what we're
talking about with California because
California doesn't have a hunting season
for mountain lions.
They have to pay people to go in and
kill these mountain lions.
They're not just letting them out in
lines live.
Not if they become a problem,
they're taking them out.
They just don't want to deal with the
backlash.
Exactly.
That's it.
So they're just avoiding the backlash
and it's not doing it quietly.
It's not for the betterment of the
animal or or you know the ecosystem or
anything like that.
It's just because they don't want to
deal with the,
with the drama.
And then you get these people.
Well they were here first.
Where were they?
Are they were here?
No,
they weren't.
First of all that mountain lions five.
I was here way before that fuck.
And they as in they come on stop.
This is the whole place was covered in
ice 10,000 years ago.
So shut up.
Like what are you talking about?
Who is they?
What is this word?
This is the world we're living in right
now.
In 2016.
And a mountain lion ate this fucking
dudes cat.
What are we going to do?
We're going to just let them out in
line.
He his kid now because it would,
if you leave that kid on the swing and
you go into kid fucking answer your
email real quick and you come back,
your kids not gone and see that fucking
tail.
Hop over the fence.
That's how it works.
That's the wild barbecued a turnover.
Your Veggie Burger,
you know,
that kid's gone.
Um,
Cecil.
Alright,
so this is the uh,
the,
this is the billboard that my grandpa.
No,
my grandpa's name was Joseph.
Look at this fucking photograph.
There is a lion that is hugging a bear
and the lion has a tear rolling down his
face and the bear has a tear rolling
down his face.
And it says they banned the bear hunt.
They are all Cecil Save New Jersey
barriers.com.
Oh my God.
For his.
Makes me want to punch somebody in the
face.
What kind of fucking crazy person
living,
living some weird bubble made this
billboard and spent actual human money
on it.
Yeah.
I don't know.
Fantasy land if they haven't seen.
Okay.
They have a giant problem with bears in
New Jersey.
And this is,
this is this facts behind this.
First of all,
a student from rutgers was fucking
killed by a bear right outside of
rutgers.
He,
that photograph student took this photo
of a bear just before it killed them.
Um,
I was talking to a guy who is,
who knows rangers out there and they're
telling people not to hike.
They have so many Goddamn bear in New
Jersey.
And why do they have so many bear?
Because they didn't have a hunt for
them.
So these God damn things,
they got overpopulated and they have now
they're,
they're entering into residential
neighborhoods.
And these laundry.
Look at this fucking video.
Bear fight far rockaway,
New Jersey,
August 14th of 2014.
These bears are duking it out,
these are big black bears,
like seven foot bears,
400 plus pound bears,
and they are going to war in this guy's
front lawn.
These are huge.
I mean if you were in Alberta and you
saw one of these bears coming in and
you'd be like,
Ooh,
boy,
that's a trophy bear.
That's a giant bear.
That's hundreds of pounds of meat for
the grill.
And these bears are in this guy's lawn.
I mean,
this isn't a,
this isn't some crazy rural,
you know,
Akins living in the middle of the
nowhere.
No,
in this jersey,
this thing just knocked over a lamp post
and now it's colliding with these,
uh,
garbage pails.
Watch this.
They come,
they're
fighting over territory by the way.
That's created by garbage.
That's what the territory is.
They attack people's garbage and these
two bears,
they bite each other and then they do
get out.
Look at the size of these bears.
Now,
these are huge,
right?
Well,
that's,
that's why.
Okay,
so maybe there was before there's houses
that was perfect bear habitat,
but guess what?
There's houses now.
So that means we have to control the
bare numbers that's hunting.
Well,
here's another part of the problem.
These bears weren't here 30 years ago.
These bears are overpopulating and
moving into these neighborhoods and
they're doing it because they know that
people live there and it's a steady
supply of food.
Garbage.
Yeah.
When you live in Colorado.
And Colorado is a,
they had a big issue with it in this
area where I was,
where the bears would find out that
people put their garbage in a certain
area and once they eat there,
once that's it,
they have to capture those bears and
they either relocate them to zoos or,
or figure something out.
But one,
when I was there,
we went to this,
uh,
wildlife rescue place and they had this
gigantic grizzly bear that they had
gotten because we'll get a fucking giant
chunks of further tearing off of each
other.
Look at that.
It's insane.
They're bs.
And now I love this video because a car
pulls up and the cars that they started
taking selfies with the bears.
But um,
they had to relocate this grizzly
because it's just started tearing apart
people's cars.
They found it,
found food and someone's car once was at
grizzly black.
It was a brown bear and it's one that
they had had,
I don't know where they had gotten it,
but,
uh,
but it happens with black bear.
It happens with bears.
Yeah.
No,
it's just,
you know,
the numbers need to be controlled.
That's all there is to.
It doesn't have a large brown bear
population.
Right,
Chris?
Well,
it wouldn't be brown bear brown bear
when they're near the coast and Grizzly,
we're inland brown bear.
They eat fish.
So they're on,
how do they call them?
Different names,
different species,
I guess is what they've determined.
You know,
there are bigger because they fish and
they get all that protein.
So they,
you know,
they can be up 1400 pounds.
Where as a mountain grizzly in average
mountain grizzly might be seven foot 500
pounds.
You know,
I mean,
life's tough or up in the mountains,
they're eating blueberries when the
blueberries are on,
um,
you know,
eating what they can.
But the bears that eat the fish there,
gorging on fish,
they get big.
It's just a high protein diet.
Kinda like what you're on right now.
I'm on a high protein diet.
You're like fat too?
Yeah.
This,
this diet is kind of for the birds but
not really.
Birds eat grain.
I'm enjoying.
I mean it's not bad but for two weeks
and I really like a bowl of pasta right
now,
but it's going well.
I bet it's interesting.
Yeah.
Well that whole Cecil and the bear
hugging thing that it's insane.
Yeah.
I guarantee you a woman made that.
How about that folks?
I'm now.
I'm done with.
I'm done with that part.
I don't know.
That may be.
It could be a gay guy.
Could be a week.
Dude,
I'll,
I'll sex gender,
all that nonsense aside.
We're joking around here folks.
What that is,
is just someone who doesn't understand
it's,
it's crazy ignorance and um,
the,
the idea that you want to let these
things keep fucking and breeding and
overpopulating to the point where
they're killing college students just
outside of rutgers and they're having
these two,
400 plus pound bears,
duke it out on your front lawn.
That's not good folks.
It's not good.
You know,
I'd,
I'd like to see these people that think
that the bears hugging each other.
Go break the,
you know,
come on guys.
Let's settle down.
Break it up.
Go break those bears up.
Up.
Since apparently they cry and have
emotions.
You know,
Cecil has a brother who's protecting his
family.
Jericho.
Kay.
Go break up that bear fight.
Let me know how that goes.
What is this?
Samantha is from their website.
Save and Jay Baer's dot com.
Oh God.
So this is another name you don't part.
I think,
you know,
we're only facilitating this issue right
here with naming the bears that
humanizing them,
because if you watch the superbowl,
it seemed like every other commercial
was something an animal seeing foreign
animal talking or it's like,
I mean,
I saw sheep singing in the acapella
group.
I'm like,
what is going on?
Well,
and so that's,
that's where hunters are fighting for
our place right now because the kids are
seeing that and weak people are seeing
that and people that don't get,
Hey,
I want to be part of the food chain are
seeing that and they're like humanizing
these animals.
Sheep don't care about anything but
eating,
eating and fucking.
Yeah,
they do.
They stay alive.
They're not talking,
they're not talking about,
oh,
here comes a guy who was bringing us our
food.
Let's see.
You know,
they're not,
they're not.
It's not realistic,
but that's the,
that's the,
that's the programming,
the programming that's getting out there
and just met missing with the hardwire
of these young people coming up with A.
Well,
a lot of hunters attribute Bambi as
being a turning point in the way
Americans viewed hunting.
Yeah,
because then all of a sudden you've seen
this beautiful animal getting chased
down and killed by a hunter.
Yeah.
And well,
we need to fight.
We need to fight to change that.
I think we are.
I mean we are because uh,
you know,
every time you see a hunter on a show or
on a who,
I don't even know what it's been on.
I think south parks even had something,
but it's obviously it's some redneck
hillbilly drinking beer,
you know,
no respect for anything that's always,
even in all the Hollywood movies,
that's what,
that's what they,
that's the image they portray.
We need to change that.
We're trying to,
we're trying to.
And I think with podcasts and with
conversations on the Internet,
at least information is getting to
people that they weren't getting before.
I've had many,
many people both on twitter,
on my website forum,
on facebook,
on all these different forms of social
media.
Say I had a perception of
hunters until yet.
Guys like Cameron Hanes on Jim Shockey,
Steve Rinella,
Steven know remy warrant.
He's really intelligent people that can
talk about Tim Barnett who can talk
about these things in a way where they
explain to you their perspective,
their grew up with this.
This is how they've lived their life and
if you lived your life in a city,
it doesn't make sense to you.
It seems alien.
You Watch Bambi,
you see these Yogi talks to booboo.
They have conversations.
Why would you want to shoot one of them
until you,
you.
You venture into that world.
You don't understand it,
and we're.
We're insulated from it because of
supermarkets,
because of this bizarre world we live
in.
When we've created these artificial
structures that we think are normal,
these cities and these,
these,
this method of acquiring food,
will you just run a piece of plastic
through a machine and you walk away with
all this food?
It's not healthy.
No,
it's not.
It's not.
It's like if you could have sex with a
faceless person where you didn't even
get to see their face,
like all you saw was like their body
from the shoulder down and that's what
you had sex within you.
You had a kid with that person,
you even know that kidney and walk away,
but I got my needs met.
I mean almost.
That's almost what's going on.
It's almost what's going on when you're
acquiring food without ever growing it,
without planting that seed,
and I'm not saying you should fucking
plant all your food and I'm not saying
you should only hunt if you're going to
eat me,
but what I'm saying is if you could do
it,
it would bring you a little closer to
understanding where that food comes from
and it'll give you a.
A just a broader view of this world we
live in and what you're doing by
consuming food you are consuming.
Whether you consuming salad and here's
another thing,
vegans.
I put this up the other day.
I was fucking with a bunch of people
where I've trolled.
People are sending me all this vegan
stuff,
so I just started trolling them by
sending them all these scientific
studies about plants and plant
intelligence,
which is a new form of study or it's a.
it's a new field of study where they're
finding out more and more each day that
plants can do calculations that they
respond to being eaten,
that they have a.
They have different mechanisms to
discourage predation.
That's where poisoned plants come from.
They are communicating with each other
in some sort of strange way that when
one tree is getting chopped down,
it's sending signals to other trees.
It's whether it's an in it's own way in
some sort of a weird way.
Your reading life,
if you're eating a plant,
your eating life,
if you say that it's okay to eat
vegetable life,
but it's not okay to eat fish if you say
it's okay to eat fish,
but it's not okay to eat animals.
If you.
What you're doing is you're making these
bizarre moral judgments and they're,
they're based on convenience and there's
a lot of them are based on ignorance and
a lot of them,
they don't hold up.
When you start looking at things
subjectively and people say to you,
what,
why don't you eat your dog?
Well,
I don't want to eat my dog.
Okay,
Jesus Christ,
but my dog as a pet.
Okay.
My dog was raised from the time it was a
baby,
have had it since it was young.
I'm not going to eat it,
but if someone does have a wild dog and
eat it and it's between that wild dog
eating them and them eating that wild
dog,
you know,
that's an unfortunate situation,
but you got to eat that fucking dog.
Yeah.
Manny Pacquiao is parents.
They eat their dog when they were,
when he was starving.
When you were a kid.
It was like a really traumatic moment
for him where his family was.
So there were starving.
They were so poor.
They had to eat their pet dog.
Yeah.
Well,
and then the people would say,
well,
you're not starving.
Why are you killing animals?
Right.
For us,
because I don't want to starve.
That's a good point.
What would I like active?
What I liked the most,
we talked about changing the stereotype
is I like,
you know,
working as we know workout all the time.
I like when people asked me,
why are you working out so hard for
bowhunting?
And this was like that.
That is the craziest look,
you know?
But it's been the same answer for me for
years is because I want to be the best
in the mountains.
I think that the best that you can be
the best I can be.
Yeah,
I understood that way more after I went
with you.
You know,
after I went hunting with you in
Colorado,
I get it.
I get it more because you're in better
cardiovascular shape than me and I'm in
good shape.
You take the average person,
I'm in better shape than the average
person and I'm not in better shape than
you.
You're fucking running ahead of me.
I'm like,
this the fuck I can't catch up.
You know,
it's like there's a certain pace that
you can keep because you run mountains
all the time that I'm just not capable
of keeping right now.
It made me up my cardio and a big time,
big time way.
When I came back from that hunt was the
first thing I started doing is really up
in my cardio.
Well.
And I,
you know,
so we had a real,
real life example of that.
What I like as much as that.
I mean not,
not as much as that because I love being
with somebody who is successful and who
experiences a hunt and I'm able to share
in that.
And that's a whole nother thing.
It's like I didn't,
I didn't kill anything but I was part of
your hunt and that meant as much to me
is me getting my animals.
So we have the whole comradery and you
know,
it's not every man for himself,
it's,
we're out there,
we're working together,
we're,
we want to be successful in harvest
meeting,
take me home to our families.
But what I like is people who are
inspired,
they're not with me,
but they see the training and they're
inspired to up their game.
Like maybe they're,
maybe they won't run a 200 mile race or
run 10 miles a day or do any of this,
but maybe they'll run one mile.
You know?
And maybe it's making.
My whole thing is if you're not making,
if you're not making a positive impact,
what's your point?
What are you doing?
I want to make a positive impact on
people and that's why I love social
media and sharing what I do and
hopefully it can inspire others to do
more.
And that's,
that's my motivation daily.
Well,
there's a great.
This is a great time for that and it's
a,
it's a,
there's a great venue or a great a
vehicle through social media that didn't
exist before.
Right.
Inspire people and I am constantly
inspired by it,
you know,
and some people get upset,
legroom,
you fucking post and pooch.
So you work.
No,
he fucking showing off.
Like I like when I read the rocks,
Instagram,
I do,
I think 40 million other people do.
Also.
Deaf fucking guy is up every morning.
If he's got to work at seven,
he's up at four and he's in the gym and
they'll show a photo of his alarm clock
going off and it'll show a photo of him
in the gym making crazy faces where it's
folded sweat and it makes me realize I'm
a lazy bitch and it makes me want to get
up and work out.
Exactly.
You know,
I mean that's just where there's a
community.
People want to be inspired.
I think they definitely do.
I know I do and I know that you've
created a community,
your instagram page and a lot of ways,
and I want to say it's your community,
but you have spawned through your
instagram page.
A lot of inspirational communities as
well.
I've looked at these other people's
pages that follow you and I'll see like
the Hashtag keep hammering and they're
out doing things and I see people
responding their posts,
you know,
I saw this and it made me go to the gym
and I wasn't going to.
So thank you for that.
And it branches off.
It feeds into everybody and it's
positive.
It's positive for all of us.
And at the end of the day,
look,
you know,
you can make all your fucking angry
videos and you can make all your angry
posts and shit on this and shit on that
and,
and get angry about people you don't
even meet.
But what is the,
what is the message that you're putting
out this angry shitty message that you
are putting out this angry negative
thing?
Yeah.
Who,
who's getting you pumping yourself up or
you stay.
You're standing on a moral high ground
and espousing your,
your,
your superiority to the world.
Like what are you doing?
What are you doing?
Are you broadcasting that?
And you know,
who was inspired by that?
Nobody.
What some people might be to also be
like,
this guy's a good cut.
I want to be a no,
I'd never heard.
I guess I don't hang around those people
because I never hear that.
Well,
you don't see him.
I'll tell you what,
when you know,
like if you meet one of those people in
real life,
I guarantee you the conversation
wouldn't be like it is in these one
sided debates or these one sided
broadcast.
If someone makes a blogs,
angry,
shitty blog,
like you have a conversation with that
person,
it's tweets and blogs like especially if
they're negative,
it's a very ineffective form of
communication and negative videos.
They're very ineffective because this is
a not a real conversation like the way
people are supposed to communicate is
like you and I talking to each other,
you know,
even fucking podcasts and a lot of ways.
It's one of the things why people get
angry because a,
there's someone listening to this right
now,
like you motherfucker.
I got something to say and I get it.
I understand,
but don't get mad at me.
If you were here,
we would talk,
but you're not here.
Should we take a few calls?
We don't do Colin's thinker.
No,
it's too hard.
You know,
the beautiful thing about the internet
is everybody has a voice.
You can text me about the internet is
everybody.
You got my number,
text me.
So that'll,
that'll eliminate a lot of people.
You know,
you can,
you can choose what message you put out
there.
You can choose how you experience life.
You can choose like how you,
how you interact with people and some
people that think they're,
you know,
this is a new world we're living in this
world of social media,
this world where anybody can start a
blog or anybody can start putting things
up on twitter or facebook or whatever.
It's a new world and we got to learn how
to navigate it better.
Well,
you know,
people,
like you said,
people can choose.
I can choose to.
I put up positive.
Yeah.
You don't think I have negative things
happen in my life?
Of course.
Yeah.
I could put a negative probably as much
as positive.
I'm overcoming all sorts of hurdles all
the time.
But what's the point?
I'm like,
I said I want to be positive.
I want to inspire people and you know,
at the show and in Utah this weekend,
um,
I was amazed at the number of people
that waited a long time to come up and
share their story,
share their story about losing weight or
the success they've had or the,
or the impact as a hunter with a bow
hunter who,
how would a bowhunter make that much of
an impact?
I have no idea,
but it happened and that,
I mean,
if,
if you ever wonder,
you know,
what's your calling in life?
Because I've wondered what am I,
what am I doing,
you know,
when I was young,
what's,
what,
where am I going,
what's going to happen?
Well,
weekends,
like this weekend where I saw those
people and talk to those people and have
that interaction that really drives home
I'm doing what I'm meant to do,
you know?
And that's making a positive impact and
I mean that's through bowhunting mean
that's it.
That's what I do.
That's how I met you.
Yeah.
I mean I met you through bowhunting and
social media.
I mean,
your,
your positive message reached me and we
talked about it on the Gritty Bowman
podcast,
which we,
we just did a.
We dropped in and did a podcast and
impromptu podcasts with these guys.
They called themselves the gritty bowman
and it's good but good bowhunting
podcast,
and we sat and we talked about it like I
was interested in hunting for a long
time before I met Steven Rinella and
then when I'm going on different
websites and looking at different
youtube videos,
I saw your stuff and I'm like,
oh,
okay.
Well here's this guy that's really into
fitness.
He's into fitness and preparing himself
to be what you call the ultimate
Predator to be your best at what you
like to do,
which is bowhunting.
I'm like,
well,
this is kind of crazy.
So then I started watching your videos.
I'm like,
what a positive dude.
This guy's working out.
He's given people great advice.
He's telling people like how to use
proper technique with archery and how to
have a good attitude about this and how
it's all good and you're like,
it's a beautiful day.
We're out here.
We're enjoying the beautiful weather,
we're out here practicing this,
what we do every day,
and I was like,
this is inspirational and this is
positive and and through you,
you meet me.
I use my what I've created this vehicle
of social media and podcasting to
broadcast it more and then all these new
positive branches spread out from that.
It's awesome.
It's amazing.
I love it.
It's so much better than shitting on
people.
It is so much better than negativity and
like I said,
when I had these guys from cowspiracy
and these guys are vegans,
they're vegans who made a documentary
about veganism and the powerful message
that they had about the anti factory
farming message.
I had a great conversation with them and
I believe,
I truly believe that most of these
people that are making angry posts on
twitter or angry videos,
if I sat down with them and had
conversations with them,
they'd be positive conversations.
Whether we agree or disagree.
I have a very well thought out point.
I would imagine they have a very well
thought out point to where they're
coming from.
It's not a bad thing.
It's just this,
something is lost in this,
the broadcasting of this message.
I think that's a real problem that we're
all sort of navigating in this world.
Is that somehow or another the messages
that get the most reaction or a lot of
times the negative.
Yeah.
Yeah,
I know well On,
uh,
in regard to hunting.
Why do you like archery?
Do you like archery better than rifle?
Hunting definitely is more challenging.
It's more in.
It's there's,
there's a book called Zen and the art of
archery.
It was a book that I need to read.
Everybody tells me I need to read this
book,
but there's something about archery
itself like today when we're practicing
shooting at that rubber elk.
Yeah.
There's something about the.
There is a,
there's a moment when you were at full
draw and you're about to release that
Arrow where everything is still.
Everything is calm and you're not
thinking about anything else.
You can't other than releasing the
perfect Arrow because it requires so
much concentration and so much focus.
And I was completely unexpected to me.
When I first started practicing archery,
I thought it was going to be like,
like shooting a rifle requires a lot of
focus.
It requires trigger discipline.
You have to like steady the gun arrests
do you have to look,
you know,
really stay still and squeeze that
trigger and there's problems with that.
You know,
you get the shakes,
you know,
you get nerves and even at a target
range,
you know,
you know the gun's going to make that
kick and say you get paid a flint chase.
Yeah.
It's nothing like archery archery's that
times 100.
It's,
it requires,
there's no resting,
there's no rifle rest.
You know,
you have to hold your arm steady and the
amount of movement that you make because
the arrows only going at the most 300
feet a second,
3:50.
If you've got some super bone,
a light Arrow,
the difference between that and a rifle.
Six thousand feet a second,
it says arrive.
Yeah.
So any movement translates to a giant
amount of movement at the end where the
arrowheads.
Yeah.
And it's just as a discipline,
it's,
it's cleansing.
Like for me,
I love after a long day,
I do a lot of Shit,
man.
I got a lot of things going on in my
mind,
you know,
I have between comedy and podcasting and
the UFC and family and the business
bullshit
and it's like so much bullshit going on.
There's so many different things in my
mind that for me would archery is,
is like,
this is like ultimate meditation is
ultimate focus point where I draw back
and I see that target and then I release
that Arrow and then when that,
when that Arrow goes right into that
bullseye,
like we were shooting that rubber elk
today and when you nail one it gets
right in that small circle.
Oh,
it's a beautiful,
satisfying feeling.
It is.
It's that moment that in the impact and
seeing where it hit.
I mean,
and then so that's just the process of
it.
But then when that happens because what,
why are we doing that?
We're doing that to prepare for the
hunt.
Yeah.
So when all that work pays off on the
hunt,
it's just,
uh,
you know,
I don't,
I don't know how to,
you know,
I see some videos and I see people
running around and tackling each other
and doing all that.
I never feel like that.
I always feel like I'm,
I feel,
I guess blessed are thankful for the
moment and mostly thankful that I made
something that's very difficult happen.
You know,
I achieved that goal and it's a,
I dunno,
it's,
it's so powerful.
And I just,
that's what I,
you know,
I like people to shoot a bow because as
you said,
shooting a bow is,
is centering and it zen like I guess if
I even know what zen means,
I don't even know if I do,
but it is relaxing.
It is,
requires an amazing focus.
Um,
so that's a good start.
But when you can block everything out
because you say you have to block
everything out to make a good shot on
that target,
on the foam rubber,
the reinhart elk today.
Well,
on an animal when the animal's moving,
there's different factors that at,
you know,
in line,
he's bugling your heart's going a
million miles an hour and then when he
can do it there and then where you take
that up,
another level is hunting the mounds,
like if your sheep hunting and then you
have it's such a physical and then it
could be dangerous also.
So you have so many things and when that
happens on something like a sheep and
the sheep mountains,
that is to me life changing.
I mean experiences like that have made
me who I am.
When people say,
you know,
bowhunting has made you who?
Yeah,
I mean because coming through and crunch
time like that is more pressure and more
accomplishment than anything I'll ever
do in normal life because it's just that
difficult.
We'll through difficult things are
character,
gets challenged,
our,
our will and our focus get tested and
through those tests and through this
very difficult task,
you learn more about yourself,
right?
You learn more about your ability,
you learn more about your faults,
you,
you learn about your weaknesses,
you learn about your and you learn
how to shore up those weaknesses and get
stronger,
and that's why people who have never
experienced it don't understand your
dedication to fitness,
don't understand your dedication to
making sure you're in the best possible
shape you can be.
Also that your your archery practice is
that the best it can be so that when
that moment of truth arises,
you can steady your nerves.
You can keep it all together and you can
execute and that execution,
that that is an insanely difficult tasks
that very few people have to ever do
anything in life that's remotely as
difficult as shoot an Arrow at an elk.
It's 50 yards away and wash that arrows
sink right into the vitals and realize
that you've done it and realize that now
you have enough meat for a year for your
family,
one animal,
and are we quantifying life?
I mean,
are we saying that you know this,
that all animals are worth something
that will.
If that's the case,
every pasta bowl that you eat,
you eat a bowl of pasta.
That pasta comes from grain.
That grain most likely was chopped from
a field from a combine that is 100 yards
long that it's indiscriminate and it's
running over everything as we were
talking about running over mice and
rabbits and fonts and ground nesting
birds and anything else that might be in
its path and there's a lot of death
involved in that,
so every bowl of pasta that you eat,
even though you feel like you're
completely immune and we're a completely
free of any responsibility of death,
it's not true,
but one elk with one arrow feed you for
a year,
right?
Just I have to fucking commercial
freezers in the back.
They're filled with me.
I gave Gary Clarke the musician the
other day.
I came to pounds of elk,
like take this home and cook it.
They'll bird the other day said he sent
me this text message that he made elk
Chili.
I gave him some advice.
I give people meet.
I love it.
Love it.
Yeah.
My friend Chris Ryan sent me this
photograph,
or Dunkin actually sit with Chris.
Ryan did too,
but Duncan sent me this photograph of
his,
his girlfriend made meatballs,
elk meat balls and they were sitting
there eating with their friends.
They had a friend over for dinner with
some meat from an animal.
That was,
that.
You're given it to them.
It's,
it's,
it's fantastic.
It's a beautiful warm feeling and it
connects you in some weird primal way
that we're immune to.
We're not getting it anymore.
We're not getting it.
And it,
for me,
people asked why?
Because I've always been drawn to,
to wild places.
Um,
big wild places and people ask,
how did that start?
For me?
How that started was I didn't come from
anything.
I didn't have,
I didn't have anything.
I was just a guy who couldn't even
afford an elk license for was $25.
I couldn't afford it,
but.
So I felt like,
um,
I don't know.
I didn't feel special in any way.
I didn't feel like I had any advantage
over anybody.
I felt lower class essentially,
but in the wilderness when I went there
could be the richest guy in the world.
There could be the most powerful
businessman,
but if he was there and I was there,
all of a sudden the playing was equal
and if I'm in better shape than him,
I'm above him in the mountains.
I can be somebody I can be,
I can be special and that's how our
prepare.
And that's why I liked it back there is
I didn't have to conform to society's,
well,
this guy's an a list or you are nothing.
You know what I mean?
That's what it was always drawn me to
that because it was a level playing
field for me and if I came in more of
like a beast than somebody else,
all of a sudden I was the guy back
there.
That's what I did and it was just like I
didn't have anything and I thought this
is the only way I'm going to be
achieved.
My dreams,
you know,
get to get to where I can be in control.
Well,
it gives you an understanding
of that environment.
That environment really doesn't care
that you make six figures,
doesn't care that you drive a bmw.
It doesn't care that you have a nice
house.
It doesn't care.
This is.
There's a lot of ways like I gravitate
towards absolutes.
I go,
that's one of the reasons why I like
martial arts.
It's one of the reasons I like pool,
like that ball drops in the whole.
It's because he made it dropped in the
hole.
If you miss,
you miss and there's no if,
ands,
or buts about it.
It's an absolute thing and I think a lot
of ways hunting is similar in that way.
I get doesn't care.
Like if you're playing pool and you're a
millionaire and you're playing against a
guy who was $2 in his bank,
it doesn't.
The balls don't know this.
They don't care and it's the same in the
woods when you were out there and you're
in that environment.
That is an absolute environment and
absolute also in the fact that if you
fuckin zig when you should have zagged
and you run across a sow,
grizzly and her cubs and she just
decides today's your day.
It doesn't,
it doesn't.
They don't give a fuck if you host the
UFC,
that bear doesn't give a fuck.
If you know,
you,
uh,
you know,
you're the CEO of your company and
you're out there.
It doesn't care.
No.
The wilderness is its own world.
It has its own,
it's an unforgiving.
It's unforgiving.
And it's absolute.
Yeah.
And like that Arrow hitting the artery
or hitting the vitals of,
of an elk I give you.
If it doesn't hit,
it doesn't hit.
I mean,
it's got to go where it's supposed to go
or are you fucked up?
You know,
and there there's a,
you know,
that is real.
I mean,
it's,
that's not just in this talk,
not talk where he zig zagged.
Um,
and you know,
Roy Roy story is a perfect example of
that front and explained who roy is.
Um,
roy is,
he's who got me started in bow hunting
and he is the toughest man I've ever
met.
I've shared more experiences with Roy
and the mountains these life defining
type experiences that,
that we've talked about.
And you know,
the bond we've created together has been
over a handful of experiences,
you know,
and you,
you realize when you're out of your
comfort zone like that and when you're
both so committed to a pursuit,
those bonds formed quickly,
you know.
And so we've formed a strong bond over a
handful of experiences over a couple of
years will really.
And I,
um,
you know,
we went to high school together,
we started bowhunting as you know,
I think 18,
19 years old and had hundreds of
experiences,
life changing life,
defining experiences together over the
year.
So our bond naturally was like brothers
and um,
you know,
he,
he was,
when everybody doubted me,
when I was growing up and doubted my
dream of ever becoming anything he never
did.
He was always,
he was always the guy that believed in
me.
Well,
this year of sheep hunting,
he was up,
she punted where we had sheep hunted
before together and I killed a ram and
it was,
you know,
it's a,
it's a tough,
difficult,
dangerous hunt and he,
but he's more prepared or he was more
prepared for hunting like that than
anybody in the world.
He's done it.
He's done it as much as anyone that I
know and I've been successful.
I think he's killed,
had killed nine rams and he one misstep.
He fell and died,
um,
prime of his life,
essentially 49 years old.
I'm just,
you know,
as a father,
husband,
three kids,
somebody who even the toughest Alaska
hunters looked up to one step gone.
And that's,
you know,
that's.
So,
it's not just talk.
When you say zig zagged,
there's risk.
But that's,
I mean,
if you're going to it,
it just puts everything in perspective.
That's the allure to it.
Because I can speak for Roy and I
because I know we,
we always have known about the risks.
That was part of the draw is we wanted
to go where nobody else wanted to go or
do things that nobody else wanted to do.
That was the only thing that made us
different and it goes back.
That made us different.
That's,
and it goes back to the level,
the playing field.
Well,
we felt like,
well,
if we would go and do the hardest hunts
and the toughest conditions,
nobody else would want to do that,
but we would,
all of a sudden we were calling the
shots,
we don't call the shots,
the mountain calls,
the shots and all that.
That hunt the mountain.
One at Roy fell and he died and it's a
file 700 feet,
right?
Yeah,
yeah.
It's uh,
you know,
that where he fell just tough,
unforgiving sheep country.
And um,
you know,
once you,
once you start going there,
you're not going to stop.
And um,
it's one of the most dangerous hunts
sheep.
Yeah.
It's uh,
you know,
on that hunt specifically,
they give 100 tags and a lot of times
there's this one sheep killed.
It's that difficult in and I think 40
percent of the people never even go
because of the weather because of the
conditions because it's so hard.
So they draw the tag and don't even get
up the hill.
It wasn't a.
That was the case with you when you went
up there?
Grizzly hunting,
you were supposed to go sheep hunting as
well,
right?
Yeah.
Well now it's moose hunting,
Moose Hunt.
We were going to do a moose sheep Combo,
but there's so much.
No,
we couldn't even get to sheep country
and that was a plan.
We're going to go sheep hunting.
And that was with Roy.
That was with Roy.
Right.
So we had,
you know,
an amazing moose hunt together and I
killed a nice big bowl.
Um,
we just had just a,
just another epic adventure,
something,
you know,
a haunt that maybe a handful of people
would want to do because we were so far
back,
you know,
miles back and had to haul a moose out
over a mountain in the snow.
A very,
very,
very difficult.
Huh.
But the ones,
it was just,
it was perfect because it's our last
hunt together.
He died two weeks later and that hunt
and capsulated everything about us,
it was just hard.
It was miserable and it was rewarding.
And,
and you know,
we achieved success were not very many
people would have and we did it together
and uh,
yeah,
I mean,
and then two weeks later,
years was his sheep hunting.
There was an iconic photo that I think
it was forever going to define you from
that hunt with you with a big cut in
your face and blood streaming down your
face.
And you sent it to me while you were out
there.
Yeah.
You were,
you're saying we haven't,
we haven't gotten one yet.
Yeah.
We're out here hustling.
And there's this photo of you looking
grizzled is fuck with blood coming down
your face.
Snow in the background.
Yeah.
And I'm like,
uh,
yeah,
that's,
that's Cameron Hanes.
It is.
Because in enrolling it would,
we would always say we can make an easy
hunt hard because we want it to be hard.
But you went into an area where very few
people were having success and even with
rifles,
you're going deep,
deep into area.
It was a rifle area,
so that means you have.
Hunter had a different size of animal
that was legal if you're hunting with a.
So if you're hunting in this area,
it was a rifle area,
had to be a little bigger so I had to be
15 inches wide but had to have for Brow
Tine switch.
So you're,
you're,
you're making it harder.
So we were there and there in the rifle
area and we got it done.
And it was,
it was the hunt that it was a hunt that
that's what we love.
We loved hard.
We just loved the test.
No.
When you go out there and there's a
bowhunter have different standards in a
rifle hunter.
Like if you were there with a rifle,
would you have to have shot a bigger
bowl?
No,
that was I,
I went to the bigger area.
I went to the big area.
So in,
in the bowl area,
it only has to have three brown times
the Moose in the rifle or it had to have
four,
so I had to find one with four.
Well mine had five on one side for him
and another,
so it was good and it was over 50 inches
wide,
so as it was league all the way around.
But if I would've just focused on the
area,
it could have been a lesser bullet in
regard to time.
But uh,
and they do this to make sure again,
that the mature animals are harvested so
that the younger animals can breed.
And so this is all calculated by
wildlife biologists to make sure that
they have healthy populations
of these animals.
Just a mature bull has served his
purpose,
so to speak.
He's bred the animals over the years.
He's probably on the decline,
so it's a perfect time to take them out.
So that's not what people,
you know,
people associated almost instantly with,
oh,
you're full control of your own and the,
Oh,
you just want a bigger rack.
But they do that specifically because
it's for the health of the population of
these animals.
Yeah,
I mean we,
you know,
we,
we care about the animals we care about
and do like to kill a big animal,
but there's dual purpose.
We want to kill a big animal because
it's a,
it's awesome.
It's hard,
it's hard,
they're smart,
they're wiser and older,
mature animals,
especially with the bow.
So that's hard to do.
And then also on the dual purpose side
is it helps the health,
the health of the herd.
So we're,
you know,
we're doing the best we can,
but most of all,
uh,
you know,
when you go back to,
uh,
to bow hunting in general is just for
me,
it's just the tests,
the ultimate test is something that's
very hard.
And that's the draw.
Yeah.
And that,
that hunt also really exemplifies why
your hard work is so important.
First of all,
you shot the moose at 90 yards,
which is an incredibly.
We were shooting today at 45 yards and
as far as,
fuck,
I never said how far I shot that Moose.
I just tell people.
Sorry,
I'll listen to,
I mean,
you know Tim Gillingham,
we're talking about on the Gritty Bowman
podcasts who is a world champion Archer
who was talking about routinely shooting
animals over a hundred yards and then he
does this because he's a world champion
Archer and he can do that when you're
shooting a Moose,
the distance that you can shoot a moose
versus a guy like me who by the way I
still shoot every day but I just,
I can't do that.
I'm not,
it's not an ethical distance for me,
but it is for you and to have to haul
that animal out.
Sorry to blow up your spot on the yard.
I thought you already told people but it
was the perfect shot,
right?
I mean,
but that's a,
that's a funny area with,
with a shooting.
Something like a rifle shot at 91st
meal,
deer mule deer right there to your left.
That was 200 yards.
It was the first time I ever pull the
trigger on anything.
Yeah.
Anything.
Right.
And that was 200 years,
but of the rifle,
that's normal.
You get,
you get arrested with a rifle,
you just thrown on my stomach.
The whole thing was perfect.
Yeah,
I mean the rifle is a tool.
You just let her perform.
It's going to work,
you know,
the bow hunt with a bow.
It's just a lot of,
a lot of variables.
So all of your preparation is shooting
every day for years and decades really.
And then also your physical fitness to
be able to pack out.
I mean a moose is how big,
how many pounds of that thing way.
We had about 600 pounds of meat.
Just the meat,
just the meat.
I mean,
how much did the animal way?
Oh,
I dunno over.
I mean 1200 pounds.
Probably a thousand.
I don't know.
It's an enormous,
enormous animal.
Until you see one,
like in,
you're there physically next to it,
you don't realize.
No,
it
took us hours to break,
you know,
I killed it.
Um,
it was in the evening and uh,
Roy and I,
we had cameraman there,
but they ended up,
they found a little bit of the,
the process of breaking it down.
Then they headed back to the spike camp
in a row and I stayed there,
which we like just doing it by ourselves
back there together,
saying in just saying he would always
say,
I don't really,
uh,
what kind of stuff would be saying no
country girl Shaker for me.
Little Luke Bryan,
maybe little little,
uh,
Lady Gaga.
I.
Oh God,
Yeah.
He,
he,
he was a well versed,
terrible singer,
but it was,
it's just what we did,
right.
It was also part of the part of the
deal.
You were happy.
Oh,
successful hunt.
It was,
you know,
God,
I'm just gonna I'm gonna miss those
times with him because uh,
it's just hard knowing that the journey
we'd been through together.
That's why it's so appreciated.
And you know,
who else?
No,
there's another example.
We hunted this year and hunted the Brown
bear together and uh,
he,
uh,
I killed this bear.
The sow went over and was attacking the
corpse of the bear,
but the bear died.
She didn't know what was going on.
She smelled blood.
Just went crazy.
The,
these brown bear are there,
big predators.
And something goes in their head,
it's going to have an issue.
So she hurt.
When I shot the bore,
it made a noise.
It sorta ran towards her.
She stood up,
didn't know what was going on,
knew he'd made this noise.
So she ran towards where he was.
Well,
as soon as she hit his path,
she smelled the blood from where my
arrow past thrown.
So she tracked him by the blood,
just basically running,
smelling blood,
blood,
blood.
She got to him and he had died already.
She started attacking him.
This is just what they do.
These are,
you know,
these aren't crying,
hugging bear.
And uh,
so she's gone and I'm,
I'm with rolling on.
Like I said,
she's turned on my bed and I'm like,
God my bear.
And I'm yelling to her.
I'm like,
you know,
so I tell Roy on,
like I said,
we've got to get up.
I said,
shoot out there.
So he shoots boom.
And she's like,
didn't even know he didn't shoot at her.
He was making the noise,
just a scare.
Nothing.
Now I'm like,
Hey,
get off that there.
And she looked up and then she liked,
saw us,
all of a sudden here she comes,
sprinting,
and it was like,
what is going on?
And uh,
she's like a blood friends.
Yeah,
just,
it was so much going on at one time and
then it got something triggered in her
head and she was just crazy.
So here she comes and I killed my bears
in a creek.
She got to the creek and Roy says,
he says if she doesn't stop long enough
to shooter.
And I said,
yeah.
So she comes up to our side of the
creek.
Now I have an arrow knocked and you
know,
I don't know what I'm going to do with
an Arrow,
but it's,
I don't have,
I never pack a gun.
So I just had my bow and he had,
he had the gun,
she stands up at 20 yards away and we're
standing there and it's in,
it's a standoff.
And so we think,
well,
she stood up,
she going to see what's going on.
Um,
there was three of us standing there and
she's going to say,
okay,
dropped down and leave.
So we're like,
get out of here.
And uh,
she drops down bee line right towards
this charging and so roy boom,
and he,
uh,
he drops her,
you know,
one shot made a good shot.
He hit like Mr. Head,
but hit like right here and it was
folded or right there.
And it was,
what the law stands out for me is that,
um,
you know,
we were out,
we were never worried about our lives
were at stake,
were never worried about.
And you know,
like maybe a typical reaction to be
like,
oh my God,
we could have died or something like
that.
I,
I was just like,
I can just because I'm like,
I was mad she did that and required Roy
to act,
you know.
So I was just,
I cussed and he's like,
he's like,
dude,
I had to.
And uh,
so we were worried about ourselves.
We were just,
we didn't want to have to kill another
bear and we weren't nervous about the
situation.
And I'm like,
I said,
I know.
And it was like,
where else am I going to have somebody
that's on that same page with me that,
that's common,
that situation and not see their life
flash before their eyes,
just do what you have to do to,
to stop the risk.
That's never going to happen.
I'm never going to have somebody like
that in my life again.
And I think about we were,
you know,
we,
we knew the risk,
we're involved in everything that we did
and we embraced it and we're fine with
it and it,
and it didn't consume us or anything.
And that's what I'm going to miss is
having somebody.
So on my same page that I can trust like
that,
you know,
Roy was about,
you'd have to have someone who's
experienced that as many times as Roy
has had where it was,
he knew exactly what he had to do in
that moment.
Yeah,
he did.
And he said,
people know what they have to do.
It's,
it's executing.
That is what's hard,
you know.
And,
uh,
so knowing what it takes,
not panicking,
being in control and then getting the
job done with one shot,
very rare and he was so roy in those
situations was,
as you know,
I don't know everybody,
I haven't been with everybody,
but I would say he's as good as anybody
that I know of,
you know,
and uh,
um,
that's why,
you know,
when he fell and I got the news that he
fell and died.
I mean,
I could,
I could believe it,
I guess,
but I was mad and I'm still mad.
Um,
and I know everything happens for a
reason and I know,
you know,
he has,
he has a lot of faith and I know,
you know,
we want to think everything's gonna be
okay and we'll see each other again.
I know all that,
but it still makes me mad,
um,
because,
you know,
we missed or we missed out on a lot of
experiences we'd still love to have.
And we talked about and we were just
like,
we had these big,
big goals and big dreams.
And I'm mad that that's gone.
So it's completely,
it's not,
it's not just understandable,
it's,
um,
it's something that very few people
could probably relate to the kind of
intimate friendship that you would have
with someone who's experienced those
kinds of hunts.
It's been in the,
in the wilderness that's done like that
Moose hunt that you were talking about
when you guys were deep,
deep in the,
in the wilderness like that.
It's,
it's something that very few people will
ever.
Very few people ever experienced that
kind of danger,
that kind of an intimate moment in the
wilderness.
Just that connection to the wild that
you guys had together.
Right?
And so the whole point,
I guess with all that is it's people
say,
well,
you just,
your murderous or you want to kill such
a small part of what me and really
experienced together.
The kills were.
I mean they were,
we achieved our goal.
That was it.
It was the journey.
It was the Brotherhood.
It was,
you know,
growing up.
And that's what,
that's what hunting is.
It's not just you're out killing,
it's,
you're experiencing nature,
its most brutal or it's most rewarding
or the entire gamut.
And when,
when that makes you who you are,
um,
it's powerful and that's,
you know,
that's hunting
was to us.
Yeah.
There's a lot of people that are
listening to this.
I'm sure they're like,
well,
you know,
why is that?
Why should you feel any worse for your
friend than we should for the animals
that you killed?
You know,
there's a lot of people that they sort
of connect animals almost with people in
a way or maybe even better than people
in a way.
Maybe it's this and I think that's a
good part of this disconnect that we're
talking about.
These people that they don't experience
these,
these moments.
They don't,
they don't know anybody like that.
They don't have a friendship with
someone like Roy that they haven't had
these experiences like you did with him.
Yeah.
It's,
um,
I mean,
what you said,
you sent me the text,
I'm sorry to interrupt you,
but you sent me the text when,
when he died.
And I knew,
I knew that that had to be
devastating to his still is.
Um,
yeah,
I,
I mean,
I don't think there's a,
there's very few men like Roy,
uh,
he was,
he was a capable,
um,
he was,
uh,
just somebody you could count on,
anybody could count on and I'm just,
you know,
tough to replace what's very easy to get
by in this world today.
It's very easy to get by without being
that kind of a person and it's very
difficult to become that kind of a
person to always make the right
decisions,
to always push ahead,
to always,
always show character.
To always be someone that you can count
on is hard.
It,
yeah,
it's a society today is too easy,
I believe.
And so,
um,
that's why I think that's kind of the
draw for me to pushing myself the way I
do physically,
mentally.
I don't,
I don't like if something's easy,
I'm not attracted to it.
I'll,
I'll want to,
I want to be hard.
I want it to be hard.
I want it to be difficult.
And um,
because society makes us weak,
it makes us feel entitled and I don't
like it.
Um,
I don't,
you know,
every day I feel like unless I'm beat
down or tired or whatever,
I don't feel like I,
I achieved what I needed to achieve that
day and it's just,
you know,
I,
I can't expect anybody else to feel like
that.
That's just me.
Everybody else is motivated,
motivated by different things,
have different priorities.
I'm just for me and uh,
it's,
you know,
and,
and so finding somebody who have the
same mindset as me can be tough.
It's very rare.
It's,
it's hard for people to gravitate
towards challenge,
but through challenge you get the
greatest reward because through staying
in bed,
like there's,
there's the call of the bed is strong,
the warm bed and just,
Oh,
let me just hit fucking snooze and this
alarm clock and get nine more minutes.
Or let me just shut it off and call in
sick to work.
Let me just not do what I'm supposed to
do.
Let me just sleep.
And there was an article that I posted
recently where they were talking about,
um,
the power that dopamine has dope,
mean meaning memories.
And it's one of the reasons why people
have such a hard time kicking bad habits
is because we gravitate towards these
like reward experiences that we have in
our head.
The reward of eating shitty food or have
a drinking too much,
or it's your,
your mind sort of carves these paths
towards these real rewarding,
like a almost self destructive behaviors
because those,
they give you a dopamine,
whether it's eating shitty food or
whatever,
but it's the rare person who's mind
gravitates towards the reward of
accomplishment through reward of pushing
yourself through a very,
very difficult circumstance.
Very difficult to get to that feeling of
accomplishment like you get.
I'm sure when you run a marathon or like
you get when you get to the top of the
mountain,
when you pushing,
when you don't want to and you get to it
and you did it and you know that you
overcome this weakness inside of you
that wants you to quit,
right?
That everybody experiences at some point
in their life and it's a matter of how
you react to that experience and how you
react to that.
That poll,
the poll towards the bed is strong,
pull towards weaknesses,
strong because it's so easy to do.
It's so easy to quit.
It's easy to quit.
It is.
See it all the time.
That's one reason why,
I mean it seems minor,
but you know,
when I get up at four or five in the
morning,
I have to be at work at seven,
but when I get up early to do my fasted
cardio runs,
um,
and I'm out and so I have no fuel.
I'm out there.
There's nobody out four or five in the
morning and I'm running into the
neighborhoods by my house.
All the lights are off.
I just envision people in their
comfortable sleeping and I feel like,
you know,
it's,
I feel,
I feel the best.
Then when I,
you know,
it's like when I run the mountain,
when it's sunny,
I don't feel as good as when I run it,
when it's pouring rain because it's easy
to go out and do it when it's sunny,
if I run,
you know,
it on a weekend in the middle of the
day.
Lots of people out there,
I don't feel that accomplished when I do
it at four or five in the morning when
nobody's out there and it's just like
that in my head and I,
my head might not be normal,
but I,
I just love,
you know,
and people always say,
well,
you know,
all that running your,
you're going to be in a wheelchair by
the time you're 60.
And I'm like,
who's guaranteed to live to 60?
I mean,
I might die tomorrow,
you know,
so what am I supposed to do?
Save myself for what I,
I,
I want to know that I gave all I have
every day because tomorrow's not
guaranteed.
So I mean,
I just don't get it.
I have a hard time with that.
That mindset of the,
the moderation mindset,
those people that are saying that
they're peering through the curtains
while you're running by their house,
their sleeves gonna,
he's gonna wind up in a wheelchair and
not me,
I'm here Martin.
I don't know.
I mean,
it's,
uh,
you know,
so some people,
some people criticize and maybe maybe I
will be on a wheelchair,
but I'll know that I lived as hard as I
could live and,
and pushed as hard as I could when I
could do it and I'm not going to regret
it.
Yeah.
The people that try to knock someone
down for working hard and overcoming
extreme obstacles,
what they're doing is they're responding
to their own insecurity.
I mean,
there's logical things.
There's people that's,
you know,
there's,
there's people that look at certain
types of extreme sports where,
you know,
there's a bmx guy,
what's his name,
Dave Mirra,
who just committed suicide,
horrible,
horrible tragedy,
you know,
husband,
father,
the whole deal.
Um,
I gotta
think it's connected to head trauma.
And um,
I think you're talking about a
completely different thing when you're
talking about head trauma because you
know,
these poor guys that do these extreme
sports,
they wind up getting really banged up
and that causes some pretty severe
depression.
So I think in circumstances like that,
I think you're talking about a kind of a
different animal,
but people will criticize people who
take chances in life.
People will criticize people who work
hard,
you know,
like why do you have to lift weights?
Why do you think there was an article
that we had talked about at some asshole
at written in some bowhunting magazine
about you.
It online.
Yeah.
Well,
whatever it was,
you know,
he was just talking shit about you.
Like why does he have to,
you know,
you don't have to lift weights like this
guy,
you don't have to.
This is ridiculous.
But guess what?
Yeah,
you do.
If you want to do what you can do,
you have to.
Yeah.
It mean.
And what he's doing by writing that is
looking at someone who works harder than
him,
accomplishes more than him and he's
trying to chop you down.
And that's crabs in a bucket,
man.
That's people.
Do you ever see crabs in a bucket?
If you don't know what I'm talking
about,
folks,
if you see crabs in a bucket,
they never get out of that fucking
bucket.
Because if they work together,
one crap could stand on another crab and
the other crab grab on the top and then
they could figure out a way to push that
bucket over and they get all get out,
but nope.
What happens is one crab tries to get to
the top and the other crabs pull him
down and that's what a lot of people
are.
A lot of people are crabs in a bucket
and it's just a weakness and an
insecurity and a lot of times it's
because they don't know anybody like
you.
They don't know anybody like Roy.
They don't know anybody that can push
them.
They don't know anybody that they can.
They can look at their friend and they
could say,
you know,
this motherfucker can do it.
I can do it too.
If this guy,
if I know what he would do right now.
He's like,
here's a funny story.
I was in Texas with Aubrey and we were
pig hunting and we were in this fucking
moves,
reliable environment.
There was so many mosquitoes.
It was brutal.
I mean,
we were just getting mauled.
By the end of the day.
I mean,
it looked like I had some kind of crazy
disease,
like my whole body was covered in
mosquito bites and I thought to myself
while I was out there,
if campaigns was out here,
he would fucking keep going.
He would just deal with the fact that
mosquitoes are biting him and he would
keep going and rob said,
how the fuck did you get through all
those mosquitoes?
And I said,
I thought if campaigns was out here,
he would keep going.
He goes,
that's hilarious.
Because I thought if Joe Rogan can do
it,
I can do it without even be there pushed
me and me because I kept going.
It pushed him,
but we were,
it was fucking miserable.
We were,
there's this cloud of mosquitoes we just
swarmed on.
Well,
you know,
I mean it's,
it is a funny story but I do in some way
feel responsibility to the people that
follow me or look up to me to not give
up.
I know people look to me for inspiration
and you know,
and,
and it helps.
It's like when I don't feel like doing
something,
I think about all the people who
expect me to.
I mean I have a huge drive to do it
myself,
but it's just like sometimes those
little things and thinking about,
you know,
this story with you or people who have
lost a hundred pounds thinking about,
you know,
the work I put in,
it's like all those things have made me
who I am.
So it's a,
it's not like I,
I think about specific stories,
but I think about all the people who
have been such a positive message,
a positive impact on me because I guess
I haven't on them,
you know,
so can return it and it makes me,
it like the,
like the big foot $200 that I'm doing.
If I'm just on my own and nobody knows
who I am,
I'm much less,
much less,
a much are not as tough a muscle,
a less resilient as the guy I'm going to
be who will line up to run the big foot
200 and August because I'll feel like
I'll have an army of people helping me
push me and I just think that that's,
you know,
as a society that's a type of things we
need to focus on.
I believe.
So inspiration to two way street.
Yeah.
When you inspire people,
those like I do these meet and greets
after shows you all the time and I can't
tell you how many people have come up to
after show that say I lost 100 pounds.
Once I started listening to your
podcast,
I started eating healthy.
I started looking at my body in a
different way and I started realizing
like I will be happier if I took care of
myself and then I'm happier when I do
force myself to exercise and now I do it
everyday and I'm drinking Kale shakes
and I'm eating healthy foods and I
stopped drinking and all this and it
makes me feel better.
I mean,
I think about it when I work out,
I quickly.
That's where inspiration is a two way
street and then it's also what we were
talking about,
like you've created a community through
your,
your social media and through the the
positive posts that you make and through
through all your actions and all the
different things you've done,
you've created this sort of sense of
community where all these other people,
they feed off of that and you feed off
of them and we all feed off of each
other.
Yeah,
no,
it's through this podcast to,
man,
this has been a nuisance,
an inspirational podcasts.
I'm going to listen to this podcast when
I workout tomorrow.
Yeah.
When I.
When I do my morning workout tomorrow,
I'm going to put this on my headphones
and I'm willing to listen to this.
I'm going to listen to specifically to
the story about you and Roy.
Yeah,
and that,
you know,
people want to be that kind of person.
You know,
people don't want to be a lazy fuck who
criticizes people for no reason.
They don't.
They don't want to be that guy that's
weak and that talk shit about someone
when they're not there because they feel
bad that that person is out there
working out.
Well,
you don't want to have to do with Kim
Haines.
Dude,
shut the fuck up.
You know what you're doing,
bitch.
You know what you're doing.
When you're doing that,
while you're doing it,
you know what you're doing.
While you're making those,
you know there's a little sneaky voice
in the back of your head unless you're
completely obtuse,
unless you're completely oblivious to
the way you interact and interface with
the world,
you know what you do and when you say
those things,
he tried to chop someone down because
they make you feel weak and instead of
saying,
this guy is out there doing something
awesome instead of just what's what's
negative about someone working
out and being healthy.
What's negative about someone who values
physical fitness and accomplishing
difficult goals?
That is the essence of character.
That's the essence of what's
inspirational about a person.
I'm not inspired by someone who sleeps
till two.
I'm not inspired by someone who can not
eat shitty food and loves to smoke.
Inspired by discipline,
discipline.
I love discipline and as you talked
about,
the rock guys like the Rock and the rock
is out to $40 million.
You get out to how many will listen to
this podcast?
I mean,
I don't know,
but it'd be more than a million for
sure.
Millions.
So over the course of how many years
this is out there in the world,
right?
So I'm inspired by you,
the Rock and so in my own little
bowhunting world,
I just try to live up to that and,
and you know,
I guess what I wanted,
I want to thank you for giving me this
platform,
given me access to all you've created
here because,
you know,
as we've talked about,
that's what feels good to reach people,
inspire people,
and yet maybe they'll be inspired maybe
even a little by the heartbreak of
losing a good buddy,
you know,
maybe to be a better friend or maybe to
be somebody who,
uh,
I don't know,
that integral part of somebody else's
life.
Maybe that'll inspire them.
Maybe the workout part,
who knows,
maybe it'll be a better,
uh,
I don't know,
more understanding to the vegans and be
able to explain it better.
There's so much you can take from this
podcast and without you giving me this
microphone,
it would never happen.
So I want to thank you and,
uh,
I'm so grateful.
Uh,
I've just,
I'm so happy I've met you and now we've
created this friendship.
I couldn't be more happy myself.
And again,
that inspiration is a two way street.
This podcast doesn't exist if it's not
for other people,
mean what all I am is like an antenna or
something.
Just broadcasting my thoughts and other
people's thoughts too.
And without a guy like you to introduce
me to something like bowhunting,
I would have no idea.
I would've gone to my grave without
having any idea how rewarding it is to
go and get my own meat through archery
in the woods.
How difficult it is to pursue such an
incredibly,
incredibly demanding discipline.
And what that's about and for you being
inspirational and for you creating those
videos,
you reached me and in you touched me
with your positivity and with your,
your inspiration and with your
dedication and focus.
And I live for that man.
I live for inspiration.
That's my fuel.
I love it.
I love inspiring people.
I love people that are inspiring me and
I love inspiring other people.
I love inspiration.
I think it's one of the most,
one of the most powerful aspects about
our new found ability to communicate
with each other,
right?
Social media,
so you can.
You can be a negative anchor or you can
inspire,
so yeah,
maybe that's the message of the podcast
today.
Just get out there,
like I say,
make a positive difference and it
doesn't have.
We can all do.
It doesn't have to be big.
It doesn't have to be to 40 million,
10 million or a 1 million
Haggen Beto one guy.
Yes.
Make a positive difference.
We can all do it and we can all do it in
our own way and it's the better way to
live.
It's the better way to live this.
This world that we're living in right
now is essentially a global community
that is coming to awaken.
It's aware of itself now in a way that's
never been a before.
We can communicate with each other like
you know,
there's this strange new time where you
can.
You could seek out shit that pisses you
off.
You can see you could just fucking spend
all day on Kanye West instagram page and
get angry.
You can just scour through all of the
worst aspects of all sorts of different
people,
or you can choose to be inspired.
You can choose to live your life in a
powerful and dedicated way,
but there's only one way to do that is
through action.
It's a choice.
Yeah,
it is a choice man,
but it's a good choice.
It's a great choice to make.
It's way through that choice.
You enrich yourself and enrich the other
people that you've come in contact with
and then we're strong or a stronger as,
as as society.
You know we're not perfect.
People folks know we're all we all fuck
up.
We all get mad when we shouldn't get
mad.
We all falter and through those lessons
of failure,
sometimes the disappointment you have in
yourself when you come up short is the
fuel you need to make sure you never
come up short that way again and maybe
you'll come up short and another way
next week.
You know?
Well,
that fucking thing is never going to
happen again either.
And you find a way to assess.
Yeah,
it is a process and that's one of the
things that I really try to drill into
people's heads.
You know,
they go,
Oh,
can you?
How have you done so many things?
I've done so many things because I've
sucked at all of them.
Everything I've ever tried,
I sucked at in the beginning,
everything you fail and then you learn
how to not fail and you,
you know,
how do you,
how do you do that?
Will you take God damn chances?
That's how.
That's how you start a bow hunting at
45.
You got to fucking take chances.
And if you don't take chances,
if you stay within your comfort zone,
man,
that's not a fun life.
Now,
it's not a,
it's a,
it's,
it's a cushy life.
It's probably a little safer.
It's insulated.
And that's what I've always respected
about you is you,
when you started bowhunting and,
and you know,
it's because I know firsthand how
difficult it is.
So you've been successful in so many
different arenas,
right?
And been,
you're Joe Rogan,
all of a sudden Joe Rogan is a new bow
hunter who doesn't know shit about
anything and it's like,
for you to say I'm okay with that.
That's a big deal.
Most people who have been so successful
don't want to be starting out on ground
zero again.
So I mean,
for you to do that and then and then
becomes.
So just disciplined and enamored with
the discipline of bowhunting has been
awesome.
And uh,
I love it.
I love doing things I suck at.
Most people don't.
That's why I like yoga and I mean it's
why,
uh,
like when we were working out today,
you have that same sort of approach to
like we were showing you all these crazy
new exercises and you were gravitating
towards the ones that you weren't good
at.
I mean,
it was.
Yeah,
I mean,
I,
I love pushing myself.
It's like when I,
when I work out with New People,
I love exposing them to.
I said,
okay,
this workout doesn't start until you're
miserable.
And then once you're miserable,
then it counts because everybody can do
it when it's easy.
Right?
Okay.
Now you can't do it.
Now we start and it's just like I,
you know,
I had a good eye.
I just like exposing.
People would always say,
you know,
and people,
other people have said it too.
I didn't invent this,
but being comfortable from being
uncomfortable and that's this getting
that moment where,
okay,
now I'm here,
now I want to start gaining,
you know?
And that's,
that's just the,
that's the journey that anything,
this has a big reward is going to
require that.
Well,
that's the essence of Jujitsu.
Jujitsu is being comfortable while
you're uncomfortable because everybody
gets tapped.
There is no way to get good at Jujitsu
unless you get mauled by another person
is the only way.
And you know,
for me,
I started Jujitsu as you know,
a,
a former taekwondo champion who would
spend my whole lot.
I was successful.
It's striking my whole life.
I had done,
you know,
different forms of striking competitions
and then all of a sudden I'm doing
Jujitsu and getting fucking crushed by
people were my size or smaller and
they're just beating the piss out of me.
Like I'm a ragdoll.
I'm a,
I'm a grappling dummy and for me I had
realized I had,
first of all,
I had to address the fact that I was
nowhere near as competent in self
defense is.
I thought I was like,
as soon as these guys got ahold of me,
they were just strangling me.
I was like,
okay,
like my perception of what I could do
versus the reality of what I could do
was I had to,
I had to just address it,
I had to figure it out and so okay,
now I've got to get fucking crazy and
attached to this shit.
And then I became completely obsessed
with that about of training and getting.
But that's one of the beautiful things
about Jujitsu.
One of the things about Jujitsu that I
admire most in the truly good
practitioners is they have very healthy
egos because their,
their,
their egos get tested.
Yeah.
They're in check all the time.
Constantly tapping tap all the time.
Yeah.
I mean,
I don't think I've ever gone more than a
few months in my whole life without
tapping.
Well,
and that's the same with bowhunting.
Don't start bowhunting unless you can
deal with failure.
You know,
it's a humbling.
Just like,
just like you know,
the discipline you're talking about.
Bowhunting is a discipline.
Just like that.
It will humble you no matter how good
you think you will.
I think all very difficult things are
good for you.
Wait,
as long as it doesn't kill you,
it's good for you.
I mean like these goddamn ultra
marathons,
you're running this crazy fuck you want
100 miles is not enough.
You're like,
well,
I've already done that a couple of
times.
Now I got to do 200.
So
here's the big foot,
200.
His quick facts.
Jamie just pulled up just under 50,000
feet of a sent 15,240 meters of a cent.
More than 96,000 feet of elevation
change.
Two hundred and three point eight miles
nonstop.
Point to point six.
Sleep stations with full aid,
hot food,
medical and crew access.
16 full aid stations.
The race starts at Mount St Helens in
the cascade mountain range of Washington
state and finishes in Randall
Washington.
Traversing point to point the cascade
mountains.
That's insane.
That's a.
So my goal with it and I've never done a
200,
obviously the furthest I've run is 106
and a half miles in 24 hours.
So this will be a new test.
Um,
and my goal for this ad,
and I don't even know if it's possible.
I don't want to sleep,
I don't take advantage of any of those
sleep stages.
I want to be able to push through and
finish in 60 hours and last year,
64 hours one it.
And I'm trying to,
that's what I'm training you want to
beat that I want to beat that.
I want,
I want to beat six 64 and I just want
to,
I want to grind it out.
I want to be better than I've ever been.
And so that's,
you know,
right now I'm training.
I haven't been training this hard this
early in the year so I'm taking it.
I'm doing a lot of miles but not
hammering hard and a bill trying to
build up that base.
So come August,
I hope to line up there for the big foot
200.
And I hope to run it faster than it's
ever been run.
Jesus Christ.
Are you going to lose body mass before
you do that?
Because you're always lifting weights.
Like what?
What are you going to do differently?
I need to get lighter.
A way about what [inaudible] 77.
Yeah.
Right now I am,
you know,
and I was up one 82 or 83 and so I'm
trying to,
I want to get down.
I'd like to get 69 maybe,
you know,
and I think I just really feel like I'd
be efficient at that and I just,
you know,
it's,
it's physical,
but it's a lot mental also.
So I mean I'll get my,
I'll prepare my body for it,
but it's just whether I can hydrate and
fuel,
uh,
well enough,
smart enough and just do everything.
Keep my feet healthy.
That's what's going to determine whether
I can finish the 60 hours.
So,
uh,
I think I,
I believe I have what it takes.
Um,
but a lot of people probably have what
it takes,
but to implement it is going to be
difficult.
But,
um,
I can't wait.
I wish it was tomorrow.
What's the percentage of people who
start that thing versus completed?
I don't know.
I think it's pretty high percentage
because if you line up for 200,
you didn't just decide to do that.
Right?
You know what I mean?
These people are crazy.
They've put in a lot of training and so
if,
if they're crazy enough,
I mean it's a thousand dollars to run
it.
So if they're crazy enough to pay the
entry fee lineup there,
they didn't just,
it wasn't on a whim.
It was,
they've geared their life,
tore it.
It's crazy too.
It's not a thousand mile.
I mean,
it's not 200 miles on a flat track.
Now it's mountains,
mountains.
I mean,
you know,
that 50,000 feet of ascent,
that's what does that to Mount Everest.
Jesus Christ is Mount Everest.
Thirty thousand feet.
I think it's 26.
She something like that.
So it's two of those,
but it has that same,
uh,
so it's 96,000 feet or changed.
So what that means is you're grinding up
as much as you're hammering down and
that down.
Break your quads down.
As you know.
It's a hard low yourself down.
This is a video of it.
Yeah.
So that's,
that's a country that it's in.
What is this guy doing?
He's walking.
Run Bitch while you're walking.
Well there's like God,
this is the country.
Yeah,
this is it.
You can't run this.
Wait a minute,
hold on a second.
Yeah,
it's like this.
Yes.
Oh fuck.
Artist ultra in the USA,
right?
Do you know which way to go?
How do you go left or right?
There'll be ribbons.
So there's probably ribbons that'll
mark,
but this isn't.
Now you're not on a bike trail.
This is the hardest ultra and the USA.
We need to document this.
We need.
This is 200 miles of this and if you try
to run,
here's what I learned with ultra is if
you try to run where it's super steep,
all you're doing is gonna blow your legs
out.
I mean,
so you have to get good hiking tooth
because you hiked the super steep stuff
or this isn't even runnable really,
but you don't want even want to try.
So it's all about being efficient in
managing,
managing your resource,
but it's,
it's a test that's a,
to put it mildly.
Yeah.
So I mean that.
I don't know,
this is what I live for,
but listen dude,
there's a problem and that is that this
is in August and you need to be healthy
and September because we got to go back.
We're bowhunting temper.
It's all mental.
Mental Madison is definitely some
physical involved in that.
Yeah.
People have completed it.
I Dunno what,
what does that one nutty run that you
told me about that very few people know
about the Barclays.
Have you heard about this?
Yeah,
that's intense.
What is that?
That's like A.
I don't even know if there's really a
course.
You know,
they have
snow course.
It's a,
it's really loose.
They don't,
it's not marked.
You can get lost.
You have to have your own map.
Oh Great.
Yeah.
It's.
And it's something like 64 miles maybe,
but it's like,
I mean,
you're in swamps it,
it's nasty.
I mean I think God,
it seems like for people finish or
something,
they only allow in.
It's a small number.
Twelve 20.
I don't know that much about.
I've heard about it just yet.
Two people finish it each time.
Some people don't finish it.
Okay.
Five.
You do it like I,
if I remember correctly,
it's like one one way up during the day
and you come back down at during the
night and then you switch and go the
opposite way the next day up and down.
And then if you can make it to that
fifth turn,
it's all.
And it's also the same kind of way.
It's nonstop.
If you want to sleep,
you sleep.
You only have I think a window of like
36 hours total to finish the whole thing
if you can make it.
Yeah.
I mean if you don't,
maybe 48 hours.
But yeah,
it's.
You got your eye on that fucking thing.
I don't know.
I mean that to me the navigation is a
whole different animal.
You know,
I want to be able to.
I want to be prepared.
I want to know where the course is
roughly.
You know what I mean?
I don't really want to waste time having
to read a map and a compass.
That's a whole different challenge,
which maybe I'll get to that at some
point.
Right now I just want to run 200 miles.
I want to run it that race as fast as it
has been run.
I don't know if that.
I don't know what I'm going to do.
I don't know what my body's going to do,
but I want to find out and I'm looking
forward to it.
Wow.
That's intense,
man.
I'll be ready by tomorrow.
We should document it.
I should be looking at a range rover
next to,
you know,
that's conditioned.
Sipping lemonade.
Yeah.
Control a drone.
A drone.
So yeah.
No,
I'm pretty.
Yeah,
it's neat.
How does someone document that you would
have to have gopros on or something like
that because someone has to go with you
that people have talked about filming
it.
Maybe under armour will.
I'm not sure how they're going to do
that.
I don't know.
You'd have to have some fucking savage
that's willing to run it with you.
My brother,
I know my brother's going to run some of
it with me.
And he's a beast.
Yeah.
So He's a,
he runs,
he's done 100 before run in your family.
Yeah.
So He's,
he's tough.
Dad was like a.
What was your dad wouldn't track and
field athlete as well?
Yeah,
he was,
you know,
my,
my dad was a,
I'm not athletic.
My Dad was a freak and uh,
he had full scholarships at Oregon,
Oregon State for track and field and
gymnastics to different sports.
He's pretty tall for a gymnast.
He was around six foot tall,
but just crazy ability.
Um,
he was an amazing athlete so I didn't
get that,
but maybe I got,
I got enough of it to be tough to see.
When people say that like,
well,
what have you attempted to do that's
athletic wear?
You failed that.
Like people that say,
Oh,
I'm not a really good athlete.
Like what does a really good athlete and
someone who practices the techniques of
whatever sport they're trying to do and
gets really good at it.
Yeah,
I mean,
you're really good at running and you're
really good at bowhunting.
Bonnie is absolutely athletic,
right?
It's like if,
if golf is a fucking sport,
what's Boeing is a problem with calling
hunting a sport.
A lot of people out because I think it's
best described as a discipline because I
don't,
I don't like to think of it as something
that you score points.
I mean,
either I don't.
It's too trivial.
No,
it's too much of life.
But I do think,
uh,
there is athleticism within bowhunting
hundred percent,
especially out west,
especially in the mountains in Alaska.
Um,
so yeah,
I mean,
I,
when I think when people think athlete,
they think to General the sports track
and field football,
basketball,
you know,
things like that.
So,
I mean,
um,
I didn't get that elite athleticism in
those sports as my dad did.
I mean,
I think he had the ability to make the
Olympics.
Um,
but,
you know,
life happened.
I was born this or that,
so he was.
He was a freak and in what,
what you might.
Normal athletic
events,
maybe bowhunting,
you know,
qualifies on.
It's 100 percent qualifies.
Look at this fighting qualifiers,
athletics.
I think it does,
but it's way more intense than regular
athletics.
It's something way more personal and
dangerous about the goal of knocking
someone unconscious while they're trying
to knock you unconscious and if,
if fighting,
if that counts.
That's athletics.
Bowhunting is most certainly athletics,
but I think we both agree that it's.
It's a little bit more intense than a
sport.
Yeah,
definitely.
It's more,
it's almost disrespectful in a way.
Not.
I mean,
if you consider it a sport,
you call it a sport,
that's fine,
but in my view,
it's so much about the life and the
reverence for this animal that you hunt
an intake.
It's not.
We won the superbowl,
we scored the goal.
The ball went in.
The hole is the journey is the journey
is not just a punch tags.
So the Punch tag,
you'd say,
well I won.
Yeah,
I won.
So in a sport there's a winner and the
loser,
you kill the animal,
you punch your,
tag,
you one.
That's not it.
I mean it's,
it's the whole journey that lease it.
And then also we talk about the getting
the meat home and providing for your
family,
how do you score that you can.
So yeah,
it's not a sport in that regard for
sure.
There's,
it's a discipline and even that word is
like,
it's Bonnie is bowhunting man.
That's what it is.
Yeah,
it's on the song.
It's not a tone.
It's got its own thing.
And on that note,
you got to catch a flight.
My brother.
I do.
Thank you again.
So much fun to hang out even just for a
few hours.
It was great to hang out with you in
salt lake and wander around all those
freaks and dead animals.
Uh,
all right folks,
we'll be back tomorrow with my brother
Doug Derryn,
Wednesday boss Rutan and Mall Rinella.
Ooh,
that's going to be fun.
The original team from one of the
original teams from pride broadcasting,
two great guys.
Morrows an awesome dude.
Um,
and bosses the best and of course on
Friday,
robin black,
who now works for the UFC,
we've got him a job.
Yes.
So,
uh,
we'll see you soon.
Thank you everybody much.
Love.
Bye.