Boom,
and we're alive.
Jamie,
where'd you get that awesome shirt.
Show everybody.
Your Shark tank.
You show the people.
You're sure.
I picked it up yesterday.
It says,
believe,
believe that.
Believe that from the hundreds that saw
the story yesterday.
What is the hundreds?
100.
Does a streetwear brand started?
Fairfax.
I thought it was like a scene in a
movie.
I was confused.
Oh.
So I just saw and I was like,
oh dope.
Yeah.
I mean that's a combination of that girl
who was on Dr Phil Show and Ufo Sorta.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Take the lead dad [inaudible] like
believe,
believe is so x files the year to 1999
or whatever it was like when was the x
files on?
It's on now,
but when,
but when was the original one?
Yeah,
late nineties.
Mid Nineties I believe is that.
Does that poster and I always just.
You can't disconnect them from the Po,
the poster and molders office,
but believed that that's today.
Nailed it.
Even whoever made that shirt,
I want to believe that's a cool shirt.
Is it?
I want to believe that would have seen
on the poster believed that's better,
but I do want to believe of all the
things of all the stupid things.
I would love to believe that someone
like got real footage of Ufo is like
more than almost any other weird like
big foot type,
loch ness,
monster,
all the really nutty shit.
If they could find out one of those was
true fucking aliens,
number one,
right?
For sure.
Even if you just knew for sure that you
saw a real ship or if the aliens looked
like a big foot,
then you kill two birds with one stone.
That was the actual theory.
Ah,
some of these big foot people are so.
There's spectrums of big foot people,
man.
This big foot people.
There's people that are like real
primatologists,
like Jane Goodall.
Jane Goodall believes in bigfoot.
Believe it or not.
It's really fascinating.
There's a whole interview with her where
she says she's sure of it.
She said she sure that there's another
species.
How can she be sure?
Let's play the clip,
see if we can find that clip.
Um,
who's Jane Goodall is a world famous
primatologist who did some
groundbreaking work with chimpanzees.
She essentially live with chimpanzees.
She's so powerful.
I mean,
this lady is amazing if he watched her
documentaries.
So when someone like her says something
like that,
I'm like,
okay,
well I should shut the fuck up and stay
in my lane.
What am I to argue with Jane Goodall
about primates?
And it used to be a real thing.
They used to really be a gigantic topic
is an eight foot tall orangutang like
thing that probably walked on two legs
and she believes it's real.
She thinks it did exist or she thinks
that links it exists right now.
Wow.
Yeah.
I don't think it was taken out of
context because I'm pretty sure it was,
um,
someone asked her a question and then
she gave a long and detailed answer
based on what we know about certain
chimpanzee subspecies that are really,
really hard to find.
Like we're just finding out.
I think they figured it out from like
the 19 nineties.
There's a giant version of chimpanzees
that lives in the Congo.
It's what they call them a Bondo apes or
there's a couple different names for
them.
They call them,
but they sleep on the ground like
gorillas.
They're giant chimps who love that
stuff.
I watch planet earth to the other day
just mesmerized,
just physically saying like,
wow,
wow.
I don't think a normal person
understands what you're talking about
when you say a six foot tall chimp.
Yeah.
I just don't think they know what you're
talking about.
You're talking about like a super
gorilla.
It's like not.
It's,
it's way scarier than a gorilla because
they're their chimps.
Chimps are scarier.
Chimps are predators.
Yeah.
Chimps eat monkeys,
man.
I mean they,
they.
People want associate chimps with
bananas and nuts and stuff like that and
they eat that stuff too,
but they also eat monkeys.
Scary dude.
They're.
They're ruthless motherfuckers.
What does this buddies from MPR
conversation?
You can find the actual recording
because it's fascinating when you hear
the tone of her voice.
She says something like,
I'm sure of it.
She has this super powerful voice.
This.
I mean,
this lady is a fucking biologists,
bad ass.
She's living with chimps.
Man.
Just hanging out with them constantly.
You know what kind of a human being you
have to be to be able to keep your shit
together and a tribe of wild chimps
where they accept you.
They don't just smash your fucking head
in for a goof.
That is crazy.
Come on man.
Well here's.
This is the transcription,
but I'm pretty sure it's a soundbite
here,
but there's no link or anything.
Oh,
I know it exists to try and find it on
youtube maybe.
Alright.
Shit.
Well,
what did,
what did she say there?
Well,
well now you'll be amazed when I tell
you that.
I'm sure that they exist.
Yeah,
yeah.
That's what it was.
That's how she said it.
Well,
now you will be amazed when I tell you
that I'm sure that they exist.
That's basically how she said it.
Did you always believe that they
existed?
She says,
well,
I'm a romantic,
so I always wanted that and there you
have it,
blah,
blah.
Where does it say about evidence?
She's also talking to Dr Meldrum who you
talk to here.
We had Dr Meldrum.
What is his full name?
Jeffrey Jeffrey Meldrum and he's a
professor,
right?
I think he brought in the big foot foot.
He was the guy.
Dr Meldrum was a really nice guy.
We also said he'd be willing to cut off
a finger to know that big foot was real.
I'm like,
Whoa,
whoa.
Like what finger?
Pinky.
Which one would.
Which one would you go with?
Pinky.
No,
because you'd want the
pinky because that's the farthest
leverage to the other side of the thumb.
Right.
So it's sort of like a claw,
maybe the ring finger.
That's a good point.
The middle finger seems pretty
pointless.
Yeah.
This is the interview,
but I don't know where in the interview
it is.
Oh,
okay.
My perspective,
I guess just considering the.
You're going to be amazed when I tell
you.
I'm sure they exist.
It's like a scene in a movie when she
says it because here she is this
esteemed scientist.
Right.
And you're expecting,
well there's no evidence and right now
that's just.
We think of it as legend and could
possibly be a bunch of different things
that people think they saw
voice and delivery's important when it
comes to being convinced of something
you think about,
like,
you know,
all the way to just comedians being
anything.
Chappelle's voice.
If you look at the transcript of what
Chappelle saying at times,
I'm sure it's not that insane,
but you listen to him say those things.
Singles who?
Joey Diaz.
Oh yeah.
For sure.
You know,
and when it's coming from a scientist
with long gray hair who lives with
chimps,
she must be amy.
And you think she's hooked up with the
champ?
I mean,
all those come on chance.
She lives with all of them.
Yeah.
Wow.
It sounds like there's some monkey
business going on.
It didn't help me.
I didn't even mean set it up.
Here it is.
Nine,
eight,
nine,
two,
five,
five.
Yeah.
Hi.
How you doing?
I'm wondering to if you believed her at
any undiscovered large APP.
Here it is.
A yeti or big photos.
Nothing message I'm missing here are
pretty much out of the loop.
Well,
now you will be amazed when I tell you
that I'm.
I'm sure that they are.
Yeah.
I've talked to so many native Americans
who described the same songs to who's
seen them.
I've probably got about 30 books that
have come from different parts of the
world,
from China,
from,
from all over the place.
You always have this belief that they're
debating that big of a romantic one too.
All right Jerry.
Thank you.
Thanks for calling.
She probably knows more than me,
so you know if you can.
When in doubt go with the person knows
more than you,
but I've never.
I've never seen any like real evidence
other than these footprint things.
I mean everything else is just bullshit.
They find hair turns out to be bear
here.
They find scat.
Turns out to be like a wolf scat.
Where did they find the footprints at?
How they find them everywhere,
man,
but you don't know what you're looking
at.
You know,
it could be anything.
Could be someone decided to fake
footprints.
You know,
it could be a big bear that's less
likely,
but it depends on the area.
Like a big grizzly bear print,
who knows?
I mean he would.
It took to make it look already human
foot.
It would after either be a giant human
foot or be just incredible special
effects.
It's one or two things.
Some of them when they got like ridges,
they've found like dermal ridges that
indicate a.
They think it indicates a footprint type
thing,
but with the,
with the feet of these things,
they seem to think that that somehow or
another makes it very,
very difficult to fake.
But people want to believe that shit.
That's part of the problem.
Part of the problem is it's fun.
It's super fun to believe that someone's
not fucking with you,
but that's some big giant monkey just
walked through with every day,
every passing minute of every day.
It becomes way less likely that that's a
real thing because there's so many
people with cameras and these people go
deep into the woods
and I think it's also like one of the
cooler things to believe in because it's
not,
you know.
Yeah man,
be even if they did exist,
like we have guns and shit.
Whereas like if aliens existed were
fucked.
Yeah,
we're fucked navy.
So we're sort of rooting for the
sasquatches in the world.
What of all the look,
there had to be a bunch of different
kinds of human being like creatures that
existed is it just only makes sense.
They're finding new ones all that time.
They're like constantly finding some new
subspecies of people that they weren't
aware of before.
It's super possible that something grew
to be like that.
Like why wouldn't it be if we can get a
chance?
Why?
Why is that so weird?
Like it's not any weirder than a person
or a chimp.
Both of those things are way weirder.
Like we found another person.
We'd be like,
Holy Shit,
look what it's done.
Like if we could,
we poked our head into some other
dimension,
right?
And we just stuck our head through and
we saw the impact of a human
civilization on the natural world.
We'd be like,
what the fuck?
That's way crazier than bigfoot.
Like a human being is making tubes out
of aluminum with giant wings and
shooting itself into the sky and landing
on different spots.
It's sucking oil out of the ground and
using it to build everything.
It's talking on vine and it goes through
the air and winds up on your phone.
All this is done by a human that's way
crazier.
The big foot.
That's fucking crazy.
Then you go to chimps.
Chimps are way crazier than bigfoot.
They're hot and monkeys,
man.
They're fucking forming little societies
together.
Some of them are figuring out how to use
tools and they're right there like
that's way crazier than bigfoot.
Bigfoot's just a shy guy.
He just wants to be alone and just let
him find a good place to shit.
You can't find any big foot shed because
he's always paranoid that people were
watching them.
So he's holding his shit in it.
I think Jane Goodall's wrong on this
one.
I'm going to be honest with you.
I don't know where,
but I'm going to go out there off on a
limb
that is limb.
That's quite a limb,
sir.
Why would you think that she would think
it's real?
Because she wants it to be real.
Yeah,
and you know,
she said that she was talking to native
Americans about it and you know,
they're like,
you know,
they,
they go off on a little bit trippy.
Right,
right.
They might be sent to jail.
Yeah.
Who knows,
you know,
just like saying you talked to to native
Americans.
It's like saying I talked to white
people like,
you know,
just because they happen to be native
Americans.
Like they got street cred for big foot.
She's what she's saying.
She's,
yeah,
she's,
she's made an appointment.
Native Americans bigfoot street cred.
It's closer to the sasquatch.
They named it.
It's like if anybody knows about almost
going extinct,
it should be state of California sued
because it won't recognize it is
bigfoot.
Is this,
is this today?
Yeah.
This last lawsuit,
that's what that is city going on here.
There's a lot of people in this country
who claimed to believe the existence of
big foot,
but one California woman believes it's
so strongly in the beast.
She's actually filed a lawsuit to prove
it.
Could you imagine being the court
systems all choked up with divorce and
corruption and tax evasion and whatever
the fuck else they investigate,
and this crazy lady like,
I'm silly.
I've got a team of lawyers.
We're taking the whole state down.
They won't recognize sasquatch.
We won't recognize them and she's just
going to town getting crazy.
She makes a Gofund me and big foot
people.
They're like super pumped.
When there's some action,
something's happening.
They'll fucking donate to that.
Go Fund me a little bit here,
a little bit here and a lot of big foot
lovers out there.
This chick would be fighting the
government video.
Imagine the lawyer that takes that case
like,
is this a video of her with bigfoot?
Yeah.
She said it was 30 feet up into a tree.
It seems real where these people are
just wonderful people that really,
really,
really want big foot to exist and when
you really,
really,
really want big foot to exist,
you sort of figure out a way to make
them exist in your mind.
There's no evidence.
The problem is there's nothing.
There's no footprints that are like a
attached to hair.
You know,
where you could get like a little bit of
hair off of it and say,
Oh,
well this is definitely a primate.
Does none of that.
They have dental,
have any of that.
They have these mushy footprints that
people have made in the month.
They impossible to fake.
Maybe.
I don't know.
I don't know if they're impossible to
fake,
but I do know that I haven't seen one
picture that looks real.
I've seen one video.
Everything just smells like bullshit.
Yeah,
the pee p,
the problem always have with it is it
always looks like a man in a suit and
here's the thing.
The only thing that looks like a man in
a suit as a man in a suit like this,
even a chip doesn't look like a man in a
suit.
They moved different men.
Chimps Kinda like throw themselves with
their arms and up.
They moved.
If you can't move like that,
you can't move like that.
You could try.
You're not going to be able to move the
way a chimp modes,
especially with chimps moving fast.
Just get the fuck outta here.
It's not even close.
You look like a guy pretending to be a
chimp.
You're moving like a guy.
All these things move like people.
They move like people like your brain,
a little computer in your brain that
recognize the shapes goes,
oh,
that's a guy in a monkey suit.
Yeah.
Right.
Instantly.
That's exactly what you think because it
is that one,
the famous one that we know that one was
a guy in a suit,
right?
Well,
there's people that dispute it,
but that's the patterson footage.
The Patterson footage is like the most
famous footage and all of bigfoot lore
because this guy who I'm pretty sure the
guy was a.
He was arrested for something like,
for not pay.
I believe it was something like not
paying for the very camera that he used
to film the big foot footage.
Wow.
Arrested for it.
So the guy,
he's stealing cameras,
right?
Dad's not good.
Right.
And then there's another guy who claims
that he wore the suit.
What the fuck is that guy's name?
I always forget that guys name Gimlet is
the guy that was there and then there
was the other guy who wore the suit,
who's a large fellow
and there's a picture of him walking
like he.
He showed how he did it and he walked
and then you see on the other side of
the screen,
the guy in the monkey suit doing the
exact same walkin hieronymus Bob,
Bob,
Bob Ross.
That's it.
Yeah.
Now I remember Bob Hieronymus who's a
big cowboy looking dude,
and they had him walk with a monkey suit
on and everybody was like,
that's real big foot footage.
This guy bought a monkey suit too,
by the way.
The guy who made the film,
he had bought a monkey suit.
Wow.
And he said he was going to use the
monkey suit to like,
you know,
film a reenactment.
So practice filming with it or something
like that.
Some cockamamie reason for having a
monkey suit.
The whole thing is so stupid.
It's if you look at all the pieces
involved,
you're like,
oh yeah,
you guys were fucking around and you
know,
you filmed some shit while you were on a
horse,
so it was all bouncy.
You see this thing walk her across the
street,
but now they can isolate that footage
because it used to be all bouncing shaky
with computers.
They can isolate it and get it all into
one flat plane and you watch it move.
It's a fucking guy and a monkey.
So 100 percent.
Right.
You've seen it.
How have you seen it?
Yeah.
Watch that shit.
You Go,
what am I looking at?
What are you doing here?
It's crazy,
but people want to believe so bad.
Yeah.
I've never
had a chance of believing in the,
uh,
in the whole big foot thing.
It was always just silly to me.
I remember,
was it John Lithgow and Harry and the
Hendersons back in the day or something
like that?
Yeah,
yeah.
I grew up on that and I was just stories
like,
ah,
it's like a fake character.
It's like,
I think it'd be see Harry and the
hendersons before finding out about big
foot.
It's like believing that Barney,
the dinosaur would exist out there.
Only reason to give it any credence at
all is the vast expanse of wilderness
that exists in the Pacific northwest
because it's so lush.
It's so crazy that no one's getting in
there and figuring out exactly what's in
there.
Like every I.
I really think everyone who lives in
this area,
especially because you.
You'd get up there pretty quick,
but anybody anywhere should go to the
Pacific northwest.
I go to the mountains right above
Seattle.
That's a crazy place,
man.
That was way crazier than looking for
bigfoot.
One of the craziest parts about that
trip was being in that real rain forest.
The real thing was fucking bananas.
It's thick like La,
like you can't see anything like every
two feet.
There's another tree.
I mean it's just thick with trees.
Which reminds me of my what my favorite
thing.
Basically mystery ever db cooper,
because that's where he jumped out of
that plane at really was in the hort
most horrible place you can imagine.
Did he do that in Pacific northwest?
Oh yeah.
Super.
They flew out to Seattle head and back
down again and he just hit that button
on the rear.
That's crazy.
They felt the plane shake and then boof,
he's gone.
He's going to land in the trees for
sure.
And it seems like that.
But his parachute,
none of his stuff ever recovered.
And then they combed that thing.
They did find like a stack of money,
I think like 10 or 20,000
of the bills sort of buried it.
A beach next to a creek,
but for the most part it's one of my
favorite fucking little.
I mean the fact that that guy may be
made off with,
I think it was only,
it was something low like 150 or
$200,000.
Yeah.
200,000
dollars.
But back then because this is in what
year?
A 71.
Seventy one.
Wow.
And he didn't just hijack the plane.
He made the plane land,
get rid of the passengers,
bring them parachutes,
bring the money and have it take off
again.
Like this is way back before p,
you know,
he just,
he was a true hijack and they land at
the airport.
They're like,
I'm going to save all the passengers
lives,
but here's the catch.
I need $200,000,
a few parachutes and something else.
Like something weird.
Right.
Wow.
And they never found him.
They never found the body.
They never found his suit.
They found this clip on tie somehow that
was found somewhere.
But it makes it even crazier when you
factor in that they found the clip on
tie and not the parachute and not the
suit and not,
you know what I mean?
Because then it's almost like he's just
got his 200,000
is just walking off.
I think they said that the money was
never spent though.
Is that true?
I'm looking up a and August of last year
they found a 18 inch nylon strap,
which they think might have been a piece
of his parachute.
Um,
I don't know how they would know that
right away,
but some looking up some other
information
might've been some shit campers left
behind too.
Yeah.
And I was just in a,
in Australia and I visited the grave of
uh,
the uh,
tie him should shimmered should the,
another crazy mystery one.
You ever hear that one?
The guy that was found at the beach in
Adelaide,
I actually went to the cemetery and
visited his grave during the day.
One of the days I had off.
They're out when I was doing shows in
Adelaide and this guy was founded a
beach.
This is one and another one of the great
mysteries ever found it a beach wearing
a suit.
A,
he had a half lit a cigarette that was
out in his collar.
They found him.
He'd been dead.
They don't know the guy.
There's no id on him,
no nothing.
So they keep them around for a few weeks
in the morgue,
waiting for some type of information on
the guy.
They just don't want to bury him.
And eventually they cut through is
closed and they find that there is a
little pocket with a piece of paper,
like on the inseam of his pants or
shirt,
I can't remember.
They trace that.
They can tell that it's cut out of a
book called the tie am should or
something like that.
I'm not saying it right because it's
some old Latin word or something and.
But there's a code on it and a phone
number or some or no,
there's a code on it,
but they know that no,
there's not a code on it.
It's just a piece of paper from a book
and they have the page and everything.
So they go to the newspaper,
they're like,
hey,
does anybody know have this copy of this
book so that we can find out who this
guy is on,
why this is so dead on them.
They don't get anything.
So they go nationwide do Australia and
try to figure out what this piece of
papers from.
They find the book in another part of
Australia with the missing part.
And in that book is a phone number and a
code that every codebreaker ever is
tried to figure out and they just don't
know.
So it's the tomb of the unknown man.
Whoa.
Yeah.
And it goes like deep.
There's so many theories about what
happened to this guy.
And it could have been the CIA,
he could have been an American spy,
could have been a Russian spy,
could have been an Australian spy,
like nobody knows anything about this
guy.
And they followed up and there's some,
there's a guy that like,
has some crazy theory,
but I don't know.
There's a guy that has a crazy theory.
I mean,
there's a ton of freedom in the world.
You know,
there's people that think that the Elon
musk thing was fake.
It was a hoax.
Oh my God.
I someone yesterday
with that malarkey tie to mystery death
in Australia to Thomas Jefferson.
Winds that from this is that guy
identified man found dead Australian
beach baffled investigators for decades
and new DNA analysis links somerton man
to Thomas Jefferson and native
Americans.
So he was an ancestor of Thomas
Jefferson and native Americans.
That's interesting.
I've never read that.
Yeah.
So they essentially just did a DNA test
on,
they call them the somerton man because
that's the beach that,
uh,
he was found out.
You guys,
you know about this Elizabeth Warren
stuff.
Do you know who that woman is?
She's a politician and she apparently at
one point in her life claim to be part
native American and now just like won't
talk about it,
won't do a DNA test,
won't.
She's like,
they were like,
do you have any pictures?
She's like,
yes,
I have many pictures and they're not for
you.
This is what she said to investigators,
man.
And then you got trump.
Just Hollander Polka Pocahontas.
It's so brutal.
She hits back at trump's use of
pocahontas vows to highlight native
American issues.
You know,
I wish I wasn't skeptical.
I wish.
I thought she was.
She was awesome.
And this isn't real.
But what's weird is that I think it,
it gave you some sort of an advantage
for her to be native American in terms
of like getting into certain schools or
what have you.
I don't know if that's true and she
might be part native American.
She might be like,
fuck you.
I don't have to tell you.
That's possible too.
I don't think that's the best move,
but maybe she doesn't know.
Maybe she like,
there's always something that's.
That is a thing with families like your
family telling you,
yeah,
you're uh,
your grandmother was 23 percent Navajo
and you're like,
wow,
I'm fucking cool.
It gives you an extra little bit of a
bad ass.
This is why Jane Goodall was willing to
accept the two native Americans told me,
well,
you could have talked to two other ones
who would have said,
what the fuck out of here with that?
I mean people are people,
man.
It doesn't matter if you're a white
person or a native American person or
whatever your ethnicity is.
There's gonna be a spectrum of people in
that group and some of them are going to
be big foot believers.
Man,
it doesn't matter if they're native
American.
It doesn't mean there's.
Sometimes people are bored and they want
to believe in bigfoot.
So they start thinking.
They hear things that they don't really
here,
they start thinking they're camping out.
This one guy thought they were camping
out outside his window,
that they lived in the forest,
like right outside his backdoor that
they come near where he is season.
They read your mind.
They they can sense when cameras are
around.
They won't show themselves.
Oh,
that's pretty smart.
What a great evolved habit that is,
but then like we were saying earlier,
some of them truly believe that big foot
is like some interstellar traveler that
may be from another dimension is a
creature from another dimension.
Yeah,
because creatures
from other dimensions are super hairy to
and look just like that and that makes
sense.
Real,
but you can only see them when you're on
mushrooms.
Do you imagine that?
That sort of makes sense.
Imagine if you did like there was a
perfect dose.
We.
You could see him,
he'd get into his world and you see
them.
It looks like bigfoot buddies all in
like a rainbow.
I mean I've been on mushrooms and seeing
the same thing that wasn't there is
somebody next to me.
I thought it was a Ufo,
but somebody,
one of the guys told me that it was a,
it was a,
like someone playing with like a laser
light thing,
like out in the distance.
Oh,
but I don't know.
It could have been if you're on
mushrooms,
it could be if you saw laser,
laser pointers are so weird,
like assholes point at planes.
Like that's how ridiculous those things
are.
It's um,
it's Kinda weird.
It's very weird.
When I was a kid that was like,
the funniest thing you could do was just
have a laser pointer and have a red dot
appear on the wall.
Like during class teacher has no first.
They didn't know about it.
Remember?
Yeah.
Teachers who didn't know about it.
Yeah,
it was red dots are showing up.
They didn't know what.
It was very rebellious.
Cats love those things.
So that's always fun.
That became like a thing in a movie.
Man.
Dude's got his hands up.
Red Dots moving all over his body means
they had the gun on him.
Right.
That was the exciting part of a movie.
Like,
oh my God,
look,
they got them.
Yeah.
It happened to me and my buddies once we
were speeding away,
we were under age.
A highschool drinking party.
Yeah,
I.
It was nasty in the party.
Got Busted by the cops.
Everybody ran out the back door like 70
kids at once.
Me,
my four buddies got slammed into my one
pals car and we're driving down the
street and you just hear,
stop.
Stopped off fucking car.
And I looked to my right.
My buddy in the middle of the backseat
has the red dot right on.
I'm up and down from his head to his
neck.
He was crazy.
Christ.
Yeah.
We all got in trouble cause you never
know.
They never know.
Could it be young Tony Hinchcliffe and
is ms dot [inaudible] friend or could it
be murderer bank robber trying to flee?
Yeah.
This cop,
that cop in particular was a real,
real bad person.
Like,
I mean,
he knew that they just busted up a kids
drinking party and that all the kids
were scattering at once and he decided
to stand in the middle of the street and
he said that like,
you know,
first of all,
he could have easily have shot us
because you're standing in the middle of
the street instead of having common
sense,
like there's so many other things
happening,
but he,
you know,
he could say that that's assault with a
deadly weapon if you're driving towards
somebody.
So he runs out in the street,
pulls out his gun,
almost can't wait.
It seemed from my buddy to not stop.
I mean
it's just,
it was one of those,
one of those shady cops.
In fact,
I'm pretty sure that's the same cop from
where I'm from that saw a Ufo and it was
on a kid.
There was a big thing in liberty
township just outside of youngstown
where this one cop saw a Ufo.
Nobody could take them seriously.
Oh my God.
That is hilarious.
But here's the thing,
by me saying all this,
I'm not saying that people haven't seen
Ufos because I don't know what they've
seen.
It's totally possible that something
that's capable of coming here from
another dimension,
especially before recently,
right,
would be able to figure out how to avoid
detection somehow or another.
They're probably pretty close to
figuring out how to do that now.
I mean,
they have the stealth bomber which
avoids radar detection and they.
I know they have those cloaks.
You've seen those jackets of people
where,
where it literally shows a video of
what's behind you,
Huh?
Yeah.
It's like this new technology that
they're trying to develop where
literally you,
your clothes would show exactly what's
behind you.
So you've got a camera,
some sort of camera system mounted
somewhere on you and it's taking a
picture of what's behind you.
It's streaming what's behind you.
And so then that appears on your
clothes.
So as you move,
you literally are everything that's
behind you.
There's this weird like Predator effect
from the movie.
It's very crude right now,
but you look at it and you go,
oh,
this is the future.
They're just going to become,
everything's going to be.
It's the future.
Scary.
You watched veneer?
Yes.
Oh my God.
They make it look like everything in the
future's going to make us crazy.
So,
so good,
man.
Wow.
So good.
Yeah.
In terms of like a show that makes you
just like after the show's over,
you just go,
what the fuck?
That crocodile expert episode rather
crocodile.
I had like 15 friends text me after that
going,
what in the fuck was that?
What the fuck?
It's so crazy and it's so good and you
can see it happening.
You're like,
no,
no fucking way.
No fucking way.
Oh my God.
I don't remember a show ever.
Does that powerful?
Like when it comes to science fiction
type show?
Yeah.
I don't remember.
I mean there were some amazing shows on
before,
but they're all really fiction shows,
right?
Like this is fiction with like a dash of
futuristic possibility,
like dystopian future.
That fucking dog one with the robot dog.
Oh Jesus Christ.
What was that called?
Metal head.
Is that what it was?
Fucking a man.
Oh,
I could see this.
This could be real,
like what?
What are we doing?
The future seems scary.
You see that robot open up the door,
open up the door and hold it for his now
dude.
Robot opened up a door.
Click open the latch.
Well,
yeah,
that guy.
Dude,
look at this thing.
Watch this shit.
Let's just first of all,
look at it and just imagine it with guns
everywhere.
Of course you could imagine that,
right?
Laser pointers and guns everywhere.
So this thing walks up,
grabs the fucking handle,
turns the door,
check this out,
puts its leg there to stop the door,
walks the door back so it has some kind
of intelligence in less.
That's a programmed move in.
Has there ever been anything that
doesn't get it like a virus or things go
wrong at some point?
Of course this is all gonna happen.
Go wrong,
it's going to go wrong,
but I wonder if that's a program to
move.
Like it told them the exact steps to
take and it measured out all the inches
and then knew the exact movements to
make or if it can accurately,
accurately calculate distance.
So they've given it in a sense,
some sort of electronic eyes,
right?
If it can walk up to a door,
grab the handle,
turn it and pull it,
and then hold the door open.
When it's leg lead,
it's friends go by like what is that?
We're fucked.
That's.
But that's.
That kind of articulation is very crazy
to think that you could teach something
to do that.
So if you only teach and to do doors or
can I do that with everything?
That's when it gets weird when it gets
weird is if,
if it can create.
If you could figure out,
well if it works on this,
what kind of door do we have here?
Oh I see.
This thing is just a slide.
Is it going to be able to figure that
out?
That's,
that's kind of,
it's.
It seems.
It seems like it would be able to figure
it out pretty easily.
Especially when you factor in that
everything in the future is going to be
more like technological anyway.
Like the doors even turning a knob or
sliding a door is going to be ridiculous
because people are just going to be like
jet eyes or whatever.
You know?
A lot of people have fingerprint things
now for stuff like fingerprint things
for like opening doors,
seeing fingerprint things for a locks at
the gym.
Just a fingerprint thing now.
That's like a new thing.
Yeah.
That's why you wouldn't want to cut off
your thumb out of,
out of all the fingers.
Cut Off.
Well,
it's just,
it's,
it's just really interesting to me how
quick all this technology's moving and
how that doesn't.
It doesn't seem like there's any end in
sight and most of us,
like you and I,
like normal people are sitting back
watching this on internet videos going,
whew.
Um,
what do we,
what do we do?
Like when,
when do we stop?
Why don't we stop making robots that
could kill us.
Like before they're smart or after
they're smart,
they're going to just stay alive
and obviously as soon as we can latch
guns onto them
going in.
Yeah.
That's what a drone is.
Think about one of the drone where the
drone is.
What a drone is it someone is piloting
something.
Just because it's flying around,
it doesn't mean it's not a robot.
All right.
That's a fucking robot.
It's a robot airship and they're flying
it around and they're getting these kids
that are wizards and video games I'll
give you want to have some fucking
impossible to beat armies.
You.
You Hook them up with some of those I
robot things from that will smith movie.
You make them all bulletproof and you
have a bunch of kids that just play
wicked video games all day.
Know how to fuck people up with madden
and that UFC game.
You fucking send those kids,
piloting these things in real time.
You send them to parts of the world and
why that would be.
First of all,
it'd be 10 times more terrifying than
drones.
Right?
Some things were running through your
street.
I just thought of something.
I was going to say.
The problem I've always had with this
idea is like our battery life that we
use on stuff is terrible.
Yeah,
it's going to eat people,
but what batteries are they using in
those drones that are flying up above
now that are over overseas doing damage
on and whatnot?
Are those like special batteries that we
don't have access to that maybe in five
years we will ask this question won't be
so weird to us
is are you sure that that's the way
those things fly was almost just going
to ask that.
I don't know how they fly.
I don't think they're gas powered
though,
but.
Well,
let's find out.
That'd be a good thing to know.
Might not be able to find that out.
I don't think they won't.
Department of Defense stuff.
You're scared to Google it.
That you want to be good.
You do not want to google.
How far?
How far can you fly a drone and wonder?
I'd rather run on gasoline while it's
carrying two missiles.
Just wondering.
That sounds like the most American thing
ever.
The drones filled with gas and oil.
Just wondering with missiles.
That's what's happening.
Drones.
Well,
we have to worry about people more than
we even have to worry about drones.
Right.
This new shooting in Florida freaked me
the fuck out again.
Yeah,
it's happening all the time now.
It's horrific.
And the crazy thing is like kids used to
joke around about this guy doing that
someday.
That was something they joked around
about.
I think that,
uh,
I think that the way that the news
reports it and the way that it's such
big news isn't helping at all because
one thing that I've noticed is the whole
car ramming thing,
like that's a new thing,
car ramming where the,
a lot of the things that are happening
or people just getting in a truck or a
car and just running people down.
It's a fairly new thing that started
with like,
I don't know,
maybe that French one or something like
that.
I can't remember the first one,
but since then because report,
you know,
they're just,
they report it and they blow these
things up and then bing bang,
boom.
Like I feel like going off of the car
ramming situation and the growth in car
rammings alone that we could sort of see
how overly reporting these.
I mean,
I don't know if that's even a thing or
if I'm.
What I'm saying is making sense at all,
but
I know what you're trying to say,
but the counter to that I would be
someone had.
What was the,
the.
Someone made a really good analogy.
The point being what this is,
is only happening here.
We have to figure out why it's happening
here.
So often it rarely happens anywhere
else,
but here it happens pretty often.
So what is that?
Is it access to guns?
Is it mental health?
Is it both of those things?
Is it,
it's just far too easy to get guns.
Is it that you're not being monitored in
the sense of being talked about and
people don't want to anybody infringing
upon their rights?
Right.
But if we just sat down and had a
rational conversation with someone to
renew a gun license,
you know,
rational conversation with someone who
doesn't work for a gun group or anything
to someone who could just give you a
reasonable reason why you should be
suspicious about this person having a
firearm or you really don't want to do
that either though,
because you can't trust people.
It's like you're putting people in a
position of power to decide who gets the
guns and who doesn't get the guns.
It's all very,
very fucking terrifying and confusing.
That seems like the Ar 15 is the one
that they need to keep an eye on because
all the biggest ones are that.
And it seems to be able to mount our
mode down a lot of people at once.
Yeah.
Semiautomatic rifles are more effective
in those type of mass shooting
situations.
That's why those guys use them.
That's why they use them.
And you know,
all sorts of horrific ways.
All we're all around the world,
right?
That's what they're good at.
That.
So then the question is,
are they to lethal for a regular person?
Just be carrying around where you'd want
to know why a regular person wants to
carry him around and then you would
realize,
is that really my right?
Even ask a regular person why they need
it.
I mean if most of these people are law
abiding gun owners,
when we freak out that one person who
legally bought a gun in this case is a
kid who legally bought it,
does it,
does this horrific thing.
It's a very good question and it's a
question we often ask ourselves like how
many times does this happen before
something happens and is the.
Is the answer arming the schools.
That's a fucking terrifying answer.
The putting armed guards at schools,
I saw a story where had held up to
signs,
which it was like a instagram thing and
so it was.
The two signs were which one of these
signs would make you feel good if you
were like a killer and it shows no
weapons,
no weapons sign,
and then it also shows a sign with an
armed guard saying that the staff is
armed and trained and you know,
you're looking at the two of those.
You're like,
God damn it.
I don't want either one of these fucking
things.
I definitely don't want weapons in the
schools,
but I don't want them to need weapons in
schools.
That's why I don't want it there.
Yeah,
but when they.
When scenes like this happen,
you have to go,
well,
how is there a way?
I don't know.
I don't know what the way is other than
even if you take people's guns away,
God damn you're.
You're not going to get all of them.
There's too many of them.
The number of guns that people have
today,
I,
I think it outnumbers humans.
I think the number of guns like total in
this country outnumber humans insanity.
Even if you are for guns,
when the number of things that can kill
us outnumber us.
Are we overreacting?
Are we crazy?
Are we stockpiling for some fucking
terrible collapsed that we're all afraid
of?
Is that just our thing?
Because we're like,
uh,
we were like the last country or
whatever you think.
Is it like defensive question?
Difficult question,
like crazy,
scared country.
Well,
there's,
you know,
there's different uses for firearms and
who are you to say that like
recreational shooters who are
respectable law abiding people and
there's a lot of them out there that are
very good people.
They just love to shoot pistols at
targets.
They do competitions,
they enjoy it.
They like being proficient with a
firearm for their own personal safety
and there have been cases,
I think there was a case in shit,
I want to say it was in Ohio where some
guy was stabbing somebody at a mall and
some dude who was a trained shooter at
one of those shooting competition things
shot the guy and killed him when he was
running around stabbing people at the
mall and it was one of those things
where no one wanted to play that up in
the media because they thought it was
like irresponsible.
It's irresponsible to play up the idea
of the rogue vigilante with the pistol.
Yeah,
but,
but that was a real guy,
like the guys actually like kind of a
hero.
Like if he was in a Bruce Willis movie,
he'd be fucking pumped.
Like that guy's kind of a hero.
Like he,
he was a normal citizen that happened to
have a concealed carry permit.
Right.
Found another similar story,
I guess from what you're describing in
Minnesota was an off duty cop that
stopped somebody that was established.
Cool.
Yeah.
It was an off duty cop.
That was the stab ones.
So I got that wrong.
It was he who was the firearm instructor
one.
I don't know.
This might have been another similar
story to it might have been,
but there was definitely one.
I'm sorry if I fucked that up.
Um,
there was definitely one where the guy
was a,
a,
one of those big NRA shooting
competition type characters.
This is a terrible,
terrible tragedy.
Tragedy.
And these terrible tragedies seemed to
keep happening and we don't do anything
to change.
Everybody's worried about,
you know,
their second amendment rights being
taken away.
You know,
people are worried about law abiding
people who would never do anything like
this.
Worried about their guns getting taken
away.
But they,
in all,
all of us we have,
we have to figure this out.
This,
this can't just keep going on this way
and whatever it is,
whatever's causing it,
whether it's the way people are raising
people,
the way people are treating people,
whatever.
Fucking crazy mental imbalances that
were not treating in each other,
whatever the fuck it is,
whether it's biological,
fact that we just can't keep as a,
as a civilization,
as a,
a thing that should in its best times to
be able to get along great with each
other.
These little aberrations,
they're horrific aberrations,
but they exist frequently.
There's so many of us.
Yeah,
320 something million people.
This was from 2015 more guns and people.
Yeah.
Well,
okay.
Oh boy.
Wow.
So the,
there's 317 million people in 2013 and
$357 million guns.
That's crazy.
But then the people who are gun nuts and
be like,
what are you fucking cure?
How many guns?
I have been home a button soon,
soon.
I would never do anything like that.
That guy,
dude,
that guy's a piece of shit folk.
Him and their right to their right to if
you're,
if you haven't done anything and you
would never do anything,
why would you get lumped in with someone
who has.
If you have a truck and you would never
dream into plowing into a mall full of
people,
why would you get lumped lumped into the
same group as a guy who has a truck who
did do that?
Why should you?
It's not fair,
but we stuffed to figure this out.
It just,
there's something wrong.
There's something wrong with.
Is that many more things that can kill
us.
Then us.
If a guy pointed a gun at you from
across the room,
do you have something in your head plan
that you would do?
There's nothing you can do.
I would do a bunch of cartwheels and
somersaults.
That's always been my plan.
I feel like if I just do weird
movements,
you could avoid almost nothing you can
do.
You know?
It's too terrifying,
terrifying thing.
The ability to just end someone's life
with a single movement of your hand
and we learned so early on.
I remember duck hunt as a kid.
The nintendo like tick,
tick,
tick.
Remember that gun,
you know,
it's like we learned so early on,
well,
it's just that people value people so
poorly that they would do that.
This is where we have to find like the
root of what that is and that sounds.
This sounds very philosophical and hippy
dippy,
but we,
we have to examine what could possibly
be inside someone that would make them
want to do something like that.
What would that be?
I don't mean how the fuck does that
happen?
How does a,
how were there in the same timeline?
We're not talking about like primitive
Roman days or the vikings or anything
crazy we're talking about right now.
How in the same timeline does a guy like
you exist alongside someone who could do
that?
There's something wrong.
There's A.
I also think that there's something to
be said about like awareness of
depression and psychological disorders
for the older generation.
I feel like in the future more people
are gonna know about it and take it as a
real thing,
but I still think now there's probably.
There's definitely a lot of stubborn
parents out there that ignoring,
you're not depressed,
get up,
you know,
and all of this because it's definitely
deep rooted,
a lack of structure in their lives,
you know,
stuff's gone wrong and they don't have
anybody to talk to her.
Anything,
you know,
that's definitely a common thing.
One hundred percent.
The dissatisfaction with their current
state in life,
their physical health people have all
sorts of undiagnosed mental issues and
maybe they don't have insurance and they
can't afford treatment or maybe they
just got off of it and they think
they're fine.
I mean we know guys who did that who got
off of stuff that they weren't supposed
to get off of.
And then they start getting really
paranoid and crazy and then someone has
to talk them down.
And one of the things with being
depressed like that is,
you know,
and like you said,
if they don't have insurance then all of
a sudden they're like,
I don't have insurance.
A little did they know that it's a phone
call away to get like,
you know,
free whatever somehow or help somehow.
But also with the depression makes you
not want to do that.
It makes you,
it's part of it is you don't want to
sort of find help.
It's hard to reach out.
Yeah.
You know what I find it's interesting.
That is a,
I think avoidable and then maybe we
should all like think about this a
little bit.
There's something that happens whenever
something takes place,
um,
where people like expect a reaction,
they expect a reaction from.
And there's this tendency to get upset
at people that are not showing a
reaction to it.
Like publicly instantaneous.
Like there's a responsibility to show a
reaction.
And I've been thinking about this and I
was like,
is there,
I don't know because I had put something
up I think on twitter,
instagram and someone about our show in
Bakersfield tonight.
And someone said,
hey,
maybe not a great time to promote.
There was a school shooting just saying
or something like that.
I didn't know about it.
I don't think,
um,
maybe had heard peripherally that
something happened.
Like when I was flipping through Google,
but I didn't know the extent of it.
And then I saw it,
I was like,
oh my God.
Like,
I mean that is,
um,
it's one of the worst things people can
do to people to like snuff out young
life for no reason.
Yeah,
it's,
it's crazy.
It's becoming so common.
It's becoming common.
And um,
it's like there has to be a way to stop
it.
It's almost like,
you know,
a way it's,
I feel like people have become so
desensitized that like,
it's almost like the new super suicide,
you know,
desensitized.
Because if this had happened 20 years
ago,
it'd be a gigantic thing that would
freak people out for days and days.
And it would be all anybody's talking
about.
So in one sense of I did hear about a
school,
I think maybe I'd seen something about
the school getting shut down or
something.
So I'm like,
oh fuck,
something that happened.
And then going into it later,
the more I looked into it,
the models like,
Oh God,
like this is just the most heartbreaking
news.
You could ever hear it,
right?
Someone decides to go kill kids story.
You're talking about with the Texas man
who opened fire in Texas church shooter.
Was Harold is a good Samaritan.
Oh,
there was that guy.
There was another guy though.
It must have been the undercover cop
because it was the stabbing story.
I'm on a conflated them.
I do that on occasion.
Well,
we gotta get the story into instances.
Someone who wasn't supposed to be there
with a gun,
had a gun.
One of them just have to be an
undercover cop.
You don't want people to be vigilantes.
You don't want people to be out there
fucking Charles Bronson and that.
But
that was performing in a comedy club in
Dallas a couple of weeks ago and I was
standing out front near the,
uh,
like the hosts booth for a second and
they get a phone call and the guy goes,
you know what sir?
I actually don't know.
Let me,
let me ask my boss.
I've never been asked that before.
And he puts the phone on hold and goes
to find the owner.
But like before he does,
I go,
what's that person asking for?
Like,
I was just curious.
what?
He's never been asked.
He goes,
he wants to know if he can bring his
gun.
He has a concealed carry license.
I don't know the exact laws here.
I'm like,
no,
don't ask the owner.
He's not allowed to bring his gun and
get back to that phone call.
No,
not my two shows that night.
Like no concealed carry.
Yeah.
I got a buddy of mine who carries ever
horror.
Wow.
Every four man.
Yeah.
Hope I never accidentally make fire
though.
It's firearms instructor.
He's.
He carries everywhere.
He lives in Arizona.
You could do whatever the fuck you want.
And Arizona,
Arizona.
Thanks.
This 1800.
You think if I did my cart somersaults
thing,
you'd still be able to get me though.
Uh,
maybe not.
Maybe not.
You are a clever fellow.
I always picture that and I don't know
what else I always picture is in
elevators.
If the elevator falls and you're in free
fall,
would you jump?
Would you try to jump at the end to sort
of zone out
works?
Yeah.
Because you're going the speed of the
elevator anyway.
Get crushed the same exact amount.
You're fucked.
Darn it.
Yeah,
it doesn't work.
I was going to try to jump.
There's nothing you could do with that
one dude.
That's sad.
Fucked up.
Way To die.
Elevator accident.
You know,
that's one of the things when you're in
a place like Manhattan and you're on the
89th floor of a building and you're
like,
what is this nonsense?
What is this nonsense?
I figured like it's even worse when they
like,
it gets stuck but it's halfway in
between floors and someone tries to
climb out and then you've heard of them
like getting to capitated or whatever
and that their heads there
half.
Yeah.
To those people up there in that 90th
floor.
Those people are just view monkeys.
Yeah.
I want to look over this whole fucking
city.
Want be on the first floor?
I want to be on the first floor.
Okay,
so I can just get the fuck out of there.
Get Out of the office,
go home.
Don't.
Why would I want to be on the 100,
four in less?
I'm just look down below fucker.
I'm up here at the top of the tree
because I'm done.
Number one champ.
You helicopter on flying right above
these guys.
I'm like Dick out the window,
right.
That's the ultimate is to be a doodle.
Lives in the penthouse and gets
helicoptered around Manhattan and
dropped down some fucking dude covered
in like extinct Fox for you know,
strutting this shit.
That's the ultimate.
To have a penthouse on the top of a
giant building in New York City and have
a helicopter landing your roof.
You'd be special agent baller.
I didn't even get in the helicopter.
I would have the helicopter.
I would attach a rope to the helicopter
and have the helicopter go and I just
fly like that underneath the helicopter
so that when they slowly land,
I land the hard guys like that out
there.
This is what you like.
Not obviously not wearing extinct first,
but there's guys that are that that just
get helicopter
around Manhattan and they go to the
Hamptons to get helicoptered out to the
hamptons.
They land in their estate,
they get out their estate.
They have people waiting there and full
outfit that work for them during some
colonial time.
I mean,
they're,
they're living in like,
this is a total alternate universe of
human beings.
Fuck yeah.
Have you seen those crazy hamptons
houses like way out and what's this?
NBC and pays for Matt Lauer's helicopter
rides to work.
Oh,
there you go.
From the Hamptons.
Bam.
Per his chopper out to the hamptons
where as a 40 acre horse farm.
So hard ball and so hard.
And Matt Lauer.
Wow.
Oh,
took a helicopter ride to his nice
office with a button.
That's that thing man.
And it's not just guys like him.
It's,
you know,
rich a hedge fund guys and Wall Street
guys.
I mean there's,
there's people that just have ungodly
sums of money.
Like you can't wrap your head around it.
You Never gonna understand it.
They have hundred million dollar
estates,
hundred million.
You're looking at $100,000,000
estate.
You're like,
what?
What the fuck is this?
That's insane.
Yeah.
That's a weird thing about capitalism
that someone can get that far out of,
out of whack.
They could ball that heart above all.
Like what?
What kind of,
what did you do?
And those are some of my favorite,
uh,
some of my favorite crazy stories is
like the jinx,
the Robert Durst one where he came from,
you know,
the family that owns just Manhattan
skyscrapers and.
Oh,
he's crazy.
The dupont guy with the wrestling team.
Yeah.
That's another wild one.
That's one of the wildest ones.
Yeah.
That was a terrifying one.
Steve Carell can act as fucking ass off
Kenny.
Hell yeah.
Yeah,
he's great.
It's another thing where someone used a
gun to kill someone that they were
threatened by and some sort of a
masculine way because Dave Schultz was
like this super bad ass wrestler.
Yeah.
Just top of him and his brother Mark,
top of the food chain wrestlers.
It was terrible story.
I almost went to the,
I think I'm pretty sure I almost went to
the match Schultes Mark Schultz,
Mark Schultz wrestling camp back when I
was in high school.
I went to the Ohio state one instead.
He fought,
gathered big daddy,
big daddy Goodrich,
uh,
in the UFC way back in the day.
It was his one and only a mma fight in
the UFC.
And it's really interesting because in
the movie that they did with Steve
Carell,
like that's a historical moments,
he,
they don't understand mma.
So when they made that movie,
the cage fighting par was like,
yeah,
whatever,
we'll just fucking fudge this.
Like,
how do I,
why would I believe that anything in
that movie is what really happened when
the thing that I know for sure really
happened.
You fucked up.
Yeah.
The thing that I know for sure really
happen is this guy,
big daddy goodrich.
Wow.
Fought Schultz when Schultz was a top of
the food chain wrestler man.
And he just took him down at.
Will he,
he handled him at will,
he took show?
No.
Oh No,
no,
no.
There'll be none of that.
Mark Schultz was a go rilla.
Yeah.
I mean,
just like I said,
top of the food chain,
American wrestler.
He's a fucking tank.
Yeah.
And so this is him fighting Gary
Goodrich.
Let like very little striking fairy
little striking trade.
He's just looking for this.
He says.
And once he gets this,
Oh fuck all loud,
boom.
Takes him to the ground like he's a sack
of potatoes,
beats the shit out of a mountain,
does whatever he wants to.
When he has him on the ground,
whatever he wants to him.
It's a level of grappling that the UFC
up until then had never seen.
You know.
It's like if a guy like Daniel cormier
entry into the octagon back there,
same kind of thing,
just takes everybody's going down,
shut the fuck up.
There's not going to be any stuff in
these take downs.
There's a guy named Jordan burroughs out
there that I would.
What's added to stop that right there
because it was different times,
man.
It was a fact then.
Yeah,
they would.
They didn't know what the fuck they're
doing half the time.
Like look,
Mark Scott,
no gloves on and Gary's got no gloves
on,
but back in the day you could wear
gloves if you wanted to.
And I think he has shoes on.
Yup.
He's got wrestling shoes and look at
this.
Boom.
I mean every time he wants to he could
take him down there in these mountain.
This is just a level of grappling that
you just don't understand.
You're not getting them off.
You stop.
Stop.
This is nonsense.
You don't even understand.
This is like a big daddy goodrich I
should just say is a incredibly strong
guy and an awesome athlete.
What's happening here?
Tap.
It's like what happened?
Big John.
Oh,
did he key lock them?
Is that what he's.
That's interesting.
Why did I have in my head I had that he
beat him up and want a decision.
What happened?
How did,
how did that resolve?
Did submit him?
No,
I can't believe I remember this wrong.
Well,
either way.
I just remember just watching.
Yeah.
It looks like you've got.
I'm going to key lock too much blood.
Oh No.
Okay.
It wasn't that they just stopped it.
Okay,
so it was a stoppage.
Either way.
There's a guy named Jordan burroughs who
when he wrestles,
he has these the greatest double leg
take down ever.
Just shoot slow drives in his opponents
and now he's going to it.
He's won multiple gold side.
I mean he's just a monster and I would
love,
love to see him.
Learn how to strike a little bit or
learn some Jujitsu and figure out.
You have to see because in like almost
the history of wrestling,
this guy is a freak.
Shoots slow.
There's nothing you can do.
Here he is,
there's just nothing.
He just dominates people.
Serious drive,
man.
Boom,
boom.
Over and over again.
Just destroys people over that drive.
Man.
God Damn.
He's good.
He wrestled on like time square.
Did you see that?
That's cool.
Yeah.
I wrestled in Times Square last year.
Maybe like in the winter.
Oh really?
Oh Wow.
Look at that.
Where is that guy going?
Nowhere.
Well,
you know,
this is what we're seeing with Habib
number.
Go off when you see like the super high
level striking or excuse me,
excuse me,
super high level.
Grappling it,
it shuts down.
Even like really good grapplers.
Is this him and time square?
Yeah.
Wow.
This is awesome.
Who is he wrestling again?
Some guy that thought he was about to
get points right there.
That's amazing.
Who is he wrestling against?
Does it say,
oh,
it's got some rap music on it that'll
get us kicked off youtube,
but this is all these are like world
championships and stuff.
Crazy man.
Serious power and technique.
I just.
I think that's the most important skill
in mma.
I've always thought it and I still do
because I think these guys can learn
defense for grappling defense,
for Jujitsu and they can learn
submissions,
which is probably even more important
way quicker than a regular person.
They're so used to squeezing shit
already.
They're used to like constantly used to
squeezing things in gripping and polling
and unlike Jujitsu with the GE,
which relies a lot of it on grips and
like there's an entanglement factor that
you have to really take into account and
they can really slow the game down that
way.
You can't do that with wrestling.
Now.
The thing with wrestling's hip movement
and hip control and spinning around a
guy room from hitting a easy reversal
just from popping down and back up.
Yeah.
If you don't wrestle,
you're not taking a wrestler down.
Yeah.
And it's crazy sometimes watching,
you know,
high level fights and you know,
sometimes I don't have,
obviously when we're a year at a live
fight,
I don't have the audio.
So it's like sometimes I'm seeing what's
just a little thing that's wrong,
you know,
like for example like in de Asma Gregor
too,
I remember a part where Diaz was trying
to take my.
Greg are down,
but his hips were above Mcgregor's who
had dropped his just lower.
Whereas if Diaz pops down and back up,
he's got them.
But you know,
all this stuff's happening at once and
sometimes you can see it with wrestling
and it's just the difference in a little
thing that sometimes the energy and the
emotions of the fight,
it's about,
you know,
just being like,
oh yeah,
drop down up and like,
you know.
Yeah,
yeah.
It's uh,
it's very,
very technique oriented and that's like
the people that have never done any kind
of grappling don't understand when
you're watching someone drive in,
when you see a beautiful.
Like if you go back to like,
who's got one of the best power doubles?
Probably may Frankie Edgar's got one of
my favorite power doubles ever.
He takes a lot of motherfuckers down
that'll really tough to take down,
but if you watch as he enters into it,
there's such a flow to it.
You know?
It's an aggressive attacking like George
St Pierre when George was in his prime.
Oh,
do everybody's scared of that takedown
man.
That power double was coming.
Josh Koscheck when early on in the sport
will Josh Koscheck had ridiculous power
and his in his takedowns just
ridiculous.
He would just drive through you.
It's so technical.
There's one.
That's the whole thing in wrestling is
strength and quickness and all this
stuff is so secondary to some dude
that'll own you doing your own thing.
He'll wrestle Jujitsu.
You,
he'll just let you think that you're
about to do something while these moves
ahead.
I think everybody should know that Yoel
Romero is a real human being like that.
That's possible.
Like everyone should know.
Like when it comes to like what's what's
important about wrestling.
Yoel Romero is a real thing.
Like that's what happens.
That's just what you have when you have
the elite is a leader.
Wrestlers you can get in a super athlete
body.
Yeah,
good luck.
He decides whether you're going down.
You mean if you take them down?
It's luck.
I mean,
he might've been half ass that takedown
defense because he knows as soon as it
gets down and just fucking flip you over
and stand back up again.
It's not the same kind of thing.
He's just way more athletic than you.
Stronger than you.
They need to get into gonoodle.
Workout with him,
dude.
Well,
when the gun is way too heavy,
unfortunately you're dealing with 85
versus heavyweight,
but at 85.
No,
I mean like trained to train with them.
It's a big guy to train with.
He's so good.
Dude.
Is this this highlight reel?
Do Peace.
He's so good.
He's knocked out with stunning accuracy.
Luke rockhold.
I'm Chris Weidman.
Look at that.
Boom.
Dude.
Tim Kennedy.
I mean,
he's a fucking monster.
Although the Kennedy fight was marred by
controversy.
You can never ignore that.
He did not come out for the.
Oh,
look at that left hand.
He did not come out for the for the end
of the round and he was still sitting on
a stool and a day wasted.
All this time trying to give him more
chances to recover.
You have to be afraid of any guy who's
shoulders stick up like that.
Dude.
He's.
He's terrified.
It's like a King Cobra.
How it like warns you with its wings.
He stopped up.
This dude with body stroll.
I mean that is crazy.
Who the fuck?
Stop someone with driving elbows to the
body.
Who the fuck stop somebody with that?
Oh.
Oh my God.
Yeah,
Dude.
I mean that was meat.
He made meat out of that.
Go back to that.
Let me look at that again.
That's crazy.
Yeah,
we'll just look at right there.
Right there with her and they'll show
it.
He's got blood all over his elbow.
The just.
That is a crazy.
His whole face is a mess,
but that's a crazy amount of force this
guy can generate and wrestling is just
another level man.
Like that kind of shit.
Yeah.
He could do that to anybody,
like he fought Brad Tavares right there
and Brad [inaudible] stud and it was
like they were nowhere near the same
weight class,
like the way you can handle them.
He's just so fucking powerful and this
is just shows you what a fucking Stud
Tim Kennedy is.
Tim Kennedy almost had them.
The reason why he didn't come out for,
I believe it was the third round when it
came out late was because by the end of
the second,
Tim had them in deep,
deep trouble.
Tim had caught him with a couple of big
punches and staggered them and so when,
when he went back to his corner,
look at that fucking shot that he lands
when he knocks him down.
Then another one,
he just smashed them at the end.
The craziest thing about Tim Kennedy is
he does all this and for a big chunk of
his career he was a active military.
It's still fighting like that.
Yeah,
you all Ramiro is.
and here's him just smashing the ODA.
Machida he's terrifying.
So he's going to get the next shot at
the middleweight title after you just
knocked out luke rockhold.
I can't believe political knocked him.
That's the crazy thing is knocked him
out like this is the crazy thing.
You're talking about a guy who's like
one of the best wrestlers to ever fight
in mma and he's knocking people out,
standing,
leaping in and crack and you would punch
is hitting you at flying knees,
knocking out world champions.
Mikaela,
Chris Weidman with a flying knee.
He's uh,
he's just,
he's on another level,
like a real fucking monster athlete.
Like it's a pleasure to get to watch
someone who has such fantastic technique
and physical attributes all combined.
Like his wrestling technique is just
ridiculously good.
His timing's ridiculously good.
It's explosions,
so like to watch that,
I mean for me,
a guy who's been around the sport for a
long time.
When a guy comes out and it just stands
out that hard,
you go,
Whoa,
this guy is a real outlier.
Physically,
he's going to make such a good progress.
Learn a few years.
Oh,
if he does decide to do that,
fuck yeah,
he would make an amazing one.
Yes.
As he gets older.
Yeah,
look at it.
Are they stretching them out here?
Yeah,
he's super fucking flexible,
dude.
You mean he's a product of the Cuban
wrestling system and if you listen to my
podcast with Matt Brown,
I'm going to plug that one more time
because I enjoy the shit out of it.
It was one of the MMA shows I did last
week with Matt Brown and he and I were
talking about it and he's um,
like,
uh,
he spent an entire six weeks,
I believe in Cuba at one of his,
uh,
his training camps and the way these
people live and trained like they are,
they are all in man.
They're all in and there's just a
tremendous amount of talent over there,
both in boxing and in judo as well as
wrestling,
taekwondo.
They have a big taekwondo team,
like Cuba doesn't fuck around
athletically,
man,
but it's just to see a guy like that and
you go,
wow,
that's a net 40.
Like what would that guy have been like
when he was 30?
Good Lord.
He's 40.
Yeah.
What would he have been better if we'd
been faster now on top of all that,
Robert Whitaker's still beat them with a
blown out knee.
Yup.
That's amazing.
Whitaker,
Monster.
That shows you how amazing he is.
Yeah.
He's still managed to take takedowns of
the compete.
Completely blown out knee.
Crazy.
Yeah.
Whittaker is no fucking joke.
He's a scary guy and he's getting
better.
I think Whitaker's is only like 27.
Right?
How old is Robert Whitaker?
That sounds about right.
He's one of the younger guys that's a
world champion currently I believe.
Twenty seven.
Yeah.
So he's still growing and learning,
man.
That guy at at 30.
I mean he's a world champion right now
at 30.
He's going to be better than he is right
now.
It's just going to keep getting better.
Another thing is your well didn't show
any of the signs of pain from the Shin
injury that he had.
That's a big part of it too,
you know,
is not letting your opponent know what's
hurting you because I'm sure if rockhold
knew that he hurt his shin more than he
heard his,
then he would have kept picking away at
it.
But he didn't let him know.
So it just seemed like he wasn't
affecting them with his leg kicks.
Meanwhile,
urls like,
oh,
what does he like?
Oh yeah,
painful.
Well,
he's a super winter.
He's what you would call a super winter,
you know,
I mean,
that's really what it is.
If you get these Olympic level athletes
that had just been competing their whole
lives,
they just not a win.
And when he learned at a strike,
everybody just,
you're,
you're fucked.
You got this guy.
There's only been a few guys that can
survive it,
that had been able to survive it,
you know,
but the most impressive one,
um,
I mean,
shit,
there's just,
this is a,
a real wealth of talent right now
going to say it's a very exciting time
to be a UFC fan.
It really is labeled bubble
because like Robert Whitaker was the
first guy to.
Is he the first guy to beat in the UFC?
I want to say he is and I want to say
that Yo,
well,
last,
like one of his really early mma fights
to fazio in strikeforce.
Is that true?
How fail content?
Yeah,
it's strikeforce Barnett versus a
Keratin off surrogate car off.
So that was like way back in 2011.
So yeah,
look,
it was one of his first fights.
He lost that fight and he lost a
whitticker so he hadn't lost since that.
Uh,
the faceoff fight,
almost all knockouts and the only one
that has an asterisk right next to it is
the Tim Kennedy fight because it was
def.
Definitely some fuckery there.
Definitely some,
some cheat and definitely stayed on that
stool.
An extra few seconds.
How long did they wind up staying on the
stool for extra?
I want to guess it was an extra 15
seconds.
I think that might be a.
What did he do?
He just chill for a bit.
Might've been less than 15.
Uh,
he just didn't get up.
He sat there.
The end.
Yeah.
Dan was around.
He was in there.
The corner was leaving.
He's still sitting on a stool.
Data oximetry.
Thirty seconds.
That's a long time.
It's a long time.
I was thinking it was 15 and I was
thinking I might've,
I might've been wrong.
It might have been 10.
They didn't even try a trick like the
old spill.
The ice,
that classic,
which I love so much.
Dude.
Thirty seconds is a long time for guy to
recover.
You could.
He could have easily been code.
He could have.
I mean,
who knows because he's such a super
athlete.
He might've been able to rebound,
but he might not have to.
We'll never know
if you're taking 30 seconds you're
taking it because 20 seconds wasn't
enough.
Yeah,
well it's.
well it would be an minute at that
point.
There's a minute and 32nd break on top
of that.
So it was a minute 30 for from the time
Tim was beating on him until the time
the round ends.
He goes back to his corner,
clearly fucked up,
and then he sits on the stool for a long
time.
It's a,
it's a 100 percent of an and an
asterisk.
Asterisk.
Do you ever say that word right?
Asterisk asked her.
It always sounds wrong.
It's like when George Bush used to say
especially,
and he would say,
especially the Vaseline,
does that have anything to do with it?
Sit on them.
And they tried to get the trainer in and
he couldn't understand what they were
saying.
Is that what it was?
That's what this and this year.
And I said,
yeah,
but he was sitting there.
He was sitting there and they didn't.
And Tim Kennedy standing there,
the rounds over and he's got his arms up
there and see if you could play that on.
You played out or they'll get us kicked
off.
I don't have to find it.
Okay.
Don't worry about it.
You don't have to find it.
Um,
but that's the only one.
Next is name.
Where are you to go?
Ooh,
you know that one.
That one a good can't take on 32nd
break.
Yeah,
that's not good.
But,
and he wound up winning that fight,
which is man,
that's a that there's a major violation
there.
That's a,
a giant like not being ready for the
start of the next round.
If you have the round starts like you
don't want,
the referee doesn't want to stop the
fight,
he doesn't want to give it to your
opponent because you can't start the
round on time.
But he's in a terrible situation where
he wants to fight to continue.
But he also understands that you're
taking unfair advantage here by just
sitting here while you should be
engaging in a contest.
There's a specified one minute break.
You've exceeded your one minute break.
Therefore I must disqualify you.
So they're stuck.
They're stuck in no man's land.
They don't want to be the party pooper.
You just get Yowell up real quick.
Like he's,
he's just in the 30 seconds later.
He finally.
What?
How,
how?
That's a big one,
man.
I didn't know it was 30 seconds.
I really thought it was 15 or less.
But take that away because you know,
that's unfortunate,
but shit happens.
Take that away and you're looking at
just a freak.
The freak of freaks to come in.
Here he is with Joey Diaz.
Yes.
Joe is going to help translate.
So if everything,
like if everything's going smooth or
maybe he doesn't understand what I'm
saying,
he might turn to Joey and they'll,
we'll abide by law,
by law though.
Shit.
Just fucking throw their hands up.
Air.
Just each other and shit.
And then we'll be back in business.
Be surprised if you all can get these
headphones on over his shoulders.
Those,
I know he's a tank.
I don't know.
Um,
I don't know how much he wants to talk
about his life in Cuba and what it was
like,
like wrestling there.
But I would be utterly fascinated to
hear about that,
you know,
and to rise to the top of the heap in
that crazy shark tank of athletic talent
and then go onto metal and like
basically every wrestling championship
that he entered into nationally.
I mean it's just one of the freak of
freaks.
Yeah.
Fascinating that those guys exist.
And I think it's so important that we
know because everybody has these ideas
in their head about like physical
limitations and physical capabilities.
And then you see like a,
like a Walter Payton and you just go,
oh whoa,
like,
how's this guy or Herschel Walker?
Herschel Walker is a great example.
You see,
you see Herschel Walker run and you'd
go,
Oh,
what?
That's the person too crazy.
How has that guy mean?
Herschel Walker to this day is super
jacked and he's in his fifties.
That was him in his late forties
fighting in strikeforce.
Look at that.
Fifty four wants to fight again.
Is this new?
Come on.
Seriously,
June 2016.
So two years ago.
So now he's 56.
Wants to fight against.
Still Open the rampage bad.
He's open to a rampage.
Jackson.
He's so crazy.
He might win.
Dude.
Hershel Walker's terrifying.
That's another what?
Exactly the same thing.
We're talking about another insane level
of physical talent above and beyond.
He like all pushups only or something
for awhile
apparently.
That's a lot of what he did.
A lot of what he did was push ups and a
lot of body weight exercises and he
didn't really necessarily lift weights.
Who knows,
man,
he might be telling the truth,
but it seems like he looks like a guy
who lifts weights,
so vqv that jacked at 47 or 48 and not
lift weights.
This was 2011 from this photo.
That picture?
Yeah.
Okay.
So.
But you know,
not a young man and ridiculously ripped
and always has been.
He's just as severe outlier.
There's like there's brock lesnar.
Got It.
Yeah.
There was a guy when Jamie and I were
back in Columbus,
way,
way back named Maurice Colorado running
back for Ohio state that only played one
year.
He was a freshman and broke every
freshman record this and that led us to
a national championship.
Wasn't even that tall probably.
I don't know.
Who knows,
whatever,
five,
10,
nine,
something like,
not that tall,
but he had thighs and hips that where he
would just keep running.
He would just keep his legs moving and
he would run people over.
Just boof.
Boof,
boof.
Smashing guys.
Guys on the defense in our,
when we played them in high school,
he,
because he was right around the corner
at Warren harding in youngstown and so
we played them in high school.
Our guys were being taken off on
stretchers on the defense guys trying to
tackle him stretcher stretcher
stretcher.
I'm not even kidding.
It was crazy.
Marise Claret.
You see the.
But he's a real human man.
Look at that.
Isn't that crazy?
These are real.
That's so much muscle.
Yeah.
Um,
did you see that video of Brock Lesnar
punching that guy for real and a
wrestling match?
He's done that quite a few times.
Sometimes.
Brock let's dudes know what's up.
If they don't do things right or if
they're not,
you
need him in the face pretty hard.
Yeah.
And his head snapped back and Brock
crack this dude.
Yeah.
Like with like real punches,
like I'm going to hit you with real
punches now I boom,
boom.
Sometimes a couple times on the jaw.
That was an old car.
That's a hard fucking needed the head
and brackets up and you could see is
very unhappy.
Boom.
That's a real punch right there.
That is the kind of shit that he hit
Frank Mir with.
That's real.
Yeah.
They're playing big time ball.
That is a freak that guy,
man.
People think about him as a ww II guy
and then they think about him as,
you know,
fighting in the UFC and winning some
fights and being this bad motherfucker,
but they don't know when he beat chain
car when.
I mean that was a big fucking fight for
him to choke out Jane,
Carl Jane Corwin.
But what people don't realize is like
when he was an amateur wrestler,
he was a fucking monster.
Yup.
It's just his decision to go into the
UFC late after you'd been doing pro
wrestling.
People were like,
oh,
this guy.
But look,
this guy is a fucking unbelievable.
Athletes ever seen his nfl combine
scores.
Now.
Can you see that Shit Jamie?
See if you could google is Shane car
when versus brock lesnar combine because
somebody made a one of those images and
it showed their numbers similar height,
similar weight.
PROC was a fucking freak
can it shows in the wwe,
right?
You know,
people say,
you know,
I'm sure if it's fake,
but it's not because you can see that
compared to all the other athletes,
some of them that only did that their
entire lives,
his hit this number of strides that he
takes longer and faster and you just see
him even from seat's far away.
You can see,
wow,
that guy is big and moving wave Jesus
moving at the same speed as the.
The crazy luchador Mexican wrestlers
were earlier,
but he's that size with shoulders like
that.
He had what I would call a fractured mma
training that led him to the heavyweight
champion and I say fractured that.
He jumped right into the deep end and
won and beat guys like Randy coture beat
guys like Frank Mir.
Shane Carwyn beats him worldclass guys.
But if he had started I think earlier in
his life and learn how to strike and
got.
Got some of that in there first.
So there wasn't such an alien thing to
him when he was fighting in the big
leagues was really unlimited striking
for a few years.
If he learned that a strike from a real
technical instructor,
someone was real tactical,
instill,
still had that wrestling ability when he
was younger,
they would.
I mean,
who the fuck else is like that?
Who else is like that?
When we got.
I mean he was in his thirties already.
He'd been doing progress in a long time.
It beats the shit out of your body.
You might think it's fake.
There's nothing fake about when he
flipped over the top rope and landed on
his head.
I remember that one.
That salt.
Yeah.
That's not fake.
Try faking that.
Your debt.
Most people are dead from that.
Yeah.
He survived and kept going with the
wrestling moves like this is not a
normal athlete,
but every now and then one of those guys
comes along and if they can,
if they.
I mean obviously brock was very tactical
when he was in high school and when he
was a young wrestler,
his,
his.
If you watch some of the videos of him
when he was a younger guy who was
slightly smaller,
he was definitely a smaller guy,
but he still was a gorilla.
I mean,
there's nothing,
there's no getting around that genetics,
you know,
but it's rare that a guy like that at
him,
you know,
can reach the level where you seeing a
Yoel Romero because like,
that's almost like another level even
past what brock's capable of doing.
Brock's.
I can't find Shane's numbers.
40 yard dash time.
Four point seven.
Vertical jump.
30 five standing long jump.
Ten feet.
Whoa.
He can stand and jump 10 feet forward.
And he's 265 pounds.
Bench press,
225 pounds for 30 reps.
40 yard dash time.
Four point seven.
Vertical jump.
What does this was a tune on the wire
repeated.
Okay.
Oh,
I see.
Okay.
So that's.
That was the last APP was the bench
press?
Two hundred 25 pound bench press for 30
reps.
that's a lot of fucking reps,
man.
That's crazy.
But I know there's guys who do more than
that.
It's a similar thing I could find was a
forum.
It said that Shane did like 43 reps on
that,
but I couldn't find it.
Stats.
Oh,
so you did more bench press.
What is a world record in the combine or
how many times a guy can bench press?
Two,
25.
I'm going to guess 50.
Do you think your guy could do it 50
times?
Probably.
There's probably some like giant 50
1:50.
Hold Wow.
Prices.
Right?
Who is it?
Didn't earnest.
Justin.
Earnest.
That mother fucker wonder.
It's probably some field goal kicker.
Jesus Christ just jacked the tits.
Want to get it.
All I knew is kicked balls and a press
bench.
Imagine if they just made field goal
kickers that are just giant Brock lesnar
style gorillas to.
That'd be fun.
Why?
Why couldn't those guys kicked just as
good or if not further and faster?
Why?
Kickers are always like you're not
supposed to hit them,
right?
Yeah.
You can't hit the kicker.
That seems so crazy.
It's a weird job,
man.
You miss a kick.
All those guys don't care about you.
They'll stab you in the back.
I mean they just.
There was no loyalty for the kicker.
The rest of the other guys hold each
other up.
From what I've read and understand,
it's like a depressing job.
It's gotTa.
Be You don't.
You don't get.
You're not a part of it.
Yeah.
You can't get hit it.
That's the one thing everybody's afraid
of and you can't get hit
in.
The littlest stuff throws them off to
like in this last super bowl,
they painted like the 25 yard line with
a special superbowl emblem and it messed
these guys up because it's white,
so they're not used to kicking off
green.
Who was the first kicker?
Is the designated kicker.
Is that always been the rule that you
can't hit the guy who was the kicker?
Am I wrong?
Do I know what I'm talking about that
you can't hit them?
You can definitely hit them.
Oh,
you just can't hit them while they're
kicking the ball so you can hit him
after the kick the ball while they're in
the process of kicking.
You can't kick their leg unless you're
about to block it.
If you hit the ball,
you can actually then run into them,
but if you don't block the ball then you
can't touch them.
But if you're reaching for the ball and
you've got to remember their legs coming
forward at a crazy fast rate,
if you missed the ball and you hit them,
and by the way the rules crazy.
And the same goes for the punter,
like if you hit them while their leg is
basically still in the air,
huge penalty.
Really huge.
And this is afterwards,
this guy as a punter,
this is pat McAfee,
he jacked up the sky on a punt return.
So like he's not afraid to go hit him.
He'd fucked him up.
But yeah,
he's probably out for three years after
that.
He knows what he did illegal,
right?
They're not at all.
Not at all.
No.
He's just now part of the team.
He can go hit them,
but usually like quarterback,
they want to try to.
He's the only punter on the team.
So you've got to protect that guy.
Otherwise you're fucked.
Without a good kicker.
You had to go to somebody else.
Wow.
Interesting.
Jimmy loved the football,
don't you?
Yeah.
It's just a weird way.
It's like it's a high level chesting to.
There's 53 guys,
you have to break it down and then it's
all strategy and it's all pre snap
strategy because it's only five seconds
at a time and it's all setting this up.
I'm going to trick you like it's just
the guys up in the booth,
old 50 year old men that think they know
a lot about football and they can't
actually go do it sorta like an mma,
like a Duke Roufus type guy.
Call things out.
It's very strategic,
very much chest.
And that's why bill belichick and Tom
Brady make it to the superbowl pretty
much every year,
which is,
you know,
just like with the UFC,
we've seen so many fights like any given
Sunday almost,
right?
Like if you made,
made the same match 10 times,
we know it's not going to go that way
every time.
Uh,
but uh,
those guys have a way of figuring it
out.
So it's crazy to see
a pro football team,
like all the planning that has to be in
place.
All the monitoring of everybody's
health,
all the knowing what everyone's capable
of.
All the different strength and
conditioning routines must watch these
guys perform and drills.
You must watch these guys complete and
then you get together.
All these people were trying to
strategize what's the best moves and the
quarterback's got to figure some shit
out and call things out in the field.
It's really a fucking nutty.
Ganesh
can't throw money at it.
They can throw money to fix any of those
problems they want.
Yeah,
and when you factor in that,
some of the times they're doing things
just to set you up completely to make
you think like,
oh,
we saw them do that.
When we watched video with him play the
raiders.
They did this,
so this next play is gonna be this and
blah blah,
blah.
Gone another touchdown.
Yeah.
That's the thing.
That's just obviously the issues.
What happens to the players when they
get older?
It's harder to watch it now,
right?
It doesn't seem the same.
It seemed like the same thing to me
anymore.
Now it goes down.
I'm like,
Ooh,
that sounds fucked up.
Coming from someone who's seen a lot of
fights,
but I just think it's.
It's all.
It's all bad,
it's all bad to get hit that hard,
but in a fight there's a high
possibility that you could avoid getting
hit that hard if you're like a mighty
mouse or if you're like a GSP or you are
a top of the food chain athlete.
John Jones,
he's going to get hit hard too.
It's still getting around
the sell those tapes.
I like biggest hits of the NFL speed
commercials on TV.
Like it's a little tough to watch those
now.
Yeah,
don't you think that they're getting hit
harder?
Yeah.
They're getting into harder than a UFC
guys.
Right?
Well,
the speed is so fast now that faster
than they were even five,
10 years ago.
Yeah.
I've seen some of those hits and I'm
trying to imagine the difference between
that and like a punch or a kick and
multiple magnitudes of power stronger.
Like a guy's getting launched through
the sky with these hits.
I mean,
well they get launched,
they lift off the ground,
they go fly,
and these 200 pound plus men,
I'm pretty sure footballs worse because
when it's helmet to helmet,
I don't think there's any Shin to skull
kick that could even compare to that
because the brain is hitting the inside
of your skull if you're receiving that
hit and I don't think there's.
Unless another guy is wearing a helmet
running at you at full speed,
especially if you're running the
direction that he's in.
Boom.
I mean it just.
That's like two cars hitting head on.
If you've seen the difference between
like a car accident in a head on car
accident,
what happens to the dummy and what
happens to people like it's night and
day first play.
Here is the very first play of the
biggest hits.
Oh fuck.
And launch this.
The Guy Stars Jesus Christ
probably knocked out.
Yeah.
I would imagine a lot of guys get
knocked out.
I mean,
you know,
they say that some concussions happen
from getting hit in the chest that we
always thought about concussions or you
got,
oh,
you got hit in the head,
you got a concussion.
I didn't know until fairly recently.
That's how stupid I am.
I didn't know that you can get a
concussion from getting hit to the body
because when you get hit in the body,
your brain jostled around just as much.
It's a different scene than the
hemorrhaging in the brain that you often
get from local trauma.
That's scary.
Shit.
People fall and hit their heads,
but just getting kicked to the body
fucks your brain up.
That's what's crazy.
It's not just hitting right on the spot,
which definitely does it too,
but guys get their brains rattled from a
kick to the body for sure,
for a take down for sure for football.
Everyone's had a bad one in a wrestling
match.
In high school I got stuck like in a
embridge and the guy had me in like a
head scissors and he snapped it back
real hard and my head hit the mat.
I woke up with Puke on me.
I was still,
I was still on my back in the middle of
the mat and night qct like projectile,
like pop up cold and cold and puked.
That's dangerous man.
He could choke on your own.
That's the one time I had to go straight
to a hospital in the ambulance.
Football
is probably the most impact because
you're both running,
so guys running at you full clip.
That never happens in wrestling.
It was never like running at you.
This is the hypnosis.
This Guy Ryan shazier number 50.
He has a normal tackle,
but he is just now getting the feeling
back in his legs.
This happened about six months ago.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
Oh really?
Freak accident and his spine on a normal
tackle.
Normal everyday tasks.
Shit.
Yeah.
This happened,
like play,
like that can happen like that on any,
any given five seconds of an NFL game,
a player like that can have his life
changed.
And that's a net.
Another freak athlete from the Ohio
State University that's been one of the
top line backers every year.
Yeah,
I mean it's um,
it's super unfortunate that the body so
goddamn brittle,
but it's also one of the things that
makes so fascinating when you see what
these guys capable of doing.
So,
you know,
there's a brief window like the
Olympics,
which is going on right now.
This is a brief window where someone can
be good as a Michael Phelps,
right?
Like,
how many,
how many years do you have where you
could just dominate swimming like that?
They've got 10.
Is that,
is that real?
Is that a real number?
Was 15.
I mean,
what is it?
How long can you can.
You definitely can't keep it up forever.
It's like when does everything just fall
apart?
So when you're watching someone who can
do crazy shit with their body and then
you see a tackle like that,
that leads to a guy being paralyzed,
like,
fuck dude,
that's hard,
you know,
but you wouldn't want,
would you want it to change
football?
Yeah,
I think they should have a big balloon
helmets on.
Big silly looking super soft bouncy
helmets.
Would you want it to change?
I've been thinking about that.
I think it's going to change a little
bit,
but I mean if you were the commissioner.
Yeah,
said young.
Jamie,
you seem to know what the fuck you're
talking about.
Would you please do us a favor and tell
us how to run this football thing?
Yeah.
There's things they.
I think they could do to change it.
There's stronger helmets they could
probably be using.
I don't know if that would have helped
them.
I could probably have some more
protection.
The technology's probably around the
corner.
It's probably like some type of weird
airbag in a helmet that they're going to
end up getting or something weird,
you know,
like maybe a decelerator or something.
It's like that that absorbs the impact
of the hit on your head so that it
doesn't snap you back though.
The conventional wisdom is that the
helmets actually make it worse because
they can hit each other much harder.
Whereas like they get more damaged than
a rugby player gets rugby players
because they know there's no padding
there not doing the same kind of crazy
shit.
It requires different techniques if you
want to have a career,
and I just mean in rugby's obviously
they get down and dirty and it's a very,
very tough game,
but they,
um,
it's a,
you have to do a totally different thing
when you're not padded up.
It's like if you watch their scrims and
you watch some of the crazy physical
altercations they have,
it looks more like running and
wrestling.
There's like a lot of wrestling involved
was a football,
it's just this like fucking chaos of
colliding bodies and people fucking
smashing into people and jumping over
people and
I just feel listened to that NPR episode
about football and how it started and
that's how football used to be.
It used to just be two people or two
teams would line up and they just run
into each other and scrum and just
slowly move the ball down the field
slowly,
slowly.
And then eventually as time went by,
they started adding the past and things.
And now it's just.
The NFL is literally just passed the
ball for as many touchdowns as you can
get.
Hopefully nobody gets hurt.
Ian Edwards is trying to turn me into a
soccer fan,
but it just didn't take.
Ha Ha,
ha ha.
Me and him at a bar.
He showed me like some super important
game and I'm just mocking him,
mocking him and making fun of the whole
thing.
I could see you being a pro wrestling
fan before being a soccer fan for sure.
No,
look,
I've stated numerous occasions.
I'm a huge ric flair fan.
Yeah,
no,
I love that.
If any of their babies,
I'm a huge.
I love the rock.
I think the rock is awesome.
I go to see all his movies.
I want to see Jumanji twice.
I got star struck.
I.
I met Ric Flair at the airport after the
royal rumble.
It was so crazy.
Our flight had just gotten delayed on
the tarmac and then canceled.
We get deep boarded.
Everybody else is waiting at the desk.
I'm like,
I'm going to go to the customer service
part of this airline.
I know how this crap works.
There's a long line,
so I'm like,
I'm going to go to the customer service
and I'm walking by myself and there he
is walking straight at me by himself and
I literally like as a,
as I'm getting closer,
I'm like,
that's not flair.
That's not very clear.
That's out of my face comes nature boy.
And he goes,
yeah man.
I'm like,
hell yeah.
I follow him on instagram.
I follow him on twitter.
I don't know if I do follow on good
instagram.
I follow him on instagram.
Best Man.
Just a legend.
Yeah.
You know,
it's like stuff like that that I enjoy
about pro wrestling.
That's what I enjoyed the most
ridiculous aspects of it.
Yeah.
Like I was a big fan of Jimmy superfly
snuck back in the day because it was
just so ridiculous that he would always
wind up on the top rope,
what some guy unconscious underneath
them and he would fly through the air
land dot.
Um,
and we were always pumped about it.
So silly.
There's a lot of fun stuff happening.
Yeah,
the man,
the natch,
the nature.
I used to be a fan of Bob backlund.
You remember Bob Course.
I was like,
he's a no nonsense guy,
a no nonsense guy.
That's how I felt about him.
I felt he was like,
to me like what embodied and actual
wrestler versus like the progress
underneath stuck out like a sore thumb
because he did like the progress
something but not really.
What he basically did is just engulf you
on the ground and hit you with some
ridiculous real wrestling.
Then you're not really prepared for is
finished.
Move fucking hurts.
Cross face chicken wing.
See?
He was just,
for whatever reason he did wasn't
appreciated and it hurts.
He was two normal people.
Didn't appreciate him enough.
The figure four hertz in real life too.
They figure four leg lock.
Is that a real thing?
That's a little flare.
Invented it.
Oh,
I know,
but I'm saying.
Is it a real submission?
It look,
here's the only catch.
It's a real submission,
but the person has to basically let you
put them in there.
I see
it or do they do?
They have to be completely unconscious,
but Bob Backlund,
I had you back buddy back in high school
when all the other kids were.
They only liked the superfly and then
hulk Hogan or it is.
Here it is.
Let me see.
See you after all the way around.
Okay.
Let me see this.
See,
this is the part they have to be like,
what are you doing on?
Let me see this drops.
Oh yeah,
that's totally legit.
No,
dude,
if you can get a guy into that position,
that shit will hurt.
If you get a guy like Gordon Ryan puts
you in something
like that.
Just for fun.
Yeah.
Fuck your legs up,
but here's a go back to it again.
I don't think it's a good position for a
couple reasons,
so like right there.
It's good if you can get to that.
If you can get to that,
but I'm not sure.
Here's the catch dop in him.
I'm not sure what's stopping him from
scooting his butt towards that guy's
right leg.
Here's the catch is that if you can roll
over while you're in the figure four leg
lock,
it completely reverses the polars of
the,
uh,
of the earth.
Pain of the pain ric flair with.
Well,
let me see it again.
By the way,
that's also true in real life.
I've tested that.
Well,
what I'm saying is like the position
it's,
you would,
there's a natural way to defend it that
it doesn't seem like the guys defending
it.
That's why like,
look.
Oh,
he's trying to keep them from putting it
in there.
Oh,
he stepped on his dick because he's
stepping on his deck a little bit.
That's the undertaker allowed.
You're allowed to.
Okay.
Now this is a short legs down.
Oh,
that's a heel hook.
Yeah.
The guy.
Here's the why.
This is so fucking stupid.
The guy who's getting his leg kranked is
actually the guy who's in the best
position.
He's in a heel hook position.
Yeah.
If you could just grab his leg.
Right.
So who's supposed to be getting hurt
here?
This is actually the guy in black.
The guy in black is.
No,
no,
the guy in the better position,
all he has to do is reach back with his
right arm and hook time at elbow onto
the ankle.
No,
you time out,
motherfucker.
This is not a figure four leg lock.
This is embarrassing.
That's a heel hook.
He's given them a heel hook and the
other guys pretending he's in pain.
This is crazy.
This isn't even a figure.
Four leg lock.
Know what this is?
It's an unmodified.
Oh,
come on.
Lucky's in agony.
No,
he's got a fucking heel hook.
Take the look.
It's right there.
You go like this.
You clap your hands together and the
match is over.
I mean it's 100 percent over in real
life.
Yeah.
Well,
what the fuck are they doing that?
What did they do at winners or losers?
Everybody gets a trophy.
Is that what you're doing?
You show in a terrible position.
The guy in white isn't trouble.
What happened?
What was the difference?
Oh,
I broke up.
Yeah,
the other guys doing it wrong for the
whole fucking time.
This finger for here.
This one maybe.
Okay.
This is one steps over.
Yeah.
Boy,
it takes a lot of work to get someone to
do that.
Wow.
What is that?
I've never seen that.
I'll tell you what that is.
Okay.
That looks painful.
To go back to that again,
let me say that again.
I think it's the same thing.
Go back the same thing.
No,
no,
no.
One a little bit further.
Little bit further back.
I gotta go.
I gotta see the setup.
I got to see the setup.
Okay.
Steps over.
The other guy is basically triangling
his lower leg.
The guy in the bottoms in a better
position.
This is nonsense.
The guy in the bottom fed his leg
through the center,
which is the worst thing he could've
done right there.
He had a triangle on that.
I should have fed it.
He should have tried to go through the.
He could have fucking swept that guy
with that.
Let me say it one more time.
One more time.
See this guy stepping over and then this
guy could just triangle that leg right
there.
Why is he doing that?
He let him put it in the center.
Even if you let them put it in the
center,
he supposed to move as soon as that guy
spins and then you're free.
He should have wound up on top there.
Oh,
see,
this is a true figure is John.
You go,
boom,
boom.
It might hurt.
Yeah.
It'd probably hurt if a guy,
a big gorilla like John Cena got you in
that shit,
but you have to be almost dead.
Yeah,
exactly.
To be able to do all that shit.
I mean,
he might be able to do it to me.
Don't get me wrong.
Exactly.
If size,
for example,
if anybody ever hit a figure four leg
lock in a real fight,
like that would be the most watched
worldstar video ever.
I wonder if it's done.
The thing is today,
well Johnson have reversed it.
Oh,
that's actual real.
That's real as fuck.
That hurts.
Like hell.
What he's doing is he's fucking that
guy's knee up and he's cranking on his
neck at the same time and and under his
nose.
The inside of this row.
You can tap now.
Oh,
you've always been able to tap.
That's the whole point.
That's how ric flair beats people.
Well,
he thought that you can count it out
when you pin the guy.
That's one way that submission,
it's a new thing counts.
How long have they been?
There's disqualification coutts tap outs
and if the ref hits the mat three times
with his hand.
How long have they been tapping out
forever?
For the beginning.
Bob Backlund who you mentioned?
Yeah,
it's cross faced chicken length.
If submission only matches like run for
45,
did they have them back in the superfly
days with the iron sheik?
Oh yeah.
Iron Sheik.
Smooth camel clutch submission.
He made guys tap.
Camel Clutch hurts in real life too.
I blocked that out of my memory.
Mandible calls one of the best.
That's a weird thing to block out of
your memory,
like why did I block out the tap outs?
Because you have not wanted to be a pro
wrestling fan.
You have been in denial of your love.
Look at this.
This is the mandible cloth from mankind.
Man Puts a sock on his hand and then
shoves his two fingers underneath,
underneath your tongue and then squeezes
his thumb underneath your chin in that
space and tries to connect.
What do they call that?
The mandible claw.
But at one point,
uh,
it was a Mr Soco when he was working
with a rock and they had the rock.
You're fucking wrong.
Yeah.
So he's got a sock puppet on.
He stuffs it in your mouth.
He keeps,
he keeps the sock in his underwear until
it's time.
And then when he gets you down,
the crowd goes crazy and he's pulling
up.
Boss pulls the sock out and lifts it up
and that crowd goes insane.
That is the dumbest and most awesome
Diaz at the same time,
the dumbest and most awesome thing at
the same time.
Heck yeah.
That kind of shit.
That's funny.
Yeah,
that's funny.
It's ridiculous.
But the thing about pro wrestling is
that a lot of people,
myself included,
don't want to enjoy it.
They don't want to let go for something
like that.
I think you were,
I think you were like perhaps weeks away
from becoming a pro wrestling fan.
Jude delusion.
It's been an interesting guy,
Tony,
but I don't trust your judgment on many
issues.
Oh,
I think you're weeks away now.
You're going to watch run down.
You're going to watch Rwanda's match
though.
You're going to see what happens at
Wrestlemania.
I mean,
he's definitely an orange highlights
wrong with you.
What was wrong with they rebooted the
cosmos,
son.
I'm watching that.
Oh my God.
So fun.
A pro wrestling is fun,
man.
I just took everybody.
We went to the royal rumble,
had a blast,
took a whole crew.
La comedians out to Philly,
saw Ronda Rousey come out.
We were all very surprised.
It was exciting.
Yeah,
it was a big deal.
Yeah.
You guys get super excited.
We went crazy.
I can't get high.
I just all the nuances to follow along.
Who's mad at who?
Oh,
you would love it if they keep it really
easy.
They give you just like UFC.
They give you a little breakdown before
they have their own Joe Rogan type who's
like,
you know,
doing the voiceover.
Here's why this person's like this.
The technical side of things like they
do a cool like,
you know,
a little background and explanation
before so you can catch up quick and
then all of a sudden,
Bam,
you're watching.
The only thing that seems interesting
about the possibility of that is that it
to me is I'm an,
I've overdosed on reality.
Whether it's pawn shows or you know,
whatever the fuck it is that's on tv,
swamp people or people making moonshine,
all that stuff.
I don't,
I don't have any desire to watch anymore
reality.
Do you know who Brunstrom in is?
No,
but when I was going to say,
I'd rather watch like a really good
fiction,
like something that's good.
Some show something that's written in
somewhere.
I know it's going to be good.
Yeah.
All the time.
Not every now and then the guy tries to
mouth fuck a dude with a sock on his
hand.
No.
Funny that it's kind of funny,
but I don't have the kind of time to
wait for that to generate.
It's like when I hear about Saturday
night live sketches and like,
I'm sure they get one every now and
again.
That's fucking amazing.
But I don't have,
I don't have 90 minutes on Saturday
night.
I agree with you 100 percent on Saturday
night live,
but they get good ones.
They get good ones.
Not as good as progress will listen
that,
those Alec Baldwin,
once he knocks it out of the park.
Alice,
there's some funny shit still.
Alec Baldwin has done some stuff with,
uh,
with pro wrestling with Alec.
Baldwin is the most popular show.
30 rock progress sling.
30 rock is pro wrestling now the rock.
I tried to make a reference there,
but it didn't work
as in 30 rock.
Just like an address.
You're silly.
You're silly person.
That's the worst pain you've ever done.
You need to take a break from puns
show you tell everybody that I'm the
punk king.
People come see my standup.
They're like,
I'm really surprised that you didn't do
any puns after
you rattled off three or four really
ones right before
this show started.
I try to hold back.
I wanted the whole Jane Goodall thing.
You don't think I wanted to say
chimpanzee and easy?
I wanted to,
but I didn't.
Why didn't you say it?
Because I don't want to be known as the
Pun guy.
Dude,
you're funny.
You're funny in other ways,
but that's it.
You are trying to be insecure.
Let your let your talents shine.
You're very funny with puns.
I'm trying to show my full balance.
You have that too.
In rain.
Don't hold your puns back when you know
that they're natural.
That's the thing.
You got them right there.
They're.
They're popping in your fucking crazy
head here,
right?
Let him free.
You're right.
Let them free.
Tony Hinchcliffe.
You're right.
That those fuckers free.
Let them free.
Woo.
Punted it up.
Yeah.
We're nice people,
so no,
we're not going to repeat what we said
before the show started where you were
rattling off all those puns.
I don't remember them.
That's important.
Is there ever been a time in your life
whether it was something that you now
think is really fucking stupid but you
believed in then like ghosts or anything
goofy like that?
Yeah,
I think there's a slight chance that I
saw something one day at the comedy
store.
It's silly,
but yeah,
I don't know what it was.
Maybe I was borderline about to pass
out.
Maybe it was like a low blood sugar
attack,
but I saw something weird one day out of
all the days that I worked there for
years in the middle of the day.
One day I was working the phones on the
second floor in the phone room where
like the bookers room is now and I was
going outside to the belly room to like
smoke a joint or smoke a cigarette or
something like that.
But that's a dark room.
And I was walking through there and when
I was walking through there,
um,
I stopped and felt like something.
It just felt weird,
like something in my gut felt weird and
then sort of stopped and I looked to my
right,
right where that other door is.
Like if you're walking into the belly
room from the belly room greener and
there's the green hallway and you
finally come across.
So you're right in front of the men's
room.
We'll write to your right.
There's that other door that leads down
to like the back bar in the back.
Gullet whole everything.
So those two doorways are right next to
each other.
And I stopped there and I saw some weird
white silver floaty looking thing.
This was like years ago,
cigarette smoke,
someone was smoking cigarettes over
there and they blew.
No,
it was indoors.
I'm indoors.
Somebody was smoking cigarettes indoors.
This is back when nobody was at the
comedy store.
Smoke cigarettes indoors this time.
Yeah.
Nobody else smoke.
It was more glowing than smoke,
like it had its own.
Was it spooky smoke?
It could have been perhaps a reflection
off of headshot.
Uh,
but there was nothing on that side.
It was an empty bathroom.
May I suggest that this was during the
day?
Yes.
And the dust in the comedy store is
world world class.
The last time they run a motherfucking
vacuum cleaner over those stairs is the
first time they run a motherfucking
vacuum cleaner over those days as you're
walking up there.
I'm just kidding.
Now they,
they,
it's pretty clean now,
but that's how it used to be for the
longest time.
And um,
you're,
you're going to see when the wind like a
windows open and the sunlight's coming
through,
you know,
that glint if there's so much dust there
to like,
you could see it in those little beams.
Like you could see it floating in the
air.
He'd be walking by going,
oh great,
I'm breathing in that scary.
But the kicker is old buildings are like
that,
right?
Kicker with this one was that I didn't
tell anybody about it because I was
obviously like a whatever.
I mean it freaked me out.
I didn't end up smoking.
I remember I slowly turned around and
walked back to the phones ring because I
was freaked out.
I'd interrupted you to try to be funny
and I failed.
So could you just explain it one more
time?
Like you're,
you're walking,
you see this thing,
what do you see?
Describe it to me it's sort of like
human height,
but like glowy sort of look like,
like I would say like a jelly fish.
It's shaped like a human sort of,
sort of a little bit.
Like it seemed like it had like casper
sort of.
Yes.
As cheesy as that sounds.
It's sort of did like,
but it was more,
it wasn't like a solid white.
It was like here's a question.
This is a good one.
Like why were Goso is depicted as being
like wispy was always ghosts were always
wispy and flying through the air.
And the creepy thing is,
is that's what this sort of felt like.
It felt whispery like on the sides,
like there was sorta like a,
like a,
I don't know,
like sorta like how you see that with
like a fish or something like that where
I like little tentacles or something
moving into the air.
I know this sounds ridiculous,
but that's what I saw it.
Now look,
it does sound ridiculous,
but again,
so to people,
people sound ridiculous.
Like if we weren't a real thing and you
had to think about like if there was no
life form that change the environment
around it,
none the war.
The biggest thing would be like a permit
crab or something like that steals a
shell and lives inside of it.
If that was how most of nature was like
bear den,
other bear dug a hole in the side of the
hill.
That was.
It does the extent of people and
animals,
birds make nests and then all of a
sudden you went to a new place and you
saw a Manhattan,
you would.
You would be so fucking freaked out.
You wouldn't be able to believe that
this one organism is capable of altering
the environment around it so radically
and it's the only thing like it.
The only thing like it by far crazy
dude.
What we are is very crazy.
You know,
I mean,
I think people are awesome.
I enjoy talking to him.
I love what we do.
I love to be able to podcasts and do
stand up and have fun and,
but just what we are,
just what the human race is is a weird
thing,
man.
Weird Little Cot,
multicolored thing that wears clothes.
Yeah.
Constantly evolving.
Crazy.
We have status.
Some of it dependent upon what's on your
feet.
Wow.
It's got some fresh Jordan's.
Is that a thing still?
Did the kids still say fresh?
Not to be bringing back fresh.
I'm bringing him back fresh.
We need to bring back fresh.
You can't let fresh go by if someone
looks ingos Jamie looking fresh.
I think that's still here.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Has to be looking fresh.
I've passed many generations of people
thinking that things are cool and
uncool.
I just missed a lot of shit.
No one really says cool though.
Oh,
I see that all the time.
Well there you go.
Well that's cool.
You look cool man.
Um,
yeah.
Duncan would definitely do it.
Yeah.
That's cool man.
Yeah,
that's fucking cool man.
Duncan definitely still says cool.
Um,
it's funny though,
how those words sort of go in a cycle,
right?
Like if people use them a lot and then
like certain words you get,
you get,
they get used so much that you're like
totes,
you know,
people start saying things like that.
Like what?
Like where's all this coming from?
Why is everybody saying that?
There's a bunch of those little weird
sayings that people start saying,
yeah,
I'm trying to figure out some other ones
that people started saying pretty
recently.
God Damn it.
I had one at the tip of my tongue.
They're really common buzzy things.
Budweiser,
wazzup.
They always say,
what's up to everyone?
That was one of the first ones.
So annoying.
That was one of the first ones,
but there's been some other ones that
people just like little weird patterns
that people just repeat over and over
again.
They hear other people say,
you know,
it's interesting how those sorts of get
passed around.
They sound cool.
Someone says,
I'm it sounds cool,
and everybody starts saying,
yeah,
there's a bunch of them.
Totes,
mugshots.
You know what I say?
And I really mean it.
I say to my friends,
I hope everything's groovy.
I say that.
Always say that in like text message.
You know what I say online.
It only only in person,
but I always say,
what's cooking?
Good looking.
They found out people love it,
man.
Love it.
Women love it.
Everybody loves it.
Why not?
Right?
That's a.
that's a compliment.
Instead of just saying hi.
Hey,
what's cooking?
Good looking.
Yeah.
They tell you Tony Hinchcliffe.
So have fun guy.
Yeah,
right away.
Yep.
Hey,
good luck in one.
Imagine that was the only kind of songs
so you could listen to it.
That's all they have.
Cooking up
with me,
man.
Fuck Dude.
Imagined back when they only had a harp.
That's all they had fucking harp and
everybody would just sit around going,
oh,
they're covered in blood and fucking
sword
marks all over the body and some
assholes out there playing a harp.
You supposed to take it seriously and be
like,
ah,
fuck that harp.
I started watching Vikings on season
one.
You're watching vikings.
It's a good fucking show.
Um,
I,
I liked the first episode.
I was like,
oh,
this is very like TV show ish.
I was prejudice going in,
but it wasn't.
The first one is a little slow sort of
setting it up at,
around,
um,
because they're setting everything up
and they have to over a long period of
time.
And to get about episode four,
it starts cracking where you're like,
Whoa,
this is a good fucking show.
I don't know how much of it is
historically accurate,
but it isn't a history channel.
But man,
the vikings were crazy.
They were doing mushrooms and,
and having orgies and the women would
fight and battle that.
They were,
they were wild fucking people.
Man.
I don't know how much of this is like
really,
really accurate or what actual
historians think about it.
I mean,
we know that Vikings were incredible
warriors.
Big giant fucking dudes and that's like
what you see still over there.
And Iceland,
like,
you know,
they have like some of the strongest men
competitions.
Like a lot of those dudes come from
Iceland,
like Dha.
Those are the rapers and pillagers just
throwing barrels.
Man.
A thousand years ago those guys showed
up on shore covered with armor and
swinging an ax and you are fucked.
You're fucked.
Everybody's fucked.
Yeah.
Those guys were crazy.
And again,
I don't know how much of this show is
horseshit and how much of it is,
uh,
you know,
actual historical data and how much is
just dramatic interpretations of what
they thought would be cool.
It would happen mostly that.
Right?
There's no way you actually know what
they said thousand fucking years ago,
but your stories being passed down.
No pictures of the guy,
you know,
like yes.
Things get real weird when you're
talking about a thousand years ago.
But fuck,
it's interesting.
It makes you wonder like,
how,
how would I survive in this crazy
environment?
Crazy.
Like I get,
I'm cold all the time.
All the time.
Yeah,
all the time.
There's always a part every morning when
I get out of the shower in which I just
want to like die right before,
right after shutting off the water
before grabbing my towel.
You had died then?
Yeah.
You wouldn't be able to make it with the
Viking?
No,
I wouldn't make it.
You wouldn't be able to make it.
You've accepted that though.
Totally.
I liked that because you just know
you're not fighting it.
Like,
this is who I am.
It's been that way my whole life.
I've always hated the cold.
No doubt it's a big part of the meat.
Picking La over New York.
Do where?
Footie pajamas.
No,
only because I don't have footie
pajamas.
If I had some,
a fucking bunch of people.
If you should set up one of them.
Amazon gift accounts that like some gals
have an instagram fame gals,
you know where people could spoil you.
If anybody wants me some footie pajamas.
I'm five.
Nine about a buck 45 right now.
Do this.
You need footie pajamas like bugs bunny
ears.
You need a full bugs bunny outfit?
Yeah,
the Tan rabbit outfit.
That'll sleeping hat up top.
Yeah,
or yeah.
Anything else to dangerously furry like
you can get away with just ears,
but as soon as you have a Pail,
you have a tail bro.
You have a tail.
It's not pajamas anymore,
man.
It's fucking costume.
Yeah,
see right there.
That's not a costume,
that's pajamas,
but let me see his ass.
Oh,
what's his feet?
His feet.
It's clearly pajamas because you can't
have a costume where the feet are heads
to.
Nobody thinks those feet of your heads.
That's ridiculous.
So those.
He's got feet.
The feet are heads.
That doesn't even make sense.
How's that work?
Imagine you got woke up.
My big girl.
Then I go walk around on the fuck kind
of species.
Are you?
Look at this.
We have this thing.
Wow.
So the ears are on top and then what?
You can't get enough mice.
So you have to have mice downstairs too.
Is that what this is?
Or a rabbit?
He can't get enough rabbit.
Rabbit,
Dad,
sweetie.
I got you a rabbit costume.
You are rather rabid.
Woke up my feet.
Rabbits Dad.
Debbie's feeder rabbit's.
Okay.
All right.
We'll get you the rabbits and we'll get
you the rabbit's feet.
But no tail.
Did some in demand?
The rabbit's feet.
This is what I want to know.
Like how did it get to that?
Did someone say,
well,
we're trying to make actual rabbit feet,
but they look stupid and then someone
come along,
go,
hey,
I've got an idea.
Take a little stuff right ahead.
You can put it right in your foot and
then just say,
what are we doing here?
It's just,
is this a new mythical creature?
We're creating Scott heads on its feet.
The fuck is that.
Each feet with its own,
everybody just accepts it.
Just take it home.
Give your kids some fucked up anatomy.
Lesson heads on my feet.
How come I can't have heads on my feet?
That's how it starts.
Yeah.
Heads on the fetus.
Exactly where it starts.
Do you ever wear anything weird to bed?
You do.
Wow.
What did I think everybody wants to
know.
Farmer never know.
Should allow allowed.
Oh,
that's cool.
You got a superman.
It's got a nice one.
Superman seems to not actually have a
cape too,
which is good.
A Batman seems to be a real cape.
Real Cape.
A Batman.
Whoa.
So you don't want to sleep with a Cape
and choke yourself in the middle of the
night.
Die In your sleep.
You know,
you know,
just doesn't seem right.
The wonder woman one,
you know what drives me crazy,
but all this wonder woman shit,
it's men who get upset at wonder woman.
It's the same thing that drives you
crazy about this black panther movie,
which drives me crazy about this black
panther movie is people getting upset
about this Black Panther movie on both
sides.
First of all,
white people making a big deal.
I was like,
oh great.
Oh,
it's all black.
Like what?
Shouldn't just be all good people like,
of course this is the way the story was
and this is the way they want to promote
it.
Why do you care?
Like it doesn't,
I don't care.
But then it goes the other way and I do
care where I've seen crazy liberal
psychos and there were white people in
fact saying white people stay the fuck
out of the theater while,
uh,
this a while Black Panther is out a
don't steal their joy with your white
privilege.
Oh my God.
I literally saw something along those
lines.
I saw a couple of those,
one of them where a woman was asking
when it was appropriate to see it and
she didn't.
She didn't want to ruin it with her
whiteness.
She was totally serious,
totally serious,
and those people,
real people,
and they think that that's.
That makes sense.
Like God damn it.
When when shaft was out,
do you think white people couldn't go
see shaft when blade came out?
Ninety eight.
Did White people stay home?
Like what are we doing?
Are we more divided now than we ever
were before?
We so silly that you can't.
I want to go see Black Panther because I
like fucking superhero movies and it
looks cool.
The fact that anybody would give a shit
one way or the other,
I guess if you're a black kid or a black
guy was like,
hey,
this gives all of us hope that there's
more opportunity for movies to be made
like that,
that people aren't really racist and
they can embrace a black superhero the
same way that it can embrace the Hawk or
thought if the movie's really good and I
hope the movie's really good and I hope
that's exactly what happens,
but how the fuck did it changed so much
from one blade was around because when
blade was around,
dude,
nobody even thought about the fact that
it was a black superhero movie.
I mean,
I guess some people did,
but the emphasis was the fact that
Wesley Snipes was blade and it looked
good and he was doing karate and chop
and vampires up,
but swords and shit.
It was a fucking bad ass movie.
That movie was super successful.
They did two sequels,
so like what's changed?
How the fuck is it changed from then
until now with likewise now,
why is it a big deer if there's a black
superhero,
but it wasn't a big deal then like are
we deteriorating or is it just more
noise because of social media?
Do you get a more distorted sense of how
the country actually feels?
Because the people that are more
inclined to chime in regularly and
vehemently are oftentimes not the ones
who are calculated and you know,
assessing thinkers,
they're maybe a little bit more
aggressive shooting off the cuff.
So what you're getting is not an
accurate representation of how people
feel,
but then you start defending it as if it
is accurate.
And so then people start telling people
to stay the fuck home.
Now you've got craziness and you've got
craziness because of the fringe,
the fringe on both sides,
but in the middle.
Most people like hope it's a cool movie.
Like,
could you imagine if you had a friend
and you were gone?
You want to go see,
uh,
that Black Panther movie?
Nah Man,
fucking these uppity black dudes are
just really getting into this movie too
much.
He'd be like,
what you would.
You would immediately stop hanging out
with that guy and you'd probably tell
all of us,
you know what that fucking guy said,
and we'd be like,
what the call?
You know?
All that stuff is disgusting.
All of it's disgusting.
It's disgusting on both sides.
It's like anytime you're prejudice
against white people or even the
critical about yourself being white,
that you should stay the fuck away from
places that is crazy.
Not talking about intruding on cultural
rituals.
We're talking about an awesome movie.
Everybody who can buy a ticket,
you buy a ticket,
it will make the movie more successful.
You want giant opening weekends.
If you really love this movie and you
want movies like this to be successful,
you should be promoting it for
everybody.
White people,
black people,
Asian people who gives a fuck.
Go see the superhero movie.
It's going to be fun.
He's got a pendant.
It turns into a fucking bulletproof
outfit and he fucks people up.
You shoot them.
He gets more powerful.
It's fun.
Go watch like who gives a shit?
If it's.
I get the people that take pride in it,
they feel like something's happening for
them that it's a black guy,
but the people that are white that have
an issue with it,
oh my God,
you got to let some shit go.
You just got to let the noise go by.
Don't let it bounce around inside your
head and come up with a year,
but I'm not rushing water.
Why have good shoved in my face and
everybody's got to meet in the middle.
It's a crazy time.
Everybody's got to meet in the middle.
There's way less tension and conflict
than is being verbalized.
That's what I think.
I think if people just realized that a
lot of the shit that we're claiming to
has just some ways we've been thinking
and behaving for a long time and then we
can all just fucking communicate with
each other just a little bit better.
I just don't think.
I don't think that racism has gotten
worse.
I think it absolutely has gotten worse
in some places.
I think there's places where racism
exists and I think those.
I think when you have young kids that
are raised with racism and family
members that are raised at racism in a
community that embraces racism,
which has existed in the past,
we don't even have to talk about today,
but in the past it was most certainly
really racist neighborhood.
The Italian neighborhoods in New York
where black people moved in,
they were treated terribly and horrible
shit happened in a lot of times.
They weren't even allowed to move in in
the first place and there's always been
stuff like that.
So if there's always been stuff like
that,
it's a natural human inclination that we
have to iron out.
We can't just eliminate it by making it
illegal or eliminated by prosecuting
people.
We have to figure out why people think
like that too.
Scary way to think.
Scary to think that any one speed.
Look,
first of all,
all of us,
all of us and almost anyone listening to
this in comparison to someone like Elon
Musk is basically a chimp.
Okay,
so you want to be racist.
You should be racist against this
African guy that's smarter than
everybody.
Like that's a real African guy from
South Africa.
Elan Musk.
Yes.
Wow.
Yeah.
He's a
real African American.
Yeah.
Like legitimately.
But obviously there's different stream
black African and I believe it was the
Dutch that originally settled that area,
you know,
and that's,
he's the descendants of those people.
But my point is like,
we're all dumb asses compared to that
guy.
So stop getting all uppity about why
people,
you know,
having better GPA and whatever other
race you're comparing us to because your
stupid compared to that one African
dude,
like you're dumb for sure.
For sure.
Like there's no way you see your vote
should count more than his.
Yeah.
Right.
Mine personally or most anybody's years,
personally,
I don't know.
This idea that there's one race is
better than the other race.
It's fucking stupid.
The people that are really clinging to
it usually don't have shit going on
other than that.
That's the problem with racism.
It puts people in a camp of winters when
they really don't have to do shit to get
into,
get into the team.
You know,
the entrance is instantaneous.
You just,
Oh,
you're white,
you're in.
You know,
that's ridiculous.
That's a ridiculous team.
That's the problem.
That's one of the main problems with,
with the ridiculous nature of racism,
especially organized racism that you
just got to take everybody that looks
like you.
That's it.
That's all.
Not,
not how they think,
not what they've read,
not their life experiences,
not how you feel when you're hanging
around with them.
Now.
How they make you laugh.
No.
You want to make sure that they have
blood from a certain patch of dirt.
Yeah,
it's crazy.
It's so stupid.
And they moved the goalpost too because
I'm a white guy now,
but when my grandparents came here,
they were dirty guineas.
Yeah.
You know,
they were,
um,
they were thought of the way a lot of
people think about Mexicans,
you know,
same kind of thing that's changed now.
The Italians are full on white.
Yep.
Totally.
We almost lost our distinction with
Jersey shore.
We almost lost it.
Yeah.
We came real close to losing it close.
But we're regular white now.
Again.
Feel pretty good about regular white.
Yeah.
You're whole family is Italian,
right?
Yep.
Crazy Italian.
Everybody.
East Coast at times.
Crazy Times.
It's almost redundant.
Yeah,
right.
Yeah.
My East Coast Italians.
Different animal.
Yeah.
My Dad has an Italian restaurant though,
so it's a little bit like amped up
because the family will go there on his
side and my mom makes crazy spaghetti
sauce,
so that's what everybody wants for every
holiday and everything,
so everybody's always trying to get like
red sauce in their stomach.
Yeah.
Whether it's one side or the other.
The family.
You know,
what's really interesting is that like
that sort of style of cooking is not the
same out here at all.
I literally last night for Valentine's
Day,
my wife and I thought out a container of
my mom's sauce that she sent out in a
frozen and had that
instead of going to some fancy dinner,
that's what we wanted and it was
priceless.
And even then in our every bite you're
like,
Holy Shit.
It's like a New York Bagel or something
like that to where it's just different,
like 70 percent better than what you can
find here in la.
Yeah,
there's difference in the bread for
sure.
There's no doubt about it and most
people smarter than me attributed to the
water.
You think that there's something
different.
The water in the east coast like New
York and Boston,
that when they make bread,
it's just a different flavor to it.
I also think that there's something to
the humidity in the air.
They're actually being there.
I mean we forget we live in a desert
because it doesn't feel like a desert,
but it's a desert to bread.
It's desert.
That's a good point,
man.
Yeah,
that's a real good point.
Pasta taste better.
Their pizza definitely tastes better
there and bagels tastes better there.
They have a different thing.
They feel different when they go in your
mouth full.
Yeah,
totally.
Yeah.
They're just better.
They're trying hard out here.
Some guys are getting really close.
We really want to go cheat it.
Cheat,
you know,
get a good solid New York style Bagel
out here for like a cheat day.
Everything's different out here.
They try,
but it's not ever really the same.
Yeah.
There's not as nearly as many of those
Middle Eastern food trucks like as in
New York,
New York.
Those Middle Eastern food trucks are
everywhere that have those killer
kabobs.
Yeah.
What do they call those things when it's
a kabob sandwich inside a falafel or
inside of a,
um,
like a Tortilla.
What do they call that shit?
I'd say like a pita.
Just a Pha.
Warmer.
Warmer,
right?
Yeah.
That's it.
And then they had that,
that white sauce that they put on it.
He only scored all that shit sauce.
Right.
And then the hot sauce on top of that.
Oh my God.
If it's like 2:00
in the morning and you've had like one
more drink than you should have just one
more year.
You're right.
And you're like,
Oh man,
I'm so hungry.
And you see that.
You're like,
we have taco trucks here though.
Yes.
Tons of them.
Yeah,
that's true.
That's true.
We have way more good Mexican food here.
Way More,
but obviously do this.
A joint down the street.
I wish we had more time today.
I'll take it to like one of the most
legit Mexican joints in the valley.
I don't even want to say the name.
I don't want white people to find out
that these white ruinous people ruin in
my authentic Mexican place.
You go in there,
dude,
they got authentic Mexican TV shows
plan.
Barely anybody understands what the fuck
you're saying when you're ordering
things,
so you have to.
You have to order,
you know those case ideas.
You gotta you gotTa talk,
you gotta read off the menu.
Yeah.
A few of those guys understand English,
but the food is insane.
They have tongue that this whole bucket
full of boiling springs language that
chopping up making Lengua Tacos.
I love that shit.
White people don't know what they're
doing with tongues.
What do they do?
They turn it into like some Jewish deli
food or that's it?
Yep.
But Mexican food,
they're like,
that's.
That's the move through language is
expensive.
It's fucking awesome.
It's really good to weird sort of
texture.
Cow Tongue.
So good.
That's a legit place though.
And then you go to the.
They always have a real legit place.
We'll have those little aluminum,
a chrome looking containers,
and they're filled with Jalapenos and
peppers and onions.
Right?
And you scoop that fucking those debt,
big clump of death out of there.
Those Jalapenos,
man,
there's always this creepy carrots for
some reason.
Some people like those carrots take you
off those Jalapenos.
But those Jalapenos kick your ass.
You use Jalapenos,
Jalapenos you find and those little
dishes at Mexican restaurants when you
bite into them and you're like,
whoa,
because all seeds,
fuck taken those seeds out.
Just thinking that that place had a vibe
where you gotta Kinda know what you're
doing when you go in there.
Similar to that place you took me in New
York.
It's a famous deli,
but I can't remember the name.
Is that where we went?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
We got to know what the fuck's going on.
Or you got to know where the fuck you're
ordering and then where you pick it up.
This is not cut and dry.
Yeah.
But how legitimate that unique place.
I just think very unique to the coast
because like in Ohio we have our own
unique restaurants and food and all that
kind of stuff,
but there aren't places like that where
it's unique to that place.
Unique to Ohio,
there are few places like that,
but it's not a similar style of
experience and is always packed.
Always packed because the food's so
good.
Don't lose your ticket.
How about that for an and how's that for
an interesting restaurant?
Yeah,
it has this weird.
Lose your ticket and try to walk out.
They charge you.
Yeah.
This Mexican joint doesn't do like that,
but the way Katz has it.
Never been.
Katz Deli in New York has been around
since.
Who got it?
It's I want to say more than 100 years
old I think,
or somewhere in the neighborhood of 100
years old,
but when you go in there,
you get a ticket.
Eighteen,
88.
Wow.
That's crazy.
Damn 18,
88 and I bet they ran it.
Just the way they run it now.
You walk in,
they give you a a ticket and then you
walk up to the counters and then this
one guy that cuts up meet another guy
has like pickles and this and they'll
give you like samples a slice off a
piece of brisket for you and you're
like,
Holy Shit.
Slice off a piece of that up.
Astronomy,
corn,
beef.
Their corn beef is off the fucking
charts and you eat it with real American
steak fries.
Yeah.
Every bite of it is just better than
anything else.
So good.
It's so good.
It's one of my favorite cheat meals.
Last time I was there,
I was with there with little Jimmy
Norton and Russel,
not Russel.
Jeff Ross came over and sat down with
us.
I was there with you.
Yeah,
I remember.
That was great.
That was awesome.
I didn't know where those guys just show
up dude.
That was so good.
Well,
Jimmy came to meet us there.
Ross.
We just randomly ran into.
It's awesome.
That place is like.
And there's just no,
there's no
doubting in my mind at least,
that there's something special about a
place that's been used for the same
thing for a long time.
You know,
like a place where you go and you feel
like this place like Madison Square
Garden,
like walking around and Madison Square
Garden.
We did the UFC there.
You're walking around,
you're like,
whoa.
Like this place feels different.
Like it's got a,
a resonance to it,
like maybe it's just my mind being aware
of what an incredible building that is
and all the incredible stars that are
performed there.
But I think it's more than that.
Yeah.
Carnegie Deli is gone.
Yeah,
it closes at the end of 2016.
Oh my God.
As long as they don't close cantors in
La,
I'm good.
I need.
Can't just stay open.
Really.
Fuck Ya.
Not a canter's guy.
You son of a bitch.
This is where he plays the healing
wrestling.
He knows cancers is amazing.
He's like crossing his arms.
So he was a body man.
Really believe that.
Look at him.
When do you go to him?
It was being with me.
Jamie's my real friend by the way.
I live two blocks away from there and
you would have met me there and
complained about the food.
Well,
I mean if we were going after this guy,
tony is a pro wrestling Greenblatt's is
great.
Oh,
how dare
here though.
I was bummed out that they closed the
Jerry's Deli and woodland hills.
Yeah.
Like,
no.
You have to go to and see.
No.
Yeah,
because they closed the one in Beverly
Hills.
That's wrong.
I think they have Manhattan beach now
and Encino.
Those the only two that are left.
That's too bad.
Old School.
Real Jewish Delis like that.
They have the most ridiculous chicken
soup.
Have you ever had jerry's deli chicken
soup?
Chicken soup that dare chicken soup with
Tabasco sauce and black pepper.
Get the fuck Outta here.
Mix that shit up.
Whew.
As it's going down.
You see chunks of juicy chicken in there
with the noodles and the broth is
perfect.
They've been making that bra since Jesus
was around.
Wow.
That's a scientific old,
old old recipe.
The broth there is Jewish food.
They've been making that broth since
Jesus was around.
Allegedly.
I don't know if Jesus is real,
but that brought real as fuck now,
which came first?
Jesus or the broth to.
I'm Tom.
I wonder if they probably chicken soup
forever when you imagine the breath.
No,
no.
You sound of a bitch.
He thought that
that was going to say that you are
focused on.
You were talking about with on rescue
nine slash 11.
Did you know that liberty to officer?
Uh,
toby Malara Turnbull.
Oh,
the whole thing.
It's on youtube to find it.
You knew this guy and he was a dick.
Yeah.
So you think it's bullshit?
Uh,
let's say allegedly.
Yeah.
Let's protect legally.
He,
uh,
Tony speaking,
I have no knowledge of this man.
Whether or not he's honorable or not,
it's not my attention.
See,
that's the cop.
I wondered.
A theory is like his buddy laughing
Adam.
Wow.
Yeah,
that's Toby Malara.
I'll always remember him.
You know what man,
if people find out that they can get
attention from saying that you have
photos are real,
that they saw them,
they'll do it.
I know it from firsthand experience.
I've told this story before,
but I don't know if ever told it to you.
I was doing a show for CBS called gang
show in my head.
And what would they had was they had a
setup where,
uh,
I had an earpiece in and the person who
was a contestant on the show had an
earpiece in and we would set them out in
the middle of somewhere and then start
asking them questions and telling them
what they were they were going to have
to do.
We'd say,
are you ready?
You ready to do this?
Okay,
here is what you have to do.
I told this guy you are a news caster.
Now you showed up to do a story about a
guy who was taken aboard a Ufo,
a person who's taken aboard a Ufo,
but this person's gone.
So you have to find a random stranger to
pretend it was them.
And then tell you a story about getting
taken aboard the spaceship and getting
probed.
And Dude,
people just get it.
It was the weirdest thing ever here.
So here it is.
So this is the young man and this young
man was a look at me.
So,
um,
those aliens.
That's right.
I'd love that to live for you and say
those things on camera you when you have
five minutes with $5,000.
Good luck buddy.
So this dude just walks up to people.
We'll probably get kicked off in two for
using any of those,
but these dude just talk.
Comes up and talks to people and he just
explains it to me.
I'm in a real bad situation.
There's,
there was a Ufo of visualization or
whatever the fuck he says,
and I just need someone to pretend it
was them.
Wow.
Dude.
People do it.
And when they do it,
they started,
they put their shit down and they start
telling a story and not just one guy.
I mean,
he got several people to do it.
Wow.
Yeah.
Listen to the guy while we can't listen
to it.
Right.
You're kicked off.
Can Take it off anyway.
You can go watch it.
People go a game show in my head.
I go it.
The dude's name was craig.
Sorry Craig,
if I can't remember your last name,
but uh,
he got a bunch of people to talk about
being abducted by aliens.
The thing was,
it was so easy to get when people know
that they're going to be on camera,
they,
they get excited.
Like the idea of being on cameras,
like I'll just fucking make some crazy
shit up and then all of us sit back or
like Jane Goodall's,
like I talked to native Americans and
they told me they were probably given
her why.
Try and try and get freaky with her.
Yeah.
Seen bigfoot.
I know where he lives getting high and
shit,
you know,
maybe.
But for real,
maybe bigfoot exists.
If you take peyote and go in the woods,
maybe you could see him.
Maybe you only see glimpse of him.
Maybe bigfoot's a ghost that you only
see when you're on pod.
I think,
uh,
if I'm doing pod in the woods,
I'm definitely seeing big foot on top of
many other things.
Let me ask you this.
If you were,
if you could say with 100 percent
certainty,
like what if you had like a thousand
dollars to gamble?
Okay.
Do you think you saw a ghost or do you
think you just playing tricks on
yourself and then the more you think
about it,
the more you've added stuff to the
memory and fuck with that memory in your
head?
It's actually a little bit scary.
I'm going to be honest with you.
It's a little bit scarier than I even
told you because get this.
That night after I didn't tell anybody
all day,
all of a sudden Jeff Scott,
out of all the nights that I've seen him
there and hung out with them,
they're the house piano player for like
25 years out of all the nights without
telling anybody what I saw earlier.
Not a soul said that he saw that that
night and I'm like,
wait,
what?
What'd you see?
And he's like,
it was like white glowing thing like
that.
And that's when I went,
Dude,
I saw that thing earlier today.
Here.
Oh my God said there's the.
There's the part that I.
Since you want to make it about a
thousand bucks bet.
If I imaginary money,
like that part has to be said out loud
because that's crazy.
We were going to.
I've freaked myself out there before.
Yeah,
bunch of times.
You know what freaks me out the most?
The the belly room when the shows are
off.
Yeah,
that's what I'm saying.
That's where this happened.
It's,
that's,
that's the spot that freaks me out the
most.
And by the way,
because it's really contained.
Yeah.
What not.
I'm not being honest.
The main room when it's dark freaks me
out the most.
The main rooms.
Freaky when it started.
I don't even like him being in the back
of the main room when it's dark there
part of every day.
If you work the phones there,
you have to walk through that when it's
pitch black,
dark to go turn on the lights to turn on
the power breaker for the whole Marquis
and everything.
So you have to go out there like five or
six before it gets dark because the
mark,
he has to
go on.
Before that I had one of them tactical
flashlights,
like the Rockwood and many of his action
films Cook.
You hold it up here.
Look at that.
Like it's a bramble knife and shit.
Yeah.
You know,
looking ahead.
Scary.
Oh,
Jamie's got one right there.
Case Shit hits the fan.
Who are you?
Who goes there?
Yeah,
yeah.
Buildings freaky and that belly arms got
something because it is.
It's contained and you got Mitsis,
unopened,
sealed off office to the other side of
that power.
That's where it's all around Xyz.
Yup.
Sean's ring.
People don't even know about that.
That's like.
Think about all the powerful decisions
took place in that one office.
Yeah.
All the different comedy that revolves
around that one woman running that one
club.
Yeah.
Crazy.
If you really stop and think about it,
what are the odds of that even being a
thing like how does one person who
really knows how to run a comedy club
the way she did,
how they exist when no one else,
no one does it that way,
and I'm not saying there's anything
wrong with the way the other people do
it and some of those other people I love
dearly.
Like I love Bob at the ice house dearly.
He runs a different lot of people run a
different.
What I'm saying is that she did
something that was like,
that's a crazy way to do it.
Let the inmates run the asylum.
Like even that one when she.
She made an adjustment to put him in the
15 year anniversary instead of some
other guy.
Yeah.
Yeah,
and that's what got him the next thing
that got them the next thing that made
him one of the biggest comedy actors
ever.
Yeah,
man.
It's
obviously everything was prior.
Robin Williams,
Andy Kaufman,
blah blah,
blah,
blah.
It goes on and on.
It's stunning to think of how much
comedy comes from the acts of one
person.
The actions of one person.
Look at that ring.
Wow.
You and arranged or something.
Look at that.
It's just crazy.
It's a gigantic black.
What do you think it is?
I don't know how it's black and white
picture.
You think it's Ruby?
Maybe that's something you can never
wear right here.
Think that we would get progressive
enough where you could.
Where Ruby's kit,
where Ruby rings.
How many dudes or any,
any rappers like ultra super floss and
wearing rubies,
rubies whenever we are going to read.
So I'm going,
I'm going to be a new wrapper.
That's my name.
My name is all about rubies,
rubies,
rubies.
Them seems like cultural appropriation.
I'll just say all about Ruby's dem,
dem dem.
Remove this.
Reminds me of the lipstick challenge
that.
Yeah,
the lipstick challenge.
One of my favorite things were high as
fuck at the comedy store and we were
trying to figure out some sort of a
challenge.
And the loser would have to wear
lipstick on stage for a year.
Are you going to have to wear it?
You'd have to wear it for the first 15
minutes of your set.
After that,
you could wipe it off just for the fear
off.
Yeah.
For the first 15 minutes you're set.
You'd have to have like a thing about
wipes,
like sitting there on your,
uh,
on your little stool,
on stage C,
d,
15 minutes of your act with Ruby Red
Lips like Miranda sings.
Do you know Miranda sings?
Yeah.
Pull up a picture of Miranda sings on
Youtube.
She's got a youtube channel and a TV
show or TV.
Show his haters back off.
It's hilarious.
So that's her lips.
You're going to have to do your lips
like that.
Go to a more attractive one right next
to that one.
There you go.
Now go back.
Here you go.
Now go back to that one.
Perfect.
Yeah,
that's it.
See what we're going to do just over
accentuate the lips.
Clearly go above the actual shape of the
lip.
One year old man and you should do a
special about it.
You should do a special say.
This is all my lipstick material that
I'm going to burn off now because my
curse has been lifted one year wearing
lipstick.
Is he wearing Ruby's rappers wearing
Gucci Mane Boi.
Gucci Mane looks so much better now.
It's all finished.
Shit.
It's kind of interesting.
Like he's always smiling too.
Like that dude looks happy as fuck.
Yeah,
he's out of jail.
But also just looks like he's smiling a
lot.
He's like,
it's interesting.
I think like if I saw Gucci and he's in
all these pictures and he's just kinda
like mean mugging,
I'd have this one thought about him,
but instead I see Gucci and all these
pictures now and he's always smiling,
but I bet that guy's a friendly guy,
you know,
he looks like he's having a good time
and he's killing it now.
Out of jail,
right?
Isn't he like.
Yeah.
See even I know he's killing it in the
rap game back.
He just released a new album.
Has got to throw you in jail.
You ever listen to Migos?
No,
I think you'd like them.
Who's Migos?
Migos is like a new suit.
It's like a rap group with three guys
that,
uh,
remember the ganging twins.
So they're like the yanging twins,
but better than like with an extra
member.
Wow.
Powerful.
I think.
I think he would like it.
Migos rings,
they just got and they're like
hilarious.
They're the funniest interviews
showing those rings again.
Go,
go big with that.
That picture with the FIS.
Okay.
Am I looking at it like a half a million
dollars in diamonds?
Yes.
That's real.
Yeah.
That seems crazy to do.
It doesn't seem crazy to be walking
around with a half a million dollars in
diamonds.
Hey,
better to be invested in diamonds than a
bitcoin or something like that.
Right?
No Dude,
that bitcoin shit.
My pop the fuck off.
And you'll be sitting here Hayden.
Yep.
You don't even know.
Right?
I do know one thing about bitcoin.
If you say,
I think bitcoin stupid people want fuck
you up.
Yeah.
If you could talk some shit on bitcoin.
They,
those bitcoin fanatics,
their rabbit.
It's like a little bit of religion just
to touch.
Wow.
Just a sprinkle.
I think it is right?
It has to sprinkle and not necessarily
just bitcoin either,
but there's a bunch of other crypto
coins which I fully support.
I have no a dog in the fight.
Yeah,
me too.
Yeah.
And um,
and we keep five of it,
which is all dedicated to justin wren
and anytime he wants he can cash out.
This is all a from when Antonopoulos
isn't in there.
So I don't really have a stake in it
because that's all justin runs money,
but real investment in Bitcoin is very
fascinating to me because if more people
were interested in doing and it
eventually spread through the entire
contract,
everybody's decided to do it and
everybody figured out how to make it as
secure as regular money is,
which is not that secure.
I mean people steal regular money too.
I think figuring out how to make it more
secure and better than it is now,
which just seems like they would be able
to.
You never know like who's going to be
faster,
the hackers or the programmers.
It seems like only one.
What was the one coin that someone stole
a Shitload of recently?
You were just telling me about 17
million nano was stolen off of an
exchange.
Now what's a nano?
It's a different critic.
That's another critical coin.
Yeah.
So what is the biggest one is bitcoin?
Okay.
What's the second biggest one?
Off of notoriety?
Probably a theory.
I'm going to be the second biggest I
would say.
Do you think it's possible that one day
artists will invent their own crypto
coins and that's how they buy and trade
tickets to shows and goods from the
people that support them.
Like think about this golden pony
dollars,
golden pony dogs is how people pay for
your shows.
You set up like a bank of Golden Polo
Pony Dot Crypto Bank.
I don't know how you do it.
You do some blockchain voodoo magic
programmer type shit figured out how to
do that.
Then once you set that up,
people by that Golden Pony money in
order to be able to pay you golden pony
money for things,
but you only accept golden pony money
and only you can only spend golden pony
money.
So the only people that accept your
money,
the people that accept you if you want
to buy a washing machine,
so I'd like to buy it.
Wasn't Golden Tony Dollars.
They're like,
no,
like you have to like you.
They'd go,
yeah,
Tony,
you're a good guy.
You're funny.
I Really Love Yon Killed Tony and you
stand up special on Netflix was a hoot.
Sure,
we'll let you pay it golden pony dollars
and then you could buy a washing machine
with golden pony dollars and that golden
pony dollars will be traded exclusively
through golden pony fans and so like you
really are reliant upon your fans in a
way different way,
like you're only getting paid by your
fans and when they want out they're like
fuck this golden pony money.
I want to give me some of that.
Sinbad dollars go on some sinbad
shekels,
but they still would have to cash out
with me,
right?
No,
no.
They don't have to cash out with you the
cash out with somebody else's in the
group,
like a certain amount of money to stays
in the group just like they do with
bitcoin.
Like there's a certain amount of bitcoin
that exists and the price of bitcoin
will go up and down,
but the number will not change.
And so that's their remedy against the
modern system that we have with
inflation and printing new money and all
that shit.
So there's only a certain amount of
bitcoin.
I don't.
If I'm butchering this,
I apologize.
I'm not smart.
I have a little variations we appreciate
and so if you did that with golden pony
dollars,
you would set up like a golden pony
fund.
Like this is,
this is the bit coin that I,
you know,
this is,
I've calculated this out with a current
bitcoin prices.
If I charge you guys 20 bucks for this
thing,
whatever the fuck it is,
then whatever you call the number,
the name,
um,
what you'll be able to do is you'll be
able to pay for my shows only using that
dissolve I'm going to accept now.
And then I want to be able to use that
to buy things from your store.
Sounds confusing.
I'm going to let people keep using
normal money.
It's very confusing.
But the idea would be like,
say like,
you have some golden pony dollars.
You got some George Lopez dollars,
you know,
like you could,
there could be a bunch of people with
their own exchanges and it could be
worth something to you worth more or
less depending on how my other killing
it right now.
It's very confusing.
It's super confusing.
What I'm saying is it's entirely
possible that someone like snoop Dogg
who's going to come up with his own
bitcoin,
I could see would have to be someone
super baller that everybody would want
their,
their coin,
you know,
would have to be someone like Kendrick
Lamar dollars.
Yeah.
See if Kendrick Lamar puts out a bitcoin
or cryptocurrency and he says,
hey fans,
this is the only way you could buy
tickets to my shows when I buy shit.
I want to buy shit only with this stuff,
but it's real money.
So if I want to buy a Ferrari with
Kendrick Lamar money better sell it to
me,
bitch,
because that's Kendrick Lamar.
Money is worth gold to all the Kendrick
Lamar fans.
It would have to be somewhat of like a
super,
super high profile to do something like
that.
Some interesting stuff.
It's not really.
You look at your falling asleep.
He's barely staying awake.
For me,
this is sort of sort of describing one
cryptocurrency.
This is called steam or steemit,
which is the website that you can look
at sort of brand.
None of us the way like dig.com.
Look very similar to this,
it's like how that started and so here,
what would happen,
how you,
you would have to exchange some money or
another cryptocurrency to get some
actual esteem,
but here is the,
for instance,
have you have a person put up a really
good article or a piece of content if
you will,
um,
you upvote it and then that person gets
a coin,
are money from you essentially gets
esteem coin.
You upvoted with a coin and that's a
very early or primitive way I guess
describing what you would do.
So like a PR person creates content,
puts it online,
and then the viewers than exchange a
currency for currency only exists in
this,
in this platform,
but yet had then you can exchange.
Then if another exchange anywhere in the
world wants to start up and say like,
I deem your currency valuable,
you can exchange it for my currency or
in another currency.
And that's where that value comes to
see.
Now that makes sense.
And also,
especially if people are paying for
stuff,
like if you're writing things or making
videos or something like that and then
people are paying for that,
that's a fucking,
you know,
we're,
we're trapped in this idea of this
system that we have now as far as like
producers of television shows and movies
and things like that that this is like
how you get a job in show business that
seems like how you get a job at show
business if you can make videos and
people will give you money for those
videos.
Kind of what youtube is and lot of
people have made money off youtube.
We're dealing in dollars and in the old
system,
but this seems like more next level
could be the new system might take over
yet.
Paul.
Fascinating too because it could be a
blog,
right?
It could be a video.
What else could it be?
This could be anything.
This is literally just linked so they
haven't.
I don't think this platform is opened up
to having like its own video hosting or
music being hosted,
but that would be amazing if you could.
Right?
Like cool ass articles and people could
pay you base on the article that might
bring articles back,
man.
I mean not that articles are gone away,
but there's a weird thing right now
where it's hard for people to get paid.
Doing digital stuff is much as most
people don't want to subscribe to.
I shouldn't say it's hard for people to
get paid.
It's hard for people to get people to
pay for digital stuff.
I like to subscribe to an online website
or something done that's a tough sell.
You know?
Medium.com
is sort of filled that hole a little
bit,
but you don't get directly paid from
posting on there.
I don't believe people can get.
Make a medium post that had,
has then gone viral and gotten them paid
in other ways,
like explaining how they do a particular
thing and then that leads to their store
or they can sell some merge that way or
other.
They might make a video that's in there.
Then they get you to money off of that.
It's a.
it's also new,
but that,
that what you're describing could take
off from here.
Well,
it seems like if everybody decides to
accept that currency,
then it seems like it would take off.
Right?
If everybody decided to accept that
currency,
it just seems to me that there's,
if,
if bit.
There's a few tests,
right?
There's bid corn,
there's light coin is,
was that doggy coin,
Doge coin,
Doge coin.
There's a few of those that are still
like volatile and still hanging.
I saw some article recently about these
young guys that were multimillionaires
from cryptocurrency,
like,
okay,
real
the millionaire or multimillionaire and
cryptocurrency.
Like what does it mean?
Same as a stock person because they
might have a bunch of money.
Then it's,
some of it's also in stock,
right?
Could they win?
How quickly could they liquidate?
It?
Somewhat depends on exchanges.
Some of it's 24 hours.
Some of it's a couple days.
It depends on the actual coin and the
way the blockchain works.
Hmm.
Crazy.
Yeah,
it's very crazy.
It's very crazy.
It's,
um,
to be.
When I think about it,
I,
I always wonder how long it's going to
take before we shake ourselves of this
system because this system is good as it
is and it's definitely good.
It's still super complicated and flawed.
It's very confusing.
What's legal and what's illegal and why
you have to pay taxes in one place,
but you crossed the line and the taxes
are way less.
Like what?
Like over here,
you don't pay state taxes at all,
but over there you do what?
Like a lot of this stuff
that we operate,
a lot of the system that we have is
fucking won.
He Shit.
The tax system is just one of them,
right?
Yeah.
It's all messed up and then a lot of
people,
you know,
you can just whatever,
build a account overseas and avoid it
that way.
Well,
it seems to me that
what I was gonna say is that if
something like a crypto currency can
really take off and just get fully
accepted,
you switch to a more accepted now than
it was a few years ago when Antonopoulos
first started coming on here and I think
you could sort of extrapolate that five,
maybe even 10 years from now.
It might be like really commonplace.
There's a lot of things you buy with
bitcoin now.
A lot of things.
It's really kind of interesting in that
way.
No,
that's.
If that works out and crypto coins
become a real thing,
crypto currency becomes a real thing.
It's totally possible that can move into
politics.
That kind of thinking of organizing and
like setting up a party and deciding on
important issues that all could happen
the same way that all could happen
through some sort of an online app where
people say,
fuck all this voting shit.
You know,
we have this new super secure thing that
elan musk figured it out and now
everybody,
all they have to do is have a cell phone
number and they take a photo of
themselves as they're doing it.
So it's biometric,
right?
So you know that someone's not cheating.
You can take a photo of you,
you put in your vote and you do.
You have little videos for each issue.
Can Watch little videos on your phone
tells you exactly what's going on with
these gestures here.
People who are pro it here,
people are content and it's like one of
those things where like if you ever
test,
take a test online,
have you ever done one of them?
The end press send and you press it.
You know all the results,
all you got 90 percent right,
and so you move on.
That could be the same way.
I mean,
it could be something along those lines.
Those things are so easily beatable.
I decided to do that for traffic school.
Get out of a ticket a couple of weeks
ago.
It's so ridiculous.
It tells you which ones are wrong on the
yes or no,
and they're like,
you want to try it again?
And I'm like,
uh,
yeah.
I don't think everyone's smart.
Yeah,
I finished a fun fact.
I finished traffic school.
What's supposed to be this huge test?
And like,
uh,
I don't know,
maybe nine minutes.
Just next,
next,
next.
Take the test.
Whatever.
Then fix the answers.
Done.
They could do that with voting.
Yeah,
they could totally do that with voting.
Yeah.
Hundred percent.
They don't want it.
Didn't want it to be that easy.
And that's when there's going to be real
weird shit were like Logan.
Paul manipulates the vote.
You know what I'm saying?
Like I don't mean it illegally.
I mean like saying,
Hey,
go out and vote for this guy.
You know where Kim Kardashians.
I want you to vote for my friend.
You know,
she wants to run this motherfucker like
a cartoon character becoming the leader.
Black mayor always has the best ideas.
I'm always late to the party.
I think it's coming.
I think Kanye could do it in 20 slash
20.
If he runs,
he'll fall apart.
You don't do well under that of
falling apart.
Could get you the role.
He's not.
He's not that guy.
He's not like that.
Trump guy trump let's that shit roll off
his back.
For most people that stuff devastating
like I don't think it's a coincidence
that Kanye had that event where he
talked about supporting trump that he
would've voted on trump.
That's what he said it and everybody
went crazy and then he went crazy and he
checked himself into a eight days for
eight days in the hospital.
Like it's not good.
Right?
That's,
that's not a person who's good,
who knows what the fuck was going on
outside of that.
But the scrutiny it compounded it with
no question at all.
When a bunch of people are mad at you
and all your fans are mad at you and
then you wind up canceling the whole
tour.
Yeah.
That's,
that guy.
Shouldn't you know,
obviously shouldn't be president,
but I don't even think she's try.
I just don't think.
Just seems like a lot of pressure for
them.
And these fucking great musician make
your awesome music.
And music don't run for president.
Like when do you think we're ever going
to get off of this?
Like people keep saying,
you know,
Alec Baldwin,
you can actually run and win for the
Democrats came.
Maybe could you might be right.
He might be able to totally put when.
When do we say,
hey,
we need.
We need to rethink this whole fucking
system.
We can't keep letting popular people run
the country.
That's crazy.
I have to do is to be popular.
I like him more.
The whole thing.
That's been the thing forever.
It's weird.
It doesn't make any sense.
Shouldn't you have to take a test?
And we find out who would be best at
running the country.
Like shouldn't it be a test?
Like there's a test for the driver's
license for graphics test for traveling
school.
Why is there a test for president?
Shouldn't it?
You'd be like,
Shit.
You have to have some good answers to
some questions.
They pose it you.
It's the most ridiculous job ever
because it was.
It was created so long ago that has so
many holes in the idea behind it.
Like you don't have to eat at least know
how to run the country like Pe.
Shouldn't.
People know the results of your test?
You should take a test and the people
say,
look,
we've got good news and bad news.
The good news is he can read.
The bad news is he got everything wrong.
He got everything wrong.
You can't be president.
Like,
oh,
all right,
well we got to find a guy who could pass
the test is also popular.
Then people will try to cheat for them.
Yeah,
you can keep
budget.
Who can speak?
Who Can Obama at least taught Congo
Gresh or constitutional law?
At least I think he would know a lot
constitution.
I would imagine those quite a bit.
Heard of trump university.
My friend got a whole universe.
Lawson.
He had his own university.
How many lawsuits are involved in that?
Don't know how many.
I think it became a class action.
You had to pick $25,000,000
or something.
Sorry,
what was trump university?
It was a,
uh,
like a one minute left.
Jamie.
Yeah,
because it was like a real estate.
They show you how to turn and burn and
flip houses and businesses and they show
you how to become a real estate mogul
for profit education company that ran
real estate training program for five
years.
Was it any good?
Uh,
like where the sort of success stories
out of it.
I don't know.
It was licensed by trump university by
owned by trump organization,
but not owned by the trump organization.
Probably a different LLC or something.
Oh,
go multiple lawsuits.
What a interesting idea.
Who's just going to teach people how to
make money?
So the idea.
Yeah.
It seems like one of those infomercials
or something like that.
He's a fucking character.
I'll tell you that when all is said and
done,
that will be a guy that stands out in
human history.
We're going to look at that guy and go,
wow.
I think that's what he wanted.
He definitely got that.
Do you think he's going to want to run
again?
Oh my God,
yes.
Are you kidding me?
This is what this guy lives for.
He lives for watching the news and
seeing him on it every day.
Is that what they think?
I'll show them that this whole thing.
It's so real.
Everything from the insight and
everything I've ever heard about.
The guy says that,
that he's just.
I mean,
how much longer do you think you could
do it?
At what age do you start to get worn out
by all this shit?
Right.
We think of the kind of hate Kanye got
for supporting trump.
Now think of the kind of hate trump
gets.
It is some next level stuff.
I mean the you have to have some crazy
resolve to be able to absorb that kind
of.
Hey,
you got to be a little insulated from
some of it though,
I'm sure.
But they might hide him from some of it,
but some of it they actually project on
his building.
You know,
they project it on his building.
They stand across the street with a
projector.
Isn't even dealing with that forever
though.
Not that I don't think so.
Wwe Hall of Famer,
by the way,
isn't he?
Yeah,
he's been in stone.
Cold.
Stunned.
He's been stone cold stone.
Yeah.
He was in a stone cold stunner.
How's that?
Go down,
you don't want to know this one.
Now I'm going to be honest with you,
joe,
out of all the one of the many pro
wrestling moves that don't seem to be
effective.
This is way up there and the devastation
that leaves like guys are like out for
like a minute after a stone cold stunner
and it's pretty bad.
I'm going to be honest.
I love stone cold.
One of the greats ever.
Probably the reason why we have the rock
is because stone cold was so raw and a
dirty on the mic.
Let me ask you this,
and I want you to be real.
You think that this stone cold stunner
existed?
Why?
Because he lost a haircut match between,
uh,
Vince and,
between Vince and trump won was going to
get zapped.
And Bobby Lashley.
Yeah.
See,
I know my shit dude.
Hell yeah.
You do.
So the stone cold stunner Steve Austin
as his arm up in the air column for cans
of Beers.
That's another thing is every time still
with cans of beer,
they drink it and they let him go drink
one in the middle of the fight.
He doesn't really know fights over
fights book.
He's about to cheers.
Donald trump.
Steve Wiser.
Okay.
Why is he wearing a shirt?
See,
wrestling has rf in this.
He was a ref,
but he's still about the stun.
Here you go.
Boom.
He hit some.
He lands on his butt,
but your head is on his shoulder and
it's supposed to just put you out.
Wait a minute,
one more time please.
Just so odd.
So I stepped forward.
Let's get a good angle.
Find the wine.
Boom.
Bam.
Jamie.
There's one were stone cold like stuns
every mcmahon and everybody in a ring.
Like there's,
there was one epic one.
Were you stunned like 30 guys in a row?
It might be one of the faker things
ever.
I've seen you repost some of bad things
that have been happening.
Feeling it hurts every time.
Well,
you know,
you need higher quality,
uh,
stuff out there.
See,
that's a stunner.
That's a stunner right there.
Technically.
Yes.
Boom.
Oh,
come rock knew how to sell that.
Kaine.
That's the undertakers brother.
Goodbye.
Yeah,
the rock made it fun.
Right?
Like it didn't seem realistic.
I read a thing recently about how the
peoples elbow,
which became his big finishing move and
it was sort of a joke that worked so
well with the crowd that they all just
laughed about it backstage and it just
became this fucking.
Okay.
Let me tell you something.
If this guy did this to actually do the
suit,
it would not feel good to.
This is,
this is not a real finishing move per
se,
but that could fuck you up.
Especially a big strong guy.
Like you're not that one,
not that one,
but some of them.
Because what he's doing is he's grabbing
the back of your head and slamming his
shoulder into your chin.
Yeah,
like,
that's semi legit.
Like I would not recommend doing it that
way.
We'll look at the rock by laughing.
Stood up after he got some.
Uh Oh,
look at this.
That's Shane Mcmahon.
But we play that one again.
Boom.
Oh,
that's hilarious.
Classic Mcmahon thing to oversell like a
stunner like that.
Like Vince does it the best.
He convulses and shakes afterwards.
Definitely have that though.
Because you're given the guy you're
back.
Yeah.
I don't recommend that at all.
That move now.
He could probably do it to me.
Yeah,
but that would hurt.
I'm telling you that's not.
It's not the best move in the world.
No,
but it's not 100 percent legitimate.
There's brock.
Now.
This is Shane Mcmahon.
This is actually.
Oh,
really insane thing that this guy did.
Tony,
do you know Shane right now is probably.
If I had to guess,
I'd say a 47.
No,
he's not jumping off about 30 feet.
Thirty five feet up at least probably.
I don't know if they actually say,
but get the fuck out of Shane Mcmahon
always does this.
He is like,
wait a minute,
wait a minute onto a table.
Come on a real table.
The undertakers about don't move.
Either way.
It's not a pad.
The undertakers like,
don't do it,
dude.
I'm not going to show it to you.
Oh,
I see.
Dot.
Yeah,
don't show it on Youtube.
So he lands on that thing,
so it's a giant spring underneath them.
Now.
What is that thing?
It's just a breakaway table at home.
Mine.
It hurts.
That's insane that he did that and we
all thought he was pretty messed up
here.
Oh my God.
That's insane.
Why did he do that Shit for the show?
Oh my God.
That guy had to get really hurt.
If you get knocked out,
uh,
he might be.
Might be coming out of it.
We,
that's one of the crazy things.
You just never know what's real and
what's not.
Why got it?
Yeah.
Mankind did that.
Mick Foley,
the guy who does the mandible claw,
he did that to the undertaker.
Once he had a tooth go through his lip.
Let me ask you this,
when someone does something like that,
like did they plan that out to the point
where they practice it or they just wait
to the moment and then do it?
Because that seems like a.
If you practice it and it hurt that bad,
I think they might practice it maybe
with some type of something,
but I don't think they practice it with
a breakaway table and these guys are
fighting on top of the roof.
This is the craziest one ever.
This is Helen is sell 1998.
Mankind is the undertaker.
This is crazy.
Undertaker ends up choking,
slamming him through the whole thing
into the ring from the top.
But you think you know more about pro
wrestling than I know about boxing.
Well,
it's a.
it's a wide field.
I think there's more in wrestling
history.
You got to realize wrestling.
Wrestling's been a weekly sport,
the most watched program on cable every
Monday since I was a little kid.
So there's a lot more stuff that's
happened in pro wrestling.
Right.
But you know results,
right?
Yeah.
Like if I told you,
I mean,
do you know any results from boxing a
little bit?
You know,
way more about this than you know about
boxing,
right?
Yeah.
You find that weird.
No,
I'm pretty big boxing fan.
I probably had more than one.
Threw them off the top.
Yeah.
They go.
Jesus Christ.
Yeah.
Where's he throw them onto?
And by the way,
that's the first time anything like this
ever happened.
So that crowd is literally like,
what?
Blah Blah Blah.
Okay.
I go fucked up.
Yeah.
Like he got fucked up for real.
I don't think you can fall that far.
Knock fucked up unless you're in falling
into a giant pillow.
These guys aren't falling.
Oh my God.
No.
Mick Foley has like broken every bone in
every injury you can imagine.
Oh my God.
You see?
That
seemed to do a back flip and land right
there.
Fuck that dude.
Oh,
water's good.
So that's a good move.
So they're doing it like that Ninja
show.
That's obviously.
It was on boxes.
Obviously.
That's protected.
That's so funny.
The whole dramatic thing that girls are
going,
oh my God.
Oh my God.
And the guys.
They're macho.
Yeah.
He just felt fucking cage.
It fell through this gauge.
Oh my God.
Is that supposed to happen?
Was that an accident?
No,
I don't know.
That may be.
Was supposed to happen the way it falls.
He fell into the center.
I bet it was to happen because see how
the center sort of gave in now how would
they engineer something like that.
How will they make sure that they're
okay?
Like this is like a combination.
Oh my God.
I broke her leg.
Did he?
I think so.
Oh,
don't show me.
This show is canceled.
Can't watch somebody breaking their leg
for a play as essentially a play magic.
There's a play where you break your leg.
I mean,
remember when people were criticizing
Spiderman,
spiderman,
musical people,
kept flying off the harnesses and
slamming into the crowd or something.
I think somebody might have died.
Oh yeah.
Um,
severe injury at the very least.
What happened during Spiderman musical?
Because that's.
I think they got it wired though.
Think they figured it out or don't show
it to me,
bro.
Please show.
I don't want to see the god.
Oh fuck.
The thing snapped.
Roped didn't work.
Oh my God.
Jesus Christ.
Wow.
Oh my God.
It's going to have to a PD die.
Now this accident,
Spiderman doesn't want to say that.
There's more than one accident.
Yeah.
I thought it kept happening.
That's why they had to stop.
Yeah.
I want to say there was a second
accident that I might have been making
this up.
This video I just pulled up here as the
fourth accident.
Oh,
Jesus Christ.
The Lord Right now.
Stop and think about how many accidents
they have in the pro wrestling world all
the time.
Yeah.
Arenas week,
multiple arenas per week.
So yeah.
And how many of those things must go
wrong in those arenas?
People have died.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Allen Hart.
Fuck.
You know about Owen,
right?
Yeah.
On the entrance.
A character.
He didn't even want to play.
Dude.
Hard way to make a living.
Yeah.
All right Tony,
let's wrap this bitch up and head out to
Bakersfield Hollow Bakersfield tonight.
Where are we?
Fox Theater?
Yeah.
I don't know.
Two shows tonight.
Bakersfield to shows tomorrow in Fresno.
And then Santa Barbara on Saturday
night.
Yeah,
I was hoping you going to join in and
ric flair.
Oh,
I didn't realize this.
You're doing.
Yeah.
Woo Bye
everybody.