Finally,
Jesus Christ,
the Joe Rogan experience is brought to
you by [inaudible] dot com that's o,
n n I t, makers of a Alpha brain
and shroom tech, shrink tech,
sports room, tech, immune
and mostly summary. Uh,
we started carrying battle ropes and
kettle bells and if you're interested in
getting fit and doing some manly type
shit, there's no manly more cave band.
Conan the barbarian type shit and throwing
ropes around and lift in Canon balls
with handles home. It's what I do
for all my strength and conditioning.
All I do is I do chin ups,
I do body weight squats and I do a bunch
of crazy exercises with kettle bells
and it's fucking fantastic.
It's the best I've ever found as far
as things that translate directly to
athletic activities. I don't think
there's anything better than kettle bells.
I think it's one of the most phenomenal
ways to exercise in the world you're at.
You're supporting a,
a big heavy ball of steel iron rather,
and you're supporting them with your
body and going through all these
complicated motions.
And it,
what it does is it makes your body work
as one unit instead of just doing bicep
curls and shit like that.
And it makes your body strong as one unit.
So it works in a natural way when you
have to use it for sports. Do you should,
uh, if you're, if you're interested in
Kettlebells, we'd sell them as cheap as,
as humanly possible and they are
the best quality available there.
Troy kettlebells and these motherfuckers
will be here after nuclear bombs go off
in the super volcano erupts.
They're huge, they're the,
they have these big fat handles
on them and they're there.
The really the perfect kettle bells,
you can't get any better and
they will last you forever.
You buy these fucking things,
they never break and you keep
them for the rest of your life.
It's really that simple and it's an
awesome investment as far as fitness goes.
And the new tropics, all the Alpha
brain and shroom tech, all that stuff.
If you're interested in it,
we have a 100% money back guarantee
on the first 30 pills. If you try it,
you don't like it,
just you just,
you don't even have to return your
product to get your money back.
The reason being is that we want
no one to ever feel ripped off.
We want to make sure that we're selling
you only the very best quality shit and
stuff that we think you're,
you're absolutely going to enjoy.
There's a bunch of science behind it,
a bunch of experiments and tests and
different trials that have gone on about
the various ingredients. If you go to
[inaudible] dot com that's o and n and it,
there's all sorts of information. Use a
code name, Rogan, save yourself 10% off.
All Right, ladies and gentlemen,
buckle. Buckle the fucking Andrew dice.
Clay is here. Ladies and gentlemen,
Cube's music. Brian, let's make it up.
Experience
[inaudible].
Ladies and gentlemen,
we have with us,
not just Eleanor Kerrigan,
not just Max Silverstein,
but Andrew dice clay as well.
This is a fucking phenomenal show.
You're so strong in everything.
In the meantime, I can't get the
coffee to come out of my car.
There's something wrong with the lid
that you got to pull the lid back.
Oh really? I thought that
was right. Does that happen
trying to drink it? Is it a faulty
one? Oh I didn't see them lifted.
Yeah. Can everybody just
be Starbucks? Why does it,
it's like Cain gorgeous,
isn't everything
pumpkin. That was pretty easy.
That's, that's sad. She's, she's
now,
you know why I got around?
One of the things that I enjoy
about being around you, man,
I said life is theater 24 seven.
I don't know why you say
it's the end of the dressing room.
It was,
you're a fun fucking dude to be
around and I've liked that about you.
I've really learnt that about Yo cause
we didn't know each other that well and
now we've become what I would call
friends. You'll have to look friend,
not be honored text.
We text all caps.
No, no, I have to do it that way
or else I can't see what I'm doing.
So it's not like you know
how they say when you text,
you can make the lord the font larger.
I've, that's what I've had to do.
I don't use that kind of phone. I don't
use that. Oh, you don't use an iPhone? No.
How dare you? I use commando. Commando.
You could talk 300 feet under water with
it. Oh, is it one of those Verizon ones?
Crazy ones. So let's say
you've got one for a disaster.
You're having a fight with a guy, right?
Right, right. And you were on the beach.
Everyone into the water. I go underneath
that could call the cops and say,
I've got a problem over here.
I mean,
what a fucking making phones to
talk on the water. Got It. Yeah.
I thought about going that way.
I tried it in my pool.
It's like I think of what do you want to,
what kind of car do you like to drug?
Do you draw like to drive a sports car
or do you want to drive like a military
Humvee? I mean you've got two
different ways and looking at things.
One is I'm going to just assume that
these roads are going to be like this and
then I can get around on him pretty
easy and just [inaudible] it's fun.
Or I can pretend that the shit could hit
the fan and every moment and all of a
sudden I'm driving through the fucking
desert. That's what I like. Fine.
Racketing eat to stay alive.
I like an industrial
trucks. I do one. Yeah.
Big fucking machine. Stay
back. I got a challenge it too.
But that to me is an industrial sports
because you have one of the new ones.
Yeah, that's what is the black
stripe. They nailed that car.
They really like replicated
a seventies muscle car. They,
they get it though.
So listen dage throw me a favor here.
Make like, um, the
convertible version. Nothing.
Nothing will be cooler than that. And
convertible. Yeah. You think you're right?
Yeah. Like the tutor convertible guy
that that's going to do this already
10 years. I mean camair
rod does it. They all,
it's a fucking challenge at the top
down. Yeah. What the fuck? Dodge. Really,
what is that?
Right?
Every time
you open the Sunroof,
you want to close it because the sun's
now beating on you through this little
fucking old, either one. It
open and not open talking.
When I'm done talking,
you start to question,
ask it when I'm done. 24, seven no,
he's got to know how to, you know, keep
them in line. Keeping in line the a,
the four 27 corvette is the
best American car available now.
Have you seen that now? But to me that's
too, I like a big muscle doom this.
They took,
uh,
they finally took the Xeo six suspension
and Xeo six engine and they put it in a
convertible zero six was the
fucking race car and that was,
they took a regular corvette and then
the zero six was 505 horsepower and
fucking racing suspension,
big fat, almost slick tires.
It's the craziest car ever. And now
they're making it as a convertible,
which is the first time that cafe brand
and the publicists, but publicists,
he's got, he's got that does Corvettes
are ridiculous. They're ridiculous.
Call the band, but then it's getting out
of it. That's the hard part. Well it's,
you know, it's also a plastic car
because everything is broken. Everything.
Everything from disintegrating
feet, shoulders, you know.
Well in a way that disintegrate.
Well I think a mother or father time.
Fuck it is.
I know when I close my face every night
going to open my hand. Wait, let it,
it snaps. Doesn't you are
wearing gloves though? No, no.
It's even worse when there
were no gloves on. Yeah,
like the joints get stiff and
then they got to like pop open.
Did you really start wearing gloves
because it's like this for three hours.
because too many people were shaking your
hands? You were worried about like getting
sick or, I don't mind shaking hands,
I just can't take sweaty hand.
Yeah. You know what I mean?
So I invented a way to shake hands
without actually touching skin to skin.
No. Because you know a lot of people
today, I mean look up me dressed,
how sloppy they are with the
genes that they look like.
They're going to take half a shit out
of that page as the walking down the
street with the flip flops,
the hygiene with their hands,
they probably get the fingers in that
that Reyes crack half the time I scratch
them and then using the keyboard. Right.
You know what I'm talking about. I know.
You know what I'm talking. Oh, I
know what you're talking about.
Shake a lot of hands.
Well, so you're with me.
When the in the disdain of people who
wear their fucking pants buckled around
their dick, it's sickening. There
is a problem with that folks.
That is just stupid and people have
said, man, you're so wrong dude.
You just fucking, you just talking
shit about style. You're being silly.
You know nothing sexy about it.
It's not style.
That is crazy pants. It's
not lazy. It's insane.
I know when I see a girl or a guy walking
around like they took a dump in that
pant. It's the last thing I want
to talk to. Yeah, they are one.
There's something
about it that just shows that all you
have to do is get one charismatic person
to do something and then every
asshole wants to follow them.
So must've been just one probably bad
ass black dude out of prison to sag his
pants and kept sagging his pants and
then all of a sudden all these fucking
dorks want to copy that guy and it's
become like this thing and the belt buckle
where they back up. They literally are
buckling their belt over there. Dick like,
you silly. Fuck. You can't even walk.
What do you hobbling yourself? It's like,
this is way worse than anybody could
make fun of a woman doing by wearing high
heels.
Like at least a woman in high heels can
kind of kick her shoes off if she has to
run. You know what I mean? Those things
aren't high to get off, but if you,
if you're wearing your fucking belt,
buckled around your deck,
if somebody wants to beat your ass, you
really don't have a whole lot of options.
You're going to get,
you're gonna get your fucking ass kicked
unless you want to fight naked by the
time you get those pants off, that
good is gonna beat the shit out of you.
You can't even walk right
up your last suit. Joey,
Joey, Joey, Jay, my nickname
field. Jay. Thank you.
And we don't talk about with
the j mean and by the way,
I need to get a pair of sunglasses.
The violence that the prescription though.
Bad ass though. Those are, I don't
give a fuck sunglasses and I don't,
I know you don't. I don't.
That's why you got those two classes
of perfect for you Joe [inaudible]
Spiderman. We will get,
I'm glad. Let me just say,
we went to see dice in Vegas and it is
one of the rare times that I ever get a
chance to go to see a show actually said
you haven't sat down and watched the
car showing you is,
well it had been about a year in the
last time was Norton before that.
Maybe I caught Louis
C k two at the Improv.
But you know to go out per on purpose.
We're going to go to Si dice tonight.
We're going to go see a show like on
purpose and me and Norton and Bobby Kelly
and Anthony [inaudible] and Sam Roberts
and all my God that we have a good
fucking time. It was so
fun. It was, first of all,
your assigned was fucking great.
It was hilarious. You know,
it was just perfect. Oldschool dice and
I think Anthony said, he goes, he goes,
it's beautiful. He's like,
it's still dice, but it's new.
Like it's like the same old dice.
Yeah, it's fresh
material. Well, with this,
we haven't gotten talking about the
special yet, but my whole idea was,
all right, I want to give them
all this new generation stuff,
technology all the way to the fucking pig.
So they walk around with that.
Plus he's at today. I wanted to
give him all that newest stuff,
but yet I want you to put some of the
classic dice stuff that the newer fans
don't know and pepper
that and into the act.
So that's why I think he
enjoyed it because you want
to watch and somebody that
all of a sudden is about politics. You
come to see somebody like myself, boy you,
you know, we're a certain
brands, so people expect that.
And that's what I like doing. Yeah.
You know what I mean? You know, I,
you know all these comics today that
are going to bullshit about, you know,
one little thing
they might've sent on stage and
then it's a media event. You know,
it's like the one thing I will,
I will let the media know is when my
special is, I'm not thinking of them.
I'm thinking of the people that really
want to laugh from my brand to Yuma.
I don't care how I say it. I don't give
a fuck what I say to them. You know?
And I'm not apologizing for a fucking
word out of my mouth and I loved that.
I now want to do,
I loved that.
I think it's one of the most important
things in comedy is that there's someone
like you that says that because from
my personal opinion as a standup comedy
fan,
as a connoisseur of Standup,
I never thought you'd got the credit that
you deserved amongst comedians because
there was a lot of backlash about your
material where they were saying like, oh,
it's sexist. So, oh,
it's homophobic and it is a
legitimate style of comedy.
You're saying ridiculous shit
and it's fucking hilarious.
And if you can't recognize
that as an art form,
that's your ignorant problem.
It's not that the materials that it's,
that's the funny shit to say.
It gets fucked up.
Gay Say something ridiculous if course,
you know what I medically sound advice.
I've had people walking out
of my show welcome, you know,
cause it in Vegas sometimes they calm
certain people's Holly writers, whatever.
So people have walked out that they
didn't like that I said the word fag.
They go,
he calls gay people FHEG and it's like,
what's the fucking difference?
It's the point I'm making. Yeah.
You know what I mean? You're not making
it hurt. You know, point, you know,
these are just different words to say.
Do they have an alternative sex style?
Yeah,
I don't give a fuck what they do.
I don't care if they want to suck dick
all the way to the fucking bus station.
That's their choice. But if I'm
doing a bit fake is the word I use.
It works better for me than the word
gay or queer or alternative fucking
lifestyle. They suck Dick on
each other and that's okay by me.
I don't want to suck Dick.
And if I date,
I'm telling you right now and have a
hundred Cox laying on my face right now
because that's how much it, if I want
it, cause that's how I am about girls.
You know what I mean? I like
pussy. It's who I am. You know? So,
so if I'm saying a word like fig,
I'm saying it because that's the
word that works best than the act.
Dumb Herrera had the best
line ever about BNK goes, Joe,
I wish I was gay just so I could come out.
That's how little I give a fuck.
Is that fucking quit as
Angela Delmarva area?
He saw just silly man.
Yeah.
Who fucking cares style comedy.
And I always hold thing about comics,
like being on truck, you know,
I went through it, I went through it
in a big fucking way. I mean this guy,
but you went through it in a time where
there wasn't that many people doing it
and you sticking to your guns and keeping
your character the way you've always
kept in the inner psychiatrist
ship facades did it? No,
no, but almost, you know, no, I've,
I've done the therapist actually
when my career took off,
I went to a therapist in New York to
see how to handle my family because they
got so, you know, because it
happened so quick, you know,
from the clubs to the arena thing
that, you know, my parents and my,
my whole family was so excited. It's all
they talk about. So I would be like, look,
I know what I'm doing but let's
talk about other things. You know,
I didn't want it to be 24 seven about
me. You know, when I'm on stage,
when I'm working on projects,
I do think constantly of what I'm doing.
But when it's downtime,
like when we came back,
I just got done shooting a half the
woody Allen movie that I'm doing.
And so the other night Max is,
you know,
it was sitting outside in
the front porch and he goes,
was sitting with my wife Valerie, and
he goes, let's put on the uh, you know,
the video camera, what we filmed. And I
said, you know what, now's not the time.
I need a few days just to be myself now.
I don't want to just stay on the movie
and watch everything and see me more.
It's like, you know, just staying grounded
in what's the most important thing.
Well,
to me that's the whole thing with fame.
That's why a lot of these guys go
nuts because it's 24, seven of them.
So it's going to drive you
nuts if you're not grounded.
Like I won't even live in the hills.
I need to see people,
I need to be like more on the street,
like if I was in Brooklyn, right.
Because when you make you, when
you isolate yourself, you know it,
it just makes you just think of you
and like, yeah, look at my house,
look at my yard, but I don't see any
people. Right. And that's no good for me.
I got always feel people. Yeah. And that's
also where you come up with material,
cause I hate most people
around them is to,
so you, you are around people because
you hate most people. Well I like,
I hate,
you know what I mean about,
you know when you get in traffic and you
just make a move and they look at you
like they own the fucking street.
Well you know,
you know if you had to Starbucks and you
take too long to order a fucking coffee,
they're looking at you like,
doesn't he know the fucking menu that
I want to fucking club them to death?
You know what I mean? Like gimme the
30 so why do I feel panicked? You know,
even at an airport,
why do you have to feel panicked to
put your fucking shoes in a basket that
somebody is looking like
doesn't he know the routine?
Why do I got to rush every fucking move?
But that's where our material comes from.
And then on stage I blow
it out comedically. But
in real life, like I said,
you want a club day ahead
through to fucking feet,
but you like being around them.
You gotta be around them,
you gotta be around them to live life.
Yeah,
you have to do definitely do
a certain amount of it. But I,
I definitely need decompression too.
You know when I light a cigarette is
Starbucks and I'm sitting outside and they
stopped fucking coughing. You
know, they're stock quote.
You ever get up in la about six in the
morning where you can't see the fucking
sky because the fucking dirty smog.
It's feet above your fucking
hedge. True. But my cigarettes,
the one knocking you out. Golf.
Fuck yourselves outside the fuck.
Anybody that don't like my cigarette,
fuck you.
And the horse you fucking wrote in. The
only time I really want, I mean, oh no,
it dealt with me enough. They see the
shit. That's true. He does get the looks.
That's great. The cigarette is
like lighting. You would have been,
what do you think about
laws?
They're passing where you can't smoke
outside certain said. You know what?
I'll tell you how I feel about
the fucking lawyer right now.
I don't know why I got in this mode
the other night. Like I told you,
I just got done. I was in San Francisco
doing the, a woody Allen movie,
which actually Louis C K is.
And also, what is the movie?
Tell us about the movie.
He doesn't like it to heavy role.
Okay.
The heaviest dramatic role I've
ever played in my life. And,
and it, you know, doing
scenes with Cate Blanchett,
like you standing there going, I can't
believe I'm even working with this.
Like how the fuck did this happen?
They kicked me out of,
I got banned from every
studio. That was, you know,
I made sure to just destroy my career.
But she didn't, she didn't know nothing.
But cause you're always funny,
you never really destroyed it.
You were always funny, you
know, went through this weird
hiatus where people, uh,
just to bring my kids up and who doesn't
like that fuck them because they're not
parents,
you know?
But the thing is talking about the
smoking with the night we got done,
me and Max were staying
at the four seasons,
went to this four star
restaurant to celebrate,
had some like champagne type stuff.
And at the end of the meal I
just lit up a cigarette. No,
let us restaurant. And Max
is looking at me, gone, Dad,
we're all right. Don't worry.
There's hardly any people.
And then the way that comes over, if the
few minutes ago, can you do me a favor?
Get me an ashtray. You know? And
he's looking at, he goes, oh,
you can't smoke in here. And I'm
done with it. You know, Shit.
Put it on the floor or get a glass
of water. You know what I mean? Yeah.
And it just felt good to have a
cigarette and a restaurant again.
Well as a nonsmoker. I going to tell
you that Shit's disgusting restaurant.
It's fucking completely disgusting.
Outside of couldn't get her last. Yeah,
but it sounds like was a big restaurant.
Yeah.
Well outside of wouldn't
like it if there was like,
but I've never done in front of my kids.
But you know,
I mean it depends on like where you're at.
It's the only place I,
I light up now and then is in a mall.
You know what I mean?
Because I don't feel they should have
that lawyer and nice and people know I
smoked so they should just
leave me the fuck alone.
You well with all these new laws to
be in past, that's probably terrorism.
They could probably tase you.
You,
you know how all this shit
about yesterday's podcast,
the thing that I've been getting the
most shit about his tasering I said that
some guy runs in the field and fucking
cops are trying to chase a macbook at the
cop could blow his fucking knee out.
You could eat, you could blow a disc.
Try and tackle some dude.
Am I going to in a bit like if you,
if you think it's not
a big deal of tackle,
a dude is trying to get away from you.
You never really tackled a dude's trying
to get away from you and not knowing if
that dude has weapons. Joy, you
can break of your body. Okay.
Tasering looks fun. I
still have it hand it. Uh,
if you want to run out on the field and
fuck with a game in front of 2 million
people and all the
assholes, you know? Yeah.
And it's a safe way to take somebody
down. If you were a cop, sorry, Dick said,
sorry.
Dick.
Head to when somebody is trying to break
into his house and a cop tasers them.
There'll be thanking his fucking ass.
I don't know who said it, but fuck
silly. Cribbing buddy. Let's point
up thing. Go to cop did dish.
So just one thing. Yeah. You
be in those neighborhoods and,
and want to have to get home to your kids
that night. You'd do what you gotta do.
That's it. Well, I think
a lot of them have,
so it's a lack of better
than shooting somebody. Yeah.
I think a lot of them have massive
amounts of pressure built up that we can't
even understand as a person.
We don't have to deal with violent
crime on every fucking on a daily basis.
We don't know what kind of build
up those guys have. And by the way,
I think he should be fucking mandatory.
They should actually learn how to fight.
You know, I've met dude's in the work
cops and I met him in Jujitsu class.
I'm like their first day and I'm like,
Holy Shit son,
you're a white belt and
you're a cop like you.
You better learn how to strangle some
fucking people. Like you're going to,
you know, someone might want
to try and take your gun.
Do you know that that can happen.
You better learn how to fight, bitch,
are you crazy?
You're going to go out there with a gun
and a fucking target and you don't even
know how to fight.
And I don't know how much they teach them.
I don't know how much it's,
it's a dedicated to hand to hand combat.
But coach should be your whole job.
Hand to hand combat and
how to hold on to your gun.
That should be like all your training.
Totally the filing. It's true.
But listen man,
I'm just aware
motherfuckers out there.
Let's talk about show you just did the
theater in a way where you just Denver
the paramount theater in Denver. Yeah.
Fucking awesome. And how was that for you?
Oh it was, cause I like interviewing
you too. Oh it was amazing. You know,
now you're doing these big theaters,
which you know a little from
everything you've been working on.
It's all from the [inaudible] know how
great you know this podcast is and what
you could do for yourself.
You know,
because my whole thing has always
been about accomplishment in life.
And look what you're doing
now. I mean, you know,
five years ago I think
he was still in clubs.
Now you're doing these big theaters and
two years ago it was mostly doing club.
And that's commendable. I mean you're
doing two, three, 4,000 seaters now.
And that's of course it is because
she put in the work and it's,
I'm proud of you brother.
Thank you very much.
I mean I had done some theaters in the
past besides breaking limbs on cops in
between. You go and do concerts
and that's a good thing.
I just want to help the cops. No,
I know you though. I know a lot.
A lot of cops in MMA.
I know a lot of cops because of a Jujitsu.
So I would like when,
when everybody people shit on cops.
I've always been wanting to defend
cops. That's a, that's a really,
really hard job. You know, I've talked
to people, I've heard horror stories,
Kaiser on the job and they're not
trying to be assholes, but if you,
you lived a life where your job all day,
people were lying to you all day.
People align you and try
to get away with shit.
That's like most of the time if
you're talking to somebody that you,
when I was growing up there with three
things that either want them to be doing
what I'm doing now, a cop or an attorney,
and you know how it changed my mind.
I'm being a cop.
When I would take the train in
Brooklyn every day into Manhattan,
what pricks people would
just to fucking take a seat.
How they would just knock
out of the fucking way. I go,
I don't want to protect these
motherfuckers. I want to kill him.
You know what I mean? So that changed my
mind on net, you know, and the attorney,
well, let's face it, my schooling just
wasn't up to par, but he's good at,
he's good. Yeah. I could dissect.
I don't fight with him. Hell you,
it's horrible. I know how to
break it down like an attorney.
Even when my kids,
when they were really little,
I used to have like an argument and take
them in the living room and I'd sit him
down and I go, okay, we're going to
have the trial. There was horrible.
Oh remember we remember what the
bathroom in my bedroom in the house dead,
Eh, that I led the LRE
stay at? No, no, no,
no, no. A Valerie owner. Alright.
Sometimes I call it valid or,
and she's Ellery gets fucked up.
So there was this towel rack in
my bathroom and one day, you know,
near the shower I come in and it's broken.
So you know,
I got a Mac so I'm going to do and I go,
well who broke the rack?
Nobody's admitting it. So now the
trial has to happen, you know,
and I just break down where they
were, what they were doing. Dylan,
it's still going on the trial.
Still going on years later I'm going
to get to the bottom of it and then the
punishment will happen because
I'll break their towel rack.
But I liked that Max is staying quiet
about it. He's not, yeah, he's not,
he's not ratting on his brother and
he's not well listen, first of all Max,
he knows he's got a great roll
the dice man. Like literally,
literally you've got a
great roll the dice in life.
I mean your father is Andrew dice clay.
That's a fucking,
you're already on awesome street
from the jump. Well, you know,
what does your dad do?
Oh my dad. Oh, nothing.
Andrew dice clay [inaudible] that way
because you can't put it that way because
I always brought them up that I am dead.
You are no look,
you are very humble
and you're very normal,
but you're still Andrew motherfucking
dice clay and I throw up having Andrew
dice clay as a dad. That's pretty
sweet. You know, that's not, you know,
they're preparing. They're
doing the special with me.
That's what, yeah, no roadmap.
Do new breath, man. They
did your show in um, in uh,
in Vegas they're rehearsing. How great
is the Riviera? Don't you love it?
A God damn like it's, it's like a
cultural experience that fucking,
we haven't changed those pictures
on the walls and forever.
They have these photos from the river
here from the fifties and sixties and
seventies. the 80s. I mean, it's like
a history lesson. It's incredible.
When I grade their, that's why
like playing those, hold the hotel.
I love that place so much on it.
And the show room still has that
feel of like if you were in there,
they actually shut casino in that hotel.
Did they really had the movie
keeps saying, Oh that's right.
You know I stayed in the Casino Room
when, when uh, yeah, Steve Sharp.
He used to stay upstairs in
the two bedroom. I'll put
you in a supernatural room,
show you, I got you in the
Sinatra Room. He was like,
who's the best? What a fucking great
guy. He was running a the Riviera.
He would do all the comedy from
the river Yarra. He was so fun.
I would so look forward to
hanging out with him. But man,
you do not fuck with that guy man.
I've seen that guy snap on people.
Holy Shit with some asshole threw his
cigarette on the carpet and sharp.
If a trip is a big fucking guy,
he got them.
Hey asshole.
Fuck that fucking bought off.
You do this shit in your house in 40
your mother fucking piece of shit.
Pick it up.
Fuck Outta here. Fuck brings
it to, it's a giant guy.
And he brought it to 10 immediately.
You could not be an asshole rusher up.
Fuck it.
I love people with a short fuse where
you could tell [inaudible] seen some real
live violence, does it? He's a,
he's kicked it up to a level that
lets you know he sees, I mean,
that's not a fakers level.
That's a level of,
he's willing to take it to a dark place,
dark,
dark
place.
Right quick.
I know I can always smell dudes who are
just ready to take it to def con four
and Syrup as one of those, you
know, I want to fuck with that guy.
That's no bullshit. He's a great guy
though. I never had a problem with them.
I always love talking to him. He's such
a fun guy, but he's a hilarious guy.
He could easily done stand up. He's
doing it now. He should be doing it.
He's kicking it. Easily been doing
it. I tell him, look, you know,
I had this great talk with sure ripple
when he was on soprano's. Like you know,
almost like the talk we had years ago.
Only about like,
why aren't you setting yourself up for
like an ABC Sitcom? He was perfect for it,
right? Like to play a father and
now, oh no, it's telling me, well,
he's first doing it now.
Now he's doing a lot.
Because I thought he was, you know, even
though he played a gangster and Sopranos,
you could see he's not a gangster. You
could see he could be a regular nice guy.
He played, the guy that he
played was like really demure.
Much different than him as a person.
He's a really good actor for playing.
The tambourine didn't do standup to
like told them when we did a print this,
I go, so you're going to hit the road.
I figured he did stand up. He goes,
I don't do standup. I go, what the
fuck are you doing on the show then?
You know what I mean? What
are you doing? What are you,
what are you trying for here?
And then he started to stand up right
after that he started and never came home.
We're scared to stand up, some of you
know what I mean? I gotta be honest.
I'm a week away from shooting
this special and I know,
I know my shit down pat now, but you
start thinking, do I really know it?
Because once you're out there, you're
alone. It's you and the audience.
And that's what we want to show.
Or two shows for the films.
I'm going to tape two shows.
I really only wanted to do one,
but showtime wants them to
do the too because I'd rather
have my back against the wall and
have to come out swinging. Yeah.
Because I feel like I've been a fight
awaiting in the cage to go fight.
You know what I mean?
This is two years in the
making the special and it
is a New Year's eve special.
And you know, I should say where I'm
doing it. We're doing it in a Chicago.
What's the theater with the Arcadia
theater to theater. It's our sale now.
A theater. And it's actually going
to be my last special, you know,
and not because I'm an old man.
I'm going to tor and I, you know,
I got other plans for movies and
I got a book coming out by uh,
not this year. They, they like
into the early part of next year.
So there's a lot I got to do.
So I just want to really do one more
special that I feel I really all myself,
you know,
and fans and really just fucking bang
them over the head with this shit and you
know, just go out a winner.
Can I make a prediction?
I'm going to make a
prediction, right? You,
the special that you're
doing this upcoming special
in Chicago at the arcade at
theater will create the resurgence that
will make it impossible for you to not
do another special.
People realize how funny what you're
doing is when people realize like it,
when people are starting to like remember
how fucking funny and hilarious some
of your shit was and when we went to
see that special or it won't do what
whatever you did,
what version of what I'm working on,
that version is going to kick
people's Dick, right? Dirt Shit was,
well, I talked about my respect
for you as a comic because you're,
you're in that, that thing that I'm
in the kind of comedy you've done,
whatever we call out genre,
whatever the fuck it is
now when you say it to me,
I believe you. Oh, you know what I mean?
I'm telling you the things you're doing
and what I'm doing. We've got a team up.
We got to do some shows. Love to do
you know what I mean? Just me and you.
When I was in open miker dude,
I used to listen to your cassette,
your cassette in my fucking car.
I would listen to it all the
way to gigs and I told her,
I'll never forget this guy,
Mike Donovan in the back of the
comedy connection in Boston, crying,
laughing, tears coming down his eyes,
crying, laughing, listening to your,
the day the laughter died
during your impression,
your impression of a doing Nixon in a
girl's ass and he's crying and laughing
and I, I'll never forget that. I'll
never forget that. That was to me,
like as a an up and coming comedian.
I was just like starting on and I was
like listening to this like established
Boston comedian just laughing.
He was going,
it was fucking crying. Tears were coming
down his eyes. It was so silly to him. It
was so, well, the thing is
you have that effect too.
And that's why we'd be great together.
And it's funny,
anytime I want to do shows with another,
what we'd call headline as scars,
it's always hard because of like egos
who goes on if the hoe. And I'm like,
you know,
just like we talked about fighting
list time that you'd be the only guy in
comedy. I wouldn't want to fight because
there's no way to walk away a winner in
something like that. No, I wouldn't fight
him. You know what I mean? Throw. I mean,
if I had to, I mean if you
push the buttons, I don't
know. It'd be like a wild cat.
Nobody's going home saying I didn't
get hurt. You know what I mean?
So he's that guy. So it would be the same
thing if we were working together. Like,
he would be the only guy that I'm going,
you know what,
if he's got to close the show,
let him close to show because
he was a fucking animal.
You know what I mean? It's,
you know, most comics can't
go on after me, you know,
so I don't even know how it would
work, but either way, any way.
And I would be honored. It
would be so fun. I wouldn't,
but I'm saying I want to go on if the
you, because you really, you know,
when you get that first shot at the crowd,
it's like you don't have the
pressure to close the show.
That happened when I did a show with
that fucking, uh, Bill Mod, this asshole
that, that, you know, and, and I
wanted to do to shut, this is the last,
the last time, you know, I did all the,
you know, what happened? 300 arena shows.
No, I'm going to tell you what happened.
I did over 300 arena shows, right?
This is before computers does,
before it hit hard ticket sales.
So in 2000 when I was going
back to the garden, you know,
I was thinking,
who could open that show for me?
And I saw a special from Bill Maher
when he does his regular stand up,
he's a filthy dirty pig
like I am on stage. Okay.
So I called bill and I say, you know
what? You've always been great with me.
You know, when, uh, you
know, when I come on,
you're politically incorrect show with
whether it was on MTV or ABC or whenever
he did it, I would always do it. And it
was great. So I said, so why don't you do,
I went back to the garden in 2000. I
said, why don't you do the garden with me?
And he goes, well, I'm not
an opening act. I call,
I'm not calling you was an opening act.
I go, I'm calling, we'll co headline,
everything's equal. And the bottom line,
he was afraid to do it, I could tell.
And so we decided, I said, well,
go somewhere else in the country and
see how it works. So we pick a Phoenix,
the celebrity theatre in Phoenix. So
I'm going to close the show, right?
Jim Norton's going to open it.
I'm going to go on at the end and bill
and bill will go on if the Norton,
so two days before the show,
my agent calls me up and he's like,
I got a call from his people
saying he wants to close the show.
And I just said, you know what?
That's up to him. I don't care. I go,
all these fucking guys are the
same. It's unbelievable. I go,
if he wants to go on after me,
let him go on estimate. No,
I'm going to tell you what happened.
So tonight is show,
you know I'm already on stage.
You know,
cause Norton went up and
now like I'm telling you,
I feel no pressure to close the show.
So I do to kind of puff.
I go fucking nuts.
And Bill actually shows up as I'm doing
the show and he sees this crowd going
fucking ballistic.
So now it's time for him to go on.
And you know,
he sets up the stage.
He said,
it's up on the stage,
a music stand with
cardboard notes of his act.
So now he's brought on stage,
he's brought on stage,
I'm behind the curtain watching,
and he freezes. I mean,
really freezes. He doesn't talk. And I'm
back there. I'm fucking say something,
you know, like, um,
he gets booed off the stage and for
fucking minutes now he's in his dressing
room doing whatever he's
doing to relax himself.
And he got on stage for four
minutes, four minutes, it comes off.
But now to promote it comes, he goes,
I don't want to give money back.
We gotta get this guy back on stage.
So I go in the dressing room,
I'm talking to him as he's doing
whatever he's doing. And I said,
Bill, you know, it's rock
and roll comedy, man.
Just go out there and he starts going
up the steps and you start screaming,
I'm a fucking monologist. And I
want to look at them and go, well,
what the fuck am I? Because
I'm in a leather. I'm not
a monologist. Yeah, right.
You know,
so he goes on and maybe a third,
maybe a third of the crowd is left.
Right, right. And this asshole,
if the every joke,
they're like,
the audience is taking potshots
at you fucking suck ass hole.
And then you see him run to
the camera that he was filming.
It's set to get the tape. I would
have loved to have that fucking tape.
And after the show is making all the
excuses, and I want to say, asshole,
why on earth would you ever want to
follow a guy that gets done the fucking
Rosebowl?
You're not that kind of fucking performer.
But I let him walk in the hug because
he was fucking frazzled and he was just
trying to save face, you know?
But he's a fucking terrible,
that's a terrible idea for when I see
him on his show with the politically
incorrect, I look at him like, yeah,
we really know who you are, don't we?
That's how I look at this guy, right?
Like you've got no fucking chops.
You just got no fucking chops and
listen. But see, I would do a show with,
you know when you're going in front of me,
no one,
you're going to fucking kill him
because that just brings me up. Yeah.
Now I got to write. It's just like
doing this movie. Come on. This movie,
I'm up against Alec Baldwin,
Cate Blanchett, Sally Hawkins.
These are fucking academy nominees,
Golden Globe winners, and I'm gone.
You're just going to have to rise to the
fucking occasion. The better the actor,
the better. My work is going to
be. The same thing with the better.
Like Norton was probably the best opening
act they ever had as a guy because I
will say Eleanor to me is the best
female standup in the country.
She just needs that exposure now.
But Norton would come on and fucking
slayed the crowd every time and he's
brought all fucking day long.
He's the only show I went to over the
last four years to just sit and got her to
show and watch him work and I sat
to two shows and he was just great.
I'm an Austin. He was fucking
phenomenal. He's a great, great,
he's one of the great comics up today.
You know what I mean?
And so again,
it's the same sort of ridiculous fucking
overexaggerated hilarious kind of
standup comedy. Very, very dirty,
very out there. But you know, it's,
it's a fucking legitimate art form.
It really pisses me off when guys like
you or guys like Norton or anybody who
does something that's particularly
dirty or crafts, whatever,
then it doesn't get as as much respect.
It's so stupid.
Well No, this is my point. They're
denying that it's hilarious.
They're trying to pretend like,
well the other way is harder to do,
so it's better.
Well that's not true.
Just because it's harder to make something
clean and clever doesn't mean it's
better cause they're all
stuff makes me laugh.
It doesn't mean I don't have intellectual
interim Italians when it comes to
comedy. That shit is a legitimate
fuck art form. I was just at a,
you know, like I said, I've
been going all over the country,
prepare on the special service,
just the governors and you know,
go and you've been there,
have a town. Everybody's been,
but everybody's been great club. So after
the show, the own is a mark and James,
they say to me,
we voted you tonight the biggest
lifts that ever happened in this room.
So I don't care how dirty, clean, the
biggest laughs that ever happened.
That's what,
and that's the bottom line laughing.
And let me tell you something
about 30 units not so dirty when,
when you're talking about
everything that goes on in life,
in a comedic cartoonish,
wet. Yeah. You know,
I mean Eleanor became great because
she's facing the hardest crowds to face.
Right. I would think your crowds and
the other hardest crowds to face,
you have animal audiences,
real people,
blue collar people come in to see you
perform and they will. Yeah. Right.
Yeah. I mean the first time she worked
a Westbury with me, she got booed off.
No, because, because what, what I admired
about it and she was really green.
This is shut up.
Shut your mouth.
I am trying to say
something nice about you.
I am defending.
So,
but the fact that she was doing comedy
three months and had the balls to face
that fucking crowd was where I gave her
the respect and now she goes out and she
just slays the crab because they'd been
the hardest crowds. It's the, it's,
it's like basic training
when you open for me.
So I could imagine. Well, you know
what's funny because of the podcast,
all the people that work with me on the
road or all my friends from the podcast,
it's all Joey Diaz and Ari Shaffir
and Duncan Trussell and Brendan Walsh,
the fucking puppet, the
puppet, Little Hobo. Ha Fun.
When he does that thing with the
thing and they say like, thanks Lloyd,
was she with the fucking Prass
genius one night he did it.
I want you to fucking throw him such a
beating because he didn't put his heart
into it. And I sacked it
through the whole fucking act,
waiting for the puppet
to turn into the devil,
whatever with the prayer and see
people running from the show.
And he didn't do it the way I wanted.
And I was like,
I fucking told you fucking rare.
I'm going to sit in a room and watch you.
I want to see the prayer,
the prayer kit.
I think my whole act down or going
on stage at you in the morning,
two in the fucking morning.
People are sleeping on the fucking table.
That's right. That's how you,
I even tell him Max that I go,
when you play these places like Marty's
and there's five people who gives a fuck
about and segment, just work your bits.
Because if he could work the silence,
the land,
I'm going to be me and Kennison.
We're on every night back to back
between one and two in the morning.
We were the last two this before you
ever came out to la and the crowd would,
whoever was there walked out knowing
they saw something special. You know,
it wasn't just one after the other.
Well,
my parents who gives a fuck if they limit,
you know, no real fucking like my son
Max when he's putting bits together.
You know, I say certain things when
I do on stage are very like you know,
out there and it's just for the effect
of making them laugh and other things
like when I talk about these
new generation pigs and how
they are, you know, the,
the, the generation that you know,
years ago, like I, I'd always,
I always knew what slobs women were
in bed right on north. Yeah. Cause he,
he or she is, you know,
but, but you, but you know,
you know, 20 years ago they didn't want
to admit to the pigs that they are today.
There is so aggressive. It's so much
material to talk about on stage.
Like when I get a friend calling me and
go and so I went out with this girl,
I wind the doing everything to
her that when I banged her rash,
she looked at me and said, I used to
be really good at this unthinking,
what? Take it to Jiffy Lube. You know
what I mean? The guy was like, nope,
because a girl 20 years ago would
never look back at you and say,
I used to be good at this,
taking in no at anything.
They would just, if they even did that,
they wouldn't even talk about it today.
They're almost giving you
a fucking checklist of what
they will and won't do and
you feel,
you feel like the chick that the next
day after you've done everything to them,
my friends go.
So I called the girl,
you know the the call to like say
how you doing today and she's gone,
I'll call you back in a few.
And it's been three fucking days.
Like she did everything and
couldn't care less about it.
That sounds like a dude who
didn't fuck her correctly. No, no.
Let me tell you something. I
went proper. Let me tell you.
So I went to a fucking ton of them between
now and orange and Valerie, you know,
just one after the other
load if the fucking load,
I'm not even doing material in
between Illinois and meeting my wife.
It was a revolving door,
you know,
get even Max nearly got the bang
one of them, you know, which which,
which was ridiculous. And
um, I set him up with some
people. It was good. No
but, but what I'm saying is,
so I saw what was out there
and, and it's like, you know,
they really do that.
I don't care how good you are in bed.
A girl could just bang a guy
and the next day forget it.
You used to do have a one night stand.
That's how they look at it now.
It's definitely a different world.
Oh my God, please. It's a different,
the age of information because of the
fact that they can get on their phone and
watch them and taking the house.
You can't stop them.
They grew up on fucking
us today at 19 feel.
If they didn't post a picture of diarrhea.
So lips on the Internet,
they're not as hip as deaf fucking
girlfriends all it's true to say,
you know how they say like beams profile,
you know,
how did he say being 40 years old profile
picture will be being 40 years old is
like the new 30. I think. Anybody
who says that's an ass no,
but you know how they do that?
Like green is the new blue.
The asshole has become the new bushing.
It's to no fucking pussy. It's like,
come on, wait, what happened to the blue?
They blow it out of control. I guess
people don't blow it out of control. Joey,
they blow it out if they want to fuck.
And then I want to get anybody pregnant.
It's too bad there's not an extra vagina.
And so like you have a baby,
make it vagina and then uh,
you know,
the asshole when we would just leave
it alone, but we wouldn't even live in
fucking Vegas. Now.
What'd you say? Ellen was going to
be opening in the show in Chicago.
We to talk coping,
very excited about it.
And the band's going to be opening up
to show also in a Chicago kicks that
Baritone a couple of notches when he gets
on the mic. La Rock, we got presence.
We just picked up the drum skin,
right?
I've just got the drums first official
La rock think it's so cool that you have
the show where you, you know, it's like
you're traveling with family, you know,
and I think that's a really
important aspect of the road.
And that's one of the things
that's made it big for me.
I said when I do these shows,
like with Joey Diaz or Duncan Trussell
where these guys are my family,
they're my friends. We've been friends
for a decade plus and we always will be.
So when we go on the road together,
it's just, it's your thing. Yeah,
we're all real really Eleanor.
I mean, how long do I know, you know,
Eleanor was the finest waitress ever at
the comedy store and everybody tried to
talk to you.
I don't know if I tried to talk you into
doing something that I'm sure everybody
does show. I was engaged to
this fucking girl, right?
Paula Brown.
Oh,
why Tolo why this is what happens,
right. We break up were broken up for six
weeks. Right now I get
the call because, because,
because I was having all these fights
at the comedy store for like about six,
seven months. I was got, you know,
it was under a lot of pressure from the
ex wife with the kids and everything
going on. So somebody fucked with me. I
would get physical, you know, it came,
that was one time I was kicking this
guy's head in the front of the store,
the cops.
It was crazy.
So now I'm fucking damn I rarer and no,
it's shut up. See what I
mean? She goes, hey guys. Had
like a confrontation. No, no.
But Dom has always been, you know, since
since the day I took off, it was always,
and I love dom as a comic. He's a
great, he's one of the great comics,
but he would always bring up debt. I'm
Jewish, like, like, like, like a Jew camp.
Be Good looking from Brooklyn and have
a fucking attitude if he's not Italian,
right? So he would go on radio
shows and say my last name, like,
no, I'm telling you what happened. But
Ellen was really great friends with dumb,
which is fine. But now
one night, you know,
I've had a couple of things happen with
dom where he did this jute thing and I'd
have to get in his face, just straightened
them out, but without violence. Right?
So now a couple of years goes
by. Now I'm on stage in the, uh,
original room just working on material
on a Monday night and not on for more
than 15 minutes.
And he had comes a dom and I want
to make fun of them and he's gone,
when are you going to be done? He's
interrupting me now. And you know what?
You don't interrupt somebody
that's done what I've done.
We're not if the comedy
factory outlet anymore,
you're not even in my fucking league.
You know what I mean? And he's gone.
When you get a Goddamn, do yourself
a favor. Get out of the room.
I'm trying to help you here. Just get
the fuck. And he keeps going. And I said,
you know what, you want me to come off
stage. I'm coming off the fucking stage.
And I'd come after him and I get them at
the front booth that a comedy store and
he makes the mistake of touching me and
I slam him against the wall is his head
breaks a fucking one of the
eight by tens on the wall.
And I'm going to bash his
face in, but our, but our,
he jumps on me and Steve Reynolds easy.
John saw me and Steve Simone jumps on me
and then this fucking asshole wants to
walk by me and go,
I'm funnier than you.
So now I got to grab him by the back of
his jacket. I pull him back. I'm like,
why the fuck would you even put
yourself in the same league with me?
You're a fucking club hack.
That's all you are.
I played the biggest fucking places in
the world. Get the fuck out of this place.
I drawn down the steps,
right?
Well now I'm in the back and I'm actually
angry at her because she has broken up
about five fights at the time. And his
store, he's Steve Simone, let me finish.
Let me finish. So Steve Simone,
I go, where the fuck was Eleanor?
Cause I can't lift my hands to anybody.
If he didn't touch me,
I couldn't have done anything.
So she goes,
she said let them work it out themselves.
I'm telling you what the fuck.
He said, tell you what.
All right, so, so now,
so the next morning, me and Eleanor
have the fight over this. So you know,
she leaves, slams the door, we're
broken up. Six weeks goes by.
Now she calls me and says,
I'm moving to New York. Okay.
So I'm actually going to pick up Dylan
who's doing Hebrew lessons and me and Max
it talking about. And I go, all
right, we can't let her leave.
So I got into comedy story, so let's
get married. Let's just get married,
forget the fight. You know what I mean?
So we, you know, we do like an instant,
you know, engagement, you know, and a,
and d and that's how we got engaged.
Well, you, you pull your picking
up. We already sticking up for dom.
That's why I always mean
when you go in with a girl,
every comic in the world was calling her.
That's not what it's about. I go, look,
I'm the fucking guy. I don't give a fuck
about dom. He's nice guys, a good comic.
But when it comes to anything
between me and your weird, a couple,
I'm the one on top of you pump
mulloway every night. That's dumb.
You're not looking at a it,
it had a lot to do with this Mac
wait time. Yes ma'am. Why do you,
why are you so hello?
Let us fight this out because
he started, no, first of all,
it has nothing to do that
fucking special personal shit.
And so it was, it was affecting every
night, every store. And so when I quit,
I thought that would be better.
And then we did live together for you,
but didn't work out our engagements.
Fine. I'm your sister wife now. No,
she's the greatest girl in the
world. Why? Yeah. That's so bizarre.
But one of the greatest guys in the world,
he was just literally,
and he truly didn't know that.
That's a bizarre scenario that I
went out with him. First of all,
please Oprah Click move on dice,
because it's not easy to score
the captain of the cheerleading.
I always thought Illinois was a nice guy.
I never made moves towards a,
and when I actually started
coming on to her all,
she knew I was happily married with
two kids. No, she actually was,
was babysitting my kids in
Vegas when they were like, no,
but how old were they at the time? Dylan
was how old? Almost like too. I too.
I was like six. So Max is sick.
Yeah. You know, so I mean, you know,
I would do anything in the world fell in
or w we off family. I do know. And uh,
but,
but that's how it came down.
So I was just aggravated that at of all
the arguments and fights I was getting
at and the comedy store, she didn't
come back me up on the I rarefied. Yes.
Everyone wasn't against Tom, you
know, because damn did have the balls.
I gotta I gotta I got a lot of
respect from because after the fight,
all of a sudden he comes dumb into the
kitchen and I'm standing next to Ellen on
now and I'm coming down from the
whole thing and it goes dice,
I want to talk to you. And I'm like, damn,
it's the biggest mistake you can make
coming near me now. And he kept coming in.
In my mind I'm going, if this guy has
the guts to get within arms reach,
I'm going to talk to them.
And then we spot, you know,
we talked about for two hours and you
know, and we haven't talked since.
But anyway, it's all good. I love
both of you and can I love dom,
I railroad like a brother.
No dumb. You know, I, I,
dom can be a little hostile though
on occasion if especially if he feels
disrespected. And let me tell
you something. If dom was
a different way, you know,
we were on the same special
with Rodney c w with dom.
I got a history with dom because when I
used to do Philly as a struggling comic,
I would always headline the comedy
factory outlet. And Dom is from Philly.
I was from Brooklyn,
so a clay here who owned the club would
it book dom a lot of times to open the
show for me. So all the way
from then to the Rodney special,
and then I just blew up from the Rodney
special and he started right away with
the like to me antisemetic
bullshit because if he didn't,
he would have been the perfect
opening act for all of those arenas.
But everybody assumed that your
accent was an Italian thing.
Why he I look, you know what I
mean? When you think of a Jew,
you know, you think of, you
think of [inaudible]. You
know what I mean? He's got,
God knows that.
You know what I mean?
If you are a decent looking
person with an attitude,
immediately you are an Italian guy.
But what was hilarious is like what
Italian do you know the was a giant
motorcycle jacket with the collar. I'm
like the wholesale. So about the attitude.
I've always had a certain attitude.
Right. But it's the, the, it's,
it's more of a New York thing
than it is an Italian thing.
But for whatever reasons, people
thinking in that way. Yeah.
Italians have before long gone,
I would see arguments go on
between two men about my,
my mother being Italian, you
know, and I would go, no,
she's Jewish. She's my mother.
I would know. And they'd be like, dice.
And these are like gangster guys going,
you don't know what you're talking about.
This is between me and him.
I go to my mother, I know what my
mother room, where was this? You know,
this is in Brooklyn.
This was at a flea market that they
turned a c is department store into a flea
market.
So I go there like every Saturday because
I love to shop and buy cotton things
and you know, wristbands,
sweat, sweat, sweatshirts,
sweat socks. I couldn't buy enough
of them. And it was all booths.
You know what I mean?
And I love going there and this is when
I was doing like Nassau Coliseum so
people would freak out that I'm there.
So all these fights would start,
cause the minute I'd be around guys they
would turn their attitudes on like they
had to like gout, dice, dice. It
was crazy and Brooklyn for me.
But I love it whenever you get around
any young men looking to prove themselves
and you're a 30 year olds.
I was 30 and going dice.
You don't understand.
I know your mother for 25 yeah, I
can put, I know it since I was born,
I was bar Mitzvah'd.
They cut his dick off when I was born.
I had a Bris they wanted to claim
you. It was hysterical. You know,
you know, but you know in
this photo, but it's never,
it's not like know you ever said
that you were Italian. It's not like
anything you've ever hid. It's no,
it's just for whatever reason they
claimed it for like a little while.
They're still claiming it. But you
know, I grew up in a neighborhood,
it was all Jews and Italians.
That's what I grew up with.
But the thing that disturbs me is
that like at living in New York,
I know a lot of Jews who talk exactly
the same way. You want to know what not.
It's not a thing that only Italian stone.
It was funny Redmond,
it was the Irish guys. It was the
Irish guys that would, that would,
that I'd fight, that would put
me in the hospital all the time.
And then that's what I wanted
up. My ex wife is Irish. Um,
fucking Eleanor's Irish
Irish dudes who've been,
I had a friend who had his finger bitten
off in a street fight when he's on PCP
and he had his toe come on e Bay.
He had his toe cut off to replace the
finger and he had it permanently bent so
he could keep throwing his right hook. So
he would shake your hand. He was on PCP,
might cut his own finger roll.
You shake your hand. He would, uh,
finger would be like tickling me. But he
was a hell of a boxing coach. Joe Lake,
shout out to Joe Lake, Shell Lake.
He's a great guy. Tremendous guy.
Joey fucking ass. Sick.
Awesome Irishman from Boston.
Like a real guy. Like if you made
a movie about my friend Joe Lake,
he was a Longshoreman who was a
professional boxer, a great boxing coach,
trained a bunch of great boxers
and he was a fucking animal.
He was talking about via fighting.
No violence.
You don't know psychos like this?
No, no, I do. My wife Valerie,
you know, you reminded
me. No, no, no cycle.
But just to shout out with some sexy
when you get to Vegas tomorrow with
something high school. Well this is
what that was. You know what that was?
That was to make sure that
she's listening. Did you
listen to me? Listen to me.
What? I send that thing to you. You
didn't listen to me. Oh, she likes really,
really put it together.
She likes putting it together.
You know the Mexican girls with
the colors and the fuck. Good.
Really beautiful by the way.
You've scored.
She's really beautiful. I met her in Vegas
and I was just blown out of the water.
She's very coarse dice clay
bank. You respect. Thank you.
[inaudible] I respect that compliment.
It's a good compliment.
But you didn't say anything dirty about
it like when you walked away. No, no, no.
Thank you. Where your Spec you too
Joe. Right? Never. Never. You know,
cause I would never say nothing about
yours unless she was beautiful and I'm not
that kind of a guy I ever met. You'll
go, no, I'll keep her away from now.
You marry your story.
I've heard she's beautiful though.
Very nice person. That's the
most important thing, man.
I've been around pretty girls
before that weren't nice. Yeah.
But they've got to have the subside. I
gotta Shit. My wife is sweet. She's smart.
She backs up my career with that.
Yeah.
Doing everything I'm doing because she
told me to go do it. That's beautiful.
That's, that's simple that in that
case relationships are always worth it.
So many of us settle for some sort
of a weird combination of, uh,
of that and then an enemy that you live
with that. So that's gets real weird.
People get real weird with that man and
was a lot of times you even [inaudible].
Even though me and Eleanor broke up, we
were never enemies do all of it. Yeah.
We had I think a lot of fighting between
people that you started off getting
along good.
I just don't like when she interrupts me,
you know when I'm around him right now
it's called compensation. I don't
know. This is how guys do it.
That's okay with us,
but every people,
people will listen to the
podcasts all the time and go dice,
interrupt you constantly. I'm like,
you've never done once we're just talking.
Yeah. She goes to that high pitch. Yeah.
That nasally when you're all talking
at the same time and nobody can predict
who's going to be talking or what's going
on or something comes into your head.
You got to say it.
You got to go with the
flow of a conversation and
that includes interrupting
people.
We're not in a David Mamet movie.
It doesn't have to like follow a fucking
script saying I can't talk to you
because you two are men and I'm
in your face.
Me that much bothers me.
Only a little of the smoke bothers you.
It does.
When he does it oddly because I love
them and I'm trying to get them to not
worry about it again. You need red
and listen. If I love him, he's great.
He's a great friend.
If we do the rub,
that's where you break my balls with the
cigarettes cause then you'll need me to,
I'll look.
I,
I only hung out with you a few times
and I would sit down and have the
conversation with you know, but you,
but I do love you. You're a great guy.
I like being around you. I love your act.
I respect you very much. As an artist,
I think that poisoning your body with
cigarettes is a stupid way to die.
Not only that, but you don't understand.
I'm going to, I'm going to go.
You don't understand. It's a way though.
It's why did I start that again? Okay.
I didn't smoke for 10 cold years.
He made me quit when my
father was on his last days.
I lit up. So I'm only smoking a
year. It's not about an excuse,
it's just what happened.
I am going to quit again,
but this is not the week it's
happening. Well you know what, you,
you know what the fuck is best for you.
You're not a child and I would never
tell you what to do or what not to do.
What can you advise and Max as well.
We want them to quit on me with it,
but they also understand what I'm
going through. But it also, you know,
I've got to respect, Brian said something
on the podcast the other day. I said,
why do you like to smoke?
And he fucking pretty passionate about
how great it feels and how much he loves
it and how it's great after a meal.
And you know what?
I got to respect that as a human being.
He's got a right to make a choice and
that choice, but I'm also smart enough.
That's why I did quit cause I just
didn't want to smoke anymore. You know?
And I would hold an unlit cigarette.
I didn't kept people smoked around me.
I just got to wean myself off of
it again. Well, and when I quit,
I won't even wean it, you know, I'll just
quit and that'll be it. I bet I would
enjoy it.
I bet I wouldn't show the nicotine rush.
Steven King said it was
one of his, um, his, uh,
biggest cognitive benefits and that the,
uh,
that smoking gave him rather cognitive
benefits and that he recognized a big
difference when you quit
smoking. He said his, uh, his,
his brain was firing slower as creativity
wasn't as, as, as rampant, which a,
you know, I'm sure I would
like to just not the moment,
you know, for me right now,
I like cigars. I enjoy [inaudible]
hates to go after a fat steak.
There's nothing like chilling
with a cigar. I love it. Fat Stay.
Me and Kevin James have
murdered some fucking steaks.
We smoked some fat Cuban cigars
before and it's a pleasure.
And it's a real buzz too. It's
kind of weird. Mellow high.
It's not a high where you're worried
about driving a car or anything like that.
You have total control of your sentence,
but it's like a, but it's like, ah,
it's just, ah, it's a reason why I quit
smoking cigars for one hit off a cigar.
I feel stoned. Yeah. It makes
it kind of like, it does,
it does make you high a ball, you know,
nicotine in its natural form, like in the,
that, that form of tobacco that
you get in a cigar. First of all,
it's not as bad for you. And second
of all, it's used in shamonic rituals.
They use it in Peru,
in the Amazon and IOWASCA rituals.
This schamens will below the
tobacco smoke in your face,
in the middle of the psychedelic
trip to to create bigger and broader
psychedelic experiences,
like to actually instigate them.
So it's gotten psychoactive compounds,
smoking.
We know we had a guy on the puck county,
how he named a rock.
We had a guy in the podcast name Rob Wolf,
who is the author of the Paleo solution
and he said that people chew nicotine
gum and it really helps their creativity.
So like nicotine itself is
probably beneficial in a
lot of ways and almost like
a caffeine,
like there's nothing really wrong with
the real problem is a delivery method
that's been designed to make sure that
you're addicted. It's that paper. Well,
it's not just the paper,
those chemicals that's mixed
into the tobacco that's designed.
If you've watched the movie the insider,
do you ever watch that movie,
Russell Crowe? It's fucking
fantastic. Unbelievable.
It really based on a real story and
based on how the tobacco industry has
somehow or another condo,
all these politicians into allowing
them to do what they're doing,
which is pumping thousands of
fucking different chemicals.
I think it's 590 actually 590 different
chemicals are approved and every
cigarette, not thousands
but hundreds. But,
but that's an insane amount of
number of chemicals. It's, it's,
you think you're getting a cigarette,
you're getting like this chemically
soaked leaf that's dried out.
It's basically the cigarette
burning is inconsequential.
It's a delivery method
for all these chemicals.
And so you can call it a cigarette and
it Kinda is, but it's also kind of not.
It's kind of a delivery method for all
these 590 different chemicals and most of
them designed to make you addicted.
You're not a college professor read,
you have all this information. Yeah,
but it's just stuff that I've read.
It's just stuff that I've read. Look,
I've done no research on my own.
Also retained it.
I only retain things that are important
to you and you could ask me things about
things that are important to me.
They don't even go in there.
I felt like almost like a retard sprain.
I have a very like half broken,
like things that I don't care about.
I don't care. I don't give up.
Especially once I started making money,
I lost all my ability to care about
shit. It don't care about like, you know,
like people will call me to get me
to do things and I'm just fucking,
I don't answer the phone.
I just disappeared. I was
trying to call him mister.
Yeah. I shut my phone off and I could
get it to taste good for you. No,
but I'd get like a text.
I bet you know.
Let me just call him rather than with
the texting. He never picks up. No,
that was because I was in
my car. I'm like, I have a
Porsche. Porsche is so loud.
It's a gt three. It's one those racing
cars, so when you drive it's like,
so that's what you're here and be like,
hey guys,
didn't car
really juvenile acid nine car.
It's a total douche bag car.
If you looked at the guide dog,
you like,
what kind of Douche bag needs
to drive a car like this?
See if I like the portion. I feel about
the challenges. Oh, it's fucking true.
Car would be American cock.
That's what car are we good?
Well call would get.
Oh and are excited at Cadillac.
Oh yeah. You know that. No, but
the big Cadillac, the Brown,
well this one's from the color of money.
I drove in the color of money.
I gave her one. I got, I got
named it. You shut your face.
I got one as a consolation
prize when I left.
I got a 95 fleet with which
you got one is a constellation.
Nice enterprises. Yeah. I gave
it to me, checked out a hotel,
how she would be adult enough
to know how to take care of it,
you know what I mean?
And she would just break it.
You broke it and she broke the mirror
off the side that because you couldn't
back up
proper
backing up. This is the same
argument. I didn't break the mirror.
I didn't break any
perfect way.
And you got a quote and
you broke it off man. Okay.
We tried to the audience at home.
It's not going to give a fuck about who
crashed your old car. No, no. But it was
just fuck that shit.
Your moons, everything.
If that was
women, I would say, listen baby, we're
rich. Let's just fix this shit. Say
No, no, no. But I gave it to us so
she'd have something to drive away.
So by, by the way, those are,
those are very difficult to drive and she
was able to throw the boxes, you know,
it's a big trunk.
I love when I love when they roll in
this stuff and then they roll it out.
That's the best off. He didn't,
you know, and I'm thinking,
yeah, I filmed, you
know Joe. So I was like,
I know what breaking up, but I got to
get the shot. Know I really enjoyed, well
when I was working at the comedy store,
when you would do these,
you would put on these little in the back
and it would be for your own amusement.
And I was always like,
well what are we gonna do with all this
stuff? Just for your own amusement.
He would have like, okay, now you're
going to come running through the door.
Fuck you.
And you tackle him shooting a TV show,
you know? And you know, and you know, I
would shoot it while they were roping,
you know what I mean?
Because I'm going to afford a set.
And he was all handheld
camera and it was all,
it seemed like a lot of it was just spur
of the moment if you, if you saw it,
but it's not, I'm really thinking
about the episode. Okay. So, you know,
I wouldn't tell anybody what they were
bad. I would say this is what I need.
And sometimes like if we were in the
comedy store, a kitchen, you know,
that'd be a waitress that
I didn't cast in the show.
So I would make me get out in the
kitchen. I say, you can't be in the shot.
And she's like, yeah, I
don't care about your drinks.
I'm trying to get my shot here.
Like Eleanor had a fist fight with wheels
in the kitchen one time where wheels
is smacking her head again. The only
guy who employs wheels these days,
I don't see wheels. Wheels go see him.
I'd never seen him doing stand up. Well,
well he's still,
he in Vegas now and he's in Vegas.
Who was responsible for the clip to,
they used to have where he claimed that
he got his start them and fame after he
blew you off stage one night at a club
very well.
But wheels was sort of
pushed into things years ago.
Well we liked by other people.
It had nothing to do with someone.
So someone else wrote that forum?
Well, no, he was made to do that.
We always told me he was like a
professional pool player. Yeah,
he is wheels
and we went to a, so we worked
in San Diego. I said, okay.
I play a lot of pull too,
because I play a lot of pool,
a famous makers.
I have a professional table in my house.
I play in tournaments.
I play a lot of pool. So like, so
wills, wills tells me that he plays
professional pool. So I said, well,
let's fuck around and just play a
dollar game. $25 later. I'm like, dude,
you can't play pool. You can't
fucking play pool. He lied.
He can barely make a couple of balls.
But he's not a professional level. No,
but he is a professional
liar. No. Let me tell you,
Stan didn't trick me 25
games in. Well, you know,
he still owes me that money of course.
But he's a funny competent.
He's just a funny dude to be around.
One of the funniest guys selling out in
a good dude. I don't mean anything bad,
but it's a true story. You can't, you
can't fuck with me on the pool table.
Well that was the most ridiculous shit.
Everything that you can play with.
When I went to Vegas the last few
times, I would be like, wheels,
you want to hang out at night? You
know? And he goes, I can't, you know,
because of what I'm doing right now.
I go, what are you doing? He goes,
well I'm doing the inspirational talks.
He was hired from some company.
He put on a suit
and tie five in the morning.
He's getting dressed and show up and do
these inspirational talks and get paid
for it.
And he's getting it from the Gary.
What's that movie you love?
Glengarry Glen Ross.
That's where he'd get his monologues. So
I'm still the speech. Yeah. Oh my God.
Genius. Oh my God. And make
a lot of money doing it.
Anybody not know? Then he's got
his catering company. He had a kid,
he's got a catering company called the
cannoli. King's herders. Caterings.
Very good.
Which is gigantic in La.
And then he'll just move to South Carolina
for a year and then I call him up.
I got what's going on? He
goes, well we're in Vegas.
I got to Walmart it cause we moved here
and then he opens a comedy club and then
he becomes an inspirational speaker.
Next thing you know,
you're walking down the street and he's
got one of those meet trucks that he
started. He, he, you know, wheels,
wheels, got a couple of nicknames. One
of them was wheels. One of them. Look,
wait what you're saying,
look at it.
Areas number one chef in the country.
Well he is a good cook though.
He brought some amazing due to the comedy
store and it's fucking just so funny
character. He's such a character. It's
fucking, it's, and he's a very good cook.
He's a very good cook. Whatever the
fuck he brought to the comedy story,
brought a bunch of lists
and cocktailing for him.
You shut your face. And I was
cocktailing and he goes, he goes, listen,
Nah. I was screaming. And
I go, hey wheels, we need
more whatever. He goes, oh,
can you call me chef? Yeah.
She would work with him
and
he would do these professional,
we're professor Joe. He
would do these Jackie. Yeah.
But there's nothing wrong with
wheels like easy as opposed to
it's a little flavor party.
He did this party for some
uh, black cigarette. Um,
that was fast. Newport? Yes. It's
gotta be 300 people. Cigarettes.
Menthols yeah, my mom,
it was African Americans.
There wasn't one white person there
and I show up with the camera. Right.
You know, with, with the camera.
Just for footage because I'm filming my
show and wheels is like yelling at me.
You got to leave, you know, I'm getting
paid a lot of money and I'm going wheels.
How am I going to get my shot?
You know,
if I don't show up at the potty and I'm
just filming us with him throwing me out
of the party and she's waitressing.
Not really.
I was just rounding up black girls
to surround him cause he was taking,
I didn't need your help.
Trust
just fucking hit me girls,
why you diminish?
You see women are always silent.
Get came. It's making this because?
Because she picks up the hands,
we're not allowed to hit back.
Be Clear if that's taking advantage
because she keeps putting her hands on me.
I hate Eleanor. Please
relax. We got to talk about,
you know what? I know he, I
know he's like a 10th degree,
but I happened to know karate
kick your Eleanor's wrestled.
If I have to use karate to see me wrestle,
I did. I want to see a restaurant.
We're fictionally but I
got pissed off at that. No,
because it could ruin like
that, you know, thoughts area.
Yeah.
You know what I mean?
He could break and I'm like
anything to be on fucking TV.
What's wrong with guilt? Oh wait a minute,
a minute. And, and Eleanor's defense,
me and I rather,
and a bunch of people from the comedy
store went down and we had a great fucking
time.
We bought waitresses.
Comics had a big group to support
Eleanor and she was easy rider.
She played this motorcycle girl,
boxer sorta type wrestler chick who
would a crush pool balls in her hands.
But she just wants to do traumatic fucking
rolls and tumble salt and the ring,
I think, I think it's better for Eleanor.
I mean, I've known Eleanor forever.
I think it's better for her to
not take yourself seriously.
So doing something like that,
but that's a, your charm,
your charm is that you're so ridiculously
silly and you're so over the top.
Eleanor and I used to do this thing.
I don't think we ever talked about it on
the podcast. Where did we talk about it?
Ask Her for change. When I go
on stage, people are like, Hey,
can I record it? Listen, I'm
not going to figure myself.
It was like, are still, it was the
stupidest running gag. And I would say,
this is what, this is what it
was, where you went to listen.
I'll explain. I'll explain it. You're not,
it's wrong. Her Apron was on
and this is what we do. It
would be, would go, uh, hey,
um, I want, I want to get changed
for a dollar for the meter,
but do you have change for a dollar?
You Go, hold on a second, let me get it.
And she would dig in her apron and
going this whole routine pretending to
masturbate herself to climax it.
She didn't want anybody to come in near
and people try to rescue where it was
fucking hilarious. Hilarious
about it. Cause it lets muck,
we did it for years,
but I'm waiting at home for this tells me,
you know,
my shift is over at 1130 but now it's
two in the morning and she comes walking
in telling me that uh, you
know, we never kept her late.
She was doing that turn up but this
is the kind of shit you would do.
I'm going and she's helping comics
with debt, personal fucking problems.
Then I'm like, I don't give a
fuck if the guy falls off a cliff.
She is waiting here. I
got a hard on, you know,
as a,
as a brother,
comedian. I appreciate that. But
as someone he loves hilarious Shit.
And as someone who also supportive of
the fact that that's one of the reasons
why she's a professional
comedian now cause we all
knew she was so fucking funny.
I know was when she was just
a waitress. Yeah, of course
you did. Yeah. We all knew.
We all knew no one,
no one doubted it.
We knew you as a waitress and you would
be like the funniest person hanging
around with backstage and it was,
it was,
it was ridiculous that you were an
onstage and you would like, I would,
I would always go to Eleanor.
What if anybody knew one on stage?
Is that going to be funding? She'd go
hat and like walk away and I knew that.
Yeah, watch this watch. I know
dude. Do Bruce Mann off? No,
don't make one joke.
Just do it.
When Jews are ugly,
we win prizes.
Do Dom dom,
I can't do that.
I can't think of one of my favorite
John Joke right now as the,
that he adopted an Asian girl to
help him with his iPhone. No, but no,
but she knows she's going back
as soon as I get these apps down.
Talk to fucking,
but,
but she knows every comic problem because
doing my own material I'm writing.
That's fine. As long as you have that
auditing in your own head, you know,
everybody is going to, especially in
the beginning of [inaudible] Andrew,
I'm like, aren't you, you, you
run the risk of maybe covering, so
this is the best way to hold Smith.
This is back when the Oj with
thing was happening, right.
And I did this whole thing about
Marcia Clark dead. Uh, you know,
once you realize this was a big
TV shot for her, she's still,
all of a sudden she'd come into
the courtroom with the pumps and,
and the scope with the slit up the side,
walking down the fucking aisle.
Like I want everybody to stare in this
fucking ass and get in here for a while
and build a TV Korea. So Holtzman did
something kind of similar to the j.
So I come over at Tim and I know he's
not a finger, you know what I mean?
And I go, you know, I, I like do that
joke. And he goes, well, you know, dice,
we overlap. And I just started
fucking laughing. He goes, hey,
when a guy says that to you, it's like,
just do it. It's too fun. You know,
like when you approach somebody
about a joke that's similar, right?
They'll beat the get all defensive. It
becomes an argument. Someone's like, well,
you know, we overlap. Well,
you know, and I'm like,
what the fuck did I just started
laughing. He's so funny. He is hilarious.
But I agree with that
kind of in a certain way.
Like Brennan Walsh and I
overlap on a, uh, a fleshlight
joke and I know, I know he
didn't read. No, he didn't.
He wouldn't have seen my bit and then
done a similar bet. He's not that dude,
but he had a similar conclusion and I was
like, well, that's the obvious thought.
You know, like you, you, you thought,
I mean, if you're intelligent,
you thinking about it, there's a bunch
of different ways to approach it.
That's one of them. You
thought of it. I thought of it.
His bits different than my bit, even
though it's based on the same premise,
I felt like that's overlapping. It's
no big deal. We overlap a little bit,
but I care.
Right. And it's, what is your
particular take on things?
I want to hear his take on it
and someone else has taken,
the only problem is when
you hear them in a row,
the problem is when you hear him
like that night in a row, look,
if he's middling and you're headlining
and then he does the bit and then you
really can't do the bit because
it's kind of a, it's so similar.
You'd have to bring it
up. Like you'd go, Hey,
I want to cover the subject
that's already been covered.
Covered in beaten to
death. Right, exactly.
That's what I would do it in a way,
like at the store where like,
I know what the other guy brought up,
but let me tell you something and
then go it. Yeah. At the store.
But like when you're on the road doing
your show, you wouldn't want that though.
You would never want a guy. Oh,
but she does like this thing about,
I don't want to say it, you
know, with the, uh, with the, uh,
whispered in the maturity
with the glitter.
Oh,
the old man,
the old man do it. When the
old man's like, you know, I
fool around with older man.
I like older men, but when they come
nothing comes out. It's like air.
It's like right. You know, and then um,
but he does something similar
or something like that.
And I say it's like air and then you're
like, well shit, where did that go?
Then like two days later I'm like,
is that fucking glitter on my face?
And I'm like, oh, it's old man river.
His balls on my face and that's it.
It's something stupid like that.
Joe's just staring,
you know when you get
old and you choke off,
it's like a three day process and then
by like the third day when it finally,
whatever the fuck is in there comes
out at like just falls off the Tipi.
A cop on the balls,
you know what you know about that was
Holtzman Holtzman a little bit about a,
yeah, it's like, it's, it's
old paint that's been the
basement too long. He goes,
it's not the same call that it used to
be. That's real. He got a bit about, uh,
I don't want to do is
doing a Viagara, but, well,
I don't want to say it also because
I don't want him to, you know,
to not be able to do that big now, by the
way, do you know where Holtzman lists?
I know where's he live?
Yeah. Isn't it like Vietnam or
something? Not Marina del Rey. No,
I heard he, he moved to
Vietnam right now. Yeah.
Holtzman when he just did someone's
podcast. We're like, oh yeah,
I think he was on [inaudible] sometimes
those go to Thailand. Thailand.
That's what it is. He was
Chinaman hairless boy there.
He said, oh, he always Joe.
I mean, he's just a kid. He's a
joke. He's a great guy. I love that.
Back up the joke. Just say it. It's
okay. That's what I mean. Everybody, you
know. Um, so you both have a
joke about old people coming.
Terrible. Not like that. Yeah.
Well it's been done. Yeah.
Yeah. It makes sense to do
it. And it's funny. Yeah.
And it only happened because there was
like an old male and I was picking on one
night and I just went into it and every
once in a while he'd just bring it up.
How many great songs are written
about the same subjects, you know,
how many great sub the songs,
you know, cover, uh, you know,
really was real similar ground. Be Still
fucking love them cause they're great,
you know, and, and in comedy there's
certain things sacs especially is the,
which is always going to be hilarious.
It just is. And as, as it is,
let's extract as much of it out as we can.
You think we'd be overlapping a lot
if we did shows? I don't think so. No,
we different, we have a different
point of view though. No, I agree.
I saw and just watched Joe a couple of
months ago at the Ice House and I think
it would be great.
I don't think that last night,
I mean seeing your show was so fun, but
you're so much more preposterous to me.
I just,
I tried to be a little more realistic
because you actually have facts in that I
can try to remember. I don't want to
be a an agent of disinformation. Yes.
You fucking act was so funny and
describing how the caves were created.
I would not, I would not, but I just want
to say that we were slapping the table.
We were fucking hell. And me and Norton
and we were looking over it, the laughing,
it was such a special moment,
like as comics, you know,
as professionals who've been comics
for 20 plus years, the both of us,
we were laughing together. Like, you know,
it was like there's a brotherhood
and that's the best compliment.
I don't get along with most comics.
I don't think you do what you, the,
you know what I mean? I get along
with a lot of comics, you know,
I give you credit. The ones that I don't
get along with, it gets got ugly. No, no,
I know that. But I'm saying I just
don't because I don't feel camaraderie.
So when I'm around the few that I do love,
you know,
and you'll one of them now obviously,
and you know Norton for years and
Florentine. I think in your defense,
I think in your defense you got so fucking
big so quick that it's real hard for
you to relate to other
people. [inaudible] comedy.
You know when,
when somebody comes with me and then
my comics mean not about the comedy,
I'm in comics, I'm saying your, you
became so fucking huge so quick.
There's like this automatic resentment
that's going to come with it with a lot
of people. You went from being a
comic who you know was in with others.
You know,
there's steady stream of professional
comics to becoming the biggest comic in
the history of standup comedy insider
a few years and it just went boom,
and all of a sudden you're doing
evidence. But 27 years, it was 10 years.
I'm sure it was a long time
and I'm sure it was hard,
but it also the, the, the,
the height hit so high that it was
impossible for people to not get jealous.
I've watched a lot of people get creepy.
I was able to talk to you.
I'm not a jealous person. Okay.
That's what I mean. And Oh listen,
I am honored to be around people like
you and honored to be around people like
Don.
My rare I am.
I don't care how long I've been doing
comedy or how I'm confident that I know
how to do it, but I am always like, uh,
honored to be friends with Doug. Stan
hope. I love that I can call up Stan,
who I believe is one of the
greatest comedians of all time.
I can call them up and we'll shoot the
shit on the phone and we'd love it.
And Stan Hope said to me the
other day, he goes, you know what?
I could quit comedy, but I can never
quit comics. He goes, I could never quit.
He goes,
I fucking hang out with,
I've tried to hang out with
too many regular people. I
can't fucking do it. Well,
that is, that is the fun part because
we're all twisted in all different ways.
Joey Diaz is different than you.
Even if I text you late at night,
I know you getting the texts
cause you're up. Yeah. Yeah.
You take at four in the morning.
Let me tell you something.
Cool wheels like one 30 in the morning
and he goes and I got to get some sleep
cause I got to get up.
I'm like, you're a comic.
He's also a chef de time pool has.
But I'm saying Jake time it is. I
agree. You know what I mean? I love,
I love the night. That's what I
am. I am exactly the same way.
That's when I do all my work. I don't, I
don't get anything done during the day.
My kids are up. They want
to play. There's, you know,
fucking something's going on.
There's noise. I can't concentrate
in my office during the day.
I play with my kids, I get my
workouts in, I do my bullshit.
But then when everyone's asleep, I do
it after Jujitsu. So I like to write,
I don't even come home till
11 and then from 11 on,
that's when I start to write saying if
a call it three you pick it up. Oh yeah.
That's when I called Opie and
Anthony [inaudible]. Anthony,
I only call when I'm awake. I'm awake all
night, which I need to do more often. I,
I fucking love those guys and hanging out
with Anthony and when we were in Vegas,
he just really reinforced how great he is.
I always know he's a great guy,
but I'd love the fact that we could
all pal around in a social setting. Oh,
he's a brilliant,
brilliant oppression.
It's a lot of people don't realize is
there's a lot of really good impression.
He's another guy always tell, why aren't
you doing stand up? Well, he sort of is.
When he does the, have you
seen his fucking awesome show
his show. Let me do this.
Let me just give him credit.
This is the reason why we're
doing this podcast today.
It's because the Anthony Kumina
mia from the opiate Anthony Show,
because Anthony Kumi has started doing
his own show called live from the
compound and live from the compound,
which he does on Ustream.
He does it in his house.
He has a fucking studio set up.
He spent like a quarter million dollars
with fucking green screens and he could
be like in front of the Colosseum in Rome.
He couldn't be in space.
It could be any professional desk.
And you know,
he used to do with these
chicks he was dating.
He would be running around with a
machine gun. It's singing songs,
playing air guitar with holding a
fucking [inaudible]. He's crazy.
He's a beautiful person. Can love him.
He's a gambling addict. He's crazy.
He's nuts. I love Anthony. He
loves to drink. He's a up to me.
He's a classic American character
and I don't get to kick.
I don't have to hang out with them enough.
So then all of a sudden we were in
Vegas together and steaks we went to Wa
craftsteak and had the most read
the fucking one thing about Vegas.
They know how to make them. Oh, bass
cliff stakes. Craftsteak is an MGM. Oh,
it's got damn good.
Oh the best though.
The best is nine nine steak house in the
palm. You can't fuck with that place.
You get the grass fed rib eye do not pass.
Go.
You want the grass fed rib by medium rare,
it will knock your Dick into the dirt.
It's the most spectacular
cut of meat available in the,
probably in the entire western part of
the United States. That nine steakhouse,
nine steak house in Vegas
and the point there, k a lot,
so we went to crab steak. Yeah, I've
been there too. Okay, that's great.
We went to crab steak. We had a great
meal. We had some wine. Anthony was like,
he knows wine, so he picked out a good
wine. It was me and my, my buddy Steve,
who I've known since I was like 15 it was
all of us as big group who came to see
you. It was such a thrill. It
was so fun to just see a show.
Why didn't I get to go, Joe,
you what? Puff. Oh Man. Oh
Hey. We had such a great time. We
walked in right when Max was playing.
We walked in and how great Max was
having a guitar solo or excuse me,
a drum solo. You know you, you know what?
You got to talk to them about that for
a minute because drum solo was fucking
spectacular. Serious hand
eye coordination, son,
you went off that was like real shit.
You didn't like have like a halfass drum
solo. You were fucking fly in a man.
The kid was flying.
Unbelievable.
It's what he needs to hear now
because you know you can do that shit.
That's them. We get to here at
the Improv. Did we get to hear it?
Wow
down.
Okay.
You need to see that someone,
someone please edit that and put that
little part of this video on youtube.
You have to see that with him
watching it in the corner.
He's walking around in the house going,
I think, you know, cause don't forget it,
showtime. You know what I mean? And this
is the band's first shot ever. Yeah.
You know, doing the song you
saw could outlaw and he's gone.
I don't know if the Solos they yet,
and I'm trying to explain every night
we'd sit outside the house and I go, Max,
there is nothing you have to learn for
this solo because you have such chops.
Like I, you know, I started out
as a drummer, but my ability,
it doesn't come close to what he can do
that. So yeah, I get jealous of his feet.
All the combinations.
No, because because he's,
he uses both his feet like his hand,
he drive a stick shift. It's automatic.
Automatic.
I feel it.
God knows how to work the pedals like
that would want to fucking stick shifts.
No, no. He's just amazing. And like when
I would tell people about him, you know,
I'm the farthest, so they think,
well how good can they really be?
And then you see that which, which
we got to see it. You got to see,
it's like babysit. Yeah. You got to
listen. You're listening to it folks. You,
if you're hearing just the audio
version of this podcast, it's like a,
it's an iPhone camera. So the,
the sound quality is not the best.
You have to see it. If you see it, it's
fucking propositive. When he would,
when he would show me like
drum Solos Chicago, like
I said at the Arcadia, right.
Arcadia theater in Chicago. Well,
I'm going to be 22 and uh,
with the,
so I actually started off only soloing
when I first started playing the drums.
I didn't play with a band
for like the first five,
six years of drumming he's
playing since he's 10.
And how old are you now going to be 22
you're going to be 22 she'd been playing
the drums for 12 years. Dude, your
fucking hands are ridiculously fast.
You should get involved in wing Chung.
You should start coming through
and mother fuckers that fast speed.
He could probably be a hell of a bargain.
Talk. Believe it translates number one.
He can box. I'm embarrassed
to say he, he, he, no,
by accident he sorta
knocked me out twice because
when I would, you know, teach them to
box, you know, I would say, you know,
we've got an that Hollywood gym that
had his love, that place. I would say,
all right,
no head shots at all.
So I would just protect my body
and let them fight me, both kid.
So now and then Max would slip and he'd
nailed me right on the chin once it
happened in my backyard
and I went right down.
Because you know when you hit in the chin,
you see the stars and you've got down.
I'm not expecting to get punched in
the face by my friend unless you yeah,
by my son.
And then he does it again at the gym
and I'm on the floor feeling like an
asshole because here I am,
I'm the father and my 14 year old
just knocked me out. Well, you know,
the reality is there's a lot of chicks
that can knock you out if they don't know.
If you don't know the punch in you, if
you don't know they're going to punch you.
There's a great video of a chick
headbutting a guy on conscious,
some asshole at a bar says
something stupid toy. She
grabs his shirt, goes bang,
knocked some completely unconscious,
and that does work. That doesn't work.
Let me tell you,
he hit me with his fist.
I'm saying a little girl can
headbutt a jet giant dude.
What I'm saying is if you don't know
it's coming, if you get hit in the jaw,
you can get,
that's even by a little girl's head.
Well that's what I tried to break the
body down first and then they go for the
chin. It's not a bad because people, when
they see a professional fight they go,
why aren't they just swinging it up?
They don't realize it's a skill.
It's a dance. It's, you'd be amazed
at how hard it is to hit someone.
Did you ever do an actual box and kickbox
I did a lot of boxing in the gym but I
have three kickboxing fights.
But it,
you'd be amazed at how difficult it is
to actually hit someone who knows how to
box. It's, it's a dance. It's a rhythm.
You got to figure out how to fucking,
how to fake them,
how to get them to move out,
when to run and cause if you run in
like if you see Ryan Bader versus Leo
Machida,
the Oda Cheetahs is bad ass karate guy
and he'd knocked Ryan Bader out cause
Bader charge them. They just caught
them charging and flatten them,
knocked them out with one punch,
but you, that's the risk you take.
If you want to be aggressive,
it's so hard to hit someone who actually
knows how to fight. It's riddance.
You will feel if you were like, there's
a lot of people that always bothers me.
Peterson Center fight. He's a great guy
to level. Want to know more about boxing?
They should get in touch with me.
[inaudible] we don't dice clay on Twitter.
Is that my Twitter things? Real dice
clay. If you want to know about drumming,
met Max does comedy and if you
want to go out with Eleanor Max,
did you get upset when you dropped your
dad? I was a, I was nervous. You know,
I came over like, you know, are you
okay? I didn't mean to do it. Oh yeah,
he show you didn't mean it,
but it was thinking about maybe that it
was major. We have a great relationship,
you know, you know well that means
probably got a good punch. Look,
if you hit the drum set hard, I bet you
can generate some serious fucking speed.
If somebody teaches mechanics,
oh,
you can't hit your kids.
That's ridiculous. You know,
I'm just handing you over to
rogue and for all your fights,
thinking about taking some crop
McGaugh so chroma guys good. Yeah,
it's interesting, you
know, but uh, there's uh,
but he knows miss a lot of benefits to
taking one martial art over a common
atory system of martial arts.
Like a lot of people think the common
atory systems like [inaudible] or
something like that is good if you don't,
we do it every now and then.
You just want to learn some self defense.
But I think there's a lot of time spent
doing shit like street techniques and
stuff like that. That's really not really
coming up. No, I don't think you do.
You really don't want to know.
You really want to know.
We really want to be good at
what works on trained killers,
not people in the street
with a fucking set of keys.
Because in a real life situation,
there's going to be a lot
of craziness going on.
You gotta be able to execute from memory
and from training and how much training
are you really have taken? Someone's going
away. I mean, are you really good at,
I mean,
maybe it's a good thing to know if you're
in the special forces or something and
you got to learn, you know, dealing
with people with hand guns all the time.
But the reality of self defense is
most of the times when things happen,
they happen one because
one person's not confident,
so the other person gets cocky.
And two,
because you're not aware of your
environment and you don't have enough
confidence in any one
particular discipline,
whether it's stand up or the ground
fighting or anything like that.
A lot of people want to fight and they
don't know how fight. And it scares
the shit out of me.
I've been a martial artist my whole life.
The last thing I want to do is get in
a fight with somebody because I know
there's some people that can do some
crazy shit to your body. Yeah, okay.
I know them. I know people who could eat.
You would be crazy to fight them. Yeah,
but people start fights with them because
there's a lot of fucking morons out
there, but I want to, for me,
it's very important that I'm the one who
is capable of deciding where everything
goes.
I don't like being in a position where
I have to trust my health to some crazy
asshole, you know? I don't like that.
I don't like the to know that some
guy could just own me anytime.
He wants to just jump all over me and I
don't know what to do and I can't even
defend myself. I can't live like
that. That would drive me crazy.
I know too many crazy people,
you know?
I grew up with too many complete fucking
psychopaths to ever think that it's
safe to not know how to defend yourself.
Yeah, I agree with that. Yeah. It's like
if you, I know how to defend myself. Oh,
I know you said mock wrestling
matches in the backseat.
Nearly beat up people at
shows that's ever get some,
some situations like what
is this one girl we went to,
we went out to this club and normally
it's a Sunday night. You remember this?
It was a Sunday night and it's usually
dead. Andrew's like, oh, I always go here.
It's usually like a hundred people.
It's not that bad. We get there.
There was some kind of dead
mouse DJ thing going on. Okay.
There was like 1500 people.
Yeah. Ran Pack. And I go,
here's where we can't go in here. And he
goes, no, we'll be fine. We'll be fine.
Girls were throwing themselves at him.
Nice. That must be nice.
Yeah, it feels good.
But you know how fast did I
take that girl off? Yeah. Yeah.
But how does she does she does security
when we go out? Yeah. He gets crazy.
He goes crazy. Yeah. No, it feels good.
But you know what? It's, you know, it's,
it's nothing I'm looking for, you
know what I mean? No, I'm serious.
Even when I'm single.
You know what I mean?
It's nothing that's ever thrilled me
unless I'm out hunting, I believe,
but that's strolling into a club.
Fill with 1500 people with those
sunglasses on and a sleeveless shirt and,
and the throwing themselves out. You'll
come on, sorry. You're in a goddamn movie,
you're going to Goddamn man.
I appreciate it cause sometimes
it does hit me in that way.
What do you get to live that life?
But I really appreciate your famous guy.
You've got to clubs,
you go out.
I mostly do shows after shows. I it's,
it's hard to go places, you know, it's,
it's, it's very rare that he
does it. But you know what,
I like to dance with my wife
sometimes, you know, and you know,
I'm very focused on her when I
go out because they see all the,
I'm watching the guys watching her.
But when you do allow you
to have a problem with like
people constantly wanting
to get your attention to take photos.
Like they never give me just,
they normally put me in
one of those VIP booths.
She stands there with her arms out,
like touching the boots.
Like she's just hanging out and
she won't let anybody put big,
this was funny when we went out
a Halloween, then we went to
the same club.
I think a true,
but that was later and they had,
I'm dancing with my wife on the dance
floor and you've got these three giants,
these three guys surrounding
us so we can dance.
So people didn't bother me,
you know,
and you just have to ignore it and
you get into the person you with.
We went to this crazy place first.
There was one that was like 10,000
people at that first place. Yeah,
we saw a fight. This shit. We saw
a lot of fights there. We went to,
that's when I felt, oh you want to
hear what's the finish fetish ball.
That's right Max.
If people thought he was dressed as
Andrew dice clay and they were like funny
where I had a hit somebody,
you could tell it,
I don't remember the name of the hotel
or where we were. It was the south,
something down near the hotel
around the south coast. Oh No.
But we were walking out and we're walking
fast because people are recognizing
them a thinking. He's just stressed. And
when people yell my name, I'm not him,
I just keep going. Right.
So all of a sudden this guy,
me and Valerie were in heels, so he was
walking fast, like 30 feet behind me,
a little bit ahead of us. So I hear this
guy go dice, dice and I'm like, Oh shit.
And he comes over and I, I we wreck.
No, like don't touch me. You know,
he touched him like this and
he knocked him the fuck out.
It was his friend brand.
It's a friend of mine,
but I didn't see him
coming and I just felt no,
I didn't see him and his hands grabbed my
shoulder so I just react and I hit him,
you know, because that's where the gloves
are off once you put your hands on me.
Hard like that. But he's my
friend, but they're yelling. No,
if he was yelling Andrew, I wasn't
just look Brandon, but he couldn't,
I didn't know.
It's my friend and I turned and he's
going back and he's out on his feet,
you know, cause I do know how to
hit, you know, in that way. Right.
Brandon's punch him in the head,
but it was,
but I hit him with a side punch. I didn't
hit her. I was turning to hit him again.
And that's when I saw
was and I felt so bad.
And to this day he won't admit that
he was out. It's just funny, you know,
I'm like, Shit. I'm like, Yo, I, you
know, how do you yell my name? You know,
you don't yell my name. That's like, you
don't say dice. You say Andrew, you know,
cause it, it's like a drunk gut. This
is what I'm picking up weight, Joe.
This is what I'm picking up. I'm
hearing a guy yell, dice, dice,
and all of a sudden I feel this two
hands grabbing revenue like that.
So I just fucking bang
the guy and he's gotten,
now I'm turning around to
really finish them because once,
and I'm sure you know you would react
the same as somebody's got to be careful.
Just grabbing you can do that.
You never know if I,
if I feel someone grabbing me from behind,
I feel like they're up to
nefarious things. Well you
grab me. I gotta do to make,
you know, that's the one
thing I don't have in place.
What, what? Sorry.
Sorry. Okay. It's all right. Yeah,
it's crazy that someone would,
why wouldn't he just, we'll just
touch us. He was, he was, hey buddy,
you don't understand.
He was drinking so he got excited when
he saw the Commodore Hotel did 30 feet
behind me. Fucking problem. The drunks.
That is a problem with people that don't
even realize that it might take you a
lot of the shows, they don't even
realize they're being ridiculous.
It's a terrible drug for, for socializing.
It's the best jug for socializing,
but it requires character.
But there's so many people don't have
character and they go out and they drink
and they're real shitbag personality
comes flying out. Hey look,
if you come over to me for a picture
and you're not drunk and you're nice,
I'll take, I'll take a dozen
of them. What do you do though?
If you're on your way to somewhere and
you just said is a river of people and
you can't get thrown. Well if it, if
it's nice people, I'll take the shots.
But if they're assholes, they put
their hands on me. I don't have a fuse,
I just don't have a fuse
and I won't deal with it.
He did something cool. Uh, last Sunday
at our show in Vegas, he, uh, some guy,
he was coming up the elevator and he
was kind of late and the guy was like,
hey man, I saw you at
Madison Square. Yeah.
This guy went to both shows at the garden
when I was still alive. And he was,
and I was in a rush.
Say it. Wow was after his Doring his
shell, like at the end of it he goes,
who's the guy in the elevator?
And the guy was like,
that was me any talking
about on stage and took it.
I took him on the stage.
He was so excited that like a
Chinaman to take the pictures.
Cause I know they make the cameras,
you know what I mean? Oh No, no,
they do, they know what they're
doing with it, you know,
and they were right in front of me
and I actually dedicated like my,
my Asian obit to them, you know, cause
they were dead center. That's beautiful.
I don't know what they knew what they
were getting, but they were cool about it,
you know. And I, I gave him some
suggestions for, for new phones and um,
but I brought the guy up from the
crowd because I was in a rush.
I was late for the show,
so I'm going,
who's the guy that was at the God and
stand up, you know, that's very cool.
Come on up. Let's take a couple pictures.
And of course I had fun with them,
but we do our show.
I felt bad that I had a blow him off when
I was coming up the stairs. You know,
we do our shows and then we hang on
after the show and take pictures with
everybody. But if I'm on a rush
to get somewhere that's that's,
that's when it becomes
a problem like in Vegas,
like after the UFC is it becomes a real
problem because there'll be a thousand
people waiting in line. I'm like,
folks, I can, I got gotta go,
I'm a meeting my friend and then they
got the ones and they get pissed off and
be like, yeah, I wrote something about
me on Facebook. See where we're at today.
Concern yourself because no,
I mean a guy and I don't like,
I don't like to blow somebody off if
they're legitimately happy to see me. No,
but you know what a thousand people
you see, it's really fucking hard
when somebody goes dice where you'd
take a picture and all of a sudden the
friend standing, I go, well how
long does it take to take? Oh, oh,
it was on the filming by accident.
That's what I got pictures over.
You know what I mean? Get the fuck
Outta here. You know what I mean?
You look at their fans,
I don't give a fuck who they are if you
want to get it right. Take a picture. No,
they do it on purpose. We do the
filming. Yeah. Cause you know and then,
oh they have more time. We
know. You know how many t no,
to get their little
piece of fucking footage.
I can't take it with the phones no more.
The guy puts it on the low
online all the time, right?
Yeah. It's like, you know what? Take
the picture. It's a nice man. I get it,
but don't start with being Scorsese and
doing a fucking feature film with me.
The guy got,
he was like, you don't want you, you
don't want to be up on youtube. I'm like,
not by, you got no luck in this
whole human being. Me and Valerie.
And he was like, and he would put it
up. This is dice his wife. Oh Geez.
Well creepy. You know what it like
when you were in the public eye. I try
to be as cool as I can with people. But
then you get the ASL when you're doing,
like I,
I really refused to do most meet and
greets because there's always going to be
the guy that wants to put
me in a headlock. Yeah.
And he's always going to regret it.
And I don't care who it is.
Why did the dude's like to do
that? Because you know, like, look,
you can add are a guy like me.
You got an attitude about yourself.
You've got a tough image about yourself.
So they want to challenge
you in front of their check.
If they get to meet you instead of
being cool and taking the picture,
they want to out macho you. And that's
where, and I don't care who it is,
I don't care if he's fucking Zillow.
You're going to pay the price for that.
And right in front of you checked.
I don't care if I am Babish you,
I don't care how big you are.
I have no fucking fear of it.
How many times you've been in fist
fights because of that? Uh, I, I've,
I've had enough problems.
I've been sued enough and you know,
but now that those things are pass me,
I could move on to the next group
of fights. It is hot. It is hard to,
to just see.
I used to run around.
That's why I would laugh when I would
see you like flipping out on people cause
some going,
thank God there's somebody else in the
business that has no fucking patience for
these assholes and this is a guy that'll
follow people out and go home with them
and argue with them.
Loved that about,
because I didn't know you
the way I came to know you.
I'm coming in the comedy store one night
and I hear that from the mic and the
stage just guide. Just you were bearing
someone, you weren't doing a bit,
you will on somebody that you just didn't
like. It was, it was Joe Rogan mean.
Oh. And I just loved it seeing
somebody get fucking buried,
you know,
cause you weren't trying to be clever.
You weren't trying to
be funny at that part.
You wanted to dismantle this
person piece by fucking piece.
And I was just so happy and enjoyed it.
Like I was hearing the funniest stuff
ever. And then when you were done,
you got back into the act and you kept
screaming about whatever you with,
you know your bits and about,
you know,
you know fucking this chick and you know,
and and I enjoyed that too.
But to walk into a place and just see
somebody so fucking angry and I never met
you.
I never saw you on stage.
And this was my first experience with
you that I had to sit down and watch and
just laugh.
Oh thank going.
This guy is just enjoying
destroying this guy with his and,
and I knew the guy deserved it.
Well there were so many ass cause he was
fuck you too. That was his big comeback.
They had fucked me too.
You want to tell me that outside?
You mother fucker.
You want to be a big shot.
You went into the whole
fucking thing and I was like,
oh what a breath of fresh air. There
was no one that would monitor the room,
the condo.
But we're responsible and it's one of
the reasons why we all became so strong,
you know, because you have no protection
in me and Brent Ernst and Sam Aaa,
we did this gig.
It's always my dad.
We did this Gig and a Africa earns,
gets off stage, you have to crush.
And he looks at me, goes comedy store
motherfucker. And I was like, yeah dude.
You know,
it's like that was a gym for us where,
and there was so many clients,
that place is a magnet
for Douche bag guys,
Tom and yell out and
try to disrupt the act.
And that's what dean of DRM on thought
it was okay to heckle, you know,
you know what I love with aren't the uh,
W W who is he? Joey, his brother. No,
no dog. Tony, Tony, Tony, Tony.
I want sweat. I made Bret go on one
night. I go, you don't understand.
It's not when you actually
start the rollers skating part.
It's, you have to explain to
the audience who Tony really is.
You got to get into his life
more. Just, Gosh, you're on stage.
You can't be afraid to expand on Tony's
life before you actually show them what
he does at the roller skating rink. Right.
You've got to talk about his history,
his family, you know, his likes,
his dislikes, what makes him happy.
So kind of bumps.
Rhett goes on one night and gets into
Tony's whole life that the crowd is like,
cause this is my type of humor
that people are looking like,
who the fuck is this guy?
He's talking and then he goes into
the bid of Tony Roller Skating.
But it was 20 minutes before we got to
the actual rovers before the music kicks
in before anything.
It's a great payoff though.
I mean we all know every Tony,
you know and Brent Arts
is such a good guy.
We were working together at
the Improv and he goes, Hey,
do you want me to not do
that? Bit like, I was like,
why would I didn't want you to not do the
best bet? He goes, because I don't know,
it's a real strong bed. I mean maybe
you don't want to follow that. And I go,
oh please, I want you to be as
funny as he can be. I enjoy that.
That's what it's about.
But that's a,
it's a weird thing where someone
for whatever reason think people,
people want to equate filth.
People want to acquaint other people's
success with somehow or another that
takes away from you.
And I think that's crazy.
It's a weird disease that people
have where you want to be.
The only person funny on
the show and you know,
and I know that there's a lot of comics
that brings up guys on the road with
them and they stack the deck.
They put terrible comedians up,
which is really not just rude to
their audience members. It's rude,
but it's also like,
so like the prodigious,
I know guys who bring up guys and there
was a national headliners do big places
and they bring up guys who shouldn't
be allowed to ever do comedy.
I mean you watch his poor audience
get assaulted with nonsense,
with nonsense in the, the fucking,
the, the rhythm of a comic.
Well see what I like to do,
like when Norman was with me,
a lot of times I would also, Steve
Simone just working for me, you know,
like road stuff. So I remember
when we were doing the, um, uh,
Venetian, okay. Some almost in
booked, there's a comic, you know,
I had Norton tope and for me
not and strong, so, you know,
we'd just backstage and we're gonna
start the show and that's when I look at
Simone and I go, you're on
deck. He goes, when he talks,
I got to go out and do your thing now
because I wouldn't want them thinking
about the act that they have. I just want
them instantly to walk out and do that.
I did it to Max to when he was younger.
Yeah. And you know, cause you know,
you got the guy coming on
before you that's going to kill.
So I like to take a
newer guy, you know, to,
to sort of train him in comedy and a guy
that really has his shit together that
I'm back there going, okay, you got
to amp up. He's killing. You know,
like when Eleanor goes up, I know if
the crowd is okay, I know if they suck,
I know if they're great, but the response
she's getting because she's top notch.
Right. You know what I mean? So when she
goes out there, I know her stuff kills.
So if they're just,
ha ha. I'm like, all right, another
shit crowd. You know what I mean?
So you've got to really be able to,
to know your audience
before you get out there.
And the only way to do it is to have an,
an unbelievably strong opener.
Because if you have somebody week,
if you have somebody weak,
you can't judge the crowd by
them because they're new. Right.
You know what I mean? Yeah. Having a
strong open is very important. It, yeah,
exactly. The whole show, the people that
don't do that are so silly. It's so dumb.
It's a, it's a weakness. It
doesn't make you look better.
So she better be strong in Chicago.
I'll tell Ya, through Brian onstage, we,
through Brian Red Band on stage in the
biggest crowd he'd ever seen and it later
was Redmond, right? Bam.
Redmans and normal name. No Red Ban.
Red Band. No, no. I get it now, but I,
I've been calling them red
man and he didn't correct him.
Whenever you want it to
be we through. No, no.
I don't want it to be with he loves you.
I want it to be what you need his name.
Tell right now. We're going to make it
red with some money. Find Red on Joey Jay,
my new buddy. Double J. Double j Rogan
and what? Jay Rogan, my new shit.
Double J GCG Oh shit. On the road.
Double J. Picture what? What, what
you think I need to get some
sort of a diamond chain,
some sort of platinum and then
two J's together. Double J.
Strong nicknames and just
take pictures like this.
I've been thinking about it on a constant
bit cause every time I call you I'm
gone. He's going to have a
nickname now. He's got to have one.
I got to find out the middle name.
Everybody has nicknames so Brian
would tumble is a cool name.
It's a good but only by your friends,
by your friends. You don't let go.
Just pull your double Jane.
If it becomes that big,
you'll have no chickens too late. I
think you just started a revolution. No,
double j is a great name. Macom
juicy for short. Thanks Sweetie.
You know what I mean? So it's
a cool name for you. I like it.
The dice man coming to Saint Charles,
Illinois dice clay show time special
at the Arcadia theater on Saturday,
August 25th. If you're in Chicago, you
need to go and check this shit out.
If you're not in Chicago,
need to get on a fucking plane
and go and check this shit out.
And if you go to oh shows o s h o w
s.com or you can call the theater.
The number for the
theater is (630) 962-7000.
I'll say it again.
(630) 962-7000.
That's not hard to remember. Bitch, relax.
And uh, the people who are listening. So,
uh, this is your first
special and 17 fucking years.
Do you have a new name for
it? The special, is it,
have you named it yet? Yeah,
I have. Is going to be
surprised. No, it's exciting.
You don't know the name of the
special. You're with me. I know,
but it's called dice and
destructible in destructive.
Change it back. No, don't talk about
it. Don't talk about them a name.
There's no reason.
Because that's the name. What if you
had like a Twitter contest to say like,
you know what the name would be? Well
you know we could do it. All right.
So on the real dice clay,
send me what you think.
Even though I'm going to use what
I already know and what are the,
I don't know what they come up with.
Well let me hear it.
Let me hear what they've got.
This unbelievable, you know, list.
It's pretty fucking good. Indestructable
cause I feel I've been through a lot.
I feel my fans have been through
a lot, you know, so, so I really,
and this show is such a rock
and roll vibe, you know,
I really want to create what I would call,
you know,
the most exciting,
standup special I've ever done.
That's what I want to give people.
How was it for you to go through all that
censorship stuff when MTV banned you?
Because you were talking about Feminine
Hygiene Products? I mean it was so, oh,
you know what it was
when my career took off,
like for the first 10 years when I was,
when I was just doing the clubs around
the country and honing my act and I would
get write ups from local papers.
They would write me up like in newspapers,
like the hoodlum of Uma, things
like that. Like it was all,
it was all positive stuff.
And then they'd write about the act.
The the day after my Hbo Special Ed,
the dice man cometh the La,
the New York Times put the headline,
the demise of Western
civilization. See, I never know,
but they ripped off.
They ripped the whole show apart and I
wasn't prepared for it because as I was
coming up as a comic, I wasn't thinking
I want to be a controversial comic. Yeah.
I wasn't even thinking,
I just did the act I wanted to do.
So it was like almost like getting
a, you know, a sucker punch.
I didn't see it common. So when all that
media backlash happened, I was like,
don't they get, I'm just a comic, I'm not
running for office here. I'm a common,
well there was something that you felt
like you were being hateful. It was like,
no, it's just towards foreigners.
And you know, there was,
there was moments where people are just
really overreacting. And I was like,
how come that's okay in rap music or
it's okay. And that all came after it.
See all that heavy rap,
all the shows like South Park,
all the controversial show came after me.
So now that I survived all that,
when I went through it was
that I stopped live crew.
What's at the same time?
Yeah, it was around the same,
because I remember you be connected
to that and all arguments about it.
So you know how many rap songs I'm in.
Yeah. I mean, even the song by that one,
EMS permission for that or do I let them
sample me because they called my office
and said Dev writing a song about
me did defending me, you know,
so we allowed them to sample,
you know,
and that song they wanted
me to present them with,
they won for best song of the year
with MTV and they wanted me to be the
presenter and still MTV when let me on it.
They still have a,
did they let it go now?
Yeah,
they unbanned me last year
when I did on Turo stupid.
I understand what happened because
when I went on MTV and did what I did,
you know, it was at a time when nobody
did that and there was no beeping.
You know, even my manager at the time,
Sandy Gallin called me up and said,
I thought that was just on my television.
Like he couldn't believe the language,
you know,
and the banding for life was one of the
greatest things that ever happened to me.
You know, I went from, you know,
from doing one show at a 20,000 seat arena
to three shows that weekend. You know,
and I was like, I don't give a fuck.
I'm not a singer. Not Today, not today.
You don't need them anymore.
They're not as important.
You doing the tonight show is not nearly
as impactful as you do in a podcast.
That's sounding, I'll never have to
worry about if you did the APP show,
it would have more because
fucking Shane Dilia head,
another comic that won't put on any
comics that'll shine that chandelier big
fuck. You know what, you know I, you
know, I never did let them in either,
but I don't have anything against him.
I think he's great at a show.
But Leno was always the type.
Like I talk about the comics that on
like he was never a type to want to help
his fellow comics.
So that's why when he brings a comic on,
they don't become superstars
because number one,
a lot of them don't even have the
chops to be on a show like that yet.
So they'll do okay.
Well he does to help Norton and nortons
an exception, not as an exception,
you know,
and he does a lot of on the street stuff.
And northern became a star before
we ever went online. All right.
But Leno doesn't look to hey sit down
like Johnny would do what you're saying.
So he doesn't create stars. He
doesn't, he's not looking to,
he only gives that this fucking
guy only cares about him.
Trust me on that.
If you really stop and think about that.
If you are a comic and you do have a show
where you occasionally I've comics on
what do you want like to promote all
your friends? No, he doesn't give a fuck.
You do it.
Let me tell you something.
No one knew me for years when,
uh,
when I was struggling and
he was already a big comic.
He was already cold hosting costs in.
And when my career took off,
he would bad mouth me to newspapers.
And I got hold of this fucking bold
ahead and the Improv. And I said,
trust me, when I tell you this next
time I won't be talking to you.
You won't even see me coming if
you ever open your fucking mouth.
I love that expression.
And he goes to me when I said
it goes with his stupid voice.
You know what I had pitched, I can't
even do this asshole. Yeah, he goes,
he goes, we weren't really expecting
to become the stars that we, and I got,
let me tell you something.
Maybe you weren't expecting
to become a big time guy,
but I knew exactly where the
fuck I was going. You know?
And it's guys like that that I don't like
because they really don't look to help.
Even the guys they bring on,
well he just filling those five
minutes like he's supposed to.
He's always been friendly
to me when I'm done to show.
So I can't say anything bad
about the guy but the hump and I,
it's okay that you're like,
just like, I don't know.
When was the last time you did an Leno
shot? I did it like a year ago. Maybe a,
yeah. When, when fear factors
back on, I did it with Ron Paul,
but a guy like you who's had
series, you know, if the series,
fear fact they've been on the road,
want to go on?
Well maybe that's the way
your friends, yeah, I'm not
asking you to go on it. Yeah,
I know my son just sky anything.
The last time I saw him I was doing this,
uh,
I was hosting this late night show with
Judd Nelson for one day and all of a
sudden somebody comes over and he
goes, uh, Leno wants to say hello.
And this was at, they had a fight with him
years earlier. So I go over to the set,
you know, and he's standing on the stage,
no one's there, and I'm just bullshit.
When am I go? So when are we doing the
show? And he goes, we need to set it up.
And I go, well, let's set it up. It's only
been 20 years, you know, and uh, he goes,
no, we're going to do it. And of course
it never happened. I'm like, what?
This is so want me to see him on
his set, you know, like I get it,
you're hosting a fucking talk show.
That to me is old fucking hat.
You know what I mean?
And that's just how I feel about.
And when you don't help your fellow
comics and you're in a position like,
like Carson was years ago, when he'd
bring a comic on, he would fucking,
he was so confident about who he was,
right?
He was just so confident that
when he bring on a Rodney
or, uh, or any new comic,
you know, he wanted you to shoot the guy.
If the guy shines, come on over, sit down,
and he'd let them shine even
more. It wasn't like, oh,
I'm giving them too
much time away from it.
You run the show every night
for 90 fucking minutes.
Give a guy five minutes to make it,
you know what I mean?
And that's where Leno in him, a two
different men, because you know,
let them and does it.
He
brings on the guys, um,
uh, uh, Kimmel does it.
They all do it. You know, I think
there's a few guys that know,
first of all,
they get how few slots there are and how
much competition there is and no one's
more aware of that than Jay.
Jay is interested in buying this next
old Volkswagen and making it look like a
hot rock. Those old code, I won't bad
mouth them because you a friend of hers,
so I'm going to let it go. He's always
been nice to me on the shots. Exactly.
So I should have never, I didn't grow
up with them. I mean I didn't call Amy.
I'll see him again.
I'll tell him how you feel.
Fucking he shook off
real fucking jerk off.
He doesn't have anything out there
that you could buy. He's a comic,
but it's hard to buy a Jay Leno CD. It's
not like it comes out with new material.
Well he does his show on the tonight show.
Does that monologue and
he doesn't shows outside,
but he recycles the same
act for the most part.
Apparently he doesn't want to do a special
because why don't we do I thank you.
Okay.
You know like
true. He doesn't, you know what I'm
saying is he doesn't put out material,
which is, which is odd. And I, his,
his reasoning for it is that it would
cost him money because he couldn't do that
act anymore and you have to write a whole
new act. I thought that was really odd.
But he's known like when he was young,
I like about Seinfeld because with,
with all his fame and everything,
he still gets out there and
he does the stand up. Yeah.
And as far as the cleaner guys,
I would have to say he's just,
well he's a master at that
kind of just the best.
But that stuff never makes me laugh as
much as you're kind of stuff I don't want.
I see observational stuff and
it's interesting. It's funny,
but it's not ridiculous.
But I go from what's behind
close doors, these, you know,
like Seinfeld. It's ridiculous.
Some of it. Yeah. And I love,
fantasy is beautiful. It's
fun, it's silly. It's,
your show is so silly. It's so fun.
Like we had such a great fucking time.
There's so much shit that you just
say it all. And it's just so well
with Norton when you were laughing at
that particular bid. I know the bit,
that's the stuff Norton and goes crazy
for you because he knows that was
absolutely no thought.
There were no facts.
But if flows grade,
it's funny fucking you know that to
me and I love Jerry Seinfeld thing.
He's a great comedian. I think it
was great as an actor on that show.
But if I had a choice, she had seen
him or you, I'd always see you.
I appreciate that kind of Hume Dam.
Why?
Because I know the kind of guy you want
and I know that's why you would come see
me cause you know I'm going to deliver
what you need for your laughs. Yeah.
I appreciate it as a,
you know like at that forum,
sorry I to look real pioneer. Uh, I'm
sorry I didn't throw somebody out for you.
Throw somebody out
like within the first two minutes what
happened right to the right. Your,
your right, your lower right. There
was a, a drunk asshole and you're like,
oh this is not gonna work. I can tell
you right now. This is not going to,
was it a ketamine moment? Guy
Was, the guy was hammer and he can
remember he, when he got up and
walked out, he couldn't even,
he didn't know what the fuck was
even happening. He was so drunk.
That's why I want him out.
You know what I mean? Don't,
don't try to help me up there.
You couldn't have worked with that guy.
I know certain guys that are just
so hammered. There's nowhere.
I calmed him down
with the band coming out that he would
be cool and they think it's a joke when I
say I'm going to throw. Yeah,
I'll give him a chance, you know?
I'll always give him a go sit in
the corner. What about tonight?
I started going up the back of 30 seconds.
Yeah.
What about when it come to the back of
the theater? When the guy got me mad,
I walked out to go and look
the bike.
I went afterwards.
That was the guy in the back of the room.
Would you do,
there was a guy in the back of the room.
Got On my nerves and get
security out of this,
get this Guy Outta here and
nobody's coming. So I go, look,
I'll throw you out personally, I don't
care. I don't know what you look like.
I don't know. I'm coming to get you.
And I just went towards the back and,
but at the time I was nearly there. They
had security, Paul and the guy. Yeah.
Oh my God. Oh, oh, you
want to hit a burst? Oh,
this is great. A couple weeks ago and
met governors in Long Island and like,
you know,
now and then I get the real ass hole and
there's a guy with dark glasses like me
and he's fucking drunk and be an asshole.
So I said,
open your fucking mouth again and
I'll throw you the fuck outta here.
Let's see what happens. You
know? And the guy's just yelling.
He don't even know what
he's yelling. So, you know,
they got tough guys working at governors,
so they come to throw the
guy out after the show.
Don Jamison goes,
you missed the greatest thing I ever
saw at one of these shows. I go,
what happened? He goes, you know
the guy you threw out, he was blind.
I go, what? He goes,
not only was he blind,
he was fighting for the guys
here going fucking dice.
I'll kick his fucking ass all
day and talk to me like that.
And these guys couldn't hold them down.
They said he had like retarded strength,
you know, and he's swinging his fucking
stick at them. He's swinging the stick.
I go, well, you know,
it's not like he had a dog with
him that I could know he's blind.
All I know is was a drunk asshole
and he got what was coming to them.
You know what I mean?
But you know,
I would've liked to see that
at least to get it on film.
That's a great youtube piece
that I did filming anything.
Why didn't the guy take out
his phone and fund them?
Fighting him so he
could put it on youtube.
He didn't even see them
coming to throw them out.
We're eventually all going to have those
Google goggles on and you won't need a
youtube or an eye on iPhone.
It's going to,
but we're going to film everything you
see through your eyes. They're already,
we're already working on it. Yeah.
There's just no privacy. Google,
there's Google goggles is legit,
man. They, they put it on,
it's got a little small
lands in the corner.
It's like you're a fucking terminator.
It's like you have this readout. You can,
you could get navigation photo. It's
going to buy it. You could take photos.
You're going to make video. You gonna
be able to broadcast in shit out.
What happened at fun?
Well,
what happened to progress
and technological innovation.
It's going to keep going and not
going to stop it. If you want a car,
you got to deal with the consequences
that people want and time travel. Okay.
Because it's all comes
from the same place.
It all comes from people figuring out
amazing shit. People figure it out.
Amazing Shit and they never stopped.
They will never fucking stop ever.
And Google goggles is going to
lead to Google contact lenses,
which is going to lead to
Google neural implants,
which is going to lead to who knows
what kind of fun to my retirement.
I'm fucking luck getting those.
Get some tests before you die.
What the fuck you like about it?
You know what I mean?
You know she's a nice girl.
Which all don't stuff your ass though.
She's only shows your ass.
Don't think that's what I'm saying.
The dimensions you don't under. She's
not built for big tits. She, she's,
she's got plenty. You're right and a half
feet wide. You're, you're eight inches.
Eight and a half inches wide.
If you measure with broad woman her
depth and it just strikes me, man.
I'm telling you.
Look at it.
Have you seen with Kim Kardashian
has done to her ass? I don't pay any.
Apparently there's new
video of it and some,
some guy on youtube and said it looked
like she was wearing a diaper filled with
pudding. She's got another ass
job. She's got her ass larger. No,
no doubt. I don't know why she quit.
She probably had a half a decent,
well she only had one shot at, I
mean, I don't mind the reality show.
I mean fucking movie she made,
she was on the money.
Wouldn't it be great to watch her fuck
one of those giant super athletes that
she fucks
the movies.
Even that movie she did like nobody
really talks about it enough.
You know what I mean? Because she was
a natural work. Great work. Right?
She's a natural attention whore.
No,
but what I'm saying is why quit cinema
now that you've got your TV show?
Well she thinks that that
got her to the dance,
but there's more money legitimately in
commercials like for Skechers when you go
to the airport and you want to go to put
your fucking wallet in the band, you'll
check this morning. I want to look
at it. You got to, this is really,
it's really strange. It's really
strange. Watch. Look at her ass.
But I mean it doesn't even look
real like watch, watch when they,
they're focused on it. Like what? Check
it. Check it. Check it. Here we go.
What's that? What the fuck
that, what the fuck is that?
She's wearing a diaper filled.
We're putting back a
little bit Brian Motion.
She is listened. Shit. Don't,
don't get me wrong. I'm not hating.
Did this part is the boring part.
You want to get past this?
You want to go to the
others? Yeah. Not this part.
From here on this is,
this is where it gets crazy slow motion.
Look what's going on there.
What's that? That's not even real.
That is not real man.
She's doing something crazy
because it doesn't match her ledge.
She looks like the Penguin I
in that Batman movie, dude,
it's not real because her upper body's
not changing. Her arms aren't changing.
She's stuffing her ass like a Turkey.
It's just craziness.
It's absolute complete madness because
the way she had a beautiful body to begin
with, you know what it is. They get
so affected that they can't do enough.
Like when they blow up that lips like
Betty boop. You know what I mean?
They do that whole, you know what the
fuck? That's sad. None of it works.
The the lips don't work. Look,
you want it for a young girl.
Somebody that doesn't need this shit,
but tits work. It does work too,
but she doesn't have the frame.
It shouldn't do it. She'd get the
frame. I probably would have
already done it. I was a girl.
I'd probably have giant tits. I'd
probably a 38 double D's I fucked that.
Had the biggest house in Bel Air. If I was
a check, I wouldn't even think of work.
We'll put little crutches in front
of me and I'll walk like that.
Wheeler's put some wheels.
She always talks about it,
but that's the 300 does
snap them on their breasts,
breasts or someone acceptable? I wouldn't
ever, man would prefer natural breasts.
Breasts are somewhat acceptable,
but there's nothing that
we're, the ass is wrong.
It's wrong.
Am doing something crazy,
especially when a woman can have
really nice legs just by working out.
That's what we learned. I don't know
about you, but you know what I mean.
Check out this ass Katy Perry the other
day and one of those water parks her.
She lost her. Let me see
here. Let me get to it.
Right. Well, should you
have image right here?
She has big boobies.
How?
Come on?
That's photo shops. No, it's
not. There's, there's a lot
of them. There's a lot. Yeah.
There's a lot of photos.
There's people just,
I wouldn't fold her right
out of the pool and look at,
nope,
you know what? This is where we think
the same way make it. But first of all,
I don't,
I don't buy that.
That just happened and she's out
swimming with a bunch of fuckers.
This is all it's about. It's a
publicity stunt. That's right.
They did it on purpose. They're trying
to get more people to go see her movie.
The box office returns probably
weren't what they expected. So Pete,
let's find out more about Katie out
and now that we've seen her ass,
here's their movie. Oh God, I'm not
buying it. I love all of you know,
I don't buy it, but I enjoy it. I do too.
She's got a killer and
master gas masks like that.
I would want the world to
said dip kid dick in and move
on. Show everybody. Right.
You stream new shoe stream.
They'll pause you just showed
was that to get fucking Russell Crowe,
cause this is the new guy
dipping his dick in and Oh,
you know what I mean?
All these filthy slobs that dead.
His wife gave me a spray Tan.
She has a film that day.
Are you enjoying it? And she took a
picture of me and put it on Facebook.
I wasn't does all the
hair and make up shit.
She's unbelievable.
But she's just practices.
They got the spray machine that it looks
hilarious. She paints you orange. No,
but what she did,
she put a tent in the backyard the
other day and she put a 10 shut.
Shut up. Shut up. I'm
trying to promote Valerie.
Oh come on please. Do you believe what?
I'm going to go extra. I'm no girl.
I'm nice enough to put her
on your show. Yeah, no girl.
And she just has zero respect for men.
You know, I came home on Saturday
for, you know, with Max and uh,
so she had like a barbecue
with the spray tanning party,
but I wasn't allowed to film a look cause
they like got to get addressed and uh,
ms panties comes out,
you know,
just in her panties and I'm like,
I can't film this,
you know, I can't, you know, I need the
footage here. Right. Cause you know,
that's like the one thing, I
don't know, it's got going on.
You know the back,
we've got a big ass,
this is a guy that on Twitter that says
that Kim Kardashians actually got an x
ray of her ass to show and prove that
it's real. He did that. His name is right.
Well you know what? Then she's just
eating too much ranch dressing.
I'll say it again, Ryan. I mostly, Nah,
I'm just know what it does is my wife,
how come there's, how's there ever
picture with the picture come from?
It's on I your wife, you
have a fun dumper. Yeah.
You see what I mean? And
so there's another one.
Look at it. Oh my God, Valerie.
I thought there was only one.
Is there any more full of shit?
You told us about it.
You knew he was going to search for it.
Girls are so God damn predictable.
You're seeing my nice body and
the photographic form online.
I told you it was online and now you're
looking at it. That's crazy up there.
I don't care. I do the picture
for us. You do care. So
just say with the fucking Facebook
and you wanted beauty is pain.
Pain.
Hello?
Oh, okay. You wanted every
once in a PGW about them.
Isn't that a code? Shows cost her.
Fuck. This shows a total cluster.
Fuck you like the olive garden.
No girls, no gross. Why
no girl dice not allowed
too much animosity.
Too much history between the jars.
Too much crossover where you
don't realize it's a podcast.
You both talk at the same time. It's
too crazy. I'm trying to pull out.
He's got to like see how you
just overlapping. Oh, you will.
You just overlapping.
Guess who's fired?
Jesus was fired. Now you're fired.
That dice man to Saint Charles,
Illinois. Andrew dice clay,
showtime special, the arcade.
A theater on set. You don't steal
my employees, man. Saturday,
August 25th the arcade,
a theater go to oh shows.
That's o s h o w s.com all or call the
theater at (630) 962-7000 you want to be
there. You want to be there for history.
He says this is his last special.
I say bull shit because it was
anything like what I saw in Vegas.
People gonna fucking demand you produce
more. It's not that I'm that retirement
plan on touring a lot. Good. It's weird
if that's what I really wanted to listen.
That's what I want to say, man.
It was a fucking artist in Vegas.
I was just going to say it's, I, I, I
love that there's guys like you out there.
It's, it's so important to me as a, as a
person who loves standup comedy and as,
even if I never did stand up again in
my whole life. I'm a fucking fan of it.
I love it and you're going to see a lot.
Thank you.
It's really fun and don't think,
I didn't love that you guys were there.
I know when your,
when your fellow comics come to see you,
you know it's like exciting.
So you know that what that show was for
you when the guys know that performance
was about you and the guy couldn't care
less if everybody else left the room.
It fires me up creatively
when I go see a show.
Like the last time I saw show up before
yours was Norton's and it just gets me
so fired up to them to perform
and to right. You know?
And I think whether we really,
comics really feed off other comics
and we get inspired by other comics.
So the really be able to sit down and
have to watch a real show was really a lot
of time, a lot of fun. Man.
I just want to say thank you and thanks
to Eleanor for interrupting whatever
Dyson. Everybody knows we were
kidding. Just kidding. Come on, we,
everybody knows we were kidding.
And Eleanor really is. I mean, I
don't know how much better you got,
but when I saw you in Irvine, which was
more than two years ago, I'm almost,
well February, it'll be six years.
I was really blown away. I mean,
you were really professional already.
Yeah,
but you know what it was is like you saw
so much shit comedy. You saw so many.
Yeah.
You saw so many old dying road hacks that
will do the same act for decade after
decade.
Do Nixon jokes and shit and you be like,
it's 2000 it's 2000 and people
were doing jokes about Ford.
Nobody knows who Ford is.
Mrs. Back when Eleanor was working
there and you know you were, it's,
it's awesome that you're doing comedy
because it was beautiful to watch you and
stay there at night. I was like,
finally, you know, and nailed it after
Andrew's house and all this bullshit.
She always wanted to do
comedy and she's great at it.
You gotta do it yourself every
night before she goes on. We, we,
we pound each other,
you know,
and I opened the cart and I never
miss a show no matter what's going on.
And it's just so great to,
to have like the feeling that I know my
open is going out and kill in. Right.
And it's just somebody that happens to
be family to me, you know what I mean?
And then of course with Max and now
we've got la rocks and my boys had just
fucking slamming it.
I've been trying to tell all my comedian
friends that hate the road. I'm like,
you got to go out with other friends.
You got to go out with your goal.
The only way to do it,
you're wasting your time.
If you go out and you work with some
local headliner who wants to blow you off
the stage. Yeah. And they, and they
step on your material on purpose.
I mean it happens to a lot of my friends,
they'll do gigs and the guy will see
their act the first night and the second
night they bring up the
same subjects on purpose.
Who tried to kill their best bits?
Yeah.
Cause they want to have a better set
than you. He knows he's from Brooklyn,
very spoiled being with Andrew very well.
Of course he lets me do my own thing
and the crowd. I always tell him
I never give up. I never give her
time. I just say, when you peek,
just get off this.
I'm going to say right now you
guys both together need a podcast.
You know fucking easy. It
would be, this is all you need.
This is all you need is an
iPhone. You on a plane, so listen,
listen, you were on a plane, you are
in a restaurant. You where you're,
you're in your hotel room wherever
you are, you having an argument,
turn on your iPhone,
turning a fucking iPhone and record the
argument and they just put dice versus
Eleanor and put on iTunes and the,
anytime you guys get in an argument,
you record dice versus Neller and
have it a fucking long running gag.
The real arguments, you can't fake
your arguments, but then that would be,
that would be hilarious.
It's going to get yelled at for
just talking at the same time,
not letting somebody,
well Brian Callen,
crystally and a will Sasso have this
10 minute podcasts. It's a great idea.
It's only 10 minutes.
So with you guys,
you'd never know what kind of
an argument you're into it.
It might be a half an hour. It
might be the podcast Mike. Oh,
but it's fun for, I'm annoyed
me more. I'm thinking no
dice versus
right maximum at the pool or
the boss. Yeah, that's right.
I'm the bowl.
Come.
My son knows when to talk and
when not to ice versus Eleanor.
You just go and go and go and then
it's the thread of Deborah. Oh,
tell my brother. Ds me at.
Are you going to be quiet for
a moment here? Thanks dice.
Thanks for doing the show.
I really appreciate it.
Welcome Joe. A longtime fan.
It's an honor to be your friend.
It's an honor to have you on
and I feel the same exact way,
but we would love to have full
desk quad support of the dice. Man,
come at the Saint Charles, Illinois.
Go out there folks. Buy those tickets.
I'm telling you from the bottom of my
heart as a comic who's been a comic for
almost 25 years,
that was a great fucking show.
And me and Jim Norton to longtime
professionals and Bobby Kelly time
professional. We fucking howled.
We had a great time. And you gotta,
you gotta love it. Kelly Love him. He's
a great guy. You're going to love it.
Go Out, go out and see it. Go to
[inaudible] dot com go to the arcade,
a theater and the showtimes
are at seven and 9:30 PM.
So go buy some tickets. He dirty bitches
and support the man. Thank you sir.
Thanks to [inaudible] dot com
for supporting our podcast.
Thanks to Alienware for sponsoring us and
giving these bad ass fucking computers
and most important that sponsored and
that's rather it be providing us with
computers. But you know what,
I'll use one if they give me one.
Well I'll get you one. I'll get
you one. I'll use that. They uh,
they would love to have you use them
there. Um, they support this wood.
What's important to me. They sponsor a
lot of fighters of his lungs are a lot.
I love make up the little face. Yeah,
me too. And he said a lady bug? No,
it's an alien.
Oh Shit. Oh No. Cause it's,
it looks like an alien should make
a dice model. That's a lady bug.
Um, it's a, it's a great computer.
If you'd like to play games,
they want to play games. It's literally
like a desktop computer. Excuse me,
a desktop gaming computer that you can
carry around with you, which most laptops,
they don't have the uh, the,
the horsepower to, to deliver
like highspeed graphics.
So when you play games on them,
they look shitty and colon.
But like you could go to my space
and everything. Tell him email. Yeah.
You go to Friendster and you get
to do whatever you gotta do it.
Yeah. You can check out,
check out your AOL mail. Yeah,
you can do whatever you want with it.
It's a real computer windows. It's a,
it's a great computer. Look at
that. And as far, like I said,
as far as gaming computers, they're
top of the food. You have one.
They give you one? Yeah, he's got a three.
So, um, what's the guy's name? Uh, well,
the guys deal with this.
His name is Cody from Alienware.
Brian Butler from some Sucker Punch and
attainment. I need like three of them.
Three of them. Listen. Well,
no, cause they need to use them.
I'm going to show a lot of people,
maybe if you start a podcast or something,
they'll hook you up with three. It's
going to be hard to get three out of them,
but they probably got them in the trunk.
You know what I mean? Maybe. I don't know.
You know what I mean?
Thanks to onnit.com if you're
interested in any supplements,
go to [inaudible] dot com and
check out what we've got to offer.
Alpha brain shroom tech sport shroom.
Take immune bones strong.
A new bone density supplement.
What Joe Rogan? Yes.
Did you know there's certain substances
have been shown to increase the fucking
strength of your bones on go get
yourself some kettlebells, gay guy.
You know what? The kettle bells and
I take a couple of them, that's me.
I sell them. Oh, you sell, you'll brand
that like robot. We sell them on on it.
I'm a part owner and on at.com
double J. Kettle bull, kettle balls,
kettle ball, and then it's kettle,
but it's kettle. Get a bowl. Oh yeah.
But you can have the
McDouble j kettle balls.
I don't think he didn't want to
hear that. I can pull, you know,
and you give it like the
look Brian, you silly, silly,
silly bitch on a Dotcom for supplements.
Use a code name Brogan.
Try out the new hemp force protein
powder to answer questions.
No Ham force will not make you
taste test positive for THC.
You could take hemp force. It has no
psychoactive substance in it whatsoever,
but it does have Maca,
which makes your dick hard and raw cocoa,
which is a powerful antioxidant and
it's sweetened by Stevia. So it's all,
it's only one gram of sugar per serving
and it's fucking tastes delicious and
it's really easy to digest. It's, it's
not, it's not cheap stuff. It's expensive,
but it's the highest quality
stuff that we could sell.
Can I ask you something
about that? Sure. That's,
it doesn't have like that stuff
in it that you shouldn't have. No,
there's no artificial sweeteners in it.
It's always sweetened by Stevia,
which is actually just a plant extract.
But what about lately have fed over
stuff and all? No, no, no. None of that.
None of that.
It's all going after that.
Then what it is the best plant based
protein powder you can buy and it's the
most easily digestible protein powder.
It doesn't give you any bloating.
And I love whey protein powder.
I love like muscle milk and those things.
They're delicious. But they make
me Fart, man. They, they're,
they like give you a bloated feeling.
Sometimes.
It's not the same clean feeling that I
get when I eat a hemp protein powder.
I think it's one of the most
easily digestible. But, uh,
if you're interested in any of this stuff,
go to [inaudible] dot com for supplements.
Use a code name Brogan.
Save yourself 10% off for battle ropes
and kettle bells that that code name does
not work because we sell them
as cheap as is humanly possible.
They're the best quality,
athletic and sports equipment,
things that are available, and that's all
we're ever going to sell. If we sell it,
it's the best shit that we can get.
It's stuff that we would use
ourselves and with the supplements,
there's a 30 day, or excuse
me, for 31st order, 30 pills,
100% money back guarantee. You don't
even have to bring back the supplements.
You just say, I didn't like Alpha
brain. That's it. You're done.
You're going to like it
because it's fucking awesome.
Go to [inaudible] Dot Com o.N n I. T.
All right, you dirty freaks tomorrow.
The great Everlast will join us and I'm
going to do a nighttime podcast with
Brian's best friend, Duncan Trussell.
We'll see dirty bitches soon.
And don't forget death squad Friday at
the ice. Yeah, that's right. Super show.
Ridiculously stacked. Greg
Fitzsimmons, dom Irrera PR. Who else?
Joey Diaz.
Joey motherfucking Diaz.
Tony Hinchcliffe baby as special guests,
maybe a special guests and me bitches.
So a Friday night, we're in top form.
These shows have been fucking spectacular.
Never had better. Ice House chronicles
podcast. Never had better shows.
We're having the time.
I fucking lives here in Pasadena.
And it's mostly because of you
guys. I mean, we have to show up,
but if you guys didn't send
us so many positive tweets,
and if there wasn't such an awesome group
of human beings that meets us at every
city, all over the world, it wouldn't
be nearly as fun. So thank you all.
We appreciate the fuck out of
you and we'll see you soon. Bye.