Hello Freak bitches.
It's societal standards and culture is
a,
is a big part of this.
The way people decide what's acceptable,
what's not acceptable.
So to these people,
I think for us growing up in America,
it's almost impossible to understand
what it would be like to be living in
like one of the most radicalized parts
of the world can understand the radical
behavior,
which is why I have no problem saying
that a guy who went and did nothing but
became radicalized.
Like to me that's,
that's a wrote mathematical equation
right there.
Like right.
It's a,
it's a hard one because you know,
people still say to this day and age
like,
you know,
you shouldn't,
you shouldn't kill,
right.
We need to,
the counter insurgency strategy is based
off winning the hearts of minds of the
people that were going into the
countries that we're going into.
And I think the only way that I can
describe it that makes sense to people
with it might at least allow them to
think outside of the education aspect.
Is that,
and you kind of,
you,
you alluded to the point a little bit,
but I mean you have daughters,
right?
Do you love your daughters?
Yeah.
Like how much though?
Like articulate for me how much you
love,
it's impossible for anybody to ever
express it in a way that someone who
doesn't have daughters would ever
understand or sons or children.
Totally.
And so love is a good analogy because if
you can understand how hard it is to
articulate that,
then you understand that there's another
side of that coin and that there's a
community of people somewhere on earth
that hates you to the exact same degree
that you love your children and can't
articulate and would do everything they
fucking can to end our way of life.
Because we let women go outside and have
their skin exposed.
You can say what you want,
you can think what you want.
And what's the solution to solve that?
It's not books.
There's not as a single,
I could,
I could put you in captivity for 14
years,
Joe and I could never convince you not
to live your daughters.
Right?
There's,
this is not our job to change.
But what I'm saying,
hold on,
let me what happened?
So what I'm saying is though is that
people think that there's,
there's just like,
oh,
you don't have to go over there and you
don't have to fight.
Well fuck that.
At some point you have to stand up for
what you believe in.
Right?
And when it comes to those people that
hate you as much as you love your kids,
again,
there's a small segment of that that you
could probably turn with books in
captivity,
right?
Which is what's happening to the guys
who get radicalized and get Mo.
But for the other segment that would
like nothing more than to end your life
and everything you believe in.
What's the solution?
It's not fucking books.
You know?
What is the solution to try to turn a
guy around once they've reached that
level,
radicalization he can't.
So you either have to find something or
believe in something to the point that
you're willing to fight for it.
Because here's the deal.
We're x people.
And then there's why people,
and regardless of what your x is,
your Christian Catholic,
whatever your next person,
there's somebody who's a white person,
x and y people are going to fight.
If you believe in what you believe
enough,
then to protect that at some point
you're going to have to go beyond the
educational aspect of that.
And then by the time it's the podcast
starts.
So what's up man?
You
know,
you learn,
you learn a lot about yourself,
like listening to you listen to your own
podcast.
I you to the good ones.
I don't at all.
I can't,
I can't stand this.
I have no desire to listen to myself.
The only time is when I'm going through
mastering the system,
my tutorial,
I do sit there and I am interested in
how I'm teaching and what I said and how
I could have made the point clear in my
teaching.
So I,
I uh,
that's the only time,
but when it's a podcast and I'm not
talking about you did sit and I'm just
talking about like just bullshit.
I don't want to hear myself.
It's good to hear though.
But for the same reason like you realize
why you were annoying to you like I
have,
I've found things that I didn't know I
did like little s little ticks,
little weird things like people do like
a big one is saying like people like
there's like Tom Segura I loved him to
death.
That motherfucker out likes me.
He hurts me sometimes.
Like,
like there's like a way like if you got
like a guy like in his like a way like
ah,
did he say that or everybody does and
what guys are telling a story.
It's hilarious.
And he's like,
she came up to me and started mad
dogging me and I was like,
what the fuck you looking at?
I paid for all that shit.
And you didn't say none of that.
You just said I was like that.
I had that look on my,
but I didn't say shit.
And if you don't question did you
actually say that?
You're like,
no.
I was like,
I was,
I was thinking like by one of the ass
too,
you would have made it seem like you
were just bad motherfucker.
And this story [inaudible] out of you
can say shit,
and I was like,
fuck you for that shit.
He said that,
no,
no.
I thought it like I thought it.
Fuck you and you all and where you came
from,
bitch,
did you actually say to him,
no,
man,
I hate that.
Another one.