Do we have enough left for tomorrow?
We don't have tomorrow.
I'll bring the sweet
Ben Shapiro.
We are live.
The people have spoken.
Well,
thank you for having me.
Thanks for being here,
man.
I became a fan of yours when I watched
you.
Um,
uh,
with what the fuck is his name?
The CNN asshole.
Piers Morgan.
That was glorious when you went after
him with the sandy hook thing,
like right away.
Immediately,
like a,
it was just glorious and you could tell
that he didn't know what to do with it
and he literally said,
how dare you,
which is what I say to people all the
time when I'm joking you was one of my
friends had it looked like he was
clutching his pearls.
He was really pissed.
He was really good.
It was a two segment interview and
during the break I said to him,
thanks so much for having me on any kind
of growled at me.
He was not a happy camper.
He.
Yeah.
Well you crushed him.
And the other,
one of my other favorite ones was
Chelsea handler crushing him where she
was literally talking like,
you don't even talk to me in the break
and the break.
You're checking your phone and checking
twitter and,
and he,
you could tell he was like,
oh no,
he just came from that Weird British
tabloid environment and you found out
that the company that he worked for did
really creepy shit.
Like check people's voicemails.
They hacked into people's people who are
dead and they gave the family false hope
because they had checked the voicemail
and they found out that someone checked
in,
they thought,
oh,
maybe she's still alive.
And then we made him a host on like the
x factor.
I brought him on.
CNN is awesome.
I just don't make any decisions on,
around why CNN thought that we have this
fascination with British people.
Yes.
If you have a British accent,
we automatically add 20 points here.
Icu.
Yeah.
They're great for like selling mops,
late night and nonstick cookware.
And I enjoyed John Oliver.
I think John Oliver's great.
And apparently he has a,
you know,
a lot of people think of all British
accents as being the same,
but he has like a blue collar British
accent.
But I don't,
I,
I can't tell the difference too much
except for when I'm watching my fair
lady or something.
Well,
I could tell people from Manchester and
stuff like that because they,
they,
you know,
they have like the sort of way of
talking so fast that all the words kind
of pile into each other.
But uh,
yeah,
Oliver's,
his uh,
his recent one.
Eddie Bravo got really mad at it.
The recent one about,
uh,
Alex Jones is fucking hilarious.
I don't know if you've seen it.
It's almost impossible to make something
not funny about Alex Jones.
You've got to meet Alex.
have you met him?
I don't know that given how much I've
made fun of him.
Fine.
He says strip off his shirt and he might
be,
they'd calm down.
You're a good guy.
We're basically on the same team.
He would come around if you remember the
piers Morgan thing happened two nights
after Alex was on Piers Morgan said,
Elena.
So appears was like flying high because
he had that whole debate with Alex and
Alex did his shtick and it was really
over the top and he thought I was going
to be like Alex Jones prior to and who's
going to be peers succeeds again and
Alex and I could not be more different
than our britches.
No,
you're very rational and very reasonable
and we've been talking about some your
debates.
There's not a lot of guys like you out
there,
which is really interesting.
It's like you're a fast thinking,
fast talking.
Very smart young guy who's also a
conservative,
like there's not a lot of those out
there.
And this is one of the things that we're
encountering today is there,
especially in college campuses,
there's this very strange separation
between the left and the right to the
point where the right is like almost
nonexistent or at least doesn't have any
representation and they're actively
shunning that representation.
Like they're pushing people out.
I know what's going on with you in
Berkeley.
Has that been written seven resolved?
Yeah,
I think that uh,
so,
so Berkeley,
after the publicity they said they're
going to explain to people if they don't
know the whole story.
Yes.
So UC Berkeley,
if you recall,
last year,
I actually spoke there before any of
this happened.
I spoke to UC Berkeley and April 2016
and then Milo was supposed to speak
there and he actually went there and
there was a riot where antifa
infiltrated the student community and
there are all these pictures of them
bombing things and blowing up cars and
then understanding them in a fire at
least in and throwing things at windows.
And so Berkeley shut down that event for
safety reasons.
Then Ann Coulter wanted to speak there
and they basically used what they called
time,
place and manner restrictions to stop
her.
They kept saying,
well we have safety problems,
we can't figure out how to do the event.
And in the end they just canceled it
because they didn't have security.
And then young Americans foundation
which sponsors me to go to a lot of
these campuses,
they.
So we want Shapiro to come and again I
spoke to like a year and a half ago and
they give them two and a half months
advance and Berkeley said,
well we have no venues available and so
this seemed to be another cover for.
We're not going to allow a conservative
on campus because their security
problems.
So we made that public and then Berkeley
said,
no,
we'll,
we'll make,
we'll make sure that you get in.
They give us an alternative venue and do
they even said they covered the security
things?
They didn't like the bad publicity.
Oh,
well that's nice.
Yeah.
So that should be good.
Well you know what happened with Jordan
Peterson yesterday?
Yes.
Yeah,
just yesterday,
Jordan Peterson was banned from youtube
and Youtube has a new policy that uh,
it's very,
it's very weirdly worded,
but apparently they're allowed to block
and restrict any kind of videos that are
about religion or that could be deemed
offensive,
which is almost everything.
Yeah,
that's right.
And anything that's remotely,
if I mean,
anything that's interesting is,
is going to be offensive to somebody.
So won't be monetize,
it also won't be in the videos of
interest or
I know they did this to a prager
university as well.
They had blocked like 10 of their videos
a couple of months ago.
So it's,
it's.
Yeah,
I mean this is nasty stuff and listen,
youtube as a private company,
they have the right to do what they want
but don't proclaim that are a free
speech promoting institution.
If you're going to block people like
Jordan,
well the the problem is they're not
blocking things that are offensive to
other people there.
They're not blocking certain things that
are representing Islam in a positive
light.
There's,
there's a lot of weirdness with this
left wing choice of what to sensor and
what not to censor and it's not just
dangerous.
It's also bad for the whole idea of
being a progressive or being liberal
cause it makes you look.
It makes them look really petty and
really weird and really resistant and
hesitant to actually have real debate.
Yeah,
for sure.
And this is one of the reasons why I'm
very meticulous in my terminology about
people who are on the other side of the
aisle,
actually separate people who are liberal
from people who are leftists.
So when there are people who try to band
speech,
I call them leftist,
and if they are not interested in
banding speech,
then their liberal,
meaning they want bigger government,
they disagree with me on politics,
but they're still willing to have a
conversation and they want an open
forum.
People who are on the hard left think
that it's actually an insult to their
identity to disagree with them.
And this is what I experienced sometimes
on,
on campuses,
you know,
at cal state la where there's a near
riot when I speak,
or University of Wisconsin where people
stormed the stage and stand in front of
it and won't leave or state where we
have,
again,
another near violence incident over at
Penn state or depaul where they actually
banned me outright.
So sometimes you get this routine,
uh,
from people who think that they conflate
their viewpoint with their identity.
And then if you have a different
viewpoint,
you're denying them their humanity and
it's like,
no,
I'm not the nine years.
I just think what you're saying is dumb.
Like
good point.
That's a very good point is that they
have their identity completely connected
with their ideology.
And when you oppose these people,
when you have these debates or these
people,
what's really fascinating is the level
of a stereo that gets reached while
you're staying calm.
Yeah.
That's what I've noticed is that there's
a ton of.
You know,
I,
I tend to keep relatively calm just as a
human being and very often when I'm
debating someone,
you see them getting more and more and
more emotional and people on the right
love this because of course it's the
triggering of the snowflakes are the
easiest thing in the world to do is
trigger some idiot college kid who
doesn't know his ass from a hole in the
ground and what.
What's.
What's hard to do is actually discuss
issues with somebody who is intelligent
enough to make the,
to make the point.
But it's the level of hysteria on the
campuses has really increased.
I mean,
I know you have to travel with two
members of security to every campus just
because you don't know which campus is
going to go off.
I never had to travel security before.
It's the weirdest thing in the world.
How long ago did this start happening?
Well,
in February of Twenty 16 is when I
started traveling with security,
so I spoke at University of Missouri.
They remember they had the big blow up a
university of Missouri with black lives
matter taking over campus offices and
suggesting that there was some sort of
big racism problem at Missou,
which is just ridiculous.
And so they flew me and I did a speech
there and then the next time I spoke was
cal state La and they brought in a
couple of security guys and I was like,
what do I need security for?
But I'm just speaking on a campus who
cares?
We get to the campus and they had
already tried to cancel my speech
because of security and I said,
I'm coming anyway.
So tough.
I had to be escorted in by 20 armed
police officers.
I had to be escorted off campus by
motorcycle cops flashing their lights.
There were 300 students who had blocked.
All of the entrances were physically
assaulting people,
trying to get into the theater.
The police had to sneak the students in
two by two into the theater.
They told them that until I left the
campus,
they couldn't actually let the kids out
of the theater because they were afraid
that if they let the kids out of the
theater,
there'd be attacked as they got,
as they were released.
It was.
That one was pretty well.
It's after that.
It was okay.
Well,
I guess the security is necessary.
Wow.
What is shifting?
Like what?
What is,
what is ramping things up?
I think the identity is ramping things
up,
so I think there's a new mentality out
there.
It's this intersectionality politics on
the left that says that there are a
bunch of victim groups basically are
there blacks and Hispanics and gays and
Jews and Asians.
They're all victim groups and we get
those all those people together to
attack the system because the system is
keeping them down and if you.
And,
and there's a hierarchy among these
victim groups,
and if you are a straight white male,
you're at the very,
very bottom of the hierarchy in terms of
viewpoints that should be acknowledged
because you're the creators of this vast
white supremacist system that keeps down
everybody else.
So if you're a black woman,
you're near the top right?
If you're LGBT,
you're at the top.
If you're a white guy and you challenged
the viewpoint of a black woman,
your viewpoint is an attack on her
identity and therefore she has the right
to shut you down.
And so the idea is that your words are
violence to her identity and therefore
she has the right to react.
This is the term you hear on campus a
lot is microaggressions as idea that my
opinion microaggressive you know,
even that terminology I think is really
stupid because normally in regular life
we would say that's insulting.
And he said something,
I don't like the terminology.
Microaggression suggests aggression.
Like I'm actually doing something
aggressive to you.
And the rational response to someone
aggressing you is to use physical force
in response.
And so you start,
you start to see a more violent
response.
I think that's.
It's been growing in our politics.
I think there's a reactionary side on
the right that's,
that's growing.
And if there's an identity politics on
the left that says now black identity
politics,
gay identity politics,
female identity politics,
I think you're starting to see in some
areas of white identity politics that's
almost formed in response.
Like,
okay,
well if everybody else gets to have
their identity politics,
why can't we defend ourselves on those
same grounds?
I hate that shit.
It's terrible.
I hate that shit too.
And I would like to find the person who
invented the term microaggression,
that fucker,
whoever it was,
they.
They created quite a mess.
Now,
I'm sure you saw what happened at
Evergreen with Bret Weinstein.
We're,
we're literally left is eating itself
and that's where it gets crazy.
He's like,
you're not progressive enough unless
you're literally submitting to leaving
your class because you're white.
Like you can't be there because you're
white.
They want a day of absence,
meaning the professors,
the white people.
And then when you don't do it,
you're somehow in other racist and a
Nazi.
I mean,
the whole thing is,
the whole thing was very bizarre to
watch,
but,
but not not surprising because you see
it so much so often all over the country
right now and it's almost like some new
flower of ridiculous thinking and
behavior has blossomed and it's in bloom
everywhere.
And when people can point to it existing
in other places,
like in Missouri where that woman,
what was her name?
Who was that woman who got the click?
Yeah,
whatever her name was that when you see
it in video,
when you see her on video saying,
can we get some muscle over here?
Like this is fucking insane.
Like you're,
you're telling a photographer and by the
way,
a minority and Asian Asian man taking
photos of a public place that you've
created some safe space.
But it's,
it's,
it's this weird thing where it's half of
it is identity politics,
but it's also wrapped up in this need to
control people and control people's
behavior.
Control their vernacular,
control the way they communicate.
And how you know how much you give in to
group think it's weird.
It's scary.
And a Jonathan Heit who's a social
psychologist over at Nyu,
he did a really good piece for the
Atlantic in 2015 about this phenomenon,
this kind of safe space,
trigger warning phenomenon.
This idea that you must never be forced
into a position where someone has an
idea that opposes yours.
And what he said is it basically makes
people crazy.
You know,
it actually makes you crazy that the
idea in psychology is that if you have a
chain of thoughts leading to a bad
outcome,
if you're depressed or if you're an
oppressive,
then you have a chain of thoughts
leading to a bad outcome.
The way that psychologists deal with
that is with cognitive behavioral
therapy.
They say,
okay,
we're in this chain of thoughts are
going wrong.
Are you attributing to somebody a motive
they don't have?
Or does your wife really being nasty?
Or is it you just attributing nasty to
her and that's why you're getting
depressed or spinning off,
right?
Try to control your own chain of
thoughts.
What the microaggression trigger warning
culture does is it actually grants down.
The more you are offended,
the more value you are granted,
and therefore you have actually an
interest in being offended.
We give you awards.
If you're offended by your,
your treasured.
If you're offended because it
demonstrates that you're woke,
right,
you're.
The more you are offended,
the more we can show that you are woke
and because you are woke.
Therefore your granted this virtue.
You get to Lord it over everyone else.
I mean,
I say in my speeches,
if we could somehow identify like the
LGBT,
half black,
half Hispanic,
one quarter native American little
person,
you know,
then we would finally have the,
the person who we could go to dance for
all of our questions because their
identity would be unquestionable.
It'd be Yoda,
right?
If we could find yoga,
we could just get rid of democracy and
discussion altogether.
He can just rule from on high.
He,
she and I don't want to put a gender on
Yoda,
right?
I don't think Yodas gender does Yoda.
It's got to be a guy or deep voice.
Maybe we're being rude by incidents.
No,
but yeah,
you're absolutely right because no one
is a no one's left enough.
Yeah,
it's,
it's.
I don't know where the limit is and it's
there so far left that they've actually
made common cause with the people they
hate.
Right.
So when they talk about safe spaces and
saw it,
you had misery and all these black
students protesting and they actually
said,
we don't want white people who think
like us and who want to help us in our
safe spaces.
We feel insulted by that.
I just thought to myself,
well,
the KKK agrees,
like if you want to do safe spaces for
separate races,
I can find some Jim Crow racist are
totally up for that from like 1962.
Well,
there's the really bizarre statement
that I've heard over and over again that
black people cannot be racist against
white people because they don't have any
power over white people.
Yes.
Wow.
Which is just insane.
I mean,
it's an an inane statement.
This idea that you have to.
You have to have power in the
superstructure in order for you to even
to be erased.
I could understand the argument if they
said,
look,
you being racist is not connected to
racist action.
If you don't have the capacity for
action that affects people,
then your personal racism is not as
important as the of people in power.
Then at least is an argument where the
idea that you can't be racist at all if
you're,
if you're black because black people
don't have enough pat.
First of all,
the idea that black people have no power
in the United States is utterly crazy.
I mean,
it's utterly crazy.
Well,
especially when it was going on while
Mama was president,
the attorney general was the president.
I always said this about Baltimore.
We kept hearing in Baltimore,
right?
Would they?
The riots they'd bought,
they'd riots and they were saying,
well,
Baltimore PD,
you know,
they're,
they're cracking down on black people.
I'll get the chief of police was black.
The majority of the city council was
black and Democrat.
The entire,
the,
the deputy district attorney who was
prosecuting the case was black.
The majority of the police department
was minority.
The attorney general of the United
States was black and the president of
the United States was black,
but apparently the majority of the city
of Baltimore is black,
but apparently it's the white guys felt
like I just at some point,
you're gonna have to make your ideas
actually work in concert with reality.
I can't.
I can't do this with you.
Do you ever step back and look at this
trend and look at what's going on in
popular culture and looking what's going
on with identity politics in this war
between the left and the right and
wonder where it's going.
I mean,
if it feels like the people on the left
are completely emboldened by the fact
that you have this guy in office who has
said things like grabbing by the pussy
and he lives all the time and makes fun
of people's plastic surgery and you
think that having this guy in in this
position,
I guess in some way emboldens them and
makes them even more convinced the fact
they're right.
You know,
fight,
but put up the resistance and the
hashtag resistance.
Hashtag resist.
It's all over the place.
Where does this go?
I think.
Well,
no place.
Good.
I think what's happening,
and it's one of the things that I
personally am not a fan of,
and this goes all the way back to the
piers Morgan debate you mentioned.
I mean I started off that debate with
Piers Morgan saying to him,
you don't get to attribute intent to me
that I don't have.
Right?
You're standing on the grades,
the kids at Sandy Hook in order to
promote your political agenda implying I
don't care enough about dead kids
because I don't agree with you.
That is the sweet spot where a lot of
people like to live,
which is if we disagree on politics,
is because you're an asshole,
right?
It's not.
It's not because we disagree on the best
methods you get to the goal or we have
different goals is because you're a bad
person and I think that what you're
seeing is with trump there an attempt to
cast all of his voters as people who
love all of the things that are bad that
he does and says is that that they voted
for him because they thought Hillary
Clinton was the worst presidential
candidate in the history of America,
which is true.
Right?
So they voted for him because they liked
the.
Grab them by the p word stuff,
right?
They voted for him because they liked
it.
He's vulgar and he lies a lot.
They voted for him because they are bad
people right there.
This is why people misread.
I think Hillary Clinton's deplorable
speech it.
The implication was,
okay,
everybody who voted for trump is a bad
human being.
They tried this with Rami too.
I mean they tried to castigate Romney,
who's whatever you can say about Mitt
Romney.
Mitt Romney was maybe the most honorable
person ever to run for the presidency.
They tried to cast him as Joe Biden's
had a guy who wants to put y'all back in
chains or he said that he.
He straps dogs at the top of his car is
an evil,
nasty guy.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
This was a big issue in the campaign is
dogs.
So there was,
there was a,
there was a story,
I think it's in the Boston Globe about
how like back in 1982,
he went on a family vacation and when
they're traveling he put the dog in a
cage and put the dog on the top of his
car.
And this was.
And this was like a big campaign issue,
right?
Do you remember binders full of women
and you remember you remember 47 percent
number.
Exactly right.
He's mean he hates the poor.
He hates what the binders full of women
thing was particularly stupid because
the entire point he was making is that I
was trying to recruit women to my
administration,
so they'd bring binders full of female
resumes to me,
second staff moral women,
and they turned it into binders full of
women.
He's like Hugh hefner and Mitt Romney
like,
really?
So this attempt to castigate the other
side is really bad and I think that you
see some of that on the right,
but I think it's more reactionary.
I think that that the unearned moral
superiority that the left likes to kind
of wallow in.
I think that that's more on the left
than on the right.
Although I think that there is an
attempt by some on the right now in
response to it to do some of that.
Well,
it becomes these sticking points that
you use to win,
you know,
and it.
And it becomes something that people
repeat over and over again,
you know,
like the deplorable thing.
Or is this sexist,
bigot,
homophobe.
It's just what I was walking down New
York City down the street.
Uh,
right after trump won when they were
protesting and there was this guy right
next to me fucking screaming.
He wasn't even in the actual parade
itself.
He was like on the sidewalk,
but he was screaming,
Donald Trump KKK,
racist,
sexist,
anti gay.
Just boiled it down to this thing.
But the best part about it was he saw a
black guy coming towards him and he just
started screaming black lives matter,
black lives matter,
and I just,
I just,
I saw him.
I saw his soul like in that,
in that one move shift to screaming
black lives banner when he saw a black
guy.
No,
there's the intersectionality for you,
right?
You have to know how to appeal to every
racial group on the basis of a
stereotype.
It could have been Thomas Sowell,
they wouldn't have known.
Yeah.
It's almost like the laziness in having
the ability to communicate is one thing.
But having the ability to express a
complete thought that covers something
as nuanced and as complex as American
politics in 2017,
that's too hard.
So let's just yell out Donald Trump KKK
and this,
this ability to like boil down what's
the difference between the left and the
right to like a little statement is or
you know,
a bucket of deplorable basket of
deplorables,
whatever it is.
You know,
binders of women.
It's so tempting because it's like,
it's so powerful that it works.
You could put it on the back of a bumper
sticker.
I think we've also been shaped a little
bit by a lot.
We all.
We all live in Hollywood.
I mean you live in Hollywood.
I live in Hollywood that that means
that,
and I think all of America lives in that
milieu because everyone watches tv.
Everybody watches movies,
so when we do politics,
we tend to see it through the prism of
house of cards or or any of the other
political movies you've ever seen.
And that means there's a bad guy,
right?
Everybody.
There's a bad guy.
The villain and the villain has to.
It can't just be the villain is somebody
who's incompetent.
Like usually in politics,
if somebody is bad,
sometimes they have a level point of
view.
That's pretty rare.
Usually it's somebody who's misguided
and it had some bad ideas.
Usually they're just stupid or
incompetent.
Like this is what I keep saying to
people who oppose trump.
Like why are you attributing to him
malice when stupidity would do like you
keep saying that everything trump is
doing is out of some sort of malicious
genius.
Are we watching the same film?
Like if you have a problem with trump,
it seems to have a solution for the
left.
By the way,
if they,
if they really hate trump this much,
it wasn't.
I thought Obama was a crappy president.
I have a deal.
How about we just minimize the power of
Washington DC and we don't have to give
a crap whose the president of the United
States.
You think anybody in 18,
32 really cared who the president was.
He had no impact on their lives.
But now the presidency has this outsized
impact.
We care about Washington all the time.
We treated them in.
The truth is we watch it for fun.
I mean,
right now,
the last week,
particularly with Scaramucci,
uh,
you know,
it's impossible not to watch it for fun,
but it's actually kind of serious
business.
Like there are other world leaders who
are actually looking at this.
Like,
this impacts my nation for us.
We look at it and go,
well,
I wonder what's on TV on tonight's
episode of trump the series.
Well,
when you say reduce the power of the
president,
I think there's a lot of people that
would think that would be a great idea
because having one person has the
authority over 300 plus million people.
It is kind of ridiculous this point in
time,
but how would you go about doing that?
Like what would be the best way to
implement something like,
I mean it really isn't just the
presidents that you'd have to reduce the
power of Congress as well.
I mean you'd have to.
You'd have to go back to a federalist
based system where localities and states
have more power over over local issues
and the federal government isn't that
powerful because what's happened
basically in the constitutional
structure,
the federal government was never
supposed to be anywhere near this big
right there.
There are very certain delegated powers
in the constitution of the United States
that Congress has and they are very
small things like building post offices
and interstate roads and regulating
interstate commerce,
but the idea that they could regulate,
you know,
your toilet flushing is just silly.
I mean the founders would have thought
that was ridiculous.
Yet you have a federal government that
that's,
that's that big,
so congress regulates on that,
but if you're in Congress,
the last thing you want is to be
answerable for that.
So what you do instead is you drop vague
statutes,
right?
You say things like,
we hope that we're passing a law that
says that we should fix the environment,
and then you kick it over to you
executive branch and the executive
branch,
you know,
run by president trump or president
Obama has a bunch of executive branch
agencies like the EPA and the EPA puts
together all of these regulations that
you've never seen,
never heard of.
You never elected these people.
They put together all the regulations
and then those are the ones that
actually govern your lives.
So if you're in Congress and things go
bad,
you say,
well,
that's not what I meant to do.
I told them to do good stuff and the
bureaucrats were not elected.
Don't have to care.
So basically we have everyone kicking
the can to the other person for purposes
of responsibility.
The only way this is going to happen is
if the American people just decide
they're sick of the federal government
running all this stuff and they start
actively working to elect people who
want to minimize their own power,
which is difficult.
I mean,
most people in power don't want to
minimize their own power.
Yeah.
That seems almost impossible.
It seems like the one who's worked so
hard to get to the top of the game is
going.
Yeah.
The other way to do it is to elect
people on the state level who are pretty
zealous about their own authority.
Right.
You've seen from like Greg Abbott in
Texas
that every so often he'll say to the
federal government,
listen,
you're telling me to do something.
Go screw yourselves.
Like,
what are you gonna do about it?
Well,
Texas is a weird one though.
They're almost ready to leave,
like at any point in time,
it's related to put a fence up and go,
fuck you.
I mean,
weren't there for the longest time?
They were,
uh,
they were not really a state right now.
They're still called the Republic of
Texas.
Right.
You said that so yeah,
I mean the people in Texas,
I mean it didn't.
Wonderful state.
I love that.
When you drive through Texas,
every single store is called lone star,
lone star brewery or Texas.
This everything is named after the
state.
Like nothing is really named after the
country.
It's all named after the state.
Like a lot of state pride in Texas.
There's a lot of state pride maybe more
than any place else I've ever been.
Yeah,
well not a lot of state pride in
California because everybody's a
transplant and it also like some,
you know,
people who got here and it represents
something that they always wanted some
sort of a liberal paradise where you
could get famous for doing nothing.
There's some city pride,
like there's Hollywood pride,
San Jose Pride,
but like California pride.
I mean the people who run the state are
idiots.
Will California so confused?
I mean we have a grizzly bear on our
flag,
but we don't have Chrisley bears.
We have,
we have a team called the Los Angeles
Lakers,
a lake in the state.
Our lakes are all manmade.
We have to keep pumping water in because
they fucking dry up a river is just a
giant concrete ravine over is hilarious.
When I've shown people the La River,
my fest,
La River,
they're like,
shut up.
Yeah.
The Romantic river.
No,
no,
no.
The La River.
It is la.
It's a fucking concrete shitty slide for
water and that the city is so dirty.
I mean it's like I've grown up my entire
life here.
I mean I was born in Burbank,
grew up in north Hollywood like this is
that I've lived here my entire life.
The first time I realized I liked it is
when I moved to Boston for law school
because at least the weather here is
good,
but yeah,
I mean it's gotten so shabby lately.
It's such a shabby city.
The weather's amazing,
but.
Have you ever been to Mexico City?
No.
I've been a couple times for UFC events.
I'm not going back because I would get
headaches from the pollution in Mexico
City to me is like Ellie in the future,
but with zero respect for the traffic
lights.
When I mean zero,
I've never seen anything like it.
It's crazy.
They're very nice people like
everybody's worried about getting
kidnapped over there.
I find Mexican people to be some of the
nicest people and real friendly and easy
to get along with,
but they don't give a fuck about traffic
lights.
When we were stuck in traffic was bumper
to bumper and it's a green light going
this way.
Cars just go in front of you and they
just sort of make their way through and
people hit the brakes and they make
their way through the intersection.
It's a straight up red light and they
just go and it's not just one.
One guy goes and another guy goes behind
them and then he got like 20 cars and
and it's just gridlock.
It's actually indicative of why the
United States works,
that people actually follow traffic
lights,
like it's true in Italy.
Also true in Israel,
like when I visited Israel with my wife
when we got married,
like no one pays attention to the
traffic rules.
Everyone's honking their horns at each
other.
I'm American.
So like,
why are these people so rude all the
time?
Mom honked the horn.
She,
but it is why in America,
because we have a baseline,
this is what I think is breaking down
actually,
so not to get too deep on a point about
Mexican city traffic,
but I think that,
you know,
the country was based on this idea.
There's a social fabric.
We all have respect for each other
enough that we're going to follow the
basic rules of the game and that's true
as far as traffic lights,
it's true as far as financial dealings
with one another and when you lose that,
when you lose the basic respect for the
guy who lives next to you,
you know,
you need to get through the red light in
a screw him.
It doesn't matter if it's red,
then it's kind of indicative of a
culture in collapse.
Generally when small rules start to go
broken,
like in Italy,
in Italy,
is that 50 percent of their economies
black market because they have high tax
rates and no one pays them.
You're starting to set in California to
California is the highest taxes in the
country by far.
We also have the number one rate of
deductions,
so we pass all these high Texas so we
can congratulate ourselves for social
justice and then we avoid all the taxes
as much as we possibly can for the
accountants.
Yeah,
exactly.
Hey,
those people are making on a fricking
fortune.
Well,
I just also feel like when you get a
giant number of people smashed into a
small area and La,
it's not even a small area includes
Greater Orange County and it goes into
the Conejo valley and it's just like
there's so many of us,
there's so many.
It's almost like you get that sort of
diffusion of responsibility thing where
there's just too many people to care
about and you lose this feeling of value
that you have for fellow people.
I lived in boulder for a little while
and when I lived there,
the People's Republic of Boulder.
You want to talk about lefties?
Oh yeah.
Holy Shit.
If you have a.
If you had a right wing anything on your
lawn,
like a sign for someone running for,
they would take it down.
They literally take things down,
but when I was there I was amazed at how
many people are polite when they drive
in.
They wave and like there's only 100,000
people.
Exactly.
So that,
that.
That's how I was gonna send me.
I'm looking it up while we're sitting
here.
It's like 110,000
people in.
The other population of La County is 10
million people.
It's
plus Mexicans.
You gotTa Count Mexicans and then you
got account.
Everybody's connected to all the other
counties around it.
It's not like there's some
border and we just drive around.
That's exactly right.
So it is in the first time I visited
Oklahoma,
I had this and I was in Oklahoma for
doing radio show.
When you look at the 23 point seven,
$7 million.
Yeah.
Sorry,
go ahead.
Yeah,
I mean Oklahoma and I'm walking down the
street and the first thing that and and
just some lady and I catch eyes now in
La,
you're from La,
you look away,
right?
You only got stabbed in others.
If you catch eyes with somebody you
meet,
it's rude.
You don't catch eyes with people at La
and among that street we catch eyes.
Lady Goes,
how are you?
I called my father.
I was like,
what?
Where am I,
what's going on here?
Like this is not regular,
but I do think that there is something
to the idea that if you have too many
people in too small a space,
we're all up in each other's business so
much that it's very hard to say to
people,
okay,
liberty,
stay away from one another,
leave each other alone.
It's like,
yeah,
but he lives next door and he's a
jackass.
Hate that guy because he's like,
right next to you run Oklahoma.
The guy next to you is three miles down
the road.
There's that.
And there's also,
um,
it's been replicated in rat population
density studies that you get more mental
illness,
you get more weird aggressive behavior
when they stack rats in these cubicles
and then jam them closer and closer
together.
And that's exactly what's happening with
people to what Manhattan is famous for
it.
I mean,
I,
I enjoy visiting Manhattan and every
time I'm there I'm always like,
no,
I can't.
I can't live here.
Oh yeah.
Too many
when I was there last week and I liked
the sky.
So you can't actually see the sky in
Manhattan,
right?
I mean you just see the brick buildings
and you know,
25 stories high.
And I noticed that uh,
we were walking past the store and there
was a shirt on sale and the shirts
entire tax was after you.
You effing F and I thought only in New
York could you sell this,
right?
I mean,
you try to take this anywhere else and
people would have been like,
wait,
what now?
But New York,
I'm sure that the best seller.
That's why.
Honestly I think it's one of the reasons
why trump won is because he's basically
just a guy from New York.
He's like a taxi driver from New York is
really,
really wealthy and you know,
he does what a taxi driver from New York
we do if you're really,
really wealthy.
He marries models and builds gold
toilets and all this kind of stuff.
And people in the rest of the country
actually take that language seriously.
So when he says stuff like you,
we're going to bomb the shit out of him,
you know,
people in New York like,
yes.
So what we do,
you know,
and people in Oklahoma like,
wow,
he's serious.
Like that's actually gonna happen and
it's probably not probably that's just
how people from New York we saw this
last week,
right?
He's talking about the cops and he was
saying this thing about covering their
heads before he's talking like a long
island or you know,
he's talking about like,
you know,
the,
they throw him in the back of the paddy
wagon and we do all the and,
and you don't put your head on that it,
you,
they bumped their head,
they just killed somebody.
And so the entire meeting went and how
dare he.
He's talking about how cops should rub
people up.
Listen,
is it appropriate for the president of
the United States to talk like that
about treatment of suspects know is,
are we supposed to take this super
seriously?
Like this is like trump is actually
recommending a policy change with regard
to it.
That's what he does.
He works the room,
he's a,
he's a New York real estate guy who
works the room and more than anything
else,
if you understand New York and you
understand La,
you understand trump.
He's not a giant mystery.
Right?
He's just any other reality TV star.
He's a reality.
He's a marketing image guy.
I mean,
that's,
that's what he does.
Like he's not even that great at real
estate.
He puts his name on the side.
He brands himself,
he puts his name on the side of
buildings.
They pay him not to be involved in the
real estate business so they can put
trump on the side of his hotels.
Great.
I mean,
that's what he does.
That's why I'm kind of shocked that he's
Kinda crappy at the imaging.
As far as being a president.
You didn't.
You'd imagine that you'd be better at
this part of it.
At least.
I just think he didn't understand the
volume of hate that was going to come
his way and I think he's such an
EGOMANIAC.
He has a hard time dealing with it.
I guess a hard time separating and
that's one of the things that I've read
about him that he's getting better at
getting away from the comments and not
reading comments on twitter,
but he fucking blocks people know about
that.
Too many sued him.
Yeah.
Well there's people at Book Group of
people suing them and now they're
actually starting to rule against public
people
who are in the public light.
Being able to block citizens and having
their own opinion about what this
person's doing or not doing.
So then you have to say,
well are you allowed to be vulgar
towards the president?
I mean,
how far does that go?
what are you allowed to say?
I mean maybe it usually be able to do
whatever the hell you want about
anybody,
but if you can't threaten them,
but it's.
It does go more to the level of,
of pettiness.
He's the most powerful man on the planet
is busy blocking people on twitter at
3:00
in the morning.
Joe Scarborough and what is her name was
facing.
He was saying that she should.
This is the fucking president.
He's saying she showed up with bloody
scars or she was bleeding from her
recent facelift.
Exactly,
and it's first of all,
it turns out that it probably wasn't
true,
but second it wasn't true.
I mean,
fuck goes out when you're bleeding it.
I agree with you.
I agree with you,
but it's it.
But this.
I wrote a piece about it in national
review about this.
You know,
you,
you say that the level of hatred
directed toward trump is warping trump.
I think that it's also a warping some
people on my side of the aisle who are,
who are so interested in the fight that
they're less interested in advancing the
policies that I'd like to see achieved.
So I think there's a whole group of
people where,
let's say that trump would just resign
tomorrow.
He'd say,
you know what I've had at,
screw it,
I'm out and Mike Pence becomes
president.
And then Mike Pence proceeds to do all
the things conservatives want them to
do.
You know,
we get tax reform and we limit
immigration and we do all of these
things.
But,
but he does not tweet about Mika
Brzezinski bloody face.
I think there's a whole group of people
on the right will be pissed.
That miss it.
Yeah.
I think that right now because it's fun.
What exactly what they want is somebody
who pisses off the left more than beats.
The left pisses them off.
If you piss off the left.
I think Obama sort of trialed some of
the right into insanity.
I think there are a lot of people on our
side.
Whereas like this jerk,
he just,
he keeps saying things just to Piss us
off.
And Obama did do some of that and so pro
trump is kind of a twitter troll and so
he does the same thing.
We're like,
yeah,
that's awesome.
Like two days ago,
trump or yesterday,
there was a report that trump said that
he thinks the White House's shabby.
Now I can say is somebody on the
conservative right my entire life.
If Obama said that,
we would not let him forget that for
1000 years that the White House is
shabby.
I mean it's,
it's an ass move to say the people's
house is shit first of all to mansion,
right?
Like it.
And second of all,
this is the most iconic building on the
face of the planet is,
Oh,
it's shabby.
How is it chat?
What was he saying?
It was shabby.
He said.
He said they were asking him why he gets
his visits,
his golf courses so much.
And he said,
oh,
because?
Because,
because my golf courses are nicer
because the White House has shabby,
but there are people in the right for
like five and it's funny,
like,
you know,
at least he's trolling the left.
At least it's ticking them off and say
guys ticking off the left is not a
substitute for defeating the left if you
actually care about the feeding the
left.
Like this is one of the things that
drives me nuts because my,
you know,
my life goal has been to promulgate
particular ideas,
not just to piss off the left,
but I think that in the fight there are
a lot of people who have fallen into the
trap of thinking these two things are
identical.
Right?
You piss off the left,
that means you're winning.
It's like no pissing off the left.
Maybe part of it,
but that's not how you win.
You win by saying things that are true
and if they get pissed,
I get
well.
My good friend,
Bill Byrd did this piece about Obama
back when Obama was mocking trump and
saying the one thing that I am that
you'll never be the president of United
States.
The crowd went nuts.
Remember when he did that and Obama was
saying this on stage and you see trump
in the audience.
Boiling was big frog.
Double Chin.
Just sitting there eating it all and
that fucking stuck in his craw.
There's,
there's a whole story that came out from
buzzfeed about his interaction with a
guy named Mckay coppins,
a reporter for buzzfeed in which was
basically like saying to trump like,
you're a joke.
You're not going to run.
I think trump ran just to just because
he was sick of people telling him that
he wasn't going to be president.
I really think that's.
That's half of what drives him.
That doesn't mean that he can't do the
things.
I hope he does do good things.
He's the president.
I won't every president to do things I
like,
but you know he's going to have to get
it under control a little bit because he
was willing to keep the MOOC.
I mean the Mooc,
the MOOC was only ousted because.
Oh,
John Kelly and the MOOC is.
Was it.
What did the MOOC say?
What was this was about?
Yeah,
that's exactly right.
About him performing.
It asks,
why would he think that he could say
that once he's in the office.
I mean,
first of all,
I was thinking to see Ben and could even
possibly do that.
I mean,
Ban is not that flexible.
I know Steve That's not,
that's not something repertoire,
a giant
unit,
but it doesn't matter.
Just the idea that he would think he
must be emboldened by the fact that
trump has said
so many outrageous things.
Well,
I mean there were reports from the New
York Post that,
that he actually had.
The trump liked it,
that all that happened is that there was
so much blow back that he had to replace
Kelly Kelly in there and Kelly's like,
you can't do this,
and trump's like,
okay,
fine,
but doesn't it seem more crazy to fire a
guy after 10 days and it does to sit him
down and say,
hey man,
don't say that again.
You would think,
right,
let's move forward.
That's what they should've done the next
day.
But the problem is he.
He'd been doing it for a week at that
point and he was out there like saying
that Ryan priebus was leaking on the
president and was an enemy of the
president for a week and you're saying
that he was gonna get him fired and at
the same time,
remember,
this is the same week that trump himself
is tweeting out that attorney general
sessions who is his most loyal supporter
for a year and a half,
that that guy is like a trader.
Right?
And that he wishes he would go away
because he recused himself.
First of all,
trump can fire any of these people at
any time.
Like this is very passive aggressive for
a guy who made his living saying you're
fired on TV.
It's amazing that all the people that
trump has fired.
I've been fired actually through
surrogates.
Yeah.
But Mike Flynn resigned.
Uh,
James Comey was fired basically through
Rod Rosenstein and sessions and then
Rosenstein had to recuse himself,
which is how you get the special counsel
and Comi found out on television,
TV,
right.
Emissary to go to La and,
and give them a letter.
And like everyone,
he fires has to be fired in the most.
Roundabout.
I,
I think that trump actually this,
I think the dirty little secret is,
I'm not sure trump actually looks firing
people and the,
I think,
I think he,
I think he kinda like toward,
at any handling torturing people,
but I'm not sure that he actually likes
firing them.
Maybe he doesn't like people being mad
at him face to face.
I think he wants them to love him in
front of his face.
So like when he's not there,
you know,
you can make a phone call,
firearm jetson and hang up the phone and
you don't have to actually see the guy
who wants
that guy to like him.
Yeah,
I don't recall me thing was really
bizarre because it was like,
oh,
you can do that.
Like there's this guy is looking into
improprieties and you can just say,
no,
you can't do that anymore.
You're fired.
You can't look into the things I've done
wrong.
It was eight.
Well,
the way he did it was the stupid part.
So I was calling for me to be fired
since last year.
I thought the way he handled the whole
hillary thing from beginning to end was
terrible.
I thought that trump should have
replaced him before he became basically
day one.
Here's my new cabinet.
Call me.
You did a great job.
You know,
usher him out the door,
bringing somebody new.
He kept him around and then the first
thing he said to Komi you remember was
when you met him,
he said,
you're more famous than I am.
Well,
when trump says that to you,
that's the writing on the wall right
there.
First of all,
it's not true,
but second of all,
I think maybe there was also a part of
the problem was a comb is a giant.
Yes.
The trump.
What is he?
Six,
eight,
six,
96.
Get giant dude.
Towered over.
Crossing is such a comedy and call
saying he was trying to hide in the
curtains to avoid trump saying he just
see Herman Munster over there hiding in
the we're now.
What did you enjoying the show?
I mean it's wild.
If I didn't think that nuclear war was a
possibility,
but if I see a fucking Korean missile
headed our way,
I'm going to be pissed.
When colby was handling the email thing,
what specifically did you not like about
it?
What I thought it was was crazy was when
he restarted or reopen the case because
of Houma,
having used her cruiser with Anthony
Wiener's,
all that stuff was like,
that's not enough.
Like that seems crazy.
The deleting the emails to me seemed
like I had Mike Baker on from the CIA
and he said essentially anyone else
would be in jail for what she did for
sure.
For sure.
Sure.
Right.
Well,
call me if this.
So he screwed it up and then he really
screwed it up.
So when he originally said publicly,
we're not going to prosecute Hillary
Clinton.
He was doing something he didn't have
the authority to do.
The FBI does not decide whether to
prosecute people.
They refer the information to the DOJ
and then the DOJ decides whether to
prosecute people.
It was Attorney General,
Loretta Lynch's decision whether to
prosecute or not.
The statute itself.
Man,
I'm a lawyer.
The statute itself did not say,
do you have intent to commit espionage?
Do you have intent to to make classified
secrets public or expose them to the
possibility of being made.
Public intent is not an element of the
crime.
Right.
If you do it,
it's a crime.
So my wife as a doctor,
and that means that she is under hipaa
requirements.
There is no element under hippa that
says that if she reveals somebody,
you know,
proprietary medical information by
accident,
well there's no intent,
so she's okay.
That's not part of the statute.
If she brings some of these medical
records out to her car and somebody
steals the medical records,
you know,
if she's working at the va or something,
that's a crime.
It doesn't matter if she intended to do
it and just left it in her purse.
So Komi read the element of intense into
the crime to get hillary off.
And then he said,
okay,
we're not going to prosecute this.
We're going to leave it alone.
He shouldn't have intervened in the
first place.
Remember he made an entire case
basically for why she should be
prosecuted and then at the end he goes,
but we're,
you know.
But no,
we're not gonna do that.
He also said we're going to keep
Congress updated on any future
development.
Well you get to October and there's a
future development.
They found this laptop with all sorts of
information on it with new emails from
Hillary Clinton that they haven't seen
before,
and now he has an obligation to inform
Congress because he told them that he
would and so he screwed the pooch again
because he's afraid that if he doesn't
reveal that information,
Hillary goes on to win and then it comes
out.
There's something criminal.
Then people are going to blame him for
Hillary winning and putting a criminal
and the White House since they say,
oh,
well,
I'll be fully transparent.
I have to honor my institution.
I'm going to put this out there.
Of course,
then hillary loses and now he screwed up
twice and then he gets into the White
House and now he's supposed to be
investigating the trump Russia stuff at
the same time,
so now he's investigating basically both
candidates in the 2016 election.
He handled this the wrong way every step
of the way because he was so focused on
what will uphold the integrity of the
FBI and the integrity of the
investigation and the integrity of the
DOJ.
He was less worried about,
okay,
what do I actually have to do under the
law?
What's my obligation under the law is
obligation under the law is to shut us
pie hole and the information over to
Lynch.
If Lynch wanted to kill the
investigation,
let her do it.
So in a sense trump was right and saying
that he's a grandstander yeah,
for sure.
I mean,
I think that part was right,
but that the problem remember was not
the firing of Comey.
It was the two days after he fired
comey,
he went to Lester Holt on NBC and he
said the reason I fired Columbia was not
all the excuses I gave about the,
the hillary stuff.
It's because of the Russia stuff.
I was angry about how he was handling
Russia.
I mean,
that's really stupid.
That's intensely stupid.
It's intensely stupid,
but it's also strange that it didn't go
anywhere.
Right?
Like that was it like that?
That's against the law.
Well,
it's.
So it's,
you know,
obstruction.
So obstruction.
Looking at the statutes obstruction is a
little bit more than that.
So you have to actually obstruct an
ongoing investigation into criminal
activity.
There's a counter intelligence
investigation going on,
but not necessarily a criminal one.
So not to get too specific about it,
but you should get specific about it.
I mean the obstruction laws,
I mean I've looked into kind of the
statutes that they've used to suggest
obstruction and it's not clear that
there is any statute that specifically
governance,
something like this.
Plus it is true that trump does have the
power as the chief executive to fire as
the commander in chief to fire the FBI
director for any reason he chooses.
Now,
all that said,
he can be impeached for any reason.
Criminal or noncriminal,
right?
Impeachment is not a,
you don't actually have to have
committed a crime to be impeached.
Right?
Most people don't even understand what a
peach means.
They think that somehow or another
impeach means that you kicked out of
office,
right?
That's not rent.
It is there.
There's the house and they have to vote
to impeach you.
Uh,
and then there's the senate and they
have to vote by two thirds.
Majority or a 68.
Yeah,
I think it's two thirds majority to
actually convict.
You have a set of crimes that they come
up with,
but these are all political definitions,
right?
When it says high crimes and
misdemeanors,
it doesn't mean they actually have to
prosecute.
You likely wouldn't have criminal court
and you'd have to go to jail or any of
that kind of stuff.
Like they could impeach anybody at
anytime.
Clinton didn't even have to commit
perjury.
If they didn't want.
If they wanted to impeach him,
they could.
They could have impeached doubly.
Every president you can impeach.
It's just a vote.
It's just about.
So all the talk about what's criminal
and what's not criminal.
The problem for trump,
there are two ways of reading trump's
behavior in the whole Russia thing
right?
Way.
One is he's got something to hide and
that's the most obvious way he's got
something to hide.
That's why he gets rid of Flynn.
We don't know why he got rid of Flynn.
He gets rid of Comey.
We don't really know why he got rid of
Columbia and then brags to the Russians
that it's a pressure off him on the
Russia stuff.
So it's a way one is,
he's hiding something and now he's
firing everybody who gets in the way and
there's,
you know,
the chain of evidence does not fit that.
I mean,
you know,
he,
he's the people he's angry at in order
our attorney general sessions,
the deputy attorney general Rod
Rosenstein,
the former head of the FBI,
James Comey,
the acting head of the FBI,
McCabe,
uh,
and uh,
and the special prosecutor Robert
Mueller.
So those are all people involved with
Russia.
Those are the only people he's really
angry at.
So there's something to be said for the
idea that maybe trying to hide
something.
On the other hand,
we haven't actually seen any hard
evidence of collusion itself.
So we saw an attempt to collude by
Donald Trump jr,
but we haven't actually seen any
evidence that the Russians were
providing special information to the
trump administration,
which was then being weaponized for use
in the campaign.
We haven't seen any of that stuff.
So here's the other plausible theory,
and this goes to trump's personality.
He's so petty and he wants to be loved
so much that he is angry that people
keep saying he run because he won
because of the Russians.
And so now every time people say that,
he just gets pissed and he fires people.
So Comi,
I mean this is totally plausible,
right?
Komi comes to him and he said privately
that you are not under investigation.
And trump says to him,
well,
why don't you just say that?
And he says,
well,
I can't say that because if I say that
I'm going to have to update congress.
If you do fall under investigation and
trump doesn't like that,
he wants the public to know he's free
and clear.
So he fires call me and then he goes up
public and he says,
I didn't like how he was handling the
Russia thing.
I'm innocent.
Why will these people leave me alone?
Right?
So yeah.
So there's two ways to read this.
Either he's totally innocent but stupid,
or he's trying to hide something.
Those are the only two plausible ways of
reading the situation.
The Donald trump junior thing was really
bizarre because he released all the
emails,
like I just,
yeah,
it's like,
look,
I've got nothing to hide.
Like you aren't supposed to do any of
these things you're saying in these
emails.
Yes.
That was not a good moment for,
for trump,
jr.
Do you think you'd go and then you hear
that he was coached by his dad again,
you know,
this is.
None of this is gooD stuff.
I think that Donald Trump jr releasing
the.
First of all,
it is imperative to note eight minutes
later the New York times released
basically the email chain.
Right?
So he was meeting,
he was beating it out of the gate and so
he puts that out there,
which was a smart move.
I mean,
it would be smart if it would be smart
if he had found a way to spin it,
right?
Like if you'd done it,
if this is the thing in politics,
now the way politics works now is your
smartest move.
If there's dirt about you is to be the
first person out the gate with it and
you put a spin on it.
Right?
So like barack obama,
imagine if obama hadn't said anything in
2008 and then we found out a week before
the election that he did coke in high
school.
Now a lot of people wouldn't care.
A lot of people would write in 2000
George W.
Bush was hit with a dui charge from like
1973 and it probably last him a point in
the polls.
So what obama did is he wrote an entire
memoir and he just kind of dismissed it
right in the middle of the memoir.
He goes,
you know,
when I was in high school,
I did a little bloke,
no problem.
Did a little blow everybody and
everyone.
Oh okay.
Did low blow,
alright,
you know,
cool.
So if you're going to release this kind
of stuff,
you have to put a spin on it.
Trump juNior,
didn't he just put out the emails and
the emails themselves contain the
damning material,
right?
It says right in there,
you know,
there's a russian government lawyer,
the russian government sees this as part
of its effort to aid mr trump's
campaign.
And donald jr is like thumbs up guys
like I love it.
sounds awesome.
And,
and so that does not look good.
it's not quite as much as you know.
People on the left want to say it as
meaning that there's no evidence yet
that any information was actually
exchanged with the russians or that
anything came of the meeting.
Most of the people in the meeting who
said something and said nothing came of
it,
but we don't know whether trump knew
about the meeting.
I find it kind of hard to believe he
didn't,
you know,
considering every major campaign figure
was there but,
but then then they,
then they just keep lying and this,
this is the part that's,
that's a problem.
Are they lyIng because they just think
they can get away with it anD they're
stupid or they lying because they're
actually being meticulous about their
allies.
And I Tend to think the former,
because this isn't a professional
administration.
I think these,
I think trump fibs a lot.
He says things that are,
I mean like on stupid things.
He says things like,
the leader of the boy scouts called me
and told me that he loved my specialist,
whichever,
and then leader of the boy scouts,
like,
uh,
what?
So,
so is that a calculated lie to hide
something or is it just the trump lies
by nature and so he does it a lot,
but I think he's just so used to it
putting that spin on things that
publicity span.
Right.
And the thing that he said about this
was it,
this is what politics is what happens in
politics.
You get dirt about your enemy and people
exchange inFormation.
It's just what happens.
It's just you're seeing it now.
So a lot of people like.
Yeah,
well that makes sense.
Right?
And,
and this is something that again,
I think that were shaped by hollywood a
little bit.
Politics is dirty,
but some of this stuff is not usual,
right?
It's actually not particularly usual to
meet with a government that is really
not friendly to the United States to
receive information about your political
opponents.
But if you've watched house of cards,
you think,
well,
I mean it's like two steps down from
throwing somebody under the subway.
So what's the big deal?
Uh,
I don't because I work in politics and
when I go home at night,
the last thing I want to do is watch
entertainment about politics.
Now watch game of thrones.
That's his political.
Okay.
House of cards is a great show.
But if it's half right?
Like I always wonder the thiNg,
the thing that gets me is when people
suicide themselves that are on their waY
to try out,
I'm like,
okay,
I don'T want to be that fucking guy.
I don't want to be that tin foil hat
guy.
But how many people are going to suicide
themselves?
I mean,
for sure someone's been murdered
somewhere along the line.
Someone knew something,
some powerful people got to them and
they murder him.
Oh,
it's gonna happen.
It has happened.
It must've had.
I mean,
I think it happens a lot in Russia.
I don't think that.
I don't believe what trump said.
And again,
I think this is why trump has a skewed
vision of what politics is and because
he thinks that the outer limit of
politics is Russia.
He thinks any thing inside that limit is
now okay.
But do you think it's ever happened in
the United States or just in Russia?
Like political assassinations?
Uh,
I can't name a specific example of where
it has.
I think that.
Are you open to the possibility?
I'm open to.
I mean,
if someone shows me man johnson,
lyndon johnson.
Did you pick somebody?
And I don't think lyndon johnson whacked
anybody about kennedy.
I don't think that kennedy whacked
anybody,
but hillary,
uh,
I don't think hillary clinton
the fiat up.
If I had my last thousand bucks,
I'd be supeR tempted to bet on black.
I'd be super tempted to go.
You know what?
I think She went dark.
She's whacked a few people.
Let's see what we've got here.
Like I want to see white water.
I'd want to see vince foster.
I want to see that enron guy who shot
himself in the head twice.
If I could,
if I could really,
I could.
You know,
man,
I think it's happened,
I just don't know.
I'm sure at some point,
but again,
if I don't know if one,
when I'm hesitant to,
I think that we and I think that we tend
to think things are regular when they
are,
they never really irregular,
right?
So we tend to think that this stuff is
happening every day and that's why you
see trump on tv saying,
well putin,
like America hasn't killed people.
And it's like,
well no,
not quite like putin.
I mean like putting legitimately
murders.
His,
his journalistic enemies.
I haven't seen you trying to double tap
jake tapper,
so I'm pretty sure I'm pretty sure.
no,
it's not a regular thing around here.
Even obama wasn't trying to like kill
chris wallace.
Right.
But maybe the,
you know,
maybe I don't know what boot is.
Obviously the extreme example,
right?
Well obviously the extreme example is a
North Korea,
but putin is in that range of,
it's like a totally feared,
essentially a dictator who's a,
I mean there are a bunch of them,
right?
I mean airline in Turkey.
Uh,
sure.
The maduro a song,
a.
Yeah.
Assad now in Venezuela who's literally
like a complete dictatorship,
and this is very recently,
but America is a.
I mean,
would you believe it if I said like
leaders in France had people regularly
whacked and find it a little bit hard to
believe?
I don't think we're significantly worse
than France and the whacking people in
politics business I don't think
regularly,
but I think every now and then the move
is I'm open to the possibility that I'd
have to see the evidence.
The lawyer in me.
Well I don't think we're a house of
cards.
I don't think it's gets that ridiculous,
but the point I'm making is if you think
that's a regular thing,
if you think that it not like a rare
thing and maybe once in a while,
you know,
once every 20 years somebody gets
whacked quietly for political reasons.
If you think that's like a regular
thing,
then fibbing is like way inside the
line.
Right?
Right.
Like you hiding documents is really.
Or are you like writing your son's
stupid statement about a stupid email
exchange and then fitting about it
publicly.
Like that's really inside the line.
So again,
I don't think that,
I think some of this,
I have a rule about the trump
administration.
I never attribute to malevolence what I
can attribute to stupidity because I
think that that's more likely to be the
case.
It's like the outcomes razor of the
trumpet.
I think that is a smart way to think.
But I think sometimes malevolence is
real.
I remember the gary condit chandra levy
thing.
Yeah,
that was weird.
that was a weird one for people don't
know the story.
This guy was having an affair.
The girl turned up dead and then nine
slash 11 happened right away afterwards,
so people kind of forgot about it,
but they.
They found her body,
the park and everybody was like,
jesus christ.
Like this is a woman that was about to
testify that she was having an affair
with this guy and that one was a good
one in terms of not a.
Not a good one.
Obviously a terrible
in terms of.
So let me say this.
I think that if there's murder and
politics that will probably tend to fall
more into the personal and the
political.
It'll probably fall less in terms of
like,
I have a political vendetta against this
guy and I'm going to kill him.
We haven't really done much of that
since Alexander Hamilton and burr.
Um,
but it's.
But there are.
I mean,
listen,
teddy kennedy left a woman in the back
of his car and a body of water,
so.
Right.
Drunk driving.
That was the thing with him.
He just didn't want to be responsible
for something horrible that he did.
Right.
Similar to dick cheney not meeting with
the police for like something like 18
hours after he shot his friend in the
face.
Yeah.
I mean,
I don't think he was trying to
assassinate his friend is drunk hunting
and that's it.
Yeah.
I would imagine.
I can't rule that one out,
so.
Yeah.
But I mean,
honestly,
I'll fantastic kennedy a little more
suspicious.
You leave the woman in the back of the
car,
swim out of the car,
go into a house,
sleep,
come back the next day and oh my god,
she's dead.
Well,
yeah,
it turns out when you leave somebody
underwater for 12 hours,
they tend to do that.
It's weird how that works
well less.
He was so drunk that he didn't know what
he was doing,
which can happen.
You can get black out drunk or you wake
up and you go,
wait a minute.
Did I crash my car
so I don't drink that heavily.
Is that really a thing?
Like he climbed out the window,
the card,
swim out to the river bank,
go to somebodies house,
come back like a day later you're like,
oh shit.
There was a girl in the backseat.
I've never had it happen,
but I have had.
I've had what I would call slide nights,
know where I get hammered and then like
a wake up in the morning with a pounding
headache and is,
have these flashes in my head like,
who is that person?
Like where was I?
Where were we?
Oh yeah,
there was that.
And then that you'll eat breakfast with
your friends that go.
You remember that thing?
And you go,
oh yeah,
jesus,
not necessarily blackout like I did
something horrible and I completely
forgot about it,
but I forgot a lot of it.
But some people,
I have a friend and he goes,
job allies,
there's a switch that goes off three or
four shots in and he,
he's gone and he's not there anymore and
you almost kinda like nerf the world
around him and protect him and get him
in his bed and he wakes up in the
morning,
he doesn't know a thing,
doesn't know a thing about what
happened.
And it's really bizarre.
It's illegitimate,
terrible things to him.
Know I wasn't nice to him.
But your instinct is to get the fuck
away from him and he just let horrible
things happen.
But,
uh,
the stories are legendary,
but he does,
he gets sharp eyes.
He gets these black,
like soulless eyes where he's gone and
you go,
oh no,
he's gone.
Yeah,
it's weird.
But I'm wondering what that is.
I feel like that's a neurological issue.
I feel like if,
if alcohol does that to you,
there's probably some switches that
aren't connected right in the head.
I imagined a seven gun on,
you know?
Yeah.
So teddy kennedy,
who knows,
I mean he was obviously a raging
and that could have been a part of the
problem.
I mean he literally might have gone
home,
not even knowing that he killed
somebody.
I mean I'd have to be as,
and it's only defense.
So you imagine.
Well that was one of the things that
they said that they would have used as a
defense against with oj the oj with the
cte,
that he might not have even known what
he was doing,
that he might have flown into some
blackout rage.
That would be an amazing defense.
Like I would like to hear that,
like everyone who has cte now gets to
like run around chopping up their ex
wife and randos who end up at their
house like that.
That'd be a hell of a defense.
Sort of like the twinkie defense,
right?
yeah.
Well the twinkie defense was hilarious,
but there are people that think that
they're going to see more and more
things like that at a former nfl players
with massive brain trauma issues.
It's actually a serious legal question.
You know,
like there was a couple of weeks ago
this kid doesn't even know he did this.
Oh god.
Oh wow.
Former nfl player.
Devonne hall accused of kIlling his
mother.
He doesn't remember.
He's in jail right now.
Doesn't recall.
Oh yeah.
Well that's real.
It's mean.
Yeah.
I don't find that wildly implausible
that the fact is that we have an
insanity defense and what it means you
don't know right from wrong.
Well,
if you don't know what you're doing,
like this is something they teach in law
school.
If you're sleepwalking,
he kill somebody and there's no motive
sets.
It's difficult to like you need mental
treatment but it should.
You be in jail for that.
Not,
not really.
I mean they've had cases where people
are like sleepwalking and they think
that in their dreaming at the same time.
So they think that their wife is
actually like this defense has been used
where they think they're the wife of
some sort of monster in the room.
So they clobbered to death and then they
wake up and like,
oh,
that was my wife.
It's a really creative defense or it's
true.
I mean,
one of the toe so well,
if we know that people can go crazy and
we know that brain trauma is a real
issue,
the two of them together,
I mean there's something about getting
knocked around in the head where it's so
completely unpredictable and then you
add in this impulsive nature of their
behavior that happens.
There's something really weird about a
brain trauma.
It causes a lot of very strange,
impulsive behavior in people with.
They really can't understand even why
they're behaving the way they're
behaving.
Just not good.
Obviously this is way off track,
but it's far from politics to brand
trauma.
You don't want a former nfl player being
the fucking president.
So that's.
They did a cte study.
There was a hundred and 11 players and
110 of them had cte.
I mean,
then you tell me,
you,
you have more experience at this.
I mean,
I didn't find that shocking at all.
I mean they've been calling people punch
drunk since 1910 and so we'll see.
The thing is,
when you get to that,
when you get to the slurring your words
part,
you're so gone,
you're already gone.
There's a lot of people that have cte
that speak really well and they're very
articulate and they're very reasonable
and you wouldn't even understand that
they're dealing with all these,
this host of neurological issues.
The by the time you avoid,
obviously I'm not a neuRologist,
but by the time this has been explained
me,
your voice
is slurring and you're dealing with like
real heavy duty symptoms like you're
fucked.
Like you're so gone.
Like you're,
you're,
you're way off.
Here's a weird question for you.
I mean,
what,
what would you do about like,
I think the nfl is gonna start losing
viewers because of us.
I think they are.
I think you're right and you know,
I wonder about mma.
It's a factor.
I think there's a,
there's two things going on.
There's the bucket factor where people
like,
I don't care.
I want to watch people get their ass
kicked.
It's fun.
It's exciting.
People love it.
It's consensual.
It's primal.
Yeah,
and people know what they're signing up
for when they do it,
they know the consequences of it and
it's worth the glory to be the guy who
delivers it versus the guy who receives
it.
So I think there's that,
but then there's also look the colin
kaepernick thing,
I think that
probably costs a lot of ratings for the
nfl.
Did that poll that came out that said,
I think of the 12 percent of people who
said that they were not watching nfl
games last year,
28 percent of that,
12 percent said that the cabernet
national anthem thing was the reason.
Yeah,
I mean it.
Some small percentage probably
emboldened them.
They probably liked it and they wanted
to watch it more.
This is fascinating about the cultural
breakdown of the country.
Basically white people hated black
people loved it.
This is it.
This is how the polls where it's like 72
percent of black people thought it was
great and like an equal percentage of
white people thought that it was just
terrible,
which is,
which is a fascinating look at it.
Sort of how race relations work in the
country at large is it?
It'S actually one of the reasons I think
that espn has been losing ratings.
Like I used to watch espn religiously
and now I,
I,
all I want is to just watch my sports
and not Be bothered with the politics
because I say I do that during the day.
It's a pet peeve of mine and every time
I turn on espn I have to lecture about
caitlyn jenner or about black lives
matter.
It's like shut up.
Caitlin jenner hasn't even been
athletically relevant fOr since before I
was born.
I was born in 1984.
Well the caitlyn jenner piece,
when they did it for espn,
and I don't know if this is true or not,
but the word was that her getting
athlete of the year or whatever the
award was like the hero of the year
award arrow a was directly tied to the
exclusive interview with Diane Sawyer.
That makes sense.
They sold the two of them together as a
package deal,
which I buy a hundred percent and if you
don't,
if you don't,
come on.
Let's think about where he works,
if that's the case.
She came from.
She's a fucking car dash 10.
Okay.
She's a giant kardashians.
Right?
That's what she is now known as.
I'm saying she saying she,
I would say very politically correct and
I'm not.
Um,
but the video where they circled her
house and she was like moving and the
shadows behind the drapes.
Did you ever see that?
No,
it was wonderful.
It was wOnderful.
She made,
it was like the first time she was
revealing herself as this woman.
So they're circling her house.
She's this gloria's house and looks like
it's in malibu or somewhere where
they're circling the house and it's in
the hills with helicopter,
like filming I guess like fucking high
production values.
Shit.
This isn't just like,
hey,
you know,
we've met with caitlin and home.
Caitlin,
tell us your troubles.
You know,
like kristen beck,
the former navy
who just sits down very reasonably and
says,
this just feels better for me.
This is who I am right now.
Know that there was like curtains and
shadows and it was mysterious.
And then she starts talking.
I was like,
wow,
are all.
I'm like,
oh god.
And then there was a weird,
the weirdest part where she said she got
surgery,
but it doesn't make me any.
I was.
It wasn't like I was any less of a man
or less of a woman before the surgery.
Well,
this is the case is about gender,
right?
Well,
why get the surgery?
That was like this as well.
There are a lot of questions as to the
logic of all of this.
I get you call it caitlyn jenner sheet.
Caitlyn jenner is a biological man.
Sorry.
That triggered sat.
Sorry to break this to some of the all
the people who listened to your show.
Caitlyn jenner.
Is it like.
I had a tweet this week.
All the people that listen to probably
agree with you at least a good good
amount to the number one retweet a tweet
I have ever had.
Had 100 and I tweeted I think a day ago
and it has 120,000
lakes and it's.
It was,
there was a headline from cnn that said
transgender man gives birth to a
transient lesbians,
transgender man,
a signed the female sex at birth gives
birth to a healthy baby boy,
and so I tweeted,
woman gives birth to a boy because it's
a woman.
I mean like that's not a headline.
I'm sorry,
like I'm just.
Because the woman believes she's a man,
doesn't make her a man.
Like biology still exists.
Sex still exists.
If you want to say she's a woman who
feels like a man,
that's fine.
If you want to say that and by that I
don't even care if she gets the hormone
treatments or if she wants to have
surgery,
like it's a free country,
what the hell you want,
but when you start insisting that I use
that,
I just throw biology out the window.
I don't understand why that's any better
than it is a religious person saying
every time you say something you have to
mention god like,
well,
I don't have the right to do that to
you.
Like what the fuck?
Are you fascinated by it?
Are you fascinated by the transgender?
The I'm fascinated by this obsession
with it.
Yes.
That's a good way of saying it.
There's not just a an obsession.
It's,
it's compulsory and it's rabid.
So I think that there's a couple of
things that are going on.
One is that it's very dark,
but I think that there is an element of
like,
this is different and we get to.
We get to revel in the,
in the weirdness of it,
but we're going to pretend that it's all
about the civil rights of it,
right?
We're going to feel special because
we're,
we're.
Because we're on their side,
right?
When we're not watching caitlyn jenner
because it's a curiosity and because
it's weird and entertaining,
we're doing it because we're on caitlyn
jenner's side,
but they're feeling really good about
people forever.
Right.
I mean,
renee richards was a trans person.
It's happened throughout history.
I mean there's,
there's.
What was I reading a couple of days ago
about a roman,
like there was something about reports
of some trans soldier in the roman army
born a thousand years ago.
it's got to be.
If it exists now and it's existed
before.
It was popular.
Yeah,
I mean there's got to be a lot of people
that turn trans now just because it's
exciting.
Oh,
there it is.
Right there.
A trans soldier in the ancient roman.
Of course it wouldn't be.
WouldN't be surprised.
Not
shocked.
I mean it's a condition.
I mean the been called gender identity
disorder and then they called it gender
dysphoria.
It's a condition.
I mean like I'm not saying conditions
for and but that in a lot of people's
mind is labeling it somehow or a
negative.
Well,
I mean it is highly linked to
suicidality.
There's a 40 percent lifetime suicide
rate for people who have this particular
gender disorder.
That seems to me not to be like a great
positive.
Whether or not they transition whether
or not the transition.
Yeah.
I don't care if you transition to what
you want to do,
but.
But the ideA that,
that we as an entire society,
you have to redefine what sex is and we
have to blind ourselves to a biology is
this is something I'm not willing to do.
I think that it's actually damaging to
kids particularly more than willing to
call her she and,
but you can only change the name once.
I'm willing to call caitlyn jenner,
caitlyn jenner.
I'm not willing to call caitlyn jenner
issue because you can't change your sex.
Can change your name,
you can change it into whatever you
want.
I don't care,
but you can't.
She caitlyn jenner is not a chicken.
Caitlyn jenner is not a woman.
Caitlin jenner is a man,
a biological man,
and if a man lost his penis and it and
it,
you know,
in a,
in a tragic accident,
it wouldn't make them a woman.
And if he were born with high doses of
estrogen in his bloodstream,
he would also not be a woman.
You are determined by your chromosomes
and it's not even talking about intersex
people like intersex is natural status.
Intersex is a biological status,
but this nonsense that if you joe rogan
decide tomorrow that you are a woman,
no surgeries nor homeowner and the
homeowner,
nothing.
You just,
tomorrow you wake up and not,
not the side,
but you feel like a woman.
Then you have always been a woman.
We must treat you as a woman.
You don't have to change anything about
yourself for us to even determine
whether you're a woman.
We just like,
no,
I'm sorry.
No,
I mean like I had mental illness and I
had a grandfather I got,
I get so much shit for this,
but I had.
This is not me being unsympathetic to
people who suffer from a condition that
is really tragic and obviously harms
people.
You know?
In terms of the.
Again,
the rates of suicide and depression are
astoundinG.
My,
my grandfather was a,
was a bipolar schizophrenia and it would
have not been good for him or my family
if people had said to him,
nate,
you're right,
the radio is talking to you,
nate.
You're right.
The curtains are talking to you.
He Went and they put them in a mental
hospital.
They gave them lithium and then he was
Better and he could actually live a
normal,
relatively happy life.
There's no good treatment for gender
identity disorder,
gender dysphoria,
whatever you want to call it,
but to suggest that it is a condition
that doesn't require treatment there.
Really,
it's just that you're actually brain
female.
Again,
this is a scientific.
There's no scientific evidence to back
this whatsoever.
Even these studies that have been done
talking about,
there's a female brain and a male brain.
First of all,
if you say this to a feminist,
you're a sexist,
right?
Right.
If you say to a feminist,
there's a female brand in the male brain
and male brain works differently than
the female brain.
The feminists will look like,
how dare you?
Well,
it's also one of the rare times where
you're allowed to celebrate classic
definitions of female beauty.
When a man embraces somebody becomes a
woman lipstick,
high heels,
short skirt.
This is like caitlyn jenner was.
Caitlyn jenner was only a woman when
caitlyn jenner was on the cover of
vanity fair to boost da.
Right?
Right.
But if he had just said,
listen,
I look exactly the same as I did
yesterday,
but I'm a woman.
Yeah.
If you've got a short haircut and dress
like billie Jean King,
right?
It's the reason why the why the media
loves laverne cox because laverne cox
has had surgeries and looks a lot like a
woman.
So I don't know who the guy from.
Uh,
well,
the transgender woman from orange is the
new black.
I never watched the show.
I've never watched that show either,
but she's on the cover of time magazine.
Oh.
Or he's on the cover of time magazine.
Well,
there was the woman in that show.
Isn't that the one where the girl who
ruby rose.
Is that the girl that's laverne cox?
That's a woman or man,
that's man.
I used to be a man.
It used to be a man and a woman now.
Very tricky know still a man.
But transgender tipping.
So out of the loop.
I'm not old man.
I'm that old man was one that headline
there,
right?
It says america's next civil rights
frontier.
And that's the case.
Do you have a bunch of people in the
United States who are suggesting that
they want the next civil rights fight?
Always the next civil rights fight,
right?
The civil rights fight.
Does immigration or the civil rights
fight is gay marriage or the civil
rights fight is transgenders.
Okay.
How about this?
How about there was only one real civil
rights fight and it was about black
people who had been historically
oppressed in the United States for 200
years.
There had been slaves who had been
slaves and the transgenders.
This is correct.
Okay.
The worst that caitlyn jenner had
experienced as being incredibly wealthy
in a,
in a high net worth suburb.
This transgender people don't,
you know,
aren't discriminated against in some,
in some areas of american life.
I'm sure that's true,
but it's also like behavior is not the
same as being born black or being born
asian or being born with,
you know,
a disabled.
If,
if I'm a business owner and I hire you
and you're a man and you come in the
next day and you're dressed in a woman's
clothing saying you're a woman,
but you still have a full beard.
Like I don't see why I as a business
owner,
I'm expected to eat the cost of that
like that.
It seems.
That seems bizarre to me.
Eat the costs is a great way to phrase
it.
I didn't have a dog in this fight.
I didn't.
I,
I was completely open and liberal about
it until there was a case where a man
who had been a man for 30 years became a
woman for a little less than two years
and then started mma fighting women.
YeS,
exactly.
Exactly.
Getting the fuck out of these women and
shy and not prOclaiming that he or she
used to be a man because what it in
quotes,
it was a medical condition that I did
not need to disclose.
Like that's not,
I'm fucking medical conditions.
Right.
And if you ever watched the fights when
Alan Fox,
she wasn't winning because she was
skillful.
She was fucking manhandling handling
these women.
It was ugly horse.
It was horrible.
It's like this is.
But again,
it's so funny how the transgender
movement destroys the feminist movement
by living off of the,
the sort of lies that the feminist
movement promulgated to the feminist
movement said stupid things like women
and men equally athletic,
proficient with that
repeated very recently that there's no
biological difference in the genders and
it's all social.
That's
absolute horseshit.
I mean,
I'm sorry.
There is no scientific evidence to back
that.
And it's particularly true with regard
to actual physical capacity.
This is just nonsense that just no
scientific evidence but a.
Yeah.
I mean mountain of my favorite study on
this,
as you know,
there was,
remember there was that those
commercials about like throwing like a
girl running like a girl.
Remember those feminist commercials
saying what is it to be running like a
girl named shown an adult woman and
she'd be running on early and then they
would show little girl and she's running
and it's still a little girly,
but she's running,
you know,
like normally it's only,
it's only exactly fierce.
It's the only society that has forced
the little girl to run.
Like when we.
First of all,
I have a three year old girl.
She runs like a girl second of all and
it's not because I'm teaching her that
because her mom runs cause she doesn't
write,
but she played with dolls because you're
a sexist pig.
It's because of that.
My,
my daughter started off liking trucks
like in the first year and I didn't give
a shit.
Now she likes playing with dolls and
dressing up in princess dresses.
Like who cares?
She's a girl,
she's always been a girl.
She will always be a girl,
but that she likes trucks or whether she
likes.
It was an issue with one of my daughters
too.
My daughter was a little worried about
argos,
she's going to be a dyke.
She was like,
no,
what's the big deal?
You like lesbians,
who cares?
I don't care.
I do not care.
And she's like,
and then she turned the corner and then
she got.
But we just let her be whatever she's
in.
But she was really into like batman for
awhile,
but my daughter is in a.
And then she was into wonder woman like
who cares?
But what's funny about this is that the
left kept saying,
even when I met my wife,
right,
who's,
who's a conservative,
and I made her more conservative when we
got married,
because that's what men tend to do to
their lives,
but she,
I remember early on we had a
conversation about this and I said,
women don't throw like men and she got
like all offended and I said,
but that's factually true.
Said rigHt?
But it's.
But it's insulting.
It's like,
no,
that's factually true.
Like I'm sorry,
like there've been studies out of a
thousand,
if you took a woman throwing a baseball
and then a thousand men throwing a
baseball,
the woman will throw faster than out of
those thousand men is in the book.
The sports gene,
the one who will throw faster than two
of those men out of a thousand.
And we're not talking about like goose
gossage here.
We're talking about,
we're talking about the accountant from
down the block.
We're talking about Paul Ryan flinging a
baseball,
right?
I mean,
that's not the way this stuff works.
Well,
that was the counter that found fox used
was that she actually lost to a woman.
She lost a woman named ashley evan
smith.
But what I said was,
no,
this proves my point is that you're not
good.
You're just a man.
well,
this was the john mcenroe got slapped
all over the lot when he saId about
serena williams.
She's great.
So one of them is great and all.
But if serena williams were compete,
he said she's the best female player
ever.
And they were like,
well,
why not just the best player ever?
And he said,
because she's a woman,
like if you were a man,
she'd get her ass kicked.
And everyone was like,
no,
how dare you.
There is something called the universal
tennis ranking should rank in the mid
ranks of college male players.
If you were a man and serena williams,
It's like five years ago now.
I never want to play with like andy
roddick.
He'd kill me.
She actually did this.
there was a 200th rank man in the world
who she wanted to just warm up with and
they played a like just a normal match
for a one,
six,
one six,
nothing right.
And he was and he was like ranked 200th
in the world and the only shock was that
he dropped a,
dropped a point to her.
Well,
there was the issue of renee richards,
when renee richards started playing
tennis against women and kicking their
ass and he was a middling player at best
as a woman or as a man rather.
But as a woman,
he was a fucking killer.
Hey,
this is what you didn't solve.
Feminists.
It turns out the caitlyn jenner,
when all these hero of the year awards
and everything we met are so great that
even when we decided to be women were
better than women.
I was a woman for six months.
He's amazing and incredible addict.
He's just using natural.
He's a gold member.
Better even at being women than women.
They know wonder feminists are pissed
and they should be.
And,
and this whole glossing over the
difference between feminists who have
been claiming that women are distinct
from men and important and different and
better in certain ways.
Like I don't understand how you hold
these two simultaneous thought.
Hillary clinton needs to be president
because we need a female president,
but also Donald Trump,
if he said he was a woman,
tomorrow would be a woman.
How Do you hold those two simultaneous
thought?
I always thought that in the last week
of the election of trump thought he was
gonna lose.
He should have just declared himself a
woman and then he too could have run the
first female president.
I would have been incredible trailer if
he just showed up on the dress and the
entire left
fires a woman.
I'm the best looking woman ever.
I've been.
I've been voted as the best looking
woman of all time.
Great arguments that I got it online
when wasn't even arguments and put it so
many people were calling me a bigot
because of this fallon fox thing.
It was.
It was stunning because it was so
confusing to me.
I'm like,
I'm talking about defending a biological
woman,
like these biological women,
at least two of them got the fuck beaten
out of them by found fox before they
found out that she used to be a man.
I'm like,
that's not an issue to these people,
and so this one woman said,
she's always been a woman,
and I said,
okay.
She gave birth.
She impregnated a woman and got her
pregnant.
I go,
what about that?
And she goes,
even then he didn't.
Then she was a woman.
She was a woman.
She went and she was fucking a woman
with her dick and getting that woman
pregnant like we are in fantasy land.
It's crazy town,
but this doesn't mean this is what's
crazy.
Like yOu can't just because something's
a logical.
You can't just decide that someone's a
bigot like you were in a weird area.
We're talking about bone structure and
here's the crazy thing.
ToDay they are.
Here's the crazy thing is that they
always rely on these gender reassignment
doctors to define the terms and it's
really interesting because I got deep,
deep,
deep into the rabbit hole with this
because I was really shocked at how many
people were angry at me and there was
one doctor who is a board certified
endocrinologist who's sort of broke it
down.
She's like,
not only is the science behind this
crazy,
but when you have gender reassignment
surgery,
one of the big issues with men
transitioning to women as bone density.
She's like,
when you have gender reassignment
surgery,
you're taking estrogen,
which actually preserves bone density.
She's like,
not only do they have less bone density,
once they become a woman,
they might have more.
Well,
because you're preserving it like it's.
You're not going to automatically be
just like a woman in a year or so.
Don't think surgeons.
I know too much about doctoring from
having spent 1000 years with my wife's
medical education to believe that
doctors have the capacity to magically
change a man into a woman.
No,
maybe it's going to happen one day with
like crispr or something that when they
start using genetic,
literally genetic before birth.
Maybe if you actually read the
chromoSome this before birth,
but no,
I mean like no once.
Once your.
Once your genes had been defined.
What's your chromosomes like?
This is fifth grade science people.
it's fifth grade science.
What scares the shit out of me is when
you hear these stories about people
deciding that their child who's like
eight or nine years old,
that beyond belief,
it's scary because you see nine year
[inaudible],
17 year old doesn't know.
That was the thing about the ruby rose
girl.
She was saying that when she was young,
when she was a teenager,
she wanted to be a man.
She wanted to be transgender and that
she had gone through that phase and now
she's so happy that she didn't do
anything.
Right.
Well they did.
They say that 80 percent of kids who
experienced any sort of gender dysphoria
as children grow out of it,
so when you have a society that
reinforces it and then in Canada they're
now having their passing laws.
Now that say that if a kid says,
you know you have a girl and the girl
says,
I'm a boy and she's three,
that the government can come into your
house and take the kid because obviously
if you.
If you don't want to humor the kid and
get the kid treatment or surgery or
hormone blockers,
then you're obviously doing something
wrong to the kid.
This is just.
It's insane.
First of all,
if anyone tried to do that with my kid,
I would meet them at the door with a
gun.
I mean that,
that this is.
This is the kind of stuff where you're
talking legit civil war.
Like when when you say that the
government can take people's kids from
them because the government knows better
than you.
How to parent your kids on basic things
like are you a boy or a girl that's
going to get violent pretty quickly?
If you send someone to my door with a
gun saying,
I'm taking your daughter from you
because your daughter says she's a boy
at school and you and you're not going
to take her to a psychiatrist to start
her transitioning process.
No,
buT how did we get so far down this
rabbit hole of insanity and the,
this is again,
this is not taking away the personal
choice of a 60 year old man like bruce
jenner who decides he wants to be a
woman free country,
go have at it,
have a good time,
but how did we get so crazy that that
becomes an option that people aren't
paying attention to?
The,
the,
the massive variables that a child
encounters,
psychological variables,
stress variables,
what's going on in the home,
what's happening hormonally,
what's happening psychologically,
what is happening to you and how,
how can you decide like this is it,
you're good.
You're going to allow this kid to make
a,
like a lockdown decision to begin gender
transition surgery at like nine or 10
years old hormone blockers in there to
an eight year old.
Yeah.
And you know,
and then they'll show you like this girl
who's like 13 who used to be a boy and
you know,
you see her act and talk and they go,
how could you imagine that?
This isn't a girl?
Okay.
I,
I don't,
you know,
I don't know.
I don't,
I just don't know what happened.
I'm going to go with the fact that
there's a y chromosome in every cell of
that person's body,
except ironically for some of his sperm
cells to tell me that that's probably a
boy.
And,
and yes,
you can block the manifestation of some
physical characteristics that does not
change the chromosomes.
And there are legitimately intersex
people,
right?
I mean,
there are people who legitimately have
conditions like kleinfelter syndrome.
They're like,
these are,
these are actual biological things,
but if you're telling me any boy can be
a girl,
no,
no.
The answer is no.
And it's,
that's not biologically correct and
you're not doing any sort of service to
a child,
especially evidence list.
I mean,
you know,
you're doing no service to a child by
bringing bye by humoring what is
obviously a mental condition and a
mental condition.
By the way,
again,
linked 40 percent lifetime suicide rate
is higher than any other population on
planet earth by a whopping margin.
I mean telling kids that we are going to
force you into that.
Like you express when you're five that
you think you're the opposite sex and
now at eight we're going to transition
you into this and your suicide rate is
exactly the same as somebody who didn't
do that.
Railroad is very similar to someone who
didn't do that and,
and like this is somehow supposed to
benefit the person.
Uh,
it's just,
it's beyond imagination.
I think it's cruelty.
What's very strange
for sure.
And as someone who doesn't experience
gender dysphoria,
I like to,
I mean when,
when someone's got some sort of an
issue,
whatever it is,
whether you call it an issue or a
condition or whatever the fuck it is,
and I don't have it.
I try to be as,
as standoffish.
I tried to be as objective.
I tried to be as kind as possible.
This is a weird one though.
This is a weird one because it's,
it's become some sort of a fad and any
criticism of it whatsoever,
even discussion of it,
you are labeled as a transphobic piece
of shit.
Yeah.
I think it's only weird honestly because
it's run into the weird sexual politics
that dominates in the country because if
we're to talk about anorexia,
which is a form of body dysphoria,
yes,
alright.
Or if we were to talk about,
I mean there actually is something body
identity,
integrity disorder,
right?
Where people want to lose an arm and
we'd be saying,
well the problem is in your brain,
it's not in your arm,
like chopping off your arm seems a
little extreme,
but if you want to do that,
like go ahead.
But if you were a kid and it's and year
wouldn't say,
oh well this kid's gonna suffer with
this their entire life.
Let's just chop off their arm.
Now.
Prevent them from developing like this
is not an end to tell the entire society
that this is a positive.
Good is is a whole nother thing.
It's one thing to try and treat people
who have a disorder humanely.
It's another thing to redefine the terms
of the entire civilization as well as
biology in order to fit that.
This is valuing the subject of over the
objective.
Science is objective.
Your feelings about who you are is
subjective.
You can have those feelings,
but once you are trying to translate
those feelings into the objective
standard,
we almost told by now you're encroaching
on my territory.
It's not just,
it's not just you doing what you want to
do anymore,
you're,
you're telling me what I have to do,
and that's a different thing.
Right?
Right.
Now,
when people say that there is this 40
percent suicide rate amongst transgender
people,
I'm one of the arguments that I've heard
is it's because they're not accepted.
I've heard this too.
It,
yeah.
Yeah.
And that if they were accepted and then
they felt themselves and they felt loved
for their true self,
then it would be just like everybody
else
and I've seen no evidence to suggest
that if,
if there's.
If there is a decrease based on
treatment,
then it's marginal at best.
Dysphoria,
it's.
Is it uniform like.
I would like to know like is like gender
dysphoria.
Is it in a similar percentile as a
anorexia or what bodybuilders get or
what strippers get when they get triple
f tits,
like the anorexic suicide rate.
The dysphoria is a weird thing,
you know,
it's,
it's it is that people.
There's a girl that goes to my yoga
class that's anorexic and it's so
disturbing.
It's so sad.
It's horrifying.
And listen,
I'm not,
I'm not saying that we should mistreat
people,
but if again,
you're talking about an entire society
being forced to redefine basic
biological terminology,
then like it be an adult like live,
like live with this.
I'm happy to treat you with a.
Listen what?
I would hire a transgender person,
but I'm not going to see.
I'm not going to change what reality is
in order to humor you.
Like if you call yourself napoleon,
I'm not gonna,
call you napoleon napoleon.
Like this is not something I'm up for.
What'd you take
going into consideration though?
I mean when you were looking at this,
still goes,
what if someone was really good at their
job and someone else was equally good at
their job but not transgender?
Would you lean towards the not
transgender person because you say,
well,
the transgender person,
they're dealing with a host of
psychological issues obviously.
Well,
I mean,
I,
I think that you would have to think
about,
you know,
typical aspects of reliability,
just the same way you would with any
other mental disorder if you knew
somebody was,
was manic depressive,
which is super common and you have
somebody who is equally qualified.
He's not manic depRessive,
you might think,
well that might have an effect on,
on how they do their job.
Yeah.
so maybe,
I mean,
I,
you know,
I've,
I haven't had enough personal experience
with transgender people to know whether
it would impact a secretarial job or
something.
Probably not.
Yeah,
probably not.
But again,
to pretend that like transgenders in the
military,
this seems to me like in a decision that
should be made my military people who
actually have to determine how much does
this impact the job and if you already
have a group of people with a 40 percent
suicide rate who have high levels of
higher levels of instability,
is a group not individually as a group
and you're choosing which groups to pick
from to be on the front lines in small
units living under severe pressure for
months at a time.
Like is that something that,
is that what you're going to go for or
is that something where you,
you'd have to overcome certain
presumptions in order to get theRe?
Yeah,
I tweeted
something that kristen beck wrote the
other day.
uh,
but when the military band,
when trump apparently there was not a
real.
I know it's bullshit.
I mean based,
just to distract from the sessions
thing.
Is that what it is?
Yeah.
I get to 10 minutes later he was back to
20 minute sessions here.
This was the part about that I didn't
like.
Like I actually agree that there is a
question as to whether the military
should be recruiting transgender people
because I think that the military has
certainly it.
It creates a bunch of questions,
not just questions about who showers
with whom,
but also questions like,
okay,
you have a transgender man.
Does he have to fill the female
standards of fitness or the male
standards standards of fitness or like
these are actual questions,
does it?
How does it work with troop cohesion?
Right.
You have a group of men and I have men.
He's technically a man,
but he's had you treat as a woman like
does he have to carry the same amount of
stuff?
Is the guy like how does that work?
Exactly.
It does this the cost of gender
transition surgery and hormones and
psychologists like,
does that come into play at all here?
Would you recruit from the anorexic
community for the military?
That's it.
These are like real questions,
but that said,
that's why they commissioned a study
from general mad as hell at department
of defense.
He was going to look into all of this
and then give a report in six months and
trump just sort of tweeted it out there.
I agree that I think that trump's
general,
you know,
his general attitude on it is probably
correct in terMs of what the military
is.
They're doing what,
what it's not there to do,
but what I don't agree with is how he
did it at all because it's disrespectful
to the people in the military who are
transgender.
I mean like I wouldn't want to find out
in a tweet.
I want a better rationale then to tweets
and then we're back to.
And then we're back to,
you know,
like,
look,
they're doing more than I am serving in
the military.
I didn't serve in the military.
It seems like it would be pretty
hypocritical of me to say,
well,
it's perfectly respectful to say in two
tweets you're out because that's the way
it is without any sort of supporting
argumentation.
And he didn't actually implement a
policy.
He didn't give the policy to the defense
department so they could even implement
it.
The pentAgon says they're not
implementing it because they don't have
a policy,
so as a pr thing,
so this is a weirD pr thing,
but it really stirred up people in the
designed to do.
Right.
I'm sure.
Well,
either that or he just felt like
tweeting.
I think that's what I.
I think that's what it was.
I mean he wanted to shift the
conversation and it was the funniest
thing about that is that he did it in
two tweets in the first half of the
tweet was in consultation with my
generals in my military experts.
We have decided that we will no longer
accept ellipsis 10 minute gap
transgender people in the military.
So there was a,
there was a,
there was a story at buzzfeed that was
kind of funny.
They went and interviewed a bunch of
people in the pentagon and a bunch of
the people in the pentagon or like
during that 10 minute cap,
I didn't know whether we were going to
nuclear war,
what right.
Because that first screen we will no
longer could have been north korea's
missile missile test program.
So.
Wow.
Yeah,
they,
it,
this again is evidence.
Uh,
you know,
I think it's an example of even if I
think the policy is good,
good policy done the wrong way is
actually counterproductive for the
policies that I want to see.
None,
like I want it laid out by madison.
I want to lay it out by defense
department.
I want all the reasons laid out so we
can have a good discussion over it.
I don't really want Just like thought
vomit on twitter.
That's just not,
I don't think it's effective.
Well,
it also seems that this issue is such a
hot issue and it's also an issue that
you're not really allowed to have an
opinion on other than the standard
opinion is always trapped in a man's
body and this is the way it is.
And by the way,
this heart healthy this day.
Cardia notion that it's like a man then
the,
the soul in the machine.
And there was a woman deep down for 40
years we had three children with a man's
penis and now is now is escaping.
Whereas like ghostbusters again goes
faster.
If you've seen the man in england,
was it in england,
knows Germany,
the man identifies as a six year old
girl.
Yes.
And so they turned them into a six year
old girl.
So there's this clip that clip with me
that's going around the internet a fair
bit when I'm talking to a college girl
about this and she,
she's saying like,
men or men can be women and women can be
men.
And I said,
well,
how old are you?
I love that clip.
I mean,
come on,
why aren't your 60 actually six days.
And she,
she's like baffled lIke what?
And then it finally hits her and it's
like,
well,
you know.
Yeah.
So it's.
I think this is what's kind of
frightening about the age we live in is
that we can't even come up with common
definitions of basic things.
How are we Supposed to have
conversations with each other if we
can't decide what a man is or what a
woman is or,
or whether a scientific fact ought to be
relevant or not.
At least we could decide what was the
scientific fact or not before and now
it's like the subjective has just eaten
everything.
If I don't think it's a scientific fact,
it's no longer a scientific fact
and that's for amateurs of the argument.
It's become About freedom,
the freedom to be your authentic self
versus biology.
Right,
and again,
be be be your authentic self.
I don't give a shit.
They will do whatever you want,
like you know,
more power to you,
but it is no longer about your freedom
to be your authentic self when you're
talking about either the legislation
that impacts how I run my business or
how I raised my child or your suggesting
that it is my duty to humor your
authentic self.
Like I think there are a lot of people
who do stupid crap their entire life.
It's not my job to humor their authentic
self.
I mean I'm,
I'm pro drug legalization but I've never
done drugs and I think the drugs are
stupid.
You know,
don't tell me that I have to like cheer
when somebody smokes a joint,
like do what you want,
but don't tell me that I have to
redefine what I think is good and bad
behavior.
LIke that's silly.
Yeah.
It doesn't make any sense.
And the other thing that it became this
weird political hot point where we're
talking about bathrooms.
Yeah.
And then it become like the number one.
It was easy for people to sort of boil
down the argument into that I think,
right,
of course like this,
what about my children?
My children would you want a bathroom
and a man with a dress is going to come
in and he's going to claim that he's a
identifying as a woman.
And it got to the point where so many
people were upset about it that people
were boycotting South Carolina.
This one I thought was amazing was,
was the ncaa saying they were going to
remove the final four from North
Carolina because they passed the
bathroom bill in North Carolina and I,
I asked online,
okay,
so when are you going to abolish the
separate male and female divisions?
Of the ncaa,
like any you've said that we can't have
separate male and female bathrooms were
biological males play and biological
males go to one bathroom and biological
females go to another.
So why do you have separate divisions?
Why do you have a.
Why do you have an ncaa women's division
and an ncaa men's division?
Yeah.
Where does this go?
I mean eventually it boiled down.
I mean eventually it goes to one place
or another.
Like either we just say this is a step
too far.
It gives me a break,
you know,
science has no.
Or we say anyone can be anything at
anytime.
A man is a woman and a woman as a man
and you know,
it's in just pick have you.
We're seeing the videos of people that
are gender fluid.
I have seen those videos.
Those videos are fascinating.
They wake up one day and there were a
woman and the next day there are man.
And so there was a guy on npr,
on radio lab on the podcast who
transitions at times of stress makes
perfect sense to me in the middle of
having a conversation.
I just switched.
I'm paul now.
I'm amanda.
When
he's more stressed,
he switched into a woman because that'd
be really sexist,
right?
I mean,
I think that like if you're stressed at
work and he switched into a woman and
started crying,
that seems kind of sexist to me.
That's implying that women are the
people who cry at work.
So that is sex.
So this raises a bunch of other weird
questions like,
okay,
if you're like there's,
there's been this.
again you want to talk about weird.
There's been this,
this,
this weird push in parts of the trans
community to suggest that a male who
doesn't want to have sex with a
biological male who says he's a female,
is a,
is now a sexist against women?
Is it trans folk?
Right?
you're a bad person if you're a man who
doesn't want to have sex with a man,
a biological man,
and it doesn't make you gay to do that.
Right?
If you have sex with a biological man
who says it's a woman that's straight
sex,
but if you were to have sex with a
biological woman who says she's a man,
you're gay.
Yeah,
kind of weird.
Definitely weird,
but I have seen the arguments in the
blog Posts and the tweets about men who
discriminate against trans women who do
not want to date trans women
and people keep saying,
well,
it's.
It's culturally defined.
It's like,
no.
That's called evolution.
What?
You have a baby together,
correct?
Correct.
It turns out that evolution wants men to
have sex with women.
Like,
I'm sorry to break it to everybody,
but evolution really relies on human
reproduction.
Okay.
If you put that thing in the wrong
place,
it ain't going to reproduce.
Like that's just salary.
I mean I don't.
I don't know why I have to keep
apologizing for science and,
and then they say that my party is the
party of non science.
Like what?
Like you're the ones who say that two
minutes before my baby is born,
it's not a baby and a man can be a
woman,
but I'm anti science.
I'm just,
I'm am wildly confused by this.
Well,
the whole thing is
wildly confusing.
Um,
but it's just such a strange subject.
It's such a strange subject that's been
brought to the fore.
I think it's about more of the moral
posturing than it is about people who
actually think this is a major issue.
I think you're absolutely right.
And I think people love to be virtuous.
They'd love to be on that side.
They live to virtue signal.
How dare you,
how dare you with dick's or lack of fake
dicks,
but they don't really have a lot of fake
dicks.
they don't really go that far.
They just sort of take testosterone and
see what's up.
But it's just,
it's a,
it's a weird facet of our society today
that is unexpected.
I mean you go back 20,
30 years and it was an oddity and you
know,
even during the renee richards thing,
it was more of an oddity than anything
I think just sort of accepted that.
This is why I say I think that it's a
think that a lot of people who are
virtue signaling are still treating it
as an oddity.
They just won't admit that.
I think that they're watching it because
it's a circus to them and I think that's
actually cruel.
I don't think that you should like put
people who suffer from mental illness on
the cover of magazines.
I just don't.
I think that that's bad strategy.
What about bodybuilders?
I mean,
I don't know that.
I'll be honest with you.
I don't know that much about
bodybuilding.
I mean,
well they don't.
Do I look like I know that much about
the argument that I've heard of crossfit
guy.
I'm more of a marathon runner.
What I've heard the argument about
bodybuilders that they suffer from it as
well is that in order to get that big,
you almost have to have some sort of a
body dysmorphia.
You.
You have to not understand how insanely
huge
you are and they'll be really into it.
Their argument is they're really into it
and which makes sense to me,
but I've heard people say that,
that it's.
It's like almost like a reverse
anorexia.
They never feel like they're big enough
that people say that before.
Yeah.
Well,
it's weird that the human mind is
suspect or uh,
subjects were really open to suggestion.
Really open to suggestion,
which is what scares people about
children transitioning for sure,
for sure.
I mean,
listen,
you,
you see it in everything including
fashion.
Like how many dudes wax their chest now
30 years ago.
Nobody likes theiR chest or they waxing
to waxing jeff chest,
wax their chest whenever,
whatever it is,
questions about the youth are turned to
young jamie.
Yeah,
it did.
But you watch tv now and every dude on
tv has a chest as bare as my young 14
month old son.
So I hear you.
And it's like,
where'd this come from?
and this came from grades.
We'll look chiseled.
And it also came from tv and tv.
It was going to be men are going to be
hairless.
Now this is,
this is the new trend of men are going
to be hairless and you don't,
you don't get the burt reynolds like
bare chest anymore.
And so if people are susceptible to even
that with regard to fashion like people
have for for five years,
people convince themselves that skinny
jeans or thing like people are open to
to virtually any sort of suggestion,
bell bottoms that come in and come out
member when they try to bring bell
bottoms back.
I did or did not a good call.
They tried and people are like,
nah,
not this one.
Platforms when they used to be our
platform shoes that that's why I'm just
keeping around all my dad's old clothes
because eventually they're going to come
back in again.
You never know.
Yeah.
The,
the idea of fashion and culture also
being like the saMe sort of mechanism
that allows people to be variable when
it comes to their gender.
That's.
I mean you actually see that there's a
study.
I thought this is fascinating.
There was a study in britain or Poland,
britain about sexual orientation and
what I found was 95 percent of people
over the age of 60 identified as
exclusively heterosexual of people who
are under the age of 30,
only 42 percent identified as
exclusively heterosexual.
It was like,
okay,
well in two generations it's not that
half the population became bisexual,
right.
That is not a scientific thing.
That means that people are open to
suggestion about their sexual behavior,
which you would assume.
Right.
So,
so assuming the culture has no impact,
and this goes against the whole of born
this way aspect of the homosexual rights
movement and the gay rights movement
that says,
oh,
you were born this way.
Like I agree that there's a genetic
component to sexual behavior,
but the idea that that's what,
why 50 percent of the uk population has
shifted toward,
you know,
I'm open to anything.
culture has something to present at,
as I say 95 percent people over the age
of 60 and then 42 percent of people
under the age of 30.
So that's it.
So that's 42 percent.
Say that exclusively.
No,
no.
Forty two percent of people say they're
extremely,
a heterosexual,
extremely high forties,
exclusively heterosexual.
So 60 percent,
nearly 60 percent,
78 percent say that they are on the
spectrum,
but not exclusively heterosexual.
That's fascinating.
I wonder if they only talk to women who
are drunk,
like young drunk girls.
They get crazy,
but I think also for perella thing,
right?
Where adam adam has a whole shtick about
like in the future there's going to be a
point where guys are considered gay if
they won't kiss another dude.
Like,
what are you gay,
you afraid that your gay kiss another
didn't show me you're not gay.
It's,
we've gone.
We've gone around the bend a little bit.
We have.
There's also this thing that I think
happens when you have to very clear
sides,
you know,
were you have teams and you sort of a
line in the sand not supposed to cross
and there's the right side and there's
the left side and we have that in this
country.
We really don't have a third party
option.
No third parties are kind of a joke.
And whenever you have two opposing
viewpoints,
people dig in.
Have you,
have you seen this new documentary
about,
um,
William F.
Buckley,
gore vidal.
And the debate is any good.
It's great.
It's really interesting debates they had
during the 1968 election.
It's fascinating to watch some of those
debates,
but yeah,
it's intense.
Yeah.
Particularly the little buckley
threatens to punch,
fit all queer and says,
I'll sock you in the face and you'll
stay plastic flask.
It's weird because it's a pastor.
It's spectacular.
And it's such a like,
it's so in the,
the speak of the day,
you know,
like 19,
68,
the brahmin accent.
It's,
it's,
it's great.
Like it's almost british accent.
Yeah,
it's fantastic.
It's really interesting.
And then.
But these,
I mean,
it's that thing,
this my team versus that team and uh,
I think the left is guilty of it as much
as the writers guilty of it.
It seems like it's,
it's a real issue where there's a lot of
people that have ideas and opinions.
It's sort of cross party lines,
but uh,
they vote on one side or another and
they vote for their team.
And I think that's right.
And I think that,
especially in this last election,
I think that was true.
I think that people felt so alienated by
the other side,
like to understand a lot of people who
voted trump.
You have to understand that there are a
lot of people in the country who felt
insulted by the left.
They were just sick of being called a
racist,
sexist,
homophobes.
Every time someone wanting to advance a
policy on the left,
and so they said,
okay,
screw that,
or at least trump's not calling me that,
so I'll do that,
and then there are a bunch of people on
the left who now feel insulted by
trump's even presence and they think all
the people who voted for trump are those
people until they're fighting racism,
sexism,
bigotry,
and homophobia by voting against trump.
Again,
I would go back to this at the end
there,
there's a hardening of of it.
There's not one bubble in the country.
There's still,
you know,
the right likes to accuse the left of
being in a bubble in the coast.
There's a bubble on the right to which
is the idea that everybody on every
piece of the media is lying to you.
Right?
Is fake news.
Everything's fake news.
Fake news.
These bubbles are not healthy for the
republic.
I mean,
what?
We can't have conversations with each
other.
If we,
if we do this 10,
no deception is not healthy across the
board and there's another thing that's
going on where everybody's a nazi,
like I've never heard people called a
nazi more than i have over the last six
months.
I mean,
it's been crazy.
If you support trump,
you're a nazi,
you're a neo nazi or you're somehow
or another,
you're a fascist.
If you didn't vote for hillary,
you're a nazi.
Like some people have boiled it down to
like the purest form.
Yeah,
I,
I agree.
I mean,
first of all,
it demonstrates tremendous historical
ignorance.
Forget the holocaust.
Like you just look at what,
who hitler was in the policies.
He promulgated,
like he was basically.
He was all over the place when he wanted
to talk to socialist.
He was a socialist.
What do you wanted to talk to
capitalist?
He was a capitalist.
He was.
He was a top down government guy for
sure,
but he would speak the language of,
of,
you know,
what would be considered the european
far right today on a lot of,
on a lot of issues.
But then he would talk about
redistribution of resources and
universal healthcare and all this kind
of stuff,
and I'm moving guns,
but he's just a convenient club.
I mean that's just a convenient club
because then and then did this part that
scares me.
Once you say that somebody is hitler,
then it actually becomes obligatory to
physically resist them.
Then we can say,
you can't have a conversation with
hitler once you say somebody,
hitler the kkk,
what are you?
What are you going to do?
Let's have a conversation with them.
At the very least you won't talk with
them and at the most you might try to
punch them.
That is really a problem with that.
Those the nomenclature,
right?
That's really a problem with identifying
someone in that way that they.
They are someone that you have to resist
and they are someone who cannot be
reasoned with.
The are someone who is absolutely evil.
There's no like variables are variants
in their behavior.
And,
and listen,
I like fiery political rhetoric.
I find it fun,
but I think once you label somebody,
you know,
completely evil,
you have a responsibility not to debate
with them.
First one is really not to talk with
them.
Even the conversation legitimize islam.
Yeah.
I mean that like I'm listening.
I'm sure you're gonna get a bunch of
shit from people for even having me on
because the idea is going to be,
well,
how could you have on somebody like
superior legitimizing his point of view
by having them on.
I know a lot of people who I politically
disagree with who've had that
experience,
what will have me on their show and it's
like,
how dare you have shapiro on because
you're just granting him cover,
you know,
like,
or we can just have a conversation and
maybe we'll disagree.
Maybe we'll agree.
Yeah.
I really don't give a fuck about those
people.
I think that's a silly conversation.
I feel like you should talk to everybody
and if you disagree or agree.
I have friends on that I owe my friend
yesterday I had on eddie bravo.
He believes in everything is a fucking
conspiracy.
I disagree with him wildly and I love
him like a brother.
I don't think you have to agree with
people and I don't think you have to at
the idea that you can't just have a
conversation with someone about
something and see if you can find middle
ground or see if you could clearly
define their point of view or find their
perspective that's missing today in a
weird way,
and one of the weirdest things about the
election was the ping pong match between
the left and the right as played out on
national television by the media.
I would watch,
especially cable news.
I would watch fox news and then go to
cnn and go back and forth flip channels.
You know you have that previous channel
button down the direct tv.
I would just put it on both of them go,
what,
what?
What's really happening?
It's beautiful.
The
worlds.
My mom said this in 2012 with romney and
obama.
If you read the right wing media,
there was no way romney was going to
lose and if you read the left wing
media,
there was no way romney was going to win
and she said,
which one of these do I believe in it,
so it's probably somewhere in the middle
like I have a basic rule which is that
if you have a New York times report and
then you have a report from my site that
daily wire and they share the facts,
you can probably assume the facts are
true,
but the opinions that are embedded with
the facts,
those are opinions and that's what's so
hard about.
I think the modern mediA landscape is
trying to separate the facts from the
opinion and so this is why when trump
says fake news,
he's not wrong that cnn hates him in the
New York times hates him.
He's right about that,
but just labeling it all fake news is
inaccurate also because most of what
they're reporting is true,
right?
It's just that it's biased against women
can be both true and biased and I'm true
and biased.
Right?
I say things that I think are factual,
but I'm obviously conservative.
That's my point of view,
you know,
tough shit.
So that's.
And you're
commentator,
right?
That's what you do.
I mean,
half of it is,
you know,
riling people up saying provocative
things.
I mean that's.
This is,
and this is where I think the right is
correct about cnn and the New York times
and some of the other networks,
like though,
if you ask the right,
what pisses you off more cnn or msnbc,
most people in the right will say cnn,
not msnbc because msnbc is honest enough
to say we're on the left and cnn
pretends we have no bias.
We're above all that same thing with the
New York times,
know we're above all that and then they
run the most egregiously bias headlines.
So we'd go,
well that if they're lying about that,
they're lying about everything.
You know,
one of my fast,
my most fascinating characters of this
whole play with Scott Adams,
and particularly because Scott Adams,
and when I had him on my podcast,
he was saying he doesn't even vote.
Yeah.
just like what I am.
What I am paying attention to,
he goes,
I'm a trained hypnotist and I'm paying
attention to the powers of persuasion
and I'm looking at trends and I'm making
some predictions that turned out to be
accurate.
And he's like,
he's looking at trump,
but he's not talking about trump and in
these glowing terms,
he's talking about him as being an
effective persuader and he lost millions
of dollars because of that opinion.
Talking about a guy that he's not even
going to vote for.
I mean,
this is all leading up to the election
where people were fucking furious at him
and even more furious at him after trump
won because he would do those coffee
with scott.
Things we does on periscope where he
wakes up and he's just starts answering,
asking questions and he's so measured
and calm.
And he had a podcast recently with sam
harris where I think it was just like a
little too far over the edge of
apologizing for some,
some,
uh,
trump's behavior and sort of attributing
some of trump's behavior too,
that you could say was in competence and
attributed to the,
like some,
some,
some sort of a master.
yeah.
Smelly quarrel with scott I think is
that he tends to believe that everything
trump does is 987 degree underwater,
upside down,
hungry,
hungry hippos.
Like everything is.
It's all just absolute genius and it's
three steps down the road instead of
like stumbling his way to victory.
Okay.
I knew everyone involved in the
campaign,
like every single person who is involved
in the campaign.
I knew this was a stumble their way to
victory.
It is amazing the minds,
human beings are.
We need to think it's sort of the joker
says in the dark knight,
we need to think there's a plan.
We always need to think there's a plan.
And so if trump won,
it must be because there was some master
plan that he unveiled over the course of
the campaign three weeks before the
election.
He was caught on tape saying that he
wanted to grab women by the p word.
No,
there was no master plan.
Right?
It's just that hillary was an awful
candidate and no one liked her.
Okay.
The,
the,
the idea that the trump was like,
even the idea that there was a broad
national movement for trump that wasn't
there for other candidates.
He won fewer votes in Wisconsin than
mitt romney did.
And he won the state.
And that's because no one liked hillary.
I mean,
this is the untold story of the
elections.
This was not a referendum on Donald
Trump.
This is a referendum on hillary clinton,
particularly in the heartland.
And people hated her guts,
right?
barack obama won Ohio walking away.
everyone talks about Michigan and
Pennsylvania and Wisconsin.
Nobody talks about Ohio.
Trump won Ohio walking away.
One of the reasons he won Ohio walking
away is because in 2012,
barack obama really drove out the black
vote.
The percentage of the black vote,
typically in Ohio,
it's like 10 percent of the general vote
in 2012 was like 13 to 15 percent of the
general board and that was the entire
margin of victory for obama in the state
of Ohio.
Hillary got closer to sort of the
traditional percentages and she lost in
a whopping blowout in Ohio.
No one likes hillary clinton and the
left was so arrogant that they thought
we can take the most unpopular,
unlikable,
unqualified,
nasty,
boring human being anyone has seen for
20 years and we'll run her.
She's the one will run.
But do you understand that the company
would have to look helen competence.
You have to be to lose to a celebrity
game show host.
Like you hAve to suck at this in a royal
manor.
Where at one,
I don't know.
Now,
now that thIng,
the floodgates are open,
but don't you think senator rock man,
apparently he's like way ahead.
Well the,
so the.
So he's going to win the primary.
If he didn't win the primary,
then he would have to run as an
independent.
Then he'd be indie rock.
Right.
Right kid rock is gonna win the primary.
Oh,
well we can only have one,
two.
Once he's in the office,
he grows into it and it becomes adult
rock.
How's ted nugent not run for office yet?
That's what I want to know.
How does he not know jim rock given a
conversation about running for
president,
you know,
and that,
if the people really wanted it,
he would do it.
And I was like,
oh jesus,
I just can't wait for the rock.
Oprah,
you know the rock my.
When the rock might win.
If oprah ran in 20,
20.
Yeah.
Is she the rock with oprah?
It's a fucking dual take.
Slam dunk man.
The rock and oprah together.
So I have this weird idea that we should
actually reinstitute a monarchy and it
shouldn't just be ceremonial and they
can be a celebrity,
right?
I'll just make a celebrity monarch and
that person will just be there to look
pretty and queen of england,
but don't really have anything.
No power,
no power because we keep conflating the
presidency with like who actually has to
do things right?
But like people who would want to
represent the country.
Yeah.
We have a popularity contest.
So who gets to control the nukes?
Which is insane.
That's pretty wild.
And I think that,
you know,
this is,
we all think in cinematic terms now and
you know,
hollywood is run by the dopiest jackass
is like,
I grew up with all these people.
These are not people who you want
controlling the narrative.
And then we're like,
you know what?
Let's take.
If tom hanks would only run if tommy,
what makes you think tom hanks would be
a good president?
Like did you look at trump and when god
he's doing such a brilliant job,
but we really need now is the guy from
castaway and we need as an actor again,
we did well with reagan.
We need another act.
We did great with swarts and anger is
the governor late.
At least.
Reagan was governor for 20 years before
he,
before he was the president of the
United States.
I mean,
let's,
let's put them,
let's put them through the ringer.
I mean,
shorts and I got approved in eight years
that he was not capable of doing
anything except kind of sucking will you
ever heard him talk about it?
The way it.
From his perspective,
he's lIke,
you don't really understand how much red
tape and bullshit you have to go
through.
He goes,
I would meet with people and they would
agree with me that it's a good idea.
However,
they would say my voters are never going
to agree with it,
so I'm going to oppose it.
So even though I know you're right,
there's a bunch of farmers that are
going to be mad at me for doing that,
so I'm not going to do that.
Well,
this is the other thing in politics that
really drives me nuts.
So there are two promises that
politicians make that are complete
bullshit.
The first promise they make is I'm going
to go to Washington dc and I'm going to
get things done.
No,
you're not.
Okay.
The system,
the system is built for gridlock.
It's built for gridlock.
It's why we have two separate houses of
congress.
It's why you have a president who can
veto is why we have a supreme court that
rules on cases is built for griddle.
It's wHy we have states that are
supposed to be able to check the federal
government.
All of a sudden the federalist papers,
it was built for gridlock
and some people are happy with that
because that's how trump is being like
sideline that every time he tries to
make something really important,
I think
they all should be happy with that
because the only way things were
supposed to get pastors with wide public
support,
right,
which she's probably a good thing.
We don't want the government shifting
wildly and veering on its access every
four years or every two years.
I liked the gridlock.
My big problem is that the gridlock now
protects a huge system that I don't like
that's been built up over 100 years and
in the case of growth of government,
but I liked the gridlock,
but that's one promise that's made and
then people are disappointed,
oh,
if we get in there,
we're going to repeal obamacare.
It's like,
no,
you're not.
You're not.
I mean like you can promise it,
but now you're not going to do it
because you're full of crap wHen you
said it and now you're not gonna do it,
and the gridlock is there and it's hard
to change things.
It takes a tremendous effort of will and
electoral power to actually change
things in a big way.
So this idea will elect trump and trump,
like trump would say,
it's all going to be so easy.
It's like,
no,
it's not.
It's.
It wasn't easy for obama.
Obama passed obamacare and that was it
for his presidency can do anything for
the next six years.
There were no major pieces of
legislation.
Nothing happened after that.
He lost congress and that was it.
Okay,
so that's a promise.
Number one,
the other promise is your anger is
justified,
and this is the one I hate even more,
and that is the idea that you know in,
in regular life,
when you have kids,
I have kids.
When you're a kid is angry.
The first thing you have to teach your
kid is maybe you're wrong to be angry
sometimes,
right?
Your anger is not justified.
If you want to make good human beings,
you have to determine whether they are
right to be angry.
Is he?
Is your anger correct?
Politicians are in the business of
justifying people's anger.
Oh,
he heard this about the trump voter a
lot,
right?
They're so angry.
Okay,
well I'm angry too about things,
but are they angry about the right
things?
Right?
Like,
and trump would say,
you're right to be angry because you've
lost your job in podunk,
Ohio because it's being stolen by the
chinese or by the mexicans or something.
And it's like,
well,
is that factually true or are you just
are just pandering to the anger and on
the left you hear people say this to to
black folks in the inner city.
It's the system that's keeping you down.
It's a racist white supremacist system
that's keeping you down.
Say,
well,
is that true?
or I just pandering to the voter because
it's hard to tell people hard truths
like you're not right to be angry.
Get off your ass and do something with
your life.
and it's true for it,
regardless of race,
you know,
go out there.
No one cares enough to stop you and your
life.
Your life is your own.
No one in the United States cares about
you,
wants to stop you.
Who wants to throw obstacles up in your
own way?
I'm not sure you can win an election on
the basis of go live your own life.
Even though everyone keeps claiming they
want to live their own life.
I think most people are full of it.
I think most people don't want to live
their own life.
They want a politician to tell them that
all of their complaints about life being
unfair or justified and the politician
is going to solve all that.
We don't want people who stay out of our
way.
We want people to be mommy and and you
know that's,
that's attempting,
attempting proposition for politics.
A lot of that when you talk to adults
because you're dealing with people that
have the momentum of all their failures
in life and all the different things
that are not going right.
And then here they are this moment
today,
right now,
and they want to figure out why and why
they're not on track in the how to get
on track.
And the easiest way is to point the
finger or blame someone else and
everybody has their own hand.
I'm not saying that people's hands or
are fair and that person doesn't have it
easy.
A lot of people that have it easy,
I have it easier than a lot of people
for sure for sure.
Absolutely.
But the reality is there's a tremendous
amount of psychological factors that go
into why someone does or does not
succeed and to placate them or to,
you know,
to,
to play on those psychological factors
as you know,
not being their own fault.
It's very tempting because it works with
people.
People love to hear that.
They love to hear that it's not your
fault.
Yep.
And I think that's what politicians have
become in the business of doing.
And it's both right and left.
It's just people saying that it's not
your fault because you're being screwed
by some foreign country.
It's not your fault because the
immigrants are doing it to you.
It's not your fault.
Well,
as maybe some.
Maybe some of that's true,
but you have to show me why it's true.
You have to show me what the actual
like.
Did you lose your job because of and
because of China or did you lose your
job because you're in an industry that
is being crowded out because of
technological change and because your
union struck and created wages too high
to be globally competitive.
Like let's look at the actual logic here
is to enhance and then how can we change
it?
How can we make it better?
How can we.
Is it something we have to do or is it a
matter of you need to broaden your
skillset.
Like you see a lot of people now who are
stuck in the mindset of 30 years ago
that you're going to work a job and
stayed there for 20 years and then
you're going to grow and then you're
gonna leave with the gold watch and
that's not the way the job market works
anymore.
I mean,
if you're.
If you're entering the job market right
now as a college student,
you can expect that in the next 10 years
you'll probably work four jobs.
You like the,
the turnover is too great and you have
to be constantly increasing your skill
set.
Also with
every new innovation,
there's businesses that branch out
become new,
and then there's also businesses that
die and there's no bringing them back.
You're not going to bring back the
printing press,
you know,
there's a lot of stuff that I really got
into printing press industry and tell
them that try and get elected from the
printing press guy.
Well,
I mean right now they're trying to stop
automated cars.
I mean those.
I mean there was a,
there was a vote,
right?
WaSn't there a vote like within the last
day or two to try to block automated
trucks.
Yeah.
Because there's a tremendous amount of
people that are moving,
but it's going to be a lot more
efficient when it's not people.
And you know,
this is the great fallacy that's been.
People have been trying to fight since
the beginning of the industrial
revolution as this idea of,
okay,
well the new technology is going to kill
jobs and then no one will ever work
again,
so we've had the same unemployment rate
in this country for the last hundred
years and the technology is a little bit
better.
Teamsters convinced congress to block
driverless trucks.
Yeah,
that's crazy.
That's crazy.
it seems crazy.
It seems like you're fighting an
inevitable tied.
Well,
I mean imagine that.
Like how is that going to work for all
the other industries that are affected?
Let's say that you now have your
artificially raising the prices of all
the goods that now have to be brought in
by the teamsters and now it's more
expensive so it's more money out of your
pocket and my pocket.
That's money that I'm.
Maybe I was willing to buy american,
but now I'm going to buy chinese because
I have to feed my family like this is.
That's not how economics works.
It's just not how economics was there.
Any argument that they're not ready yet
that these trucks aren't viable,
so that that's one of the issues is that
way with a lot of the.
So the automated trucks basically in
order for them to work,
you need dedicated lanes because
otherwise human error is,
is such that if like if there's a google
car on the road and you're a bad driver,
the google car is probably going to get
into a crash or might be more likely to
get in a crash then that if it were a
human driving.
Have you ever seen people freak out
those tesla cars and seeing what they
could do to them?
I haven't.
I haven't seen those tests.
I actually saw somebody do it to the
google car when you're,
uh,
when a car is on that automated thing,
if you just swerve at it,
they slam on the brakes and back up on
you.
Like people have done it to people and
filmed it.
When we see people using automated cars,
it's a,
it's,
it's not done.
It's not ready.
Yeah,
it's in the mix.
Again,
it's sort of like a hell.
There's a lot of fuel efficient,
lighter cars on the road,
but there are a lot more dangerous than
the heavIer cars because they're heavier
cars.
The clunkers are still around from 1970
in their tanks.
They just run through three prius's.
How do you feel about universal basic
income,
because that's a subject that comes up a
lot lately.
When elon musk is talking about these
driverless cars,
one of the things he's saying is that
one thing that we're going to need is
universal basic income.
He said,
we're going to have to figure out some
way to feed all these people that are
going to get taken out of the job market
because their jobs have become
irrelevant.
So I think that universal basic income
is for when the technology gets so good
that they're legitimately are no jobs.
I don't think that we're there yet.
So if you have a machine that can make
everything basically for free,
and then there's a bunch of people who
you don't need anymore to do work,
then you can talk about a universal
basic income because there's no
scarcity.
Scarcity is what creates a need for
labor.
So if their scarcity in any,
then there's
going to be a need for for labor,
there's going to be need for new labour.
People are going to still have to work
on these trucks and deal with
technology.
And the computer industry didn't destroy
jobs all over the United States on
typewriters went out.
So I think it's a little premature.
I'm not sure there'll ever be a day when
there's a machine that when the machines
society is so well developed that it can
take over all jobs.
I do think you'Re seeing a bifurcation
in the labor market.
So think people who Are in jobs like
yours and mine,
like we're lucky this is a creative job.
It's hard for machines to create.
But for jobs that are single task jobs,
a lot more of those are going to be
technologically driven and so people are
going to have to,
you know,
work the right side of their brain a
little bit and we're going to have to
train people in a different way.
But my perspective on universal basic
income is when you have a four percent
unemployment rate,
it's very difficult to say you need a
universal basic income.
It's again,
96 percent of people in the labor market
who can work are working.
so that's not,
that's not,
that's not suggesting to me that there's
this vast underclass of people who are
totally incapable of working.
And once you do that,
you see what you've seen actually with
the disability programs in the United
States,
right?
where now everybody's on disability.
Like the fastest growing government
program in America is the disability
program or people declare themselves
disabled so they can get government
pensions basically.
Once you have a universal basic income,
is there an incentive to work?
And also I'm not sure that you've solved
a lot of people's problems,
like people still see need something to
do with their day.
Sixteen year olds.
Do you see who retire and they're dead
within three years.
The utopian ideas that somehow or
another you're going to open up these
people's inherent creativity and they'll
find stuff.
Yeah,
the actually enjoy the country.
Julio,
I mean,
how many people say again?
You said who we like 30 2:33?
Yeah.
Thirty three to using the term holy.
Yeah,
I love it.
Yeah.
Again,
you know,
I'm,
I'm never,
I hope I'd never retire because I just
know too many people who retired and
they're,
oh,
I'm going to retire and I'm going to
golf there.
Other paint I'm going to trY and six
months later they're dead.
Yeah,
well people enjoy doing things and
feeling like they're valuable.
You know,
and I don't know if that necessarily has
to be a job,
but it's a very clear,
definitive test of whether or not you're
valuable.
If somebody gives you money and you get
that money,
you're like,
look,
I'm valuable.
I'm doing something.
I'm contributing.
I got a check for my.
We.
Exactly.
There's,
there's a lot of hours in the day and
it's going to be hard to fill that with
watercolor painting and beat poetry
classes.
I don't know,
man.
I'd find shit to do but I see.
But I,
I've been fairly self employed most of
my life.
I just have gotten in
driven.
Like I would find stuff to do too,
but there is a difference in,
you know,
not all human beings are the people who
would actually go out and take classes
and find things to do.
Do you have aspirations outside of
commentary when it comes to politics?
Maybe some point down the road.
Do you think you run for president or
something like that
and the.
Apparently anyone can.
And this is what I'm finding.
Yeah.
So,
but you're a reasonable guy.
I don't know.
I mean I,
I like what I'm doing in the sense that
I get to work on what people believe,
which I think is sort of the root of,
of politics.
I'm not sure implementing is the same
thing as I said,
I'm not sure that the president can get
like I'm more focused getting people to
think in the terms that I'd like them to
think,
you know,
about limited government and you taking
control of your own life and it might be
able to do more good.
Promulgating that message using a
growing media.
I'm like,
we're,
we're very lucky.
I mean,
the podcast went from having 3000
listeners,
you know,
a 300 episodes ago to now we have
300,000
listeners a day,
you know,
so it's,
it's,
it continues to grow.
So as that crowd continues to grow,
it's actually harder for me to say I'd
want to jump into politics.
Not easier.
I think the limited government thing to
me has always been a fascinating subject
because the people that don't want
limited government,
that is the utopian ideal in my mind
that somehow or another the government's
going to be effective if you give them
more money,
like,
well this isn't an argument with a
friend where he wanted people to be
taxed more because he felt like that
money could be distributed to people and
you would get more funding for the arts
was one of his arguments,
but it,
my,
my thought was like first of all,
the arts,
like when they're valued,
when people like them,
they pay for them.
If that's not getting funding for the
arts means you're going to have fucking
lacma,
la county museum of art.
You have a fuckIng box on the ground.
Let's someone's calling a piece of art
that guy think he went to.
It was either in san francisco or lack,
but where he went there and he took off
his glasses and he just put them on the
floor and then he stood next to them
going kind of standing there and kind of
stroking his chin scene.
There were 30 people all around and
staring at the glasses on the floor.
It's like,
it's amazing.
Yeah,
it's fucking horseshit,
right?
That the modern art exhibits.
Like there's.
There was another one recently where
someone like left behind a pineapple or
something.
Listen to the.
I remember this.
Yeah.
It's crazy.
It really is crazy and it's also
pretentious and it's also a stoking
those fires of pretension and making
something that's not legitimately
creative.
Making it a celebrated because you don't
really have the ability to create
something that's legitimately creative
as pointing this out today with regard
to.
It's funny how a lot of people who want
bigger government,
they embrace states that start to grow
the government and then when things go
to shit,
they're like nowhere to be found.
So Venezuela is the most obvious
example,
right?
Venezuela has turned from what was the
richest country in south America and had
the best oil reserves of anywhere in the
western hemisphere.
Basically they've turned it into just a
garbage heap.
People waiting in lines have a friend
named nami horwitz.
Went down there,
did some documentary stuff down there,
and he was a,
I think it's camera man got shot.
He was,
he was watching people like literally
shooting dogs in the streets for food.
And this is,
I mean it's.
Caracas is the most violent city in the
western hemisphere now.
And all of this is because google chavez
was a piece of garbage who centralized
all power to himself,
redistributed the wealth to all of his
friends and cronies and then,
and then supposedly uplifted the poor
except that now everyone is poor.
Wait a minute,
wasn't even friends with sean penn.
So I don't even know what you're saying.
Yeah,
exactly.
So,
so I might show today I played like sean
penn and Jesse Jackson and,
and uh,
that freak,
jeremy corbyn who's the head of the
labor party in great britain and they're
all just praising chavez,
right?
He's a great guy.
He waS a hero to the poor and now
Venezuela is going to shit.
And where all these
people,
like when someone's stick a camera in
sean penn split face like now and just
asking sean penn,
so like five minutes ago you were saying
this one
who's awesome.
Well there's gotta be some sort of a
left response for that.
like what is,
what is their take on why?
So the no true scotsman fallacy,
right?
They,
oh well,
you know,
this is them living on and it's because
they never really got rid of enough
private industry.
If theY just gone further,
it would have been better.
It's like,
well the soviet union and it didn't work
out that great either,
but like I actually got a response.
It was really funny.
the today I tweeted out that according
to the world bank,
Venezuela has one of the least income
unequal societies on earth.
So it's actually pretty income equal,
right?
Cause nobody has anything right.
And the end it's garbage.
And so the,
the socialist,
the official socialist party tweeted me
and they said this is because socialism
has never truly been tried.
Okay dude.
All right.
sure.
Why not?
Well that was the wonderful idea of
socialism is that it's going to even
everything out and that you shouldn't
get paid more for that no one should get
paid more and then everyone should have
some sort of a like a peak that you can
reach,
right?
Like there's some sort of competition
involved,
but he's got to be some.
TheRe's got to be some sort of incentive
but only so much.
Right.
Just like the bernie sanders's
democratic socialism,
like formal socialism is the state owns
the whole thing.
But democratic socialism is there's
private industry but only to a certain
point.
And then we tell people no.
Did you find out about bernie and his
wife and his wife's idea was to buy up a
bunch of land and expand the college and
then the fucking college went under and
now they're being sued.
Yeah.
Come on man.
It's awesome
based on,
on a lot of mythmaking about like
western europe in the Netherlands,
right?
So there's All this stuff.
Democratic socialist countries.
They're working great.
First of all,
a car in Denmark has a 60 percent import
tax and costs literally twice what it
would cost in the United States.
Tax rates in Denmark are insane except
for corporate taxes,
which the left in the United States
really,
you know,
they love corporate tax.
They want those higher.
Denmark has some of the lowest corporate
taxes and regulations in the
industrialized world.
so everybody is coming in and investing
in Denmark.
It's only the citizens who are getting
screwed by paying for this giant welfare
state.
Then their gdp tanked and now they've
had to elect,
right wing governments just lash back.
The the level of government.
I mean it turns out the capitalism is
the great engine that drives like
Singapore is.
There's nothing on Singapore.
Singapore is like a rock it.
There's nothing there.
Singapore has one,
the most powerful economIes on earth
because they basically have no business
regulations,
no taxes and no tariffs so that you can
do whatever you want and when people can
do whatever they want,
they make a lot of mutually beneficial
exchanges and of story.
This is not that difficult,
but.
But it is difficult if you think that
life is unfair.
Right?
So what would you propose?
Like what would you propose for the
United States?
Like the United States obviously would
trump wants to do is reinvigorate
manufacturing,
make things in America again,
bring back the labor force,
make the take away the jobs that are
going overseas and other countries in
south America.
Okay.
So I think that that's a bunch of
slogans from him and I don't think it
means and it so,
so number one,
I don't think a manufacturing job is
more than a tech job.
A job is a job and in industries that
are thriving,
you actually need more jobs and
industries tHat are not doing as well.
If the jobs disappear,
that's just the wages of a global
economy.
And that's.
I know it sounds harsh to people who are
in those industries,
but it's not a referendum on you or your
value.
it's just saying that certain industries
over time,
always our outsource,
like we used to make tee shirts in the
United States.
We don't make tee shirts here,
make them in Vietnam and it costs us
five bucks.
Right?
So,
so the.
So my view is I'm not going to Privilege
one day.
I understand a lot of this is politics.
You want to favor manufacturing basis
because there are a lot of manufacturing
hubs in Pennsylvania,
Ohio,
Michigan,
Wisconsin.
But then they vote since I don't care,
right?
Since I'm not a politician,
my view is that if you want a thriving
economy,
you relieve as much regulation as
possible.
He lowered the taxes for everyone,
personal and corporate.
You attract as much foreign investment
as possible and you allow people to
build businesses with as little risk as
possible and then you allow them to
compete and if they succeed they
succeed.
And if they fail,
they fail and you get rid of tariffs as
well because I want cheap inputs for my
products and I want you products on the
shelves at the store so I don't have to
pay a bajillion dollars for a pair of
shoes.
So I'm,
I'm,
my view of this is that economics is an
element of freedom.
I am a free person.
I get to do with my money.
What I damn well please.
And you don't get to stand in my way
unless there is some sort of moral
thing,
right?
LIke if you,
if you want to say,
well,
let's put sanctions on.
Let's put sanctions on Iran.
let's put sanctions on China,
right?
China is funding North Korea right now.
It hurts our national security.
We want to put sanctions on China to try
and pressure them into ending North
Korea.
That's a national security thing.
But the idea that like today,
trump rolled out this new plan on
immigration and he says,
I want to cut down on legal immigration,
but the reason is because I want to
raise wages of people in the United
States.
And I think,
well that's not productive because what
you're actually doing is you're
restricting the supply of labor
artificially increasing the wages,
which artificially increases prices,
which means it's not competitive on a
global scale,
which means the companies outsource,
right?
So it's the exact same thing as minimum
wage.
You create a minimum wage or
artificially increasing wages that
increases prices,
that makes it noncompetitive.
People outsource.
So it actually achieves the opposite of
what you're trying to achieve.
All government intervention in the
economy save for interventions that are
designed to prevent externalities.
You know,
things that I do that hurt you.
All of those are unjustified in my view.
What about our environmental?
So those are externalities,
right?
Right.
So like if I were to pollute a river I,
it's not my river,
I don't get to pollute it.
I get to throw my trash over my fence
into your yard.
Right.
That's,
that's,
that's a different thing.
That's it.
Yeah.
That's one of the most distUrbing things
about this administration is the cutting
the funding for the environmental
protection agency in the changing of
their Standards are removing some of the
funding for things like satellites that
they using to track the climate change
and things along those lines.
And I that,
that scares the shit out of me.
Like it scares the shit out of me.
They're going to ignore the environment
in favor of the economy.
So I think that some of the
environmental regulations are badly
drawn and some of them are overwrought
when it comes to,
for example,
fracking,
you know,
obama pushed a lot of environmental
regulations on fracking or the keystone
xl pipeline,
that kind of thing.
How do you feel about fracking?
Uh,
I'm,
I'm very in favor of fracking.
But what do you think about,
like when you hear stories about more
earthquakes happening and the in stable.
So water supplies the water table,
from what I've seen,
the,
the earthquake evidence is
extraordinarily weak.
Yeah.
And it's,
from what I've seen,
you know,
I'm,
again,
if you present me evidence that I find
convincing,
I'm happy to change my mind on this.
Right.
Um,
and uh,
as far as the,
as far as water pollution,
again,
the evidence has Been pretty weak.
So if that changes then I'm happy to
regulate it.
As far as when you say it's been weak,
there's,
there has been instances of fracking
leading to pollution,
right?
Sure.
But that's not every fracking leads to
pollution.
And so the question is coming on as the
regulation or how many are you willing
to accept?
Right.
Which is the truth for all business,
right?
I'm like how much we all drive cars,
how much water bottles?
Somewhere there's a seagull choking on a
cap.
Correct.
So like how much are you willing to
accept?
Like what I don't appreciate is when
people kind of.
What's the evidence when it's like,
oh well I accept my set my water on fire
because of fracking.
It's like,
no,
that's not because of fracking.
That's because of the ground water.
But in any case,
the,
you know,
as far as the satellites in,
in global warming,
um,
listen,
I think that it's pretty clear that the
climate is warming,
mean the greenhouse gas effect is a
thing.
The question to me is less whether it's
happening and more,
what are you going to do about it
because even the left seems to have no
real solutions as to what to do except
for massively cutting economic growth.
And it seems to me that if we're talking
about an increase according the epcc,
If something like seven degrees
fahrenheit over the course of the next
century,
then on average,
right,
not,
not universally on average,
then it seems to me that it's easier to
just say that the climate changes over
time and maybe cities that are on the
coast are going to have to pull back a
little bit over time,
like a 100 years,
a long time,
a 100 years ago you would've said that
the pollution was the chief thing to
worry about in the United States because
we were all using smoke stacks and
parts.
Intuit's.
Yeah,
exactly.
And now,
not relieving to regulation,
but just through market competition,
uh,
you've gotten better environmental
products.
So I think that the market does take
care of a lot of these things.
People don't actually want to live in,
in human waste,
you know,
like we actually don't want to do that.
So that has been disturbed.
Remain recently is how many times I see
bill nye on tv talking about climate
change.
What did he say?
Like again,
he's,
he has the same qualifications either.
I mean,
here's like a mechanical engineering
degree.
Yeah.
Well it's kind of a comedian.
I mean I think he is from my childhood.
Yes.
I believe he was a comedian.
Is a standup guy.
Yeah.
And
he does.
Did you ever see his,
his thing with tucker carlson,
which was great,
tucker carlson kept saying,
okay,
but you're talking about science.
So tell me how much of an effect do
human beings have on climate change and
what,
what is,
what's the science?
Me.
And all he wanted to say was that,
you know,
are you
consensus settle.
Yeah,
exactly.
And like,
what is,
what is the difference is changing,
right?
Give me a range.
Like it doesn't even have to be an exact
number,
but give me a range and then tell me,
okay,
what we have to do in order in your
opinion,
in order to stop the climate change
where it stands or if we can't do that
in order to minimize it.
What's the actual risk?
Also like people keep giving these
catastrophic scenarios where it looks
like the day after tomorrow and dennis
quaid running into subways and shit.
It'S like weirder ones.
He said was that we were supposed to
have an ice age.
Now that's not gonna happen like jesus
christ.
Man.
That's good.
Yeah.
You know,
randall carlson has been on my podcast a
few times and he's an expert in
collisions and asteroid collisions and
one of the things he said is he goes,
global warming is not great.
He goes,
but it's way better than global cooling.
This is true.
This is true in the middle.
Cool.
And kills everybody.
Right?
The little ice age was,
was not a good thing for the world.
The global warm period was actUally a
pretty good thing for the world.
So I mean this is,
thIs is the other thing is that there
are costs and benefits to the climate
changing which had,
which it has throughout time,
what are we willing to sacrifice in
order to prevent in order to make that
seven degrees into six degrees.
Right?
And just losing some coastline is not.
The real issue is far more devastating
than losing coast.
So I think that if you're going to worry
about,
if you're going to worry about,
you know,
the,
the emissions problem to worry about
the uh,
the c absorption of emissions,
like detoxification of the oceans like
that seems to me to be a bigger problem
than the climate changing over time.
We're pretty adaptable.
Like there's a lot of land.
Okay.
So we move.
We have historically in venice,
the sea level rises in venice.
Every year people are going to move.
I mean like,
that's just,
that's the way It works.
And there's this weird idea and it's
true in economics.
It's true with global warming that where
you were born is where you must die,
right?
And that you can never move.
And it's like,
well,
this is the most mobile society in human
history.
When you get on a plane and be on the
other coast in six hours,
it's easier to move than ever before.
So if,
if we,
if you really think that the climate is
that bad,
first of all,
I'd like to ask barbara streisand if
she's that deeply concerned about global
warming,
why she doesn't sell the coastline to
state,
but it's like,
am I going to lose a lot of sleep,
have a bunch of hollywood stars lose,
you know,
five feet off their coastline because we
dIdn't kill the industry of the United
States and lose $4,000,000,000,000
a year.
Like,
no.
And I'm not really sure that that would
have worked that way one way or another.
It has been absolutely proven that human
beings are having an effect on the
carbon dioxide levels.
Of course.
Right?
Yeah.
And there's a greenhouse gas effect.
Sure.
One hundred percent.
So the modeling's been so wrong that
like I want it,
there's no level of certitude and then
there's no level of solution that I know
for sure is going to do this.
So you're talking about human being
suffering in the now for the later and
let's be real about this.
Like yes,
there are a lot of emissions from the
United States,
but the leading admItter is on the
planet right now.
We're trying to nydia and they're not
going to stop this shit anytime soon
like that.
That's not gonna happen.
Well,
there's also this thing that happens
where if you even discuss it,
you become like a hitler or nazi.
You become a climate change denier and
once you get locked into one of those
labels,
you know you,
you're a piece of shit.
Well this is.
Yeah.
Nobody wants to be locked into those
labels so that they don't really want to
have the discussion or the debate.
And that's one of the things that I felt
like bill nye was not
prepared for because I felt like he's so
lazy with this conversation because so
many people just appease him and agree
with it.
Yeah.
I think that's when tucker carlson was
challenging him on it.
He didn't have any data to support this
argument.
He just wanted to sort of like play word
games and,
and have this.
We say,
well,
you know,
you guys on cnn,
there was one time when they had some
guy on who was saying exactly what we
were saying,
that the models they have not been
proven to be accurate.
And that al gore's movie predicted that
we'd be underwater in 2014.
Mike,
didn't it?
Yeah.
Mean his predictions and emily are not
correct.
They're not correct at all.
And he's made some insane amount of
money.
He's going to seek out this week.
Isn't he like the first billion dollar
green guy,
like he's made a shitload of money off
of giving these speeches and catholic
trade.
ANd the whole thing is very strange
because it becomes this untouchable
subject like what We're talking about
before with transgender people or with
many other subjects become.
You can't discuss them.
They're not even open to debate or
scrutiny.
They become locked down.
And when tucker carlson was pressing
bill now like what is,
what are the numbers?
Like what is happening?
Tell me how much of an effect are we
having.
And bill nye had nothing on it and it
just became stammered.
And started getting angry.
It was like,
wow,
this is weird.
This is weird to see.
I mean,
if this is the cause of your life,
you know,
a little bit more about it than everyone
who disagrees is a denier.
And I Think the way tucker handler,
that was brilliant.
I thought it was tucker's best moment I
think on a show.
Yeah,
I think so too.
Because he was saying essentially he was
like,
I'm not denying it.
I'm not saying it's.
I just want you to tell me how much of
an effect tell me exactly.
And he had nothing.
It's like,
so maybe bill nye is the wrong guy.
Tend to have there,
but I shouldn't be selling himself like
you can't have me come on a fucking show
and talk about global warming because I
don't know anything about it.
Or at the very least,
bill nye should say,
listen,
the intergovernmental panel on climate
change did this study,
right?
You can look up the numbers there.
I dOn't have them off the top of my head
or the numbers of the fucking numbers.
You're going to be on one of those shows
seven minutes,
so everybody in the media is lazy.
Nobody.
Nobody actually does tHeir prep for a
debate or for tv appearances like
because the truth is you think you're
going to be on for five having done a
thousand tv heads at this point.
Most people think,
okay,
I'm beyond for five minutes.
I can get through five minutes.
Right?
Like it would be that bad if I'm on for
10 minutes,
how bad can it be?
And the answer is you can get parents
done nationally in five minutes.
If the person knows what they're doing.
Well you've done that many people.
One of the things that I think is do you
talk fast always is like,
you're Born this way.
My family,
everyone in my family talks to the
family.
Just talks about it because I was
wondering if this was a strategy to
develop to be really good at those
shows.
No,
no,
it's,
it's been fortunate that it fits that
way,
but yeah,
even even my kids talk this way.
Even of the three year old.
This was some people that are just
really good at blah blah,
blah blah and you,
you,
you get them in the podcast and you have
to like peter shifts.
A great example though,
after like 20 minutes,
I'm like,
you want a drink?
Let's have some whiskey.
We had a couple of glasses of clInk
cheers.
and we settled down and then he settled
into like a normal way of talking,
but he's just so used to like force
feeding you facts and opinions and ah,
it's just,
it's such an ineffective way to
communicate with those three heads and
the one person who is the host throw the
Megan Kelly throw in a question and then
this person is talking over that person
and it's such an ineffective way to
communicate.
It's one of the things that I do like
about long form podcast,
like this one or like mine,
I,
I just,
I liked the ability to actually expand
on a point on tv.
It's like,
okay,
you have 30 seconds of a point.
Excellent.
We can make that work for us.
It's the only place left that you can do
this unless you're making youtube videos
and you know,
Jordan Peterson is obviously finding out
that that's a problem.
Yeah.
But unless you're doing something along
those lines where no one's there but you
and you get to expand and express
yourself.
There's no other form of conversation
like podcast where you're not getting
interrupted by a commercial.
You're just talking and you know as well
as I know that conversation sort of
evolve and move and they,
you know,
when I get to know you better,
I see how you're thinking better and I
kind of have more questions to ask and
you expand more and you get to know a
person for real and that's just those,
those television shows are so there.
It's so divisive and that way it's hard
for me to watch cable television because
of that.
I don't feel like I'm getting tons of
information that way.
Well,
cnn had nine fucking people on the other
day and it's crazy.
The candle on cnn.
It's a.
It's hollywood squares now.
Yeah.
Anderson cooper standing,
sitting there in the middle and there's
people and the people that had just made
a diagonal cool and they're interrupting
each other and said,
excuse me while I talk.
You might.
You might not interrupting me for a
moment.
Like their grand standing and trying to
have this point they think is going to
be a zinger because they wrote it last
night and it's just like,
oh,
the best you can hope for is that you
have 30 seconds where you say something
that goes viral.
That's basically.
That's,
that's the extent of it.
Yeah.
well you've done a lot of those.
I won't get good at it.
I'm good.
you're good at it.
But it's like we were talking about
before that a lot of the people that
have debated you that are real,
they're really fuckIng lazy.
Like,
like they have this suppose had passion
for something,
but when it comes to preparing for this
sort of interaction,
they're not really doing that for sure.
And I think that part of that is there.
There are people who are experts on
particular topics who could,
I'm sure know more about their specialty
than I do on a lot of topics to discuss
climate change with the person who was
like an expert on climate change.
I would not know as much as that person.
Sure.
But you know,
there are a lot of people who think
they're generalists and have never read
a book,
you know,
lIke I know one fact about one thing and
it's that you're a denier and if I know
too then I beat you.
So that's what.
That's.
So the climate denier thing seems to me
one of the laziest things about the
left,
and this is not saying that there's not
some sort of a real issue with human
waste because I think there is,
I think it's a,
there's a giant issue with plastic in
the ocean.
There's a giant issue with pollutants in
our water system and our air and there's
a lot of issues with the side effects of
being a person in the industrialized
civilization.
There's,
we burn things,
we create poisons and we've got to
figure out a way to be sustainable.
I don't think there's any denying that
by anybody.
I think it's also worth noting the
market makes these things better in many
cases.
I mean the fact is that if you look at
the areas where,
for example,
everyone is down on carbon based fuels,
okay,
fair enough.
But if you go to places that don't have
carbon based fuels,
they're burning animal dung and would
there is nothing worse for particulate
than,
than animal dung and woods.
So as we get,
and If we,
if we did even better than than this,
we would get to nuclear power,
right?
Which unfortunately,
a lot of people have been because of
unbased fears,
like most of france's electricity is
provided by nuclear power.
and that's about as clean as it gets.
So,
you know,
I,
I do think so.
It goes dark well till it goes
fukushima.
Hey,
even even in worst case scenario at
fukushima,
I mean,
if you're talking about the,
if you're talking about global warming
and environmental damage,
the amount of environmental damage
supposedly done by carbon emissions is a
lot larger than fukushima.
Right?
But the local damage.
Oh yeah,
that's devastating.
That's a disturbing thing that they
don't have a way to stop that,
that like they've figured out a way to
like put a wall of ice around the
containment area and that didn't work.
It seems so fucking science fictiony and
they really don't know what to do.
And
uh,
yeah,
I don't know enough about nuclear
containment to take off on that one,
but let's just say that one disaster in
basically there've been three major
disaster,
right?
Chernobyl,
three mile island and fukushima,
the only one that's happened,
the two of those three have happened in
the first world,
right?
Fukushima and three mile island,
three mile island basically ended up
having no longterm impacts of cliquish.
Shame is really the only major disaster
in 40 years of industrialized countries
using nuclear power.
Well,
apparently they had some weird meltdowns
here at rocket.
Don really weren't really discussed.
Yeah,
don't tell aBout it.
Well,
they're there,
you know,
it was all during the sixties,
fifties or the sixties when they're
involved in the rocket program.
But the rocket dyne stuff,
um,
my friend's dad is a scientist and he
was explaining to me the half life of
whatever was released in the atmosphere.
It's nothing to concerned,
but there's a bunch of rocket town was
like right there on the street,
there was a,
a bunch of articles that were written
about it,
like worrying about people that have
higher cancer rates in this area.
And you know,
but this also like,
I think there's a website called the
sins of rocketdyne.
Really see if you could find that.
I think there's a website dedicated to
that that people.
But there's a lot of cancer just living
in cities,
man.
Like they say that one of the worst
environments for a human being is living
in a place that has a lot of brake dust.
Like if you're living in manhattan and
you get your window open,
you just inhaling particulates from
people there.
it is the sins of rocketdyne.
But the thing is like,
I mean how much more cancer are these
people?
This is from
sometimes the statistics on cancer or
hard to to correlate because you'll have
groupings that are sort of weird.
And that's just because random
statistical grouping cabins.
So how much of it is due to x factor or
why factor.
If we knew that then presumably the
cancer rates will be going down a lot,
but they haven't really in most cases.
So it's pretty rare.
You have like a lung cancer situation
where smoking obviously causes lung
cancer.
Most cancers like breast cancer,
we have no idea why it happens.
It's also the value itself.
Again,
anything that happens in the valley,
like when you drive from thousand oaks
over the hill and you look down at the
value like jesus,
that can't be good.
Yeah,
I hear you.
I've been flying into the valley my
entire life and every time you fly into
the brown gunk that is,
that is the valley atmosphere.
You think that's not great mean.
That is one area where obviously we have
gotten better.
I mean the smog alerts have gone down
tremendously in the last 30 years.
Yeah,
it's gotten a lot better.
It's gotten a lot better.
And.
But that's also one of the things that
Donald Trump is a relaxed.
Some of the,
uh,
the standards,
the standard wasn't.
I don't know if he really didn't.
It wasn't an emission standards.
He changed the car emission standards.
Maybe a,
it's again,
I wonder how much of the car emission
standards,
like there's a,
there's actually a pretty thriving
debate in the libertarian community,
particularly about what the standards
are,
what drove greater fuel efficiency or
whether it was the price of gas that
drove greater fuel efficiency.
It has.
The price of gas has,
has risen and fallen.
You see people change their buying
habits,
right?
In the nineties,
everybody but an suv and then the prices
went up and everybody would bought a
prius.
Well the prius thing is interesting too,
particularly like the tesla thing
because then you look at the
environmental disasters of creating
these batteries.
Yes.
And you're like,
whoa,
this is not totally green.
Yeah.
Like there's some weird gray area to it.
It's pretty complex.
And,
and I think that the one thing we know
is that there are millions of people all
over the world for all of human history
who have been living in absolute penury
and misery and we now support 7 billion
people on the planet and the rate of
global poverty has dropped by 50 percent
in the last 30 years.
A lot of that is technological change,
a lot of that is fossil fuel use and so
before we,
you know,
we always have to ban,
these are two things that are worth
thinking about balancing like,
and this is what's again a little
frustrating is that sometimes you see
people on the environmental left who
will say,
well this has to be done,
or it's the end of the world.
It's like,
well how about those people in
developing countries?
How many of those people you're going to
say have to live in poverty in order for
this to happen?
And then on the right you'll see people
say,
well no environmental regulations at
all,
just let it all hang out and you know,
sometimes the market hash it out and
sometimes the market doesn't hash it
out.
And so,
you know,
I think a little caution is warranted.
I think that's a very reasonable point
of view and that's one of the things
that I really like about your
commentary.
I know you're a right leaning guy,
but you were very reasonable.
You,
you make argumentS that are sound and
easy to trace.
That makes sense.
I think I appreciate it.
I think we need more of that,
you know,
and I think it's rare that you find that
in a 33 year old guy that's some strange
sort of conservative character that
travels around a clown sap.
So the berkeley thing is going to
happen.
when is it going to happen?
September 14th is the date it's supposed
to happen.
So good luck with all that and you know,
if they cancel it,
we'll still go.
You got go on a bulletproof popemobile
yeah.
That,
hey,
he wears funny hat and said,
oh,
I said
yours is a little low profile though.
Yeah,
we keep,
we keep it on the dl around here.
What do you,
uh,
when you,
when you do show up at these places and
you see the antifa people and they're
screaming and yelling and cheering and
that's got to be a surreal thing and
it's just you and your thoughts and your
opinion.
I mean,
you're not selling babies.
You're not there.
Slaughter and dogs and this weekend
festival.
Yeah,
exactly.
Exactly.
It's weird.
I think that,
uh,
you know,
I'm not,
I'm not arrogant enough to think that a
lot of those people know who I am.
I think that what happens is that
there's sort of a call that goes out
from a select few saying this kkk
members coming to campus,
go stop him.
That's what happened at cal state la.
Like when I spoke there,
there were actually a couple of
professors were telling their students
that I was a closeted member of the kkk
anymore.
Show up wearing a yarmulke.
I'm their favorite person.
I'm like a charter member.
It's,
my thing was I was literally in 26.
It was hilarious that year I was 2016
was a wild year,
so I was.
So David Duke accused me of being a far
leftist black lives matter accused me of
being a member of the kkk and I was the
number one recipient to the antisemitism
from the,
according to the anti defamation league.
I was the number one recipient of
twitter,
antisemitism in the United States for
journalists last year.
So I do have a little trophy in my
house.
It's the most hated jews in America,
which is a hell of a title that green
frog.
It is.
It's a green frog and then a little
model of a gas chamber.
It's perfect.
Number one,
I have by,
by a huge margin,
by the way,
it was like 40 percent of all
antisemitic tweets on the internet
directly to journalists in 2016 were
directed at me personally party.
HOly shit.
It was a good year.
A good year.
You know,
some years are more productive than
others.
What did that feel like?
Want me to felt like my twitter feed was
just a,
a dumpster fire.
Anytime I recruited anybody I get
somebody,
I get people emailing me,
please don't retweet me because as soon
as I recruit someone,
they just be hit by waves of these
people died off.
Yes.
And since the election it's really gone
down a fair bit,
but you know,
uh,
there,
there were some pretty serious death
threats.
Like I got people calling my cell phone.
I had to up my security.
I had,
I already had a shotgun,
but it was,
uh,
well what,
what started it off?
probably me quitting breitbart.
Uh,
so,
so when I was,
uh,
you know,
I was not,
I was not a trump supporter.
I didn't vote for either candidate in
this year's election or last year's
launch support,
uh,
in the,
in the primaries,
cruz cruz.
Um,
I support him in his position.
He was the closest to me politically.
um,
so,
you know,
I was not pro trump during the
primaries.
He didn't earn my vote during the
general election.
I thought like,
there's two ways to look at your vote
and this is what I always said to
people.
I said,
vote for who you want to,
but for me there's two ways to look at
your vote.
It's a coupon,
expIres November 9th,
right?
And so either use it or lose it or it's
just,
it says something about what you are
willing to accept and it's possible that
there can be election where both
candidates suck and you just don't want
either of them.
So what did you do during the election?
I voted down ticket.
I skipped the top of the ticket.
First time I've ever done that.
so I didn't think either of these people
was qualified to be president of the
United States.
Once tRump was elected,
then it was like,
okay,
if he does good stuff,
I'll praise him.
And If he does bad stuff I'll,
I'll hit him as I would any other
presidents and uh,
so I've been sort of calling balls and
strikes with him and some of the stuff
like gorsuch I love and some of the
stuff like makeup brudzinski's bloody
face.
I'm not so hot.
I'm so uh,
that's uh,
but yeah,
so the,
uh,
I think what,
what led off was,
it was a combination of three things.
One,
I'm jewish too,
and obviously so a two,
I was working at breitbart and then I
quit in the middle of the election cycle
after there was that whole,
you remember the Michelle Fields
incident where a cory lewandowski
grabbed the reporter from breitbart or
the arm hurt after bruiser.
And then the actually bruiser bruiser.
I mean he,
like,
she took pictures,
she report it to the cops.
It was,
you know,
unless you,
unless you believe she bruised herself,
didn't look much like a.
I mean when I watched the videos it
looked like he just kinda grabbed her
arm and he looked like he did.
Her body didn't like move,
like she was being injured.
Yeah,
I mean she,
lets put it this way,
she,
that was her account.
That was also the accounts have been
terrorist at the Washington post was
that she was grabbed hard enough to
bruise and then she had bruises.
So you know whAt,
let me as a fight commentator,
there's a lot of things that I see live
that look a lot worse than when you
watch them on video.
You know,
when people get knocked out like that
wasn't much of a punch.
I'm like,
oh,
you have to be there.
The example that comes to mind is the,
the ali listen punch,
right?
and find number two.
Right?
So that's probably,
that's probably,
It's probably a bad example.
But bottom line is that the,
that she.
There were three,
there were a bunch of different excuses
that breitbart went through on that.
One.
One was that she was never grabbed it
all and the second was that it was a
secret service guy.
And then the third was that,
that from thought she was a security
threat and quarterly he had to protect
trump from this 90 pounds soaking wet
girl.
Uh,
and so once breitbart did that,
then the real question for me,
it was not,
you know,
what a horrible thing had happened to
her.
It was much more about as a journalistic
entity,
do you stand by your reporters or do you
stand by the candidate who you support?
And once breitbart made clear to me that
it,
like I already knew they supported
trump.
That wasn't any great shock,
but I was kind of their token non trump
guy.
And once it became clear that they were
willing to sort of sacrifice
journalistic credibility on the altar of
getting close to trump,
then I was out.
And then it's no longer a journalistic
outlets.
I quit,
uh,
and uh,
and that sort of started the ball
rolling as far as,
well,
I really didn't get an isometric
responses on twitter before that,
uh,
not too much.
Not too much.
So I won't say that breitbart directed
at amex.
I don't think they did,
but I think that there are a lot of
people who,
who follow breitbart and you know,
milo yiannopoulos and they're pissed at
me and I had seen me as like an ally and
now they saw me as an enemy and this
kind of thing.
So,
and then,
you know,
this is the war for them,
right?
Oh yeah.
I mean people enjoyed it.
Obviously.
That's a weird thing about the online
hate is how much people enjoy it.
It's anonymous.
You never get.
You never get tagged for it for now.
That's fine for us for now,
for now.
I mean I've said this to a bunch of
college students about,
you know,
the,
the outright.
First of all,
I think it's important to mention a lot
of people who say they're all right
aren't actually outright just because
you like a meme doesn't make you
outright,
but like there's a group of people who
actually like Richard Spencer and jared
taylor and the race based identity
politics of white supremacy.
uh,
and those people are actually outright,
when the outright is a,
is coming after you,
then it's not a lot of fun,
but there,
there are a lot of,
there are a lot of young students who
will retweet things from like things
that are obviously nasty and are going
to hurt them in their future career,
right?
Where the,
they'll,
they'll be joking around on facebook and
using the n word and I'll say to them
like,
guys,
you may think it's funny and 10 years
from now your employer is going to find
that and you're going to be toast in.
There are a lot of people who start to
fall into this idea that what you do
online is not a mess and it is not,
it is not going to remain anonymous.
Just a matter of time for a blows.
Yeah,
I mean crap.
Any anonymity in 10 years.
I agree.
I think that we're,
we're moving in that direction and this
is actually a thing that botheRs me in
general.
Like did you follow the entry to the
donald sterling saga here?
Yeah,
sure.
So it,
it really bothered me that everybody was
willing to take donald sterling's team
away from him because you said something
shitty to his girlfriend about magic
johnson when there is no evidence that
there's actual discrimination among
clients at the clippers.
And again,
if tHere were actual evidence of
discrimination,
then sure boycott his team and do what
the mba has to do.
But like I'm pretty certain that every
human beings has crappy things to their
intimate loved ones about groups of
people and other people.
If this now becomes the standard,
then I think that we're all toast.
Oh,
for sure.
In his defensive it was like very
reasonable.
He's like,
I was trying to get laid.
Like I was just.
I was just saying he thought he was
alone.
He thought he was with her and no one
was recording.
I mean she was trying to say that she
had recorded all of their conversations,
that it was a part of her,
her job.
He's like a senile old guy and he's
obviously not with vista viano because
she's a nobel prize winning physicist.
Like he bought her a condo and a bentley
and a ferrari and uses his interview.
His interview
with anderson cooper was one of the
classic interviews of all time I ever
saw.
Oh my goodness.
the moment where he says,
because there's a moment where he turns
to anderson.
Cooper says,
henderson,
have you ever fallen in love with a
woman,
an anderson cooper who is,
you know,
super gay.
Fuck yeah.
Single request.
He starts laughing.
He goes,
no,
I've never had that experience.
Well,
henderson,
when you do fall in love with a woman
and he just,
he's so unaware.
It's like,
I'm sorry,
like I can't consider this guy.
Like he's a kkk,
threatening figure.
Like the guy can't even find the toilet
in the mornings.
He's stumBling over his autumn.
And like
I did,
I did about.
I'm defending him where I was like,
because if you look at what he actually
said,
everyone's like,
he's a racist,
is a terrible person.
He said,
do me a favor.
He goes,
I don't.
don't take pictures of black eyes.
He goes,
in the next sentence,
he said,
I don't care if you fuck them,
just don't take pictures of them.
I go,
in my world,
that's pretty reasonable.
Like you gotta grow your buying or a
ferrari.
All always say,
just don't take any pictures so you
could fuck them.
She should just leave well enough alone.
You're getting a ferrari out of the
deal.
No,
I think that was.
That whole thing was just like it was.
It was our capacity to get ourselves
outrage so we could show everybody how
outraged we work while the president of
the nba,
whatever the fuck
his name is,
what is adam starts now,
adam silver,
the guy that got on tv and was talking
about it like it was the most horrific
thing that's ever been said by being jim
crow at at clipper,
at the staples center.
He shoUld have gotten on tv and said,
look,
this is obviously.
We know what this was.
This is a gold digger and an old man to
Stories all the time.
He said some stupid shit.
Old people say,
stupid shit.
Old guy.
Here's the thing.
Don't take his advice.
When it comes to race,
and he probably should have said,
look,
but on the bright side he told her she
can go fuck black guys,
so hey,
everybody's happy.
What would have been better?
Presser the ratings with self righteous
and bullshit and let me know a lot of
that again is I think that if you look
at the nba statistics and who watches
the nba,
the outsides number of people who
watched the nba are black and they spend
an outsized amount of time watching it
and so you know,
donald sterling pissed off a lot of
black folks with that,
understandably until a lot of people
were like ending the nba was like,
we're not going to lose our fan base
over there.
It was a money decision.
In other words,
I don't think it was a values decision
as much as money.
While I agree with you 100 percent,
but I don't think they had to make that
decision that way.
I think it could have been in him.
They could have been.
It could have divested him and put him
like put his kids or his wife in charge
of the team.
Like this idea that you're gonna force
him to sell his team,
it's going to disband the clippers
because there was a tape of an old man
saying stupid ass things to a gold
digger is.
It's pretty much so anyway.
And he wound up making more money from
that team that he ever would have.
So much more valuable.
jillion dollars.
Yeah.
It became much more valuable.
Is the whole thing is bizaRre.
Yeah,
that's it,
dude.
We just said three hours.
Well,
that's crazy.
I appreciate it.
Flew by as great.
Well listen,
people have been asking for a long time
for you to come on,
so I'm glad we finally got together and
let me do it.
Thanks for having me.
My pleasure.
Let's do it again.
Sounds good.
Thank you.
Thanks ben.
See you guys.
See you next week.
Or girls to non binary folks to
everybody all inclusive by.