Five,
four,
three,
two,
one.
Dr.
Rhonda,
Patrick.
Hello.
Welcome back.
You've got a big fat book of notes over
there.
It's like it's something I use like
before I'm giving a talk or something
like that where I like to something
about writing,
handwriting things like helps me
remember.
Oh yeah,
this,
they've shown that I do that before
shows.
If you looked at my notebook and you
think if you ever thought that I like
actually wrote in my notebook,
you'd think I'm a crazy person because
I'm reading the same thing over and over
again.
Like all work.
No play makes jack a dull boy.
I just like before a set,
what I do is I just write out the key
things that I wanted to work on and I'll
write them out over and over again.
So like I'll have 100 page notebook and
it's like 100 pages of like half of it's
the same stuff over and over again.
I'm Kinda the same way.
Like I,
I'll write out things like that are in
more detail and then like you said,
all like righteous,
just like a cue,
like it's different when you're giving a
talk,
at least like in academia,
like a powerpoint talk you have to slide
and this slide cues like a couple of
minutes of talk.
So you've got like,
it helps you remember what you're going
to talk about.
Yeah,
that would help for comedy.
I bet.
Probably a good idea.
I should have a slide show,
you know,
like that would actually be a really
good idea for like particular points
where you could show that you weren't
lying.
Like look this is a real thing.
You know,
you have like a reference there because
there's a couple of things that I'm
talking about in my new set where I have
to,
I have to reassure people that I'm not
making this up because it's so
ridiculous.
You know?
And I'm like one of them was this woman
who proposed as a high school student.
She was a 25 year old police officers,
super attractive,
and she poses a high school student and
convinced a young boy to sell her
marijuana and then arrested him.
So it was just an experiment?
No,
it was a sting operation.
Wow.
And he was a regular kid.
He was an honor roll kid.
Oh my God.
Now he's a felon.
That is crazy.
Yeah,
there it is.
Teen falls in love with undercover cop
and marijuana sting gets arrested.
Yeah.
So this is one of them.
I would love to be able to put that up
and go see because you could.
I guess you could just make stuff up if
you wanted to know what comedians do.
They make stuff.
I mean you can a lot,
but if you made something up like,
Hey,
there was a story in the news and just
made it up.
That sounds crazy.
I guess it.
Who cares if it's funny.
You know,
people just come to laugh,
but yeah,
I guess you're right.
People like comedians usually make up
personal stories.
Sometimes they say it's true and I'm
like,
it's so outrageous is really true.
Like,
I don't know because it's just so funny,
you know,
like some of the stories that,
that some of these comedians tell when
I'm just like,
how can this be true?
They said it was true,
but it's like,
are they my friend part of comedy?
Can you do that?
You definitely tell my friend Dom irrera
has a really funny joke about that.
He goes,
he goes,
he's a true
story.
He goes,
hey,
how about you just make something up
that's funny.
You know,
like it doesn't have to be true buddy
rich.
I can't say it's true.
So it's Kinda like messing with you
because the whole time they're doing,
you're likely true because that's
fucking hilarious.
Sometimes it's true.
Sometimes it's not.
I guess it depends.
Depends on the person.
I assume everything in your notebook.
It's true.
I hope so.
The other thing that helps me like said
this,
this helps,
you know,
writing it down helps me,
but also there's the running running
like helps.
So actually this was very interesting
because the study just came out not long
ago showing that if you.
So if you run the four,
you're going to learn something and you
want to like,
let's say you want to like,
you know,
do something short term recall,
so you're gonna go up on stage and say
something,
you know,
say a skid or whatever,
and um,
if you run right before that,
it improves the short term memory.
So your short term recall if you run
right before,
whatever it is,
you're quickly read over something and
then you want to remember it.
But if you are learning something and
then you run after you learn it and then
like the next day you want to remember
it.
So it's more of a longer term memory.
It improves that.
So it's like whether or not you're
running before,
after you learn it affects the short
term versus long term memory.
Wow.
How did they work that out?
That's bizarre.
Well,
it,
it wasn't like they were testing for
that.
They just found it out through because
they were just,
you know,
doing running before,
after they're probably looking at just
to see how it affects short and longterm
memory recall.
And they were surprised to find out this
was a study that was done.
Um,
I can't remember where it was done.
I know I tweeted about it not long ago
because it was like within this last
month that it came out.
So,
you know,
it's like if you want to,
if you want to.
So like while I'm,
you know,
learning new material throughout the
day,
then I go for a run in the evening and
then the next day I'll be able to recall
it better.
Theoretically now I'm subject to the
placebo effects.
I know about this.
I'm like,
oh,
that's a problem.
I don't run normally,
but I did a five k on Monday,
like I don't run at all.
But a buddy of mine had a five k race in
Vegas.
So I flew in for him and my friend
Cameron Hanes and um,
I ran it and it was surprisingly hard.
Just like all the working out I do.
So only three miles.
It's like three point one or someone
like her heart is a fucking hard.
It's not easy.
Yeah.
No.
So do you do any like aerobic between
kickboxing,
Jujitsu and I do elliptical machine and
I do a lot of yoga but doing,
I'm trying to do yoga three times a
week.
I'm not always successful at getting
there.
I got there last week,
three times a week.
But um,
I don't run so I figured.
But all that stuff I do,
I'm like,
I'll have,
I'll be fine.
Nope,
not really.
So you didn't train at all,
you just kind of like on the fly just
did this five k and I saw,
I saw you post something about this and
I'm isn't,
doesn't cameron?
Isn't he like some kind of like crazy
runner?
He's preparing right now for the
[inaudible] which
is 235 or 234 miles.
Something crazy like that.
And Jamie's a runner.
So when Jamie shakes his head like that,
you know,
it's really gross.
Yeah.
That's incredible.
Yeah,
he's a nut.
He did two.
Oh five last year he did the big foot
200,
which is 205 miles.
Plus it has something insane like 55,000
feet of elevation change over the course
of the entire race because you're
constantly going up and down and up and
down and at some points in the race it's
so steep and the terrain,
it's an outdoor race over Mount Saint
Helens.
So sometimes the terrain is so brutal
that the top speed is two miles an hour
or
he's going to be like one of those like
amazing super agers like,
like,
like that.
Just very mentally sharp when he's in,
when he's older.
Either that or he's not going to be,
that's been shot like it's been shown.
Like if you.
Part of being a super ager,
like being a super ager means your old
but your,
you're physically fit,
you're mentally sharp and mentally
sharp.
Is,
is really the key thing,
you know,
cause we start losing brain mass at like
the age of 20 and by the time if you can
actually make it to 100 years old,
you lose like 20 percent of your brain
mass.
So they found that one of the keys to
maintaining your brain mass is pushing
past that comfortable zone physically.
So like,
you know,
exercise wise and also mentally just,
obviously like,
like learning new things and challenging
yourself so you know,
so when you're working out you don't do
this kind of like,
you know,
half ass thing,
you have to push yourself,
you have to really push yourself and
that seems to be key for becoming a
super ager.
That's crazy than it works with your
brain.
Why exercise?
I mean exercise has profound effects on
your brain.
I mean specifically if you're looking
at,
you know,
a robotic aerobic exercise,
a row,
it's hard aerobic exercise as you said,
doing a five k running three miles.
I mean you do,
you do a lot of training and yet that
was still hard for you,
you know,
because during that type of aerobic
exercise is difficult.
Um,
studies have shown that even just like
20 to 30 minutes of aerobic exercise
can,
in healthy young men increase serum
bdnf.
So which is brain drive neurotrophic
factor.
This is a growth factor that is involved
in growing new brain cells and in
allowing the existing brain cells to
survive.
So,
you know,
talking about combating brain atrophy,
you're talking about commenting that the
fact that your brain is atrophying,
starting at the age of 20,
that's the way to do it.
Your brain starts to atrophy at 20.
At 20 you start to lose brain mass.
Yeah,
I know.
It's really frightening.
20,
you start at the peak at 20.
It was so stupid at 20.
I'm so much smarter than I was when I
was 20.
No,
I agree.
I mean it's not necessarily like brain
mass and intelligence.
I mean,
I don't know if you know that there's
definitely a correlate but,
but like when you start losing mass in
your hippocampus,
I mean that's memory learning,
you know,
that part of the brain.
Um,
but there's just so many studies showing
that exercise roebuck exercise and also,
you know,
it doesn't have to be Arabic.
You can do resistance training.
That sort of stuff also affects the
brain as well.
But for me,
like I've been a runner since high
school and track I guess long a long
time and for me,
you know,
I've done like a few races,
I've done a marathon and I don't feel
like marathons are my thing.
Like I felt like that was just really
rough,
you know,
like it was.
I mean I'll run three miles and I will
feel challenged.
Like if I push myself I can do that and
that I feel like doing that a couple
times,
three times a week is plenty for me.
But when I run,
you know,
for me it's my,
I entered this like state of,
of like daydreaming,
sort of.
I get creative,
you know,
when I'm going on a,
like a three mile run,
I'm just,
I start thinking about things,
um,
if I have an important decision to make
or something that's causing me some,
some sort of anxiety,
I go for a run.
And I feel like I can address that issue
better.
And what's interesting is that there
have been studies that have shown that
going for a run,
um,
and specifically aerobic exercise,
it activates the part of your brain and
Bolt and executive function,
which helps you make decisions.
You know,
it's,
it's Kinda like that overarching part of
your brain that helps with all the
planning,
long term planning,
all that.
And so I always,
I do,
I feel like if I go for runs and it's
bothering me,
if I'm anxious and I always feel better
100 percent of the time,
like there's not a single time that I go
for a run and I'm like,
damn,
I feel worse.
Why did I do that?
You know,
it's like I feel,
I feel like crap while I'm doing it.
I'm like,
Oh,
this is.
Well,
I
human mind.
I mean this is all just theoretical in
my own theories.
I think the human mind is designed to
confront serious things like predators
and dangerous enemies.
And,
and we don't really get much of that in
this life.
So when a person is dealing with stress,
I think the mind is preparing for some
things that don't exist.
So even if you can work things out
logically,
there's still remains like this residual
effect of all these human reward systems
that are kind of in place when the time
we really did have to have all those
rules,
those reactions in place to deal with,
you know,
a dangerous invaders or you know,
horrible natural conditions,
you know,
whatever they would be that we hardly
ever experienced any more.
So like when I work out,
if I have anything that's bothering me
or troubling me,
I think I get like a distorted
perception of the danger of it or the
physical real.
Like it could be something real simple.
Like I have an issue at work that I have
to deal with.
Like maybe I have to make a decision or
maybe you know,
I'm stressed about something and I feel
this no matter how much I work it out
logically,
I still feel this physical,
like residual issue.
And that issue only seems to be resolved
for me because I don't run with hitting
the bag.
Like for me it's a punching bag,
which is really hard to do.
Like when you,
when you do rounds,
like kickboxing rounds on a bag,
have a timer and I could set it for
three to five minutes.
It'll,
it'll allow you to set it all the way
down to one and then it has like
intervals.
So it gives me like 30 seconds.
Every 30 seconds of Buzzer go off and it
has two lights.
One light is yellow and one light is
blue.
And so the yellow light,
I kind of a go at like 60,
70 percent.
And then the blue light I sprint.
So it's like sprint,
try to catch your breast print,
tried to catch your breath.
And I do that for seven to eight rounds.
And when I do that I don't give a fuck
about anything after it's over.
I'm like,
who cares?
Like it's amazing what it does because
like my mind still has all the same
data.
I still understand all,
whatever it is,
like work related nonsense.
I still understand all the issues about
it and they're all,
there's no new information,
but now the information is coming into
my brain and it's going,
oh,
this isn't a foreign invader.
These aren't vikings that are coming
over and have a fucking boat.
That dragon's head at the front of it,
swinging swords.
I.
This is just some nonsense,
whatever it is,
you know,
agent issue or manager issue or tax
issue or whatever the fuck it is.
That seems so physically daunting before
the exercise,
but then afterwards when that aspect of
the problem is alleviated,
that stress,
it's almost like my,
our bodies are just like confused as to
what these problems actually are.
I'm like,
I love,
I love your,
your interpretation because it's exactly
the way that I would like to talk about
why we need this type of stress.
I actually just like you said,
I actually think that from an
evolutionary evolutionary perspective
that we were meant to be stressed.
We were meant.
We were meant to be out side either
hunting,
tilling the land for food,
you know,
to prepare food.
I'm bombarded by UVB radiation,
which is stressful.
We were designed to have stress and what
I mean by designed was we have genetic
switches which are supposed to be turned
on.
These genetic switches that are
activated by stress are supposed to be
turned on and just like you said,
we're in a building novel time now where
we don't have to go outside,
we don't have to till the land,
we don't have to hunt for our food,
we can sit,
we can sit on the couch on her butt all
day and order delivery or go to the
grocery store and we don't have to eat
foods with polyphenols.
Flavonoids are things that are also
slightly stressful,
you know,
so this is kind of that concept before
me says,
but I like the way you explained it
because I really agree with you think
that humans were meant to be stressed
exercise as a form of that stress.
And there's different,
various different types of,
of that stress.
Um,
and I,
and I think that we were supposed to
switch on those,
those genetic switches,
those genes that are helping us deal
with stress.
So like,
you know,
like you said you have a problem and I'm
the same way with my Ronald,
have some something that's bothering me.
I have to deal with whatever it is.
I mean in my mind I blow it up and may
not even be that big of a deal,
but I go for a run with no new
information with nothing new,
you know,
like I feel better.
And I think that's partly because I'm
switching on all these,
you know,
stress response pathways that helped me
deal with the stress better.
These antiinflammatory pathways,
just all this really good,
you know,
these good genetic switches that are
being
just switched on.
So when it totally makes sense,
I think this new time that we live in,
I just don't necessarily understand that
the body understands where the stress is
coming from.
I think you know,
your body is a physical organism and
nature is an absolutely brutal thing and
it has been for us as well as for all
these other animals forever.
But now for us it's not really that
brutal anymore.
And so all these mechanisms are in place
to protect you.
And they don't get served and for me,
martial arts is always been like the
best one to deal with.
Oh,
we're weight lifting's good to like a
good kettlebell workout does it too.
But like the big ones for me are Jujitsu
and kickboxing because Jujitsu is
really,
really hard to do and it's also you are
solving problems.
So I think Jujitsu serves two purposes.
It's incredibly grueling as far as like
the sparring process of just rolling and
competing with each other.
Even in a friendly role.
Like with a guy that I really like and
we're laughing and we slap hands every
time someone gets tapped out or
whatever.
It's so difficult.
Like your,
your,
your body's taxed so hard and your mind
is taxed because you're dealing with
countering.
You're dealing with setting up moves,
you're dealing with,
you're thinking several steps ahead and
then you're.
You're adjusting those thoughts based on
whatever this person that you're
sparring with is doing too.
So people get really,
really addicted to Jujitsu for all the
right reasons.
And one of the things that I've found as
that Jujitsu people like for the most
part,
are way more mellow than most people
would expect.
Like way more chill about stuff like way
less likely to respond to something in a
DM or an imbalanced way because they
whatever your body,
whatever these requirements are that
we're addressing,
your body has all that in Jujitsu,
but without the real real violence,
you know what I mean?
Like the ones trying to kill you,
they're just trying to do this thing to
you and you're trying to do that thing
to them and those things mimic actual
combat,
actual real life and death struggle in a
friendly.
And it also has this camaraderie built
into it too because you've kind of
understand that you're going through
this incredibly intense thing together
and you also understand that it takes a
unique person to go through that and get
past all these psychological hurdles,
all these physiological hurdles,
and then you also are aware that this
person understands like really clearly
the kinship that you all share in having
this experience together.
That's really,
that's really neat.
I kind of relate.
I mean,
not to the same degree,
like what you're,
what you're describing is on a whole
other level.
But um,
I experienced something similar when
I'm,
when I'm out surfing,
um,
you know,
it's,
I'm,
I'm getting the physical exercise,
but I'm also like a tackling these fears
of these big waves and getting pulled
under and drowning and getting tangled
with my court,
you know,
there's like a million and every time I
do I always have that fear paddling out
there.
But I get out there,
there's a group of surfers and we're all
sitting out there and there is a sort of
friendship that we develop out there
because we all love surfing and we've
all like,
we know,
we know.
It's like,
oh,
here comes the wave.
We're helping each other.
Like,
look,
there's one on the outside paddle out,
you know.
So it's Kinda like I'm completely like a
different level from what you're
describing with Jujitsu,
but still I kind of can relate a little
bit,
you know,
read.
I don't know if it is a different level
and a lot of Jujitsu people surf as
well.
I think there's like a similar
attraction to it,
but because also you're a monster
dodger,
like you're out there in the monster
soup.
Yeah,
it's,
um,
that's what that is.
It's crazy that I still haven't,
you know,
you'd think that after doing it for so
many years that I would get over that
fear,
but.
So they're so powerful.
Yeah.
I mean,
how can you get over that fear?
I'm my friend,
Shane Dorian is a big wave surfer and
he's been on the podcast before and he's
a big time Paul Hunter too.
And we talk all the time about this and
you know,
um,
the way he describes it is just,
it's so attractive.
Like,
I wanna try it,
but there's not enough hours in the day
for me.
There's not,
I'm,
I get too addicted to things and it's
just.
And I have a fucking real fear of
sharks.
It's real.
Sharks are scary,
scary or so.
But they're real.
They're out.
Yeah.
Oh Jesus.
What is this?
Jamie?
Shane Dorian is big wave.
Oh my God.
My hands are sweating.
Watching.
He is out of his fucking mind.
Totally.
He's a legit maniac.
Wow.
Like that is what is how.
How high would you say that wave is,
Scott?
To be 50 feet,
right?
Say It's in Hawaii.
It's called jaws is the name of the
jobs.
Oh my God.
Look at the size of that is so insane.
It's so insane.
Like losing my mind is when I see these
guys big wave surfing like this,
my heart starts racing.
I'm so anxious.
Right?
God,
it's so insane.
That's more than 50 feet.
Right.
I would say at the very peak of it,
it does look like it's more than a 50
foot faith now when it comes down to
does it say there on the youtube thing,
what it comes down on you?
I mean,
it doesn't really like that if it that,
if that.
If you got smushed,
like if you fell and that came down on
you,
I mean you're,
you're probably fucked.
Right?
That's the fear.
Yeah.
I mean damn.
I mean the biggest way I've,
I've ever surfed is like overhead,
you know,
like over time and a half overhead,
so not even double overhead.
So.
And that was like,
I had a couple of,
um,
scary moments where I was just tumbling
during donuts and I couldn't find which
way was up or down,
you know,
it's like I've had one time I was
surfing out in this place.
I'm in San Diego called sunset cliffs
and it's a brief break and it's really
hard to get out there so you have to
like,
time you have to like jump out when the
after the wave breaks and then you
paddle out and there's all these kelp
beds.
And I was surfing there this one time
and this was back when I was really dumb
and didn't wear a leash because it was
like Alicia is,
you know,
I like to dance on my board and they get
in my way.
And so I didn't release.
But um,
I,
you know,
there was a big wave and I was writing
it and I wiped out and I like got caught
in the kelp.
Oh Shit.
And so it was like the sky,
you know,
you have this moment where you panic and
that's really bad,
like panicking when you're like in the
water,
cause panic takes like your energy.
And I panicked and I was because I
thought it was going to die.
I was going to suffocate kelp bed.
So I remember having nightmares,
I've had nightmares about it.
Like that stuck with me.
That was like,
that was one of those moments that,
you know,
sort of traumatizing in a way.
How long did it take to get out of the
Kelp?
I don't remember.
I don't remember because it was just,
I think the panic sort of just lost
track.
It seemed like forever to me.
Like I don't know how long it actually
took and of course I lost my board and I
like swimming and I got cut up on the
reef.
Yeah,
reefs are brutal.
Brutal.
Yeah.
I actually stick to a beach breaks now,
but I don't,
like you said,
I don't even get to surf that much
anymore because I just don't have.
So people that when they surf breaks
that are over those reefs.
Like you just can't wipe out.
If you wipe out,
you're going to go right into all that
Jag and shit.
Yeah.
It depends on where the reef is.
Like,
like I was riding the wave in kind of in
more so I was closer to where the wreath
was.
But yes you can.
It's,
it's dangerous.
They're beginners should not ever go out
on a reef.
And I've seen many beginners out there,
but it's,
yeah,
it's definitely more dangerous.
Feel the scratches and cuts.
Yeah.
Pretty,
pretty,
pretty brutal.
But any shark encounters?
No.
I'm the only sharks.
I've actually.
Actually,
I shouldn't say that's not,
that's not actually accurate.
I don't have any scary shark encounters.
Um,
I served for a long time in La Jolla and
there's a breeding ground,
therefore I'm leopard sharks,
which are not
to be confused with tiger sharks.
Tiger sharks are definitely scary.
Leopard sharks are the ones that have
the spots on them and they're really
harmless.
They're kinda like nurse sharks.
Yeah.
Oh,
don't eat.
They're not like,
I really do like sand sharks.
There's this around.
Yeah.
And they're really cool to look at.
But I've never had,
I've never actually known anyone that
serves in southern California that has,
you know,
with all the surfers that I've known
that has had an encounter in southern
California with a shark.
Do you know people that have encountered
them in the bay area?
You.
The Bay area is a big breeding ground
for great whites.
I would never surf there.
Really?
No.
I would never say,
oh,
I would never surf there.
Yeah.
The sharks
look say yeah,
the sharks.
But they're all.
It's all connected.
It's like,
don't go outside.
There's a bad neighborhood somewhere.
Will stick and move around.
I guess just in my head,
I was sort of like convinced myself that
they're not,
they're not coming to San Diego.
There's a video of a drone flying over
Malibu where some guy takes a drone and
he's flying over the Malibu surf and
he's like,
the drone is like maybe a few hundred
yards away from some surfers and you see
a big fucking great white just swimming
along,
just swimming along and show me this
video.
Drone shark footage.
So here's these people.
They're all on this board.
They came and were just southern
California,
new big deal,
and when the drone keeps going further
and further out,
you see this fucking whopper shark
that's not far away from these people
will find it here.
Jamie will find it.
There's one right there.
Where's this?
Oh,
nothing.
Just a shark right there.
Right there.
That's the fuck.
Dammit.
Joe.
Don't show me this.
You know,
you're a smart woman.
You understand monster soup.
I try not to think about the sharks.
Well,
it's a gold look.
There's two of them.
Interesting book that surfer and two
sharks.
No big deal guys.
That's pretty scary.
Yeah,
it's supposed to be scared.
Just I know.
I don't know.
Apparently Catalina,
that whole area outside of Catalina is a
crazy shark fishing mecca where I have a
friend of mine from Texas and he
traveled to Catalina Island and he said
it is the most savage stretch of water
in all of North America.
He said,
it's just infested with Maaco sharks,
and they go out there to catch me kosher
are delicious.
Mako sharks are really,
really good to eat too.
They taste like swordfish.
That tastes amazing.
Are they dangerous?
Like they'll fuck you know,
fight you,
but the thing about sharks,
now it's because people are so silly
because of the awareness of shark fin
soup,
you know,
because shark fin soup is the practice
of acquiring shark fins is really brutal
and not sustainable.
All it's
really horrific and a lot of Asian
fisheries engage in these unsustainable
practices where they'll scoop up
thousands and thousands of sharks cut
their fins off and then throw them right
back in the water so they waste most of
the shark in order to get the fins for
shark fish soup and so because they're
trying to raise awareness of this now,
people are getting really upset at
anyone who catches sharks even if they
catch sharks legally for food,
because sharks are not endangered and as
well as any in any more sense than tuna
is endangered because tuna are in vastly
diminished numbers than they were just a
few decades ago.
If you talked to anyone who's a
commercial fisherman or even a a sport
fisherman,
if these guys that run these charter
boats,
they'll tell you like to use to catch
way more tuna.
It used to be way more prevalent.
I think there was something that you
addressed in that Jiro Dreams of Sushi
movie as well,
is that the commercial fishing is just
brutalizing the tuna Martin,
but yet everybody is still eats tuna and
they don't think twice about it because
this campaign against shark fin soup is
made people like really upset at people
that catch sharks to eat.
Even people that eat meat,
it's like we're so simplistic in like
are protesting and like people just have
it in their head that I heard you're not
supposed to eat sharks anymore.
Like can you catch and sharks you
fucking asshole.
Like,
like that is the one thing that you want
to talk about like fish that don't do no
harm to human beings.
Like sharks aren't on that list.
You know,
in this,
this is scary God damn animal and if you
could eat that,
I say Kudos.
Kudos to you
because sharks are higher up on the food
chain.
Don't they have higher mercury levels?
That's a good question because I know
like swordfish,
like I would not eat swordfish.
Really?
Oh No,
no.
Yeah.
There is like,
oh,
I wish I could remember the amount.
It's something like 150 micrograms per
four ounces or something.
So compare that to a wild Atlantic
Salmon,
which has like four micrograms.
Whoa.
Yeah.
Swordfish.
So the ones that are really safe to eat
that I know of are the wild wildlands
salmon,
wild Alaskan,
sorry.
Analytic Wild Alaskan Salmon,
cod.
Um,
let's see.
White tuna is okay,
but the albacore tuna has a little bit
more mercury.
I think it's like,
you know,
twice as much or something.
But I'm old.
I'm a little thinking that shark would
be high on the mercury level.
That's interesting.
I'd like to find that out because I know
that people have had issues that eat a
tremendous amount of Sushi.
People that eat Sushi like every day.
I know they have had issues with mercury
in the past.
I actually had an arsenic issue with
sardines,
or bottom dwellers,
and I used to eat sardines all the time.
I have,
I love Sardi.
Yeah,
I love sardines too.
And if you eat canned sardines too much,
I
got some blood work done and the doctor
was like,
you have some significant amounts of
arsenic in your system.
I'm like,
am I being poisoned?
He's like,
no,
not,
not that.
He goes,
it's not like someone's trying to kill
you,
but it is like a dietary issue.
And then he asked me what I ate and I
said,
you know,
we went through all my food.
He's like,
nothing else.
I go,
he goes,
what about seafood?
I go,
oh yeah,
I eat seafood.
Oh yeah,
I eat a lot of sardines.
He was like,
that's it.
I didn't know.
Sardines,
uh,
accumulate arsenic.
Does that make sense?
So I backed off.
I didn't eat sardines at all for three
months.
Came back,
the issue was completely resolved.
Yeah.
You know what I'm besides sweat,
you sweat out a lot of these heavy
metals like mercury,
arsenic,
um,
garlic,
some of the Beta mercaptans and garlic.
They key late,
they bind and key late mercury and help
pull it and excrete it out of your body
through the urine.
So like when I,
whenever I make salmon or fish,
which I actually do eat a lot of salmon,
it probably like two or three times a
week.
Um,
I always have fresh garlic with it.
Oh Wow.
That's amazing.
And Salmon is outstanding to because
it's so high in essential fatty acids
strictly.
It's really good for you.
Exactly.
Yeah.
It's really high in Omega three fatty
acids,
EPA and Dha.
So.
And it's got a modest amount of vitamin
D.
whenever I'm sick I eat giant cloves of
garlic.
I'll just break it down to point where
it makes me feel horrible.
I'll have like a big glass of Kombucha
and I'll take like a lump of garlic and
I'll break off like four or five cloves
and I'll just take off the skin and chew
those bitches down and Chug it.
With Kombucha it's off,
like sometimes it,
it's painful as it's going down.
Like my,
my system is like,
what in the fuck is this?
Like,
I could feel it inside my body burning.
I love it.
I've,
I've done the same thing previously.
I mean,
I don't do that anymore,
but uh,
yeah,
I mean garlic is very powerful.
Antimicrobial compounds in it.
So,
I mean,
that makes perfect sense.
Lots of last time I did it,
I went,
I had to take a knee,
a knee to knee.
Really?
Yeah.
Like,
I didn't actually go down,
but what I did was I put both my arms on
the counter and I went down like this,
like,
oh,
because it was just burning,
going down.
I just was like,
well,
this is probably not even working.
I'm just being retarded.
No.
Getting back to some of those like
pungent compounds that are in these,
these,
these plants.
I mean that kind of gets back to what we
were talking about a minute ago with
switching on those genetic switches that
are meant to be switched on there.
Man,
we're supposed to eat these kinds of
foods,
garlic,
Broccoli,
cauliflower,
Kale,
these things that have that pungent
mustard,
you know,
that,
that pungent tastes.
I mean,
these things are,
um,
you know,
various different polyphenols and
compounds and one in particular I become
obsessed with lately is sulfur fain and
that's present in most of the
cruciferous family,
Kale,
Broccoli,
cabbage,
Brussel sprouts,
Wasabi,
Bok Choy,
just,
you know,
that whole family of vegetables,
pretty much.
I eat those vegetables a lot,
but I become very obsessed with this,
this compound that is,
it's actually sulforaphane refrains,
not in the plant.
It gets formed once you break the plant
tissue once it's like chewed or crushed
or blended or whatever,
chopped somehow because it's stored as a
precursor and then once the tissue gets,
you know,
chapter or whatever,
uh,
then it forms sulforaphane and that's
part of it's,
you know,
hormetic response.
It's,
it's plant response to try to ward off
insects or whatever thing.
So that's,
that's why it forms,
but it actually,
when we ingest it,
it's a really,
really,
really good for us,
you know.
So the sulfur in particular,
um,
which is actually really,
really high in Broccoli sprouts.
Have you ever had Broccoli sprouts?
Broccoli sprouts actually contained like
a hundred times more of it than mature
Broccoli.
So it's like probably the best source of
sulfur,
dietary source of sulfur fain out there
on your instagram that you,
you make shakes with that,
right?
I do,
yeah.
I've become sort of convinced that it's
a very powerful anti aging and also
powerful nootropic in a way.
I guess I could say.
Um,
and I can elaborate,
but you know,
so I've been doing these shakes where
you can,
you can sprout,
you can sprout your own sprouts at home
for a relatively cheap.
You just buy some organic weed dealer.
That's what about three point five
pounds of Broccoli spouts,
wink,
wink.
That's what they call it.
These kids,
believe it or not though,
if you freeze them.
So I was actually,
I'm freezing.
So those bags are going in the freezer
when you freeze them because when you
freeze the plant,
the tissue also gets like broken.
It actually doubles.
In some cases you can up to double the
amount of sulfur Fein because it like
has a longer time to form this so you
can have more concentrated.
I learned that the hard way,
but um,
what hardware,
let me just,
because it's so pungent and powerful
that if you make a shake with it and
you're doing,
like at first I was doing fresh shakes
and then we start freezing them and I
was making shakes that were from
previously frozen sprouts and it's like
I needed like half the dose,
um,
you know,
to feel,
to feel the same thing or if I feel I'm
okay.
So I guess I should probably,
you know,
it's kind of just like,
like when you drink coffee,
you know,
how you kind of just,
you feel a little happy and good and you
feel a little more alert.
Um,
sort of like that.
And it was.
The thing is,
is that it's been shown.
So there have been clinical studies in
humans and this is very interesting
because it's been shown like if you give
it,
you give,
you know,
even just a small amount.
I think it was like between seven to 30
milligrams of sulfur free in a day to
two young adults with autism that it
improved their autistic scores by like
34 percent.
And artistic scores,
they liked the,
there's a range of different tests that
are done to like measure different
various brain functions,
but improve this and this.
He autistic autistic individuals by like
34 percent.
The same was done.
Um,
in a pilot study for people with
schizophrenia were like improve their
symptoms so they're just,
their brain functions better.
Wow.
Yeah.
So,
and this is like pretty,
um,
the,
the results were so powerful that,
you know,
this was done at Johns Hopkins.
The study is now being repeated,
um,
you know,
because it's like this is what is going
on here.
Like how is this affecting the brain?
And I think,
you know,
if you look at a lot of the animal
studies,
there's lots and lots of animal studies
that have been done,
which are,
you know,
people aren't quite as convinced because
it's like,
well,
how much of this relates to humans,
but it's been shown to be as effective
as um,
the,
the antidepressant Prozac in alleviating
depression and mice.
And they do all these battery of tests
were they stress the mice out and make
them depressed and social defeat in like
the hanging by their tail.
It's actually just kind of gnarly.
But,
and then there's like,
you know,
a bunch of tests they do to see if
they're depressed and you give them,
you know,
your,
your placebo,
you give them Prozac or you give them
the,
the Broccoli sprout extract and it
performed just as well.
Um,
so it helps depression,
it's been shown to help with
neurodegenerative diseases,
all sorts of things.
But the point is,
I think that the reason it's actually
affecting all these brain functions and
why even you know,
someone like me may notice a small
effect from,
from eating them is because it has very
profound effect on inflammation.
And that is because,
as I mentioned,
it's,
it switches on one of those switches
that was meant to be switched on a
pathway called NRF two and our body that
controls over 200 genes.
And so for Fein is the most potent
naturally occurring compound that we've
discovered yet that activates this
pathway.
So it's no other plant compound or
they're naturally occurring plant
compound can activate this pathway is
potent as sulforaphane and nrf two is,
I mean,
it's been shown in multiple studies to
be involved in delaying aging and a lot
of that happens through lowering tons of
different inflammatory genes,
activating anti-inflammatory genes,
lowering oxidative stress,
glutathione related enzymes.
It helps with detoxifying compounds that
we're exposed to on a daily basis like
percentages and things.
So I think that we're having a low level
of this like inflammation stuff that
we're constantly being exposed to and it
affects the brain,
you know,
so if you're,
if you get a dose of this,
you,
you may notice a small effect now with
someone that has autism or
schizophrenia,
inflammation and oxidative stress had
been shown in previous studies on
multiple previous studies to,
to play a role in the etiology of those
diseases.
So I think that's how it may be
effecting the brain,
but it's not just affecting the brain.
And probably one of the most well known,
um,
functions of sulfur Fein is that it's
like a very powerful,
a cancer preventative,
um,
compound.
So it's,
you know,
it's been shown to prevent cancer.
Uh,
for example,
if you have men that had prostate cancer
when they were given 60 milligrams of
sulfur,
feign a day for,
I think it was like a month,
I don't remember exactly how long,
but it lowered its slowed the doubling
rate of a tumor biomarker called
prostate specific Antigen Psa,
which is what is usually measured when
men have prostate cancer.
You mentioned the progression of it
because it has a doubling rate.
It doubles every so often,
but it slowed that doubling rate by 86
percent,
which is pretty,
pretty profound.
Of course,
there's lots and lots of associative
studies that have shown cruciferous
vegetables,
you know,
if you eat more of them,
you have lower risk of bladder,
ovarian,
prostate,
kidney,
just all sorts of cancers.
Um,
but there's the clinical trials I think
are what's really telling because
they're,
you know,
you're giving someone this compound and
it's slowing a tumor.
Progressive Progression Marker by 86
percent.
Um,
there's another study which is really
interesting also,
and this is kind of like what really got
me interested.
I'm not sure if other people are
interested in it,
but um,
you know,
we're exposed to two compounds from like
air pollution.
So like living in Los Angeles for
example,
is probably definitely one of the places
that you're going to be more exposed to
the.
So some of these airborne carcinogens,
so benzenes one of them Aqualina.
These things are in the air.
We're breathing them in.
We're,
we're getting to some degree,
we have it.
We have benzene in our system and it is
a carcinogen.
It's been shown to cause cancer
specifically linked to leukemia,
has a smokers get a ton of it because
it's in,
it's in cigarettes.
So cigarettes smokers are like really
loaded up with benzene.
But there was a study where people were
given like 40 milligrams of sulforaphane
in the form of a Broccoli sprout drink a
day for like a week and starting on day
one of tea drinking this drink,
they excrete id 61 percent of the
benzene,
like on day one,
61 percent of benzene which is coming
out of their urine,
like as you measure metabolites.
And I was like,
wow,
that is amazing.
Like getting rid of some of that stuff,
you know,
I,
because I'm definitely want to get rid
of the benzene and all that stuff that
I'm being exposed to.
So that really got my attention too
because it was just so significant and a
profound effect just after one day.
Um,
so that,
that was another sort of thing that got
me really it.
And then the aging stuff where it's been
shown some inflammation has been
identified as a key age or of aging.
Taking sulforaphane has been shown to
lower inflammatory markers in people,
um,
by like 20 percent c reactive protein,
other inflammatory markers.
Of course there's like dozens of studies
in animals that have been done,
but I'm sort of,
I think the human studies are more
interesting to talk about.
So definitely more relevant.
Um,
and then also it's been shown to effect
a cardiovascular health because of the
inflammation.
I think so type two diabetics that were
given,
uh,
some,
some dose,
I think it was something around 40
milligrams as well as of sulforaphane.
They were given this daily and for a
month,
for four weeks and it lowered their
triglycerides by 20 percent.
It lowered their atherogenic index,
which is measuring,
you know,
the dangerous type of Ldl,
small dense ldl triglycerides,
looking at all these things,
lower that by 50 percent,
improve their blood sugar by almost 20
percent.
So that's like I'm getting my mouth,
I'm trying to get my mom on this.
I'm,
you know,
my mom,
she,
she definitely has got like high
triglycerides,
you know,
thing.
So I'm really convinced.
And then there's been studies in animals
that's just shown that it like delays
aging.
So I'm convinced that I think it's one
of those things like you get it in Kale
and I think that I've been getting a
good dose of it.
I've been drinking Kale smoothies.
I'm pretty regularly since I'm probably
like 2010.
Yeah,
probably about six or seven years.
And I do feel like it's like help age,
like help me age like a little better.
I mean,
it could be completely in my mind,
but just because I know it killed has
held,
killed with healthy,
but I think that I've found something to
take it to another level where I think
that I'm pretty convinced that if I
continued taking the Sulforaphane,
um,
I think it will absolutely affect the
way I age and I think it will affect my
brain aging as well.
I mean,
it's been shown to at least an animal
studies to affect brain aging,
traumatic brain injury.
I mean if you administered after
traumatic brain injury,
it improves.
Outcome,
improves your brain swelling and all
that by like 50 percent,
you know,
just all sorts of nones.
It's just like I could go on and I have
a video.
I did like a 45 minute video where I'm
literally just talking about this for 45
minutes and then I went on Youtube.
It's on youtube.
Yeah.
And I,
um,
I did this,
this research took month,
many months and it's like a 16 page
article I wrote.
Um,
and I hope to get published.
I think I'm going to submit it for
publication because it's just,
it was a lot of work and I haven't seen
anything in the literature as
comprehensive covering every base.
Like I just,
I tried to cover everything that was
like a good study,
you know,
that was important.
And I'm so,
so um,
and then I flew out to Johns Hopkins,
uh,
recently I was invited to give a talk
there and I met it just so happens the
guy who discovered that,
first of all,
the guy who discovered Sofer Fein is
there,
but he's much older.
I didn't meet with.
I met with someone who trained with him,
um,
who discovered that Broccoli sprouts are
the best source of sulfur.
And so he made that discovery back in
the nineties.
Um,
and I interviewed him and he just went
on and on and on and talked about so far
are like,
in addition to like what I had already
talked about on one of the videos I did.
And he actually had some really
interesting stuff to talk about in terms
of like,
um,
you know,
you.
So in order to get the sulfur thing,
you have to,
the plant has to be crushed or chopped
and that's because it has an enzyme in
it called my Ra cynase.
And my Ross cynase is I'm heat
sensitive.
So when you,
when you,
when you steam your Broccoli,
when you boil your Kale,
when you saw your kill,
any of that stuff,
unfortunately your inactivating my
Roston a's.
And so you're not getting as much sulfur
fain,
you're getting dramatically less
dramatic,
almost not almost nonexistent.
The precursor Glucoraphanin is still in
that plant.
So,
so you're getting the precursor and we
do have some bacteria,
some types of bifido bacteria in our gut
that contain the,
my ra,
Annie's enzyme,
highly variable from individual to
individual,
but so you can convert some of that to
sulforaphane.
But what was interesting that he
mentioned is you can actually sprinkle
mustard powder,
like mustard powder that you buy,
um,
after you saw your Kale or after you
steam your vegetables or what if you
cook,
if you apply heat to any of your
cruciferous vegetables afterwards,
you put the muscle paddle on mustard
powder.
It has active my Ross and he's in it and
it's pretty.
The myrosinase in the mustard seed is
more heat stable so you can actually
convert your precursor into the soul for
fame by adding the mustard powder.
And I was like,
that is a really great wow.
Like thing to know because now I'm like,
because I do cook a lot of.
I saw take all the time.
Um,
I,
you know,
I steam my Broccoli,
put some butter and salt,
pepper.
That's how I eat my broccoli.
So it wasn't very useful.
Are there any compounds in Kale or
broccoli or anything else that makes
them more bioavailable when you do cook
them?
Um,
yeah.
I mean a lot of the minerals and stuff
in it,
like magnesium,
the calcium,
those things are,
those things become more bioavailable
when you cook them.
And so you would get that benefit.
Plus if you just cooked it,
the mustard.
So when the master seed powder,
you have to make sure it's.
What I like to do is sprinkle a little
bit on my hand and lick,
lick it,
like it's got to give.
It has to have that bite.
If it doesn't have the bite,
it's like,
it's been degraded.
It's been on the shelf for too long.
It's been an Amazon shelves for too
long.
Whatever,
you know.
So,
um,
yeah,
it has to have that light mustard bite
to it.
Could you regular mustard?
I don't think so.
Now.
Mustard seed.
The mustard seed.
Yeah.
Uh,
so that.
So that was a very useful like,
you know,
because the Sulforaphane,
it's really good joe.
I really am.
I'm trying to get people to.
I think the more people that get the
sulforaphane in life,
I think they're gonna be healthier.
I think it can help prevent cancer,
lower inflammation.
I'm just so many different good things.
So smokers,
for God's sake,
if you're a smoker,
they should be taking sulfur free.
They should be drinking those shakes.
I'm drinking,
drinking like every day,
you know,
because they are getting so much
benzene.
So two questions about this one.
Where does someone get Broccoli sprouts?
Where,
where would you get that?
Well,
also the thing is,
is that you can borrow,
you can buy Broccoli sprouts already,
sprouted at like whole foods or sprouts
or whatever your local grocery store is.
Most,
most grocery stores contain a have
Broccoli,
sprouts,
sprouts.
It's very rarely that you find Broccoli
sprouts,
isn't it?
At whole foods?
They're at sprouts.
But the problem,
here's the problem with buying sprouts,
um,
they're very prone to,
to bacterial contamination.
The cookie Kolai that the longer they
sit on the shelf and a lot of times when
you go into these grocery stores,
they're sitting on the shelf and so
they're probably likely a little more
contaminated with Nikolai then if you
were to sprout them yourself and get
them fresh so you can buy them.
Um,
but I think,
and they also charge like it's like five
bucks for like a little package of it,
you know,
it's like one shake,
right?
Yeah,
I'd say one shake,
whereas you can spend 20 bucks and get
like a pound of seeds.
And so how do you grow it?
Um,
well there's lots of different methods
you can,
you can use hemp.
Like,
so previously we used to do these hemp,
um,
hemp bags where we just put,
you put the seeds in the bag and you add
some water.
Uh,
you basically just keep adding water to
them and let it drip and they sprout
within like four days.
Then we started doing this jar method
where now we have mason jars with a lid
on top that has like little holes that
are big enough for water to come out
obviously,
but not for the seeds to come out.
And so,
you know,
you get these jars and you add water,
let it sit for like six hours and then
dump it out.
And then you just,
after that you continually just add the
water and dump it out and add the water
interpreter and kind of leave it tilted
so that the water isn't just like,
you don't want the water just sitting in
there so that it's like growing bacteria
and stuff.
So like let you know,
tilt the water and just wet.
Yeah.
And it really just takes like four days.
And then you have sprouts.
The only thing is you have,
you do have to be,
you know,
clean like your counters all dirty and
your hands are dirty and all the dish
where you're using this dirty,
then you're probably going to
contaminate them.
So you have to like,
be a little fastidious about the way you
spread out these things.
Um,
you know,
but I think once you're aware of that,
then it's okay.
The other thing is,
um,
and this is something that I'm going to
talk to to the expert.
His name is Dr Jed Fahy.
I recently interviewed him on my
podcast.
He mentioned something to me that like
caught my interest.
He said the seed itself,
the Broccoli seed itself has the enzyme,
it has the precursor to sulforaphane.
And if you break or crush the seed or
chew the seed,
then you're actually getting.
So for refrain.
So you can actually crush up the seed
and like a coffee grinder or something
and like take a shot of it.
But the thing is,
is there's been no research doing this
method.
So all these studies that I just talked
about in humans,
those were all done from like Broccoli
sprout powder extract from the sprouts.
Powder extracts is something they
goodbyes a supplement.
Great question.
Um,
so.
Well the powder extracts were mostly
made by researchers.
In fact Jed,
jed is supplied a lot of,
um,
a lot of different universities with
the,
with the extract himself.
Um,
but there are so supplement wise,
that's the other thing that he really
sort of illuminated for me because,
because he's actually been measuring
this certain supplements that are on the
market and like if they actually have
what they say they have.
Um,
and so because myrosinase is so
unstable,
it is hard to make a supplement with
sulfur roofing.
There is one supplement only one that I
know of that actually has sulforaphane,
the actual active compound and that's
called prostitution.
And that's only available in France by
the way.
I have no affiliation with any of these
supplement companies at all.
I'm just telling information.
It's only available in France.
It's only available in France and so and
that.
So he actually tested that one and
people that were given Prostif I'm the
bioavailability of the soul for roofing
with 70 percent,
so 70 percent of it ended up like in
their bloodstream.
Um,
there's another supplement called Avma
[inaudible].
Avma McCall has Glucoraphanin plus
myrosinase in it,
so it doesn't have the Sulforaphane,
has the two compounds that can form,
so for a friend,
but it hasn't been together,
um,
that has been tested and that was a bout
40 percent by bioavailability.
So about 40 percent of it was you were
actually getting sulforaphane 40 percent
of the time and that was also tested.
There's another supplement and that is
available in the US.
There's another supplement by thorne
called Coursera I think.
And Chris Sarah only has the precursor
no enzyme,
so you're totally relying on your gut
bacteria.
And some people it's very variable,
so that only had a 10 percent
bioavailability.
Um,
other than that,
those are the three supplements that he
really could.
And this isn't a study who just
published recently that he got behind.
I asked him about a few others because I
had actually been taking,
uh,
there's another one called Brocka Max by
jarrow and he kind of was like asked him
about it and he was kind of like
[inaudible] has some of what it says in
there but not all,
you know.
And,
and the problem is,
is that these supplements,
I mean there's a lot of,
a lot of the times like he was telling
me like,
Jeez,
like seven out of 10 times these
supplements had like cloverleaf in them
when they're supposed to have like
the cruciferous precursor Glucoraphanin.
So it's just like,
it's kind of disgusting how supplement
company,
how somebody a supplement companies are
totally just putting all this cloverleaf
and whatever.
And there was a study that came out like
a couple of years ago on this,
like,
like 75 percent of all these,
like herbal Achalasia,
like all these,
you know,
compounds that are,
marketed for whatever,
don't actually even contain economically
or whatever they say they contain.
It's really,
it's really kind of bad.
So it's a giant issue and if you're a
company that sells that stuff,
a lot of times you're not even,
you're not even getting it directly from
the source,
you know,
they're buying it from companies that
supply it to them.
And a lot of times these companies are
in China and places where there were
regulations are not that strict.
You can,
you can get just with.
I mean,
we had an issue with that when we first
started making Alpha brain where we
would get stuff tested,
we get batches tested in the batches of
different individual ingredients would
have stuff in it that they weren't
supposed to have in it just because
they're mixing it all up in the same
bins.
Oh yeah,
that's true.
There's also that.
Yeah,
I mean there's just,
you got to find a reliable brand,
you know,
and I think,
Thorn Thorn seems to be a pretty
reliable one that,
um,
I've seen multiple,
multiple different,
you know,
times where scientists were like,
yeah,
we've tested that.
It,
it's more expensive,
but they seem to be pretty reliable.
So it seems like the best method is a
sprout your own Broccoli sprouts.
So I think that's the best method and it
seems like very cost effective to.
Exactly.
It's cost effective.
You don't,
you don't have to have extra cash to buy
all these expensive supplements because
the all the ones I just mentioned that
actually are effective and have what
they say they're not cheap.
So that those bags that you had,
that instagram photo,
is that all sprouts that you'd made
yourself a mason jars at two,
six,
six.
Oh Wow.
That's not that bad.
Yeah.
I mean they get really dense to.
They fill up inside the jar.
Yeah.
I have like other pictures somewhere on
there.
They were there with the jars,
but I'm thinking I might just do a quick
spreading video like a fiber six minute,
like I'm already going in my head about
how I'm going to start sprouting.
Awesome.
And they're good.
Like,
you know,
you don't have to do.
I always sort of take it to the next
level.
Like I make my shake and it's like,
um,
but they're good on salads.
I mean,
you know,
you can sprinkle them on anything,
it's,
I really,
I really liked them on salads quite a
bit.
So that's amazing.
Now,
uh,
there you go.
Oh,
there we go.
Does the.
Yeah.
So those.
So those are the mason jars that have
holes already in them.
Yes.
You can actually buy this sprouting kit.
So these actually we found these are the
old lids we were using.
We actually found better lids that have
even smaller holes because some of the
seeds were getting out of this,
but this came as a kit,
a sprouting kit you can buy on Amazon.
It has like a little wooden going to set
the mason jars in so they're like tilted
and you can like,
you know,
drip the water out.
They came with those lids.
But then we did some experimentation and
found other leds that are superior to
those.
But those,
how much maintenance is involved in
making these.
Like how often do you have to attend to
these things?
Oh,
it's just like after the first initial,
like six our water.
You know what?
You let them sit.
It's like twice a day in the morning and
evening dump water on them,
but you have to rip them out.
And how long does it take to grow that?
That was about five days,
I think.
Four or five days.
So for a guy like me who goes away on
weekends a lot,
I'd have to make sure that I am home for
a stretch where you can.
So,
so you could have Harvard is actually.
So here's the thing,
the longer you're letting them sprout.
So I was just trying to maximize and
went more dense,
you know,
because I wanted to get my bang for my
buck.
But you can actually,
you could have Harvard is harvested
though,
is probably like early,
like three days,
three and a half days.
Um,
and actually the longer you wait,
the more you have to be careful with
contamination too.
So it's like,
it's better probably even to harvest
them sooner.
Freeze them.
So they're like,
you know,
no bacteria that way you're just,
you're safe.
And you're just putting them in a ziploc
storage bags.
Yeah.
Do you ever vacuum seal things and
freeze them?
And now I should do that with me.
Yeah,
it's a good idea.
I mean,
that,
that would,
that would be a good idea to do.
Wow,
that's a,
that's really intense stuff.
The other question that I wanted to have
a talk to you about was when you were
saying schizophrenia and how so fewer
feign can prevent or somehow mitigate
the effects of schizophrenia.
Do you think that there is a possible
correlation between a lot of these
mental health diseases and a lack of
proper nutrition?
Oh,
absolutely.
I think that a lack of proper nutrition
is a huge component of a lot of mental
diseases and psychological diseases in
general.
Um,
in fact,
inflammation is now it's really been
identified as I caused playing a causal
role in depression.
Um,
and that's something that,
you know,
so with the depression thing,
uh,
it's,
here's,
here's kind of a funny story and it's
not that funny.
It's actually kind of eye opening,
but back in the,
so the CDC has estimated that about 11
percent of,
of um,
Americans are on some sort of
antidepressant.
Eleven percent.
That's a lot.
So here's the story behind that.
So crazy it is,
and I know several people that are on
them or have taken them or you know,
you know,
whatever.
But the story behind that is kind of
interesting because back in like the
early seventies,
um,
a lot of these clinical trials were
being done on antidepressants with
people that had depression and at that
time people that had depression,
um,
that were involved in these trials
were people that were severely depressed
and hospitalized,
so they were so depressed that they had
been hospitalized for depression.
I don't know many people that had been
hospitalized for depression nowadays,
but so they were hospitalized for
depression and then they were given
either placebo or an depressant and a
multiple trials.
You know,
FDA had reviewed these trials 70 percent
of the time,
the antidepressant.
So the antidepressant worked in 70
percent of the patients compared to 30
percent of the patients were placebo
worked,
right?
Seventy percent is pretty good if you're
comparing that to 30 percent in placebo,
it's like,
well that's efficacious.
That seems to work.
Right.
What then happened after those trials
were done starting in the seventies and
eighties,
is that the clinical diagnostic manual,
it's called the dsm.
At that time it was the DSM two,
they changed all their,
um,
their diagnosis,
you know,
markers and,
and uh,
symptoms for depression and they
expanded it a great,
great deal.
And they then called depression major
depressive disorder.
So it became this sort of like broader,
you know,
a disease,
quote unquote,
where it was like,
it's not just these people that are
severely hospitalized,
it's people that are feeling depressed
and anxious and sad or what,
you know,
it's just basically you're,
you're getting a bigger group of people,
which is probably a great opportunity
for,
for a pharmaceutical company.
But then when clinical trials were
repeated on this new population of
people,
so these,
these are clinical trials that were done
from like the eighties all the way up
until like the 2000 year,
2000 when those were reviewed,
reviewed by the FDA.
What was found was quite shocking and
that was that only 40 percent of people
were now responding to like
antidepressants.
SSRI is other norepinephrine reuptake
inhibitors,
lots of whatever the standard of care is
compared to 30 percent placebo.
So now you're talking about only 10.
They're performing only this
antidepressants performing only 10
percent better than placebo.
It's like,
okay,
something so clearly.
It's not that the antidepressants don't
ever work,
it's just that we are now over
prescribing them to people that you know
or have this major depressive disorder
and they're not working on people that
weren't,
you know,
the,
the initial group of people that were
like severely depressed and
hospitalized,
you know.
So it's like,
okay,
that's,
that's a big problem because they're,
I mean they're prescribed like,
I mean I just like,
I can't even believe it,
you know,
I just have so many personal stories.
People I know,
you know,
that have gone,
going through some crisis and personal,
a divorce,
whatever,
and also in their given you some crazy
center giving some crazy drug and they
changed the personality of the person.
And I'm just like,
please get off of this.
Like,
you know,
it's not like.
And like I said,
it's not like they don't ever work,
it's just that,
you know,
I think once the clinical diagnostic
book changed the whole procedure for
diagnosing depression and became major
depressive order disorder,
all of a sudden you're getting people
that are now like having just,
you know,
whatever stressful event in their life
that's making them a little depressed
the time which everyone's probably
experienced are now being given this
antidepressant when they don't really
need it.
And there are effects that are not good
with taking some of these,
you know,
and a depressant.
So it was a big effect on Libido.
Yeah.
Onto the lobby.
I know a lot of people that have taken
it where their sex drive just goes away.
Yeah.
There's actually a gene that's a gene
polymorphism,
a variation in a gene that,
that is linked to that.
So people that have it have even more
severe effect where they really don't.
They really have like sexual dysfunction
and response to a.
It just shuts down.
Yeah.
It doesn't happen to everyone quite as
much,
but there,
there's a percentage of people that it
really,
really affects.
And there's lots of other things.
I mean it's just,
it's changing your brain chemistry,
right?
It's not exact.
It's an inexact science.
No,
there's a lot of experimentation going
on with it.
I had a friend of mine who had gone to
several doctors and they had prescribed
a bunch of different things to him and
he was severely depressed and eventually
they gave up and he had to find a much
better doctor that his care,
his whatever his insurance package would
not pay for.
And once you found that doctor,
then the doctor was just more
knowledgeable about what potential
different ones.
I mean,
I don't know how many different ones
there are,
but they got them on something that
actually worked.
He's off it now.
It took them awhile and then eventually
got happy.
And then oddly enough,
which is an interesting thing because
people always want to connect
depression.
They want to say depression is a disease
and they want to say it almost like,
oh,
you got herpes.
Like,
you know what I mean?
It's like,
well,
you've got depression.
Oh,
well you need medicine.
And for him,
the.
One of the big factors in fixing
everything was his own success,
his own personal success,
and then he became more happy and then
his,
the medication helped.
He became more successful and then as he
became eventually really successful,
he started to experience like a better
quality of life.
He was happier,
he was more confident and then he slowly
weaned himself off and now he has no
need for them to mean.
That is so fascinating because so we're
not talking about necessarily a disease,
like he does not have cancer.
It's not like that they cured him of a
disease.
It's,
it was a blanket that was keeping him
warm,
you know,
it was something that was,
was allowing him to bridge the gap
between an unhealthy mental state and
healthy mental state.
But a lot of that health had to do with
his own life.
He still eats like shit.
I mean,
he's not like the healthiest guy.
He eats a lot of fucking candy,
but a really healthy now as far as like
his mind,
he's very happy.
He's not lying,
you know,
he's not faking it.
So to me it's always.
I mean,
when,
when you know,
I've talked to friends that have had
really good results with
antidepressants,
so I think there are some dark moments
in people's lives where that can kind of
get them out of that,
but then part of me doesn't buy that.
That's the way to go because part of me
is like,
okay,
well did you exercise?
No.
Did you take like really healthy foods?
Did you clean your life up?
No.
Did you like how,
what happened here?
And one of the things that a lot of
these antidepressants do is they make
you not feel bad about stuff like about
anything.
Like A.
I had a friend who was on Zoloft and she
said like,
she took it for a year and she's like,
I kind of lost a year of my life.
Like I didn't give a fuck about anything
during that year.
Like anything can happen.
It's scary.
Yeah.
But that not giving a fuck,
not,
not feeling bad.
You also,
you don't feel great either.
You don't feel like you don't feel like
God,
it's a good time to be alive.
Look at me,
I'm healthy.
I can move,
you know,
like all those thoughts don't sort of
come into play.
It's like it dulls everything.
It dulls the highs and the dolls,
the lows and it keeps the pain away.
That's kind of interesting because
believe it or not,
that's actually a symptom of depression.
I think it's called Hedonia or something
where someone's not really responsive to
anything.
It's like you can't,
like,
you just can't like,
you know,
like excite them or,
or like make them super anxious either.
They're just kind of like,
you know.
So that's actually kind of interesting
that she was experiencing that while on
an antidepressant.
Will the results vary pretty widely?
Totally.
Yeah.
I mean with the same drugs,
right?
Yeah,
yeah.
Now is that because of biodiversity,
like what,
what's causing that?
That you could take something and you
would have a totally different reaction?
I can take something and it would just
perfect.
Yeah.
I,
you know,
I honestly,
I don't think we actually know really
why that is,
but what we do know is that there are,
I mean there are different,
you know,
we are different people and I've got
different genes that are regulating how
much serotonin I making,
how much dope immune I'm making,
how much I'm metabolizing it,
how quickly I'm metabolizing it than you
and other people.
And so when you like MP and this is,
this absolutely does affect how some of
these drugs are,
you know,
when they're taken,
how,
how they are with their biological
effect is now,
you know,
why,
I don't know,
you know,
so it's,
there's definitely like a,
a genetic variation that,
that affects the way our
neurotransmitters are being fired away
in the way are I'm being metabolized.
And so if you're,
if you're adding a drug that's changing
the way something's being metabolized
already,
then it's gonna affect people
differently I think.
I think that's one reason,
but honestly,
I don't know.
Who knows?
There's maybe like other,
you know,
life situations.
Well,
other dietary situations,
all these things probably play a role,
you know,
with the inflammation I was talking
about actually playing a causal role.
I mean,
there've actually been,
studies were normal,
healthy people are injected with either
a placebo,
which is saline water,
saltwater,
or they're injected with something that
our gut produces called endotoxin.
Our gut produces it when our immune
cells in our gut attack the bacteria in
our gut because endotoxin is actually a
component of the bacterial cell membrane
and that is released upon inflammation.
So when you're eating a terrible diet,
lots of refined sugar,
um,
and that's,
that's actually been shown,
um,
you release endotoxin and it causes
inflammatory response.
So when people are injected with
endotoxin or they're injected with
proinflammatory cytokines,
interferon gamma,
which we also make in our body,
when we're inflamed,
people start to,
at normal healthy people start to
experience feelings of depression.
They start to feel depressed,
anxious,
social withdraw.
People with the placebo did not
experience that.
Um,
also they had elevated levels of other
inflammatory biomarkers,
biomarkers in their blood.
So it really like,
and this is just,
this is causal.
And when we're talking about injecting
in relation to inflammation,
all of a sudden they're experiencing
these depressive symptoms.
It was actually people that were then
given.
I'm one of the omega three fatty acids,
EPA.
They're given an actually a pretty high
dose of it.
I think it was close to like two grams
or something,
uh,
completely,
um,
alleviated any of those symptoms so
that.
So those people that were getting the
inflammatory cytokine or the endotoxin
and the EPA did not experience those
symptoms.
So it was really like inflammation,
you know,
driven,
uh,
these symptoms that were not experienced
in the placebo.
Um,
so that's kind of,
and there's been multiple studies
showing this not,
you know,
it's not just one studies,
multiple studies,
multiple studies.
Again,
this is kind of like a new method people
are using to explore how inflammation
affects depression.
It also has been shown the same sort of
scenario where there's a placebo and
they're injecting a inflammatory
cytokine.
Dopamine levels lower in the brains of
people that were injected with the
proinflammatory cytokines,
but not the saline water.
And also the reward pathway in the
brain,
um,
is also decreased.
So,
you know,
again,
like I was mentioning,
you're not that excitable,
you don't,
you know,
it's just kinda like and that,
and that was not,
that did not happen in the placebo
group.
So this was not just an effect of being
shot up with something,
you know.
So,
um,
when,
uh,
scientists have looked at some,
some of the mechanisms and explored
will,
how is it that inflammation is affecting
dopamine in the brain?
How is it that it's effecting people's
mood?
It's thought now there's a variety of
mechanisms.
One is that,
you know,
these inflammatory cytokines,
they actually cross the blood brain
barrier,
the get into the brain and they disrupt
dopamine release.
They disrupt serotonin release that
disrupt norepinephrine release,
you know,
they're disrupting these
neurotransmitters being released.
Um,
the other thing is that there's been
recently a discovered that the lymphatic
system is actually directly connected to
the brain through the meninges.
And then it was previously thought that
that was like cutoff.
The brain was protected from the
lymphatic system,
but it turns out we were wrong in
everything that we learned in text books
for years and years and our science
classes was not accurate.
Actually,
we are.
Our lymphatic system is connected and
what that means is that our immune
system,
the chemicals,
the inflammatory cytokines were
producing,
you know,
from our immune cells are getting into
the brain and disrupting
neurotransmitter release and other
things.
So there's obviously a really strong
connection to inflammation and
depression that's shown to be causal.
But when you think about it,
it's like,
well,
what causes inflammation?
Okay,
well we can talk about the sugar stuff
because that's been shown eating a
terrible diet does.
But the other thing that causes it,
and it's what you,
you mentioned that is a stressful event
in someone's life,
an emotional event,
you know,
a breakup,
um,
a tragedy,
work related stress,
social anxiety,
whatever it is,
anything that causes you to release
cortisol,
stress hormones,
believe it or not,
those things actually affect
inflammation in your gut.
So it's like a two way street here.
I think that previously you and I have
talked about in other podcasts,
like how gut microbiome bacteria,
you know,
you can take microbiome bacteria from an
anxious mouse and transplanted into a
nonanxious mouse and make us anxious and
vice versa,
right?
So there's like some sort of gut brain
access through with something called the
vagal nerve.
Well,
it goes both ways.
You can go from the brain down to the
gut.
So it's been shown that like,
um,
cortico releasing hormone,
which is a stress hormone,
you know,
we get through the vagal nerve when you
release it,
goes into the gut.
It activates immune cells which then
activate other proteins in the gut that
chew up there called proteases.
They chew up the gut barrier and then
you start to release more influent,
inflammatory cells,
which then like get in contact with
bacteria,
more inflammation,
and then it goes back.
It's like this feedback loop.
So I think that's how stress also part
of the mechanism,
how a stressful event and any sort of
breakup or tragedy,
those sorts of things also cause
inflammation.
They cause inflammation.
In fact,
it's a totally off topic,
but that's one reason why people should
never go and like get like blood work
done,
like like a day or two after some kind
of traumatic event because get fired.
Don't get your blood work done.
Yeah.
Like do you not get your blood or break
up or whatever?
Yeah,
because they will like,
it will skew everything.
Wow.
Everything.
Well that's,
that's so amazing.
And when you discuss this and when you
lay all these facts out,
it makes it seem so irresponsible that
10 percent of the people are on this
drug.
Eleven percent,
excuse me,
are on this drug or whatever,
a pet category of these drugs instead of
dealing with it.
I mean it seems like it's,
it's,
we're in a weird place when it comes to
the holistic treatment of the human
body.
We're,
we're in a very weird place where we
have all this information now,
but it doesn't seem like it's being
applied when it comes to the average
person who is suffering the average
person who is dealing with the disease
or depression,
which I guess you could call a disease
and it just seems so insane that with
all we know that we're treating it only
with this chemical pathway.
We're only treating with a pill.
This pharmacy,
you know,
this Pharma collage,
local solution to this,
which just seems so limited,
upsetting.
It's so upsetting.
It's very upsetting.
I am like,
it's like a mission of mine,
you know,
I think,
I think that the problem is multifold
one is that you have,
you know,
psychiatrists and they're trained a
certain way and people when their
patients come in,
they expect that they're going to come
pay.
They come in because they want a pill.
Most of the time they do,
they come in because they don't want to
deal with it and they want a pill.
And so,
you know,
that's kind of a problem because they
need.
People need to understand that these
pills are not the magic bullet.
I mean I just told you,
only 40 percent people are responding to
these antidepressants that are standard
of care compared to 30 percent that
respond to placebo.
A sugar pill like that is ridiculous,
you know?
So I think I would love if there was
some way to get a physician or I'm
usually their psychiatrist that people
go to for these sorts of problems to
like push someone to say you have to go
run,
you know you're going to run six miles a
week,
you're going to run,
you're going to do that.
That is going to help you.
Like,
you know,
it's,
in fact,
it's been shown.
It's been shown in multiple studies.
That exercise helps improve depression.
And one of the ways it does it very
interestingly is that aerobic exercise
specifically has been shown that whole
serotonin pathway.
We're talking about inflammation
inhibiting release of Serotonin.
Well guess what?
Inflammation affects serotonin.
And another way,
Sarah,
the precursor to Serotonin,
Serotonin Tryptofan,
when you have inflammation.
So like I said,
an emotional event causes inflammation,
doesn't have to be your sugar diet.
Okay.
What are,
you know,
inflammation can be caused by your,
your cortisol release.
When you have that inflammation in your
body thinks that it needs to fight off
something,
but that's what it thinks.
It's like,
okay,
this,
I'm sick,
I've got foreign invader,
I need to kill it.
And so the trip to fan,
which usually is being transported into
the brain to make Serotonin,
which plays a role in how you feel it
plays a role in lots of brain functions,
then gets diverted into another pathway
because your body's like,
wait a minute,
I don't need to feel good.
I need to,
I need to survive and need to live.
So the trip to fan gets converted into
this whole other pathway called
learning,
which helps with.
It means basically immune cells need it
to a different immune cells needed to
make different types of immune cells.
So your body is like,
okay,
the trip,
your going to this other pathway,
I need more immune cell,
blah blah blah.
But the problem is that the journey and
then gets converted into.
So now what you have is you're depleting
your brain of Serotonin.
Boom,
right there,
right?
That's the first thing.
So if you're not sick and if you have
chronic inflammation,
you're chronically stressed,
chronically eating a terrible diet,
then you are going to constantly be
diverting the Serotonin.
You know the trip to fan and his other
pathway.
You're going to be depleting your
cranium Serotonin,
right?
So that's one thing.
This is a twofold problem.
Then that whole kind of yearning thing
gets converted into something called
quinolinic acid,
which actually crosses over the blood
brain barrier,
becomes a neurotoxin and also has been
shown to cause depression.
So not only you're not getting
Serotonin,
you're getting this gnarly shit and your
brain that's not supposed to be there.
I'm an exercise.
It's been shown specifically aerobic
exercise causes your muscle to soak up
the Kenyan running.
I'm actually another precursor to it so
that it can't form quinolinic acid.
So it doesn't form the,
the neurotoxin park part,
but you know,
exercise also caused you to make to.
It makes trip to fan.
Go into your brain,
you know,
it alleviates some of the competition
with branch chain amino acids like
leucine and lysine,
leucine,
so that's another way it's doing a
million things,
brain derived neurotrophic factor.
We talked about at the beginning of the
podcast that also plays a role in
depression,
helping prevent depression,
you know,
so neurogenesis,
neurogenesis,
all that stuff that helps growing new
brain cells,
making new connections helps.
Helps you deal with stress.
That's why you make it.
When you stress your body,
it seems like there could be some sort
of a whole holistic approach like or
clinic that looks at all of these
factors.
It looks at all these factors and
prescribes instead of just prescribing a
pill,
prescribes a very specific diet and
exercise routine and maybe even
meditation,
maybe even something that the practices
or or or or enhances mindfulness or
promotes mindfulness.
Something that allows you to manage the
way you're viewing and taking in
scenarios and scenes and events in your
life and then processing them in a more
healthy manner.
It seems like all of these things would
be as effective or maybe more effective
than just a pill.
I agree with you and I'm hopeful for the
future.
I think that the more.
There's a lot of scientists that are
studying this now.
I mean it's becoming very common to look
in the scientific literature and,
and see,
you know,
scientists researching inflammation and
the role of inflammation and depression
and the role of exercise in helping
treat it and the role of other,
you know,
dietary and lifestyle factors in causing
and treating depression.
So I think that,
you know,
I,
I really am hopeful that in the near
future that it,
like you said,
it's going to be a multipronged approach
where it's not just a magic pill.
And I'm not saying that's not also going
to be included in some,
you know,
I'm just saying I think,
I think the Diet lifestyle,
meditation exercise,
if we
could just get that into like,
you know,
the clinical world and if people were
motivated enough to realize this will
really help them.
Like it really will.
People will be so much happier.
I really,
I really think so.
So um,
people just don't want to fuck an
exercise.
It's weird.
They would so much rather go to a doctor
and get a pill.
It's,
it's so strange.
It's a lot of people.
Well,
it's this fear of discomfort.
People have this extreme feeling in
their mind,
uh,
when it comes to their associations with
exercise,
they want to avoid discomfort.
They feel like any type of exercise is
just like something to be avoided.
That's not for me.
Fuck that.
I don't want to sweat.
I don't want to strain.
And a lot of times this association that
they have is about the beginnings of
getting in shape.
It's not about once you're actually fit
because once you're actually fit,
exercise is something you look forward
to.
It's an alleviation of stress.
It's,
it feels great.
Like if I can't get a workout in,
I look at my schedule,
I go,
ah,
shit,
I don't have any time for a workout,
which means I'm not going to get that
good feeling.
And so instead of looking at it like,
oh,
I've got to go grunt and sweat,
I'm thinking I'm not going to feel good,
I'm not going to feel relaxed,
I'm not going to feel carefree and I'm
not going to feel even appreciative,
like my appreciation of things.
And it gets enhanced greatly after
exercise.
I just feel better.
I feel like I can take things in for
what they are rather than,
you know,
whatever the sensory data that I'm
getting from any event is just one more
distraction that gets in my way.
And,
and you know,
that that's a lot of times how I look at
things if I'm overstressed or if I'm
working too much.
Totally beautifully put.
Um,
because that,
that that's exactly like,
at least what's been shown from like
neuro imaging studies is that exercise
does what you're talking about is that
executive function.
You're talking about feeling good
without that sensory stuff,
which is the Amygdala,
the emotional center that's been shown
to be decreased in activity after
exercise where the executive function is
increased.
So it's,
it's just,
it's done exactly in the right
direction.
Right.
So you're,
you're able to logically think about
this more and you feel good and it's
like you're not that,
that sensory response that like gut,
you don't feel it as much that that part
of your brain is actually quieter after
exercise.
Meditation does a similar thing,
but if there was just a way to get this
knowledge to,
to pay for people to understand people
that are adverse to exercising,
you know,
if there was just some way,
and I'm really trying to find a way
because there are many people that I
care about in my life that are that way
and that feel depressed and are on some
sort of know antidepressant,
which doesn't really work for them
still.
And so I'm trying to find a way.
I like how like I can tell them I'm
having this conversation with you and
you get it because you experience it,
you exercise,
you,
you know,
you eat healthy,
you experienced these things.
But for someone that's
never experienced it,
how do you communicate it to the.
It's so hard for people to start
anything new.
It's,
it's hard for people to start a pottery
class that's not gonna,
you know,
it's not going to be involved with any
physical pain or any stress or any
exhaustion.
There's no,
there's not that feeling that you get
when you're really tired,
you know,
the feeling that you get for me is
particularly difficult.
Doing boring stuff like on an elliptical
machine,
like elliptical machine to me.
Uh,
it's a great workout.
It's awesome if I'm at a gym because if
I go to a gym like at a hotel and you
know,
they have some bullshit weights and,
but they have an elliptical machine.
I go,
okay,
if this thing has a high setting,
I could get a real workout on this.
But those times when you're tired and
you don't want to do it,
they're so fucking boring.
It just,
you'd have to listen to something.
You have to watch something like others
stimuli has to come in,
in order to get you pumped up.
But I know this because I've done it a
thousand times,
for someone who hasn't done it a
you,
they get to that point like,
fuck this,
I'm out of here.
Oh my God,
let me get a donut.
You know,
give me a coffee.
I'm gonna.
Go outside and smoke a cigarette.
Woo.
I feel better,
you know,
and it's so hard to get past that
because we have all these connections in
our mind when it comes to comfort,
comfort and stress,
comfort and like our bodies for whatever
reason,
uh,
most people,
their associations are to avoid anything
that's uncomfortable.
But it's so illogical because when you
look at comfort and you look at success
and progress and the eventual,
the feelings of accomplishment and of
getting past certain hurdles and in
terms of like how you feel about life,
a lot of those are connected to
discomfort.
Discomfort is your friend.
It really is like discomfort and,
and not being happy and content with
certain situations in life or certain
feelings in life.
There are massive,
massive motivators and they're,
they're amazing at,
at facilitating change.
And yet our instinct is to avoid those
and just sit on the couch and watch some
fucking reality show about dudes and
make moonshine with our jaw open.
Like it's bizarre.
It is.
It's too much,
too much of that.
Like stimuli or where you don't have to
do anything and you can still like get,
get that sensory information.
The need to act like to need to actually
go out there and act is so strong.
It's such an important thing.
But yet we resisted many people.
I know you don't.
I don't,
but so many people do.
But I feel the thing,
you know,
I don't,
I don't allow it to work,
but I feel that fuck this,
I don't want to work out.
I feel it all the time.
Almost every time before I work out I
have at least an inclination of blow it
off.
I don't ever embrace it,
but it's there.
It's there with everybody.
Like no one is like completely 100
percent healthy and without any
resistance.
Yeah.
I wonder if also that has.
We're talking about this being a super
ager.
I wonder if there is some association.
There were,
you know,
where we're looking at,
we're looking at how it's important to
push past that uncomfortableness,
whether it's physical or mental and
that's linked to being a super ager,
but what if it's just like the ability
to make yourself do that is important
too,
right?
It's not just the act that you're doing,
it's not just the strenuous exercise,
which is obviously good and we know that
it's good from science,
but what if it's just being able to like
push yourself.
Like maybe some people don't have that
ability for whatever reason or they just
haven't tapped into it enough because I
haven't really experienced it.
I think that's it.
I think it's a learned thing,
you know,
because if I take time off,
like um,
I got sick recently and I couldn't work
out for like a week or six days or so,
and the,
the act of getting back into the gym,
I think a lot of ways we rely on
momentum.
We rely on the momentum of past
experiences where you're just
conditioned to do that.
It's one of the things that you do and
for me at least when I get,
when I would get like really disciplined
and really I get really consistent with
my workouts.
One of the things that I feel,
I almost feel momentum.
I feel like there's like a push behind
me.
Like,
all right,
we're,
you know,
like after I get out of the gym,
I have a really good workout.
I'm like,
yeah,
now I'm doing it.
I'm doing it all the time now and I'm
looking forward to the next time and it
makes that resistance much weaker and it
makes my motivation and my discipline
much stronger.
I think a lot of it is based on just the
consistency,
you know,
it's one of the things that I talked
about recently on the podcast.
I said,
you know,
blowing something off.
It's not just not good,
like blowing off of an exercise that you
planned is not just bad for you
physically.
It's also bad mentally because then that
option is now available.
The option to fuck off is available and
you did it before and you're probably
going to do it again and you'll get
mediocre results,
not just in that aspect of your life,
but maybe in all aspects of your life
because I think that option to fuck off
when you embrace it,
that is a pathway that you might choose
when it comes to dealing with conflict
and your personal life,
dealing with business decisions,
dealing with career decisions like an
uncomfortable decision that you might be
faced with where you,
maybe you need to make a change as far
as like what your pathway is in life,
but you don't do it instead you fuck
off.
And that the inclination to fuck off.
I think that gathers momentum as well.
The inclination to be disciplined.
That comes with momentum too.
And I think both things like you,
did you take a path,
the path of the healthy person or the
path of the fuck off,
like both of them are available and
whichever path you embrace.
Totally.
I,
I think that um,
the same thing goes for like lying to.
I mean when you,
I think it's very bad to lie,
like even if it's something that is
really benign,
like what they call it,
a little tiny white light.
Great.
Yeah.
That,
you know,
because then you start making these
neural connections in your brain and you
start to like get used to doing it.
Like you were saying and I think that it
just kind of dawned on me as you were
saying this,
that with the motivation and the
momentum you were talking about,
I think that's the same way.
I think you're like building these
neural pathways,
these motivation pathways and,
and that's really important for that
momentum to do it again and again,
you know,
there's been some studies,
a few of them that have been done where
you can take a person and do that direct
transcranial stimulation,
which I don't know much about,
but I remember these studies and
stimulate a certain part of the brain
that's involved in motivation and you
can motivate them to go to the gym.
So you motivate them to actually go work
out.
So that's good.
More of those electrodes and they put on
a specific area of the outside of your
head and then it's like a little nine
volt batteries attached to it and it
just zaps you a little bit,
saps you a little bit and like activates
a certain brain region and that brain
region.
It's activating specifically with this
study I was talking about actually
there's a couple of them were involved
in motivation and that's probably with
you and I.
We already have those pathways activated
because we are constantly forcing
ourselves to go.
I mean I feel the same way.
There are times I'm like,
God,
I don't want to go for a run.
Like once you do it,
God damn me feel great.
You feel great and you know what?
You accomplished something so it's not
only like you're feeling great from all
the neural mechanisms that are being
activated and all the biochemistry
that's going on,
but you've accomplished something.
You did.
You push past them and you didn't want
to do.
When you feel good about doing that
after magnetic
stimulation therapy,
Wilmington woman finds motivation.
Energy.
Yeah.
There's a a radio lab about this,
a radiolab podcast.
It's called nine volt nirvana and it
pretty good.
I liked it.
I love it.
I love radio lab and it actually deals
with the first story.
The opening story is amazing because it
deals with this woman who went to this
like sniper training,
simulation video,
video thing that they do where they.
They put you in front,
they give you like a fake gun and they
put you in front of a video screen and a
scenario plays out and then the scenario
there's like a terrorist attack and you
have to take out the bad guys and they
did it with her and she was.
It's 20 minutes long and she was
terrible.
She fucked it all up.
It was just like a disaster,
like she didn't respond correctly.
Then they put these electrodes,
what would you exactly call them?
One of those things.
It's electrodes,
so they put these on her brain in the or
on the outside of her head in very
specific areas and stimulated it and
then recreated it and in the recreation
she was 100 percent effective.
She killed all the bad guys and she went
through this 20 thing and when it was
over,
when they told her that it was over,
she thought they were fucking with her
because she thought it was only two
minutes.
Like,
yeah,
like every is incredible.
It's amazing the way she describes it as
amazing.
It's amazing.
It's a little scary too.
Um,
just because,
I mean it's like,
can you like program someone to do
something?
There's another study that was published
like two years ago,
same thing,
trans cranial direct stimulation and um,
I,
I liked him,
so not an expert on any of this,
but I just remember this study because
it was trying to investigate what part
of the brain's fault in consciousness.
Right.
And so she said that the study was
designed in such a way where she was
reading a book and then they zapped or
in a certain part of the brain and she
stopped reading the book,
this woman and just looked at them like
a Zombie,
like no,
nothing,
no talk,
no.
And then they zapped your again and she
started right.
She picked up right where she left off.
I have no recollection at all of doing.
So this was like,
you know,
trying to figure out if this part of the
brain is involved in consciousness.
Anyways,
that was a little scary.
Well that's.
Yeah,
that is
real concern,
right?
Because one of the things about this
transcranial direct stimulation of
Radiolab podcast was that they talked
about how many people are out there just
fucking experimenting where there's a
whole community online where people are
talking about like experimenting with
the voltages and experimenting with the
placement and one guy did something is
lost his sense of taste like,
but people are buying these and like
doing it like you can go.
It's like you'd go to fucking radio lab.
The consequences of a world where anyone
with $20 in access to radio shack and
make their own brains Zapper.
Yeah.
That is,
is that from radiolab?
They're their podcast page.
Wow.
It's amazing because there's apparently
this gigantic community of it like,
hold on a second,
go back up there and make that larger
again.
The last couple of years.
Itd tdcs,
trans direct cranial stimulation has
been all over the news.
Researchers claim that juicing the brain
with just 2 million amps,
nine volt,
but think nine volt battery battery can
help with everything from learning
languages to quitting smoking,
to overcoming depression.
And so they brought it into a
neuroscientist,
Michael Weiss and at Wright State
Research Institute into the studio to
tell them how it works.
Really interesting.
Very interesting.
I,
you know,
I feel like in terms of like treating
depression or helping people get
motivated to go to the gym,
it may really have relevance,
but it also might be like slapping a
supercharger on an old chevy
below the fucking engine on the thing.
You know,
it's true.
It's true.
I mean,
you don't really,
you don't,
we don't really know enough about what's
going.
I certainly wouldn't be experimenting
with that.
Amen.
Now let's do it.
Fuck it.
I'm thinking about going to radio shack
radio shack right after I get outta
here.
Not really,
but sort of.
I mean,
it's just interesting.
It's,
uh,
it's,
it's amazing that we are really some
sort of a system and you can choose that
system like electricity here,
a little vitamin,
they're,
you know,
a little,
um,
Broccoli sprouts here.
It's like,
that's the weirdest thing about people
and one of the weirdest things about
people is how variable we are depending
upon what we put inside of us.
And we don't think of it that way.
Most of the time we think of ourselves
as ourselves.
You know,
I'm sure you think of yourself as Rhonda
Patrick,
but Rhonda Patrick relies on a bunch of
fucking chemicals to be Rhonda Patrick,
right?
I mean,
there's a lot of stuff going on in
there.
It's not just,
it's not this one like this is a laptop,
you know,
I'm not adding shit to this thing.
Like I can put programs in it and stuff.
But I mean this is the,
everything in there.
It's kind of worked out.
You know,
there's a processor,
there's a motherboard,
it's all the,
all this junk is in place and the
electricity plugs into the back and it's
not really variable.
You know,
the,
the human body.
So fucking variable and pliable and
malleable.
There's so many different things that
you can do to make yourself better.
Like I had this conversation with a
friend of mine who's a not a physical
fitness guy and he's kind of a realist
and nihilist,
I guess you would say.
I never say that word.
I just read it and he's,
you know,
he's a little bit of a curmudgeon and
he's like,
yeah,
what's the point?
You know,
like really what is appointment?
You're always doing all his martial arts
and exercise.
I go,
okay,
if I could give you a pill and that pill
would turn you essentially into a super
person,
like you can do shit that you can't do
now.
You could lift weights,
you can't lift,
you could beat people up,
you could do physical fitness fits feats
that,
you know what you right now are totally
insurmountable and outside the realm of
possibility which take that pill.
So,
so,
so simple.
And he goes,
no,
I wouldn't go.
You wouldn't?
Okay.
Um,
if I could give you a pill that would
prevent you from being a decaying old
man and you could stay in the state you
are right now,
would you take that?
He's like,
yeah,
I probably would take that.
I go,
well that's how it feels like to me.
Motherfucker.
Like that's how it feels like to me.
Like you're a decaying old man,
you know,
like he's not much.
I think he's a year older than me,
but he looks like he's 50 years old.
I mean he made his body's all humped,
he's cute legs go ponch it doesn't have
any muscle tone.
And I'm like,
dude,
all of that is just physical fitness.
Like you're not broken.
Like there's nothing wrong with you.
But if you got on like a steady yoga
routine and started doing some
resistance training and started maybe
swimming or something like that a year
from now,
you would have a completely different
body,
you know?
And so talking to me,
I'm like,
I've done it my whole life.
So like stuff that I can do stuff that
you don't think is possible.
And to me it's like two times a week,
three times a week I do that stuff like,
this is not like your body is like a
race car that you can juice up yourself.
Like you can add the fat tires,
you can add the improved suspension,
you can beef up the horsepower in the
engine,
you could do all that yourself.
Or You could just choose to have this
shitty body that's always fallen apart
on you.
Right?
I mean you're,
you and I are both choosing to do as you
know,
we're,
we're both kind of obsessed with
nutrition and aging and being,
you know,
as,
as optimal as we can in terms of our
health.
But ultimately what we are doing is
delaying the aging process by switching
on all these switches and like,
you know,
exercise and getting all the
micronutrients and avoiding the refined
sugar which is causing inflammation and,
and all that stuff.
And it's really because that stuff is
part of the aging process and it
accelerates the aging process.
You know,
where I don't think people that don't do
this stuff realize that it's like,
it's not just about looking good,
it's about aging.
It's about like being older and being
fit and being mentally sharp and not
being degenerate and decrepit and how.
I mean,
how awful would that be?
It'd be like 60,
which is young.
I mean 60 is still young and to be like,
you know,
yeah.
Broken,
which is really common.
It's super common,
especially for sedentary people.
Exactly.
It's under Ip.
Most sedentary people are people that
also choose to eat terrible diets,
so it's like not only are they
sedentary,
they're also eating crappy food and not
getting all the nutrients they need.
So it's just like this mega explosion,
dynamite of just bad
increasing inflammation.
I think intelligent people like my
friend,
he is intelligent and I think he
connects vanity with those things and he
thinks vanities for fools and he thinks
it's a,
it's a trait that he finds
reprehensible.
He just doesn't like it.
He sees people that are,
you know,
whatever.
Maybe it's flashy clothes,
maybe it's the way they wear their hair,
whatever it is he thinks is
preposterous.
He connects that with physical fitness.
I'm like,
man,
but it's your vehicle and it's like how
you get through this life and it's how
you think it's,
it's,
it's so many different things that are
all connected into one super organism,
which is the life that you're living.
It's,
it's,
you know,
I mean,
I think everybody knows now.
I mean it's not something we grew up
knowing,
but everybody knows now about your gut
biome.
This is a really huge factor in how you
exist as an organism or as maybe even an
organism is the wrong word because we're
essentially ecosystems,
you know,
and we're,
we're in charge.
This weird consciousness that has all
this resistance and has all this
inclination towards comfort and fucking
off and blowing things off is what is in
charge of making all these things happen
that keep this ecosystem healthy.
It's almost like if earth itself had
like a shitty manager,
you know,
if like there was a manager of a natural
manager of earth that was like,
Oh God,
who cares if it rains?
you know,
like,
let's let you know I'm,
I'm going to stop growing things.
I don't give a shit anymore.
It's all stupid anyway.
I mean it's literally like the,
the,
just blow it out.
Fuck it.
Let's just kill all the life.
It's all going to die eventually.
I mean,
the sun only lasts 7 billion years and
see that is the perspective a lot of
people take with aging where it's like,
well,
you're going to die.
You're going to age.
You can't stop aging.
And it's like,
yes,
you're right.
But that's not the point.
The point is to age better.
Like that's the point.
The point is to increase your health
span,
you know?
And that is,
we know is possible.
Like that can be.
There's some,
there's some of these centenarians and
Supercentenarians I've seen that are
like in,
you know,
over 100 years old and they're like
riding bikes and racing and it's like
they're old.
They are very old.
They're experiencing a very good quality
of life and experiencing a quality of
life that these other people that don't
exercise feel.
They physically feel their own body
diminishing and they just feel it's
inevitable.
It's just,
it is what it is.
You're wasting your time.
You're out there running around,
but no we're not because this experience
right now,
it's not like no one's under the
illusion that you're gonna live forever,
but you are enhancing the experience
that you're currently involved in right
now and you are alive.
You are alive.
You do experience this life,
but do you experience this life
optimally?
Is it,
is it as enjoyable as it can be?
And we all know that there's a spectrum
for that.
Enjoyability like we've all had times in
our life where it's not been so great
and then times in a life where
everything came together like what a
fucking great day,
Woo.
Like make more of those,
like you could make more of those and
then the whole things better.
And I think when that whole thing is
better,
it affects everybody.
You touch everybody that's around you,
everybody you come in contact with and
that in turn,
I mean it sounds so grandiose,
but in turn can affect the entire race
of human beings.
I agree.
Totally.
Totally agree.
And I love the way you put it about like
the feeling good.
It's not just about,
you know,
staving off cancer,
it's not just about what's going to
happen 20,
30 years from now.
It's about now it's about not being
depressed.
We know that,
you know,
it's about feeling better.
It's about being smarter,
it's about having more executive
function,
having more longterm planning,
less emotional Amygdala,
you know,
anxiety that is like right here,
right now that is happening.
That is so,
you know,
it's not just longterm effects which you
also are,
you know,
also effecting which is very good.
So it's like a win win.
You're not just affecting the future.
You're affecting right now how you feel,
how you perform,
you know,
it's,
yeah,
it's an important concept that I
continue to try to get across to people
and it also will optimize everything
else you do,
whether it's creative pursuits,
whether it's relationships that you get
into.
A lot of those things are predicated on
how you feel as you enter them,
how you feel when you participate in
them and you can enhance,
you can
enhance that.
And I mean,
there's a weird thing that people do
where they want to pretend they're not
trying to do better.
You know,
I'm fine.
Everything's great.
Like it's not,
that's not true.
You're,
you're,
you're putting out effort.
It's a matter of you.
You have a mindset or you have a
connection in your brain with putting
out more effort and connecting that to
discomfort and that connecting things to
discomfort.
Have you ever,
um,
Steven Pressfield has a book called the
war of art have brought up in this
podcast a million times.
I actually have a copy of it.
I'll give it to you afterwards because I
bought like 50 copies of it.
I handed it,
I handed out to people,
it's great and he's been on this podcast
before and his book is essentially
mostly about the creative pursuit and
it's about resistance that people feel
when you know you should write or you
know you should paint or whatever it
used to sculpt whatever these things are
that you pursue and that there's this
thing that comes up that tries to keep
you from doing that,
this resistance,
and he's like,
this is a battle that you will fight for
the rest of your life.
But the key is to fight it,
not to give in,
don't give in to that resistance to
fight,
just to fight that resistance and in
doing so everyday you do so you have won
the battle for that day and you will
continue to fight that battle.
And if you continue to fight that battle
with that same mindset,
you will win.
And this is a guy that like up until the
time he was 40 years old,
he was basically a loser.
He wasn't doing well.
It was like a failed writer.
And then he kind of just figured it out
and got his shit together and then wrote
books about it and now he's a really
accomplished author and it's a,
it's an amazing story and he's a really
cool guy too.
I had them on for a podcast and you
know,
in his enthusiasm and the way he
approaches it in this book because it's
very pragmatic,
like you can see the steps and he left.
He lays it all out in a way that's very
easy to digest.
Awesome.
Yeah,
I'd love to read it.
I mean,
I,
I think that's something that's a very
important part of,
um,
of the human experience is pushing past
that resistance to whatever.
And,
and you're right,
it,
once you do it,
you get better at it next time too.
I mean,
it's still there,
but you,
you do get better at it next time.
There's also a problem.
I think that what it comes up when you
and I are doing these podcasts where
there's so much data,
there is so much to take in.
I mean we have done how many podcasts
now?
Like sixth or seventh?
One a lot and every one of them is three
hours of like,
what the fuck,
how does she know all this?
And just notebooks,
like when I put it up on twitter,
you know,
the,
that you're going to be here.
Everybody's like,
get your notebook out.
And I mean,
that's like the number one response in
the comments.
That's awesome.
Yeah.
Cool.
There's a lot of stuff that I,
I enjoy learning,
you know,
so it's something that I like to learn
about,
um,
things that can make me better or things
that can make other people better
mentally,
physically healthy,
aging and all that.
So I like to
share that with,
with people.
Have you heard of this?
Um,
we're talking about an aging pill and it
kind of came into my mind when you were
talking about giving your friend that if
you could take a pill I could,
you know,
delay the way you age or make you live.
You no longer are better.
Um,
have you heard of like nicotinamide
riboside or Nicotinamide Adenine?
Dinucleotide not at all.
Not at all.
No.
Oh Wow.
It's like,
it's kind of like,
I guess it's maybe it's not made its way
into the popular media media as much as
I thought,
but it's definitely blown up in the
science.
So,
um,
there's,
it's so nicotinamide riboside and
nicotine,
my model nucleotide there,
they're like precursor forums to vitamin
B three and in the body they get
converted into something called Nad.
And Nad is something that you absolutely
have your mitochondria which make energy
have to have to make energy.
Like you can't oxidize fat,
fatty acids,
you can't oxidize glucose,
you can't make energy from any of the
food you eat without an because your
mitochondria and need it to make the
energy.
So it's very important for your
mitochondria to function,
to make energy.
But also,
um,
it's very important.
It's like the levels of Nad always rise.
Like when you're fasting in between
meals.
So like between breakfast and lunch or
breakfast and dinner,
whatever your nad levels go up like
slowly after a meal and during the
fasting state and also when you
exercise.
So the levels of Nad will,
will,
will go up somewhat.
But I'm the,
so these are precursors to Nad,
right?
I'm telling you this because this is
kind of the studies that have been done.
All the mechanisms go back to this
forming nad nad is something that
decreases with age.
Um,
it's something that,
you know,
it's just,
it's very important for aging.
Anytime you're inflamed,
all the nad gets sucked,
sucked up into that inflammation because
your energy to,
you know,
energy,
it requires energy to like have your
immune cells to be activated and
fighting off whatever they think they're
fighting off whether or not it's refined
sugar or actual infection,
but,
um,
DNA damage,
sex it up.
So it's like,
you know,
it's,
it's basically a limiting factor in a
lot of ways.
So there's been all these studies over
the past,
I don't know,
I'd say like six years,
probably now,
five or six years where various
scientists are,
have been,
um,
feeding mice.
You know,
this nick attendant,
my driver's side or nicotine mind
monitor nucleotide,
and they're finding that,
you know,
for example,
if you feed them nicotine and wide
mononuclear nucleotide,
um,
it delays aging in their liver and their
bones in their eyes,
their muscle.
I'm there.
So it's basically like their tissues are
aging better,
they have enhanced endurance,
they have a better mitochondrial
function and these are doses like human
equivalent dose to like 24 milligrams
per kilogram body weight per day,
which could be a lot if you weigh a lot,
but I'm showing that it improves
mitochondrial function and nicotine
riboside which gets converted into
nicotinamide Adenine dinucleotide.
It's kind of confusing on it just
anyways.
Lots of studies on that.
Showing that it like if you give it to
mice that have some sort of
mitochondrial defect in their muscles,
all atrophying,
a Co completely reverses that.
Their muscles are like they're making
lots of Mitochondria and they're
improves muscle function and enhanced
performance anyways.
Like you get the idea like lots and lots
of animal studies.
Recently there's been a human clinical
trial done with nicotinamide riboside
and that just to show that it's safe and
that it actually does increase nad
levels in,
in human blood,
which it does,
um,
even even as low as a 100 milligrams
dose a day and this is a supplement that
people can buy.
So the nicotine in my mano,
nucleotide is not,
that's found in Broccoli.
Broccoli's really high in it.
Cucumbers are really high in it.
Cabbage is high and in May,
but nicotine might arrive aside which
gets converted into that which
eventually makes its way to nad is,
it is a supplement.
So a few scientists actually,
um,
some big name scientist in the aging
field,
like linen warranty and a couple of
others have started a supplement company
called a Elisia.
Come to me,
me that pad,
I've,
I forgot to put a pad over here.
I've got to write that down.
Thank you.
Yeah.
And so it's called a lease iom and it
has nicotine in them.
Like the Matt Damon Movie.
Yeah.
E L Y S I,
u m.
Oh look at this.
They have it.
So it has nicotine in my and by the way,
I know it's affiliation.
I don't have any affiliation with any,
a supplement company.
What is the company?
I think it's a company called the
company's called Lisa.
Whereas the supplements,
the supplements called Elysium.
But how do you spell the actual
nicotinamide?
Nicotinamide,
and I see a nick o,
t I n a,
m I d e right beside R I b o s I d e.
yeah.
So it's interesting.
It's also there's another company I
think thorne makes makes one.
I'm with it in it,
but born.
Yeah.
Thorn.
The thing that's interesting about the
Elysium though that I found,
because I started looking into this,
I've met lenny warranty.
He's the guy who um,
who,
whose lab the whole pathway that Rivera
trawl Axon was discovered that act.
So Nad switches on this whole,
like genetic pathway,
that's like anti aging and it just
changes all these epigenetic factors.
Okay.
Without getting into all the details and
like boring people to death,
it's like it actually,
it's basically nad levels rise that acts
as a switch.
This rises Nad levels.
So this is a supplement that's rising
nad levels,
but what's interesting about the
illicium is that it has something in it
called terrorists still being Charles
still being is found in blueberries and
blueberries is probably the one of the
best sources of it.
But what was so interesting,
I was trying to figure out like why are
they putting,
trying to figure out why they're putting
terrell still being with the
nicotinamide riboside because
nicotinamide riboside is affecting nad
it's affecting mitochondrial biogenesis,
which it's been shown to increase
mitochondrial biogenesis.
Like I said,
these mice and mice,
you know,
we're,
we're um,
we're performing like 42 percent better
at different endurance activities after
being supplemented with this.
So that's insane.
Yeah.
It's.
But they're giving a lot like the 32 to
24 to 32 milligrams per kilogram body
weight.
It would be the human equivalent dose.
So you know,
figure that out.
That's a lot.
That's probably like four grams a day or
something like that.
Right.
For like a 160 or 80 pound person,
something like that.
I don't know.
Anyways,
the Terrell still beans interesting
because,
well,
in and of itself,
it's interesting because it's actually,
it's chemically similar to raspberry
trawl and um,
but it's four times more bioavailable
than was trial and it actually has been
compared side by side in mouse studies
to like to a different mouse studies
that I've looked at cognitive function
and it's better at improving cognitive
function in animals.
Then risperidol is largely because it's
four times more bioavailable.
Uh,
so anyways,
I was like,
well,
I don't know if that's why they're doing
it because it's not affecting the same
pathway.
But then I came across something really
interesting in that is I'm terrible
still being actually has been shown.
Again,
this is an animal study to increase the
type of bacteria in the gut that causes
the,
um,
conversion of certain compounds,
Alijah Tannins,
which are found in berries and some
nuts,
but really high and pomegranate Alijah
tannins get converted into something
called teros still,
I mean called,
um,
your,
uh,
within a by your gut bacteria,
which is what pterostilbene is
increasing that gut bacteria.
So Tara soybeans actually increasing the
production of your urine within a from
berries that are having this other
compound.
You're in a.
What that does is this has been shown
also in other studies.
It causes my defeat Mito faigy or my
topic g,
which is the clearing away of damaged
mitochondria a.
So you're basically clearing away
damaged mitochondria like they eat
themselves.
So faigy would be eating itself,
kind of like [inaudible] or [inaudible]
as it's called,
which is a self sort of a damaged cell
that gets cleared away and eats itself.
That happens a lot during the fasting
state.
Well,
this Mito faigy is doing it specifically
for Mitochondria and this the reason why
this is so cool and I'm going to try to
not bore you,
but I can go on and on.
I said,
I'm worried about.
The reason this is so cool is because.
So you know,
Mitochondria are very important for the
way we age.
It's not just muscle function,
brain function.
They're providing energy for everything
like period,
like your mitochondrial decay,
you decay.
That's the way it is like period.
So their mitochondria as you are aging,
they're decaying,
they're getting damaged and all this
stuff.
Well,
they have this whole repair system where
you,
where you have,
um,
lots of Mitochondria inside one cell,
let's say you have one damage,
Mitochondria and one healthy.
What they do is they fuse together,
exchange all their content and fizz back
apart.
So they were kind of like repair each
other.
So you have a healthy one,
a damaged one.
The healthy one kind of mixes with the
unhealthy one.
And then you have to healthyish ones,
right?
So this is happening constantly inside
every cell.
If you ever,
if you look at the Mitochondria,
it's never like you never see
Mitochondria by themselves are always
like,
like a network.
Like they look like Vermicelli Spaghetti
because they're constantly doing this.
Well,
if you clear away the damaged ones and
you increase mitochondrial biogenesis
with nicotinamide riboside.
So not only are you getting rid of the
damaged pool,
you're now creating new ones that are
like brand new,
healthy,
young brimming,
young mitochondria like you had when
you're a young person,
young child.
So now your,
your,
your pool that you're mixing with,
it's like not mitochondrial biogenesis
is good in and of itself because you're
making new mitochondria,
but having damaged one still around can
still dilute the pool out,
you know,
it's still diluted.
So if you get clear out those damaged
ones and you're making new ones,
it's kind of like boom,
you're going to get like young new
mitochondria.
So I think that possibly is a,
another reason why they combine those.
I mean it's completely speculation.
I'm just.
But anyways,
he learned some cool shit about
terrorists.
You're lifting A.
Yeah,
my might've age is a very interesting
thing,
you know,
exercise to some degree it can increase
it.
Fasting does.
And why does fasting increases?
Um,
when you're fasting,
you,
you try to.
So Nad levels rise,
you try to,
to conserve some of your energy.
And the way you do that is by eating
different Organelles,
eating,
eating the cell itself,
which can then provide energy for other
cells.
So you.
So usually what happens is fasting will
selectively get rid of some of those
damaged cells are damaged Mitochondria.
So that,
that happens during,
during the fasting.
Does that make sense when you.
Yeah,
so it's interesting though that the body
manages it so well that it goes after
the damaged ones before I know it's,
it's,
well,
there's lots of like molecular
mechanisms that have been,
you know,
figured out why that is.
And that's because the damage one there,
their mitochondrial membrane potentials
like different and it's just,
it's all this complicated stuff,
but it's like,
it all works out perfectly where it's
like these,
these,
these enzymes that like targeted to,
to,
to um,
know,
to basically become,
um,
to undergo Mito faigy.
It's like they recognize this certain
one with a lower membrane potential
which happens to be more of a damaged
mitochondria and it's just kinda like,
it's kind of beautiful how it just all
works out that way,
you know?
Um,
what was I going to say?
I completely like was going to say I
lost my train of thought there.
But um,
yeah.
So anyways,
the fact that you can like,
have new mitochondria is like pretty.
I mean,
that's Kinda like the big thing with,
with aging and it's been that for a long
time is like young new mitochondria.
I know you're probably aware of this
study,
but they injected old mice with the
blood
of young mice and they found that the
old mice started behaving more lively
and then they did the reverse.
They injected the young mice with the
blood of old mice and the mice struggled
and,
and deteriorated and now there's some
crazy new startup were for was like
eight grand.
They fill you up with a blood of young
people.
Okay.
I'm glad you mentioned that recently.
Actually.
I know Peter Teal,
the paypal.
Yes,
he does that.
He's he.
He's the guy that he's.
He's on trump's board now,
isn't he?
Yeah.
He's like one of the first people that
trump hired,
which is fascinating.
So fascinating.
Yeah.
Yeah,
he does.
He's talked about how he's like,
he gets blood injections.
Okay.
So here's,
what has he said about it?
I don't remember exactly what,
just that.
I don't think he said anything about
whether it's doing anything,
but I think let's just start showing up
younger.
Well,
now he's got a snapchat filter on.
here's the thing that was really
interesting about this whole thing
because I've been following this field
for awhile too,
because I find it very interesting for
multiple reasons.
One,
it's like it could be applicable,
right?
I mean easily,
but various look at him.
Look,
looks young as fuck.
He's nine years old.
Wants inject himself with young people's
blood or is doing it.
Trump delegate and gawker bankrupt or.
Oh yeah,
he's the guy who,
he,
he financed whole cogans attack on
Gawker because gawker outed him as
being.
Did they outed him as gay or they
attacked him and they,
they got really shitty with him and you
know,
he's a fucking billionaire.
So he went off and um,
thank you for turning off your ad
blocker.
Enjoy the Forbes ad light experience.
Flutter off Nick Denton files for
personal bankruptcy.
Yeah,
he,
uh,
he went after that guy because of it.
Yeah.
Um,
so when you go back to the other
article,
I want to change the articles there.
Um,
so what he's doing a given fields
obsession with warding off death.
It comes as no surprise to silicon
valley billionaire is interested in
lease one radical way of doing it,
injecting himself with a young person's
blood.
Wow.
INC magazine published part of a year
old interview with thiel and which the
venture capitalists explains that he's
interested in power of biosis twist
called,
which includes the practice of getting
transfusions of blood from a younger
person as a means of improving health
and potentially reversing aging.
Said,
I'm looking into this stuff.
I think it's really interesting.
Blah,
blah,
blah.
It's unclear whether the 48 year old
entrepreneur is currently receiving.
Guaranteed you is,
um,
reports that are fuel capital employee.
Actually the personal health director
has a personal health director,
personal health director to Peter Thiel.
That's hilarious.
That's what you do when you're all
baller.
I'm going to get a personal health
director is the same company.
Ambrosia LLC.
This is the one that we were talking
about the other day.
Yeah.
Interesting.
So this is actually happening.
Says thiel spends $40,000
per quarter per quarter to get an
infusion of blood from an 18 year old
based on research conducted at Stanford
on extending the lives of mice.
So he's got one fucking 18 year old that
he's vampiress one kid.
He's given them beats and Broccoli
sprouts and making them run up hills.
That's what you would have to hope that
kids not doing meth,
you know,
like he's got this 18 year old.
All these biomarkers in the blood,
I would imagine.
Yeah,
because you have to make sure.
I mean,
that's so weird.
We're going to farm off young people
and.
Oh Wow.
That is so crazy.
He's given $6,000,000
to biomedical.
Jen,
gerontologist,
traumatologists all opry to gray.
That crazy fucker.
I had him on it.
I had him on my podcast too.
Yeah,
he's interesting.
But he drinks.
He boozes like every night.
He was like three in strong at 11 in the
morning when I walked into his office.
He.
Yeah,
that's what I was saying when I was
hanging out with them.
He's like,
well,
he,
he's basing all of.
He's putting all of his eggs in the
basket of science.
He thinks that science and things like
with Peter thiels doing it's going to be
able to mitigate all this stuff that
he's doing,
but I'm like,
dude,
you're fucking stuck in a position where
it's like,
okay,
they can delay the aging,
but like you're stuck like now,
okay,
you can't make you like 18,
but we can stop you from dying,
but you know,
so it's like,
that's possible.
So He's going to be stuck.
Like,
well,
he also does an exercise.
I found him to be perplexing.
I really enjoyed talking to him,
but I found him to be quite perplexing
because of the booze and because of the
lack of exercise and his big fucking
crazy gandalf beard.
Like what's going on with you?
Dude?
There's a lot going on here and like
this is.
There's a lot,
a lot of image here,
you know,
disagree on a lot of nutrition.
Oh well hold on a second,
let me talk about that.
But in some say that the pay to
participate study with the potential to
collect up to four point 8 million from
as many as 600 participants as mounts to
a scam.
What certain is,
it's based on some intriguing if
inconclusive science,
a car,
maisie in a 32 year old Princeton
graduate and competitive rower said he
was inspired by studies on mice.
That research it's sewn together with
their veins conjoined in a procedure
called Para biosis.
Okay.
That's what we're talking about.
That study about mice.
So what did you guys disagree with?
Um,
well,
just the role that nutrition plays in
aging.
So he didn't think it was a big role.
We didn't think it was a big race.
He's boozing.
Yeah,
it in.
He's not working out.
I mean,
how can you ignore all the science on
the positive benefits of exercise and
nutrition?
Oh,
there's lots of studies showing that
that diet and lifestyle,
you know,
have a huge impact on,
on aging.
I mean,
just one more thing about this pair
biosis there because it's kind of.
People were thinking that it was the
young.
There was something in the young blood
that was,
um,
present the 11 that it just said on the
screen.
That was actually 11.
What does that,
right,
it's a growth factor.
11.
Yeah.
So it was thought that this was what was
responsible for rejuvenating tissues and
growing new brain cells because that's
what happened when you gave it to the,
um,
older mice.
But then other studies started to come
out also out of Stanford showing that in
fact,
it may not be something that's in the
young blood,
but something that's in the old blood
that's actually causing the aging,
something called a v Cam,
one that starts to,
you start to make it as you're getting
older and it causes inflammation in the
brain and starts messing up things.
So there was a recent study that just
came out and show that if you like,
make an antibody against that v Cam one
and prevent it from doing its action.
It's like you can stop that from
happening.
So anyways,
there's a lot to be figured out,
body that they're currently working on.
They're trying to make some kind of
some,
some something that you can take God
damn solution that was going to be
weird.
It's going to be weird if you see like
old people become young,
it's not going to be weird if people
don't get any older will be kind of
weird.
But like if I came,
I ran into you like 20 years from now
I'm like Damn Rhonda,
you exactly the same.
It will be cool,
but it wouldn't freak me out.
What would freak me out of Arnold
Schwartzenegger started looking like it
was when he was 20 again.
Like that would freak me out.
Like if we start seeing the change in
the process,
we started seeing things reverse,
not just halt or slow down,
which we kind of have seen with like
really healthy people.
Like some people know,
some people kind of defy aging least to
a certain extent.
Like Tom Cruise is a perfect example.
I want to know what they're filling that
dude up with.
Who else?
I think who I was thinking that defied
aging like famous wise,
Keanu reeves.
I feel like that guys look the same for
like a long time.
Yeah.
And he's in his fifties now.
He looks great.
He looks great and I think he smokes
too.
Yeah,
no,
yes.
Yeah.
So that's,
that's just show you.
He's got some kind of like genetic there
are.
There definitely are Tom Cruise 1983,
2014.
They're injecting him with some kind of
young fluid.
No,
I'm sorry.
I'm,
I mean look,
he's got fucking ungodly sums of money
and that's part of a part of the issue,
you know,
I mean they've uh,
they that you can definitely do things
with money that badge and make you look
younger.
Trying to figure out what surgery wise
and stuff.
I don't think he's doing surgery though.
No,
no.
Well I don't.
One of the things that they think is a.
What does that picture up above?
What's that one with the shirt off?
One up there.
Is that him working out of there?
See that chose aging.
So one on the right,
like he's got substantially less tone to
his muscles,
but that could just be.
He's been busy.
Says the maverick days are over,
hold on,
go back.
What does that say?
Is it from 1986 to right on the set
yesterday?
So yeah,
that's also that there's not that much
of a variability there that could easily
be,
just hasn't been working out as hard.
I mean when you're on a movie set,
you're working 15,
16 hours a day sometimes.
Especially these gigantic big budget
budget blockbusters where you're,
you know,
involved in these crazy stunts and all
that stuff.
So interesting.
Yeah.
Um,
but you know,
back to this like diet aging thing that
like Aubrey and I just read on,
I mean it's,
it's so,
it's so weird that someone that's he's
familiar with the aging literature
would,
would disagree with,
with some of the science out there.
Like there's been studies looking at,
for example,
people that have like 1:12
ounce can of like sugar water or sugar
soda,
some kind of sugary drink a day.
They have,
if you look at them,
their telomeres in their white blood
cells.
So telomeres are a biomarker for aging.
When you look at their team number link,
their telomeres are shorter compared to
people that don't have that soda every
day and that corresponds to like four
point six years of biological aging.
I mean that's like someone that's the
same exact age as you,
but has a team member that looks,
you know,
either five years older,
younger,
same.
Yeah.
It's totally insane.
All,
all based off of like this refined sugar
soda.
I wonder if it's all a personal thing
with him because he knows that he's not
addressing that and his own life.
Maybe that's why he's decided to put up
these blinders and ignore the science.
Well,
I think also he's interested in
extending lifespan to like a massive
point.
Sugary soft drinks may be linked to
accelerate a DNA aging study.
So he's.
I mean,
like I said,
he's putting all his eggs in the basket
of science just of who knows.
I mean there's,
it's,
it's kind of interesting that he is
doing that though because he will
concentrate very heavily on that.
And again,
when you were talking about all this
nutrition and exercise,
the benefits of it like,
God,
there's so much to study,
there's so much that it maybe his,
maybe his desire to shoe that and go
straight to the science of it only and
talk about genetic manipulation and all
these other different variables.
Like maybe,
maybe there's something to that.
Maybe you really can't spend enough time
in both fields.
Totally.
Yeah,
I think that makes sense.
And I,
and I do think that there's hope for,
you know,
things like genetic engineering and stem
cell therapies that will help tune
humans up eventually.
And that will make a big difference in.
Have I talked to you about my stem cell
experiments?
No.
Okay.
I have been getting stem cell shots.
I got them for an injured shoulder to
shoulder that.
Um,
I had a rotator cuff tear,
biceps tendon tear and labral tear in my
shoulder and it was most likely had been
dislocated before and I didn't know
which is just the side effects of years
of doing difficult stuff with your.
Especially Jujitsu.
Jujitsu is all about joint manipulations
and joint locks.
And Chokes and grappling and there's a
lot of,
just a lot of damage that your body goes
through.
Everybody and I know that does Jujitsu
at a certain point in time either has to
get some form of surgery or has some
pretty significant injuries that they
have to work around.
went to a doctor that was like,
well,
you probably have to get surgery,
like this is gonna if,
if not now,
sometime really soon because every time
I would work out and we get really sore
and I'd have to ice it afterwards,
I get these shots and they're doing them
from the,
they're extracting the stem cells from
women's placenta and they take the stem
cells and then they shoot them into the
area where you have the injury and the
results are fucking freakish.
You heal like wolverine.
I mean it's really bizarre.
And now this same shoulder that I had,
you know,
like a real problem with,
I was worried about needing surgery.
I do 90 pound presses with kettlebells
with one shoulder and it's not,
have no pain,
no pain,
no discomfort.
It's not bothering me at all and it's,
it's unbelievable how much strength and
function that the shoulder has now.
That's really cool.
I didn't realize they were doing that
with placental stem cells.
Placental stem cells are like,
kind of like a goldmine because they,
um,
they possess a tap of stem cell called
multiphoton stem cell,
which is able to form multiple different
types of cartilage cells that form
cartilage cells that form bone,
even cells that form neurons,
so they're able to form lots of
different types of cells.
Um,
and usually placenta just like thrown
away.
So that's kind of cool that they're,
I guess there's companies that are
freezing them down and I'm finding
donors that match.
Yeah.
Let me tell you the name of the company.
So people who are listening,
it's in the.
My doctor's name is Dr Roddy Mcgee and
he's in Las Vegas and the company is a
listed here.
That's good.
I've got it on my instagram and my pen
ready here to let me know.
I won't let you down.
Just give me a second.
I'll scroll through my instagram and
I'll find him because it wasn't that
long ago that I was there,
but,
um,
I,
uh,
I posted something about it on
Instagram,
but I am a,
I'm a believer in it and I've had some
friends,
my friend John Dudley who's an archer,
was experiencing a tendinitis in one of
his elbows for a long time.
I mean he had it and it was something
that he had been working through for
quite a few years and he had one stem
cell shot and within two weeks the pain
was completely gone.
It was just,
yeah,
it's freaky what they're able to do.
I'm fine to get stem cell therapies.
I mean,
that's something that I'm extremely
excited about for the future.
But have you ever tried a hydrolyzed
collagen powder or like bone broth?
Yes,
I drink bone broth every morning.
I love them.
So,
um,
that,
that's another thing like,
because I,
I've been getting into the bone broth,
but I was doing hydraulic add,
hydrolyzed collagen powder to like my
coffee in the morning and also my
smoothies.
Then what does that do?
Well,
it's this,
it's just like a,
it's got a lot of the same things.
Is Bone broth bone broth?
Probably actually even better because it
has more stuff,
but it's been shown in animal studies.
If you take the hydrolyzed collagen
powder and like radio label it so you
can follow where it goes and an animal.
It goes right to the cartilage in the
joints and ligaments.
Um,
I used it.
It has helped me heal like injured
wrist,
you know,
obviously like my injuries are like way,
way,
like less magnitude and something that
you're experiencing in your shoulder.
It is a total sports medicine in Vegas.
That's the name of the company that,
that.
Does this stem cell injections or that.
What about the company that you applied?
Biologics.
It's called a flow graft.
Amniotic fluid therapy,
that's what they're calling it a,
but it's total sports medicine in Las
Vegas.
That's where I got the stem.
So biologics,
is that the company that freezes the
Placenta?
Yes.
Applied biologics flow graft,
amniotic fluid therapy.
And um,
my friend,
uh,
Rodney Mcgee,
Dr Rodney Mcgee is a total sports
medicine in Vegas.
He's awesome.
He's such a knowledgeable guy too.
If you ever wanted to talk to him,
I get you in contact with them and he
can explain all the details.
He talks like you took a fucking geek
out together and confuse the shit out of
anybody standing next to you.
Well,
you know,
pretty soon they actually there you can
make stem cells from skin cells now.
Yeah,
I've heard that.
I know they did that with a woman.
They created a new bladder for her.
She had bladder cancer and they created
a completely new bladder from her skin
cells in a laboratory environment and
then replaced her,
her damaged bladder.
That's amazing.
I had only heard about the clinical
study that they did with [inaudible]
where like the woman,
some woman was,
had some sort of blindness and they were
able to use skin cells from her own
skin.
You know,
clocks.
I'm into becoming retinal cells,
but bladder is really cool too.
I mean,
so there's these lots and lots of
animals studies,
but every once in a while there's like a
new clinical study where they're just
kind of piloting,
you know,
doing this and seeing the safety in,
in humans and that is where I'm like,
I can't wait like it's crazy stem cell
injections for my brain,
you know,
I'm shooting her rent money or it's
going to be very bizarre when we get
past a healthy human state.
That's what I'm really not just
concerned,
not concerned about rather,
but curious about like it's curious,
it's not even a strong enough word,
but I feel like within our lifetimes,
maybe it's 50 years or whatever it's
going to be,
they're going to be able to engineer a
human body to perform and I'm sure
you're aware of myostatin inhibitors and
the benefits that they've shown that the
accidental ones that they've done with
like whippets and cows,
but now they've started to do it on
purpose for mice and they're,
the mice are living longer.
They're super nice.
They're are like way more muscular.
I think they're like two to three times
more muscular than the average mouse.
They look freakish when they kill them.
When they killed him and they skin them
and they show the body of the miles
compared to with the muscle structure
and comparison to the body of a natural
mouse.
It's like,
what in the fuck are you doing here?
Like this is,
this is like the hulk.
It's like you're making a,
a tiny thing,
you know,
and you're putting all this extra muscle
on it and for whatever reason it's
living longer.
Yeah.
That is,
that's the interesting part that it's
living longer.
Trying to figure that out.
Like what you know,
because usually there's some sort of
trade off where you're like,
well,
let's see if we could find that.
Jamie,
the thing,
the Mile Staton inhibitor studies they
did on mice because their physical
performance was extraordinary.
Like they could do things that the other
mice just could not do,
but on top of that they actually live
longer.
Yeah,
that's,
that's very interesting.
I know they were doing it with like pigs
too or something.
I seen some pigs or they'd done since,
I think they were doing gene engineering
on them with the and inhibitor.
But yeah,
it's all,
it's all very interesting.
They've done it with animals that you
use.
I mean they're,
they're thinking that you could do it
with animals that we use for food and
they would just,
they would provide more meat that way,
which is kind of interesting.
But what's man exactly what.
I found some,
a couple of different studies.
Some were older than like 10 years,
so I don't know.
Oh,
okay.
It's cliche.
Muscle mass and muscle fiber in aged
mice,
but does not increase bone density or
bone strength.
Huh?
Be a problem.
Snap.
That's an old study.
The [inaudible] from 2009.
It's 2013 is the one I clicked on.
Interesting.
Uh,
maybe 2013 is probably where I saw it.
But the,
some of those images click on those
images,
Jamie,
because some of those images,
um,
you could see they had the like go down
there with the mice carcasses right
there.
I can see the difference in the size and
no,
that's not it.
It's not necessarily a,
I think it's actually the one where you
made.
Was that
uh hm.
Well there's plenty to look at,
but yeah,
there it is.
You could see the difference in the
muscle size from the average mouse,
which is on the left versus the
milestone and mouse,
the milestone knockout mouse.
But look at what they're standing there.
That one mouse just looks like a giant
ass power lifter mouse.
These are strange times when it comes to
the science.
Really strange times.
I mean,
muscle mass is,
that's exactly what I saw.
That's exactly the one that I saw
pool.
Good Lord.
It's incredible.
I mean,
you've got like two levels of it.
You've got level one,
level a,
and level b.
you've got the natural mouse,
which is on the left.
What is this image?
What does this,
uh,
image title,
Jamie.
Sorry.
Okay.
Bodybuilding and Myostatin.
And there's an image of three mice.
One is a control,
which is the average mouse.
The other ones has dominant negative.
Uh,
how does that work?
Go at Trib Trib two eyes,
uh,
and the other one is follow staten and
in the false downton want it is just a
fucking Lee Haney of mice,
you know,
that's a giant ass mouse.
It's ridiculous.
It's like double the size of the middle
mouse,
which is double the size of the other
mount.
Either of those pathways are or what
they do,
but clearly they regulate muscle mass
was going on.
That would be kinda weird to like do an
injection and like all of a sudden
you're gaining lean muscle mass without
like doing not doing anything.
Yeah.
It doesn't look like those mice are
working out.
No.
That would be super weird.
You know,
that would,
I don't know.
Well that's one of the misconceptions
about steroids.
You know,
people think like you do.
Steroids just get bigger and muscular.
You actually have to work it out.
What this is a guy says is a milestone.
This is bullshit.
This is just don't even click on that
can take that fucking off.
That's lies that these goddamn
supplement companies that do that,
that's really gross.
One of the things they do is they pay
someone to get in really great shape so
someone gets in really great shape,
like they'll give them steroids,
they'll pump them up and then they pay
him to get fat.
So they pay him to stop working out,
they get fat and then they changed the
way the lighting is like.
One of the things that you could see
when you're dealing with fraudulent
companies is,
uh,
these shirt off picks before and after
what a transformation is like in the,
the good picture there,
Tan and the lighting is really good for
accentuating muscle.
Uh,
you know,
the,
the shape of the muscles and the shadows
and everything.
They look ripped.
And then the other one,
they're like pasty and white and they
pay these guys to get fat.
A friend of mine,
they paid him to do it.
Yeah.
These things right here.
Like that guy on the right,
the after is the fucking before.
And the guy on the left that before is
they paid that guy to stop working out
and give facts.
People live with themselves.
Like doing that.
Like I just don't.
It seems like people are douchebags
fraudulent.
There's a lot of monsters out there.
This is from bigger,
stronger,
faster.
I think this was actually taken like the
same day.
Oh,
what did some photoshop they do that.
They do that too,
for sure.
They definitely do that too.
And um,
our friend Chris Bell and Mark Bell who
were in bigger,
stronger,
faster,
you know,
they know a lot more about that than we
do.
Then there's a picture of him right
above that that if you haven't seen that
documentary,
I highly recommend it bigger,
stronger,
faster,
which talks about the supplement
industry and the use of steroids and all
these different things.
But that's one of the interesting.
Yeah,
it's one of the weird practices they do,
like if you look at any of those before
and after pictures,
it's mostly what you're seeing.
I mean,
unless they're like a really ethical
company and they hired someone to take
their product and continue to work out.
But even then it's like when you show a
before and after,
what was the guy doing before?
What was the guy doing after?
How much of that has diet?
How much that is exercise,
like how do you know,
you know,
did you get a blood test on this guy?
Is he on steroids?
Like what?
What's,
what's happening here?
Yeah.
I think we should just focus on
ways we can actually.
Yeah,
science and ways we know like we can
increase muscle mass,
you know,
obviously,
weight lifting and I don't mean to beat
up on Aubrey de grey,
but when you,
when you brought up the science of
nutrition and the factors,
you know,
the,
the positive benefits of it.
Like what was his reaction and what
episodes of this podcast,
the podcast that I did,
I can't remember what episode,
but it's been a year and a half.
At least I would say.
Um,
I can't remember his exact reaction.
I mean,
you can tell if you listen to the pot I
talk,
I talk a lot about,
we talk a lot about crispr and stem cell
and a lot of these possible therapies
that are being used that can potentially
extend lifespan.
But there's a point in the podcast where
nutrition comes up and you can tell it
gets a little awkward between the two of
us because we kind of have different
viewpoints and I'm,
I'm sort of not trying to be rude
because look at them,
they're fucking wizard.
We were like so close and his office and
he's anyways,
he's an odd guy.
That beard is fucking awesome though.
God Damn that point was just that you
can't,
you're not gonna,
you're not gonna extend lifespan by,
you know,
40 or 50 percent with diet and that's
what he wants to do.
Right.
And that's fair.
But the point that I think,
you know,
it's,
it's one thing to say that and another
thing to kind of disregard nutrition
altogether,
you know,
because that's because that's just
stupid nutrition plays a role in the way
you age.
And so I think that should be,
you know,
it shouldn't be something that people
should completely disregard,
disregard and not think about and not.
And not even not thinking about.
But when they talk publicly,
talk it down.
Like,
I don't like that.
Like that's fine.
If you want to focus on technologies
and,
and I agree with that,
I mean I'm,
I'm all about,
you know,
all these gene therapy technologies and
crispr and you know,
induced pluripotent stem cells and I'm a
huge,
huge fan of all that,
but I don't think that being a fan of
that and being excited about what the
science and what new technologies are,
are gonna be able to bring us,
should,
you know,
make us talk about like kind of poop on
nutrition,
right?
Watching the also a big factor is the
way you feel and a big factor too.
I mean,
I assume they just doesn't just want to
extend a shitty life,
right?
You want to extend a life where you feel
wonderful,
right?
Right.
And well if your booze and all the time
like he is that guy boozes every day.
I talked to him like we were drunk as
fuck in New York.
I went to that.
Um,
what is it,
2045 conference.
Uh,
there's a,
a conference in New York where all of
these nutty people who think you're
going to be able to download your brain
into a super computer and the year 20,
45 like this extended life conference
and a lot of it was run by this Russian
billionaire that I talked to,
which was,
who was a very odd character,
but he was building a robot that they
were not satisfied with the results of
this robot.
So they,
uh,
they never a unearthed it.
They never unveiled it rather.
But these all these people is 20,
45 conference in New York.
We're all like this gathering of these
super geeks that are all in various ways
trying to extend life.
And Aubrey de Grey was there as well and
I met him at the bar and we just got
fucking hammered.
We got hammered and we're talking.
I'm like,
is,
are we extending life that's going on?
It feels like we're just drinking
guinness.
You are causing massive inflammation.
Brain cell death.
This is terrible.
What are we doing?
But you know,
those are two very contrary ways of
existing to,
to extend life.
But yet to diminish the potential of the
life you're currently experiencing,
but,
you know,
I guess he's having fun,
you know?
Yeah.
I don't,
you know,
he was an interesting guy and I enjoyed
talking to him,
but I don't want to talk bad about him.
But when I was very shocked when I
walked into his office that literally
like 11 in the morning and he had
already down two beers and you respond
is third.
And I was just like,
I didn't,
I wasn't expecting that.
I wasn't.
I mean,
it was completely shocking to me.
God bless him out there hammering it.
Who knows?
Yeah.
But I guess there's a lot of different
approaches and I think he's,
his approach is welcomed.
It's interesting.
It's an,
it's,
it's just as important to have a guy
like that that's kind of fucking up his
body and still still after it.
Like,
it's,
it's interesting,
right?
Um,
you know this,
like I was saying though,
the thing that with him and I,
you know,
the,
the major differences is focusing on
nutrition and that's something that,
um,
that I want to get the message across
that I want something to do right now.
So maybe you can do right now until an
end.
In the meanwhile still telling people
about the awesome science coming out.
But until then,
let's keep,
let's keep it going.
They're not mutually exclusive.
They're not,
they're not mutually exclusive.
The other,
you know,
one of the things that when we were
talking about the muscle mass,
I started thinking about this time
restricted eating.
Have you heard about this at all time?
Restricted eating a little bit,
like eating within a certain time
period.
That correlates,
corresponds to like the day it has
really profound effects on muscle mass
without any other factors that having to
exercise or anything.
That's something that's extremely
interesting.
Interesting.
But this time restricted eating is,
it's very important for,
for health and metabolism.
It's also something I've been obsessed
with since like probably early summer
I've been doing it like just,
you know,
really fanatically making sure that I'm
eating within like uh,
uh,
no more than 12 hour period.
I try to do like 10 hours.
So like when you wake up in the morning,
you have a cup of coffee or you know,
you eat even a cup of black coffee,
the first thing you put into your system
that's not
water starts all these metabolic enzymes
start some in your liver,
your gut starts using these enzymes and
those enzymes are on a clock because
humans are diurnal creatures where we're
meant to be awake and working and active
and thinking during the day and we sleep
at night,
which is different from nocturnal
creatures like some rodents and other
animals that are,
you know,
sleep during the day and,
or night.
So because we're men,
we are active during the day.
We're diurnal,
all these,
all of our metabolism,
metabolism,
enzymes and all these things are active
during the day.
Um,
and things that activate them are light,
light exposure and also food intake.
And xenobiotic is also something,
so anything that gets metabolized like
buyer buyer system by your liver,
whatever activates these enzymes and
once they're activated,
they're on this like 12 hour clock where
it's like,
okay,
so you're metabolizing glucose,
fatty acids,
all these things,
you know,
well if you're eating within that 12
hour clock,
but when you go beyond that 12 hour
clock,
that's when things start to go really
wrong because your metabolism enzymes
start to shut down and they're not doing
things properly.
So you're not like insulin responsive,
you're not even fatty acids and things
like that.
Just metabolism in general is not
working as well,
you know,
after 12 hours.
And so that's kind of a big eyeopener.
I know there was,
um,
a lot of people think they eat 12 hour
time period.
Like if you were to survey them,
like,
Oh yeah,
I don't eat more than 12 hours.
But there's actually a study done by a
friend of mine who's a expert in this
field.
He's at the Sulk Institute.
His name is satchin panda.
I'm very good scientists.
I interviewed him on my podcast and he's
done a lot of research on this,
this topic,
and he did the human study where he had
like this app where people logged there,
they took pictures of the food that they
ate and it like,
you know,
sent it to some database they had and it
had a timestamp on it so they could see
when the clock,
when they,
when their first cup of coffee or
whatever was in the morning,
and then when they were eating.
And I turned out most people were
actually eating in a 15 hour clock.
So they were having their cup of coffee,
you know,
at eight,
seven in the morning.
And they were,
you know,
they're eating at like nine,
nine,
10,
10:00.
Yeah.
So they're eating much later.
Um,
the,
the thing is,
is that when you do that,
you start to gain more,
more fat.
You start to become more insulin
insensitive and you start to like,
your muscle starts to waste regardless
of what you eat,
regardless of what you eat.
So,
so okay.
No,
I take that back.
So you,
if you eat healthy,
so if you're eating a terrible diet,
if you're eating a terrible diet,
and this has been shown in mice like
Lard,
fat plus sugar,
those two together,
which is the actual bad combination,
but you brought that up and I'm gonna
make a note to keep those two are the
bad combination.
So if you eat,
if you're eating that,
if you're feeding the mice that and you
let them eat whenever they want so they
can eat their nocturnal,
but I'm just going to call it day and
their day is actually night.
Just know that that's true.
If they're eating
during the day and night,
they gain like,
you know,
tons of ways to come.
Fat become like,
you know,
type two diabetic,
fatty liver.
I mean they're just a mess.
They're breaking down like,
like earlier than they should.
But if you eat normal,
so if you're eating a healthy diet
that's not high fat,
high sugar,
you don't necessarily,
you're not necessarily gonna gain more
fat,
you don't,
you don't become type two diabetic and
all that.
If you're not eating all the crap.
So you probably just going to be okay,
but if you take that same mouse who
eating a healthy diet and you make it
eat within a time restricted window of
at least 12 hours,
actually the best wisdom,
nine to 10,
they gain way more muscle mass.
This is on a normal diet,
just way more muscle mass.
And if they ate within a nine hour
window they had like a really improved
endurance.
That's something I've noticed in myself.
I eat within a nine hour window and I go
for a run the next morning.
My endurance is like very noticeably
improved,
like extremely noticeably improved.
So do you have like a timer or like how
do you do,
do you time yourself at the beginning of
your day?
Like when you first eat and then.
Yeah.
So I typically will make.
So my friend Kevin rose has an APP that
like um,
it's called darn what did he.
Kevin rose has an APP.
Yeah.
Yeah,
I've had them on.
I love that guy.
Yeah,
he's awesome.
He just cute agenda proponent as well.
Yeah.
He doesn't actually do Keto anymore
because it's uh,
after he got a bunch of blood work done
and I mean there's,
there's different,
you know,
genes that people have that can affect
the way they respond to that sort of
diet.
Most of the time people can respond
good,
but there's a dizzy was on here just one
of them long ago introducing zero that's
app to help you fast.
So he has an app that helps you do that.
That actually works really well.
Personally,
what I do is I'm just kind of crazy
about it and I just remember it that
day.
So I'm like,
okay,
I had my first cup of coffee at 8:00
AM,
but his app actually is really cool
because it really helps you keep
dragging.
It sends you reminders so like helps
you.
And it's a free app.
So powerful.
Kevin rose.
Anyways,
it's really cool because you can just
like literally these mice were gaining
more muscle mass just not by doing
anything but eating within this time
restricted window.
And um,
the thing that was also very interesting
about this was that,
um,
you could cheat a couple of days a week
so they could like,
like let's say weekends when you have
like social events and you're like out
drinking or whatever,
you can,
you can cheat two nights and still have
the same benefits so that at least in
mice,
we don't know if that's the same for
humans.
Sachin's doing,
trying to aggregate some data with
humans.
He actually has an ongoing trial that
anyone can sign up for.
Um,
it's called my circadian clock and it's
an also an app on his phone that you
just basically all you do is sign a
consent form,
take pictures of your food and uh,
and like allow certain data,
you know,
different,
different fitness data for them to
collect.
And so they're doing this clinical
study,
humans from data that they're
aggregating,
which is kind of cool.
Jen is fasting tracker right now.
Yeah.
And you can do,
he has different options for Kevin's
fasting.
It's like the circadian option,
which is the one I'm talking about.
And then there's like people that are
doing intermittent fasting and what's
the circadian option?
That's the time restricted eating.
That's certainly.
That's just basically circadian is the
circadian clock you're on.
So that's what.
It's this 24 hour cycle day,
day night cycle.
So eating within at least a 12 hour
window is so 12 hour is the most you
ever most.
So if you get up at 8:00
in the morning and that's when you have
your first cup of coffee,
that's when it starts.
Not with food.
It starts with First Cup of coffee.
Because that's interesting because a lot
of people don't think that they think
that they're still fast and they have a
cup of coffee and then they go run.
That's the thing.
I'm so because coffee,
even if it's black,
so people think if they have black
coffee,
they're fasting and they go run.
But black coffee is caffeine is a
xenobiotic.
It's something that has to be
metabolized by liver enzymes.
Your gut processes it.
So anything that happens in water,
exactly.
Anything other than water.
And the same goes for like taking
vitamin pills and drinking herbal tea
late at night,
like the same,
the same thing goes.
Even herbal tea.
Herbal tea is also got irb stuff in it.
So Kevin non-caffeinated herbal tea.
Yeah.
Because those are xenobiotics camomile.
I mean that stuff's got to be processed
by your liver,
your gut.
It's not,
it's not water.
You know.
So I mean,
and this is something that's kind of a
big question and that is,
well,
if the fascinate,
let's say you're,
you're eating within a nine hour window
or 10 hour window is optimal.
Nine hours is really what I found to be
optimal for endurance in terms of the
animal studies,
like 10 hours.
Also if they eating their healthy diet
within 10 hours,
they still had um,
they increase their lean muscle mass.
They didn't have to do anything else.
No extra exercising it just because what
was happening is they were,
they were basically,
I'm,
their mitochondria are working better
and they were also.
I'm getting rid of fat easier.
So you know,
so it increased their lean muscle mass.
That's incredible because I,
I late at night all the time.
Well you're a comedian.
I mean that's probably,
you probably eat after a show or
something.
He came home last night at 2:00
in the morning,
pigged out after a show.
I mean it was healthy food.
I like Kiefer and pistachio nuts.
I buy those big jugs of shelled
pistachios shells,
so I just eat like piles of pistachios
because I feel like I'm not eating
anything bad.
That's good for you.
But this knowledge now knowing this,
I'm going to.
I'm going to cut that out now.
Please let me know how that goes.
I'm going to start right now.
Yeah,
that's awesome.
I mean,
like I said,
you can cheat.
There is cheating at least in mice
twice.
Twice a week was okay.
Two Times a week is a good cheat.
Yeah.
And that's kind of cool because it's
like a weekend.
Right?
Right.
You know,
so you have your social event it,
it's hard to do with social events and
stuff.
If you have like something late and you
kind of have to fast are all early in
the morning all the way up and so you
can do it later,
you know what I mean?
But I do a lot of workouts fasted now
and one of the things that I like to do
is I'd get up in the morning without
having anything and then I work out.
But I've been having coffee so I,
I thought I was fasting.
He will see.
The thing is,
and this is kind of what I was talking
with Satya and about,
is that it's,
if you're fasting itself,
the fasting itself is having a positive
effect on all these enzymes.
So maybe there's some sort of canceled
out.
It's not,
not,
it's not as good.
Not as good I would say.
So just water.
We don't have actual empirical data on
that saying,
okay,
well you know,
and that's something that Satya and
would like to look at and humans because
it's like a big question.
What if you are just fasting,
uh,
in the bay?
In theory it's not,
you're starting all those clocks.
The clocks are difficult.
Caffeine starts the clocks that's around
so,
but then again,
you know,
like I said,
fasting changes your metabolism in a way
too.
That makes it better.
So maybe it's not quite as bad.
Not quite as bad,
but not as formal.
Exactly.
I like that.
That's perfect.
Yeah.
So shoot for nine hours.
That was like that nine hours is the
best,
especially for endurance,
like enhancements,
like really.
So if you get up and you're at,
you know,
you're up at 8:00
in the morning or 7:00
in the morning,
whatever it is,
you almost have to eat dinner like at
five.
Yeah,
that's the problem.
You have to,
you have to either fast in the morning
where you have to eat early,
which is really hard for working people
nine to fivers yeah,
I mean it's like you're eating breakfast
before you go to work unless you're not
right now.
And that's kind of the problem for
people that are going,
you know,
humans,
we have,
you know,
life is kind of different now,
but it's,
you know,
there are people that we're talking
about you,
they just take their breakfast to work
and they wait so they'll wait till like
10:00
to eat or something like that because
also there's people that like to go to
the gym after work and so that's more
time.
It's like you gotta get a racist clock,
I got to eat,
you know,
so really if you can start the clock
later,
if that's possible for people that are
working like that,
they don't have flexible hours,
um,
then then it would be better to start
the clock later.
And there's a lot of human data on this,
like just looking at like the
associations between people that eat
within an 11 hour period and fast for 13
hours.
For example,
women that do that,
that have already had breast cancer,
they reduced their breast cancer risk
recurrence by like 40 percent,
you know?
Wow.
Yeah.
Because it lowers,
it,
it causes insulin sensitivity,
it lowers igf one levels.
I mean,
it's just like,
it lowers all these hormones and things
that are known to promote cancer growth.
It's really a powerful thing and
improves metabolism,
really improves metabolism and that's
something that um,
a couple of scientists that I've talked
to that are at UCFC are looking at and
actively seeing that it just,
it seems to be really important.
And obviously people doing shift work,
like nurses are kind of.
I mean that's the problem.
The other kind of fucked when you're
doing that late shift stuff and they are
there.
They have twice the cancer incidents
like
yeah,
twice,
twice shift workers.
They're also much more likely to be type
two diabetic.
You know,
it's because you're eating,
you're eating.
Like when you're at night,
you're eating,
you know,
your metabolism is all screwed up.
Not only are you like when you're eating
after the 12 hour clock are you not as
insulin sensitive and so your blood
glucose levels are higher also.
You're confusing your clock.
So it Kinda like it says,
okay,
I'm restarting now because it's late.
I'm getting my first signal in its after
it's been after 12 hours.
And it confused it,
so then when you go to sleep,
say you eat at two in the morning and go
to sleep and you wake up the next
morning and you have your meal,
it's already going to have started that
clock a while ago,
so you won't be as insulin sensitive
because the earlier in the day you're
the more the more insulin sensitive you
are.
So you know what I mean?
So you kind of like confused in the
clock.
It's like this.
I'm a very complicated but I think
important mechanism and system for
people to understand and time restricted
time restricted eating,
like I have really implemented that
because I think that's something that
also will affect the aging process.
I've talked to people like at
conferences I've given a talk at that
have come up to me afterwards and there
they were talking about how they've been
on a ketogenic diet for two years and
how it would reverse your type two
diabetes.
It's been great,
but still their fasting blood glucose
levels were still in the high end,
you know,
even though they're no longer a type two
diabetic,
which is really good.
And they started doing the time
restricted eating or they're eating
within a nine hour window and it
completely resolved.
It,
completely resolved it and it actually
had multiple people tell me that.
And so the amazing thing is the increase
in muscle,
the muscle is really the increase,
the,
the interesting part.
I would like to like talk to such and
more about that and have him do more
experiments of possible,
uh,
because we didn't dive as much into that
on the podcast and we chatted,
but he is such a phenomenal scientist
and he's very,
uh,
proactive and into health and all this,
you know,
preventative medicine and he's just a
great,
great person at the salk institute in La
Jolla.
Very prestigious place to be.
It's a lot of really good scientists
there.
Jude,
do your podcast with him through skype
or did you know?
I met with him there.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I usually try to,
um,
I like to meet with people when I,
when I interviewed them,
so,
so I,
uh,
I've noticed so I can't have done skype
ones and they're just,
it's like there's a disconnect.
There's something missing.
Yes.
It was nice for you is you actually have
a studio and people come to your studio.
So right now I'm,
I'm like going around to institutes and
what,
you know,
if I'm at a place where I'm giving a
talk and I'm like this great scientist
there,
I'm going to ask people to,
to intervene.
How do you suppose name s a t a c h I n
Satchin Panda.
He is a great name.
Actually his first name is such and to
Nanda,
that's his,
because he's Indian,
so we shortened to Satchin
but he's um,
he's a really good person to talk to you
too.
Like he is very uh,
you know,
just,
he speaks eloquently.
He explained things well.
He's a little bit of an Indian accent,
but you know,
it's just,
it's kind of like cute,
but his science has changed my life.
Like,
Oh yeah,
all my circadian knowledge.
I've,
I've been following him for a few years.
I've really looked up to him for if in
fact I don't even know if I told them
this,
but I was interested in doing a post doc
with him.
Certain point,
like after I'd finished my phd because I
thought his,
he was back back in 2012 when I
graduated.
He was making these discoveries about
late night eating and how it like,
how it makes you,
um,
you know,
more so you basically more insulin
resistant,
how it's like screwing up brain function
to all these things that I didn't even
talk about and start.
I got really interested in it because I
know a lot of people that eat late at
night and people that are having trouble
losing weight and all that,
they're eating late at night,
so.
Wow,
that's amazing.
I'm going to listen to his podcast with
you and,
or your podcasts with.
Yeah,
check that out.
That's a,
that sounds awesome.
That'd be cool.
So the saturated fat sugars,
what you wanted to narrow that down?
I did,
because you actually sent me an article
about that,
which I found was really fascinating
there.
Although saturated fat is important,
it's how would you describe it as a
precursor to hormones?
It's,
it's not just a precursor to hormones,
so saturated fat,
saturated fat,
increases ldl cholesterol,
ldl lipoproteins,
proteins which carry cholesterol and
fatty acids.
We always call it cholesterol.
It's a type of it.
It's a transporter of cholesterol,
but it also transports fatty acids and
other things.
But the thing is is,
you know,
the Ldl is very,
very important because,
um,
every time you make a new cell in your
body,
which is happening constantly,
you're always making new immune cells
are making new kidney cells.
You're making new liver cells.
I mean,
it's happening all the time.
Anytime you make a new cell,
you need ldl there to transport
cholesterol and fatty acids because cell
membrane,
the cell itself,
the membrane is made of it.
It has fatty acids and cholesterol and
phospholipids and other things.
But so you need that cholesterol.
When you damage the cell,
you know,
and you're repairing that damage.
Cholesterol needs to be there.
So,
I mean,
you really,
really need cholesterol.
LDL cholesterol is very important for
that,
for that reason,
and without it you're kind of screwed,
right?
I mean you can't like repair damaged as
well.
You're not going to make as many new
cells.
So all these people that are avoiding
saturated fat and cholesterol in their
diet,
they're doing the literal doing
literally doing their cell regeneration
the disservice.
Well,
I don't want to make that broad state
because I don't know what else they're
either,
maybe they're getting other types of
fatty acids that also helped.
But yes,
people that are like on stands for
example,
which is a very broad way of inhibiting
like cholesterol synthesis
brought like fullstop.
Um,
that's why a lot of those people on
statens I'm one of the major,
major side effects is muscle atrophy and
muscle wasting.
You know,
because your muscles,
one of those cells,
you're constantly repairing damage and
making the muscle.
And it's a big,
big problem.
Huge problem with Staton staton users.
It also.
So a colleague of mine,
Ron Kraus,
he's at a children's hospital in
Oakland.
He has been studying status and their
effect on Mitochondria and he was
telling me that it's like toxic to
mitochondria and he's trying to figure
out why is.
It's like,
maybe that's partly why it's.
I'm also causing muscle wasting.
So if people don't consume saturated
fats or they lower their radically lower
the saturated fat in their diet,
how does their body produced new cell
membranes?
Well,
I mean,
you still,
you're,
you're making cholesterol in your body
and you're making it from there.
Getting fatty acids.
They're getting it from plants.
I mean plant sterols,
they're getting them from,
from other sources,
you know,
but I think the problem with the,
with the saturated fat was,
it's not so much that because people
still get it to some degree.
I mean it's like,
but it's not an optimal.
Yeah.
I mean,
I don't know.
I can't attack.
I'd have to see like the person.
I think it varies depending on what else
they're eating.
But you know,
the Pr,
I think the problem was that saturated
fat was demonized.
Well,
it was demonized in a very corrupt way,
which is the,
the,
the recent New York Times article that
was released,
which was a mindblower,
which detailed how the sugar industry
had bribed scientists to release data
blaming saturated fat for heart disease
and obesity and all these issues when it
was in fact sugar that was causing all
that.
So they were literally rigging the
system and paying scientists and it was
a horrible article because that
propaganda and these lies that they
spread,
I believe it was in the fifties,
here it is,
how the sugar industry shifted the blame
to fat and it's if you get a chance and
you want to feel sick at what can be
done with money,
watch or read that because it's just,
it's awful.
It is really awful.
And um,
it was an internal sugar industry
document that was discovered by a
researcher at the University of
California in San Francisco.
And it was published,
he said Monday when this was out,
I believe it was a couple of months ago,
but it was amazing.
It suggested that five decades of
research into the role of nutrition in
heart disease,
including many of today's dietary
recommendations may have been largely
shaped by the sugar industry and
propaganda and money.
They spent money to literally bribe
scientists to release false data.
It's horrible,
really nasty,
but I mean the thing is not that much
money either there.
Here's
a goal.
Go back to it.
Here.
They paid three Harvard scientists
equivalent of $50,000
in today's dollars to publish in 1967.
Review of research on sugar,
fat and heart disease.
Studies using the review were handpicked
by the Sugar Group and the article which
was published in the prestigious New
Jersey.
New England Journal of medicine minimize
the link between sugar and heart health
and cast aspirations on the role of
saturated fat even though the influence
peddling revealed and documents dates
back to nearly 50 years.
More recent reports show that the food
industry has continued to influence
nutrition science.
This had such a negative like con.
There was such negative consequences
from this,
from from the demonization and saturated
fat because people then obviously
started eating more refined,
like for breakfast in the morning
instead of having eggs,
you're having like cereal,
but the real problem was the trans fats
because trans fats can,
can have similar,
but their hydrogenated hydrogenated
fats,
which you know,
you take like a,
a mono saturated fat and hydrated and
you can have similar properties,
properties as a saturated fat like
butter,
how it's solid and then melts at a
higher temperature.
But these trans fats,
I mean I remember my mom had a big tub
of margarine.
I mean we used to put margin on our
mashed potatoes and everybody thought it
was healthy and it was so.
I mean,
it's not just unhealthy.
I mean it was literally,
that's what's called,
it causes heart disease because the
trans fats,
like I said,
you take these fats up into your new
cells,
right?
Because that's part of what,
you know,
fatty acids and cholesterol,
that's part of what you're doing with
them in your body.
The transplants get taken up and the
whole structure of it's screwed up.
So when this happens in the endothelial
cells lining your blood vessels,
it makes them real stiff,
real stiff and like,
I mean it's just like screws it up.
So trans fats are like,
we have known about the,
like the fact that trans fats are
playing a causal role in heart disease
for decades and the FDA finally in 2015,
2015,
okay.
Finally banned them from the u s and
gave all the companies that are still
putting them in their process foods and
a lot of fast foods companies use crisco
because it's cheaper three years to get
it off the market.
So we have until 2018 Jesus Christ,
three years to get rid of poison.
And that's after already like decades of
knowing.
It's like,
you know that this is like,
it's like so bad,
so,
so bad for you.
Anyways,
that's a,
that's a whole.
That's one of the major repercussions.
And then obviously then people became
scared of saturated fat.
And the thing,
the thing with the sugar,
and this is kind of what you were
initially hinting at,
is that a lot of there,
there have been a lot of studies that
have linked,
you know,
that weren't corrupt by the shirt,
like these were the early study,
but there have been studies that have
linked saturated fat and take to heart
disease and,
and a lot of those studies were also
because people were eating,
in addition to saturated fat,
they didn't correct for like refined
sugar intake,
which is really what the problem is.
And that has now shown in multiple
studies.
So you know,
and this came down to actually being
able to have new technology available
that was able to then,
you know,
ldl is not,
there's not just one ldl cholesterol in
the body comes in all sizes and types.
The type that we're talking about,
the good type is the large,
buoyant type.
And that's what saturated fat increases.
There's also,
it gets processed into smaller parts
that are small,
dense ldl and that's what gets
basically,
it can't get recycled back to the liver.
So it stays around the bloodstream and
undergoes inflammatory transformations
and sticks in the blood vessels.
It causes all this problem,
right?
That's what refined sugar increases.
And that's been shown in clinical
studies.
So like healthy young men that were
given 20 ounces of soda a day for three
weeks.
It totally healthy young young men
increase this,
increased their ldl,
small dense ldl particles like massively
increased small dense ldl particles and
also increase their inflammatory
markers.
C reactive protein,
but like almost 100 percent,
which is like crazy.
So we're talking about like,
you know,
the refined sugar is what can make
saturated fat dangerous is when you
combine the two because the ldl gets
processed into the small dense and it's
refined sugar that does that.
So,
so small dense ldl versus ldl.
Yeah.
And so the thing is is that even now
it's not standard of care at a lag.
Measure all the particles sizes.
It's like we've known about this for at
least a decade now.
Like so Ron Kraus,
he is,
um,
he's the guy who actually pioneered this
assay and figured out how to measure
them.
The small,
dense ldl.
It's called the ion mobility as say a,
it's in a quest labs does it,
but you can also ask your physician,
you can ask your physician to measure
the particle size.
Um,
but the thing is,
is that because it's not something
that's standard of care,
when you go in to measure ldl
cholesterol and it's above a certain
number,
physicians are like freaking out and
they're like,
you should get on Stanton's.
But the reality is that you need to look
at the small dense ldl.
That's what's actually puts you at risk
for heart disease and that's just not
standard of care that you have to like
specifically ask for it,
you know,
and so crazy that there's such a vast
difference in the consequences for your
health.
But yet it's not tested even though the
knowledge is there.
Well,
that's what I was saying with the Trans
Fat.
I mean the knowledge was there.
Like I was talking to my,
like 88 year old mentor Bruce Ames and
he was like,
I remember back in the eighties though,
we stayed away from that and never gave
margin.
And my children,
I'm like,
well you're a scientist.
Like my mom wasn't,
you know,
like he's known about this for like when
I was like,
like five,
you know,
he's known for 30 fucking years and now
2015 is when,
you know,
there's always a lag between research
and the application of it.
But I mean,
I don't know how much of A.
I don't know what it takes to,
you know,
maybe these regulatory committees May.
There's probably a lot more than I know
that goes into like figuring out like
how you make these regulations.
It's only financially motivated.
That's what's disgusting about it.
They're given these companies three
years to get poison out of food.
That is what really upsets me.
I'm like,
okay,
you finally finally have banded in the
US,
but you're given three years,
like three years for people to profit
off of poisoning for killing.
People don't realize you should have a
fucking cancer recommendation or a
warning the same way you have on
cigarettes.
And it's not even like you can go.
Like people go to the supermarket and
you'll say no trans fats on their food.
And all that,
but when they go to fast food or they go
to some restaurant where they're using
Chris crisco's,
they're not even going to know they're
getting it.
And I'm telling you this was awesome.
Oh man,
totally.
God Damn on the budget.
This was great.
You blow my mind every time.
This is amazing.
There's a lot to study folks,
so go over this podcast 30 or 40 times
and I know I'm going to go over it.
A few found my fitness on twitter.
What your,
your podcast found my fitness.
I have a podcast.
It's called found my fitness and
actually I just released a podcast today
with Dr Roland Griffiths,
who is the notorious Psychedelic
psilocybin researcher.
I met with him when I was at Johns
Hopkins outside of my realm,
but you should listen to it.
It's interesting.
I will definitely do that and let's do
it again soon.
It's been too long.
So much fun.
Thank you so much.
Thanks for.
I appreciate it.
All right folks.
We'll see you.
Bye.
The.
Yeah?
Yes.