Shy,
yeah,
we feel professional with headsets on
and we're live.
Welcome back Louis.
Yeah,
thanks.
Nice to be back.
Uh,
I was saying before the podcast started
that you sent me down a scientology
rabbit hole last night,
my friend.
I've been down those before,
but last night knowing that you were
going to be on and looking forward to it
eagerly.
I uh,
I watched a lot of stuff.
Uh,
and you know,
I spent three years down the rabbit hole
and a,
it's a weird one.
So when were you on the Internet where
you just clicking around?
Yeah,
just on Youtube,
but there's various very,
very well resourced websites.
There's one called clam bake.
I've been to that one.
Yeah.
And then there's all the Tony Ortega
stuff.
I mean there's just,
there's just whole worlds.
And actually,
I mean I know there's a lot to talk
about,
but perhaps the biggest obstacle to
making a documentary about scientology
is the over abundance of material,
you know,
because there's just so many ways to
come in on it.
And if you could just chase intriguing
leads and then months go by and you're
known narrative filming it.
I had a lot of thoughts on this and one
of the thoughts when I was really trying
to unpack it all is that I feel like one
of the reasons why a lot of these people
defend scientology there,
I think there's several reasons.
One,
because it's their team and once you
become a part of a team,
it becomes something that you identify
with,
becomes very important to you.
And then you want to,
you want to defend that.
So I think there's that.
But also I think some people take some
benefit in what l Ron Hubbard created
because,
uh,
if you,
if you read going clear.
Yes,
when I read going clear,
I watched the documentary and then I
read the book and one of the things it
was more fascinating about the book was
the fact that he was essentially trying
to diagnose and treat himself.
And he was essentially a really nutty
guy.
You was very damaged.
Yeah.
He,
he had a lot going on.
And um,
he was a guy who was trying to sort of
sort it out himself and in the process
brought a lot of people in and then
created this thing and some people they
get some benefit from this thing because
like I was watching like some of these
people that are upset with you,
like that woman or that there was a
trailer where this woman was upset at
you because you were in.
I haven't seen the documentary yet.
It comes out in America in January.
Um,
but you were on a road,
you had a permit for and she was telling
you,
you are on private land.
And I'm looking at this woman.
I'm like,
this is,
it seems like a reasonable,
intelligent,
assertive,
confident woman that would probably,
if she didn't get into scientology,
she would have been successful in the
corporate world I'm sure.
But here she is.
Her Corporation is written by a nutty
science fiction writer who wrote more
fiction than any human has ever walked
the face of the planet.
He,
he made up more shit.
He wrote down more things that never
happened than anyone who's ever lived.
And they don't have a problem with that.
They're like,
I mean,
you've said about 10 different things
that I could break down and analyze.
I mean,
I basically on the same page as you.
I think that's the first thing to
acknowledge about scientology is that
it's a religion and that all religions
have a very high portion of,
um,
you know,
to try to put it politely,
but just bogus,
fallacious,
clearly nonsensical material.
Right?
In scientology is,
is,
uh,
is the same as all of those.
I think there's a lot of people who've
had derived a lot of benefit from
scientology.
I think people probably.
There's people whose lives have been
saved by it.
Kirstie Alley,
we'll say at any opportunity that it was
scientology that got her off drugs.
But I think a lot you have to sorta take
the whole package.
And we,
as far as Hubbard goes,
he was an only child.
He was a fantasy,
just a lonely guy who was also a
narcissist.
And I think as a writer,
I mean,
you can't.
One of the things in treatments about
scientology is created by Scifi writer,
right?
There's not,
most other religions are created by sort
of desert mystics or mores or people
introspective people,
but a modern day Scifi writer who's
writing things about aliens taking over
foreign galaxies.
That's really that it accounts for a lot
of.
It's um,
it's very bizarre inflection.
Do you know what I mean?
Yeah.
Well,
not only that,
I don't think he wrote a second draft
ever.
No,
he didn't have time.
He was just sending it out.
I think a lot of the stuff that they say
he wrote,
he didn't write like because he was
married three times and at least one of
his wives took credit for writing some
of his stuff.
I think even some stuff of scientology
may be written by a second wife who we
then,
he subsequently disavowed said he was
never married to,
but I'm,
the guy was a,
he,
he lied about so many things.
He was also abusive to his wife.
Wives,
I think plural.
So physically he,
he,
he was,
um,
abusive to them.
He was very,
very troubled and suicidal.
One of the most intriguing things in
going clear is reading this list of,
uh,
I think they call them affirmations,
which when he was in after the Second
World War,
he was right with self doubt.
He thought it was a failure.
He was embarrassed about his sexual
urgency,
urgency's,
compulsive masturbation and so on and so
forth.
And he wrote down a list of things.
Do you remember this section of it where
it says you do not feel compelled to
mass conveyed 24 times a day?
It's not literally everything,
right?
You are.
You were not a disgrace to the military.
You were,
you acquitted your service in the navy,
very creditably.
It was all these sort of lies he was
telling himself to reassure himself that
he was actually to feel okay about
himself.
It's a very humanizing document because
you just see all his neurotic
inclinations laid bare that then
subsequently informed his lifelong
attempt to,
as you say,
sort of therapeutically healing himself.
And I think
there's other people that identify with
those self sort of damaged thoughts,
these thoughts where they don't like
their past.
They don't like who they are.
They don't like the pattern that they're
on and they seek to try to change that
and improve upon their position and
improve upon their,
their understanding and their acceptance
of themselves and I think that's where
scientology does benefit a lot of people
and so it is tricky like many things in
this life.
It's not that black and white,
I mean is it black and white that it's a
cult and that there's a lot of damaging
aspects of that?
Yes,
absolutely.
It's pretty clear when you see the
people that have tried to leave it and
you know,
and,
and tell the truth about their
experiences in it and what,
how they've been harassed and hounded
and yeah,
that's all pretty black and white,
but I think we can in some ways we can
sympathize with some of the people that
are in it.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
I mean,
but the other thing to say is because
you started by asking what was it that
made some people defend scientology and
is it loyalty to the team?
But I also think that I'm on the outer
periphery.
There are concentric rings of commitment
to scientology and in the,
in a,
in a circle,
it is extremely demanding and I would
argue abusive and uh,
and,
and cult like on the outer circles as
you get further from the center,
I think it can be relatively benign and
especially if you're a vip or a
celebrity in which you're exposed only
to the best sorts of treatment you're
given kind of platinum card treatment,
you go to the celebrity center,
they rolled out the red carpet for you.
And I think those people feel immensely
indebted to scientology.
I think that explains a lot about Tom
Cruise,
that he's only ever been treated like a
prince when he's been in scientology.
So he,
he,
he feels so grateful for everything that
they've done for him.
Yeah,
I think his experience when,
when he talks about them,
if he's being honest,
I mean if,
if everyone had that experience,
scientology would be amazing.
You know,
when you see him,
when they had the happy birthday thing
for him and he's dancing and everybody's
cheering,
like imagine if you just people treated
you like that all the time.
Oh my goodness.
Auditioning actors like female actors to
see if they were going to be your
girlfriend or did you read that whole,
I mean,
imagine if they rounded up the most
attractive young female actors in
Hollywood,
uh,
to see whether they would go on a date
with you.
Yeah,
it would make life very simple.
If you weren't married as I am,
would it?
I don't know man.
I mean dealing with a bunch of nutty
paid through that process.
Yeah.
And actually because it would be like
I'm almost king midas thing where you
wouldn't trust any of your instincts.
You won't feel as though people were,
were erecting potemkin villages
everywhere you went.
Do you know what I mean?
Nothing would feel quite real.
That's a good point.
Also,
like imagine your wife today.
If you found out that your wife today
was one
of the people that had auditioned to be
Tom Cruise's wife.
I mean if you don't make the cut,
you're damaged goods for the rest of
your life.
That's interesting too.
You're a nutty broad who is willing to
go and sign up to become Tom Cruise's
new wife.
Well,
to be fair,
they didn't know that was the job they
were going in to be fair.
Yeah,
that's true.
So,
so just being,
they just thought they were up for some
Gig,
do you know what I mean?
Maybe a Sitcom was essentially they
were.
And then there's also all of the
difficult things get screwed around with
the scientology treatment of
homosexuals.
Were they sort of shield them from the
press or hide their activity and sort of
you don't want a beard is.
I do,
yeah.
They hire beards,
you know,
that's,
I mean that's a great point.
And I think actually that's another one
that,
you know,
I guess we've,
we as a society have evolved a lot over
the last 50 years to some extent.
Hubbard was a creature of his times in
his attitudes towards homosexuality.
The trouble is because they're saying
it's a religion that's been enshrined as
scripture.
And so there are,
there are,
there is l,
Ron Hubbard scripture that dictates that
homosexuals are perverts.
They're one point one on the tone scale,
which is the same as John List's,
oddly enough,
but it's very,
very low.
Basically,
you are kind of broken,
deceitful,
a devious character.
Journalists are one point,
one of the tone,
same as us,
but,
and that she,
I think quite explicitly,
explicitly.
I mean,
I could go down and that explains a lot
about why it's so hard to make a
documentary in practical terms,
why they don't cooperate with
documentaries.
They just see you as a pervert,
you know,
if someone who's dedicated to the,
to the,
uh,
basement of humanity and so someone
who's holding humanity back from being
what it should be,
but that's just incredible that he's
managed to define journalists under that
category,
the very people that we rely upon to
investigate the truth and,
and,
and express that truth.
Thanks.
Disseminate that true to the general
public.
Those people are perverts and,
and um,
yeah,
and that scripture as well,
you know what I mean?
So,
so it's not like you can argue against
it until,
I mean one of the big things they're up
against is any attempt,
most,
uh,
kind of malfunctioning regimes,
whether it's a corporate entity or
something else.
You say,
this isn't working,
let's try something else.
So much of what happened in scientology,
this was explained to me by one of our
sources in the in the film,
I'm a guy called Marty Rathman,
who was very high up in scientology.
He said something could be working
extremely badly inside scientology,
but if it came out of Hubbard,
then you couldn't really change it.
Hubbard apparently once said,
oh,
the best way to wash windows is using
vinegar.
Don't use windex,
use vinegar,
and because of that,
whenever they washed windows in the sea
org and the inner sanctums of
Scientology,
they had to use vinegar because Hubbard
said that was how you was supposed to do
it and nothing can be changed.
It's a bit like Mormons.
I mean now Mormons,
I don't know how they got rid of.
They say that you don't have to be
polygamous,
but so it's like turning an aircraft
carrier around.
If it comes from basically,
if it's Gospel,
then how do you,
how do you refer,
you know,
God's changed his mind is basically what
you have to say.
Well,
that is the real problem with religion
because we all recognize that no one
person has ultimate truth and especially
when you're just going through this life
trying to figure out yourself,
trying to figure out what is this all
about,
this strange spinning ball that's
floating in the sky and were hurling
through infinity and what is the purpose
of this existence?
And there's a lot of open ended
questions that never have any answers.
So when someone comes along and they
have this rigid ideology where things
are very clearly defined,
you must ask who is defining these
things?
Who is this person that is beyond
reproach and when that person is a
yellow tooth weirdo that's dressed like
a captain with some medals that he put
himself on his own jacket and he's a
science fiction author who wrote more
bullshit than any human beings ever and
wrote bad books.
I mean,
he's a bad writer.
I've only,
I haven't read any of it.
I've read,
I've tried to read dianetics uh,
several times.
It's almost unreadable in my view.
Have you tried to make Diana bought
dianetics once a late night before the
Internet?
There was a late night infomercial.
I've always been a person who's really
in a self help and psychology because I
was,
I've always tried to figure out like
what is it about why,
why do people sabotage themselves,
why do I get lazy,
why do I not fulfill some of my goals?
And so I really got into like Anthony
Robbins and I got into a lot of
psychology books and self help books and
one night I was at home and I was
watching this commercial for dianetics,
so I said,
all right,
I'm going to call this.
And I called and I guess I gave my
credit card number or whatever it was.
And this is while you were an actor at
this point?
I was working at quite successful.
Yeah,
I mean they wouldn't.
Okay.
If they saw you coming,
they would have.
Absolutely.
That would have made their year.
Well,
I never went in.
I've never went there,
but I did in the future.
I did do the meter thing,
but that was way later.
So this is like 1994 when I first came
to Hollywood and I was alone in my
apartment in north Hollywood pop,
probably lonely trying to figure things
out and just got here by buy this
fucking thing.
Those people sent me pamphlets and
paperwork and an invitation to seminars
and this thing and that thing for a
decade.
I mean,
it just never ended.
It was like weekly,
monthly,
constant.
This.
They're very,
very relentless in their pursuit.
And if you looked at what their
pamphlets were saying,
it was all really reasonable enticing
stuff.
It was all about improving yourself is
all about fulfilling your goals,
eliminating negative thoughts,
eliminated other people's negative
thoughts that are influencing the way
you view your life.
Eliminating the,
uh,
effect of past experiences that were
negative and that may have defined you
in some way.
Yeah,
all of that.
But that's basically Freud basically.
Yeah.
It's Freud with a lie detector hooked up
to a lie detector that in essence is
auditing.
The problem is when you read dianetics,
you realize how loopy it is in my view
at.
And in fact,
it,
because some times,
and I,
I,
I praise this sort of skeptical minded
approach where people say,
well,
what's your problem with scientology?
You know,
all religions are Kooky.
But the fact is,
is just exhibit a is just read dianetics
if you read the Bible,
it's got loony stuff in it,
but it's got passages of transcendent
poetry and,
and just parables that you could
meditate on and a beautifully written
in,
in the translated English,
um,
you read dianetics and it's just
childish stuff about literally things
about,
Oh,
a lot of your problems may be because
when you were in Utero as a fetus,
your father try to,
uh,
bought you,
your father,
tried to abort the fetus are,
and you can still remember that and
that's holding you back.
And at the same time a record was
playing and every time you hear that
record,
it's sort of this sort of Pavlov mixed
with really weird.
I'm totally unscientific ideas.
And,
and then it expands to past lives.
So it's traumas or bad memories from
previous lifetimes.
And at that point I was just like,
I'm not on this ship.
I was not a before but even more.
It's,
it's hard to be honest,
I think,
but that's what we were saying earlier
about rigid ideologies that rigid
ideologies are always problematic
because there's so many open ended
questions when it comes to being a human
being on earth.
And that is a problem with religions.
And that was one of the things that
religions do by creating these rigid
ideologies is they make things so that
you don't have to question stuff and
that gives some people comfort if you
know that these are the rules and you
don't have to think about why
homosexuality is bad or why,
you know,
fill in the blank,
whatever the,
whatever the issue is.
When someone defines something like that
for you,
it makes it so you have less questions
and you have comfort in these truths,
you know,
air quotes.
Um,
but that's not good for anybody.
So it's bad for everyone involved
because there are some things that I
think we've all learned a be nice to
people and it feels better to them.
Feels better to you.
You have a healthier existence when you
have harmony with your neighbors and
when you can create a good community of
people that are being harmonious
together and friendly together.
It's a really nice place to live.
Those are pretty.
That's a pretty much a universal truth.
You know,
there's a bunch of those that exist,
but even those can be debated and
discussed and you know,
you find,
you know,
wha various approaches to the end goal
of,
of happiness.
Whenever you have someone who wrote
a bunch of Wacky Shit like this and then
you have seemingly intelligent people
defending it.
Like that woman that we were discussing
when that woman was,
she did not seem stupid at all.
No,
I'm sure she will reliably informed
because in the,
in the film we go off and meet her ex
husband who's now no longer in
scientology and he describes her as a
very sensitive,
caring person.
A lot of the assertiveness.
She,
she,
she shows,
I think she probably acquired through a
scientology and and and,
and a lot of scientology training in
terms of what it imparts to people is a
quality of being,
direct,
being assertive,
being confident,
being in charge and being okay with sort
of dominating the situations that you're
in.
It's one of the reasons that I think it
appeals a lot to actors because it,
it,
it works.
I think for people who have any sort of
insecurity or who are going into
situations of uncertainty and it allows
you to almost reprogramming your
circuits in some way and be okay about
using assertive body language and speech
and it also imparts a sense that you
have all the traits necessary to save
humanity from itself.
Not just humanity on earth but
throughout a time and space and it is
your obligation to ensure that those
truths are saved,
saved for posterity,
and communicated as widely as possible
in a totally unadulterated fashion.
Because any adulteration of the message
means that not only do they not work,
they become toxic and dangerous.
It seems to me that there's a bunch of
things going on and that there's some
aspects of it that maybe could be
beneficial that they could extract from
that.
Almost like these people that have
abandoned scientology can start
scientology lights.
Well,
they do.
They are doing that.
Are they?
Yeah.
But one of the funny things is once you
have scientology light,
it's called the indie movement
independent scientology,
and it's often make an analogy is made
with Martin Luther and protestantism.
You know,
when,
you know,
people said,
the,
there's nothing in the Bible about the
papacy.
Really.
There's nothing about selling
indulgences and having palaces in Rome
and the Vatican.
So actually really there's just stuff in
the Bible about following Jesus and
reading the Bible.
So shouldn't that be what we were doing?
And so they go off.
You have protestantism.
The trouble with the independent
movement is,
um,
it turns out that if you remove the,
the raw predatory money raising side and
the,
and the sort of fundamentalist
controlling side,
you get something a bit wishy washy
that's more or less indistinguishable
from many other self help creates,
it sort of loses its potency.
It's almost that the,
the authoritarian dimension of,
uh,
of the,
of scientology and the way in which your
demands total obedience from its
followers is intrinsic to its ability to
have an effect that's fascinating.
Um,
people do in some some way gravitate
towards discipline and um,
that you see that in the military,
like the benefit of.
So.
Yes sir.
No Sir.
That's one of the things I talk about in
the film is,
I mean we talked as well about the
appeal of scientology.
Why do people defend it?
So it works for some people.
I think there's an obvious thing if the
thin end of the wedge,
you know,
you get in knee deep and then you think,
well I've come in this far.
So even though I've got doubts,
I got a little further.
And then you sort of reach a tipping
point of commitment where it becomes
almost embarrassing to back out.
You're sort of $100,000 or more in your
10 years in your family is annoyed with
you.
A lot of them,
you don't see you,
you read this.
It's very hard to walk away from that
commitment.
Uh,
so there's,
there's all these powerful.
I'm really compelling reasons for why.
But the,
the other part of it is,
and this is the part that I as an
outsider appreciate and I own up to in
the film,
is that there's something grandiose.
It's a bit like trump,
right?
You see these gilded casinos,
you see these towering shiny buildings,
you know,
they kind of over the top and grotesque,
but they're also sort of majestic and
imperial.
And if you ever watched scientology
footage,
there's,
some of it's on youtube and you see how
they are very good at a certain kind of.
I'm over the top aesthetic.
Do you know what I mean?
Almost a kind of re Leni Riefenstahl ask
'em with lights and flaming Brazier's
and thousands of people surging up with
in unison.
And it has an effect,
you sort of think,
wow,
these guys know how to run a show.
If you go into any org,
have you been into an.
They call them all because when the
organization.
Okay,
so near where I'm staying in Los Felix,
there's one,
it's on Hillhurst I think,
and you go in and it feels like you're
kind of in a religious library,
sorta,
sorta designed by jp two man,
you know,
that like the catalog company and it had
sort of old globes and kind of
distressed wooden furniture and,
and wicker chairs and it feels like it's
kind of like slightly colonial golden
age of exploration feel.
I know what I mean.
And it feels very,
it feels very sort of swept up in this
narrative of we're in a place where
there's adventure and,
and,
and in a certain sense of order and,
and actually this sort of seductive
quality to it.
Yeah.
There's a seductive quality to it.
A lot of
religions.
Oh yeah.
I find a seductive quality to people
that are very confident in what they're
saying and this,
this ultimate truth that they're
espousing.
And um,
I went to the Vatican recently and one
of the things that was really apparent
to me was the sheer scale and the,
the vast,
the size of St Peter's not Saint Peter's
Cathedral.
It's a school pages,
isn't it?
Yeah.
The basilica.
Thank you.
Um,
the,
which was just,
to me the most amazing thing I think
I've ever seen as far as like a human
creation,
the most amazing thing I've ever seen in
my life other than cheech and eatsa
other than the Mayan Pyramids.
I was just stunned by the amount of work
in the hundreds of years of work that
had gone into creating that.
But when you're there,
the overall scale of it is so.
It's so immense that it makes you feel
pure and it makes you feel small.
It makes you feel insignificant in the
greater picture.
And I think that that is a,
that's a big factor with a lot of
religions,
is to eliminate the power of the
individual by making you feel diminished
by the sheer scale of what you're seeing
and what,
what the,
the,
the hall that you're in.
I'm sure.
I'm sure that's intimidating,
very much so.
Yeah,
and that's one other thing which,
which is,
uh,
you know,
last year on the slightly on the back of
doing the scientology program,
I was trying to,
I was living in the UK and I was trying
to get a program going about a
fundamentalist Islam or not even
fundamentalist actually beyond where
it's extreme radical Islam,
so cold,
you know,
uh,
basically people who support isis of
which there are some in the UK,
although they're hard to interview
because it's actually a crime to,
uh,
to glorify terrorism is what it's
called.
And so they have to talk very gingerly
around the subject.
But if you get into a debate about
someone who is sincerely committed to
isis brand of Sunni Islam,
right?
Where they're saying,
actually,
yeah,
sex slaves are okay.
They,
they'll say like,
slaves isn't quite the right term,
but we're approved that and blah,
blah,
blah.
And then your throat.
They say,
well,
by what authority do you challenge what
we believe?
Right?
When you start coming at them with some
kind of humanistic,
secular,
liberal sort of view of life and you try
to explain,
well,
I'm not basing my,
I don't have an authority as such,
you know,
like,
I,
I'm not preaching a religion,
I'm just saying,
you know,
it's kind of better to be nice to
people.
And they said,
but based on what,
under what authority that you,
you find that you actually don't really
have,
it's surprisingly difficult when you're
thrown back on first principles to make
the case for um,
uh,
sort of sensitive a secular way of doing
things.
Does that make sense?
You know,
one of the appeals of,
I think whether it's scientology or
Islam or,
or,
um,
Christianity,
whatever form that takes,
they could say like,
we have all our answers there in a book
and God told us.
And so who told you?
And I.
Well,
no one told me I'm relying on two
millennia old tradition,
you know,
founded in,
uh,
you know,
Greco Roman times with various people,
in interpreters over the years.
But actually I,
I,
you know,
I can't really articulate that in 10
words.
Do you know what I mean?
And it's surprisingly hard.
So once you're in the prison of a faith
based system,
it's very hard to kind of leverage your
way out.
I didn't do a good job of trying to get
them out basically.
Well,
it's very difficult when they say that,
like by what authority and you realize
you don't have any and they think they
do.
Yeah.
And that's where it gets weird.
And like I don't have a book like
whatever we call the other way of doing
things,
you know.
And also you don't want to say like,
well,
in western trip,
you know,
you're trying not to because whether we
like it or not,
all our beliefs have a um,
some sort of geographic contemporarily
specificity to them as much as we might
want to say that there are golden rules
that exist through time and space.
I don't think there really are.
These are all kind of constructed golf
culture.
Yeah.
Like old truths or culture.
And so you're having to say,
well,
you know,
over the last few hundred years since
the enlightenment,
uh,
we've found that in general tortures not
a brilliant idea and capital punishments
not great and slavery is largely
discredited and they,
and they said,
well,
so this is about the Western
enlightenment,
that's your authority and I don't want
to be kinda basing it on that.
So I just,
I slightly made a hash of it after,
after I did the interview,
my producer said to me,
so yeah,
I think he kind of owned you in that.
The guy who's like the isis defend,
he's now doing,
he's doing,
he's in prison now.
That was why we didn't,
one of the reasons we didn't finish the
documentary anyway,
that's sort of going off on a tangent or
would he go to prison for,
for allegedly glorifying terrorism,
you know,
did you hear that twitter yesterday?
Bam.
Two hundred and 35,000 twitter handles.
No.
Really for promoting terrorism,
really 230,
5,000.
That's incredible how,
I mean,
I'd be intrigued to know how they define
promoting terrorism as well as it.
Would that all be Islamic or.
Yes,
or I would assume because I am not so
must've been that,
but I wonder if they cause this.
Yeah.
There was a conservative breitbart
blogger who is,
who has been Milo,
Milo.
Elena.
Yes.
That was very sketchy.
Uh,
I don't agree with what he said,
but if you,
if you really pay attention to what he
said,
it was very sketchy that they,
they banned abandoned.
I mean if you believe in freedom of
speech or you don't,
kind of.
Yes.
And what he,
what he,
all he did was,
he made a post on Breitbart about the
ghostbusters movie and it was very
critical,
even basically called it a piece of
shit.
It was a terrible movie.
He said,
is this ridiculous feminist film?
And that,
uh,
creating this all female ghostbusters
cast were all the men are buffoons and
no flame.
The African American actor,
he flamed everyone.
He called them fat and ugly and
disgusting.
And you know,
what he's saying is essentially like,
look,
I'm,
I'm bitchy,
bitchy all the time.
He's a very flamboyantly gay guy.
He's been in this podcast a couple of
times.
He's hilarious.
I find them funny on twitter,
use it.
I mean,
we used to go only abandoned.
But here's what's interesting.
He didn't do anything bad on twitter.
When you look at what he said on
twitter,
it was like nothing,
you know,
it was like nothing more than
she had said.
Leslie Jones had said a bunch of things
about him or what other people had said
about her.
And she wrote something down that was
just poor grammar.
And uh,
he.
And he wrote a,
my word barely literate,
you know,
such a shame.
Schools in America,
you know,
that's essentially what he wrote.
And then he was banned.
I mean,
that is really mild stuff.
if you,
I think what,
there's a problem,
first of all,
that he's conservative and they don't
like that and that he does a attack.
Feminists and social justice warriors
and progressives and the left and he
goes after them.
And that's essentially the whole base of
twitter.
Twitter has this,
what do they call it again?
What is their counsel?
They have
strange.
It's very orwellian.
It's like safety and trust and safety
council where things,
a watchdog group within twitter that.
Well who decides what is and is not
harassment and sorta.
It's sorta like placating people who are
recreationally outraged by other
people's opinions.
The trouble is it's a public space that
is basically a opposed to a corporate
entity.
Right.
So in essence they can do whatever they
want legally.
Right.
But it's very ideologically based.
It's very left wing.
It's very weird and a lot of ways which
I am in many ways leftwing.
So when I,
when I read what they're saying,
I agree in some ways,
but outside of actual real harassment,
I just don't think that you should be
able to just ban someone because they,
you know,
call someone a bitch or call someone
ugly.
It just,
it doesn't seem to me.
I'm not going to disagree with you.
I mean I feel as though we're in a weird
place.
We don't want to touch it slightly,
but you know,
it was around the time of Charlie Hebdo,
you know,
which was everyone was marching for the
right to be offensive.
Right.
And around the same time,
trolling became a buzzword and it was
the idea that we should stop trolling
and there's a certain disconnect we're
living through as a culture to do with
wanting to defend the right to be
offensive,
but also come down hard on trawling and
actually at a certain point you can't
have it both ways.
Yeah.
Well there was also a lot of people that
were defending what had happened in
Charlie Hebdo by saying that those
cartoons were really racist.
They were going so far,
pro Islamic to sort of a bite.
Well,
I'm going to say I.
What I heard was because I understood
this was some people saying absolutely
it's a crime.
It's hideous and people have the right
to be um,
uh,
you know,
to be offensive.
But I'm not going to valorize the
message or even hold these people up as
free speech monitors anymore than I
would do if temet SCO or Neo Nazi was
killed.
He does not thereby become a hero.
He becomes a victim of a,
of a,
of a lynch mob,
of a murderous campaign,
but I'm not there by a supporter of his
output.
Does that make sense?
Yeah.
I'm sorry.
There's a mistake here.
Um,
uh,
I have to text that to Tom.
Pablo thinks he's supposed to be here
right now.
Apparently he's outside.
He's supposed to be in next Monday.
Lips.
Tom?
Um,
yeah,
I think so.
So Penn,
for example,
the uh,
the,
I think it was penn,
the American magician,
no writers union.
It was a,
it's a guild of writers.
It supports the rights of writers around
the world in America.
And they said,
well,
we don't want to give an award.
So there was a divide in the among
parachute,
which should we give an award to Charlie
Hebdo by giving them an award,
a,
are you there by saying saying we
support you for saying that Mohammed was
a piece of shit or whatever they were
saying,
or are you,
in other words,
do you get an award for being killed?
Does that.
There's a little bit of a conflict there
in other words,
so I don't,
I,
I'm sympathetic to people who feel that
absolutely was a crime was hideous.
You know,
Islamofascism killed Charlie Hebdo,
but that does not there by mate.
Charlie Hebdo message.
A loadable creditable one.
Yes.
That's a really good point.
Because what were they doing and what
was the point of what they were doing?
Were they trust trying to be funny?
Was it parody?
I don't know if it was funny because I
don't speak French and I haven't,
I haven't really paid any attention to
the translations.
Just to me it didn't seem that fun.
But if joe,
if Julia striker right,
that,
you know,
the,
I'm not,
I don't want to compare them directly
with this,
but you know,
an offensive propagandists for the Nazis
just to take an exam.
You know,
I shouldn't even go down this road
because once you bring the Nazis ended,
it just clouds everything.
As soon as you say Hitler thought
blocking it blocks off,
he's worse than Hitler.
That's trump.
Yes.
Yeah.
I think,
um,
the,
the real bottom line is people were
killed for cartoons.
There's no way to defend that.
Right,
right.
I think everyone agrees that we agree
with that.
Does that make the cartoons good?
It certainly doesn't know.
They could be shit cartoons and people
were killed for shit cartoons.
It's wrong to kill people.
We show them cartoons,
but uh,
the cartoons are still shit.
Even l Ron Hubbard.
Would you agree with that?
Yeah.
Hopefully.
Well,
let's bring it back to scientology
because that's one of the interesting
things about scientology is that anyone
who is a quote unquote opponent of
Scientology,
they are allowed to violate pretty much
all of their principals and just go
after you.
You are the enemy.
Yes.
And the,
in you,
there's a whole different set of rules
for engaging with someone who's an sp,
like how they do that as,
that's what they do in the military too,
by the way.
You know,
they,
they abbreviate acronyms and a lot of
stuff that,
uh,
in scientology is based on hubbards
naval experience.
He loved,
they dress up in naval uniforms and
they,
he loved things like,
um,
little bulletins or anything that felt
kind of quasi military and you know what
I mean?
They love it in a way.
It's a mixture of so military can enable
stuff and then some corporate style
stuff.
What it isn't is a lot of religious
stuff like that is the one thing that
you don't get a flavor of in terms of
the way they dress and drill this in
show business,
you know,
you've got a little touch of Hollywood,
you got to touch of Navel.
You don't have any sense of it being
kind of spiritual,
religious and I'm talking the way they
style themselves,
the language they use,
they're constantly using abbreviations
that are more or less than
unintelligible to the outsider,
which by the way is a lot of how
allegedly according to the experts on
thought reform or colts so called,
they say,
but by learning a new language,
it's part of what kind of gets you
caught up in thought patterns of,
of an abusive system.
Well,
that's also military people.
If you talked to people who really have
a deep understanding of the military or
people who love the military,
they love to talk and those acronyms,
they love to use them because it sort of
lets everybody know that you're on the
inside.
Yes.
You know,
it's like when people talk about cars or
anything where it's,
um,
there's a,
there's a surface knowledge that most
people have.
Oh,
that is a Ferrari.
that is a corvette.
But then there's deep,
deep knowledge as you start going into,
you know,
the different types of gearing and the
axles and you know,
it's got 4:11 rear end and this and
that,
and you're like,
oh,
he knows he's the deep knowledge.
He has a deep knowledge of the car with
the deep knowledge of the military.
And a lot of that is sort of expressed
through acronyms.
Yes.
Yes they do.
They do,
they do stuff.
So that's a big part of how they
operate.
And I think as well,
I mean this is something I mentioned
before,
it is important to bear in mind as well
that as much as I'm scientology kind of
costs the world and us and them terms
which is very characteristic of a lot of
systems of thought that are inimical to
sort of freedom or free way of thinking.
It's us and them.
It's like Bush saying you're,
you're either with us or against us.
And in Scientology,
in a famous statement of Tom Cruise's
that he gave in 2004 when he was given a
Freedom Medal of valor at a big
scientology wold ceremony in England.
He said,
you're either in or you're either
playing on the pitch or you're out of
the arena.
You know,
that's the one when they gave him that
huge flavor flave style.
And,
and so his thing is like,
you on the pitcher get out of the arena
because there's no half measures you get
in or you're out.
And that whole idea,
like if you're not part of the solution,
then you're part of the problem is a
very dangerous,
slippery road to go down.
Because your then by definition saying
there's good guys and bad guys and if
you're not on my team,
you're a bad guy.
Well,
let's define what the solution is,
Tom,
and sit down.
Tell us about what.
What are thethe?
Agent explained to me,
how Dayton's they throw them into a
volcano.
What happens?
Well,
you know,
I'm going to sound weird now because one
of my promises that I made to myself was
that I would never gratuitously mark of
the beliefs
of scientology and one of the things
they find offensive is,
is,
is to reveal some of the secret truths
that are unveiled.
A.
Okay.
I take a step back,
was unique to scientology,
is that it's a mystery religion,
meaning that many of its beliefs around
veiled as you advance up the ladder of
enlightenment and okay,
so you don't have day one.
Get told.
Unlike with Jesus and Christianity on
day one,
you're told he died on the cross for
your sins.
Believe in him and you will be saved and
go to heaven.
There's no kind of catch on later sort
of amendment that gets made when you're
a year,
two years,
three years down the line in
Scientology,
you learn more as you go up.
Some say that that is partly something
that owes to Crowley or Alistair
Crowley,
I think it's pronounced,
that Hubbard had practiced a form of
satanism when he was living in Pasadena
in the forties,
right after the Second World War and
incorporated that aspect of it.
And it is quite a seductive idea.
The idea,
oh,
I'm going to learn more as I go on and
kind of unraveling mystery.
Um,
so,
so that is part of scientology and when
you get to own the ot levels,
which is,
once you've gone clear,
which is sort of half ot is operating
fate and yeah.
So,
so to begin with you're going clear is,
was originally the best thing you could
do.
And then subsequently there was,
he added more levels and more layers and
you get to the ot and this eight
published ot levels and ot,
three various secrets are revealed.
And I'm allegedly,
uh,
if,
if an uninitiated ot or an uninitiated
person is shown the secrets,
it makes them go crazy,
but one of the things that,
but I,
you know,
you're not in a documentary about
scientology rejoices in telling you
what,
what the ot stuff is.
And I think you were about to touch on
it.
I promised myself that I wouldn't reveal
them because I sort of felt,
you know,
it's a little cheap when all these
documentaries,
um,
say,
you know,
this is what you $100,000 in or 200 or
500,000,
you're going to learn what happens with
[inaudible] and then we,
you know,
they spoil the surprise for everyone.
Um,
and I also felt like I'd like to be able
to say to,
if I ever meet a scientology,
I mean,
I'm sure I've met some,
but without knowing it,
but you know,
if I ever meet Tom Cruise or back,
I want to be able to say like,
you know what?
I didn't ever do anything.
I just,
I have a right to know my truth and
express my truth.
I don't want to mock you.
I don't want to make you have a right to
believe what you want to believe and if
you think you know,
no more than enforced the Jewish guy to
eat pork or,
or terrorist baronet to cut his hair.
And so I'm not going to say to an ot,
uh,
you know what?
I know what happens to ot three and it
sounds like a bunch of junk.
Well,
you don't even have to say that's a
bunch of junk,
but just expressing,
I think there's what we know.
Okay,
well we know about their doctrine or
their,
whatever you want to call it,
their scripture.
And there's an amazing moment in the
documentary,
the hbo where it was,
it was
Paul Higgs.
Is that what gets Haggis?
Haggis thank gets to ot three.
Yeah,
you're going to say,
fine.
He gets to ot three and he starts
reading some of the handwritten stuff by
l Ron Hubbard.
There's a whole palava.
It's an interesting bit in the book too.
Do you remember?
Like he's guided into a room and
literally it's almost like they take it
out of a safety deposit box and kind of
open it up with gloves of white gloved
hands and then there's a hand written
kind of piece of parchment inside
written in Hubbard's manuscript and you
read it in that room and then.
And then the guy has a little routine.
He follows the person who brought you
in,
comes in and says,
has it been read and comprehended or
something like that.
Right?
And then you've read it and you go like
a yes,
and then I ask and it shall be done or
something.
And then they put it back in and take it
away.
Yeah.
Well it must be.
It's a great sense of theater.
Like I love.
It's like being in the Mason,
so I mean all that secret squirrel
stuff.
It's very appealing.
I forgot about secret squirrel.
Yeah.
But I think it's important to talk about
what we know about what that is about.
What is fine.
I mean it's on the Internet.
What I would say is what they believe is
that man is an immortal in a mortal
spirits and you have not you,
you are not your body.
You are the spirit and the spirit is a
Fayton.
That's the term they use for spirits and
your spirit.
You,
in essence have lived multiple lifetimes
in multiple bodies going back,
Millennia and going forward,
Millennia.
And that's not a unique thought.
No,
I mean unique to them.
you have that in Buddhism.
But unlike in Buddhism,
the transmigration of souls does not
resides only in humans.
Right?
You,
I don't think you can become a,
a chipmunk,
right?
Which you can in Buddhism I think,
can you not.
You not know.
And I think you know,
depending on how you're calmer is nest
number one.
And number two,
which is even more important or just as
important,
is that you can carry your memories
through the lifetimes using a
scientology.
And the gift that scientology gives you
is the ability to retain your memories
and your identity across multiple
lifetimes.
And that's why it's so important to a
scientologist to,
um,
to recollect his or her past lifetimes.
Because it suggests that you're sort of,
you're on,
you're now on your cosmic destiny and
you will carry it forward into your.
When you,
when you next incarnate.
These are all unique ideas.
I mean they're there,
they're interesting,
but when you know the source of all of
it and yet they ignore it and they,
they,
they choose to not pay attention to the
other things that he read or wrote
rather like a battlefield earth.
That movie with John Travolta Grc that I
never saw.
That one.
It's wonderful.
It's right up there with GRC showgirls.
Yes,
I have seen showgirls.
Showgirls is like a tour De Force of
writing a movie while you're high on
cocaine.
Hoven.
Yeah.
Directed it.
It's a great combination.
It's in one of the best unintentional
comedy that's ever been mined.
All you could.
Hobans a brilliant director and I think
and starship troopers.
He made and I'm the first Robo Cop he
knew.
I think he knew what he was doing.
I think he has a keen eye for camp and
thought this is hilarious.
Don't you may ask the house?
Maybe not.
It could have been,
it could have been,
um,
I think they were just coked out of
their mind and they made a wacky fucking
movie and they probably thought it was
great,
but fuck it.
Print it out.
Let's go out.
Let's,
let's at the Ivy and I don't know,
I mean,
I think they were just out of their
mind.
I mean,
if you watch that film,
there's a scene where,
what is her name?
Elizabeth Berkley.
And the other guy from,
um,
I can't remember who blue lagoon is.
It was from.
Was He from?
Was that TV show that he was on the
handsome on Kyle.
What the fuck's his name?
Mcconnell lock.
A lot of Caughlin.
This is Kyle mclachlan.
They're having sex in a pool and she
starts flopping around like a fish.
She literally starts having spasms,
like if you continued to have sex with
her,
I feel like that's rape.
Like this is a woman who is having a
goddamn seizure and you're going to keep
having sex with her.
Have you ever seen the scene?
No.
Seen the movie.
So yes.
Yeah,
it must have.
It's wonderful.
She,
she starts,
they're having sex and she starts
flailing like as if she's having a
goddamn stroke.
She was in the middle of a heart attack
or a seizure and that choice is the only
thing that haunts me about that movie.
Like maybe it is,
maybe it was camp,
maybe they're doing that on purpose.
I think it was,
but I read an interview with the
director of,
um,
of battlefield,
his battlefield,
and he,
he apparently is a pretty good director
and had,
he's a European,
I think maybe French and I think he just
didn't know what he was walking into and
I think he didn't even,
he didn't really check out what he was,
what the Gig was.
Well that was a product of John
Travolta.
Travolta was labor and it's wonderfully
bad.
Yeah.
There's a funny bit in,
in going in the book where they,
I think Cruz sees it and,
and it's like,
this is so embarrassing for him.
He's really upset about it.
Well,
he was upset that they showed that video
of him saluting to Lrh.
They salute when they got the metal.
All that crazy shit.
Yeah,
that's all.
It's all over youtube recruitment.
Was he upset about that being.
Oh,
they try to get that taken down and of
course it spread like wildfire through
the Internet because you just,
you just can't.
You can't take things like that down.
No,
it's classic.
Although a lot of stuff's been,
there are a lot of great scientology
videos that have been taken down.
Really?
Yes.
There's a famous one.
It's very hard to find.
It's the orientation video that was
shown to new parishioners.
Uh,
this is back in the eighties and it was
done by an infomercial pitch man
who was then a scientologist and then,
um,
subsequently left,
you know,
by the way,
do you know one of the,
they don't cost scientologists in
scientology a commercials.
Do you know why?
Why?
Because they blow to off like they leave
and then they no longer want to be in
the video or it becomes embarrassing to
have someone speak.
Can you imagine if Leah Remini was in a
commercial for scientology?
They'd never be able to use it again.
Right.
So they call it sort of insurance
because they want to be able to use the,
they spent a lot of money on the
commercial.
They don't want to be embarrassed when
the scientologists who's The star of the
commercial leave scientology and says
that they were brainwashed.
That's their actual reason I'm told.
Yeah.
How many of them left?
Uh,
well I mean say the retention rate.
No,
they're very,
they keep the data very close to their
chest.
So I know that they have,
um,
they say millions,
I think they say $40,
million and some vast amount worldwide.
I know that in,
on Tony Ortega's blog,
he's,
I think there's a US census data that,
that the,
that perhaps suggesting in the US it
might be 20 or $30,000.
We should probably get that fact
checked.
But I believe I read that there are more
people who identify as Jed,
I,
that's their religion and they're all
just decided a long process to become a
jetta.
Or can you just,
uh,
climate.
I think this is a long process,
but it's very cheap.
It's a good thing.
Oh,
well I've watched all the movies.
I think I'm in.
Um,
I just,
it's amazing to me that this exists.
I understand that it exists.
I intellectually,
when I sit back and I look at the,
the,
the many,
many different religions and many,
many different ideologies that people
subscribe to in the,
the vast amount of people out there that
are searching for truth and an answer
and end something to belong to.
Even that,
even though all those things make sense
to me intellectually,
I'm still fascinated.
I'm still so puzzled that in 2016 with
the Internet,
with all the access to information that
we have today,
but that still exists.
It's a [inaudible] and you look forward
and you wonder,
it will you.
Is this going to fizzle out?
But I think what they've done is they've
kind of created a,
a marketing juggernaut that is,
if not immune to but at least highly
resistant to any attempt to discredit or
undermine.
So I,
I read a thing that said,
well,
it's religion that sells secrets,
right?
That's its USP.
You advance something,
you pay more money to get the more
secret levels and the Internet is
Kryptonite to that because the internet
is a,
is a machine revealing secrets.
Yeah.
Wiki leaks and whatnot.
And you can google anything.
So,
so that will be scientology's waterloo
will be the fact that we now have
searchable data.
Um,
but I,
it shows no signs of coming apart,
you know,
that the numbers may not be high,
but the amounts of revenue coming in and
are a huge,
from what I can tell and I get the
feeling that um,
well you just have to see how,
you know,
the amount that they're able to spend on
advertising,
the number of new buildings that go up,
uh,
so however small it may be,
it has a huge.
I'm punching power.
Where are they getting the money from?
Well,
it's an interesting point are the first
thing is that it's it,
it's structured almost like a
Mcdonald's.
So,
and in fact,
interestingly in 1950,
the year that dianetics was published
was also the first year that Mcdonald's
was established as pointed out by,
I don't know if you've ever read Janet
Reitman's book inside Scientology.
It came up a year before Larry writes
book.
I'm going clear,
but,
so it was slightly,
it's,
it's done.
That was stolen by going clear.
But it's also an excellent book and a
great primary,
if you enjoyed going clear.
I really highly recommend inside
scientology.
She points this out that in 1950
Mcdonald's was invented and so was
dianetics.
Um,
so they basically kind of a franchise
system in which they are sort of selling
the,
they own the property of the,
of the various buildings in which
scientology is sold.
And then they licensed the materials but
they can't really,
you know,
some of the franchisees can lose money,
but scientology itself can't really lose
money because they're just getting rents
from the people who are,
who are selling the scientology.
Does that make sense?
The services.
But it doesn't make sense that they get
that much revenue from that.
Again,
take real estate holders.
So they have huge amounts of real
estate.
The other part of it is that they,
because it's a religion,
the money is a tax deductible or
whatever,
like they don't pay taxes on it in
essence.
And so I think,
I think that means that it's very hard
for them to lose money.
It's a huge,
it's a huge cushion against financial
failure.
Well,
that was a really disturbing part of the
documentary.
It showed how they became a tax exempt
religion.
The,
the,
the government essentially caved under
the threat of massive amounts of
lawsuits.
Yes.
Yeah,
they were,
um,
basically the scientologists found a way
to pressure individual irs employees to
the point where their lives have become
extremely hard so they,
they'd settled.
But what year was that?
When I want to say I'm going to get this
right?
Ninety two,
I would say 92,
93.
It's amazing that that's upheld.
I know.
But then again,
uh,
I mean,
what the benchmark for being,
for having charitable status is not that
high.
Look at the Clinton Foundation right
there.
There are the people scrutinizing what
qualifies as a charitable enterprise do
not seem to be.
I'm working,
especially you on top of their game.
And um,
so yeah,
I think once that's in place,
I think the other part of it is,
so you paid one of their routes for
finances,
you pay for services,
you turn up,
you spent,
I want auditing,
so I'll get an order package for $300
and you get whatever,
five sessions.
But the other thing is they solicit
donations and five or six times a year
they have large events.
And uh,
that's the footage of Tom Cruise,
is it one of these events?
And they cut their,
like these huge Hollywood style award
ceremonies where they pack hundreds of
Scientology's into an auditorium and
they both looked quite impressive.
So to the outside they look kind of
grandiose and impressive,
but they are in essence a kind of live
infomercial event where everyone who's
there is then aggressively reged,
which means that they're aggressively
hit up for donations.
Does that make sense?
So anytime you see one of those events,
all those people who were at the event
before they can leave,
someone comes up to them and says,
how committed to sign Tom Gru,
we would sincerely appreciate an
expression of your with your support and
the guilt tripped into making a
donation,
a tax deductible donation.
And I'm,
I'm sorry,
I know I'm rambling,
but there's a lot of information so,
so,
so they get huge amounts of money for
that and that money.
Then I'm.
One of the good things about that is
that can never be revoked like if you
leave.
So one of the problems they had in the
past was if you,
if you spend $10,000 on credit and say I
love scientology,
it's going to be amazing and then you
like a thousand dollars in your,
into your services.
You're like,
this isn't doing anything I want to
leave.
And then you ask for your money back and
it's very hard for you to get your money
back.
Whereas the donations that are made to
something called the Ias in Association
of Scientologists,
you can't get those back once you leave,
which I'll make it very simple for you,
is very rich scientologists who make
large donations.
Basically.
There's a guy called Bob Duggan,
has a multibillionaire who's donated
literally tens of millions.
I mean,
and there's a lot.
There's a lot of actors.
Who mean.
Well,
Leah Remini,
one of the,
um,
she's one of the most famous detractors,
right person who's left,
right?
Right.
Until she was like one of his most
famous supporters.
But that's a,
that's weird because like,
her turnaround was like that.
I,
um,
I know I have a lot of respect for.
I mean,
I think there's a lot of guys like this
guy who was,
I was talking about this pitch,
the infomercial pitch man who did the
orientation video that was taken down
from youtube.
It's called Larry Anderson,
right?
And He,
I really wanted to interview him for our
film because I just thought the
orientation video is so funny.
It's one of those,
some is this video where they say,
uh,
he goes,
welcome to scientology.
You if at the end of this video you
decide this is not for you,
that's fine.
You're welcome to leave.
Just as you're free to jump off,
throw yourself off a bridge or blow your
brains out.
So it's just very over the top kind of
thing.
It's just ludicrous.
But he left scientology so they couldn't
show it anymore,
but he left an Mo,
like most high profile defectors.
He just didn't want anything more to do
with it.
He's just like,
I'm done.
And very often they cut a deal where
they say find the scientology will say
like,
we'll let you do the x,
y,
and Z,
whether it's get some money back,
speak to your people,
your friends and family who is still in
scientology,
but we don't want you speaking out.
And so then the,
the,
the effect will be like,
okay,
fine,
I want a simple life.
But Leah Remini to her credit has
actually gone out there and absolutely
made it a mission to,
to call them out.
How far did she get?
I don't know where she,
I think she was quite far.
Most of the actors.
Um,
I think actors,
they're considered people of influence
and so they get certain amount of
services for free.
That's the impression I have.
And so I think,
and I think they're encouraged to go up
the bridge quite quickly.
I had a neighbor who was a scientologist
and he wanted to buy a piece of
property.
We had a discussion about this,
how I found out he was scientologists he
sent out of nowhere,
you know,
we,
we started talking about this.
He's like,
yeah,
I'm thinking about buying it.
But uh,
right now my wife is about to go clear
and uh,
I go,
what's,
this is a long time ago.
I go,
well,
what does that mean?
And then he starts expressing what it
means and that she's no longer going to
be influenced by negative thoughts and
this is going to cost $50,000 and it's
probably more now probably is the
nineties,
but $50,000 for a ceremony where you're
no longer going to be influenced by
negative thoughts.
And then you find out actually footnote,
there's this other thing you have to
deal with.
And then there's another like 15 levels.
So yeah,
I,
it's a funny,
it's a funny one.
Did you talk to Leah Remini?
Uh,
we approached,
uh,
you know,
we,
I should explain that we took a specific
approach.
We knew going into it.
I had been just stating this idea for
years and I'd been fascinated with
scientology going back to the late
eighties when I was a student and then I
remember in [inaudible] 90 or
[inaudible] 91,
I took a tour around the l Ron Hubbard
life exhibit there on Hollywood
Boulevard and,
and had this weird feeling of,
if you've ever gone in where you just
think wow,
it's like they took a person who was
kind of an average Scifi writer and
attempted to make him sound like he was
the second coming of Jesus.
And so everything is spun and it's,
it's just a weird feeling,
you know,
seeing a whole museum dedicated to
someone who seems to have been a
relatively unremarkable person.
Do you know what I mean?
And so they're working extremely hard.
Say like he was one of the youngest ever
Eagle Scouts to ever qualify in the
state of Montana.
And you're like,
well,
and I was like,
my dad was an eagle scout.
And um,
and so then I remember halfway through I
thought,
well this is,
this was funny for 10 minutes.
And then an hour later when you're on
this guided tour,
I've had enough.
And so I said,
I really need to leave.
Where do you need to go?
Like,
what's so important that it's more
important than you've seen in the rest
of the.
And I suddenly felt under pressure that
uncomfortable feeling of like,
oh wow.
And I had to pretend that I needed to be
somewhere just to get out of the
building.
Anyway,
so years go by and I think I'd love to
make a program about it and then I could
never quite find that I approached them
and they said,
um,
long story short,
we're not really interested.
We,
you know,
we,
they took me on a tour of the celebrity
center.
They strung me along for a bit,
but it was pretty clear quite quickly
that they weren't going to let me in.
So a few more years went by and I was
approached by a Hollywood producer
called Simon Chinn,
who,
who made a man on wire and searching for
sugar man.
So He's,
you know,
he's well credentialed and he's like,
you should do something about
scientology.
I gave him the spiel about why I hadn't
because they won't let me in.
And as you know,
my way of making documentaries is by
invitation,
you know,
I make an approach and people say yes
and they let me in.
Oh,
you're very polite in Europe and
actually,
you know,
I've done whatever in a big game hunting
or the Westboro Baptist church or Gurus,
you know,
in India.
But it's always,
I say like,
can we come and film?
And they say yes and we do it.
So I,
I just couldn't get my head around how
you make a film where the people don't
want you to make the film.
As I knew they didn't.
And have it be still true to what I do
in some way.
And I didn't want it to be a kind of
just poking them for the sake of it,
type of thing.
Anyway,
we decided that there was a way of doing
it,
using reenactments in which we took a
sort of approach to the reenactments,
where the whole process of casting and
reenacting,
how you do scientology using actors was
filmed.
In other words,
we filmed casting a character to play
Tom Cruise costing an actor to play
David miscavige a roleplaying the
different lines and used x
scientologists to kind of co-direct.
So they were like,
this is how,
yeah,
this is how you do it and this is what
scientology is.
And this was what it was like when I was
in scientology.
And really a part of it was knowing that
once we did that in and around
Hollywood,
because Hollywood is so central to
scientology,
they would get wind of what we were
doing and would start coming to us.
So there'd be this wraparound of them
and sure they shut up and stop filming
us.
Uh,
and it turns out they were making a
documentary about me making my film
about scientology.
So then it becomes this sort of whole,
when is that getting released?
January.
It's,
it's,
it's out in the UK.
In October.
January.
Not Mean Yours.
The one on you.
Oh,
there one.
Um,
you know,
I think it'll come out.
It's a great question.
I,
I'm surprised it's not out yet.
I think it'll come out probably in
January.
I don't.
And what do you think it'll be about?
I think it'll be a lot like what they
have done to other journalists.
They did one to give me.
They did one on um,
Larry,
right.
They do them on x,
scientologists midair of sufficient kind
of profile.
It will be a 10 to 15 minute thing.
They,
they,
they'll extract any photograph where I
look like a Dick,
you know,
what I look ugly or ludicrous.
Any ill advised bit of publicity I ever
did where I was promoting a series and I
was like,
it looked goofy.
They'll say like this is a serious
journalist and then they'll take quotes
from interviews out of context to make
me sound like a,
either a goofball or,
or kind of malicious a deceiver.
And um,
you know,
if you want to really see the DNA of
scientology,
I often think because occasionally I get
caught in this mindset of like,
you know,
what is,
so what is it?
Just another religion.
There's no better or worse than other
religions really.
And then some,
you know,
sometimes you can slightly lose,
you go native slightly or you're on
their websites and your thing like it
covered.
Some of this makes sense.
But if you look at how they attack their
enemies,
they're there.
So unlike other religions,
certainly unlike Christianity for the
most part,
so official scientology's pronouncements
when they attack x members and
journalists are so sort of tabloid and
childish and so malicious and nasty,
you really see into something deep about
them,
their mindset,
because their view is,
you mentioned,
is that if you're a suppressive person,
I,
someone who's attempting to hold
scientology back then you are fair game.
Anything they could do almost anything
to try and put you out of business.
Do you think that these documentaries,
whether it's going clear the book by
Lawrence Wright or the other woman,
what was the name of Janet Reitman was
her bucket inside scientology.
You think that all this data,
this accumulative data reaches any of
the members that are inside scientology?
They don't.
They don't ever examined it.
Oh No,
no way.
It's,
it's a,
it's considered end theater,
which is a scientology term.
It means in turbulator good data.
I love guy.
This is like catnip to explaining this
stuff kind of.
I just,
it's like I said,
I was steeped in it for three years.
Kind of absorbing all your whole life or
what?
Not Constantly but,
but you know,
you would spend a few days kind of hours
would go by the end of it.
You were emerging like have I learned
anything?
All I know now is just absurd terms.
The no use to anyone like and Feta and.
But in turbulators data energies,
fader is Dayton's a spirits.
Data is spiritual positive,
spiritual energy,
but interpolated is bad.
So it's basically.
And Theater.
It's kind of bad for your energy.
I think so.
It's [inaudible] to,
for you to be in scientology and it can
be exposed to anything negative,
anything critical of scientology,
so encouraged to be off the internet and
to be off,
you know,
don't consume anything you think might
be critical.
They're encouraged to be off the
internet.
Wow.
Well I should say I should say that
applies to people within the sea org,
in the inner circle of scientology and I
explain that it's a really important
distinction because I'm absolutely
certain that there's plenty of extremely
nice,
well adjusted scientologists people who
consider themselves scientologists
neighbor.
There's a really nice guy,
betty was and I'm sure I'm.
Everything I hear about Beck,
the musician is that he's a nice guy and
um,
you know,
I'm sure Giovanni Ribisi isn't,
is a nice guy and yeah.
Really?
You didn't know that that guy's in.
Yeah.
Who?
And Jenna Elfman.
I mean she makes sense.
Really.
Juliette Lewis.
Yeah,
I bet she's nice.
I bet she's very nice.
She,
she and I have gone back and forth.
We've talked to each other through a
messages on twitter.
Yeah.
How did it get her in talk to Danny
Masterson?
He's from easily that 17th show he's
into.
Yeah.
Woo.
And Jason Lee,
I think.
I think he might be out.
You know who I mean?
My name is.
Oh yeah,
that guy's in.
Yeah,
man.
You,
you didn't spend very long down the
rabbit hole.
Well,
my rabbit hole was not limited.
I try to avoid any rabbit hole that
involve celebrities,
but scientology is predicated on one
thing l Ron Hubbard got right.
Was the idea that if you get celebrities
in,
yes,
then you,
you've got a kind of golden ticket to
reaching the masses.
Yeah.
Um,
I jokingly thought about joining when I
first came here,
I was like,
maybe that's the move,
just get it become a scientologist.
You could make a documentary about
scientology.
That would be totally different because
I'm actually,
maybe we've blown it by even talking
about it,
but if you'd gone under,
I don't think they would listen.
They would probably fucking hate me.
Well,
it depends what you've got out there.
It's too late to a documentary maker
either.
We don't have that sort of attention
span that you have.
You could,
you could go,
you could have gone undercover.
They,
you would have been such a great scalp
for them.
They would have.
Absolutely.
Because when was the last time you heard
of an established celebrity actor
joining,
joining like,
um,
I mean,
can you imagine if maybe they can.
I mean that's when will smith,
there was a sniff that he might be going
that way and,
and it went and it didn't pan out.
But um,
that was an unbeliever and they were
trying.
There was a rumor that David Beckham
might be flirting with it,
but I mean none of these things were
born out.
What they could do for you if you were a
David Beckham or maybe even for me,
is they could act as like a gang that's
sort of like your policy covers your
back.
Absolutely.
I think that'd be.
And when I was doing the film,
I went in a totally undercover,
but I went in Norway for a sequence in
the film.
I just to sort of keep myself grounded,
to keep it all real,
you know,
because one of the challenges with when
you're not exposed,
you're not actually having day to day
contact with the subject that you're
covering.
It's very easy to slip into a us and
them mentality of your own and like,
Ooh,
scary scientologists Ooh,
they're bad.
And actually,
um,
you know,
they're not,
they're good people,
many of them.
And,
and so I wanted to make them real and I
went along to um,
scientology,
Oregon just sort of chatted to some
people until,
you know,
I'm a make documentaries and things.
I'm interested in this subject,
you know,
what's it all about?
And they really did.
One of the things they do is a fairly
hard sell,
but you got the impression that they
would 100 percent kind of take your
money.
No,
I don't accept you.
They would tell you money,
but they would absolutely,
I think be right on it.
I don't know.
I,
you know,
I kind of lost confidence in.
I was going to say 100 percent.
You got to have your back and be or
gang.
But I don't know if I really did have
that sense.
I think if you.
If they know,
if they knew you were a celebrity,
if they thought you were,
they would really go to the.
You would get special treatment.
I was in San Diego when I was filming
this television show.
We had a few hours downtime and they had
one of these booths set up where you
would go over there and hold onto the
those cans.
You meet her and I did all that.
How long did you.
How many sessions did you do or just
one?
Just one while I was there and it was
pretty good,
wasn't it?
It was boring.
Was it the guy that.
The guy who I got was very
unenthusiastic.
He's just.
It seemed like something.
They were exposed to them.
You're supposed to be unenthusiastic.
Well,
on the meters,
there's a script for how it's called
being an auditor.
When you.
When someone's auditing you in a sense
being the therapist,
they have a script.
They have to.
It's called.
They have to sit there comfortably,
but they are not supposed to show any
emotion when they're auditing,
you know,
he's doing it publicly to holding onto
this thing and asking me questions as
you read in the needle and saying yes,
and did he say that?
Is there a prior something that there's
a whole script they'd sort of say and
did you have to say like,
I had back pain and then they're like,
why would you remember what road you
went down with your,
with what you were saying?
Partly just remember thinking this guy.
It's nothing that's special.
Yeah.
The guy seemed like he,
they were forcing them to do it.
He didn't seem like this is something
that he was interested in is just really
not interested in what he was doing and
he seemed like a volunteer.
Like that's interesting.
I mean if on the,
when they're auditing they're supposed
to be somewhat blank.
A big thing in scientology is,
is I'm sort of being comfortable in
yourself and not like learning how to
stare at someone that there's a drill
that we do in the film where you have to
sit and stare at someone without saying
anything literally for like minutes,
if not hours.
And it's like,
it's actually a powerful tool because
it's slightly,
it's all about,
um,
I'm,
I'm unembarrassed bubble,
you know,
I'm gonna,
I'm gonna not,
I'm going to own any sort of sense of
awkwardness by just like I'm impermeable
to any kind of social
influence you think you can put on me.
Right.
It's one of the paradoxes of being kind
of really controlling religious movement
because so much of it is about
controlling yourself.
Do you know what I mean?
And not allowing other people's thoughts
are negative actions to control you,
control you.
And actually a big thing as well.
And one of the things Tom Cruz talks
about when he's in his video is a pts,
a SP confronting shuttering suppression.
Uh,
um,
I don't think I said they got my acronym
right.
But anyway,
his thing is,
he's like,
when he says like,
one of the best things he learned in
scientology was how to confront and
shatter suppression.
Right.
So anytime you see him in an interview
and there's a few of them on youtube
where he's big,
he thinks he's getting a cheeky
question.
You can see he kinda gets a steely look
where it's a sort of it not exactly
adversarial.
It's just like,
no,
you're out of line buddy and we're not
going to allow our interview.
Yeah.
It was devastating for his career and
short term he recovered from it,
but there was.
That was a window into madness and into
what he's really all about.
When you know that's the scary part.
I mean,
as much as I say like there's a big
chunk of it that feels kind of valid,
a normal,
maybe even therapeutic,
but when you tip into thinking that
you're the only one that you have,
you're the authority on mental illness
and that's dangerous individual issues
with people that you have not diagnosed.
You don't have any medical training
whatsoever.
You don't know what their specific
neurochemistry is.
You don't know the effect of the
medication and whether it's enhancing or
hurting them and you just have this
blanket view of psychiatry.
That was a an issue that l Ron Hubbard
had,
and if you go down sunset,
sunset on sunset,
psychiatry kills.
It's psychiatry,
the industry of death.
That's a fun often and that's one of
their centers,
right?
Yeah.
If you go in there,
they'll explain the CC her citizens'
Commission on Human Rights and here's my
issue with that.
I think prescription drugs are
overprescribed.
I think there's a real argument that
there's a lot of people that are on
antidepressants that shouldn't be on
antidepressants.
I think there's a lot of natural
alternatives.
One of them being exercise,
one of them being and enhancing your
standing in life in terms of like what
you do for a living or where you live or
you know the people that you hang out
with.
All those things can affect the way you
feel and that can be interpreted as
depression.
There's a lot of.
I mean there's a reason.
If your life is shit of all the aspects
of your life is shit.
You feel bad,
the solution is not a pill,
right?
So I think in some ways they've got
something to say that makes some sort of
sense in a weird way.
That's the dangerous part because it's a
sec.
It's with scientology into sex with a
totally valid social critique.
Right.
The trouble is if you are,
if you have someone who's
heavily psychotic and it's not,
it's not a medication induced psychosis.
Psychosis is a real medical phenomenon
and a scientology is not going to take
them on.
If you go to scientology and say,
I'm interested in scientology,
I've had a couple of psychotic breaks.
Um,
but I really think you could help me
out.
They're not going to say,
oh,
come with us.
We'll,
they'll,
they'll run a mile from you.
So they critiquing people who they have
no intention of helping themselves.
Oh Wow.
Yeah.
And if you say,
oh,
and by the way,
I've used some in the past,
I was medicated for my psychosis.
They'll say,
well,
that disqualifies you from treatment.
When I went to my one,
they said,
if you thought forms of intervention,
have you had in the past,
have you done any sort of psychiatry?
Have you had any problems like that?
And I said,
well,
no,
but I've had,
you know,
a little bit of therapy over the years
as well.
What have you done?
I said,
I did a few sessions of CBT.
Cognitive behavior therapy is kind of
bog standard,
talking about problems or things that
you could do differently.
The woman's like,
oh,
okay.
Uh,
just give me five minutes.
Okay.
And she left the room to check whether
that disqualified me and came back.
Oh yeah.
That's not a problem.
Okay,
let's carry on.
But if you had done on some sort of
medication,
said I was on Zyprexa for 10 years
because I had an episode where I thought
I was a poached egg for a few weeks that
she would've said she would have said,
oh,
well good luck with that.
And um,
you know,
don't let the door hit you on the way
out.
Oh Wow.
So they're not interested in treating
people that have had treatment?
No.
Oh,
that's weird.
No,
they say good,
you know,
tough break on this live.
Good luck in your next life.
They really check that.
But I'm pretty sure that's the case.
Oh man,
that's fascinating.
And there's an intro if you want to
read,
we don't go into this in the
documentary,
but if you can read up on,
um,
on the Internet and about cases where
there's been people who had mental
illness either within scientology,
I mean,
perhaps the most famous scandal within
scientology or the most notorious to
scientology watches was the case of Lisa
Mcpherson.
Do you know about her?
She's the one that died.
Yeah,
she's,
she's done in detail in,
um,
inside scientology.
And the Janet Reitman book,
she was a paid up scientologists.
Took it very,
very seriously.
A young woman,
maybe 30 and um,
she had a psychotic episode in Florida
and instead of being taken for a given
bed care in a facility,
she was taken by scientologists from a
hospital and I'm more or less
sequestered in a hotel for a week or
maybe longer and,
and died in the hands of the
scientology.
What was the cause of death?
I believe it was dehydration.
We should double check on that.
Wow.
That's a rough way to go.
Yeah.
And she'd been having,
you know,
total psychotic break.
She was attacking people in the who were
attempting to,
you know,
take care or holding her hostage
depending on how you define it.
And um,
you know,
there was a whole script that Hubbard
had for dealing with,
um,
people in psychosis,
but I don't think it was,
you know,
medically supported.
It was basically involved ignoring them,
keeping them secluded,
kind of locking them in a room.
Now I saw an interview with you where
you were talking about someone who used
to be a former scientologist a woman.
Uh,
she was,
she wasn't a former scientologist.
She had gone undercover to sort of
investigate that.
And uh,
you were talking about the auditing
having a positive benefit.
Yes.
I think it probably does.
I mean,
I think any kind of bolted on,
on you.
Yeah,
I mean,
the editing I did,
I only did one session and that was
with,
you know,
the main guy in the film.
It's a guy called Marty Rathbun and he
was in it.
There's a sense in which the film is as
much about him as it is about
scientology.
He was,
he was a Mr. fix it.
Within Scientology,
he was the number two to David
miscavige.
David miscavige is the guy who took over
in 1986 or thereabouts from l Ron
Hubbard and has been running it ever
since.
He's an unaccountable leader who,
uh,
is in,
in essence the pope of scientology.
And there are many allegations of him
being physically abusive towards his
followers.
Marty Rathmann was his right hand man
for many years.
Marty Rathman left in 2004 or
thereabouts,
and he was so,
he sort of our deep throat in the film,
but he also cops to the fact that when
he was in scientology,
he was involved in all kinds of devious
covert activity involving a private
investigators,
destruction of documents.
And I'm also certain amount of physical
violence himself,
which he has apologized for.
And so he,
uh,
it becomes a sort of examination of him
and his ability to,
the fact that he's been seduced by this
thing and it's still in certain ways,
it's still in him,
you know,
by,
by almost,
by definition,
you can't be in something that long and
that,
you know,
Leah Remini was a celebrity parishioner,
right?
She was,
she was going around the celebrity
century,
was doing scientology,
but she was not in the CEO.
The CEO gets this.
Clergy is the intersect is the
difference between someone who goes to a
Catholic church a few times a year,
right.
And eats communion and thinks and praise
a few times you.
That's okay.
You can be a scientologist in that way,
right?
Which maybe your neighbor was,
but if you're in the seal,
it's somewhere between being in the
Vatican and being a monk.
You take a vow of poverty,
you volunteer,
you think about poverty.
Yeah.
You get paid below minimum wage,
tiny amounts.
You,
you're leading a kind of Spartan
existence to save the planet.
You sign a contract for 40 billion years
or something I think is interesting
because it's supposed to cover all your
future lifetimes,
so when you come back,
you're still in the sea org.
They're um,
their slogan is something I vein our
business or whatever the Latin is,
it's we come back,
meaning that we come back in future
lifetimes and we're still going to be in
the sea org anyway.
So it's really important to get that
distinction because,
you know,
I wouldn't want people to have the
impression that everyone in scientology
is sort of going around in a uniform,
marching around in a vow of poverty.
That's just the seal guys.
And most of them live down.
Many of them lived down in Hemet,
outside La,
and that's where it's outside is if you
had towards palm springs,
basically it's in the desert.
That's where they live.
Yeah.
There's a pace down,
although they have some giant center
down there that they're going to start
producing movies.
Right.
Well that there's a center in Hollywood
that they've just bought.
Yeah.
They've just,
in fact,
not just bought,
they're just refurbed it and they've
opened it.
And they're going to open it,
which is bizarre because they have it.
There it is.
Yeah.
Thirty dollars,
million dollar TV studio movie and TV
Studio Complex in Hollywood.
That just opened the.
But they have a complex in Hemet as
well,
bizarrely.
So I don't know why they need another
one.
They like buying shit apparently at one
point in time they were the number two
real estate holders in Los Angeles.
Well that.
Yeah.
That's amazing.
She's actually maybe Hollywood.
Not necessarily.
Maybe,
maybe,
I don't know,
but,
but the um,
but I think a lot of that is to do with
someone explained this to me.
One of the rules about a nonprofit or
about being a religion,
having their religious status is they
cannot hold their income,
like money that comes in has to be spent
otherwise they're in violation of their
charitable status.
So this is this.
Someone just told me this,
the other.
So in other words,
it's in,
they have to kind of keep buying
buildings because there needs to be a
cash outflow,
which sort of makes sense.
Right?
Yeah.
That's totally understandable.
Yeah,
that makes sense.
And then,
yeah,
so,
but,
so this Guy Marty rathbone who sort of
my,
um,
my guide through scientology and he's a
fascinating guy and Marty was in for how
long,
I want to say 24 years.
Maybe it was 27 years,
but I think he said 27 years.
He had a nice outfit on and a nice,
uh,
he,
he uniform,
he got the uniform.
He was holding ropes around the
shoulder.
No,
what I will say this about him,
you know,
if you're in it and you're up at the top
echelons as he was you on some kind of
crazy saifai adventure,
you know,
if you think about it,
think it's real liquor that you are
living in a kind of,
I reality,
you know,
we'll get that rope because across the
chest you're saving planets.
What does this metals for it?
Look at all his metals.
Know that,
that thing that might be some of them
are photoshops.
Oh really?
Yeah,
like Katie did.
Well that might not be.
Some of them had metals.
Just to make fun of that might be a real
one.
I don't know what the one that was above
it seems real right now.
Look at that.
That's real.
Now what?
He doesn't like that now because he's.
That's 30 years ago.
Amazing.
Is it that they give them military
metals?
I mean it looks like no different than
what a general would have.
Yeah.
What does it mean?
Beautiful thing in a
way.
I mean,
yeah,
I mean it's an exciting life.
They probably wouldn't be doing the
dishes in that outfit,
like that special occasions,
special occasions,
and I'm sure he would get special
treatment and I'm sure being in the
number two guy must have been amazing
because you basically.
There's only really a number one,
which is David miscavige and then
there's just everyone else.
Do you know what I mean?
Oh,
well then there's Tom Cruise and then is
there a Tom cruise is kind of number
one,
right?
Right up there.
It.
No,
because actually there's a don't you
remember in,
in,
in Lawrence Wright's book.
There's a bit where Tom Cruise explains,
I think maybe to Nazneen Bonnie rd.
Like his girlfriend at the time.
He says,
don't you Like,
he's annoyed with his girlfriend.
This is after it split up from a cruise?
No,
the one before the australian broad,
um,
you know,
nicole kidman thank kidman.
WHo's who by the way,
she was considered an sp because her
father was a psychiatrist,
I believe in any way,
so,
so he went out with a woman named bonnie
rd for awhile and there's a section in
going clear where they talk about,
I think ms dot gavin came around for
dinner or something and it was,
and um,
I think it was.
Anyway,
his girlfriend at the time was having
trouble understanding what ms dot savage
was saying because he speaks quite fast
and I'm like,
wow,
what are you saying?
And tom cruise was really upset and
said,
why don't you get it this lrh?
Then there's david ms dot cop is what
they call them,
their cob.
And then there's me,
dude,
you're doing a goddamn good tom cruise
impression take.
It's just be attaching this lrh then
their cob and then there's me.
you get it together.
You're glip,
glip,
matt your clip.
Um,
that's a very good impression.
It just got to be,
you know what it feels like.
I don't think I need scientology if like
I've called 270 milligrams given me a
like a.
It's an oth.
I'm on ot five right now.
Not morning.
Thunder is.
I think I had that.
He makes this caveman coffee with some
emulsified mct oil in an ice coffee.
That's what I have every morning.
What is the most qualified mct oil?
Mct oil that you can mix very easily
with cold beverages or is mct oil or
medium chain triglyceride oil?
It's the most nutritious aspects of
coconut oil that are blended together.
IT's they spin in a centrifuge extract
the bushel.
You can get it anywhere.
Mct oil is readily available at any,
any sort of health food store and a lot
of erewhon and whole foods and those
types of places carry.
I've never even heard of it.
Can you know,
have coconut oil,
right?
Yeah.
It's their.
They're healthy fats that are really
good for your brain.
Good stuff.
Yeah.
So it morning thunder,
the point being it off,
but what a cop cop as chairman of the
board.
Ah,
there we go.
Cop rtc,
there's cob and then there's me and then
there's glib,
glib,
nicholas,
matt lauer,
and then there's ciantra fault.
It just below matt lauer.
So they have quite dim view of john
travolta within science.
What,
why this is such.
This is called a bud fucking.
What is it?
I think massage viewed,
I don't know.
Marty raspbian top.
That's allegedly.
Can I throw an allegedly,
allegedly they have a bad view of him.
Just pause everything now.
A lot of what I'm saying,
it's based on,
once he blew,
once he left,
marty rathbun spilled his guts on the
internet in all,
you know,
in the,
in order to let people know what was
going on and he kind of,
he was the biggest thing I would say in
sort of in terms of exposing scientology
for what it is,
probably more probably in the history of
scientology.
John travolta's wife was on fear factor
and I got to meet john travolta because
his wife was in the finals.
She lost coolio.
Who was a,
by the way,
you want to talk about a guy who
performs very well under the influence
of marijuana.
Coolio might be at the top of my list
right there,
right up there with joey diaz,
coolio,
uh,
where they would open up his trailer and
it was like a cheech and chong and it
was hilarious and he would go out there
and he would perform these stocks just
high as a kite.
I mean,
just gone because you look in his eyes
were just glazed over and he would
perform flawlessly.
And the last stunt involved balance,
it was his balance thing.
And I had a conversation with him before
we did it and I was a unfortunately
stone cold sober at the time I believe.
And uh,
coolio was a,
he's like,
ah,
I've,
I've done this a million times in a
million different lives and other
universes.
I'm ready to do it right now.
I'm like,
get after it.
So good luck to you.
But I'm john travolta,
his wife.
What is her name again?
Kelly kelly.
She's very,
very Nice,
very nice and a very.
Seems so normal.
You know,
I had conversations with her and uh,
and she even sent me a gift.
There was some sort of protein powder
that she was drinking,
some,
some health drink that she was drinking.
I asked her about it and she said,
you know,
give me your address.
I'll have them sent to you and lunch.
So she sent some to the studio.
I believe she was very nice.
Credit.
Van susteren is assigned torches.
fuck outta here.
that's the one thAt surprises me really.
Isn't she a june ms dot?
I would,
I would have fox news.
Is she on the show journal and tone
scale or not?
She be,
maybe there's a side,
maybe there's an exception.
Well,
uh,
I met her as one once as well.
She seemed very nice as well.
There's something about george carlin,
I'm sure she is nice and I'm sure you
can be.
I mean,
not to sound like a broken record.
Again,
my neighbor who,
my former neighbor many years ago was a
very nice guy and I've met a lot of
scientologists inside of hollywood and
they all have actory thing going on,
which is I would like to believe that
they are as nice as they are pretending
to me,
but I'm not sure,
you know.
Then actory thing like,
yes,
aNd I know,
uh,
I know one of my early experiences when
I was talking to a scientologist when I
was trying to first negotiate access to
the church bacK in 2003 was I'd sent her
some old documentaries that I'd done,
so this is who I am,
this is what I do.
And she was on the phone.
She said,
oh yeah,
I got the dvds and watching.
And she started laughing in the act of
talking about liKe a fake laugh.
Yeah.
And I say that didn't.
I was like,
that didn't feel quite real.
Later on,
another person I knew who was a
scientologist did the same thing where
like I saw the thing you did on that is
a desert pet peeve of mine.
I Was like,
oh wow,
man.
There's a giant,
maybe that's part of what they do is
sort of a similar kind of weird love
bombing.
I don't know.
Maybe that was just coincidence.
It makes sense because they're trying to
be influential and they're trying to.
They're trying to be charming.
Yeah.
I find a lot of the scientologists that
I've met that are actors,
they're.
They're extremely charming.
Like there's one of the things you hear
about tom cruise.
He looks you in the eye.
He talks to you.
Remember,
I'm make sure that's true.
I mean they drill,
as I said,
they drill on looking people in the eye,
but let's just assume that that's his
real behavior pattern.
Now.
It's a very good behavior.
Nice.
I'm in favor of positivity,
although I think the world needs
negative people,
but I think there need to be some what
do you.
But wait a minute,
but the whole part of the ecology of
life is to have been in the yang.
Yeah.
The one was positive then.
I mean it would be a little too much.
Well,
it would be very strange if the world
didn't become enlightened.
Like what if some pharmaceutical company
device,
some pill that eliminates all the
negative aspects of humanity,
so we all just started taking it.
Yeah,
I mean,
look how many people brush their teeth.
pretty much everybody,
right?
What if everybody started doing whatever
this is and this new thing which
eliminated,
became prevalent throughout the world.
Eliminate like vaccinations.
Right?
Pretty much.
I would.
I would have some at high,
90 percent of the western world is
vaccinated every now and then our meat.
Some kid who had hippie parents and they
gave him apple cider vinegar and they
never vaccinated them.
There's those,
those,
a few of those exist,
but for the most part,
most people are vaccinated to prevent
against diseases.
If we came up with some sort of a
vaccination to prevent the more
disgusting aspects of human beings,
negative behavior or aggression,
meanness,
it'd be very curious.
Very curious as to how that would play
out.
Whether or not that would diminish a
ambition and progress and who knows.
Yes.
I think it was.
Yeah.
I thought you said the yin and the yang.
I think scientology aspires to be that.
You know,
and I think the danger of it is,
um,
it,
it would be certain similarities to a
sort of almost fascist vision.
I think.
I mean,
I think that there is an overlap there,
you know,
the cult of health,
the culture of glowing,
smiling beacons of,
of health and humanity marching up and
down.
And actually it's our ability to rub
along with difficult characters and,
and um,
to sort of embraced the ugly side is a
iron.
Can't define exactly what it is,
but it feels like that's an important
dimension of life.
Well,
it certainly seems to be that there's a,
there's a dynamic that plays out between
human beings and that we learn not just
from the positives but also from the
negatives.
And I learned a lot from other people's
negative behavior,
how to never be like that myself without
having to make those same mistakes.
Also learned from my own mistakes of,
sure.
But when we see horrible things in the
news and negative things,
I think that does sort of reinforce how
fortunate you are that you're not
experiencing those horrible things and
that there is some sort of an
understanding of the worst aspects of
people wear it.
It Broadens your,
your spectrum of patients.
I agree.
But I also think that many of my
favorite writers you would probably
defined in some sense as a walking
negative side of life,
think about hunter thompson,
thompson,
william burroughs,
or,
um,
you know,
for them anyway,
Philip Roth,
if you like the talking about the
absolute most contemptible and
disgusting impulses,
we feel bukowski.
Oh yeah.
Um,
uh,
you know,
that's absolutely rambo,
the french poet,
this is sort of like,
this is who we are.
This is the stuff of life,
the ineradicable.
And I think I'm suspicious of anything
that,
uh,
that pathologizes it too much and says,
you know what,
that's sort of,
um,
you know,
that you know,
which scientology does.
In fact,
they say that's your reactive mind.
It's a malfunctioning part of your mind.
It's a pseudo scientific thing.
Whereas actually christianity,
I'm not a christian,
but it sort of embraces the fact that
it's just your human side,
you know,
your human side is his earthly and
twisted and sexual and and actually you
need to embrace some sort of high empire
being well,
I think most religions or ideologies
that are,
that are trying to promote some sort of
advancement.
They look to the past and to the
horrific nature of animal behavior,
the tooth fang and claw of the wild and
the recognition that somehow or another
we've emerged from that and that we
aspire to do better.
And then that we know that in our own
lives.
I mean if you look at your own life as a
microcosm,
you,
you've sort of fIgured out what you've
done wrong hopefully and have advanced
past those days of youth and foolish
behavior and you're now wiser,
more educated person and you seek to
continue to advance,
continue to do better.
So it's sort of like it's all analogous
at all sort of ties in together.
Now when,
when people go too hard with that,
when,
when people to go to hard with
eliMinating the bad behavior,
I always wonDer if like l ron hubbard
himself,
if he was,
you know,
when,
when we talk about him self-diaGnosing
and self-treating,
if that's what they're doing as well,
it's like,
do you know that like isn't an old
expression that a.
Well,
there's an old thing that you see with
women,
um,
that are,
uh,
what's the best way to put this sexually
loose that they always like to point the
finger at other girls that are sexually
loose.
It's like one of the first indications
that girl might be a slut is that she
likes to point at other girls and,
and that's a real common thing.
And I think that the things that annoy
you the most about yourself,
you tend to highlight those aspects when
you discuss human beings or other people
that irritate you.
I'm sure that something in that they
say,
uh,
yes,
my dad likes to quote,
there's a,
um,
a bulgarian,
last and radical.
The lights can net huge had enough
reason that the thieves hell is the fear
of thieves.
So we sort of project our qualities to
others and it fills us with anxiety that
they may be that I have to go to the
other point,
know though,
it would be wonderful to feel that we
advanced through life acquiring wisdom.
I don't know that it's necessarily the
case.
And what strikes me about hubbard is
the,
you know,
the merit that you see in scientology.
The bits that feel workable and make
sense seem to have come out fairly early
on.
And then later on,
the stuff that was coming out with more
and more outlandish,
whatever therapies he was evolving it
when it went to the ot levels,
it was really getting properly out
there.
Like,
um,
I mean,
whether that may be.
He was spiraling out.
I mean,
there's allegations that he was fully
mentally ill,
uh,
at least four episodes towards the end
of his life.
And,
um,
we spent a great deal of time.
The sea org was kind of concocted
because he had to be in the ocean.
He had to be,
first of all,
I'm away from America.
so he went.
He took to s to the sea,
so didn't prosecuted basically,
as I understand it.
Yes.
And so he had a sort of ocean going
religion where they were kind of
traveling around and then for a while he
was in england and then for a while he
was in what was then rhodesia,
what is now is involved way sort of
trying to find a niche,
find a kind of new frontier that he
could more or less make for his own kind
of claim for scientology.
But then even when he came back,
he was so caught up In lawsuits in the
last 10 or 15 years of his life.
People pursuing him,
uh,
for money because they,
they felt scientology had made them
psychotic or they just thought it
fraudulent or
that they wanted their money back.
He had to disappear and was living in
seclusion more or less hiding out.
while money was kind of shuttled back
and forth to him.
And that's why I say I said at the
beginning of the problem with
scientology is an overabundance of
material.
you probably saw the master right to the
Paul Thomas Anderson film had fell
asleep as watching it in a hotel room.
And I passed,
it had its moments,
but there's so many weird stories within
scientology and the master is loosely
based on,
I would say,
fairly closely based on aspects of l ron
hubbard.
Yeah.
I mean,
was that,
is that public?
I mean,
if they had not acknowledged that,
uh,
I think he had a screening for tom
cruise and I think he publicly said it
wasn't based on our ron hubbard and what
it does.
I think tom said.
What do you,
what do you hear about tom?
Like everyone seems to say he's a good
guy.
Like you meet him.
He's,
um,
like,
as you say,
very focused,
very attentive.
Um,
I've heard several things.
One that is not as short as everybody
says [inaudible] lot of people at once.
So he's like five foot two,
apparently five foot nine.
That's what I've heard.
But who knows?
He could be wearing some funky stuff.
And issues,
uh,
that he's very friendly,
but he's a very,
very focused,
very intense,
very,
very charming,
very charismatic,
very smart,
and um,
seems to be genuinely interested in what
you have to say.
Yeah,
I mean I've heard the same thing.
If you.
And what was your line on?
Would you,
if tom cruise is interviewed on a chat
show,
you feel he should be asked about
scientology?
No,
you'd be good.
I'm ask him about whatever.
I think chat shows as you put them or
they're pretty much bullshit anyway
because what they really are as you have
the seven minute chunk where you
supposed to be promoting some movie
about a super spy that fucking repels
down from the ceiling and gets passed.
Lasers and.
Yeah,
that's.
I mean that's really.
Or the other.
I think he's a great actor.
I loved that movie.
What is it?
The edge of tomorrow?
It was called.
I love them.
and that was,
that was the time travel one.
My love time travel.
So it's like groundhog day meets mission
impulsive.
Yeah.
Meets alien.
It's a great movie.
I really enjoyed it.
I think he's a great actor.
And I think you have to be fucking crazy
to be a great actor.
He was good in that and you know,
what was nice and that was that he
started out,
uh,
in that movie as a kind of non tom
cruise character to remember he's kind
of cowardly and slightly weak and he
learns in the course of the movie to
become tom cruise.
Whereas.
And it felt refreshing after seeing so
many kind of cruise as uber manch films,
which by the way,
I think it's part of a scientology as
well,
is that he doesn't want to take on roles
that are.
And theta.
Yes.
In other words,
see,
well,
one of the things I learned was members
of the ceo who had taken this vow of
poverty living extremely abstemious
cloistered lives and they're not allowed
to go to the movies for the most part,
except when a tom cruise movie comes
out.
So you know,
it better have a positive,
uplifting message.
Oh,
that's interesting.
Yeah.
So they would literally be bust.
I was told to the cinemas to watch the
matinee performances of the early held
back while the previews are playing.
It's a good question.
I would imagine they would have to be,
or they what?
What'd you think would be the worst
thing they could see in probably a
preview for my film?
Yeah,
that wouldn't be good.
They worked out how ironic their eyes
would drop out of their heads.
But um,
and I think that's one of the perhaps
issues they have with john travolta as
well as that he's playing a heroin
addict pulp fiction.
That makes sense.
I mean,
he really embraces some very bizarre
roles.
Yeah.
He was in drag in hairspray.
They probably didn't love that.
Yeah,
he's very good.
He's very good at.
Don't you love john travolta the right
time?
Yeah,
I do.
I love him.
I think he's a great actor.
Do you feel like we've been on such a
journey with him from vinnie barbarino?
He's like,
um,
he's,
he's a,
he's a legend.
He's a fascinating character.
And uh,
I met him as well when his wife was on
the show and he was very nice,
but it was that thing,
you know,
where he's like really engaging,
looks you in the eyes,
very present,
you know,
you think he's gay.
is that where we can,
um,
people say that he's gay?
I don't know.
I hAve zero problem with people being
gay,
but I do have a liTtle bit of a problem
with someone who's not gay.
Pretends that they're in or someone who
is gay rather.
Well that would be real problem.
Someone who's not gay and pretend gay.
That's hard.
But that's something like if you're,
if you do gay stuff,
you're just gay.
Like even if you're not gay and you
pretend and you like,
you start dating guys like I'm not even
gay,
but I'm going to triCk these dudes.
I got news for your pal.
Yeah.
it could happen.
It's um,
you know,
it's,
it's an unfortunate as tending.
Is he pretending not to be gay?
Allegedly,
that's the word.
The word is allegedly is that he's,
he's definitely not out.
So if he is gay,
he's pretending to be straight,
but there's photos of him kissing men
and you know,
there's allegedly these massage
therapists that have claimed that he
tried to have sex with them.
I don't know if they're telling the
truth or if they're just exploiting a
possibility.
Does it make you gay if you have sex
with a man?
It.
It definitely helps unless you're in
prison.
Yeah.
And even then you're just gay for the
stay,
right?
Exactly.
Oh,
you know,
I,
I just think it's an unfortunate aspect
of our society that we're in.
And this is a reality.
If tom cruise's gay,
it would be a very smart business move
for him with his business to stay in the
closet because he's a leading man and
he's a leading man that has love affairs
in these movies with women and you
cannot do that if you're gay.
It's one of the weird things about being
a gay person,
even in today's liberated and very
progressive society that a woman can be
gay and she can play a straight woman in
a movie because no one cares.
Like if a guy meets a girl and she's
beautiful,
but she's been gay or whole life and he
turns around and all of a sudden she's
heterosexual and then he winds up
marrying her and having children with
her.
Everybody's like,
we got our year.
I like men get excited,
but if a woman meets a guy who's been
just blowing dudes for the past 20
years,
then all sudden he decides he's not gay
anymore.
They're not excited about that.
They're like,
are you sure you're not gay?
Like I don'T mean,
I don't even know how I feel about this.
It's we don't accept a,
a gay person yet.
At least playing a straight man who is a
leading man in a movie.
I don't think there's anyone has been
able to pull that off.
There's not want to Do doogie howser,
the doogie howser dude.
He's,
he's,
he played like a womanizer and some
sitcom,
but nobody's buying that bullshit.
Shawn.
Michael,
patrick or neil Patrick Harris petrie.
Yeah,
it's,
it,
it's an interesting.
One of the allegations about scientology
always used to be that,
um,
you spill your secrets in order to.
Which is like confession and then
suddenly that kept in a locked vault and
if you leave they become public and sort
of a test set,
black Male going on.
so whether that's really happening,
uh,
now I Don't know that that may have
happened in the past diligence.
Well,
there is an issue with them going after
detractors and people that leave because
it doesn't really exist in other
organizations or,
or,
or other religions.
I go,
perfect example of another religion that
was most obviously created by a con man
is mormonism.
Joseph smith was 14 years old when he
claimed to find golden tablets that were
the last work of jesus.
And then only he could read them because
he had a magic seer stone.
It's a ludicrous story.
It was a story that was created in 18,
20.
It's such a ludicrous story that,
you know,
a lot of people when they find out about
it,
they go,
well wait,
wait,
hold on.
Like people,
people like they become mormon and then
they get deep into it and then they find
out the roots of this and they go,
wait a minute,
what the fuck?
By the way,
it's not scientology that mormonism is
the fastest growing religion in America.
I wonder if they're nice people.
They seem very nice.
They're very nice.
Would it be you sit against mitt romney?
I am,
I'm glad he's not the president.
But whenever I would see him with his
fAmily,
I thought,
well,
you know,
why can't all family be a bit more like
that family.
I am not glad he's not running for
president right now.
Um,
I think he's a better choice.
And I was shocked that he wasn't willing
to oppose Donald Trump because I think
that that would be a fucking easy run
for people that were conservative,
that we're uncomfortable with this trump
character and all his fucking loose
dialogue and all the crazy shit that he
says.
I don't think so.
I think what I think what trump has his
way he's proved so,
uh,
so durable and popular is just this
absolute.
I'm different.
I know.
Fuck everything into establishment at
the.
That's exactly what romney doesn't have.
Ron miller side,
the consummate insider.
He's um,
he's,
he's establishment Washington.
All the rest of it and trump seemed is a
kind of caveman.
yeah,
he's a weird guy.
So there was,
you know,
the people out there,
I think white collar,
blue collar,
kind of white americans on the front
porch see trump and they think,
yeah,
that guy is my guy.
While they embrace the strong man,
he's a strong man who doesn't give a
fuck.
He says crazy things.
He talks about our biggest penises.
I mean he does that mean that the run up
to becoming the republican nominee was
one of the most embarrassing times ever
for the republican party because you had
all these fools dancing around this
strong man.
Really good robo candidates.
Almost literally in the case of rubio
was malfunctioning with his,
his kind of soundbite algorithm was
glitching.
So was coming out with the same sound
bite within 10 seconds,
but all these robo candidates and then
someone who seemed like a kind of
visceral flesh and blood human on stage
and who.
Moreover,
when he said stupid crazy stuff did not
then hit the trail to,
to apologize,
he would just keep saying weird things
and I think felt like,
you know what he's showing the media for
the shell game that it is.
Yes.
Because he's saying,
well,
I'm not going to do that thing if like,
I'm so sorry I said that.
Where It's like,
and also they all cliche,
but who would you want to have a beer
with?
Would you want to have a beer with
romney?
Romney probably doesn't drink beers and
drink and then,
uh,
and,
and trump actually,
you would probably enjoy the kind of
weird,
ludicrous.
Just peering at him would be
entertaining in itself.
Did you ever see the picture that he put
up on instagram with him in trump tower
eating a taco bowl?
And this was after all the crazy remarks
that he'd said about Mexico and mexicans
coming over here and raping,
and I talked to the president of Mexico,
who's going to pay for that wall?
You know,
we're not going to pay for that wall.
Yeah.
Well,
the wall just got 10 foot higher and
everybody starts cheering and then he
takes a photo on instagram of him
smiling,
eating a taco bowl,
look at this at trump tower and it says
he's got the thumbs up.
He's eating this,
this taco bone.
It said something about like,
I love hispanics.
Happy cinco de mayo,
but,
but what?
But though the best taco bowls are made
in trump tower grille.
And then he also said,
I love hispanics.
Like see if you can find the actual
instagram post.
What's your initial point at this?
Because it isn't.
I love hispanics is fucking crazy.
That's fucking crazy that.
I mean I saw that.
I'm like,
okaY,
we're being trolled and look at the
likes,
look at the retweets and the likes.
Forty 2000 retweets for.
That's his genius is that he could speak
out.
He'll,
he'll say something crazy and then 10
minutes later he'll say,
he'll say something contradictory.
Well,
it's fun for us.
It's fun for us.
It's interesting.
It's fun for us and also he doesn't
necessarily represent for
a lot of people.
He doesn't like.
One of the things that romneY
represents,
it's problematic for people is that not
only is his father a mormon,
not only is it from the but he's from
one of the most bizarre sex of mormons
were they left the United States so that
they can have multiple wives who?
Romney's family.
Yeah.
You don't know that.
Let me hook you up.
Romney's family.
No,
I don't know what the fuck it is,
but there was a vice piece on.
It's a fascinating piece there.
There.
They all live in Mexico.
The romney's family.
I know who you mean.
They moved to Mexico before romney's dad
was born.
Romney's dad was not born in the United
States.
He was born in Mexico and when the
United States made polygamy illegal,
they just said this was in the 18
hundreds.
We didn't have cars,
so people were like,
well,
who gives a shit?
If we're in the United States or Mexico,
we're still riding horses and banging
our nine slash wives.
Let's just go over there.
So they didn't want to give up the
polygamy aspect of the religion.
So they just went south to Mexico,
which was not that Much different than
the United States back then.
Then when cars were invented in the
United States,
it really exploded and became much more
prosperous than Mexico.
Then ultimately it got even crazier who
they get involved in the drug war,
the drug war where there were,
there was a drug cartel.
people were kidnapping people in the
romney family and other mormons that are
living down there.
So they started being.
They had armed gUards on century 24
hours.
I mean,
it's like a scene from the walking dead.
they're all standing there with high
powered rifle when we're talking with
now.
So family is still down this?
Yes.
Oh my goodness.
Oh,
it's amazing right now what ronnie was
born in the United States.
It's the mexican mormon war and it's a
vice series and it is wonderful because
this is something that for whatever
reason was not really discussed during
the campaign trail.
I think they tried to keep this because
I think they thought it would be
incredibly damaging to the republican
party because this guy is the front
runner for the republicans.
And I don't know who the fuck on the
democratic side agreed to not really get
into this,
but that means they're not just a part
of a cult or a part of a gun toting
polygamous cult that has an armed
compound in Mexico.
How do I not know this?
Well,
that's why romney's dad wanted to be
president,
but could not run for president because
he was born in Mexico.
He came out of his mother's body in the
wrong patch of dirt.
So we did not allow him to run our great
nation.
It's,
um,
did he become a senator?
Uh,
I do not remember.
It was involved in politics in some way.
Ted cruz was born in Canada though,
running.
So did they change the rules?
Dirty canadian.
He's not one of us to love canadians.
I'm kid.
Did they change the rules?
A?
No,
because he has dual citizenship because
his mother was a can be born.
Yes.
Like my friend
brian was born in the Philippines,
but he's american because he was born.
He was going to be,
I mean,
yeah,
but you can't be president and not born
in the us.
In my book,
no,
because,
uh,
he was not given the god given right to
be born the right patch dirt.
So fuck him.
That's in my book,
but constitution.
Well,
that was something that Donald Trump was
bringing up.
Well,
by the way,
people do forget conveniently,
the Donald Trump was one of the primary
birthers.
He was one of the biggest proponents of
the idea that obama was not born in
America,
that he was born in Kenya.
Do you remember that?
That was a bIg issue.
Big time.
Huge.
He was a.
He still.
It's a propounding.
Absolutely.
Fringe conspiracy nut beliefs about,
you know,
he said that obama founded isis right at
a rally in Florida.
Did he find Iceland?
Did he,
the atom bomb?
I had started ice,
but did he decide to say this at a rally
in Florida or did obama found isis in a
rally in Florida?
I think he said it the rally.
I said that obama founded it.
Oba,
let me hear this.
Let's hear this
all over the middle east and it was a
terrible mistake.
And then obama came In and normally you
want to clean up.
He made a bigger mess out of it.
He made such a mess and then you had
hillary with Libya.
So sad.
In fact,
in many respects,
you know,
they honor president obama.
Isis is honoring president obama.
He is the founder of isis.
He's the founder of isis.
The founder said it three times and I
would say the cofounder would be crooked
hillary clinton.
I wonder
if he knows what the word found means.
He doesn't give a fuck.
you know what I mean?
He's a pro wrestling candidate.
I had a bit about this in 2005.
I had a bit about George Bush in that.
He was so dumb that I don't think that
he was really the candidate that the
republicans like the best candIdate that
could have.
I think it was a test to find out how
dumb people are because there's only one
way to tell if the people that the
bankers and the industrialists,
they don't really know how dumb
americans are.
They know about pop culture.
They know what people like and that they
the only.
There was only one way to find out.
You put a dumb guy in the office and you
see how people react and that at the end
of the,
uh,
the first year when he won again,
or the first term when you want again,
I think there were sitting around going,
I think we can go dumber,
and they just decided to get some
fucking
pro wrestling type president.
Some,
some dude who's like a combination of
like a drill sergeant and have a pro
wrestler who just,
you know,
you just go to ted nugent concert and
scoop people up,
but nets and you just set them up and
that this is kind of what he is.
I mean,
you watched that.
That is like the way the audience is
yelling along and cheering.
It's theatrical.
This is,
this is all like a parade.
It's theater.
They don't,
they don't necessarily think that obama
really founded isis.
They don't care if he did or not.
There's no thinking there.
There's a,
there's a box that they operate on.
It's a very small box.
They operate.
All their thoughts exist inside this box
and they never expand.
They'd never go there.
There's no,
there's no nuance.
There's no subtlety,
there's no,
there's no broad spectrum,
there's no big picture.
There was none of that.
It's just assholes have their king.
We have a lot of assholes.
It's really easy to survive.
It's real easy to have.
You can't have thought when this started
you,
you couldn't have thought that this
would get this far,
you know,
seemed like a joke to begin with.
Yeah,
I thought somewhere along the line,
cooler heads will prevail,
but it's,
I,
I'm torn because as a comedian,
you know,
I mean this is a fucking gold mine.
They are,
they're about to open up a dam of gold.
They're going to break down the dam and
gold is going to flow down.
it's going to be amazing.
But as a human being,
this kid literally lead to the end of
civilization.
Yes.
All.
So as a student,
as myself,
as a sort of student of kind of self
sabotage and the puzzle at [inaudible]
of the human condition,
do you know what I mean?
I find it fascinating,
right?
You know,
it could be the end of the world,
but it just,
you just see things happening that
absolutely are unprecedented and,
and it's.
I have a kind of chaos,
chaotic streak that enjoys.
It's like that feeling you get in the
playground as a kid when a fight breaks
out,
fight,
fight.
You just sort of.
It's like it's.
It was an arsonist thrill of seeing
civilization burned.
Something's gonna happen.
Something's crazy.
It's going to happen.
It's not business as usual.
Here's another thing that I like about
it.
There's a lot of things that he says
that are absolutely true and here's one
of the things that I like about what
trump represents.
He is not the political establishment
and the political establishment sucks.
It really does suck.
It is a corrupt,
completely corrupt institution.
And what he's saying about crooked
hillary,
I agree.
Look,
if you look at the clinton foundation,
you look at what they've been able to do
and the laws they've been able to skirt
and the amount of influence they're able
to have and the amount of money that
they're able to generate and where that
money goes and how ambiguous it is and
how would that hasn't been investigated.
He's right.
He's right in a lot of ways.
So I hope that a lot of what he's doiNg
is theatrical and if he does wind up
winning,
I hope that he puts around hiM some real
political advisors that understand
international policy,
that understanding the,
he tones everything down.
And This was all.
That's the ultimate hope,
right?
I don't necessarily think it's true that
he loses.
What do you hope that hillary wins?
Because I hope that she doesn't win
either.
I don't see what I mean.
I don't see jill stein winning.
I mean,
I think It's either.
What about Gary Johnson here?
My.
Who is Gary Jones?
How dare you.
He's the,
uh,
he's an independent.
He's a Gary Johnson.
The libertarian candidate.
It's very reasonable.
Gun weld was the libertarian candidate.
No,
it was johnson,
johnson with weld as well.
Does well device.
We're going to find johnson is the form
of government hillary and and trump.
You would go trump.
No,
no,
no.
I wouldn't go.
Asteroid which opened.
Asteroid hits like I don't like either
one of them.
What you said about it took a orange
head casino magnate.
Pathological lying issues.
Point out the truth about the american,
the brokenness of the american.
Gary johnson and bill.
Well bill weld as his vice president.
Okay.
Um,
I think we're,
we're in a bad place with either one of
them because either one of them are
exposing the ridiculous aspects of our
society and the ridiculous aspects of
our political establishment,
our political system.
It's just not a good system.
Representative government doesn't make
any sense when people can represent
themselves.
it made sense back when it was
impossible to get word to Washington how
all these people felt.
But now that people,
you,
you're almost saying by continuing
representative government in 2016,
you're almost saying that,
well,
you can't have one person one vote
because people are too fucking stupid
for that.
Mean you're almost saying that,
well,
maybe they are,
but are they,
and if that's the case,
we need to fix that instead of just
continuing business as usual to figure
out how to expand our educational system
or enlightened some of these people and
maybe drop mushrooms everywhere or
something when there's gotta be a better
way than just continuing business as
usual.
And that business has been shown,
at least in hillary clinton's case,
to be completely corrupt.
Do you think?
How would you rate obama?
I liked him as a human.
What I like about obama is he's
measured,
he's intelligent and I think there's one
thing that has.
I mean as much as when you look at
politics,
you look at someone who's running the
president,
there's a lot of speculation.
How much power does he have?
What does it like behind closed doors?
What are those meetings like is,
you know,
like sam harris is an interesting point.
He's like,
is obama a guy who was lying all along
or when he was running for president and
then gets into office and does different
things like keeps guantanamo bay open
and doesn't leave Iraq and all the
different things that he sort of reneged
on,
or is it that you become president and
then you are briefed and then someone
sits down and explains to you the
horrific nature of the outside world and
here are the threats to civilization
itself.
Here are The threats in terms of
terrorism,
in terms of these different
dictatorships that are seeking to gain
nuclear arms and here's,
here's some real problems and here's the
strategies and here's what we have to do
and here's why we can't do what you
promIse is that too.
I don't know what we don't know,
but what,
what obama does represent,
and here's what trickles down is as a
man,
he's very measured.
He's very intelligent.
He's.
He's very articulate.
He doesn't lose his cool.
He doesn't respond to nonsense,
and the speeches that he gives are.
There are a great representative of
education,
of dignity,
of a guy who speaks very well and a guy
who is smarter than most people that,
you know,
I think there's something to be said for
that and I think that that is what
George Bush wasn't and that was what was
appealing to me about obama,
but you know,
but he bullshits too,
you know,
so it's like,
at what point in time do you get to
speak your mind?
Do you ever.
Do you ever get to say What you really
think?
If that's what he really thinks.
If that's who we really is it when
you're a politician,
you are almost required to try to play
this game of not pissing people off,
over expressing your true feelings on
things like you.
You've got to kind of play it as MuCh
down The middle.
You know that there's going to be a
bunch of people on this side that are
going to hate you.
It's going to be a bunch of people on
that side that don't think you're going
far enough,
but you shoot down the middle and you
get the best results.
It's almost like pretending to be
someone who you're not to try to pick
people up at a bar,
like it's a bullshit act and that's what
politicians are.
They're bullshitters there.
They're really good at bullshitting.
What's bizarre about trump is that he's
not doing that.
This is who he is.
I think that that's true.
I think,
but I go to your point about where the
people are stupid or not.
I think that's an unkind way of phrasing
it.
I'm an uncommon dude,
but,
but actually no one has the time,
you know,
we have jobs to do and to be informed on
all the subjects you would need to be
informed on to make the right decisions
to run the country you would.
No one has the time.
So very good point.
We need people to specialize in these
things and it's like brexit was a
triumph of,
uh,
you know,
in the uk when it was put to the vote,
this massive decision whether to be the
eu.
No one in that space of time as a member
of the electorate could educate
themselves to the point where they could
make an informed choice on and so people
thought,
you know what,
I just want to have something different,
let's vote for a change.
And we had brexit with,
I would argue,
disastrous results
temporarily disastrous,
but to be seen whether or not it was
disastrous friend steve hilton,
who a very bright guy who's been on this
podcast before,
he was david cameron's righthand man.
He actually is a supporter of brexit and
that's one of the things that he had a
problem with cameron over.
They had a falling out.
Um,
I want to talk to him,
sit down with him.
I don't know enough of it.
I don't really follow any politics.
I barely follow the United States.
I had,
I didn't know what the fuck brexit was
until it was going down and everybody
was saying is the end of the world.
Yeah,
I mean,
I agree.
Like I feel as though it's easy to go
along with the group think.
But um,
I was in favor of staying in europe.
Well,
when I'm talking about representative
government when I'm talking about is
like this electoral college set up and
the one person one vote set up and that
the idea that 300 plus million people
are going to be represented by just a
handful of people.
I agree with that.
Yeah.
I mean the whole way in which bernie
saunders was marginalized I think,
and likewise in a way the fact that
trump could run away with it.
It's me.
It's just fascinating how he managed opt
overturned the apple cart.
I hadn't,
you know,
I haven't really grappled with the
minutia of how us democracy works,
but it seems to me like it's a really
bizarre arcane system with delegates and
whatnot.
Exactly.
Who came up with that?
Well,
they caMe up with it back when there was
nO communication.
Then they came up with it back when you
had to take a horse and you had to carry
a handwritten letter across the country
to communicate with people and that was
just ineffective.
They had to figure out how to have
people in your various states and
various counties and various districts
represent the greater good of the people
and also have the ability to decide over
the rest of the people.
That's one of the things that people
don't even realize in representative
government.
When you have this one person who
represents a group of the people.
If the group of the people,
the group decides to vote for hillary
clinton,
that one person doesn't have to agree
with that.
It's a weird,
funky system and it's designed for back
when people were illiterate and there's
a bunch of farmers and pilgrims and
savages that came over from europe on
rafts and made it to America and just
fucking have at it and they're trying to
trying to manage this and trying to to
try to figure out how to take the
founder fathers ideas and best keep it
all together while they're exploring
this whole new world and dealing with
governing these people that were
literally thousands of miles away that
you couldn't even reach.
We can do that now instantaneously.
Someone can send a facebook message.
They can send an email,
they can,
they can tweet,
you can find out what people's opinions
are,
but then it becomes whether or not these
people are qualified to decide which
direction the country goes.
Well,
if they're not qualified,
we should probably figure out what the
fuck we can do to make people more aware
of what are the consequences of all
these different decisions that are going
to be made by our politicians because
there's a lot of stuff that gets made
when it comes to disasters,
implications for the environment.
I mean when obama was in office,
he.
He is set so much in,
in order are so much in motion that
environmentalists and people that are
against offshore drilling.
I mean there's a lot of fracking and
offshore drilling and all sorts of
things that could potentially have
disastrous implications that were set
forth by him that no one had any say in
no.
No person in America that it was just a
regular citizen had any say in these
major decisions.
Like,
you know,
mark ruffalo just tweeted something
about all the different offshore oil
rigs that obama had agreed to while he
was in office.
And it's disturbing really.
That's interesting.
See,
I have to say,
is it someone who,
you know,
who,
who resides in the uk and more used to
the british system,
the biggest shock when you come over
here is during the election cycle,
the amount of money that gets spent and
the length of the campaigns and for all
its flaws and in britain there's a cap
on how much they can spend on their
campaign.
So they have like one or two tv ads each
and then a couple of posters,
but they do not do anything on the scale
of what happens here and the amount of
money that gets spent.
And it's just insane.
So it does seem,
it has all the hallmarks of a broken
system.
I would say.
Well,
not only that,
there's two recognized parties in
anything else.
You're throwing your vote away.
That's the,
that's the implication.
That's what,
that's how people think.
And um,
you know,
uh,
tom rhodes friend of mine was in,
he lived in holland for quite a quite a
while and he was talking about the
variety of candidates to choose from in
holland and now they just have so many
different people.
They have conservative liberals,
they have conservative green party
candidates,
they have liberal green party
candidates.
They have,
I mean it just goes across this wide
range of different philosophies on how
to govern and people get a better sense
of what would they would like or what
they agree with most because this hard
line,
right and hard line left in this rigid
ideology that you have to subscribe to
on both sides.
Like if you're on the right,
you don't support gay marriage,
you're antiabortion,
you're this,
you're that,
you want gun rights,
you want this,
you know,
fuck immigration,
there's all this stuff that you have to
kind of agree to if you agree to the
right.
And then on the left you have to agree
to a lot of things that people may not
necessarily agree as well.
So it's,
it's,
it's so complicated to have a two party
system and try to pretend that there's a
real democracy that is.
And it's not really democracy.
So representative governor.
Yeah,
I mean that's,
that's for sure.
Do you think trump's got a chance of
winning?
Yes,
I do.
Especially if if people find out what
hillary has really been involved in,
I mean if they really start hammering
that,
look,
we,
we've a few months to go.
It's only august.
We have to go through all of september,
all of october and then november.
That's a lot of time and in that time
crazy shit can come out
and it seems,
I mean I've read in the la times that
he's already on a mini rebound based on
this semi he delivered last week
and that if he could tone it down a
couple of notches and just sort of
appeal to a few more women just seem a
little bit less insane.
Yeah.
He will climb in the poll numbers,
he could do it while she's under to
criminal investigations.
And there's also plenty of video out
there where there's a direct
contradiction between what the fbi has
said they were investigating what she
was guilty of and then what she has said
they said.
So she's not honest,
she's just not.
I mean it's pretty clear when you
compare many things to what she said
versus the actual facts.
Just she's a lawyer,
she's a lawyer who became a politician.
She's a career politician.
She knows what to do.
She's,
she's got teflon and her dna and she
keeps plowing forward no matter what.
She doesn't do interviews,
she's not doing these rallies.
She's just,
she's just going forward.
And It's very bizarre.
this also a lot of questions.
I mean dr drew did some big thing the
other day talking about her health
because she had fallen down in 2012 and
apparently like had a blood clot in her
brain and really hurt herself really
badly and it her advanced age,
this is a really dangerous condition.
And he talked about her healthcare and
talked about the care that she received
and what the diagnosis was.
And he's like,
this is not.
This is dangerous stuff and so who knows
how much of her behavior,
because traumatic brain injuries are
really significant when it comes to the
way your brain works post injury,
although the way you behave,
impulsive behavior.
Um,
I made a prediction.
I made a program on that subject.
Did you last year,
what was it about?
It was,
it was cold,
a different brain and it was,
it was set in a brain injury
rehabilitation clinic in the uk and it
was basically about serious personality
changes in the wake of a traumatic brain
injury,
as you say,
impulsivity.
Um,
sometimes a lack of empathy,
erratic behavior and,
and it was about a god.
People inevitably is about the
relationships that they're in and the
way in which people have to adapt around
to the new needs and you know.
Yeah,
it was,
it's unbelievable stuff.
I mean,
you told you about.
you know better than anyone from those
sports kind of interest that I'm post
boxing,
post nfl,
post hockey.
If you,
if you're a fighter in hockey team and
pr pro wrestling too,
there's Been several terrific
documentaries.
One by steve james cold,
I'm head games and a few others that all
examine the levels of erratic behavior
after an nfl career.
Unreal,
whether it's divorce,
bankruptcY,
suicide or,
or,
you know,
serious depression.
It's off the charts.
Yeah.
Um,
I've seen it firsthand.
I've seen it firsthand from friends who
became erratic and became really
unstable after getting beat a few times
in mixed martial arts fights.
I've seen it from boxers,
people that I knew when I was young and
then I met them 10,
15 years later and they were just.
Life was a mass.
They become.
Alcoholics have a huge issue with their
endocrine system and they supplement
with alcohol and drugs to try to self
medicate.
It becoMes a real problem in the brain
is very fragile.
It's,
it's connected with this very,
very sOft connective tissue that keeps
it in place inside the head.
It's just not meant to be hit that much,
you know,
you're meant to like survive a few bumps
and bruises and that's what it's kind of
designed for.
And anything else,
especially prolonged continued abuse
like that can have dire consequences or
one significant injury can have dire
consequences.
The one significant one that can be life
changing or in the sports context to
concussions,
I'm sure you know back to back within a
single sort of space of time,
like one game you're the first one is
not good,
but the second one is cataclysmic
happens a lot of times where people deny
the first concussion and they go right
back to playing football or they go
right back to sparring.
It's a huge issue.
You think hillary may have a tbi,
traumatic brain injury?
Well,
I'm no doctor obviously,
but she definitely had a traumatic brain
injury.
She fell and she had a blood clot in her
brain.
I mean this is all open public record
that diagnosis,
when you have a blood clot on your brain
at 60 something years of age,
that is incredibly dangerous.
It's really bad.
And then you have to dress like what
made her pass out in the first place?
Like what made her black out when she
fell down and hit her head.
That's not good.
I think what we,
what we really need in this country is
like some altruistic elan musk type
character,
some real genius.
Someone who's like a really brilliant
person who sees the state,
the country's in and offErs some
intelligent,
well thought out solutions that doesn't
exist because those people are too busy
doing whatever they're doing.
So what we're left with his career
politicians and then this madman.
Who's a reality tv star,
a casino man.
I don't.
I don't think that our system is good.
I think it's very archaic and I think
it's just not the best we can do and I
think we're just going to continue to
use it until it blows up in our face.
It's like instead of redesigning cars,
we've got some model t and we're keep
adding turbo chargers to it and fucking
bigger wheels and someone says,
hey man,
I think we can make a better car.
Fuck that.
This is our car usa,
usa.
And they keep.
They keep slapping bolts and fucking
rivets and screwing this thing in place
and it's not good.
It's not a good system and it's not the
best we can do.
It's certainly not ideal and I think
human beings in all areas of life,
other than our political system,
we have advanced radically since the 17
hundreds.
If you look at the way we approach
education,
if you look at our ability to
communicate with each other,
you look at technology,
the innovation and the,
the,
the constant expanding of our horizons
and possibilities as far as what we're
capable of with technology.
All those things radically improved
since then.
But we still have this goofy system that
was created back when people rode.
Horses wrote with feathers.
And when you wanted a picture of
something,
you had to draw it.
I mean,
that is,
that is done.
But that's great because that's a great
metaphor for the human brain in a way
and,
and kind of a big thought to carry us as
we sort of Georgia the closer barbecue,
but you know,
because that is the brain,
you know,
our brains are hinged around,
um,
the of most parts of our,
of our brain,
the amygdala,
which is essentially reptilian in
origin,
you know,
and so many of our deepest impulses,
the fear response and so forth are
programmed from a kind of evolutionary
heritage.
You know,
we've got neurocircuits that go back
thousands if not millions of years.
And you know,
that metaphor you use to describe our
political system of being an old jalopy
that's been turbocharged is in essence
what our brains are.
And you know,
as muCh as it would be lovely to believe
that technology and our ability to
control nature and control our
environment had been hand in hand with
sort of a moral and civilizational,
uh,
improvement that you could deduce maybe
as many examples that suggests that all
it's done is allowed us to do
everything,
whether for good or ill more efficiently
and more effectively.
So we can help more people,
we can blow more people up,
you can drive faster,
but you can drive faster away from a
crime.
Do you know what I mean?
So,
uh,
I don't hold out any huge hope,
um,
that there'll be a positive change.
We also see,
I think,
I mean,
I might be wrong sometimes I read things
that persuade me otherwise
I think that were more advanced and more
safe now than ever before.
I think if you look back on 2000 years
ago,
when you look at today,
which is just a blink of the eye in
terms of the age of the earth,
it's infinitely better to live today
than it is
certainly here in America or in the
west.
But you know,
in an,
in a global six,
is it 6 billion?
So I think it's seven.
If you were going to,
if you were dropped at random on earth,
where would you wear?
I mean,
chances are You wouldn't be joe rogan.
You would probably be what I would you
probably be.
Well there's places makIng apple phones
in a factory.
You could be,
or you could be in China living in some
sky rise,
being some multibillionaire cell phone
magnate.
Who the hell knows,
you know,
I mean,
there's certainly some wonderful spots
in the world outside of America.
There's certainly some great places to
live.
Even if you live in poverty,
you could live a wonderful,
happy life that's way safer than it
would be thousands and thousands of
years ago.
The internet is pretty much worldwide.
Cell phones are pretty much available
everywhere now.
And so I think that access to
communication is going to change the way
people view the world because they're
going to have more data to choose from.
They're gonna have more cherry picking
that they can do.
They can certainly have more
confirmation bias and stick to their own
group.
Like we're talking about when
scientologists who don't go on the
internet and don't take any suppressive
information and don't watch any videos.
and I think,
um,
I think what I'd like about your
approach and what I like about what
you're saying when it comes to
scientology,
is that you're not a mean person.
You're not like mocking them and you
don't want to shit on them.
What you want to do is you want to look
at them for what they really are and try
to get a real good understanding of it.
One of my favorite parts of the trailer
was that guy filming you and you're
filming him and you go,
are you making a documentary too?
Well,
and that's it,
isn't it?
because you don't want to,
you know,
if I can quote nature,
which is kind of a sophomore,
they do,
but it's the idea of like you do when
you were.
When you look into the obesity of
bisquick sold to and to you,
like when you fiGht monsters don't
become a monster and I don't want to.
They're the bullies.
In many cases I didn't want to bully
them back and I didn't want to be
trapped into a paradigm of us against
them and I was really trying to say,
look,
let's keep.
I don't want.
I don't.
I want to see the human in you,
not just an agent for an oppressive
regime.
I think that's beautiful.
I reallY do
do and I think that is a very measured
and intelligent and wise way to approach
this and I I've enjoyed that about your
other videos as well.
I think in that Sense you're very unique
in the way you approach documentary
filmmaking and I think the
scientologists,
they're not our enemies and the
gentleman who left,
who was the number two guy,
what was his name?
Look,
he's a perfect example that you're
talking about.
A guy who was in it for two plus
decades,
he left and he's sort of coming clean
about all the stupid shit that he did
when he was in there.
People become a prisoner of their
earliest ideology,
the earliest ideology that they adopt,
and that's one of the problems with any
sort of a group think whether it's a
cult,
religion,
whatever the fuck you want to call it,
ideologies become problematic when you
can't escape.
You can't vary.
You can't.
You have to stick to the dogma.
You have to stick to the doctrine and
that's not good for people.
It's not healthy.
It's not smart because I think the
ability to communicate and open debate
is why we've advanced to the point we're
at in the first place.
The suppressing of that is almost always
someone who has a bad idea.
They're trying to shelter.
So when you see people that are chasing
after someone because they're trying to
communicate about something like you
who's doing it super diy respectfully,
when,
when you see that what you have is a
bunch of people that are trying to
defend a bad idea and defend it with
aggression.
Exactly
right.
and if the more you kind of become a
mirror image of whatever,
whatever they're projecting,
you reinforce them in that position as
well as from doing other stories about
extreme religious beliefs like the
westboro baptist church.
I know from people who I met who were in
the church when I made my documentary
and then subsequently left that,
uh,
what short circuits their beliefs,
what allows them to see something bigger
than what they're in is when you treat
them with kindness,
you know,
and instead of shouting back at them or
hurling abuse back,
which just reinforces their view of you
as an enemy of god or suppressive or
however they characterize it,
if you actually behave decently and
attempt to robustly present your
position,
but in a respectful way and with a kind
of coming from a place of caring and
empathy as opposed to sort of sense,
so hostile attitude that actually can be
much more effective.
Absolutely.
You know,
as well as being humane.
Kudos to you sir.
I'll.
Thanks.
I'm a big fan.
I really am.
I'm,
I really appreciate you coming back here
and I'd love to have you back before the
grades out which jen,
january.
And hopefully by then the scientologists
have they've wised up and they've maybe
though,
and maybe that film will be out and we
can be wonder if we can plug that
documentary.
Yeah,
we will.
Maybe their film was going to say,
louise,
a really great guy.
Yeah,
we investigated it.
We found out he really praCtices what he
preaches and we're sorry,
I don't think it will be,
but we'll see.
All right folks,
we'll be back in just a little bit with
hannibal buress.
He'll be back at 5:00,
which is an hour from now,
so until then,
enjoy yourself.
Great.