Five,
four,
three,
two,
one.
Welcome Courtney.
Thank you.
First of all,
how did you do what you did and how are
you?
Right now?
We're just jumping right in.
Let's just jump right in.
For people who are just tuning into
courtney one the Moab to 40,
which is a 238 mile endurance race
through the MOAB,
Utah
Deserts.
Kenyans,
mountains.
And how long did it take you to run?
Two hundred and 30.
Eight miles.
Took just under 58 hours.
That is so crazy.
And you beat the second place person by
more than 20 miles,
right?
What was the distance?
I'm not sure.
The distance.
I think it was around 20 or so.
It was about 10 hours.
How did you do that?
How this is and your.
How old are you?
Thirty two.
That's young for these kinds of races,
right?
Be True because these kinds of races,
usually it's like grit and anger at the
world that gets you through.
You're only 32.
You're young and you.
The way you're winning is like so crazy
and you've only been doing this like big
time races like this for a short amount
of time.
Correct?
Yeah,
that's right.
How long?
Running ultra marathons for?
Maybe seven,
eight years,
but I'm getting pretty competitive in
the past couple of years.
Wow.
So how did you start out the race?
You start off running in high school?
Yeah,
back in junior high,
high school.
I ran cross country and track and
continued in during sports through
college and tried some marathons and
then it was just like a natural segue
into trail racing,
but it's just the way you're beating
these people's insane.
Not just beating them.
You're like demoralizing people.
Oh,
you're too nice when you read the second
place person by 20 hours or 20 miles.
That's so crazy.
Ten hours.
You said it was about 10 hours.
That is insane.
You're both start at the same time.
Ready,
set,
go.
You're finishing 10 hours ahead.
Like you could go,
go to sleep,
get eight hours sleep,
have a nice meal,
like sit down and,
and then just,
just show up,
clean and showered and everything like
that.
Oh,
you're finishing now.
How cute.
I just slept all night.
That's crazy.
Yeah,
it was,
it was cool.
I mean it was a cool thing.
Venture to,
to travel with your feet for 238 miles
was.
I mean it was brand new territory for me
so I didn't know how it was going to go.
Pretty much brand new territory for all
the runners.
Right?
This is like the first ever 2:40
PM,
2:40.
Quite a few.
Tom had done a bunch of 200 mile races.
There you go.
It's a picture.
You hoofing it.
Hoefling crazy.
So what is going on?
Why are you so better than everybody
else?
Um,
I think I,
I had a good day out.
Get out of here.
Three days such as you try to be too
nice.
No,
but,
but I really like objectively,
like how are you so much better than
everybody else?
I don't,
I don't know that I'm physically better
than any of them,
but I,
um,
have been really trying to learn how to
tap into my brain when it physically
becomes hard because I think our brain
can help us overcome so much and it's so
powerful.
So I'm kind of that mind over matter
thing and,
and when it physically becomes
impossible to try and switch gears into
like have it be a mental thing and just
keep pushing.
So what are you doing to do that?
Like have you studied some forms of
meditation or.
No,
I think just experience like I keep on
doing these races that put me in
uncomfortable physical states and um,
and then I,
I try and keep in mind that my brain can
help me overcome this physical pain if I
just keep going.
What?
So that's it,
just just stay tough.
Trial and error.
Yeah.
Wow.
So essentially self taught in terms of
like your mental fortitude
kind of.
Yeah,
I guess probably could give some of that
credit.
So like my parents or my upbringing or
you know,
coaches I've had along the way.
Um,
but in these,
in this past couple of years,
it's been just like not letting myself
have an excuse to stop.
Well,
that's terrifying to everybody else
because if you did decide to start like
learning meditation or something,
what if like it took you to another
level?
How do you meditate?
Yeah.
You want to do that?
Ah,
I don't know because I can't do what you
do.
I can tell you.
I mean maybe it's just being comfortable
with that excruciating agony and pain
and just like finding a,
a state of mind that you obviously know
how to achieve.
Maybe there's nothing more to it.
Maybe it's just incredibly hard work.
And just grit,
which you obviously have bolded those.
I mean that could be just,
it.
You might have the form.
Yeah.
I mean a lot of times people try to
overthink things,
right?
Like how many people do you know,
where their life sort of never changes,
but they're always like doing self help
seminars and reading all these books and
fucking nothing changes.
It's,
they're just a safe person.
They keep screwing up,
they keep getting involved in bad
relationships.
And you know,
sometimes maybe it's just there's a
simpler thing or simpler answer,
right?
Set your mind to something,
put in the work to get there and then
just execute the plan now is just the
furthest I've ever run.
That is the furthest.
Yeah.
What was the previous furthest?
Um,
the previous furthest was 155 ish miles.
Wow.
That's a big difference.
Yeah.
Wow.
And that was just on a flat track.
Oh Wow.
So this was really different than what I
had done before.
Well,
that's the interesting thing about these
mountain races like,
cause it's not just a in terms of it's
not just your cardiovascular endurance,
you have to have muscular endurance
because you're climbing.
There's a lot of elevation change,
right?
Yeah,
quite a bit.
It's nice though because then you get
the reprieve of using different muscles.
You're hiking muscles might be different
than like your flat running or your
downhill muscles.
So you get to kind of switch it around,
switch the effort around in why is
everybody in this race using trekking
poles?
I noticed that for me,
they were helpful.
I didn't use them until the,
the last quarter of the race,
um,
and they were helpful just as my feet
were becoming a little more tender and
um,
my muscles not quite as quick to catch
me on the downhills and the uphill is
just to like dispersed the effort a
little bit to my arms.
Well Jamie,
pull up that video of the,
what the,
you know,
the sort of preview video of the mob to
40 when they showed all these people
running over the top.
There's some precarious section and when
you're tired you've already run like 80,
90 miles.
Then you hit these crazy precarious
sections.
Like what does that look like?
Don't die.
And no one's there watching you.
It's not like running with other
runners,
right?
Like this would be a lonely death.
No of 200 endurance run as two and 38
mile foot race through some of Utah's
most stunning and challenging terrain.
And it really is so beautiful.
And so Solomon is the sponsor of this.
They're the presenting sponsor.
Um,
and then there's a bunch of like sub
sponsor.
I loved their trail shoes.
Look at this section.
That is insane.
This is the one that drives me nuts.
It's like if you just stumble off the
side,
that's a wrap.
Yeah.
Well,
and they're making it look like so easy
to run down.
I'm pretty sure I was like stumbling my
way down that a lot less gracefully.
Well,
how come these guys can't do it the way
you do it though?
Like something's going on because like
this is kind of be like insane too for
the other people that were running it,
that you win by these giant margins.
Yeah.
I don't know.
I think you really don't know you.
What is your
diet like?
Oh yeah,
I'm Nachos.
Nachos.
I mean just a normal diet.
I don't restrict or like try and include
anything different than the normal.
I guess the average American.
Wow.
Um,
so do you supplement with vitamins or do
you take anything else?
Uh,
I take a multivitamin.
That's it.
Yeah.
Wow.
No minerals,
nothing critical.
Creatine.
Nothing crazy.
No,
no,
no.
So just essentially a multivitamin and
hoofing it with Nachos in your belly.
That's crazy.
Like I would expect that someone who is
so far ahead of the rest of the pack
that you would have some,
like you go to Colorado Springs Olympic
training program and they get you hooked
up to these rocky four machines.
Like they had drago the Russian guy,
you're doing all this stuff and they got
like a music video soundtrack playing in
the background.
I mean,
that's what I would think.
But meanwhile you're just drinking beer,
eating Nachos.
Yeah.
Does it help live in Colorado?
Like you're,
you're at a good altitude,
right?
Yeah.
Great altitude.
I think it probably helps.
I mean,
I'm right outside Denver so there's
trails out my door.
So I,
that's my,
like everyday run is on trails climate
around the foothills of Colorado.
So quite a bit of climbing.
Um,
we're already at altitude so it's gotta.
It's gotta help.
So talk me through your preparation.
So when did it start?
Like when,
when did you sign up for this race?
When did you know that you're going to
do it?
I signed up in May,
um,
but I also was signed up for a 100 mile
race a month prior to Moab in,
so like mid September,
um,
and so my preparation was mostly for
that hundred mile race and then after
the hundred miler it was just trying to
recover,
um,
make sure my legs and body felt fresh
again and then got squeezed in a couple
more weeks of solid training to get
ready for Moab.
It's so funny because you say 100 miles
wide,
they ain't shit.
It's all relative because a marathon to
me would kill me.
But I mean you saying that you read 238
miles and then a hundred mile,
it doesn't sound like much child's play.
How long does it take you to run a
hundred miles?
I'm usually somewhere around 24 hours or
under depending on the trail and the
climbing and stuff.
So when you're getting ready.
So you,
so you're preparing mostly for the 100
mile race and then it sort of recovery.
And then did the 100 mile race
essentially get you in condition for the
2:40?
What I hoped is that it can be a good
springboard to the next one.
So,
um,
is that condition,
is that a mental thing or are we talking
about a physical thing and a mental
thing?
I think both.
Yeah,
your body.
I mean your body is important.
So like the physical aspect is important
as well.
Um,
and just being able to like pound your
legs for the,
the amount of time,
the amount of miles that you need to for
these races is physically learned.
So what kind of daily miles were you
putting in when you're getting ready for
the 100?
I would average about 100 miles per
week.
So I don't know.
So that's not even too crazy.
That's not too crazy.
Right?
Because my friend campaigns was trying
to do a marathon a day.
Yeah,
he seems insane.
That's so cool.
Is that too much?
I mean,
no,
he was doing great with it.
So
keenan and a day later than you,
you're like,
yeah,
keep it up.
You know what you should do like 40
miles a day buddy.
It depends on people's bodies.
Like some,
some people 100 miles per week is a lot
of their bodies can't sustain that and
for some like campaigns he can do a
marathon a day and,
and be in great physical form for it.
But he's a meathead and I always wonder,
I love him,
but I say this with all due respect,
I wonder if like he pushes too hard.
Like maybe there's like a fine line
between there's like a point of
diminishing return perhaps know where
you go so hard that you're kind of
overtraining and even though you can
sustain it really you get better
performance out of being like a pushing
left.
Yeah.
I don't know.
I can't speak to,
to his training,
but um,
I think he's pretty.
He's pretty new to all these ultras as
well.
Yeah,
I think so.
Over the last few years he did the big
foot.
200 last year is 205 miles.
He did that in [inaudible] 78 hours.
He actually did this race two hours
quicker than you did the 205,
which is so cool.
Crazy.
Probably because he's just humiliated by
you.
She beat me by a day,
so like,
forget about the second place person who
you could have taken a nice restful
eight hours sleep,
gotten a fine meal at a restaurant,
had a glass of wine and took a shower,
brushed your teeth,
painted your toenails if you have any
left.
Did they all fall off?
No.
Still got 10 cams all fall off there.
He takes pictures of taped up,
like really disgusting.
So when you,
um,
when you're recovering from something
like this,
how long does it take before you feel
normal again?
Um,
after this one I felt like a human.
So I finished Sunday night and I felt
human by Wednesday probably.
And got out for some jobs then like
Friday,
Saturday.
Really?
Yeah.
Wow.
I would be done with jogging forever for
this.
This is so stupid.
I just take a car next time.
What?
So like when you say you felt like a
human again?
Like what do you mean by that?
For me,
those first couple of nights after I
don't sleep very well.
I think like everything is just on
overdrive.
My legs are throbbing and uncomfortable
and um,
it's hard to turn your brain off as much
as you want to.
So I was finally like getting good
normal sleep by Wednesday and it Kinda
messed with my appetite for a couple of
days as well where food just like
wasn't.
It didn't sound that great.
Even though I was like totally depleted
of nutrition.
Yeah.
It's got to be such a shock for your
body.
Oh for sure.
Who knows?
That's probably not good for,
but
you can't be.
Well,
I say it can't be,
but maybe you can be right because maybe
you're recovering and maybe when you
recover from that extreme exertion your
vitality ups because like there's all
these people that say like,
I've read this,
that if you take them out,
if you'd run a marathon,
you should take six months off.
I've read that.
I actually read that.
Like someone's recommendation and it
takes you six months to recover from
marathon marathon.
Well,
who?
Who You fat?
So really talking about who is saying
this.
Like obviously there's people that can
do more than you,
like people,
people who are writing this stuff down
or silly because.
No,
because cam can,
if he can run a marathon a day,
obviously he doesn't need six months off
and I've hung out with him after he's
done this and he's totally normal.
Like it doesn't seem like there's
anything wrong with them.
So that's not true.
So the question is like who are we
comparing to it?
Like who is our baseline is our
baseline,
like a guy who barely works out or as
our baseline you cause you're gonna get
two radically different results.
Kind of take those articles with a grain
of salt.
Yeah,
well that's the thing.
What I was saying to Kim,
I was like,
well how do you know how much to train?
He goes,
no one knows how much to train for this
stuff because it's really just
guesswork,
which is part of the cool part,
you know,
it's like there's a million pieces to
the puzzle of ultra running and,
and figuring them out is part of the fun
of doing this sport now.
What has it been like for you after you
won?
Because you're a,
like I,
I've talked to so many people that
really have no interest normally in
endurance running and they've brought
you up constantly.
Like you're like a superstar.
It says,
I'm sure it sounds crazy to you,
but like,
uh,
my friend Brian Stevens,
he was texting me the whole way back and
forth while this was going on and you
know,
he was like looking at your numbers and
your times.
He's like,
this is fucking insane.
Like this woman is insane.
Like,
how is she doing this?
Well,
thank you.
They had a good tracking system that
was.
So.
Yeah,
that's what Brian was saying.
He's like,
I've never been less productive.
I'm just going online and checking this
thing constantly.
Um,
yeah.
I mean since then I had to create a
twitter,
didn't have any social media,
instagram,
facebook,
but I love you.
That's how you were successful.
You weren't bogged down by all the
nonsense that people just know and
social media nonsense could eat up a lot
of your dad.
I'm still figuring it out.
So don't bother.
Just occasionally post things and just
ignore everything else.
I'll just retweet it via.
That's just learning about that little
retreat,
but whenever they is.
Interesting.
That's a good move.
Yeah.
So like when you,
when you finished the race,
like what is the feeling like when you
crossed the line and you look back and
you don't even see a person like you,
you wouldn't be able to see them with
fucking binoculars like they are on the
other side of the earth.
Like the curve of the earth.
If you believe that the curve of the
earth
is literally so far like they,
they are beyond the curve.
That's true,
right?
Isn't it?
Twenty miles I would imagine you can't
see straight 20 miles.
I would imagine 20 miles you might be
able to see like the top of dudes head
and he's like,
you'd have to have one of them crazy by
knows those your glass and you can
probably see him.
But yeah,
if you're glassing glassing,
I mean what is that feeling like?
It felt amazing,
you know,
with the tracking system that we had.
Um,
when I left the last aid station,
there's like 17 miles to go and it was
pretty much um,
we could see that it was certain that I
could get to the line first as long as I
didn't like take a nap out there or
become like physically incapable,
which you could take a nap.
That was the thing.
You can take a nice one.
Just think about that.
Let me just take a nice nap here.
Oh,
nice.
Five hour nap.
And you still have like five plus hours
ahead of everybody.
Oh yeah,
that'd be nice.
Also,
it was nice because we could,
I was running with my husband at that
point.
We could enjoy the trail and like not be
like super anxious about trying to be
really efficient but just try and be
efficient on the course.
But then we saw that getting under 58
hours was possible.
So then I got a little bee in my bonnet
about,
about trying to push the pace a little
bit more.
I've never really been a great phrase,
oh you should come to Minnesota.
We've got all sorts of good graces.
So does your husband run the same kind
of races that you run or did he just
like hop in every now and then?
Um,
he runs 50 milers and 50 k's,
so 31 miles.
But he didn't enter this race.
No,
he didn't.
He just kind of helped you along,
jumped in certain spots.
So how does he get these spots?
You have to drive all relaxed and if you
picture a 238 mile loop,
he,
he had to drive to all of the places on
this course.
So maybe he spent the day in the car the
couple of days in the car and I had a
um,
a fantastic crew of friends out there.
And in these races you can have pacers
for certain sections.
So I could have a buddy run with me,
um,
who was fresh and like their brain and
their eyes and their legs were.
I'm more alert to help me just keep
track of the course.
Flags like staying on course and stuff
like that.
That's interesting.
Like when you're doing this for this
amount of hours,
what was the total hours again?
Fifty rate under 58.
So when you're doing it for this amount
of hours,
how much sleep are you getting?
Um,
I slept 21 minutes.
Wow.
That is so crazy.
That was two separate naps.
So like 10 and 10 and 11.
Really the one minute nap and it was
amazing.
The best sleep I've ever had.
Was it really?
It really was.
Well just why did you get up though?
After a minute?
Um,
so I did the 20 minute nap
intentionally.
I crawled in the back of our crew car.
We had a sleeping bag back there and I
tried to get some good rest after it was
like middle of the second night and I
didn't sleep very well.
Um,
I was just really uncomfortable and
yeah,
and I was still like pretty amped up so
I couldn't shut my brain off even though
it was like becoming pretty delirious.
I'm.
So then I left that aid station after
laying in the car for 20 minutes and I
was on the trail with one of my good
friends and Pacers and I was falling
asleep as I was running like Zig zagging
all over the trail.
I couldn't keep my eyes open.
So at one point I was bent over and I
was like phase planning towards the
ground and he's like,
just laid down,
like take a nap right here,
right on the trail.
Um,
so I'm like laying down already snoring
as I'm like one minute,
just one minute,
wakes me up one minute later and I was
like more alert than I've ever been.
And then we were super pumped up the
rest of the time because we were like,
oh,
one minute nap.
It was,
that's the craziest thing I've ever
heard in my life.
A bunch of people like,
um,
I talked to Cam,
I think he took us similarly,
like really short nap and it just like
rejuvenate's you in a weird way.
I've,
I've heard that before.
The like if you're really tired,
a 20 minute nap will make a huge
difference.
If you could just lie down and I've
always ignored that.
Like how is that gonna be better next
time?
Try just one minute.
I'm lazy.
I would.
I would stay asleep when he woke you up
after one minute.
Will you like,
why'd you wake me up?
No,
I was like,
why'd you let me sleep so long?
It had been.
I thought it had been at least 30
minutes and I was like,
dude,
we gotta go,
why'd you let me sleep so long?
It was like that was one minute one
whole minute ready go.
And you were just out cold was cold.
I rem cycle like dreams and everything.
I remember them.
I don't,
but I.
It was like the deepest sleep.
Wow.
And what was cool is as I was laying on
the trail for one minute,
it was dark and beautiful stars out and
there were elk bugling like up on the
hill.
So it was cool that I didn't.
I didn't hallucinate that that was real.
You hallucinate at all.
I just had some hallucinations.
Yeah.
What would you see?
You know,
in the forest at night,
everything just becomes something.
So there were tons of like faces and
animals.
There was a guy playing a cello.
Um,
there was a leopard hanging out in a
hammock.
Vivid are these,
I mean pretty like where I think they're
real and I'm like waving at them.
You're waving at the Leopard in the
Hammock?
Well,
I didn't wave to him.
I waved to the cello player.
Really?
But did you know he wasn't real as you
were running by?
Yeah,
I mean now that I've done these quite a
few times in the night,
I usually see some things and so now
it's just like Kinda cool to acknowledge
that it's happening and try and
remember.
So I can tell my,
tell my friends afterwards.
So is there any part of you that thinks
like,
hey,
there's a guy with a cello in the woods,
or is there
just a recognition that you're freaking
out because you're running 58 miles or
58 hours?
I think just a recognition like,
Huh,
guy with cello.
So you're just so focused on what you're
doing that even the most bizarre thing,
like a leopard in a hammock.
Yeah.
I mean,
it just happens now,
so I know there's not actually one,
but how often does this take place?
I mean,
how many of these have you done these
ultra marathons?
I'm quite a few.
And did they start the hallucinations
started in the early ones?
Yeah,
basically like my first couple of
hundred milers where you go through the
night.
It's always the nighttime where the
shadows just like play tricks on you.
Um,
and so I'm like in the mountains of
Colorado and there's giraffes and like
flying eels and all sorts of weird
things and at first I was freaked out
about it.
Um,
but now it's just like,
all right,
that'll be a fun story to tell
afterwards.
Have you talked to a doctor or anyone
and say,
hey,
what happens to the mind when.
No,
I haven't.
I'd be fascinated to know,
like what is,
what's happening that's causing you to
have these like extreme visual
hallucinations because you're saying
they looked real.
Yeah.
But I think it's just like shadows and
your brain is too tired to like process,
so it just jumbles them together into
something that would make sense.
Wow.
I don't know,
but it's not freaking you out.
You're just like,
all right,
cello guy.
Hey Man.
Rock on dude.
Yeah,
thanks for the tunes.
Could you hear him?
No.
So he was just like silent including a
child,
which is creepy.
It itself.
Wow.
Is that the only hallucinations or was
there anything else weird
during this one?
Um,
those were like the significant ones.
Otherwise,
just a lot of like random faces on trees
or rocks and stuff like that.
Now
as you're running right and you're
running for 50 whatever,
miles or 58 hours and you're constantly
moving forward because you're a point in
time where your body like,
like what does it feel like de you look
in constant pain or are you just numb to
it?
Like what happens?
Um,
it's Kinda,
you go in waves,
like you'll be riding this wave where
you're just feeling like amazing and
really fresh and like your legs can
cruise pretty well and nothing
hurts.
You know,
everything's feeling really good and
then that wave will eventually come
crashing down where things are hurting
again.
And then you might be like whimpering
along for a little bit,
but the cool part about these is that
those waves,
like,
I mean,
they always come and then they,
they go.
So you ride this like high and low the
whole race.
Um,
and when it gets really low,
when you're feeling awful,
you just have to remember that you're
going to feel better again soon.
You just got to keep chugging along.
So you're in pain and then somehow or
another you feel better even though you
don't stop running.
Yeah.
How does it work?
I don't know,
like a switch flips or um,
sometimes I'll like intentionally during
those lows take more calories in
thinking maybe that will help.
Just like give my body some something to
burn for awhile to make it happy again.
What kind of stuff can you eat while
you're running this much?
I'm in one this length.
I was doing a lot of um,
like water gatorade and then there's
this powder you can put in water called
tailwind.
It has electrolytes and 200 calories per
bottle.
So you're getting in calories and then
like normal athletic foods like honey
stinger products,
which are like gels and shoes and stuff.
But then I was eating boatloads of the
Cheese Chiesa Dia's at all the aid
stations.
They serve cheese case a day.
Oh my gosh.
It was like a whole buffet line.
Anything you wanted were real about
these aid stations?
Yeah,
it was good.
Oh,
it was amazing.
Wow.
So you could eat cheese,
case ideas and just keep running.
Yeah.
So I would stop at each aid station,
um,
demolished a cheese Chiesa Dia,
like hang out for just a second to let
my body reset and then keep cruising.
Wow.
Which normally I'm not very good at
eating real food during,
but this just felt like too much.
There's Cam with the Bacon cheeseburger
cover you a blanket.
Oh,
that's another thing.
Like there's points in the race where
it's extremely cold.
Right?
It got really cold.
I think we hit nine degrees on the
second night.
And what are you wearing?
Um,
a couple of jackets,
like a windbreaker jacket and a rain
jacket and some gloves.
And like a headband,
some pants,
nothing like absurd.
So just the fact that you're constantly
moving,
you stay fairly warm and the windbreaker
is uh,
the,
the rain jacket to stop rain or are from
wind.
Just layers.
I just wanted to like try and insulate
the body heat.
Are you eating those?
Uh,
those little waffle things,
those bee stingers we've had them.
Yeah,
that'd be great.
Or awesome.
So you're just trying to take in like
the densest stuff,
like sugars and cheese in case of
anything.
Just anything that would stay in.
I didn't want to get nauseous and start
losing it on the trail.
And
Cam said he doesn't go to the bathroom
the entire time.
Like he doesn't have to just food just
goes
in and just burn.
Yeah.
Is that the case with youtube?
Question to ask women bring?
It isn't.
But he said he didn't poop for like
three days.
I don't know if that's healthy cam.
He's got a lot of healthy problems.
Talk to him.
Maybe listen to you.
He doesn't listen to me.
No.
I use the restroom while I was out
there.
Did You have to pee?
Was.
That's crazy because I would think that
you're sweating so much through would
just go right through your skin.
I'm sure the science of it for awhile I
was paying way too much,
like multiple times per mile and I think
it has something to do with the amount
of salt that you're taking in.
That was another question I had.
Do you do.
Are you taking salt tablets?
I wasn't until I was having this problem
and then it was like we got to try and
stop this [inaudible] that's not good
either to go as often.
Has that?
Yeah.
So then I took some salt tabs or
whatever mills.
Did that clear it up?
Yep.
Now what are those like?
Do you know what milligrams,
how much salt you're actually taking in?
Nope.
No.
S,
s caps or something.
They're just a normal like you can buy
them at any.
Any athletic store.
Oh,
so this is just a little pill of salt.
I think it's mostly for runners
essentially.
That's all I've seen used them.
But you could.
You could probably have some if you
wanted.
What's the thought process behind it
though?
The top processes that your body is
pushing through all these minerals and
the salt helps you retain water.
And what about other minerals?
Do you have to take magnesium or
anything else were you doing that?
I didn't know and I don't even really
know the,
the exact contents of that tailwind
powder that I was putting in.
I know it has lots of electrolytes and
stuff like that that's supposed to help,
but I'm not sure if it has some of the
other pieces that people need during
these.
Now before the race gets started,
do you hyperhydrate or you do drink a
ton of water to get ready or.
Yeah,
I tried.
I mean,
nothing too crazy but crazy.
No.
What about food before the race?
You just eat like a pig and get ready?
No,
no just normal.
Just normal.
Normal.
Natchez.
Just normal beer.
And so like when your,
like as you're leaving like as ready,
set,
go,
what's the state of mind you go into
when you know that you're about to run
238 miles and kick everybody's ass?
Uh,
it was exciting,
it was this big adventure that I had,
I had high expectations of myself while
at the same time having no expectations
of myself because I didn't know,
I didn't know how it was going to go,
um,
and I really wanted to just enjoy being
out there,
like moving my body with my feet for
multiple days was really exciting so I
was pumped at the,
at the beginning and um,
spent those first
probably 50 miles,
like running with various people through
the desert.
There's like canyon walls just like
towering on every side and just trying
to enjoy that.
Like this is just the beginning.
If you start to comprehend or think
about like how far you have to go,
you're going to freak yourself out.
So like just be right now.
So you just sort of stay in the moment.
That's what I was trying to do.
Yeah,
just left foot,
right foot,
left foot,
go,
go.
Easy as that.
Is there ever a moment while you're
doing this where you want to stop
and quit?
Yes.
No,
I never wanted to quit.
I,
uh,
I knew that the cutoff time was,
was Tuesday night and so no matter what
happened out there,
I was going to make sure I'm finished
this race.
Even if I was,
I'm coming in Tuesday night,
like if it meant I had to sleep for
many,
many hours or multiple times or if I had
to like death march my way around the
desert.
I was gonna finish it.
Death March,
you know,
just like slow.
Oh,
okay.
That's a harsh way of looking at though.
Oh sorry.
No,
no,
don't apologize.
It's good.
So I did notice that there were some
people that were still running,
you know,
after you guys had finished.
And you know,
after Cameron finished,
I stopped looking at the uh,
the time for quite a while and then I
went like eight hours,
nine hours later and I'm like,
oh my God,
people are still running.
Yeah,
those are warriors.
They're so impressive.
I mean,
they were out there putting on their
headlamp for the fifth night.
That's a long time to be out there.
And they were,
it was incredible.
We got to hang around the finish line
and watched quite a few of those stuck
around.
Yup.
Yeah.
That was one of the best parts.
Sleet and ice cream.
A drinking beer.
But did you think to yourself like,
how the hell did I finished so much
faster than anybody?
Um,
no.
I thought,
how the heck are these people?
Like so incredible and still going
after.
I mean,
I'd like to think I'd be able to keep
pushing myself on that fourth day into
the fourth night,
but that's mentally really hard.
Oh,
it's got to be.
Yeah.
But you do understand that you stopped.
Everybody's asked.
You Do,
you do get that right?
You,
you're like,
you're so humble.
So this is kind of amazing.
Thank you.
Do you understand that though,
right?
I mean it's like has an internalized.
Um,
I understand.
Yeah.
I put together a pretty good day.
When you,
when you stop and you think about when
you reflect and you look back on it were
like,
you know,
a week past,
it was about more than two weeks.
How long ago was it?
Oh,
one week.
One Week.
Yup.
So you're a week passed it and how do
you like,
how do you process that?
That's still.
I'm still working on it.
Like just the whole adventure.
All the places,
like all the sites.
I got to see the people that I got to
meet.
The fact that my feet carried me that
far.
Like I'm coming Tuesday.
Ron Solomon choose which ones and
they're called the sense ride.
Have you tried them?
I see you.
You got some Solomon's.
I always wear these a trail runner
things.
Yes,
they.
They're good.
They have a lot of grip when I'm not
wearing those vibrams or were those five
finger shoes too?
I sort of alternate.
So do you run the.
You run the sidewalks in?
Those are just running trails.
You run around here?
Yeah.
That's awesome.
It's good.
But it's not like Colorado.
You're dealing with altitude and a lot
more.
You also,
you have like,
didn't someone just die?
Some endurance guy just got bit by a
rattlesnake near you?
Yeah,
that's in Golden,
wasn't it?
Yelp,
which is where I live.
Holy Shit.
What happened to that dude?
Just really unfortunate.
I don't actually know the whole story,
but he was out on a trail,
like it's a couple miles from my house
and got bit and had some like,
weird reaction to it,
like he had help pretty quickly,
um,
and got to the hospital in pretty good
time.
But unfortunately something about his
body and that bite like wasn't good.
Wow.
Yeah.
Because I've thought rattlesnakes,
like you have a few hours.
Yeah,
usually.
Right?
Yeah,
I mean it's not good,
but it's not good at few hours and
pretty much if you read anything about
what to do after a rattle snake bite,
those things are wrong.
Like,
you pretty much can't do anything.
You shouldn't suck the venom out.
You shouldn't like slice it open and you
shouldn't do anything.
Just get to the hospital as calmly as
possible.
Shouldn't suck the venom out.
No.
What was that?
Uh,
Dan Akroyd movie or he got like Venom is
bought and he was telling someone to
suck the.
Remember that.
But that word,
but we're going to see it here and it's
like he's furiously typing because the
reason why I remember it was because Sam
kinison was mocking him,
was mocking it,
but they almost all had some sort of a
feud back in the day anyway.
Well if he wasn't in city slickers.
Oh,
okay.
that's why Sam Kinison was mocking it.
He got kicked off the original city
slickers.
He was in it.
He was in the original cast and he
didn't get along with somebody and they
got rid of him.
Well,
it wouldn't have helped if he did suck
them in.
A lot of people think that you should do
that.
I don't know,
old wives' tale or something.
I'm not sure you.
They say you're supposed to cut it,
cut it open and yeah,
you're not supposed to do that either.
What do you do?
Do you make a tourniquet?
I think that's actually a good idea,
right?
The,
the latest thing
I read that's the best to do is just
have a sharpie along circle where the
bite is and mark the time and then like
every 20 minutes as you're.
If you have to hike yourself out or like
you're trying to get somewhere to go get
help,
circle it again 20 minutes later to show
where the swelling has gotten to so that
the doctors have a better idea of like
how quickly it's moving through you.
I saw horrible thing online to this
young man got bit in his arm and his
skin started to die and there's tissue
starts to die,
you know,
necrosis.
And so they had to do all these massive
skin graphs and just massive surgeries
and it had essentially rotted down to
the bone and you can see like the bone
in his arm.
It was rough,
but he,
he lived.
Yeah,
I think you've gone through more than 10
surgeries.
Geez.
Yeah.
It was awful.
And I didn't know the rattle snakes
could do that to you.
I'm like,
Whoa,
you have rattlesnakes here?
Oh yeah.
I killed one just a couple of weeks ago
with your bare hands stomped it.
Oh yeah.
I stomped on every chance I get.
People say you shouldn't,
but fuck them.
Like if they're near my house like this.
No.
I have kids.
I have little kids like any rattle snake
that's in my yard is dead.
What else do you guys are mountain lions
out here?
Yes.
You ever seen one of those?
I've seen them,
but I saw him in Colorado.
I haven't seen one out here.
I saw one in Santa Barbara actually.
That was weird.
It was in Montecito,
which is like this really nice
residential community and we're driving
up the road and I saw what I thought was
a coyote.
The coyote would a tail.
Oh,
it's a fucking cat.
Just out on the street.
Just out on a regular street.
Yeah,
it was a big fucker to know.
I can probably 70,
80 pounds.
You know.
Those are scary.
Yeah.
It's like,
it's not big for a mountain lion.
They get to be like 1:15.
And what's really interesting on here as
people don't.
Everyone here is so urbanized that their
understanding of what a mountain lion
is,
is like,
you know,
they think it's the lion king.
There's this one that uh,
he has a name too.
It's like p two or p 41 or some shit.
And he went on a killing rampage at an
Alpaca farm and killed like 11 alpacas
and goats.
Yeah.
And doesn't even eat them.
He just went on a rampage and this woman
got a depredation permit to kill it
because it's her Alpaca farm.
And like this lion is just decided to
start fucking up or animals and this is
what she does for a living.
And she got all these death threats from
animal rights activists.
I mean like death threats.
Like she was terrified.
So she decided not to do anything.
She's going to hire someone to kill this
mountain lion.
But it's like if you love animals,
wouldn't you want to stop the animal
that's murdering all her animals?
You fucking crazy assholes.
One,
it's not doing it for food,
which is unusual.
Well,
the apparently they have a reaction.
They can get into a pen when there is a
bunch of them in there.
They just can't help themselves.
They just,
they just can't help themselves.
They just see them all there and they
just Jack One and Jack the other one.
And he wasn't even eating them.
He didn't eat any of them.
Yeah,
I've never seen one out on a run,
but I've always got my eyes peeled.
It would be so scary.
Oh,
they're terrifying.
They're terrifying animals and you know,
for the most part they're important.
They're an important part of the
ecosystem.
But the weird thing about here is we've
sort of sectioned off their habitat by
our highway system and so there's some
of them that are stuck in the Santa
Monica mountains and the genetic
diversity is not very strong.
I actually had a coyote expert on here
who is a,
he works for the,
what did he work for?
The,
what was the actual organization he
worked for far with.
How was it
anyway,
some sort of park ranger type fellow.
A really nice guy.
But he was telling us about,
um,
the ones that they have,
like in Griffith Park,
there's a mount mine in Griffith Park,
people jogging and ride their bikes and
this guy is just out there eating deer
all day long and they have to capture
him every couple of years.
They have to dart him because his
collar,
the,
uh,
the tracking device on his collar runs
out of batteries,
so every couple of years they've got to
put the whack on this guy,
put them to sleep and repeat them in the
park.
Exactly.
Want to relocate?
No.
It's interesting.
It was one of the good things about
California is that we don't have a lot
of car accidents with deer.
You know,
it's,
it's very uncommon.
Whereas you said you're from Michigan,
Minnesota,
Minnesota has a lot,
lot of,
um,
a lot of car accidents.
Yeah.
And these places where they don't have
apex predators,
they have a lot more.
Do you guys have,
what do you have out there?
Like as far as you have wolves in
Minnesota?
Yeah,
so I think like way north there's even
like,
I mean there's got to be Moose and you
have mountain lions,
Minnesota.
I don't know about any mountain lions
out here.
There's a,
there's a lot of coyotes which get the
Fonz and then there's mountain lions
which decimate the deer.
So no car accident.
Very few deer.
California is like a really low dear
densities state.
Interesting.
So there's a.
there's good to that.
Northern Minnesota fighting cougars now
believed to be broadcast fighting each
other.
They're up in a tree.
Yeah,
that's a bobcat.
Where's this tail?
This one is the one on the left.
It is that probably to hide some
cardboard cutout to cut out the size of
a Cougar Mountain.
My left is compared to the photograph of
a box,
just probably doing it for the photos.
Oh yeah.
Oh,
that makes sense.
Passing the time.
Yeah.
I saw a bobcat that I thought was a
cougar.
I saw a bobcat with the cubs and uh,
in,
uh,
at the home ranch.
And I thought it was a cougar.
Yeah.
Well I just saw the cat.
I was like this big cat in the road and
I was like,
whoa.
Is that an outline?
And then we eventually figured out that
it was a bobcat.
They get to a good size.
We do have bobcats soda.
So I got a question for you.
Can you talk about the run rabbit run
race you had that you won or that end?
I'll let her describe it because it
sounds pretty crazy what happened.
So the hundred mile race that I was
doing a month before my lab at about 12
miles roughly to the finish line,
my vision started blurring like in the
periphery.
Um,
and over the course of the next couple
of miles closed in until it was pure
white,
I couldn't see anything.
Um,
so I just stumbled my way along roughly
10 miles of trails to get to the finish
line.
Pretty much I would say like 98 percent
blind.
I could see my feet like right in front
of my feet,
but it was just white out.
So I was running and falling everywhere.
It was probably hilarious if people were
watching.
But um,
I hit my head also on Iraq.
One of them,
yeah,
one of the Times I fell.
So I had blood dripping down my face,
like stumbling along.
Totally couldn't see the trail.
Still one.
Yeah.
Managed to finish and,
and hold the lead.
You're a savage.
Give seminars on how to be a savage.
That is crazy.
So what,
what did,
what happened to your vision?
Um,
so since then there's been tons of
people kind of talking about it.
Apparently it happens in an ultra is
quite often they are thinking it's a
corneal edema.
So basically like I wear contact lenses
to see,
um,
in the like contact mixed with the air
and the dryness and all sorts of things
cause like a kind of fluid or I'm not
really sure how it works.
You ever thought about getting Lasik or
something?
People who have done lasik also get this
corneal edema.
So for now I'm just a stay in,
stay in with the context because I'm,
I've been learning how to deal with
those a little bit better.
Did that concern you at all when you
were about to run 238 miles?
Yeah,
I really didn't want to go blind again.
Jesus Christ.
But I actually had that course.
Yeah.
Yeah,
right off a cliff.
I was using eye drops just like get some
like tears going in there.
And I wore glasses for this whole race
in Moab because that's supposed to help
as well.
Grit from now when you back and you won
that race and you were basically almost
blind,
how long did it take for your vision to
recover?
Five.
Six hours.
Oh,
that's it.
Yeah.
Oh,
that must have been a relief.
Such a relief.
Yeah,
it was pretty sick of it.
By the time I finished we.
Were you concerned that it could be
potentially permanent?
You know,
it didn't feel permanent.
It felt.
I think because it went white and
because it like moved in slowly.
It felt like topical.
I don't know.
I didn't,
I didn't really consider while I was
racing if it was permanent,
I was just like,
amped on finishing the race at that
point.
Um,
but once I finished,
no one seemed overly concerned about it.
Like we went to the hospital and um,
they were more concerned with checking
out my head.
Um,
so it didn't feel like that urgent.
Yeah.
But it was weird.
Did you think about quitting?
No Jew,
even though you're blind and you got a
concussion,
he looked like carried night.
Like what the hell?
Well,
I hit my head and it thunked pretty
hard.
And then there was liquid dripping on my
face,
but I put my hand up to touch it and I
couldn't see my hand in front of my face
to see if it was blood or not.
Wow.
I had no idea.
What is this course like you're running
on?
Um,
it's in steamboat Colorado,
so mountains and I'm pretty rough trails
on this section where I fell.
Um,
yeah.
But the last six miles of the race,
you finally get to like a fire road.
So a little bit wider,
a little more room for error if you go
crooked.
That's just so crazy.
So how,
how are you knowing where to stop?
You're not,
you're just guessing.
So that's a picture of the course.
Yeah.
So you're running that course blind?
Well that sections quite a bit more
technical than the section I went blind
on.
When you say technical,
what exactly do you mean?
Like big rocks and cliffs,
stuff like that.
The second thing I wanted to be,
why would that be technical?
Um,
I dunno,
that's just the word that I associate
with like trickier trail,
like you have to be more used technique.
Is that what they're saying?
Maybe I've heard that term before.
That's why I always ask like,
people talk about like technical
terrain,
like do you know,
I don't know what a,
I don't know the root word for it.
I guess you just can't just flat out
just huff it.
You have to think about what you're
doing.
Like your foot placement is critical.
A little bit tricky.
Kind of looking down a lot while you're
running.
You can't just run straight.
Right?
Right.
Like,
because most people,
like if you're running on a flat trail,
you just kind of looking ahead.
You're assuming the road is going to be
the same with the left foot as it is for
the right foot and the left say that
right.
This,
you can't right now when you do in
something like that,
I would think.
Well you got to constantly looked down.
That is when I would be concerned about
like mountain lions or something like
that.
Yeah,
because you're not looking.
Yeah.
And they probably think you're to get
away,
right?
Yeah.
I,
I'm pretty sure if you end up seeing the
mountain lion,
it's already too late for you.
Did you hear about that kid in Alaska?
They got eaten by a bear and a race.
Yeah.
That's unfortunate.
Called his mom to call this mom before
the bear attacked him and said,
I think there's a bear that's following
me.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I mean animals are a real part of it out
there.
There was also a guy who was jogging
along,
minding his own business and a hawk came
and tried to swoop him,
scoop his head.
He had scratches across his whole head
from the talents of this hawk.
What?
Pull up that picture?
Yeah.
What?
Like the Hawk thought he was food,
so he was going to grab them and bring
them to the nest.
Gangster Hawk was this guy.
I don't think that little thing like a,
a,
an an adult.
I'm pretty sure
if a hawk landed on my head,
I guarantee you I'm going to have a
stuffed hawking here right here.
I'm going to have that fucker and I'm
going to have like a plastic hand around
the neck.
Fucking assholes.
I have hawks in my yard all the time.
They're trying to get my chickens.
One.
I think they got one.
One of them went missing and we're
trying to figure out what happened.
Look at that.
Wow.
That is crazy.
That's from the the whatever.
Escaped Harris Hawks are attacking
runners and walkers prompting fears
there now breeding in Britain.
Oh,
this is an England.
Wow.
That is a huge gap for people who are
just listening.
We're talking like 11,
12 inch gash is on this guy's head and
the whole head.
His whole.
The whole top of his head is like a
track,
like train tracks,
like two straight lines.
Kind of a cool scar.
It's going to make the beautiful scar.
Right?
What happened to you?
Gangster Shit.
I wonder.
I wonder if he did.
He said,
oh my.
This hawk is trying to take me away.
Oh,
did someone help me?
That's not the hawk.
That one looks too small.
Harris Hawk.
So this is an escaped hawk.
They're saying.
So is this a hawk that like essentially
was a captive hawk and now they got
loose and they don't know how to eat,
they don't know what to do and maybe
that's crazy.
Maybe it liked thought this guy was a
give it a shot.
I recall hearing what I now know is the
bird's wings flapping behind my head and
then suddenly just tell him.
But other than that,
there was no warning.
She thought it was a mugging.
He thought he got mugged.
Wow.
What a crazy bird.
The bird thinking they could kill a
person.
Yeah,
that is.
That is like gangster burden.
Escaped bird attacking human.
Go back to that again real quick.
What do you say?
Whilst the attacker was originally
thought to be a buzzard,
no one had become aggressive during the
nesting season.
Experts pointed out the native birds of
prey seldom strike in the summer months.
Wow.
Harris Hawk.
Yeah.
Those,
those things that the claws and those.
We were just talking about eagles the
other day,
like imagine like a,
something that can swoop down and grab a
salmon out of a river and fly off with
it.
These ridiculous things they have at the
bottom of their feet.
Pick up like small deer and stuff.
Yeah,
we can.
Yeah.
The Mongols use them to um,
to uh,
attack wolves.
They,
uh,
they have trained eagles that they
swooped down and they grab wolves and
they killed the wolves.
They drop them from the Pi.
They just kill them.
They kill them with their talents.
Their towns are so strong.
It's like knives.
They just grab a hold her neck and stick
the towns into the side of the neck.
It's crazy to watch.
I mean,
these aren't big wolves.
These are like coyote size wolves,
but it's still,
it's like,
it's,
it's so weird to watch.
It's like this thing just trying to run
away and this eagle just knows what to
do.
Swoops down.
Just grabs him by the neck and wrestle
them to the ground.
And then the Mongolian guys come over
here.
You can watch it here.
So they're trained.
See they have those little strings
coming off the back of your legs and
there's wolves like fuck.
And so this dude just releases the
eagle.
The Eagle swoops down and just death
from the sky.
Just Jackson.
It's crazy to think that this was
somehow or another,
they trained these things to do this
too,
and then they would kill the wolves and
take their skins.
I guess they like make jackets or
something.
The Wolf knows what's going on too and
look at.
He's so much bigger than the eagle.
That's what's really crazy because what
does an ego way,
like 20 pounds or something like that or
ran a little faster there.
This tired ass.
They are though.
It's just.
He loved birds.
Huge,
but even a huge bird is a fraction of
the size of that wolf and then just
holding them down.
Then we expand freaks it out.
I just don't think.
I think it's just a superior murdering
machine.
You know what I mean?
I think like when it comes to like
nature's killers,
eagles are just far superior to a wolf.
I mean they,
they have air on their side.
They,
they swooped down on you,
which is cool.
Yeah.
They moved through three d space,
you know,
it's just a whole different thing.
So did they ever get your chickens?
Uh,
I know that a hawk has.
Well we'd know.
I saw a coyote get one.
I saw a coyote run over the fence with a
chicken in his mouth.
I was sitting with my wife and my kids
were playing some game,
like monopoly or some shit and we look
out the window and I see a coyote
running through the backyard with a
chicken in his mouth and he just hops
the fence and I opened the door just to
go,
you fucker like that.
He was gone and it was a,
it was a very complicated scenario
because he actually had talked my dog
and to helping him.
No Way.
Yeah,
I think it was a girl.
I think it was a pretty sure it was girl
coyote and uh,
my dog.
Yeah.
My dog thought it was,
have a big dumb dog and he thought that
like this Murphy wants to play with the
triggers and told help them because the
dog can.
My dog is a,
he's a nice dog to people,
but he's not nice to chickens.
He's murdered a few chickens in the
past.
He's got,
I think so far he's killed six of my
chickens.
Oh Wow.
Yeah,
he broke into the fence recently.
I don't think I talked about this.
We were outside,
um,
uh,
and we had heard something.
We heard these chickens squawking and
making up all this noise and I look and
I'm like,
how is the dog in the chicken coop?
He clawed through the chicken wire.
He's a massive,
he's a big man and he's just smash the
chicken wire enough so he could get his
body in there and just went on a rampage
and just was murdering and chickens.
Whoops.
Yeah.
See just their instinct,
you know,
they just can't help it.
And like a friend of mine said that he
had a dog that did that once.
They killed his chicken and he took the
dead chicken and tied it on the dog's
head and then chained the dog to a tree
and left him there for a couple hours.
And he said,
he said it worked.
He said the dog never fucked with the
chickens again,
sir.
Are you going to try that?
Uh,
no,
no.
My,
I think my golden retriever,
he's a sweetheart and I think he's
killed the chicken too.
I don't know if he killed it,
but he showed up with one in his mouth
and it was dead and we're trying to
figure out if he killed it or if it was
already dead because sometimes they just
die.
She because we don't like to think he's
a kid.
He's still a baby,
but he might've died two dogs,
just dogs and chickens.
It's like,
you know,
it's a classic relationship now.
I don't know how we got on this.
Oh,
runners.
Animals.
Yeah.
Sorry about that.
Worried about,
do you ever bring any sort of first aid
with you?
Do you bring like a backpack when you're
running?
Um,
it depends on where I'm going or how
long I intend to be out there.
So like when you're running moab,
do you bring any sort of a backpack or
anything?
Yeah,
I had a pack that was carrying water and
I'm like an emergency blanket and jacket
just in case and food.
So when you have an emergency blanket,
is that one of those thin like sort of a
silvery blankets just folds down into a
very small those really work?
Yeah,
I mean fortunately I've never had to use
one and an actual emergency,
but um,
you know how after marathons they give
everyone like a tin foil wrap basically.
I think it's the same thing where it's
like holding in your body heat.
So if worse comes to worse out there,
you've got something to,
to help you get through it rather than
nothing.
Right.
Now,
when you were running a new drinking
water,
are you,
do you have bottles of water or do you
have like a hydration bladder in a tube?
Like what do you,
how do you run it?
The guy was using has bottles
so it can carry.
I mean at one point I had two and a half
liters of water with me for like a
really hot long section.
How long did that last?
Before I made it last for 20 miles.
That's crazy.
That's it.
Two and a half liter.
Seems like a tiny amount of water to
drink for 20 miles of running.
God,
that's crazy.
Yeah.
And it was a really hot,
exposed day out there in the desert.
Have you ever been running like a.
Kim was telling me that he did the big
foot 200 and there was a stretch where
he miscalculated and you realize that
terrain and he didn't have any water.
You to go for several hours with no
water.
Have you ever done that before?
That's awful.
Um,
I don't know if I've ever had to go
several hours,
but yeah,
I've gotten to the point where it's like
miles and miles away still.
And you're fresh out of water.
So that's got suck.
Yeah.
The,
the,
how much of a performance hit does that
take?
I think it depends.
Like also it can take a big toll out of
you mentally if you stress out about it
too much,
but if you're just like,
well this is the situation,
the only solution is to get to the next
aid station.
Then,
um,
I think it is just a blip on the radar.
That's an interesting approach
and that's what I wanted to get to this
about how it transcends and how your,
this,
your mental fortitude sort of like how
it manifests itself in everyday life.
Like your ability to just deal with shit
is so superior to the average person.
Like when you hear people complain like
starbucks is out of fucking Venti lattes
is such bullshit,
you know,
like no more Combo macchiatos like
normal everyday complaining stuff is
like what a lot of people sort of engage
in sort of a recreation.
The people love to complain about
nonsense,
right?
Yeah.
Well how do you deal with that to each
their own?
I think,
I mean it just let it happen.
If that Venti Latte was going to make
your day,
I'm really sorry that they're out,
you know,
but there's got to be a part of you that
realizes like how.
I mean,
so many people are just really very weak
in terms of their ability to overcome
adversity.
No,
I think they just aren't giving
themselves enough credit and I think
we're all capable of way more than we
think we are if we just like jump in and
go for it,
whatever it is.
Right.
And do you think like you realize that
more the more you push yourself,
like do you understand yourself more
after running 200,
30,
eight miles?
I'm trying to,
yeah,
I'm trying to like find my physical
boundary.
I'm trying to find the mental boundary,
like where,
where can I take this and trying to
learn about myself and about the world
and meet people along the way.
I think that that must give you immense
confidence to overcome bound obstacles.
Boundaries,
like the fact that you can do what you
can do,
that you can just put your mind into
this state of just dealing with the
constant grime.
You're falling asleep,
you're half blind.
I mean the site is more than half blind,
98 percent of blind.
I mean this has got to sort of
transcend.
I mean it's really must sort of make its
way into your everyday life in a very
weird way.
I hope so.
What do you do for regular stuff?
Like do you have a regular job?
Uh,
I taught middle school and high school
science for nine years and just this
past year I stepped out of the
classroom.
So now you just run.
So currently am I'm running?
Yeah.
Wow.
So how does that work?
You have sponsors or something like
that?
Yup.
I have some sponsors and a really
supportive husband and um,
and my school has been super supportive
through all this and they were like go
see what you can do without the,
without the 7:00
AM to 7:00
PM,
shift,
you know,
like,
see what you can make of this and uh,
and let us know if you want back in
teaching ever.
Did they freak out when you won the
Moab?
Well,
one of the guys I teach with Islam was
actually one of my pacers out there,
so he has been really supportive and
awesome to train with and I haven't
actually talked to anyone else at the
school since then,
but they gotta be incredibly proud.
I mean to,
to say,
hey,
go go see what you can do.
And they're like,
hey,
look what I can do here.
It is pretty crazy.
And then.
So is this your,
your,
your goal now is to just run,
uh,
yeah,
for the time being,
I want to,
um,
just see what can happen if I really
dedicate more time and energy to
training and traveling for races and um,
all of the pieces that go with it.
That.
And what does the woman's name that put
on the job?
Candice.
Burt.
Generous.
And does candice like look at.
I know she,
is she involved in bigfoot as well?
Yeah,
all those 200 mile races are hers.
But if she looked at the 2:40
now and look at you and go,
courtney might be able to do three slash
20.
She,
she,
uh,
just the other day.
Suggested on the like 200 facebook group
and she put it out there.
What about a 500 mile?
Courtney?
No,
that's candice.
She suggested.
I know courtney don't do that.
I mean,
why you're a psycho.
Candice is a crazy person.
Does she run these races to?
Oh,
well unfortunately when your race
directing she can't run the $200,
but she definitely,
I wish I could wish I could run with you
courtney.
She does a lot of a 100 mile races and
yeah,
it was a great runner.
500.
That is next level.
What is the longest anybody has ever
run?
Like what's the longest race ever?
Um,
no.
let's see.
So there's races that are called six day
races and it's just on a small loop and
you try and go as far as you can do that
loop as many times as you can in six
days.
And I'm not actually sure what the
record for that is,
but I'm certain that it's higher than
2:38.
So when she's talking about a 500,
3000,
100 mile race,
there you go.
Relay race.
But marathon team look up six day are
world record.
Welcome to the 21st annual self
transcendence,
3,100
mile race.
You know why they said the self
transcendence?
Because after 2000 miles you run with
Jesus.
He's literally with you.
You transcend your running on air.
That's crazy.
Fifty two days.
They must log an average of 59 point six
miles a day.
That's fucking wait.
I think this is the one in New York.
It's just around like a city block in
New York or something.
The runners begin 6:00
AM and run for extended periods
throughout the day.
Taking breaks as needed.
If they want to,
they can continue as late as 12 midnight
when the course closes for the night.
Oh Wow.
Whew.
That's pretty cool.
Boy.
Now the community has got to be a very
strange community of like ironed willed
human beings.
Oh,
it's such a special community on imagine
like this.
The character of those people know
everyone's got a story and they're all
out there battling their own battle,
you know,
and it's cool to be at the finish line
then and celebrate together and God swap
war stories,
you know,
I'm sure.
I mean I just like to find other human
beings that are capable of putting their
mind and their body into that position
and want to do that,
like choose actively choose to do that
and look forward to it.
And look forward to the next one.
Pay Money to do it.
How much does it cost?
Uh,
for this one I maybe seven,
800 to win anything?
Nope.
Jesus Christ.
We've got to get you a prize.
She should have.
You should win something that alerts.
This is crazy.
Thinking about how much they win when
they fucking play golf.
Oh,
you're knocked a ball in the whole way
to go fatso.
That doesn't impress me at all.
What you do is like,
I just feel like it's massively
underrated in terms of society's
appreciation of it.
Yeah.
Well a lot of people don't even know
these are happening.
I'm like ultra marathons are a very
alien thing to a lot of people.
I wasn't aware of them so I became
friends with Cam.
I didn't know anybody.
Who was that crazy.
So what mileage are you running now?
I only run a couple run like three of
the most.
Everyone is like four.
I mean they have even half marathons on
trails.
That would be cool for you to just check
out.
Trail running is so awesome.
It is.
Well,
mostly what I'm doing is like super
steep hills.
That's where I like to do.
I do a lot of hill sprints.
Yeah,
put it's.
It's made a big difference in my martial
arts training.
I've been doing it for like six,
eight months maybe.
No,
January I think I started running so
it's more than that.
Incorporated with all sorts of other
changes just makes a huge difference in
my wind.
Like and I never used it.
I used to feel like my.
The thought like I guess it was just
laziness or just didn't want to try it,
but a lot of people's thought processes.
Well if you do cardio like specific to
your athletic event,
right?
Like if you do Jujitsu,
just do Jujitsu.
Just do a lot of rolling,
do a lot of sparring and your cardio
will go up.
Did you do kickboxing?
Just do a lot of kickboxing,
hit the bag a lot and your cardio go up.
It will,
but I maintain that just it was just
sheer cardio from running is a different
thing and that your capacity for cardio
is expanded.
Especially when you do hit a hill
running or sprints things.
So yeah,
I would think so.
Now if you,
do you do anything else other than
running?
Do you,
are you involved in any other athletics?
Ah,
right now,
no,
I played on some like adult coed
volleyball and soccer teams recently.
But um,
otherwise just running right now.
Do you have an illegal longterm goal or
is there anything that you'd like to
accomplish?
Um,
I don't know.
I just want to keep pushing the limits
and finding,
finding out what's possible,
going a little bit faster or a little
bit further.
Um,
and getting to see parts of the world is
what I'm hoping for in this next year.
How many other women when these things
there's been in the past couple of years
there has been,
um,
it's becoming a little more frequent to
have a female overall winner.
Yeah.
Because for a long time that wasn't the
case.
Right,
right.
But why do you think that is?
I'm not sure.
I don't know if I'm like the confidence
or the time women are putting in or like
just figuring out nutrition stuff.
I Dunno,
I dunno what's been the like thing that
switched it over,
but um,
it's not as absurd as it used to be for
sure.
Well,
what you do is absurd.
I mean that's absurd to not just win,
but the wind by such an enormous margin,
you know,
like what an inspiration you must be to
other young runners that are coming up
right now and just know that that's
possible,
that someone can,
can do that.
Yeah,
I mean,
I,
I hope to inspire future generations.
My niece like,
I mean,
that'd be cool.
I don't know if it's happening,
but okay.
This is 100 percent happy trying.
I have no desire to do it and you've
inspired me.
Oh,
thank you.
The,
you know,
the story of the four minute mile,
right?
Yeah.
That before,
who was the guy that Jesse Prefontaine?
No,
not good.
That guy is.
Who was it that broke the four minute
mile?
Was it like Alan,
I forget his name.
I was gonna say Jesse Owen,
but it's on him,
but whoever,
whoever the gentleman was,
it broke the four minute mile.
They used to literally think it was
physically impossible.
Bannister,
Roger Bannister,
thank you,
but once he broke it,
then a bunch of people broke afterwards.
Realized it could be possible,
you know,
which is another one of the reasons why
when someone says,
Oh,
if you run a marathon,
you have to take six months off.
Like shut the fuck up.
Nobody knows what people can do mean.
It's really true that there's.
There are boundaries to human
performance that have not been explored
yet.
I agree.
Absolutely.
Yeah,
so people like you,
you're like at the tip of the spear of
this shit.
You realize that you are,
you are.
I'm telling you,
you are like in,
in human history,
I don't think there's a whole lot of
people that can ever say that they've
run $238.
I bet there's maybe one or two other
people that have ever walked the face of
the earth that have done what you did.
Well,
they might not have ever.
I mean maybe there's some crazy
aborigine are some indigenous people
that we don't know about.
Someone who lives in Mexico,
in the mountains or something like that
has done something crazy like this,
but for the most part,
I mean,
how many people have ever done what you
did?
I think there are 95 finishers at the
rab to 40.
But how many people have done it in less
than 58 hours this year?
Just one.
But I think it'll keep falling.
That's my,
my thought process.
And do you think that there's anything
left?
Um,
do you think you left anything on the
table as far as like when you crossed
the line,
was there a thought like I could have
done that maybe like five minutes
faster?
Uh,
I mean,
sure,
yeah,
you can cut out time at aid stations.
You can do sections more efficiently.
So I,
my hope is there's always room for
improvement and if I went back next year
I would absolutely be trying to push the
pace and drop my time.
What would you try to get an under 50?
I don't know.
I think I'd just have to see how the day
was unfolding and I'm like,
what sort of obstacles were coming up?
If you did it under 50,
I guarantee you some people would just
throw themselves off the side of the
car.
Fuck this.
It'd be like me playing basketball
against Jordan and I'm like,
I can't do this anymore.
You know what I mean?
I don't know.
Seven.
That'd be almost eight hours cut off and
I don't think I can.
That'd be a lot.
Yeah,
but why?
Why not a person that came in second,
if you didn't exist,
that person who came in second would be
a bad motherfucker.
Look,
I just beat everybody's ass and this
crazy race.
He means so much.
He's a little bummed out right now.
He sit at home going fucking 10 hours.
I bet that guy gets a good night's sleep
and brushes his teeth and forgets about
it for a little while,
gets in his car and then he's in traffic
and the light turns red.
He was fucking 10 hours,
10 hours.
I guarantee you.
I hope you're not thinking that shot
show.
I.
You're thinking,
Sean.
I would be thinking to good news.
Beat me by 10 days.
Think of.
Think of it in terms of,
well it's,
it's,
you know,
you're the high watermark now I guess.
I mean,
I can't imagine there's any other way to
put it.
You won the first one,
but you want it by such a ridiculous
margin.
Yeah.
We'll see next year.
What people are capable of now.
Candice and her crazy idea for 500
miles.
Are you going to indulge her in this
ridiculous quest?
I mean,
yeah,
she threw it out there.
She had like immediately positive
response from everyone in this,
in this group of course.
But just fucking psycho.
I know.
Yeah.
And she was saying maybe 20,
19.
She'd be able to pull it together.
Oh,
why?
Why does she need that much time?
I mean the logistics involved and then
there's like permitting you have to do.
And where would you,
where would she have one of these
things?
She didn't say.
How about the surface of the sun or the
moon?
I'm like,
let's all go to the movies.
Easy.
It's cold.
Yeah.
None.
No gravity.
You'd be like cheating.
It's only like one sixth,
one,
sixth.
Earth's gravity.
Yeah.
I mean,
I just wonder like,
what is the limit?
Like what is the limit of a human in
terms of like mean?
You said that when it was over,
you were wrecked for days,
you couldn't sleep,
you really weren't eating well,
but when you cross that finish line and
if someone said,
okay,
the real
finish line is another 80 miles,
you just would've kept going.
Yeah.
If that's,
if that was real and I had 80 more miles
to cover,
I would figure out how to do it.
What have is 180?
How many,
how many more miles did you think you
have left in your body?
I mean there's,
there a point where you're,
you're just tissue would just give out
maybe.
Yeah.
Um,
but like for this 500 mile ratios
suggesting there's like a,
she's thinking a 10 day cutoff or
whatever.
Oh God.
So then you just got to build in some
good sleep.
And I'm sorry candice,
if we weren't supposed to talk about
this yet,
I don't know.
We're talking about it.
That's like that's 10 days is not.
Well,
I guess,
but no one's going to do that,
right?
You're just going to keep running.
No one's going to just go 50 miles a
day.
Right.
You could like,
you can build that into your plan.
Yeah.
But no one's going to do that.
I mean for this one,
people had sleep plans.
There's aid stations out there that had
like cots and blankets and you can stay.
They say for six hours,
they'll let you sleep there before they
boot you to the course.
Six hours,
six hours get up.
Lazy.
Yeah.
I don't know if they just want to keep
turning them over in case there's a need
for more or that makes sense.
So they wake you up at six hours.
Apparently I didn't have.
I don't have any personal experience
doing it off the car.
Just live right on the ground right now.
What?
I'm
not getting up right here.
It's over.
Yeah.
So I guess for this one they'd have to
have sleep stations out there and I mean
I see what I'm getting at is the
fascinating part of this to me is that
the boundaries are in least somewhat
unexplored because what you did was in a
way very revolutionary,
like what you did was like,
like you just,
you just flip the whole thing on its
head by coming in 10 hours and 20 plus
miles ahead of the second place person.
Like now people are going to go,
okay,
well what,
what's possible?
Because maybe there's someone out there
that can do that at Courtney.
Yeah,
absolutely.
There is like glue.
I haven't met them.
I'm really exists.
I don't know if that's the question.
That's the cool part is if people just
keep like wandering that then we'll be
breaking down all sorts of barriers.
That's what's fascinating about it to me
as a completely outside observer is that
what you're doing is you're essentially
an unexplored territory and even the
training protocols,
right?
Like your protocols different than cams
and I'm sure that Sean,
God's got a different thing that he did
and everybody's got their own little
methods and wasn't there a guy that was
leading for awhile but he had a,
he had a bail,
like 150 miles.
He couldn't take it anymore.
Yep.
So I was going back and forth for awhile
with a guy until maybe.
Yeah,
I think it was 150 miles.
What happened to him?
I'm not sure.
I think his legs or his quads or
something was given out.
I'm not positive.
I didn't get to have it.
Your conversation with him in,
does that happen often where someone
just comes out of the gate too hard or
maybe like he's trying to keep up with
you and he outpaced himself?
Yeah.
Unfortunately they're called dns or did
not finish.
Um,
and those happened pretty frequently.
What's the percentage if you had to
guess?
It was 100 plus people entered,
right?
Yeah.
I think this,
the 200,
the Moab race had way less than a
normal,
like hundred mile race.
For example.
We left dnfs way less people dropped
out.
Yeah.
Interesting.
I don't know if it's like the mindset
going in,
you just know it's this big adventure
and,
and you're going to be out there for
multiple days,
so you're ready for that versus a 100
mile race.
I mean people are breaking down barriers
with how fast those can be done.
Um,
and so then you're,
you're going out guns blazing from the
start and then you've got a higher
potential for a blow up that just can't
be fixed.
So is that what happens?
Like your,
your muscles just break down,
you get,
what is it called autolysis or something
like that.
Your muscles start eating themselves.
Yeah.
And just like no response.
You're getting nothing back from um.
Yeah.
And what is that thing that,
those crossfit people get robbed?
Doe myelocytic.
Oh yeah.
Do you ever get that?
I've never gotten it wrapped.
Rhabdo.
Rhabdomyolysis.
Yeah.
Something about like,
your muscles
are breaking down into your bloodstream
or.
Yeah,
that's not good.
It's supposed to be horrible and
apparently you like way more common
today than it muscle breakdown damages
the kidneys.
Apparently.
It's way more common today because of,
uh,
these crossfit classes and people push
themselves and push.
That's the thing is like,
it's not a matter of what's possible.
Like,
Hey,
courtney ran 248 miles.
I can run it to,
well,
yeah,
maybe,
but you're going to have to build up to
that stupid kids.
Just do it tomorrow.
You know?
That's kind of the crazy thing about all
this,
right?
Is that like you're,
you're building like a mountain one lego
block at a time.
Right.
And someone who's like,
oh,
well her mountains like 5,000
feet,
I'll just fucking build a footnote.
So it takes a long ass time to build
that mountain.
Right?
Yeah.
I mean for me,
I've been,
I've been training for this long stuff
for seven years now,
so I wasn't like instantly successful at
the hundred mile distance and it's taken
a lot of training and a lot of just
learning along the way
now because of the fact that you ran
this 238 mile race at a certain pace and
did so phenomenally.
Do you feel like your body is now going
to be stronger for the next one?
I hope so.
I hope if I treat it nicely for a little
bit here and let it fully recover,
um,
that then I can try and springboard off
of this for the next day.
Plenty Nachos.
Plenty of beer.
Yeah.
Just loaded in.
No.
Do you do any other kinds of training?
Do you do any weight lifting or yoga or
anything else you incorporate?
Anything else?
Yeah,
um,
I do.
I go to the gym mostly at the gym.
I do core work and like throw,
throw around a couple of five pound
dumbbells.
But otherwise,
no,
I think yoga would be a great thing to
incorporate.
I just haven't,
I haven't gotten the motivated to head
to those classes.
That's so funny.
How do you stretch a sometimes,
but wouldn't you think that that would
be a good thing to do?
I mean.
Oh absolutely.
Why don't you do it?
I mean I try.
Yeah.
It's just not like incorporated into my
normal routine.
Very well.
Do you think maybe like things along
those lines,
like maybe yoga or weightlifting or
stretching would maybe possibly advance
you to another level?
Yeah,
I mean I might as well try and see.
Yeah.
But that's what I'm thinking.
I'm like,
you're so far ahead now that I,
I would imagine it's a matter of like
what could possibly make you better like
your,
you're obviously trying to win by that
extreme.
A margin.
Like I would think obviously what you're
doing now is amazing.
Like what if it ain't broke,
don't fix it.
Right?
But are you your very best?
Um,
I hope not.
I'm going to keep trying to strive for
higher.
Just keep putting lego blocks up,
keep building.
I like that.
And I love Lego's.
Who Does it?
But it seems like it's a fairly good
analogy.
You know,
that it seems that it's a slow,
arduous process of improvement and it
takes discipline and constant focus and
constant attention and just time in.
Yeah.
And enjoying it too.
Like that's a huge part of it for me as
well as I'm loving it still.
So.
But do you think that's part of the
success as well,
the enthusiasm that you have?
I think it's gotTa be if,
if you're out there grinding everyday
for hours and you're just hating it,
I mean,
then you won't be jazzed to go to any
starting line.
Yeah.
Well that's
sort of what you were saying about the
water thing that if you're low on water,
like don't just,
don't let it freak you out to just deal
with it and it will be less like of that
really does apply to life,
doesn't it?
I think so,
yeah.
Yeah.
No matter if you run or not,
I think I'm just figuring out how to
deal with situations like that without
freaking out.
And having a record day is huge.
Now what about runner's high?
How high do you get when you run in like
that?
Is that real?
Yeah,
I get it.
I just get tired.
You get runner's high.
Sure.
Yeah.
I mean when you're out there like
cruising along some beautiful trails and
you're in an amazing place and um,
you feel really good and maybe you're
with people or maybe not.
It definitely can feel really awesome,
but people like sort of chased that
down.
Right.
There's some people that that is like
the only way they stay sane.
I think you got to go out and get their
medicine in that running.
Do you have like an end goal?
Like do you do,
do you look at like this running career
and go,
okay,
I'm going to get to be x amount of age,
I want to accomplish a certain amount of
things and then stop.
Or is it just life?
Yeah,
life is just life.
The cool part about this running stuff,
I mean you alluded to it earlier,
but people in their forties and fifties
and sixties,
they're doing these races and I'm still
enjoying the trails and I hope to.
I hope to still be doing it when in 20
years,
in 30 years,
my friend Ari,
his dad who was a holocaust survivor
who's 80 years old just ran a marathon
in six hours.
Fucking.
That's amazing
Doug.
I mean,
come on.
I can't run a marathon.
Six hours.
I know burt can't that fat.
Fuck sorry Brent.
I love you.
It's inside joke.
That's a total inside joke,
but his are.
His Dad is like,
how
does,
how does one do that?
How does it.
How is an 80 year old man run a marathon
in six hours?
That's insane.
That's cool.
Yeah.
Just grinding.
I mean,
what is the oldest competitor that you
guys had in that race?
I'm 69,
I think.
Wow.
How did they do?
He finished.
Yeah,
it's amazing.
Sixty nine years old and he runs 238.
I think he had something.
Uh,
he's 69 years old and it was like his
6,800
plus mile race he'd ever done or
something crazy like that.
At that age.
You're on borrowed time.
Why not just burn that candle with a
blowtorch?
Fuck the wick.
Just throw that candle in the fall.
Kaino.
Yeah.
Or maybe he's making more time.
He might be.
Couldn't be Rhonda.
Patrick.
Dr Rhonda Patrick,
who's this brilliant moment of added fat
on the podcast a few times,
posted something on twitter just a
couple of days ago that regular rigorous
physical exercise can expand,
lowers the biological age by as much as
nine years.
Wow.
Was it seems like you find that.
Yeah,
it's some crazy study they did on
extended.
Since any rigorous exercise
goes,
a physical exercise reduces cancer
incidence is lower than the rates of
recurrence inhibits tumor growth.
Uh,
no.
It's one that I retweeted.
It was here it is
intensity exercise,
delayed biological aging by nine years
as measured by telomere length.
So was just like scientific analysis of
your telomeres.
That's amazing.
So like what,
nine years every time you.
No,
no,
but I mean like people who are
rigorously exercising.
So you say if you,
you're 39,
your telomeres results showed that
regular activity accounted for
significantly longer.
Telomeres in US adults,
the longer telomeres found an act of
adults accounted for nine years of
reduced cellular aging.
Regular physical exercise activity
reduces disease risk possibly due to
the,
uh,
preservation of telomeres.
Wow.
So that's an interesting thing because
for the long telomeres are nucleo
protein caps positioned at the end of
chromosomes and agent causes telomeres
to shorten significantly and results in
gradual sell deterioration.
And that makes sense because you see
people that don't exercise and they get
older and they look like shit as opposed
to someone who does exercise and they'll
stand right next to them and you go,
whoa.
Does those two people the same age?
I.
that's crazy.
That's cool that they're studying that.
That will be interesting to see like how
that unfolds as they learn more.
It makes sense,
right?
You're requiring more of your body.
Your body has to maintain this much
higher work rate than the average
person.
Yeah.
That's cool.
How much sleep do you get a night?
A normal night.
Normal.
Probably seven or eight hours.
So just normal stuff.
Yeah.
Like you're not,
you're not doing anything crazy?
No.
Other than
the actual accomplishment physically.
Like you're not doing anything crazy
outside of it?
I don't think so.
Do you get massages?
No.
Really?
Do you wear those crazy pants?
What are those?
Uh,
those crazy pants.
It's Smush your legs.
And what are those things called?
Compression.
Those.
The Cam,
they send them to me and I sent them to
him.
Like compression tights or.
No,
no,
they,
they massage your legs.
You're like,
he put them both.
I'll have them send them to you.
They send them to me.
I didn't even ask for them.
And they like the big boots.
The other pants.
NORMATEC NORMATEC.
There's supposed to be the shit.
No.
Yeah,
pull up a video of the NORMATEC system.
They sent it to me and I,
I sent it to camp.
See if you find Cam's a instagram video
of him using it,
but you climb into that thing and it
massages your leg.
It says pulse,
leg recovery system.
People swear by these things that are.
Good question.
Doesn't show up.
Um,
but uh,
that could be cool if it wasn't even no
water.
Oh,
right.
Have you done cryotherapy?
Nope.
You want to do it today?
Please write down the street.
Well,
what does it,
what does that involve?
Exactly?
Involves 240 degrees below zero for
three minutes.
Oh Jeez.
Hey,
standing there.
It's awesome.
Come out.
You feel fantastic.
If you want to do it,
we could do it.
Areas.
Oh,
that's cool.
So that's him at a place doing it.
Looks like he has one at home now that I
sent them.
They sent me one.
I didn't even ask for.
I don't know how they got my address or
anything.
They just sent me a normatec.
I'm like,
okay.
I sat in my wife's like,
again,
I'll just send it to cam.
He'll use it.
So he uses it.
But you didn't,
did you try it?
No,
no,
no.
Sorry.
Athletes using it to like Lebron James
uses it.
Like after training it looks bad ass.
There's all these different methods of
recovery.
But court don't need shit.
Good pitches.
You guys keep using it.
Did,
uh,
when you were running the long,
the long digital like a certain playlist
over and over and over again.
Like do you hate certain songs now that
you're listened to him for 60 hours
straight or.
No.
Headphones and I use music occasionally.
I didn't use it for the entire thing.
I probably did a couple of hours with
music the first day and um,
maybe a couple hours of music the second
day just to like pat or ipod.
I mean someone,
Hey,
I need it back on board who are like,
I want to change it up a bit.
Cool,
cool.
Yeah.
So most of the time when you're
training,
do you use music or.
No?
I don't often use music.
Some days I will,
but especially out on trails.
I mean we just talked about all these
animals that can kill you that I'm not
using music.
Right.
If you don't hear the rattle that suck.
Or like the wings flapping behind your
head before you get a scalping.
Yeah.
Now did they test you guys for drugs?
Occasionally.
Some races have that.
This one did not.
So you can be jacked up to the gills.
How many people?
How many people you think were juiced up
to the gills and they still couldn't
beat you?
This one at this race,
no one was Jewish.
There's someone out there is one person
who's on epo for sure.
I won't believe it.
I believe it.
One person,
like none of that stuff is like
filtering into the trail running scene.
I mean there was a $0 prize on the line,
so I understand that.
Why is someone going to epo for that?
I know what you're saying and it's very
logical.
You're right.
But there was actually a,
an article that was written about a
silicon valley ceos that were taking epo
and doing triathlons and a marathon
races and they were taking these
endurance drugs.
He's a performance enhancing drugs just
for.
I mean just to try to up their
performance in these amateur events that
it's a big thing that it's a very common
thing lately.
Interesting.
Yeah,
I would.
I mean,
I don't even know where the fuck they
get it.
Yeah.
I don't know what all that would
involve,
but um,
I like to think better of the,
of the trail running community and that
people are pushing just their natural
limits without,
without seeing what the,
what,
any sort of drug reps.
I would like to think better of them
too.
But I just,
I'm because of the UFC have seen so many
people.
Oh,
I've got a drug test that I didn't think
I was like,
that guy.
Wow.
Huh?
I just think take Abbott fail.
No habits.
All beer.
He wasn't my guy.
He's your guy.
He's an animal,
he's a,
he was an anywhere,
anytime guy,
he'd fight anybody.
He would hop off a bar stool and beat
the shit out of people we used to rent
like for,
for uh,
the videos from blockbuster.
It does it before I was involved.
Those were awesome.
No,
no.
Uh,
I gougey no fish hooking,
but there was probably definitely dudes
that were on steroids.
I mean,
I don't know if he ever took anything,
but there's a lot of people that have
worked,
things like that.
Then you can take whatever you wanted
and there was no drug testing,
right?
The early days.
But you know,
like it's,
it's like how much does that help and
how much,
how much is,
especially when it comes to trail
running,
like what you're doing is first of all,
you're living at elevation,
which is phenomenal,
right?
Then you're also just constantly putting
in the work and grinding and it's a full
time job now and you're obviously a
special athlete when it comes to your
ability to focus and you went fucking
blind lady.
He lived.
Why you kept running,
you know,
so there's no drugs out there that can
fix that.
There's no,
there's no,
there's nothing that's going to give you
that kind of mental fortitude to push
past blindness.
Right.
And they're getting better about.
I mean,
more and more trail races are starting
to implement a drug testing just to try
and like,
I'm cut it out before it even becomes a
thing
that's smart.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Weed out all the performance enhancing
stuff,
but you know,
there's going to be,
there's a line,
right?
Like what,
what are you test for and what don't you
test for?
Like what's,
what's okay,
you know,
multivitamins or okay,
alright,
what about,
you know,
there's some weird stuff that people
take,
you know,
some really good stuff from GNC,
we're having issues with that in the UFC
were guys take just over the counter
stuff at GNC and it turns out it
actually,
uh,
steroids in it.
Yeah.
Apparently it's super common that these,
you know,
all these muscle building,
this and rail stack that,
you know,
a lot of that stuff is they,
they literally put performance enhancing
drugs in them,
which is why they work.
So then it's just your job as an athlete
to know what's on the ingredient list
and is it okay?
Yeah.
You saw it actually has a list of things
that have tested positive for steroids
and it is crazy.
I had Jeff Novitsky on who was the head
of Usada and now works for the UFC.
He's a drug enforcement program and
trying to catch people cheating and we
pulled up the Usada website and your jaw
drops,
like what supplements you're buying from
just a regular mom and pop vitamin
store.
Just crazy steroids in them.
Then you,
but you just take a multivitamin.
That's it.
Yeah.
Just a women's multivitamin or a women's
multivitamin.
Is there a difference now?
I don't know.
It's probably a marketing scheme
probably.
Right.
And do you think that there's anything
that you could take that would possibly
enhance your performance in any way?
I mean,
is there that's legal?
Yeah,
I mean is there,
what is something that other runners
rely on?
Is there something that like you hear
people talk about like vitamins or
supplements or anything?
No,
I think more the conversation is always
about the diets and like changing up
what you eat or what you,
what food groups you live in and all of
that is more what I hear talk about and
I'm just not interested in cutting out
carbs or cutting out fat.
Like I want it all.
So yeah,
that's one of the guys that ran.
He ran a hundred miles.
What does this gentleman's name?
He's actually emailed me.
He ran 100 miles faster than anybody
ever.
And he's on some fat burning diet.
He's on one of those.
That Quito.
Yeah,
he's on a ketogenic diet and his whole,
his name Zack bitter.
Yeah.
You know who that guy is?
Yeah,
he is.
Uh,
he,
he won.
There it is.
Yeah.
He eats almost no carbs.
Carbs are my favorite.
Well,
you brought up something to that I think
is really important.
That really neat.
Can't be stressed enough is that
everybody's body is different.
It really is.
He ran a hundred miles in 11 hours.
Forty minutes and 55 seconds.
What a monster.
Yeah,
that's on a quarter mile track.
Six and a half marathons.
That is insane.
Four hundred and two laps on a track.
Jesus Christ.
That's awesome.
Yeah.
He's a really great athlete.
That's a,
that's a monster.
That's insane.
What's incredible that he could do this
with almost no carbs.
Fat,
right.
You're just not interested in trying
that?
No,
I mean,
I don't,
I don't see a need for it.
I should,
yeah.
I want to.
Um.
I'm not saying they aren't enjoying
life,
but the things that I enjoy involve,
just not worrying about it.
Yeah.
Like do you regulate your sugar intake
at all?
Know if you've run as much as you run,
you don't have to think about your diet
at all.
Right?
I don't.
I mean maybe that could be one of the,
the lego pieces that I try and find
tune,
but it's not on my to do list for the
near future.
Yeah,
I mean,
again,
it's like if it ain't broke,
don't fix it.
What if someone like comes creeping up,
like real close to your courtney,
someone starting to like your,
you're finishing and they're finished
and like a couple minutes behind you and
you go like,
well,
I might need to kick in the
afterburners.
Is that when you would go to a
nutritionist or to tighten up your diet?
Yeah,
I mean there's plenty of people who beat
me and I,
I'm,
I'm just trying to work harder,
like train more,
train better,
get stronger.
Especially like those core muscles and
like what kind of exercise do you do for
your core?
Just like the normal planks and things
of that nature and uh,
yeah,
it doesn't,
that doesn't motivate me to change my
diet.
People beating me.
No,
it would take more than that.
It just is like,
okay,
you need to train harder,
you need to like put in more work for
this.
But don't you think that the fuel that
you use in your body,
obviously me giving you any advice is
fucking ridiculous.
But don't you think that the fuel that
goes into your body has some sort of an
effect on your performance?
I mean,
it must surely
Shirley,
but I also just want to live life and
enjoy it,
you know,
like I don't want to be counting how
many Kale
he says I'm eating.
Well,
that's a good attitude.
I mean,
obviously your enthusiasm is a huge part
of your success and your mental state.
I think it can,
it can be argued at all that that's not
a huge part of your success is.
And just to keep enjoying your life in
living the way you're living perhaps
fuels that mental state.
Yeah,
I mean the,
I'm thinking they're all intertwined,
but who knows,
you know,
what thing could be tweaked to make it
better?
Well,
I don't know,
you know,
I mean,
it's all that,
uh,
the Jack Nicholson in the shining,
you know,
too much work.
No play makes jack a dull boy,
right?
Yeah.
Is it John or Jack?
Who is he in the movie was jacked to
Johnny.
Johnny adult boy,
right?
Yeah.
Here's Johnny.
That's right.
Yeah.
I mean,
I wonder if like maybe the,
just the ultimate grind of discipline
and no reward is just not.
It's not beneficial to performance that
there's some sort of a balance that must
be achieved,
enjoying yourself and being enthusiastic
and appreciative and also disciplined.
I think a good balance of all that is
important.
We'll listen.
Courtney,
thank you so much for being here.
You are an inspiration and I'm so blown
away by what you've managed to do and I
can't wait to see what you can do in the
future and if you really can run 500
miles,
if you do 500 miles,
you gotta come back in here.
We got to talk it out on the course with
the foam finger.
I'll wear whatever you want.
Chicken outfit like those dudes are so
real estate.
Whatever you need.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
And everybody tell people
get ahold of you on twitter.
It's different than instagram.
Instagram is courtney dot Walter.
Instagram is coordinated.
You alter.
Twitter is court do alter and d a u w a
l t e r m,
whoever's got courtney.
Doe,
Walter on twitter.
Give it up,
bitch.
Come on.
That's ridiculous.
Give it to her because they got it
right.
Right after you won.
Right.
That's when they did it.
Some weird series of events led to a
twitter being made and they say they
were going to give it to you.
They said they were going to give it to.
Okay.
Make that happen.
Thank you so much.
Coordination,
but also.