Bom Bom four,
three,
two,
one.
Ben Greenfield eats ants.
Just want everybody to know,
hey,
if I was going to go to Disney as much
as you go to Disney,
I'd eat a lot more black ants.
Why are you eating it?
Supposedly I actually don't know that
much about dance.
I'm just,
I'm just eating it because it supposedly
gives you energy.
I need to pick me up this morning.
We lifted the waste this morning and I
needed a second boost of energy.
But apparently these ants live in
Ginseng roots and they have something
that grows in their heads that acts as
like a nootropic.
It's like some kind of a chemical
nootropic and it also supposedly is one
of these Chinese energy tonics.
It's like the whole,
you know,
the doctrine of signatures,
the doctrine of signatures.
Now it's the idea that that things in
nature give you clues,
right?
So,
so like when you slice open a tomato,
you've got the four chambers of the
heart and tomato,
supposedly good for the hearts or
pomegranate is good for your blood.
And the little pomegranate seeds look
like red blood cells.
You slice open a carrot that looks like
an eye or you,
you crack open an egg,
it looks like an eye.
Those are,
those are good for your vision.
Um,
sweet potatoes,
which everybody thinks is like at like a
sweet,
sugary food,
those are actually shaped like a
pancreas and they can actually help to
normalize your,
your Beta cells,
like your,
your insulin producing Beta cells in
your pancreas.
So you're looking at walnuts for your
brain and people talk about a Aba
Cahtos,
right?
Supposedly they look a little bit like
an ovary and they're good for female
reproductive function.
So you can,
you can carry that over from the plant
kingdom into the animal kingdom and say
that if you eat ants because they're
such energetic endurance driven
creatures that it supposedly will make
you stronger.
Boys,
that's a stretch.
Oh wait til this stuff hits me in the
arm.
Wrestle.
Find that.
Have you been doing it for awhile?
How long have you been taking this
stuff?
That was the third time I've,
I've actually used it.
You just send dissolve.
I mean,
I use it for workout a couple of times.
So this is your concoction,
right?
You took ground but ants.
I didn't grind up the answer myself.
That would have been exhausting to catch
you by the up.
I bought ground up black ant powder and
just pulled up some Ginseng.
Yes,
I don't think they're called.
That's actually,
that's where I bought them.
So that's where I bought them.
Last part,
Paulie.
Righteous ants.
A Qi tonic of Chinese herbalism.
But you know what?
The Chinese people are also into the
Rhino Horn.
It's not just a pre workout or according
to the website.
It's a pre workout.
Super Herbs,
a super supposedly far more
scientifically super regular food.
Right.
It's like a super food.
Exactly.
I'm a little annoyed with that word.
Super.
I,
I like that idea though,
of the doctrine of signatures.
Rarer like certain things that I see in
nature being good for you.
There's,
there's one called,
um,
I forget the,
uh,
the name of this plant,
but it's called the insulin of the heart
and it's amazing for decreasing
sympathetic nervous system activation
and causing you to relax and it has
these beneficial cardiovascular
properties and people who are just so
driven that they tend to have,
for example,
you know,
a heart attack or an emi and it's uh,
it's not split.
Lance thies,
I forget the name of this but it,
but it looks like a heart and it has all
these red vessels that kind of come off
it.
It's called the insulin of the heart.
Um,
there's,
there's an APP that my kids and I used
to identify a lot of these.
It's called flower checker.
So you read about this and stuff online
and then you started taking it and then
you mix it in some sort of a tincture
here.
Just vodka.
Yeah.
Urbane that stuff nature.
But forgotten remedy for heart disease
bay.
And I interviewed a physician on my
show,
Dr Thomas Cowan,
and he wrote a book about how the heart
is not a pump and he talks about the
true reason for heart disease,
being sympathetic nervous system
overdrive,
what?
What does he mean by the hardest,
not a pump mineral depletion and
dehydration and what he means by the
heart is not a pump.
It's a fascinating book.
The shape of the chest is a,
I believe it's called like a tetrahedron
or some something like that,
but basically as fluid moves through the
heart,
the action of the fluid actually moving
through the heart allows it to pass
through the heart and not have to be
pumped through the body,
but rather the shape of the heart is
almost like causing the fluid to move in
a vortex.
And so most certainly out of the oh the
heart,
the heart contracts,
but,
but it's less of a pumping action and
more of like a,
like a vortex flow that it creates.
A book's called why your heart is not a
pump.
It's very interesting.
Is it why well received amongst
scientists.
It kind of flies under the radar a
little bit.
Yeah.
Yeah,
but it's.
It's an interesting book.
Short book.
It's like maybe pages loan universally
regarded as a pump.
Yeah.
I don't know if,
if you would necessarily classify it as
a pump as much as a contracting muscle
that boom,
boom,
but when you die and then they bring you
back to life,
they push your heart to make it pump.
Pump,
pump,
pump seems good.
Yeah.
So I don't know.
Shit and read the book.
It's interesting.
It's interesting,
but this,
this,
uh,
this flower checker app is flower
checker APP.
It's really cool.
You,
you take a picture of a plant and then
there's a team of live botanists on the
other end and within 24 hours they
identify the plant for you and you can
learn it's edible properties.
It's medicinal property.
So my kids and I can walk around and
take pictures of different plants,
different flowers,
different things on our land,
and it develops this online or Barium
that then allows you to keep track of
all the different plants and what you've
learned about them and what they're good
for.
So we use that whenever we're
identifying plants.
There was one time when we were fishing
off the,
uh,
the north fork of the clearwater.
So we went on this fly trip and we're
starting
this water,
the clearwater up in Idaho.
So we were near a Grangeville.
Most people fly into Grangeville,
Idaho.
It's a great fly fishing,
huge steelhead.
And uh,
the,
the hike that we went on,
we didn't have our phones or anything
with us to take pictures of,
of what we were finding.
And we found this,
this enormous,
uh,
almost like a,
like a field of wild asparagus,
which,
and my buddy who was with us,
he had bear broth that he was,
that he was,
it was like a bare bone broth that he
had in this vat back at the cabin.
So we harvested all this asparagus and
this was before it went out fishing and
I put all the asparagus into the bone
broth and then just left for the day.
And then we came back and we had,
we had fish,
we had bone broth,
we had asparagus and we all ate this
bone broth and it turns out that this
stuff was not asparagus.
So my kids in our heads were spinning
all night.
The guy that owned the cabin,
apparently he didn't sleep,
he was just like hunched over the toilet
the whole evening and it turns out this
stuff is cold.
I think it was Brassica,
it looks like Asparagus,
but apparently it has very high levels
of nicotine.
So we were all career dosed on nicotine
for the next two days on this fishing
trip to be really careful.
That's the only time I haven't used that
APP to actually go,
go plant food chain.
Who thought it was asparagus?
We all thought it was asparagus,
you know,
it was me,
one of the chefs who is out of the cabin
with us,
uh,
my kids and,
and twin nine year old boys know a lot
about plants,
so we always trumps the wild asparagus.
But I was convinced it was asparagus.
I mean I,
I kind of tasted it out there where we
were.
We were out in the field and it tasted
like asparagus,
but no,
it's not asparagus.
It's Brassica Jesus Christ.
That sounds horrible.
Yeah.
But there's another app called plantsnap
and apparently uses artificial
intelligence,
you know,
like a reverse google image search to
identify a plant.
I've used that and it's,
it's useless.
Anything you take a picture of it,
it doesn't seem to be able to identify
anything but this flower Checker,
it's just live people on the other end
does google,
there's a google image search is like
some,
there's an application that use cameras
and if you take a photo of something can
identify exactly.
I think that's called like a reverse
google image search or something like
that.
But,
but the ai doesn't seem to work as well
for plant identification and I would
imagine it's looking at the leaves,
the shape of the leaves,
how it comes up,
plan,
you know,
the veins,
the opposite versus symmetrical and
everything that goes into a plant
identification.
But now when you,
you still rather go with a real person.
Still had.
Yeah.
You got to go with a real person.
You got to go with an actual botanist.
Steelhead are a ocean bound,
a rainbow trout,
right.
They come forth.
Yeah.
Um,
do you guys do catch and release or do
you eat them?
This was all catch and release though.
There is a common thing with those.
There's a certain kind that you can
catch.
And I,
I'm not a fly fishing expert.
This is like a fun trip with my kids to
learn how to fly fish and we didn't
catch any of that.
We could actually keep.
Yeah.
I don't understand that kind
of fishing.
It's weird,
you know that take a long trip,
go out into the wilderness,
go to the river,
catch fish,
let it go.
Yeah.
Seems it's,
it's the thrill of the chase.
I get it.
It feels great for kids.
Yeah.
I've done it with kids,
bass fishing before,
but it's just a can't do that.
When you bow hunt?
Nope.
Nope,
no catch and release.
Weird thing.
You're sticking a hook and a fish's
mouth and then letting it go.
Yeah,
got them.
Let's let them go.
They're hard to reel and less like a 10
minute fight.
Efficient and they're big.
Yeah.
There's powerful fish to the ocean
currents.
Ocean fish are almost always more strong
when you pull them in a freshwater fish,
other.
They're very strong.
They're stronger than ants,
I would imagine.
Yeah.
Spiel back to the animals.
Go back to this amp thing and,
and tell me what has been the reaction,
like when you take it,
how you feel.
It's more just like a cup of coffee.
You really did feel like you do.
You do feel more energy.
Do you think it's because of the Ginseng
or is it possible to see both fact and
they just live within the gen sing and
that makes the story sexier for the
website that sells.
So you think just eating the ants
themselves,
give you an entry.
I would imagine that you'd have to catch
a lot of ants to get what you'd get out
of like all the powdered extract that
they sell you.
Right.
But I mean eating the powdered extract
then just that somehow or another.
What's the mechanism for giving you
energy?
Uh,
there's some chemical that's in the ants
hot.
I don't know the mechanism of action
again,
I like,
hi,
I really don't claim to be an expert in
index extract,
but yet you got a bottle of tribe.
I have a bottle of.
It was,
it was in with all my other supplements
and uh,
I was packing up this morning and
thought it would be an interesting one.
It is interesting to show to you just a
giant bottle that says aunt on it.
What is the,
what's the standard way that people take
it to the cloud or as a tincture?
Yeah,
I would imagine you could probably put
it in a smoothie,
you know,
with your,
with your bee pollen and other insect
derivatives.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
But yeah,
what a weird one,
Huh?
Yeah.
Anyways.
Oh,
you should've come out and done the
spartan.
I knew you were Disney.
Yeah,
I told you I couldn't go.
So I said I should cook Spartan.
Spartan's a sport.
Ends a little bit more interested in
business in my opinion.
I didn't go to Disney for myself.
Yeah,
yeah they have.
They have kids you'd like to,
but you were doing commentary or
something?
Is that what you're doing?
I was doing the uh,
they,
they have commentary all day long with
these spartan race.
So I was doing the commentary and then I
raced the next day.
Oh,
so you did it one day competition one
day.
So it was a two day race thing.
It would,
they do the way they do it,
they get like tens probably I would say
some of these races,
eight to 12,000
athletes that in that approximate range.
So they break it up,
they go out,
they break it up,
there's long races,
they're short races.
So the long race was 13,
about 13 miles,
which on the road half marathon,
that'd be like a 105 that an athlete
would do on a,
on a race like that.
And so with the obstacles and the hills
and it's not a big bear,
which is a ski,
which I just found out from my wife
apparently used fake snow.
There's like a pond at the top of the,
at the top of the resort that they make
all the snow with apparently snow,
but it's artificially created.
Right.
It's like you make with the snow
machines artificially created real snow
made from water at the top of the
mountain in the snow machine.
It's not.
Yeah,
it's,
it's not.
It's not foam.
I wonder if anybody's trying to do that
to make foam snow.
Yeah.
And it makes some snow.
Asked him at the mall in Dubai.
They've got some,
they've got something over there.
I don't know if that's a snow machine.
Right.
It probably is actual Snow Dragon Mall
in Dubai.
They have like a crazy hill.
Right.
And it gets,
you know,
they have an actual indoor skew.
They've penguins and indoor ski resort,
everything.
Yeah.
So this race though,
for those same 13 miles,
it's like two hours and I think the
winter did a to 16 to 17,
something like that.
So it's.
So you have to jump over a lot slower.
You gotta carry,
carry sandbags and carry big gravel
buckets.
It's like doing yard chores and then
running to the next chore,
Barbwire Crawling and Hoisting ropes.
But it's good for full body fitness
because I used to do triathlon when I
did triathlon it was weak,
right?
Because you swim,
you bike,
you run.
And I had an engine that could go for
days,
but I did my first spartan race.
I couldn't climb a rope and I couldn't
carry sandbag up a hill.
So I think it's good for functional
fitness.
Here it is right here at.
Tammy's.
Got a video out there that's a,
that's a stadium.
That's actually a good way to start
inside of the stadium.
Dodger's stadium a couple of years and.
And you know,
you don't have to get muddy and there's
no fake snow and the stadium races can
selfies.
I don't know how it can be kind of a
joke because some people will go out and
uniforms with big cowboy hats on and you
know,
dressed up as spiderman in their Lycra
and then some people they have these
elite waves where it's actual,
you know,
legit athletes doing this kind of
interesting though.
But it is,
you know,
you can see you move your body in a lot
of different ways on these courses.
So it's fun.
You know,
it's fun to train for it because you got
to train all your different body parts
and you train for power and strength and
there's endurance.
So it's a good mix of everything.
I didn't know they're doing them in
stadiums.
That's kind of cool.
The stadium races are cool because you
show up at a t and t stadium,
we're running a race and you go up and
down and they will turn a stadium into
like a three to four mile event.
I mean,
that's how many times you go up and down
the stairs and they have an event for
the kids where the kids will go up and
down the stairs and the kids have
miniature sandbags and miniature spears.
So it actually is kind of a cool then
that's pretty bad ass that looked family
except for his fucking selfie stick.
Like everything must be documented.
You cannot live in this life without
people knowing exactly what you're doing
at all times.
Running a selfie stick.
I'm taking my kids to one of those,
uh,
those trained hunt competitions this
weekend.
Oh yeah,
in bonners ferry.
So they're going to do their first
actual kids and same thing,
it's the kids' events where the kid
shoot,
they've got 15 to 20 yard shots and then
they have like a sandbag lift and a run
and then they've got another shot and
then they've got burpees up and over
cooler and another shot.
And there's a,
there's a grownup event and a kid's
event.
Those things are fun too.
And that's,
those are really interesting.
The idea behind them is kind of cool too
because it lets people know what like if
you're,
if you're involved in one of those back
country backpack hunts,
it's,
it's very much a physical event,
like pretty much you're carrying most
likely at least 35 to 45 pounds on your
back,
especially if you're carrying your camp
on your back and then you're hiking,
you know,
thousands of feet of elevation.
You're up and down,
climbing over logs and shit.
You're carrying your bow.
There's a lot of physical exertion
involve like there will.
There's a lot of crawling,
a lot of crawling.
Yeah.
I mean you did that.
Hawaii hunt hunt,
Lanai Lanaya.
I hunted Kona,
uh,
I guess it was like five weeks ago.
And on the sheep hunt because the sheep
stale and the in the open plains you'll
crawl sometimes for an hour and a half
to two to get close enough for a shot.
Yeah.
The final day when I killed,
I killed two axis buck out there and the
final day we crawled for at least an
hour,
at least an hour,
like super fucking slow.
Those things are switched on.
It's frustrating to with with an enema
or sheep.
Sheep are not stupid.
They're smart.
No,
they're not as fast as an access,
but that's the most frustrating part is,
is you'll put on a crawl,
right?
Maybe you're 200 yards out and you spend
an hour getting 60 and then the wind
swirls.
Yeah.
They pick you up and they're off and
that has to stand up and brush yourself
off and you got to go crawl again.
Yeah.
But you know,
if it was easy wouldn't hunting.
Yeah,
just be killing.
I got one of those jungle scrub cows.
I told you how you were telling me about
that.
So these to explain to people what a
scrub bull is because apparently they're
just.
There's feral cows and bulls and cows.
I shot a cow and I thought at first that
it was going to be kind of a stupid
hunch and the cow because it,
you know,
the,
the pigs are pigs that they eat really
well because they feed on macadamia
nuts.
They're a lot better than the pigs in
Texas and they taste amazing.
Now you're Damien.
We did it,
we did it,
yeah.
Was very fatty and it's like,
like a nutty meat.
So we did a Cinco de Mayo cookoff,
me and my kids and we took the ribs
from,
from this pig.
Then I shipped back so you know,
it costs 150 bucks to ship 250 pounds of
meat back from Kona.
So had sheep,
pig and cow and shipped it all back,
which is not that expensive.
And the pig was,
I mean,
it,
it ain't better than any pork I've ever
had in my life.
These ribs.
And we blended them up and my kids made
it,
made an adobo sauce with the peppers and
they have a little food podcast.
So we,
we did all this for their food podcast.
But oh my goodness.
It's like the fattiest but,
but like a nutty,
flavorful fat [inaudible] because they
feed on these macadamia nuts,
you know,
there's no grain,
there's no corn and they're just wild
and running around out there.
So the pig was really good,
but the cow was tough.
It was,
it was a,
it was a tough cow.
I went on the first day we were out
there,
I took the back strap and I soak that in
lemon juice all day and in that kind of
broke it down a little bit and it wasn't
that bad.
But what I do when I got home was I've
got a refrigerator in my garage and I
hooked up a temperature controller to it
and get this temperature controller.
It's called a four one nine,
you know,
keep the temperature of the refrigerator
about 34 to 38 degrees.
So rather than plugging the
refrigerator,
the wall,
you plugged into this,
this temp control unit and then you put
a humidifier in and a fan like on the,
on the bottom of the fridge and then you
take all your meat and you lay it out on
grates in the refrigerator.
And I left it in there for about three
weeks to scrub cow and it develops this
hard gristly coating on the outside of,
of the,
of the meat.
And then I took it out and just sliced
all of this hard gristly part off of the
outside.
And the inside of that meat was like
butter to dry aging and essentially
that's it.
That's exactly what it is.
It's a dry age and refrigerator,
but you control the,
the temperature,
you want about 34 to 38 degrees and then
the humidity can vary a lot more than
that.
But I kept the humidity at about 60 to
70 degrees.
And then basically you just slice off
all that hard gristly external coding
and you've got this amazing super soft
super tender.
And then I just have this,
uh,
this vacuum packer and it's a cool
little unit.
You can just cut a bag any size you
want,
right?
For a neck or a shoulder,
like a smaller bag for a backstrap or a
tenderloin and a bagged it up.
Yeah.
I have one of those vacuum sealer.
So those things are awesome.
Yeah.
So the dry aging was key.
I have friends that have one of those
walk in coolers and they could set it to
a certain temperature and they hang the
meat and dry aged out there.
But I don't know what walk in cooler
they have because I looked into the dry
aging refrigerators and those are like
$5,000.
But you can get a refrigerator off
Craig's list that a four.
One thing I bought that was like 50
bucks I'll think is it on the
refrigerator?
Just a normal size refrigerator.
And so and so the food is on grates
inside the refrigerator.
So it took all the shelving out of the
refrigerator and I just put some plywood
on,
on either side of the refrigerator and I
put these metal.
Great.
So,
so you constructed your own sort of
exact and then just laid the meat down
on the grates and put the fan on the
bottom of the refrigerator.
So it's constantly circulating air
inside the refrigerator.
And then the temperature controller has
this,
uh,
it'll display.
So in my kitchen,
in my house,
it'll display the temperature and the
humidity.
So I know if something goes wrong.
So not all that meat spoils inside the
refrigerator.
Cause I'll see when I'm inside my
kitchen it'll read that,
that the temperature is getting too
high.
And the refrigerator,
maybe somebody unplug the fridge or the
controller,
you know,
needed to be reset,
which happened a couple of times,
but if you want to keep an eye on it,
yeah,
that's a great way though to take meat
and make it far more flavorful.
More tender.
Well,
especially that kind of meat.
I mean,
that's tough anyways.
It's tough.
Gamey.
Yeah.
These,
um,
water buffaloes,
like you see the one behind me,
a buddy of mine shot one of those in
Australia and he said that he had a
campaigns.
He had a piece of it in his mouth and
who's chewing one piece for a half an
hour.
That's how tough it is.
And this was the backstrap,
which was one of the more tender parts
of the body.
There's this idea of animals that's good
for.
It's good for your jaw.
It's good for your teeth structure.
Like there was this guy,
I think it's maximum mew.
My brother sent me this,
this youtube video of this guy,
but his,
his whole idea is that that humans,
jaw structure,
our bone density or teeth or trigeminal
nerves,
all of that don't work as well as they
should because we grow up on soft food.
We don't have to chew food.
It makes sense.
A lot of boxers to like big chunks of
Bazooka,
bubblegum.
It gets kind of hard after awhile.
Exactly.
Dig into it and develops muscular
endurance or your jaw Mazda.
Um,
uh,
I've seen machines rather where you take
like a leather strap in your mouth and
you're hanging a piece of weight from it
and you're,
you're doing this.
I,
yeah.
People were selling those for awhile as
a way to decrease rating of perceived
exertion during exercise,
exercise mouthpieces and that.
The advertising on them was that the
vikings used to chew on leather before
they go into battle to reduce pain and
increase their time to exhaustion.
And so they actually sell these
mouthpieces that you bite down on when
you're exercising,
but they were designed to strengthen the
jaw as much as to reduce how hard you
felt like you were working during
exercise.
And some people swear by these
exercises,
mouthpieces.
Well,
I know that the mouthpieces supposedly
can maximize the amount of effort that
you can put forth.
Like there's a difference in the amount
of strength you tightened down.
It's almost like when you shake
somebody's hand and make a fist with one
hand than you shake their hand,
you're,
you're stronger.
You know?
And that's,
that's something that puzzles that.
Celine talks about his books.
You know,
about how to generate as much force as
possible for as low as one fist.
You know,
even if you're going to do like a
bottoms up kettle bell press,
right,
you can do it with one hand open and
press and you close your hand and
contract this fist and it's,
it's far easier.
So what is the idea behind that?
At some highlights energizes your entire
body.
It's Fascia,
you know,
the,
your,
your Fascia covers,
your entire body should be tightened up,
one part of it.
It causes you to be able to produce more
for.
So let me try some time with a
Kettlebell or water bottle or a coffee
cup.
I flex my hand outward when I'm doing
like bottoms up kettle bell.
You Flex your hand?
Yeah,
I definitely flex my hand.
I'd never just like let it sit.
You know,
there's always,
there's always some tension.
It's,
it's,
it's full body tension,
you know,
so it's the same reason that you'll see
a lot of tennis players or I think
boxers do this to a Valsalva maneuver
when you strike.
So you hold your breath and go right.
Understand that same thing.
It tightens up everything and allows you
to produce more force.
Um,
the uh,
the other gum,
you mentioned the bazooka,
there's a gum called mastic gum and I
interviewed this guy,
Dean Karnazes,
who run the.
He did the 50 marathons in 50 days and
he,
he ran the,
the traditional marathon in Greece,
which is apparently not 26 point two
miles.
It's like 100 and some miles that he ran
and he would chew this mastic gum,
which they do use for jaw strengthen,
but it makes you produce more saliva to
so.
So when you're running,
you know,
you can get dry mouth when you're
running and in a lot of times you get,
you know,
be thinking about food you want to eat.
This mastic gum apparently keeps your
appetite satiated and allows you to
produce saliva.
And I bought some and it's to that shit.
It's A.
I think I got it on mastic gum.
Amazon of mastic gum.
Yeah,
that's what it looks like.
Little rocks in.
The interesting thing is,
is you can take it out after you're done
chewing it and then just like the next
day,
put it back in your mouth and keep
going.
You can chew that stuff for days.
It's like a,
like an everlasting gobstopper tastes
like it tastes like ass.
It's not that it's not that good,
but if you have this,
uh,
there's this h pylori issue.
It's supposedly very good for that.
Yeah.
Look that one they added,
they added licorice,
annecy and the fennel.
So it tastes even shittier.
Yeah,
but,
but it's supposedly,
you know,
this idea that we,
we grow up on soft food and babies eat,
eat soft food.
Yeah.
You wouldn't want the capsule that
would.
I mean the capsule would be good for
your.
That's where you got to be careful.
There's a lot of companies sell it as a
capsule.
Right.
Is mastic gum as a capsule but gum that
you chew on,
that's the exact one I have that kronos
said there's nasty trumped.
Yeah.
And that's,
that's the stuff that you actually
choose to make your jaw stronger and to
produce extra saliva.
Huh.
And do you use this stuff when you work
out or you just occasionally chewing?
No,
I don't like to have gum in my mouth.
So many different things going on in so
many different modalities of you're
experimenting with.
There's no way you can do is I try stuff
and I write about it.
It's not like,
it's not like I'm doing mastic,
gum and black powder and injections all
day long and it works.
I would think you would keep doing it
all the time,
but it's just like you forget about a
lot of stuff though.
You try out so many things.
You forget about it.
Like,
Oh yeah,
I tried that out a while ago.
It was pretty good.
I need to order some more of that.
So yeah,
you start to lose track of all the.
All the stuff I try,
I don't have it all systematized.
Some big excel spreadsheet.
What are you doing with the exomes?
Explain that because I just got some
shot into some tears that I have on my
shoulders.
You got it.
It's,
it's exosomes.
Exosomes.
They're signaling molecules so your body
actually has them.
Your,
your cells have exosomes and they're
used as cell to cell communicators.
So they interact with cell surface
receptors and they'll actually carry a
message from one cell to another such
as,
you know,
uh,
you need to,
you need to absorb this into the cell.
You need to carry this to a joint or
whatever you'd want to use an exome for
to carry messages throughout the body.
It's part of your belief.
It's referred to as the Para System,
right?
You're your body's internal cellular
communication system.
So the idea is that if you combined the
exosomes with other therapies,
let like a platelet rich plasma
injections,
which you'd do for it to increase the
amount of growth fast.
What they did to a specific joint.
Did exosomes plus prp you,
which I,
I,
I can,
I can tell you the full procedure that I
did,
but I just got that all over my face.
My face five days ago was red and
swollen because it was covered with
exosomes prp injections.
So it's a beauty procedure.
Beautiful as you are.
Thank you.
You don't need change.
But now I'm a beautiful 13 year old and
a 37 year old.
So the uh,
the exosomes can be combined with other
things like prp and also with stem cells
or with bone marrow.
And that's what I did.
And the interesting thing is that you
can get something like a placental cell.
Right?
And in my case,
they actually took placental cells from
this lab called Kymera labs.
I had this procedure done in Park City,
Utah.
Going to him,
Dr Harry Adelson and he,
he had these placental cells from our
labs.
They destroy the placental cell so that
there's no actual DNA from some other
person that you're putting into your
body.
Right,
which is,
which is the.
That's considered to be part of the risk
of stem cells.
Even umbilical or amniotic,
you're still getting somebody else's DNA
into your body,
not your own DNA.
So the idea is that you would take
exosomes that you've isolated from
something like a placental tissue and
then you would mix those with your own
stem cells.
In this case,
what I used was a bone marrow aspirate
they went into to both of my iliac
crest.
They took out the bone marrow.
They mix it with the exosomes and and
these,
these videos.
I published both of the videos on
youtube and it's like a.
it's like a huge syringe full drawing it
out.
I'm going to see the drawing on my hip.
How much bone marrow.
They're taken out of your head a lot.
I was while I was out,
you know,
I was heavily sedated during the entire
procedure.
Will not heavily.
I was under general anesthesia,
it's called full body sedation to
general anesthesia with few of the
risks,
the actual anesthesia.
I was not conscious.
Not though.
I mean,
all I remember is they said count from
100 down to zero and I got to like 93
and then I woke up.
Yeah,
exactly.
So they took the bone marrow from the
ILIAC crest.
Right.
Which is just like bone broth for your
whole body's got collagen.
Peptides got stem cells,
they mix it with the exosomes which act
as communicators from those placental
cells.
This place called [inaudible] labs,
which my opinion is just a great sexy
name for some kind of a mysterious lab
company where you buy placentas.
So basically they,
uh,
they mixed the exosomes with the bone
marrow and then what they do.
Oh yeah.
See that's what,
let's let your ass that.
Yeah,
that's one of the early at crest.
You asked me how much they took,
how much they're pulling out of you.
Holy Shit.
Bone marrow.
He did that like four times because he
did it twice to.
Are you fucking shitting me?
This was five days ago.
He told me I was supposed to not do
anything for two weeks,
but I did the Spartan race.
I armored myself up.
Why didn't you listen to them?
Well,
I,
uh,
I was signed up for the race and I had
sponsor obligations to actually not do
sponsors to suck my Dick [inaudible].
That looks like a fat Dick there.
I use like four rolls of rocktape.
My entire body was just taped up because
I didn't want to ruin anything that he'd
done.
So anyways.
How could he.
He did.
What do you mean by rocktape?
What is rock tape?
Kinesio tape.
You've seen this stuff before.
It's like what you see crossfitters were
tendinitis supports.
It supports the joints.
Oh Jesus.
They're going in for another tube.
Four of those,
four of those big tubes,
Jamie,
to think you have in your body.
You think you have four tubes of marrow
floating around so I could pull out
here.
Oh yeah.
Well,
the tubes also,
you know this,
when you give blood you can give like 19
tubes of blood,
but it's not as much blood as it
actually looks like because it's inside
of that little skinny tube.
Right?
No,
I get that.
So he and his partner,
it was like quite a lot.
What they did was he went with that bone
marrow to mixed with the exosomes.
They mix it with ozone,
which apparently using an [inaudible]
which apparently increases the efficacy
of the bone marrow.
And you're doing this for no specific
injury,
no specific injury?
No.
This is all just for for two reasons.
Number One,
anti aging.
Number two,
just immersive journalism just to write
about.
I think this stuff's fun to write about
and look into and study.
So and,
and apparently the stem cell state of
Elvis,
so this,
this is an over exaggeration,
but it's almost like you'd be like
wolverine or like you recover faster
when you get hurt for the rest of your
life.
So here he goes out round two for people
who are listening to the audio,
not watching the video.
It's like a horse pulling a horse
second,
so it's a lot of blood.
And uh,
then he injected my entire
musculoskeletal system.
He did my cerebral spinal fluid.
He did all up and down the discs in my
back.
Oh Daddy,
you conscious here?
I've got needles.
No,
dude,
I'm totally out.
I would not want to be conscious.
I was just box breathing.
Yeah,
I was meditating.
I'm totally out for this.
[inaudible] done.
You can see there.
I have,
I have the ironman corporate logo on my
back,
so I didn't.
Yeah,
I'm technically that's trademark
infringement.
The iron man logo I had,
I'm retaking done in my spine like that.
Bulging discs is awake.
It's just so weird.
They just just done a lot of this stuff
before.
I mean,
I had my,
I told you this last time.
I had my stem cells taken out of the fat
and my back down in Florida and then,
uh,
I re injected them intravenously and
then I tested my telomere length.
Look at this,
look at this.
They just,
Oh,
this goes on for our students.
And like I was there for three or four
hours,
so they just screw it in and pop those
in and find a new hole.
You're totally alcohol.
But I'm totally a cold.
My wife's in there freaking out.
She can see her somewhere in there
holding the camera.
Hey,
she was,
she was doing a facebook live and
answering questions as we went.
So get this.
His partner comes in,
she takes those exosomes after he does
ankles,
knees,
hips,
elbows,
wrists,
back.
Every part of my mother,
they flipped me over by ice cold.
Yeah.
My wife said that was the weirdest part
was they flipped me over and I'm losing
limp.
Like a noodle.
I think she's moving my hand.
See that.
So,
uh,
then his partner came in and she's like
a sexual performance and beauty
specialist and I don't want this to turn
into another podcast about just
injecting things into your deck.
But she did a hip,
but she did,
uh,
she,
she injected the Corpus Cavernosum,
which is the shaft of your unit.
And then she did the head of the penis
and then she did my face over and over
and over again,
everywhere.
Exosomes all over my face.
And I've seen some 50 and 60 year old
women who have done this and it actually
does seem to have a pretty significant
effect.
I don't,
I don't know how much of an effect it
had on me,
but I said if they were going to put me
under just,
he called it a full body stem cell make
over.
Apparently nobody's ever in the history
of the world,
done this before.
So if I,
if I die,
that's the one thing I can brag about
you.
This is what I don't understand.
You don't need this shit.
No.
A lot of the,
like I said,
a lot of a lot of this stuff is uh,
it's,
it's interesting to write stories about
and to talk about and tell people what
it's like.
And then they did a,
yeah,
they did that on the face.
What,
where they do on your face here.
And uh,
that's the exosomes and mixed with PRP.
What does that inject into the face?
Doing it with,
what is that thing?
I don't remember because I wasn't awake,
but it looks like it's got little
needles all over.
I think it might be like some kind of
like dermabrasion type of thing.
I'm not sure.
Can your face up,
man,
I mean this was a few days ago and how
many feel like a heel five days ago?
Yeah.
So I healed up pretty quickly from CSI
because five was when I was doing my
head to where I'm a great minds think
alike.
Dude.
That is crazy.
That's actually what day is it too bad?
No,
it's Tuesday.
So this was actually this.
No,
seven,
seven days ago.
Seven days ago.
Mine was Wednesday.
Um.
Anyways though.
Their fucking face.
Absolutely.
Yeah.
And I had,
I actually had just gotten a concussion
because I got in a bike accident when I
was down in Austin,
Texas a couple of weeks ago.
And so the other thing that,
this is interesting because for a Tbi
there's all sorts of things that you can
do right?
Like ketones,
exogenous ketones work really well for
that and that's a lot of dominic
d'agostino is research on concussions.
A Dha is another good one.
Hyperbaric oxygen therapy chambers with
the high oxygen plus the high pressure
that's really efficacious for
concussions.
But the other thing is stem cells.
And so what I did was I ordered the stem
cells that they harvested from my body
and Florida because I think I told you
about that the last time when I was on
the show that they store.
I have like 30
injections of my own stem cells stored
down in Florida that I can use for,
for joints,
for anti aging.
And I also,
one of the reasons that I did that was
if I'm ever in a car accident,
if forever get some,
some traumatic injury,
I can,
I can heal myself faster with these stem
cells.
And in that happened,
I got a concussion.
I was riding my bike and Austin on,
on first street and in rush hour traffic
in a car clipped me on the side and I
made love to the pavement.
My entire face got torn open.
And uh,
and I got a concussion,
so I did all these things,
have ketones,
Dha,
hyperbaric.
I'm a PMF.
That's also really,
really good for concussions.
Pulsed electromagnetic field therapy.
Uh,
it's,
uh,
it,
it's a used for anti-inflammatory,
uh,
for,
it's,
it's used for sleep,
you know,
it's kind of like grounding and
earthing.
There's a lot of interesting studies on
PMF also for concussion.
It enhances your own stem cell
production.
It shuts down neuroinflammation.
So I did that,
but then also a stem cells won't cross
your blood brain barrier.
So I ordered up this stuff called
Mannitol,
and if you inject mannitol into your
bloodstream,
it increases your blood brain barrier
permeability.
So this is what you do in a fight or a
football player.
Somebody gets a concussion,
you inject with mannitol first,
and then you follow that up with a stem
cell injection.
If the Mannitol is already in the
bloodstream,
the stem cells cross the blood brain
barrier and they go into he'll neural
tissue with the exosomes,
cross the blood brain barrier because
they're smaller,
very small.
They're very small.
I think they're like 100 to 200
nanometers,
which is pretty small and I would not be
surprised if they cross the blood brain
barrier as well.
One of the things that they were saying
about stem cells versus exosomes that
stem cells tend to get pulled up in the
lungs.
They don't pass the lungs and they get
absorbed there and they believe that the
exosomes being released by these stem
cells are the reason why you generate
regenerate tissue.
They think that going straight to
exosomes is going to be more efficacious
than just going with stem cells.
So I think that some pharmaceutical
company or some supplement company is
going to make a lot of money in the next
10 years by figuring out a way to,
to make exosomes or figure out some way
to do it in a way that is more available
to the general population.
Then,
you know,
harvesting it from placentas and you
know,
some crazy lab.
So you weren't supposed to do anything
for two weeks now for two weeks.
But I asked the doctor and I told them I
was going to do a spartan race.
He just said,
proceed at your own risk,
and in my plan,
apparently few jar the joints a lot when
they're already kinda weak from the
surgery,
you can risk tearing a ligament
spraining straining,
doing damage to a muscle that that's
kind of weakened lax from the surgery,
from the surgery,
but is it a really a surgery because
they're not cutting the the injection
and I sprained my ankle within a few
hours after,
after waking up from the surgery,
like I just kind of stumbled and it was
extremely lax and almost like a,
like a pregnant woman creates this
hormone called relaxin right?
And they get more flexible and they're
able to give birth more quickly.
It's kind of that
same idea is the joints,
the joints and the ligaments become more
lax.
So my whole body felt a little bit more
like,
like Gumby.
That's what that was.
Why I taped up everything.
You know,
I had knee braces on an elbow braces and
wrist braces and I felt fine during the
race and this whole procedure was how
many hours?
It was about four hours.
Four hours out.
Cold Shit Up.
What does it feel like when you wake up?
Oh,
there's a pretty funny video I posted.
I thought it was funny.
I was trying to speak French,
so my wife,
I'm like,
I have a confession to make.
And the doctor's like,
Oh,
here we go.
I'm like,
speak French.
And then she.
And then she asked me if I speak French.
Nice.
I didn't actually speak French and then
you could see me trying to laugh,
like it made a joke.
But you.
Have you ever been sedated?
Yes.
Yeah,
yeah.
Yeah.
You're kind of loopy make up.
So I don't remember that much.
But uh,
and,
and I still,
I mean,
I'll be honest with you,
I don't notice much of a difference from
any of this stuff.
What's six weeks?
Yeah,
it's supposed to take a really long time
before it really kicks in and it flares
up.
Old injuries were like kind of strained
my upper hamstring when I played tennis
and that's flared up.
Uh,
my left knee is flared up.
Like I'm feeling old injuries that are
most interesting.
They almost like brought back,
not flared up like it's red and inflamed
and swollen,
but I feel it.
I feel my right ankle,
which I strained a lot when I was,
when I was playing tennis.
That one feels,
you know,
it feels like I mentioned it's weak,
it's paid.
It's going to be something they said
that it could flare up old injuries that
you'd feel worse before you feel better.
Huh?
That's interesting.
I didn't hear that at all,
but I did hear that six weeks,
six weeks is the benchmark.
It's a little bit of time before they
actually feel better.
Yeah.
The other interesting one,
uh,
for not only enhancing your own
endogenous stem cell production because
it actually would know a lot of this
stuff.
It's fringe.
It's expensive.
I mean,
you know,
that procedure,
I think he's like a $30,000
procedure.
Not Everybody's going to go out and do
that and this is another fringe one,
but I want to.
I mean there are ways that you can
endogenously increase your own stem cell
production.
I mean,
in your own stem cell viability and
health,
without actually doing stem cell
injections,
I'm fasting is probably the the one
that's the most efficacious in a lot of
these things that are kind of
uncomfortable for you seem to increase
your body's ability to be able to heal
or produce its own stem cells.
So fasting for long periods of time.
I'm not necessarily fasting with,
with caloric restriction.
I think that's the mistake a lot of
people make.
They try to fast and they feel like
crap.
But the idea is the benefits of fast and
don't come from nodding a lot of
calories,
not even a lot of calories.
Isn't that great for your thyroid is not
great for your metabolism.
You want to live till you're 120 and be
cold and thin and hungry the whole time
because it'd be a horrible way to live a
long time.
So the idea with,
you know,
things like,
uh,
you know,
valter Longo is research or a lot of
these,
uh,
intermittent fasting type of diets.
As you fast and you increase cellular
autophagy and stem cell production,
your own stem cell production by going
for long periods of time without eating
and the magic seems to kick in and about
the 16 hour mark.
So I do 12 to 16 hours every day and
then you get even more benefit once you
get up to about 24 hours.
So I try to do a 24 hour fast from
Saturday dinner to Sunday dinner,
but I'm still eating the same number of
calories.
It's just a compressed feeding window.
Right?
So,
so it's not like you're starving
yourself,
you're getting all the benefits of
fasting,
but you're still maintaining some amount
of anabolic them,
right?
Because you're,
you're still eating as many calories,
but you're,
you're almost giving your body,
your gut in your metabolism a break in
between a lot of these meals.
And that's where the benefit comes from.
That's where the Bennett,
the benefits are not from,
you know,
not eating so much damn food.
The benefits are going for a long time
in between your feedings.
Right?
So,
so the idea is,
you know,
you,
you'd wake up and in the population for
which this seems to be the most
deleterious,
our lean active females,
they do not respond well to these long
fasts,
are a lot of time spent doing
intermittent fasting.
It's like the cons outweigh the pro for
that population.
But for,
for most everybody else,
these 12 to 16 hour fast,
preferably up to 16 hours going without
eating and then eating as many calories
as you'd normally eight with the
exception rest the,
the amount of calories and compressed
feeding window.
Right.
So,
um,
you know,
what,
the guy whose house I was staying with
her when I was doing the stem cell
procedure,
Dan pump,
he's very into this stuff and,
and he's,
he's a doctor down in a park city and he
just,
he goes all day and then he has a huge
dinner at the end of the day,
right?
Like uh,
an enormous lovely dinner,
you know,
a couple of glasses of wine and you
know,
stay thousands,
3000 calories for dinner.
And I'm more of like a two meal,
a light breakfast or light lunch.
And then just two males,
I've been doing the 12 to 14 hour thing
and sometimes I have ramped it up to 16
hours and I do feel better when I do
that and I,
I definitely become more accustomed to
not eating for long stretches.
And sometimes when I wake up in the
morning I almost think,
should I just eat?
But then I'll stop and go,
well,
I'm not really hungry.
I mean it's really just a matter of
habit,
force of habit that I'm even considering
eating right now.
Yeah.
But.
But fasting is probably one of the
better ways to increase your own
endogenous stem cell production.
Provided you're going for about 16 hours
and provided you're still eating as many
calories as you would normally eat.
The only kind of caveat to that would be
protein cycling.
And this is why I'm not a huge fan of
the reverse diet.
Were eating four to six pounds of meat a
day.
Yeah,
you were.
I'm trying that for awhile.
You're putting that on your social
media.
I sort of.
But yet I was eating one of those big
stakes every single night for dinner,
just like a bunch of steak every single
night for dinner,
for how long?
And this was like 10 days.
Not that long.
How'd you feel doing that?
I felt pretty good.
But uh,
but I love steak.
I was eating these bone in a bone in rib
eyes.
I ordered them up from a Missouri,
I think is where their farms are,
but they make these,
a French cut grass fed grass finished
bone in Ribeye steaks in there saying
that I've got.
I've remind me,
I'll tell you how I cook them.
They will tell you how I cook them
afterwards after we finished the silence
because,
because I didn't want to get because
I'll,
I'll just forget everything if I start
talking about cooking because I love to
prepare me.
So,
so real quick.
Quite a few people that are doing this
now.
So real quick and then we'll talk about
how to make these steaks tastes really
good.
Um,
the,
the idea is that protein cycling,
right?
Having a meatless Monday or having as a
lot of religions would do like the
eastern Orthodoxy Church or the
Mediterranean Diet,
they have certain periods of time where
there's complete meet restriction or
your protein intake is restricted to
fish and eggs for example,
and the idea is that you would strike a
sweet spot between not being in a
constantly anabolic state.
Right?
And and not having,
having this mammalian target of
rapamycin and constantly activated,
which would theoretically accelerate
aging or,
or in,
in a lot of rodent models.
We see that on restricted protein
feeding actually causes aging to
accelerate.
So the idea is on your lower activity
days,
especially for an athlete,
you could still intermittent fast and
get all the benefits of that and you
could still eat as many calories as you
would need to sustain a normal healthy
metabolism.
Right?
So,
so you're not starving yourself,
but on the less active days you would
shift to a lower protein intake.
Right?
So you're talking about like zero point
five grams per pound of body weight
rather than what a typical athlete would
need,
which would be depending on.
You asked.
It was zero point seven to zero point
eight,
five grams per pound of body weight,
right?
So,
so there's some days where you're high
protein,
some days where you're low protein,
some periods of the week such as a
meatless Monday or some periods of the
year,
you know,
such as every quarter for a week where
you're eating a plant based diet or
you're restricting me,
you're basically giving your body a
break from being in that constant
anabolic state.
And I think that the,
the carnivore diet causes a lot of
people to miss out on some of those
elements.
And then if you look at the blood work,
have a um,
a doctor who does die,
he published his blood work online and I
don't know what else is going on with
them from a health standpoint but,
but you know,
he had really high blood glucose and
really low testosterone and some things
that suggest that it might not be
healthy to just meet you know.
And did you have really low
testosterone?
That's interesting.
It was like 200 to $300.
It's really low.
Diagnosable hypogonadism combined with
a,
uh,
you know,
almost like borderline diabetes did.
Is it possible to do it after a workout?
A,
he does a lot of rowing for real high
pressure testosterone.
That's significantly.
It would increase your HSC RP and your
inflammatory markers.
Right?
Which is why you never want to.
You never want to go to a doctor for a
heart checkup after you've done a
workout because they're going to tell
you you're gonna have a heart attack
based on the levels of HSC or p,
but you know,
that blood work is just one example and
I don't want to pretend like that.
One example is going to paint with a
broad brush the entitlement carnivore
diet phenomenon,
but I just,
I think that unrestricted protein
intake,
an unrestricted meat intake probably has
an accelerated aging effect on the body
and well,
here's the different Dr Ron Rosedale is
a doc with some good information on
that.
He's got a good video online.
What's going on with this carnivore diet
is there's no science behind it.
There's a lot of people that are giving
it a shot,
a lot of people finding good results,
but I find that people,
when they just change things,
there's a period of time with a say they
feel great and that is absolutely 100
percent of placebo effect.
It's the same thing as like a Vegan
Diet.
You feel fantastic and named me,
well,
name me one population,
one blue zone that eats meat and nothing
else and there's.
There's actually very few centenarians
who are purely Vegan for their entire
life because you can,
if you don't do it the right way,
build up fatty acid deficits,
amino acid deficits.
Korea team is when you don't get vitamin
B,
12 a Dha,
but at least it's been studied.
Corrine on Vegans,
right?
I been a lot of studies on vegans and we
know that if you eat a like e three
live,
you know you.
Oh you can.
You can supplement it.
There's a lot of really smart vegans.
I mean those guys like rich roll,
like they do things the right way,
right?
It's a lot easier to see the piece of
meat to get some of the [inaudible] and
some of the other amino acid you're
trying to free up by soaking and
sprouting and fermenting,
which my wife does a lot of it,
but I watch her like she.
She's in the kitchen like three hours a
day making vegetables bioavailable
because you have to take her hours to
make sourdough bread.
Do you know,
to actually make a bread where the
gluten is pre digested and it's actually
healthy in the glycaemic index is lower.
She's not Vegan.
She's just a rancher girl and she likes
to leave.
We have goats and chickens and we eat
meat but she.
She's very into like an ancestral
preparation of vegetables.
You deactivating a lot of these,
these stress or is that Dr Steven gundry
talks about and you know before we part
because we're talking about Tom Brady
and how he does like a no night shade,
no tomato,
no potato,
and I'd rather eat those things,
but actually figuring out a way to
render them more digestible and
friendlier to the human body.
Yeah.
That's the other thing too,
when people talk about food that has
protein in it,
um,
you know,
like Broccoli has so much protein,
true,
not really bioavailable to shit,
ton of Broccoli.
It's just not the same.
Your body doesn't absorb it the same way
it does it.
Grass Fed rib eye steak.
Yeah.
Body absorbs that protein instantly
knows exactly what he does.
Yeah.
By the way,
there,
there was a study that just came out
about stem cells.
They found that carnosine,
which you find in copious amounts in
grass fed rib eye steak with blueberry
extract,
enhanced your stem cell production,
and it was a hugely significant number.
I don't remember the exact percentage
but,
but this combination of polyphenols and
flavanols with meat is a good combo.
That's why when I did the carnivore diet
or not,
the carnivore diet,
that's when I was.
When I was eating meat,
I was doing lots of salads.
I was doing lots of.
I had like wild blueberry powder.
I had these vegetable powders,
you know,
I was doing a lot of big salads for
lunch,
flavanols,
polyphenols,
any of that same thing with the high
saturated fat diet,
a high saturated fat diet,
like the whole coconut oil thing is
highly inflammatory in the absence of
plant polyphenols and flavonols,
which is why if you're doing a high fat
ketonic diet,
it needs to be a plant rich,
high fat ketotic Diet.
Otherwise things on those lines.
You can get a lot of your friends.
I mean Avocados,
yes,
but I'm talking about more like you're
doing coconut oil,
butter and you know,
avocado,
chocolate pudding and all these thing.
You know,
your Keto genic fat bombs and all these
recipes that are out there,
but he got.
He had a lot of plants.
Even in the animal kingdom,
you see animals and they rip up another
animal,
like a carnivorous animal.
They're in the intestines and the
reading.
A lot of the organs that are chock full
of what grass plants or herbs,
whatever.
That omnivorous animal that the
carnivorous animal is eating predicted.
Exactly,
exactly.
When you're talking about carnivorous
diets,
the real issue that I have with it is
there's almost no research other than Dr
Baker doing those tests on himself,
which,
uh,
according to you are not very promising.
I didn't.
I have some friends that are trying it.
My friend Jordan Peterson,
his daughter had some serious anti,
some serious immune system issues,
autoimmune disorders,
and like to the point where she's had a,
she's,
I believe she's like 30,
31 set of hip replaced.
She's about to get one of her ankles
replaced,
like serious arthritis.
Real problems.
The only thing that's been able to clear
that up as meat,
just a pure meat diet.
So with some people,
but she might have some,
I wouldn't say the only pages allergic
reaction to plants.
I mean there might be something.
The meat wasn't the medicine.
Probably the elimination of whatever she
was saying.
She might have some sort of a,
a,
a real serious problem,
some sort of allergic reaction to some
plants or to gluten and maybe a bunch of
different ways.
A lot of these diets are right.
Yeah.
It's,
it's the elimination,
not the magic of just eating me mean,
but Sean Baker keeps going on and on
about how meat,
heels and meet this and meet that all
carnivorous diet and you know,
all these people trying it like man,
it's got a lot of good stuff going for
it.
But,
but restriction of plant matter,
in my opinion,
long term is not a good idea and eating
meat all the time long term is not
necessarily a good idea.
And eating only plants with the absence
of some meat based protein is for a lot
of populations.
Not that great of an idea.
Yeah.
Well that's the point is that for most
people you're going to have to
experiment a little bit to figure out
what works best for you.
And there are people that,
especially if you use e three live and
algae and get your [inaudible] vitamins
and your fat soluble vitamins,
you can live off of Vegan Diet.
It can be done,
but you really have to be careful about
it.
But then there's other people where they
can't and and,
and you really have to figure out what
the fuck is going on with the carnivore
thing to me is kinda tweaking me out
because I just don't.
It's like they start talking about the
poisons and Fido toxins and all these
things that are in plants that are bad
for it.
I'm like,
okay,
but the issue with Dennis mild hormetic
exercise is bad for you.
Sunlight's bad for all that stuff
because it's going to say for a medic
stressor is that your body responds to
that in a positive way.
Even show that some of the,
some of the rodents outside of Chernobyl
are living longer from the radiation.
And I'm not saying like go,
go move your cabinet next to a nuclear
disaster website.
But the idea is that's a hormetic
stressor.
Mild amounts of UVA and UVB.
Yes.
Every day I actually,
every single day I do cold.
Every single day I do hot.
If I'm not in the sauna that I'm wearing
more clothes than I would normally wear
when I go to the gym to get my,
get my heart rate up and actually get
myself into the discomfort of hot for
the heat shock protein and the nitric
oxide.
Everything else,
so that does for you in the discomfort
of cold because it's a hormetic stress
or they're doing tests right now at
Harvard,
so it's fast yoga and trying to figure
out if hot yoga has the same hermetic
stress response as I'm sauna because
they know there's been quite a bit of
work done on.
It's very equivalent physiologically.
Yeah.
I mean I don't do the full choreographed
90 minute Bikram Yoga,
but I have one of these big Saunas.
It's like it's a four person sauna and
if I go in there by myself,
I can do in down dog and pushups and I'd
take these,
uh,
these cats who blood flow restriction
devices in there and do pushups and
squats.
And those are the research behind those
for muscle maintenance.
With bodyweight training,
it's very intriguing.
I travel with them everywhere.
These,
these cats who training devices and I
just tie them like tourniquets on my
arms around my legs and they do a lot of
studies and seniors for muscle
maintenance without the need for as much
joint impact,
but what happens is you get micro damage
to the capillaries,
you get a big release of lactic acid
which causes you to produce more growth
hormone after the workout.
I mean in my opinion,
for bodyweight training,
like at this point,
Katsu training like doubles.
Yeah,
I've heard that before.
I haven't really gotten into it,
but I'm very big on the sauna to the
point where obviously we have one here
at the studio that he used all the time.
I just think it's,
you know,
those stressors that they're talking
about as being a negative thing with
eating vegetables.
I just don't buy it.
People have been eating vegetables
forever.
I don't think they're bad access or in
people like your friend with the immune
system issue or people with leaky gut or
damage.
There might be a period of time where
you actually have to be careful and
really careful with gluten,
which is a digestive stress or uh,
and again,
even that in small amounts,
it's probably good for you.
They've been shown that kids who get
gluten restricted when their kids wind
up having more issues with gluten later
on in life because their guts might be
weaker.
Right?
But,
but yeah,
lectins and plant phytochemicals and a
lot of things that plants use to poison
mammals are two,
cause they're their seeds to be digested
and pass out through the digestive tract
and the stool of the mammals.
They can grow elsewhere.
A lot of that stuff really is,
you know,
it,
it makes you stronger.
You ever had that coffee?
Kopi Luwak you ever had that stuff is
the stuff.
Yeah,
the,
the cat,
the Lemur coffee and shits it out and
then they take the coffee and sell it at
this outrageous rate.
It's actually delicious.
Ferments coffee man,
that's very nice.
But your elephants do to black,
black,
ivory caught your eye.
That shit.
I don't want to like support the ELA.
I don't give a fuck about lemurs.
I don't.
It's a Lima.
I think it's harvesting coffee beans
from elephant poop sounds far more
laborious than than harvesting.
Shuttles are lemurs.
Just hose it down.
Get better.
Bang for your book is titled One little.
It's like a needle in a haystack,
right?
If it's just a few coffee beans and the
trial elephant shit,
get jacked up.
Coffee.
The elephant elephants chasing you.
You're digging through their shit,
chasing you through the field.
Plus they probably shit like crazy.
Just like a person doesn't eat coffee.
I give them some,
uh,
lte and there it is.
What it is.
Those are coffee tourists.
That's almost like a bunch of coffee
beans with a few pieces of Turd thrown
it.
Yeah.
Look at that.
Bam.
Son was almost looot coffee,
so they just feed them nothing but
coffee and they shared it out sort of
like we should out corn and can't really
digest it properly.
There's a fermentation process that
makes the bean tastes better.
My problem with the carnivore diet is my
same problem that I have with the Vegan
Diet.
Is it?
I don't think they're being scientific
or objective about it.
I being dogmatic it's becomes an
ideology and the ideology is the meat
heels and meets this and meet that and
meet is the thing and like no meat is
one part of a good diet,
one part of a healthy diet and again,
for some people there's some people that
have.
I'm sure you aware of the lone star
tick,
you know about that.
Right?
What about it?
Do you know about me down?
Allergies?
No.
Lone Star tick is a tick that bites
people and gives them an allergy to red
meat.
It's horrible for Texas.
Yes,
yes,
but it's spreading.
It's spreading across the country.
See,
all we have up in my land is a ticks
that as long as you get them off within
24 hours,
that doesn't allow them to produce the
saliva that would make them release
their hold on your skin and it's that
that produces yellow fever,
not the actual tick bite itself.
So you don't get a lot of lime up where
I'm at,
but I've never heard of this loan.
Slime as much more prevalent on the east
coast,
it's starting to make its way out here.
There have been some lyme cases out here
in California,
but this lone star tick is,
um,
it's a real problem and it's giving
people.
It's something called Alpha Gal Alpha
Alpha,
short for Alpha,
Gao Alpha,
less shadows that sugar.
So here it is,
it makes you allergic to hot dogs.
Alpha Alpha one,
three.
Galactose.
Alpha Gals,
the most mammalian cell membranes.
The allergy doesn't extend to non
mammalian meat.
Poultry and seafood are all fine,
which is really interesting.
So you,
you can't,
once you get this shit,
you're just,
you're allergic to this Alpha galactose.
But you could eat eight and human meat
according to the article.
So you're not allergic to those pig.
I wonder if pork.
Welcome a million doubt it.
So could he ate meat?
So if you want to go to the jungle and
have what they call a bushmeat credit.
Okay.
Speaking of me.
Ribeye steaks.
Yes.
This is how to make these Ribeye steaks
taste really good.
So what I do on on the rub is like a
really core salt,
use a salt called Colima salt,
super high in minerals,
really kosher salt course.
Now it's different.
They harvested from the Mexican coast
and it tastes fabulous.
It's really good.
What's a girl?
Only salts I travel with and Boz is
Kalema salt and then this stuff.
I am a c o,
l I m a and Black Kona salt black Kona
salt from.
From China.
From Hawaii.
Yeah.
I use that when I cook some of the meat
from Hawaii just because it seems right.
It does.
He use salt from.
From,
from the,
from the volcanoes in Hawaii.
So.
And I rub a Cayenne black pepper salt
and then to reduce the carcinogens that
conform when you cook me either time or
rosemary or both or just rubbed thyme or
Rosemary Reduces carcinogens there.
And Dennis.
Yeah,
they reduced.
They reduced the formation of a,
I think they call them polycyclic
aromatic hydrocarbons.
These,
these,
you know,
things that form on the meat when you
black in the meat because you want to
get a good crisp sphere on the inside of
the meat,
so it's nice and crunchy on the outside.
She was strict.
A lot of the unhealthy effects of doing
that.
When you get some kind of an urban there
like that,
so you take out the.
You get to room temperature,
you put this rubbing,
you take a cast iron skillet,
so I'll do it on the grill at all.
It's a cast iron skillet.
You heat up the cast iron skillet in the
oven and then you take it out of the
oven and you put it on the stove top.
You put the stove top on medium high and
either use an extra virgin olive oil.
A have used lard before.
Why do you use,
although what has a low flashpoint gives
me a good put no extra virgin.
Olive oil has a bunch of antioxidants in
it,
so it's actually guernseys as higher
resistance to that.
He never burnt.
Never an issue.
It doesn't burn,
doesn't smoke,
but when they see or things,
that's one thing they tell you is never
use olive oil.
Well,
I use extroversion all.
I'm part of an olive oil clubs,
so maybe it's because I have really good
olive oil.
They shipped me three bottles of olive
oil every quarter from a different pool
that or find that out because I've
really read don't cook things at high
heat with olive oil.
Look it up,
even extra virgin olive oil.
At this point,
all I can tell you is the shots,
how you're speaking.
You're saying hi.
He said medium heat and this says medium
heat too,
so maybe that's the difference is the
high heat maybe,
but when you're searing I would assume
that it is kind of.
It's not on there for very long.
Anyways,
extra virgin olive oil into the pan.
Heat up the olive oil and you put it on
for maybe two minutes Max on the cast
iron skillet.
You heat up the olive oil,
then you put the steak on and you do
exactly for a perfect medium rare three
and a half minutes.
One side,
three and a half minutes.
The other side.
Then you take it out on this is where
you get there.
Probably about that thick.
What is that?
Oh yeah,
we're on audio.
It's about an inch and a half.
So anyways,
the um,
it's like when you asked me in the last
podcast how big my dick got after I
inject it with about that big,
not that big.
So anyways,
the uh,
then then you put it in to the oven,
you take that entire cast iron skillet,
you put the oven on Broil and you broil
it for one minute on one side and then
you turn it over and you do one minute
on the other side and then you take it
out of the oven and you finish it with
butter.
Meaning when you take it out of the
oven,
you just take the steak off the cast
iron skillets,
shove it aside,
just put on a plate,
whatever.
And you take a pad of butter and you can
infuse the butter,
right?
You can,
you can use like garlic infused butter
would just use a plain old grassfed
butter.
You put a pat of butter on the skill
that you let the butter just get to the
point where it's melted a little bit and
it's not Super Brown.
You put the stake back on top of the
butter,
put the burner back on,
and you finish it one minute each side.
Let it off.
Let it rest.
Three or four minutes.
That technique is the best technique for
the most perfect steak you'll ever have.
It sounds very good.
Is really good.
That sounds very good.
It's really good.
Mostly what I do is the reverse sear
method with a pellet grill.
I keep it at about 250 degrees.
You ever used a pellet grill?
Well,
like about pellet grills is you're
getting an appellate socially a similar
horrible.
You're,
you're essentially getting hardwood
that's compressed.
So what,
when they cut hardwood,
like for um,
let's table it would take the oak and
the saw dust,
they would compress into these small
pellets and there's a bunch of different
companies,
uh,
triggers a,
a good one.
They,
they,
they make one for the good girls.
Yeah.
They have good grills and they also make
one that you could use with an APP.
What I like about it is you can control
the temperature completely with your
phone.
There's a thing called a timberline is
one of their new ones.
Um,
so anyway,
you get these compressed pellets and
they go into a hopper and then there it
is right there.
That's a.
What is that one of the woodwind?
That's where a pellet stove look like
when I was growing up.
So the pellets go into the hopper and
then at the bottom there's a gear,
like a worm drive that feeds the pellets
into that fire at the bottom,
comes from an element,
so the element and then there's a fan.
So once it's lit,
the element shuts off and then the fire
is stoked by this fan and it's all
temperature controlled.
Like very,
very precisely.
One of the good things,
what I like about this trigger that I've
seen is that it seals up like a,
um,
like a yeti cooler.
Like it's very insulated and fixed.
So it's really good at retaining the
perfect temperature.
And again you can do it on your phone.
So I get it to 250 degrees.
Then mostly what I'm cooking is wild
game,
low fat content.
And so you don't want to make sure you
don't dry it out.
So I took it at a low temperature.
I'm cooking a 250 degrees.
I get it to an internal temperature of
120 the once it hits 120,
I pull it out.
And you've got to open up the grill,
the test,
your internal temp wire.
Now I have a wireless wire wire,
wireless thermometer that's connected to
it and it's outside the circle.
We see it and that's like what my dry
aging has and it's also,
it lets me know,
it gives you a beep when it hits 1:20.
So I know I go and get it.
So I pull it out technical.
Then I pull it out of there and I use
this cast iron skillet as well.
But I cook with grass fed butter.
So I take the cast iron skillet,
I put it probably same temperature,
medium,
high heat.
And again,
when I'm got the steak on the,
on the grill itself,
I'm using sea salt and crushed black
pepper and garlic powder.
That's what I usually use.
No black end extra.
No,
no.
I'm going to try now.
I'm.
So then I take it off of there and then
I use grass fed butter in a cast iron
skillet once it's heated up.
I sear it on both sides for about a
minute and a half and then I let it rest
depending if I'm an ambitious,
sometimes I'll let it rest a,
cover it with aluminum foil and put it
in a Yeti cooler and I'll let it sit in
that Yeti cooler for about 10 minutes
and I pull it out and it is just too
cold.
After 10 minutes,
the Yeti cooler now to the Yeti Cooler,
the Yeti cooler maintains the
temperature.
The stakes we should have.
My wife just texted shopping stakes
yoder,
yoder pellet grill in the band,
a cast iron pan.
I mean that's the reverse sear method.
The idea is that I'm cooking it to a
perfect internal temperature of 120
degrees,
which will raise both in the Yeti,
the Yeti Cooler,
and also from the Siri on the outside,
so once I get the cast iron pan heated
up to a medium high heat,
I throw that butter in there and I see
her the shit out of the outside for
again,
about a minute and a half.
Both sides wrap it in foil,
put it in the Yeti Cooler for 10
minutes.
It maintains its temperature and it
continues slowly cooking so that it gets
it somewhere around 1:35
ish,
which is what I like.
I take that back very precise.
This is even more precise.
This is like the sound effects is like
beep,
beep.
I was cooking steak.
Well,
I'm a big fan of these pellet grills
because you get this real smoky flavor
to your food that comes from hardwood,
but there's no chemicals.
They compressed the hardwood sawdust
just with natural sugars.
The natural sugars in the sawdust and
you know,
there's a bunch of different companies.
There's a green mountain grill.
Makes a good grill.
I got to yoga at home.
I really like.
Again,
trager is really good.
Most of my friends are using triggers
because they this temperature control
thing and the apps are so good to be
able to use it on your phone.
I'm a big fan.
Yeah.
Wow.
That's amazing.
Yeah.
I liked the fact that you can use good.
You said it and you could just walk the
fuck away from it too and it's going to
smoke your meat at 250 degrees and it
has a good rich,
that smoky flavor,
whether it's Hickory or cherry,
you know,
whenever you choose.
The only thing that I have to do,
I don't know why I'm like this with a
steak because I still need to dip it in
something in the same way that you dip a
prime rib and horseradish.
You stone mustard.
I did my statement.
You know like the stone mustard with a
little little texture to it.
That's perfect.
I know it's fricking the middle of the
day on a Tuesday and I'm hungry to
[inaudible] last night and had steak.
That's a good spot.
Was it was good.
I had a fascinating,
fascinating discussion about artificial
sweeteners there with uh,
one of the guys who runs quest nutrition
and was talking about Tom said no,
it wasn't Tom,
it was Ron Ron Pena and,
and he was drinking diet coke and we
were talking about some of the studies
out there on assets will family
potassium and the potential for
neurotoxicity or sucralose to cause
things like,
uh,
you know,
microbiome issues,
the death of bacteria in the gut.
And he was explaining how the amount of
artificial sweeteners using that study
was just like way far in excess of what
you get from a diet soda and that what
they call the increase in response like,
like that,
that spiking of the appetite that is
attributed sometimes to the consumption
of artificial sweeteners only occurs in
people who aren't used to artificial
sweetener consumption.
And once they've kind of gotten into
like a,
like a diet coke habit that now this is
all Brendan is like 12 hours ago.
Right?
So I started drinking diet coke and I do
know they use artificial sweeteners,
so bars.
And so yeah,
some of that planet as well,
but he said you could take a shower in
diet coke and you wouldn't get sticky
because there's that.
That's such a small amount of artifice.
It's like a dusting of artificial
sweeteners.
So actually it's,
it's,
it's making.
I haven't delved into the research yet,
but it's at least made me think last
night about reconsidering my stance
because what I usually do is I just use
Stevia and like Pellegrino,
like my refrigerator.
Just full of Pellegrino.
You ever try z?
Because I do a lot.
I love to love that shit.
I love it.
Yeah.
I drink the shit out of trouble the
other day because I'm so busy.
I was doing that spartan life feed
announcing and they're sponsored by a,
a fit aid.
Right.
And then they cut to camera and I had a
big oldZ via.
There were supposed to be pretending
we're drinking that night or whatever.
They'd take the TVA down.
Fitted.
I don't know.
It's a,
it's A.
I think it's a God proteolytic enzymes
in it.
I think that's the main thing.
I could be confusing that with kill
cliff.
That's the other kind of flies off.
We've got a bunch of those proteins
which are great.
They break down fibrinogen.
They're wonderful for recovery.
These enzymes,
and I don't know how many of them they
have just like that.
A blood orange kill cliff [inaudible].
Use it as a marinade for wild pork.
Holy Baby Jesus.
That's like beer can chicken.
Well,
that's one of the things I wonder if
that's.
Well,
proteolytic enzymes.
One of the reasons they work as they
break down fibrinogen and they're almost
like an enzyme,
right?
That same thing.
If you have no marinade and nothing and
all the tenderize me,
you get your digestive enzymes,
your,
you're on it.
Gut Pack or whatever you have around and
you break open the capsules and you
sprinkle that on top.
The meat.
It's like,
uh,
it's like,
you know,
free suggests j almost,
right?
With lemon and lime fish.
It's a phenomenal marinade for meat.
That's cliff orange.
I'm guessing.
Kill cliff is good too.
Yeah.
It's just so,
so delicious.
And you're getting very little sugar.
Yeah.
No,
it's just,
it's just deliciousness.
Oh yeah,
yeah,
but I go with Pellgrino.
Pellgrino is less acidic and perrier and
it has a lot of sodium bicarbonate in.
It doesn't,
I don't know if you looked into these
studies on baking soda for Athletic
Performance and its ability to be able
to buffer lactic acid.
It's a,
it's a potent ergogenic aid,
but the problem is that it causes gut
distress when you take as much as they
use in a lot of these studies and so
more,
more and more what the studies are
doing,
your dosing right with,
with small amounts of baking soda for
two to three hours leading into your
workout.
So my philosophy is this,
if Pellegrino has pretty high levels of
sodium bicarbonate in it,
which it does,
it's got more sodium bicarbonate in it
and any of the other bottled waters like
twice as much as Gerald Steiner and you
know,
any of these other waters out there.
I'm kind of dosing with a little bit of
a lactic acid buffer all day long.
So anytime I want to jump into a
workout,
I'm able to push myself a little bit
harder.
Do you notice a difference?
Yeah,
I know zero Pellegrino studies on this,
but do you notice a difference
physically between not feel amazing when
I drink that stuff all day?
I drink that and I drink this.
Uh,
uh,
it's,
it's hydrogen enriched water,
a molecular hydrogen.
This,
this foundation called the molecular
hydrogen foundation.
They do studies on the antiinflammatory
and antioxidant potential of water that
has a lot of hydrogen ions in it.
It's called hydrogen rich water.
And the cool part about that is that,
and I,
the only other thing I know of that can
do this or green tea,
polyphenols is they act as an anti
inflammatory post-exercise without
blunting the hormetic response,
that positive beneficial stressful
response where you're talking about with
exercise and so you can have your cake
and eat it too,
right?
You get your antioxidants,
you shut down inflammation and it
doesn't blunt.
In this case,
the hormetic response to exercise would
be the proliferation of satellite cells
and the production of new Mitochondria,
which why you shouldn't take a bunch of
vitamin C and Vitamin E and some of
these high antioxidant compounds.
Post workout,
same reason.
You shouldn't do a cold bath postworkout
and the idea is that hydrogen rich water
allows you to shut down inflammation
with once again,
why shouldn't you take a cold bath pulse
workout and is there a certain period of
time where they think you should,
you could,
but it's the period of time to adjust
for me.
I go two or three hours for it.
And as far as some people say don't,
don't jump into the cold bath 15 minutes
after an hour cryo chamber.
According to Rhonda,
I wait two or three hours and I don't.
I don't know if,
if Rhonda is basing that on research or
if it's an extrapolation or or what,
but I wait a couple hours now that the
exception to that rule is that if you
exercise any closer than three hours to
bedtime,
it elevates body temperature to the
point where it affects your deep sleep
cycles.
Right?
So,
and one reason for that is because your
core temperature is elevated.
So for me,
if I do an evening workout and I do,
you know,
hard later afternoon,
early evening workouts,
quite often I will still take a cold
shower.
I actually have a giant claw.
I bought one of those endless pools,
you know,
like those fitness pools that you swim
in and I keep it out in the forest
behind my house and it's just chock full
of cold water.
We talked about that.
Jump in there.
I love that idea,
but it decreases your core temperature
and allows you to sleep better later on
if you do that after an evening workout.
So even though it probably restricts the
efficacy of the workout a little bit,
that's my.
Yeah.
My reasoning is that I'm going to sleep
way better and the benefits I get from a
good solid nights sleep outweigh any
loss of benefit from decreasing a little
bit of that mitochondrial density and in
satellite cell proliferation.
So when you're doing this late night
workout out how far,
like how long before you sleep you're
doing.
What research has shown is that it's
ideal to finish a hard workout within
three hours before bedtime.
If you don't want to,
if you don't want to mess up your sleep
exactly,
but with your cold bath you could
probably mitigate some of you and I go
to bed pretty early.
I usually go to bed about but usually
9:30
9:45
AM in bed reading and I'm asleep around
10,
30.
So if I'm not finishing up a workout
until like 7:30,
which is the case sometimes you not
finish work.
I'm not getting into the workout until
like 6:45,
seven.
Like sometimes I'm working out closer to
bedtime three hours.
So in that case I'll do the cold shower,
did a podcast recently with Dr Matthew
Walker about sleep and it's kind of
changed the way I feel about sleep and
the importance of it and how much,
how much you need.
I think you can just power through and
get through with like three,
four hours at night.
You'd be fine.
You can,
yeah.
But it fucks you up.
Well there's,
there's exceptions to that.
I mean,
some people have,
this I think is the d,
c to gene that allows you to actually
get by on a lot less sleep.
Some members of the population has that
gene.
It's a very small member of the
population.
Small moment.
But furthermore there's this guy named
Dr Luke Huddle.
Nick little hills is his name.
I could have really messed up.
They didn't know Dick Middle Hails.
Anyways,
he's um,
he,
he's got this concept.
He works with a lot of these European
soccer teams and what he looks at is not
the seven to nine hours of sleep,
not how many hours of sleep per night
you get,
but the number of sleep cycles right
from stage one to stage five sleep that
you get throughout the course of the
week.
Meaning you're supposed to get 31 to 35
sleep cycles over seven days.
And so you might get three sleep cycles
one night and five sleep cycles and
other night.
And he also,
I haven't seen research to back this up,
but this is what he does with his
athletes.
His,
he counts a 20 to 30 minute power nap as
a sleep cycle,
so technically you could sleep four
hours night and then you could do a
eight hour sleep night on a Saturday and
a 20 minute nap on a Sunday and then you
add up all your sleep cycles and you can
use any self quantification device to if
you want to actually measure how many
times you're.
You're cycling during the during a night
of sleep and you look at that instead of
am I getting a consistent seven to nine
hours of sleep a night?
Look at the total sleep.
I,
I literally just wrote an article about
this this morning on my website.
You should listen to the podcast with
Matthew Walker because he's pretty in
depth about what is,
what's recommended and why and the risk
of Alzheimer's for people to get less
than five hours sleep a night and I'm
asleep.
But are you getting every night?
I am for 24 hour cycles,
getting about eight hours,
which means like if I sleep seven hours,
I take a 20 to 45 minute nap and that
sounds perfect.
I'm a big napper and my naps are very
elaborate.
Well,
you're also.
You work extremely hard.
Yeah,
I mean I'm not,
I'm,
I'm not working out as hard as some of
these pro athletes who are like 10 hours
of sleep per night Friday,
but for the average person,
oh,
these normatec boots that I lay in
these,
these great aided compression boots that
kind of move the compression from the
ankle all the way up to the hips and I
lay on this bio mat which is like laying
on a warm teddy bear.
It's like this map that makes infrared
rays,
so it's just like an infrared radiation
matt,
almost like a sauna.
And then I've got these,
these binaural binaural beat.
It's,
it's an artificial intelligence based
audio that confuses your brain and lulls
you into this.
This total state of relaxation.
It's called Brain FM.
So I lay on my back and I've got the
boots on and I have the mat on and I
notice every.
Now I'm sounding like a,
like a princess now,
but I have.
I have an assistant who lives at my
house and she really helps out with a
lot of stuff.
She does the banking and she helps out
with bringing stuff to the post office
and you know,
she's just,
she's just there whenever I need her to
do stuff and you know,
she helps.
She's back home with the kids right now,
so she just kind of like a live in
assistant and everyday about 1230 or
one,
she goes up to my bed,
she lays out the biomass,
she plugs it in and she pushed it on my
temperature.
She lays out the NORMATEC boots.
She pushed the pillow out with a sleep
mask and the headphones and then I just
go up there after lunch and I lay down
for about 45 minutes and I'm just dead
to the world.
That's a pretty sweet setup.
It's,
it's a good setup.
That's fine.
Live.
It's a good person like that that you
trust.
Yeah,
exactly.
It's crazy.
So the idea was sleep though is yeah,
if you,
if you nap and if you pay closer
attention to the number of sleep cycles
that you get each week,
I think that's more important than
getting like seven to nine hours a
night.
How would you know how many sleep
cycles?
Unless you're monitoring it,
you usually have or is that what you're
monitoring with?
Yeah,
he use when he's in the ring is pretty
accurate.
I mean it's a,
it's not as accurate as a sleep lab
study,
but it's,
it's accurate.
Kevin rose tried to get me to wear one
of those things.
Yeah,
big.
They've got another one that's smaller,
but
it seems very start the sentence like,
yeah,
exactly.
I need a lot of necklaces and Blaine to
go along with it.
But it works.
I found it in Finland like four years
ago and I bought it and I really have
been using it ever since.
It does like my sleep temperature.
Oh that's.
Yeah,
that's,
that's the littler one.
Smarter,
get more restorative whatever.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
The Mora.
Ooh.
I wish I'd have invested in the company
because they seem to be everywhere now
and and help.
They were there.
I was at a Finland of biohacking
conference and there was this tiny
little table with one guy at salon,
this little ring and all of a sudden
it's just like kind of diamond.
Are those diamonds?
I don't quit.
Is that light?
I don't know if they're real.
What's that?
Are they trying to say it's bling bling,
blitz diamond,
linking it up,
let them bitches know,
but it's kind of cool because you can
pull up your body temperature during the
night so a woman could use this to
tracker cycles.
It will tell you your heart rate
variability,
which I used to measure every morning
when I wake up,
I look at my parasympathetic and
sympathetic nervous system score and
then I'd be able to tell if I should do
a hard workout that day or each day.
Well now the range is.
It measures it all during the night like
it does with the five minute
measurements throughout the night while
I'm asleep so I wake up,
I can get a running average of my
guitars on your smartphone or.
And then it,
it pairs that with like how hard I
worked out the day before and my heart
rate,
my body temperature,
and then it tells me here's your
readiness score.
So if my readiness score is at like 60
percent,
then I'm going to go in the sauna and do
yoga.
Right.
And if my writing or scores had 90,
I'll do.
I'll go out and do the obstacle course
at my house and swinging bells and,
and beat up the body a little bit more.
So it's pretty useful because it ever
had 100.
I've never seen it.
100.
What would that mean?
Like why?
Why wouldn't it be better if I took a
two hour nap on the mat with the boots
and probably get to 100.
Those normatec boots,
they send them to me.
I sent it to my friend Cam Cameron
Hanes,
but he,
he runs a lot of you.
Have you seen for arm they haven't for
the arms and the hips to be like a giant
marshmallow man,
what does it do?
I would imagine if if you do a lot of
upper body activity,
like maybe you're a pitcher,
maybe a swimmer.
Yeah,
box or someone who's doing a lot of
upper body activity that the arms would
be efficacious.
Curtis,
yeah.
They look kind of silly and they're kind
of hard to get on by herself,
so I would be one more thing for my
assistant to have to help me with.
What is it doing?
Again,
it's graded compression,
so it's apparently a form of compression
that they've patented.
Unlike a lot of the other boots out
there to where it the first time it
inflates.
It measures the diameter of your limbs
and then bases every subsequent
compression to be customized to the
diameter or the girth of your limbs and
pump the blood.
In this case,
if you're wearing the feet or the
leggings from your ankles all the way up
to your hips,
you got a picture with him.
It was that Loma Chenko and those one of
those earlier pictures.
No,
it was another one earlier than that.
It works.
I mean your legs feel light as a
feather.
FGL used them.
Yeah.
And so this compression,
like as it's doing the compressing it,
what is it doing to the legs by just
compressed?
Just pumping.
It's pumping blood like up,
up and away from all the extremities
and,
and just moving it around.
Veterans at the idea?
No,
it's moving it back up to your heart.
Just circulating blood throughout your
body.
So it's almost like an additional heart.
It's like a massage,
like a massage,
but we'll know if it seems more hard is
not a pump then.
It's not like an additional.
The horseshoe.
Yeah.
Anyways though.
So it's,
they,
they work though and they're incredibly
relaxing.
It's,
it's almost like someone's massaging you
to do watch TV with.
Well you can kill two birds with one
stone.
Ooh.
Oh Wow.
He's got the full meal deal.
This guy has,
he's got legs on now.
This is a little bit it,
it could,
it could get expensive to do that
because now you've got to have to
inflation units rather than just one
because you can't plug them all in at
once.
So that's a spendy setup.
But that's the UFC featherweight
champion later.
Well,
if he's the UFC featherweight champ,
he can,
he can afford the Cadillac of
marshmallow man suits.
Well,
he's at Honolulu.
Cryotherapy getting his freak on.
That's what a lot of these crowd
therapy,
uh,
centers have noticed.
They've got the walking cryotherapy,
they've got the NORMATEC boots,
they've got the vibration platform so
you can lose weight while you're
standing there in the vibration
platform.
Yeah.
Learned a lot of fat.
What do you think about those things?
So it was um,
ultrasonic things,
you know,
I'm talking about what are those called?
Turbo Sonics.
You ever seen those verified vibration
platform that they go through like a
whole cycle?
Like they'll do it.
When I was in park city,
I did one of those.
Yeah.
Great Dude.
I had to go take a shit right after.
Seriously?
No,
I'm serious.
I was on that thing for like eight
minutes and I said,
excuse me,
and I had a glorious dump afterwards,
so I have,
I have,
uh,
a mini trampoline at my house and I jump
up and down on that thing in the
mornings and it gets everything moving.
Yeah.
That's like my one two combo for having
a really good dump in the mornings is
there's this herbal blend called try
Phala t r I p h a l a and I put about a
half teaspoon of that into a competent
super bitter.
So I put some Stevia in there or
something to sweeten it up a little bit
and I pour the hot water over that.
And you have that at night right before
I go to bed.
And you wake up in the morning and you
could use the vibration platform.
You could do the,
uh,
the Tai Chee bouncing.
That's another thing some people will
do.
We just kind of bounce up and down like
this script programming or you can,
you can jump on a trampoline,
probably skip rope too.
And that one,
two combo just gets things moving
amazingly.
Yeah.
I have a couple double espressos before
that too.
Yeah,
and I do.
I did a hot cup of coffee in the
morning.
I don't put anything in my coffee black,
but my.
My Protocol
for staying lean your rod is because I
used to be 215 pounds and I had to shut
a lot of weight to get into iron man
triathlon so that an iron man triathlon
for about eight years and the way that I
stayed lien for races.
You get up in the morning and have a cup
of coffee or green tea because both of
those can help to mobilize fatty acids
from adipose tissue and you do this when
you're in that fasted state that I was
talking about.
Right?
So you wake up after a 12 to 16 hour
fast and you take the cup of coffee or
the green tea.
Then you go exercise or move a
robotically for whatever time you have
available at 20 to 45 minutes.
Doesn't have to be that long and the
reason that you do at aerobically is
because when you wake up in the morning,
you already have a lot of cortisol in
your system,
right?
There's,
there's no need to just stress yourself
out even more by doing a very hard
workout.
I like to ease my way into the day.
I like a non stressful morning unless
I've got a very busy day and I know that
I'm not going to get hard work at any
other time.
I say my hard workout for the later
afternoon or early evening.
When your body temp peaks and your grip
strength peaks and your postworkout
reaction time or your post workout
protein synthesis peaks your,
uh,
your reaction time peaks like,
like your body is very equipped to do a
hard workout in the afternoon and the
evening more than it is in the morning.
Well,
the way you can really tell his Jujitsu,
my Jujitsu training in the morning,
I'm way weaker.
Just don't feel the same in the
afternoon.
You have much more energy.
Yeah,
exactly.
So the,
uh,
the idea is also when you do a hard
workout in the morning,
you get a lot of times postworkout
caloric compensation men and you just
want to eat everything in sight until
fricking lunch.
You're just,
you're just hungry.
And part of this probably physical
because you empty your glycogen stores
more quickly and part of it probably is
mental,
right?
Like I fucking punished it this morning.
I just,
uh,
deserve to,
you know,
have,
have a few extra slices of bread for
lunch.
So the,
uh,
the idea is I get up,
I do the coffee and then I'll do the 20
to 45 minutes of easy movement and that
might be the yoga in the sauna.
It'll be a walk in the sunshine.
So I'm getting my vitamin D and I'll do
like breath work,
you know,
where I'll breathe in through my nose
and do breath hold.
So I'm still kind of making my body
better,
but I'm not stressing it out with a lot
of east centric muscle tissue damage.
And then I finish up that whole session
with a cold shower.
So I'm getting a lot of those benefits
of white adipose tissue to Brown fat
conversion in the absence of any
inflammation,
right?
Inflammation and calories keep the white
fat from getting converted into Brown
fat,
which is what you want when you're doing
a cold shower,
a cold soak or some kind of cold
thermogenesis and I'm able to stay super
lean with that protocol.
You get up caffeine aerobics exercise in
a fasted state,
you finish up with a cold and I mean
even if you weren't working out,
you can stay pretty lean with that type
of protocol and this is what you did
specifically to try to lose weight to go
from when you were buying originally to
just shed muscle.
And then I would do really long
catabolic chronic cardio endurance
workouts,
which are not that great for you.
Right.
But I was just let you know,
I would go,
let's try a low rise.
Yeah,
yeah,
exactly.
Yeah.
So when you were doing this,
we,
you calorie restricting as well,
like take these.
Oh it's calorie restricting or you'd go
to bed at night and he'd be staring at
the ceiling hungry.
I guess it's,
yeah,
you're trying to lose weight,
right?
So your body start to weight ratio.
Your body starts eating yourself.
Now for these,
for these fasts and workouts,
if you are going to have facet hard
workout in the morning,
you can stay.
You can stay anabolic,
but relatively non insulinogenic without
spiking your blood glucose too heavily
with something like amino acids,
right?
So it's like a lot of people will do a
branch chain amino acid or an essential
amino acid.
You elevate your blood levels of amino
acids,
keeps you anabolic,
it allows you to stave off central
nervous system fatigue,
keeps you from shedding too much muscle
and you just spike your blood levels of
amino acids and then go into your
workout and you could even throw
something like ketones into the mix too.
So that's like a very hypo caloric way
to get a pre workout in without actually
getting a lot of calories.
And at the same time,
and we were talking before the podcast
about we were talking about different
athletes and diets and things on those
lines and you were saying that you don't
think it's good idea for a pro athlete,
particularly like a basketball player to
be on a Ketogenic ketogenic diet.
Yeah,
I,
I don't think that a strict ketogenic
diet is a good strategy.
I think that is cyclic ketogenic diet
would be the way to go for something
like that.
Yeah.
Zack bitter.
And that's exactly what I do is I'll eat
almost zero carbohydrates the entire
day.
Plants,
starches and fats.
I think I told you about my morning
smoothie you the last time I was on and
it's just,
you know,
like coconut milk and bone broth and
these precursors to nad,
which is another very,
very.
That probably next to stem cells is one
of the most potent anti aging protocols
that you can engage in.
Nad stands for.
I'll nicotinamide Adenine dinucleotide
is what that is.
And I can tell you about that in a
second after I.
I'll,
I'll just briefly tell you about the
cyclical ketogenic diet.
Basically,
it's all plants,
all fats,
no carbs or very low carbs the entire
day,
and then in the evening,
and this is where the beauty of that
scenario I talked about earlier fits in
because you've done your your hard
afternoon or early evening workout,
so your glute four transporters are very
upregulated.
You're very insulin sensitive in any
carbohydrates that you do eat are far
more likely to be shuttled into muscle
or liver glycogen rather than hanging
around the bloodstream causing
inflammation,
or rather than being shuttled to the
liver and converted into triglycerides,
you're basically using the carbohydrates
that you do eat at the end of the day to
sock away energy for the next day.
It's hard.
Glycolytic demanding workout,
right?
And so basically you're,
you're teaching your body how to be a
fat burning machine all day long.
You're restricting any amount of
glycemic variability all day long,
assuming you're not doing the
carnivorous diet because high amounts of
meat,
it's gluconeogenic.
It can spike blood glucose,
but you're essentially doing lots of
plants,
modern amount of fats and some amount of
protein but,
but not a crazy amount of protein all
day long.
And then with dinner,
you know,
we'll do just to make sourdough bread
and while the sweet potato fries and my,
you know,
my kids will make rice cakes,
we're dark chocolate,
red wine,
any of that stuff is all in the
evenings,
so that refills your glycogen stores for
anything explosive and demanding and
then you just rinse,
wash and repeat the next day.
So that's a cyclic ketogenic diet.
Now this is cyclic one individual 24
hour session,
but are you experiencing states of
Ketosis during the day?
Yeah,
absolutely.
Absolutely.
I,
so I have a device called a level in my
office,
L E v e l and it's a breath ketone
device.
It's just quicker and more convenient
than a blood stick.
It's also long term it,
it,
it's a good proxy.
It's a good approximation.
Lev,
Lev l there's another one called the
ketone x and you can get just like a,
you know,
a ketone monitor,
a blood ketone monitor.
Uh,
but if people don't want to do a blood
prick everyday,
I type,
I don't have the band aids on the
fingers when I'm trying to write things
on my lap.
It's just,
it's easier for me to just breathe into
a tube when I walk into my office.
I'm easily that's exact track and
adjust.
So weird how this has become such a
massive part of culture these days is
measuring your ketones.
Just constantly hear people talking
about and it's so fatty fad now,
you know?
Yeah,
I get it.
It was funny that he,
uh,
anyway,
I mean it,
I just said it and I had to explain what
I was saying because it sounded weird to
me anyways though.
The,
uh,
the cyclic ketogenic diet allows you to
be back in the state of Ketosis by that
morning easily.
And then you just basically maintained
that all day long.
Then you refuel and carbohydrates at the
end of the day.
Uh,
and then there was another question that
you asked about nad that's something
completely different but that,
but that's the cyclical ketogenic diet
works.
So your body having those carbohydrates
at night knocks you out of Ketosis,
right when you're,
when you're eating the bread and your
blood glucose will rise,
you're not going to be shuttling a lot
of Acetol Coa,
which is the precursor to ketones and
ketone generation and then you're going
through a 16 hour fasting,
but then you have a 12 to 16 hour fast
and he said,
I couldn't get up.
You do the fasted morning aerobic
workout,
a cold shower,
a little bit of coffee or green tea and
it's a perfect scenario.
PTOSIS works perfectly.
I'm telling you,
you,
you start your day off like that and
then you end your day with the
carbohydrates as a hard afternoon
workout.
That easy morning workout and it like
for,
for metabolism,
for body composition,
uh,
for,
for maintaining fitness,
for teaching yourself how to be a fat
burning machine will still refilling the
body of carbohydrates stores.
It's a beautiful scenario.
Also.
I just think there's some,
there's some benefit in enjoying what
you eat to not constantly worrying about
your glucose levels and ketones and all
that stuff.
I mean,
I,
I don't think there's anything wrong
with having a little bread or a pasta or
something like this.
There's nothing wrong with it and that,
I mean,
it's also my beef with,
uh,
with the carnivore diet is,
you know,
I like sweet potato fries and I like,
I like cauliflower
rice and I like,
you know,
all sorts of different plants and
vegetables.
Now this,
um,
this nad you can get these injections or
ivs now and it is something that
enhances your own stem cell
proliferation,
but it is one of the most potent anti
aging molecules you can put into your
body in terms of decreasing the rate at
which your telomeres shorten.
So you've probably heard a lot of these,
sir,
two enriched foods like blueberries and
Cacao and chocolate and resveratrol and
a lot of them work.
But the most powerful of any of these as
nad nad to Nadh ratio is highly
reflective of your telomere health.
And these are the most horribly painful
and uncomfortable injections or ivs you
would ever get in your life.
You can,
you can do it orally.
There's a,
there's a capsule,
there's companies like elise,
a nitrogen that sell nr.
Take that stuff.
Nicotinamide,
nicotinamide riboside.
It's a precursor to Nad,
but it doesn't hold a candle to just
mainlining it into your bloodstream.
And how do you get it?
We're going to do.
So one way to do it is in a medical
clinic,
you can get a six to eight hour ivy
bringing a laptop and you work away.
And some people do this on a monthly
basis,
just six to eight hours of.
It's a long drip.
Um,
you know,
they have some of the guys down at on
it,
do it,
and they'll have a nurse come in and
push a little bit more quickly.
That's like an hour long.
Uh,
Ivy has it.
Just do it short like that.
It's way more uncomfortable.
The shore you get,
the more uncomfortable it gets because
you're pushing this stuff into your
bloodstream more quickly.
And it feels like your whole body is on
fire.
I mean,
you have to box breath and close your
eyes and meditate.
Painful.
It's,
it's like if you ever done dmt DMT,
but you're on fire and getting punched
in the gut at the same time and you feel
like your heart's going to explode and
then you finish and you feel like
superman.
You feel like you have more energy on
less sleep.
Your workouts are better.
I mean,
it's one of the,
it's like fish oil where when you take a
bunch of fish oil,
you just kind of keep your fingers
crossed that it's working.
It's not like you can feel fish oil and
you want to go destroy the world.
Um,
it's even better than black ant extract.
So there's,
you can get it to you.
So I get it shipped to my house and I do
a self administered push ivy.
I do the same thing with Myers
cocktails.
So I just shove a butterfly needle into
my vein and then I push this nad and
very,
very slowly.
And you can even chase it with a myers
cocktail which enhances the
effectiveness of it.
Meaning you can do like a,
an Nid.
And this is a common protocol and lot of
anti aging clinics are a lot of,
you know,
like a alternative health clinics as you
do the Nad injection and you follow it
up with a myers cocktail and you feel
like superman admires,
that's just vitamins,
vitamin infusion,
it's ivy infusion of vitamin B and
sometimes they'll nootropics and they're
like lithium and stuff like that.
It's too much to remember,
man.
Oh.
But it's.
So you had a.
I'm a complete idiot about anything
except health and nutrition and fitness.
That's how like,
I don't know,
I don't watch TV and,
and uh,
I don't follow politics or anything like
that.
I just studied.
Keep the poison out.
Yes,
exactly.
It's like Sherlock Holmes and Watson
tells us him him his name and he says
I'm going to work hard to forget that
because he doesn't want anything
cluttering up his head at all.
Right.
Aside from his sleuthing.
So is there an nad place in la where I
could go and do this?
Yes,
there I was speaking with somebody
yesterday about this and he asked me if
I could find a clinic and I found one in
Beverly Hills and uh,
it's probably an one of the long ivy,
so you'll want to wait till we have some
computer work to do and you can sit on
your laptop and just kind of get stuff
done six to eight hours or you can just
listen to Paul,
you can,
you can push it in and about 15 to 20
minutes and you can have a nurse
practitioner do this.
And then there are some clinics that
will do,
it's called a push ivy and nad push ivy.
So beneficial.
Just more painful.
I'm doing this once a week now and it's
painful 10 to 20 minutes of my entire
week,
but you feel amazing.
And I'm,
I'm testing my telomere length with this
company called Tello years.
They say there's another one,
I forget the name of the other company
that tests your telomere length.
There's only a couple out there.
So it tests the rate at which your
telomeres are shortening.
And the two things that have had the
most profound effect on my results from
that test have been the stem cell
injections intravenously and the Nad
injections,
my biological age right now,
which started off at an age of 37 when I
was 34 and then decreased to 35 when I
tested again at 36 years old.
I just tested it 37 years old and my
biological age is 20 in terms of the
rate at which my telomeres are
shortening.
And the only two things that have
changed have been the stem cell
injections and the Nad injections.
So me and biological age,
you can reverse your biological age.
Now there is some side effects.
No,
like,
so the telomere test is a test of your
white blood cell telomere length,
which is not reflective of every cell in
your body.
Right?
So,
so technically,
uh,
it's,
it's not like a,
it's not an ironclad test with a ton of
research behind it,
but it's an approximate corollary to
your biological age.
It's the best we have right now to be
able to test telomere length.
But I'm not going to pretend like it's
a,
it's a,
it's a gold standard test and I'm not
aware of a gold standard test for
telomere length,
but I can tell you that I feel amazing
and that telomere length is shortening.
And those Nad injections just make you
feel like superman.
So do you think it's a combination of
the things or do we,
would you attribute it more to the Nad
is the problem with this shit?
I do,
Dude.
He's just so many different things.
Yeah.
And there's.
And there's stuff you can do to enhance
your own endogenous stem cell
production.
We were talking about meat and I told
you about that study with the.
We were talking about the carnosine and
the blueberry extract.
That's one of chlorella is another
colostrum is fantastic for that,
for endogenous stem cell health.
Coffee Berry fruit extract.
That's another really fascinating one.
And you can buy that on Amazon as a
powder.
And I put a lot of this stuff in my
morning smoothie now.
So when I wake up,
you know,
I've got Chlorella,
I've got Dha,
I've got this,
uh,
this stuff called Howdy Arco Bark Tea,
which also enhances your own nad
production,
a colostrum,
bone broth,
vitamin C to enhance the bone broth
uptake.
So you can kind of make yourself a
little,
a little cocktail of ingredients that
you just take in the morning without
necessarily spending,
you know,
8,000
bucks on a stem cell and extraction and
injections.
Have you thought about like having some
sort of an online thing where people
could subscribe to a protocol and you
would,
you know,
what I thought about doing was just
making like a,
like a,
a supplement or something like that
where you can take all this stuff and
just combine it into a shake or into
some kind of a supplement.
So I'm just going to buy out or
something.
And I mean some,
some people who don't understand the
supplement industry or formulation to,
well,
why don't you just put all this stuff in
a capsule,
but I mean,
you,
one compound can decrease the
absorbability of the other compound or
you know,
one compound will create an aesthetic or
an alkaline scenario in which the other
one doesn't work well.
So it would require a lot of testing.
But ultimately,
you know,
at this point I just blend it all in a
blender and kind of keep my fingers
crossed and dump it all into my big
biggest mug.
And it seems like,
you know,
someone like you who knows so much about
this stuff,
it would be a great resource if people
could subscribe to something and you
guys could put together some sort of a
protocol for people that would fall.
They could follow it on a daily basis
and you know,
you're creating more work for me.
Uh,
yeah,
but,
but it would,
the problem is genetic variability,
right?
Like this whole high fat diet.
And,
uh,
you know,
I saw yesterday that you tweeted out a,
uh,
you know,
my friend Nina Teicholz is,
data,
you know,
encouraging the high saturated fat
intake and I love her and I love her
approach and I love the idea that she is
getting a lot of people,
you know,
via the lobbying to focus less on grains
and high carb diet,
which I think is helpful for a lot of
people.
But at the same time there are,
there are genes are like the PPA,
our one alpha gene,
which would cause a little bit of an
inflammatory response to high intake of
fats or to a lot of saturated fats
without a lot of poly or mono
unsaturated fats there.
I think the last time that we talk,
we talked about familial
hypercholesterolemia,
right?
Where some people,
if they shift to a Kenogenic or a high
fat diet,
it screws them from a metabolic
standpoint because they get not only
high cholesterol but you know,
high particle count and,
and oxidation of that cholesterol.
Um,
there's,
uh,
there's ways around that,
you know,
for example,
like a catava and diet would be what
you'd consume if you were,
if you were eating or if you had this
familial hypercholesterolemia where he'd
eat a lot of tubers and fish and coconut
meat and wild plants and that's
technically like a 70 to 80 percent
carbohydrate based diet.
Now with a lot of grains,
you know,
now with a lot of junk food.
But that would be a diet more
appropriate for someone with that issue.
Um,
someone with a PPA,
our Jane issue,
they'd want to eat less of the coconut
oil and the butter and the cheeses and
more of like the Avocados and the extra
virgin olive oil and more of the
Mediterranean diet approach.
You know,
I mentioned earlier that the,
the fact that coconut oil and a lot of
these saturated fats and a lot of people
are inflammatory,
so they would want to eat a lot of,
a lot of antioxidants and flavonols and
polyphenol rich,
small,
non sugary berries and dark leafy
Greens.
And so again,
you could have a subscription based
service that teaches people a lot of
these things,
but then once again,
you got to have either artificial
intelligence that screening each person
to look at what they actually need or
you've got a real person talking to each
person looking at their labs and saying,
okay,
this is the one that would work well for
you.
Rather than just saying,
okay,
this,
this has been smoothie,
everybody should be drinking this.
Right?
Yeah.
I went to this one thing once where they
monitored my blood and I abandoned it
immediately because they told me I
shouldn't have avocados.
I'm like,
what are you talking about?
Igg Food Allergy tests.
And the problem is that you produce a
lot of these immunoglobulins to foods
that you eat a lot,
so people will be of eggs and they do
this test and they walk out depressed
with their tail between their legs
because they can't have avocados and
eggs anymore.
And it's because they were eating a shit
ton of Avocados and eggs.
The DM,
right?
Yeah.
There's one called the Cyrex food
allergy panel.
It's a little more.
You don't get this huge laundry list of
foods that give you false positives.
It's a pretty accurate test that I use.
Knew it was nonsense.
It was like,
I feel great.
I eat Avocados all the time.
This can be anything other than
nonsense.
Yeah,
well,
it's not nonsense.
I mean they should immunoglobulin
reaction to Avocados and there's no
bodies in the streets.
No evidence that that's going to
actually are you.
That's the problem.
It's just you would have to go on some
sort of a very neutral diet for a long
period of time.
Get your body's baseline established
exactly at your blood work,
done whatever rice for a month and then
get it taken proteins at all and even
then,
what would that do?
Probably do like a wash out like a five
day fast and that's that.
That new valter,
Longo longevity diet is you do,
I think it's five over the know once a
quarter,
five day fast,
right?
To clean you out to get all the benefits
of cellular autophagy and with that
particular diet.
I was talking before about how long term
calorie restriction is bad for you,
you know,
and this whole idea of intermittent
fasting with caloric restriction creates
hormone deficits and associated with
gallstones and all sorts of nasty things
happen to your body when you don't give
it enough calories.
What about long term?
Like you know when people go into those
five day fast like Dom D'agostino,
valter,
Longo,
his approach is you do a five day fast
just a few times a year and I think in
in active individuals,
athletes,
he only recommends like two or three
times a year Max that you do this five
day fast and you put it in an off season
or recovery phase or some period of time
where you're not training heavily and
that scenario would allow you to get a
lot of the cellular autophagy and the
cleanup benefits and theoretically you
could do that,
right?
And then go get your food allergy tests
and see what kind of proteins are
floating around your brain and you're
doing a 24 hour fast.
How often?
What works for me because I don't do
well,
not even for five days,
I'm too active.
Like I just have too much shit going on.
Oh,
like there aren't many times during the
year when I could point out a five day
slot in my schedule where I'm not
hunting or competing or working out or
doing something that requires me to need
calories or outside.
I'm just going to.
I'm already skinny,
like I can't go for a long time without
eating and my metabolism is sky high.
So what I do is a 12 to 16 hour fast
every day.
Not a calorically restricted fast,
but just 12 to 16 hours without eating
every single day.
On the lower activity days I'd taken
less protein and restricted meat.
That's one of the days where I'm not
beating up my body too much and like a
Wednesday and a Sunday,
which are more recovery days.
Those were the days when I do,
you know,
fricken.
I close myself love days or like I do
clay masks and coffee enemas and
infrared therapy like.
So I'm still.
So for,
for,
for upregulating,
your own glutathione production,
your biopsy,
you feel clean as a whistle plus it's
the best way to get coffee up your,
but there's no other way that you do.
You do get a lot of caffeine absorption
to know.
But I'm,
I'm seriously,
if you've never done something like that
and experienced what it feels like to
just be completely cleaned out,
it's a pretty good feeling towards the
duty of the coffee enema not only cleans
out your colon,
but it causes your liver and your
gallbladder,
gallbladder specifically to increase
bile production.
It upregulate your glutathione
production,
your indulgence,
Buddha,
fire and production.
And so you're increasing your production
of antioxidants.
And it also causes Paris dialysis while
she just moved stuff through.
That's kind of moving slowly.
So once a week,
Wednesday mornings I get up,
uh,
my,
my wife makes coffee every morning and
have her make an extra pot as leave that
out on the counter until it gets to room
temperature.
And normally when I'm drinking my
coffee,
I'm going through all my morning
research and articles and everything
down in my.
I have a standing desk in the basement,
but instead I go in,
I,
I lay on my right side,
on the bathroom floor and I keep
coughing in there for about 20 minutes
while I'm working and then I get up and
you just let it all out and you lay on
your coffee and your.
But I get a stainless steel animal
bucket,
so plastics,
so you're not injecting classics up your
butt and then you had.
It's about a quarter,
so have coffee in the back side with
this tube.
It's a lot of coffee,
Jesus.
And then you lay on your right side for
20 minutes and then you get up and you
let it all out and,
and of course I have the squatty potty
so it comes up more easily.
Of course,
you know of that kink in your photos and
everything comes out and you just,
you walk away just like whistling with a
big smile on your face.
That's squatty potty is legit.
I feel wonderful.
It's,
it probably works really should be
getting into a hole in the ground when I
don't have one.
I perch my best dumps.
So when I'm hunting or camping or on the
toilet,
you hold onto a tree and you kinda do it
like a dog person and it's perfect.
So.
So on those days that I'm doing coffee
enemas or sauna or any weird woo woo,
things that don't involve workouts,
I do protein restriction because I'm not
beating up my body that much.
Coffee Enema doesn't cause a lot of east
centric muscle tissue damage unless
you've done something horribly wrong.
So I basically have those days as my
lower protein days and then once a week,
and this would be,
unless I'm traveling because it's harder
to doing travel.
I do a 24 hour fast Saturday at dinner,
you stop eating,
sleep all night.
All he gotta do is skip breakfast on
Sunday and skip lunch on Sunday and then
have dinner on Sunday night and that's
pretty easy to do.
And so I get the benefits of the longer
fast.
Right?
Because a lot of those cellular
autophagy and endogenous stem cell
production benefits don't kick in until
you're about 16 hours in.
Right?
So I get that benefit once a week even
though for me really it comes out to
about twice a month that I'm actually at
home because I travel so much,
doing that full 24 hour fast and I do a
lot of work that day.
I play with my kids,
I just feel things in throughout that
day to keep my appetite satiated.
And sometimes they'll do some of those
new ketone esters and sometimes we'll do
some amino acids or you know,
a cup of bone broth doesn't count as
breaking your fast kind of sword of
cheating.
But it's,
it's,
it's like it's a speed bump for a
skinny,
you know,
high metabolism guy like me to have like
a cup of 40 calorie bone broth in the
middle of the day.
The bone broth fast.
The ketone esters also break your fast.
They're a caloric.
Yeah.
I'm technically,
you know,
from,
from just a pure,
you know,
very simple physiology standpoint.
Your body would need to utilize those
ketones for energy before it would,
you know,
turn some of your own Acetol Coa,
a derived from your fat into extra
ketones.
But I just liked the way I feel on
fasting using these,
these especially like the newer ketone
esters in the case on why aren't you
supposed to take them with glucose?
No,
no,
no.
You are going to get a huge performance
advantage by taking them with glucose,
but that's also,
uh,
it,
it's,
it's an ancestrally inappropriate state
for the human body to have
simultaneously elevated levels of blood
glucose and elevated levels of blood
ketones because traditionally we'd have
elevated our blood ketones through
fasting and while I'm okay with
elevating blood key tones via a non
ancestral roots,
such as the consumption of these ketone
esters designed by the US Department of
Defense for soldiers in battle,
they have to go two or three days
without eating or for Tour de France
riders have been using them for awhile.
The idea of consuming glucose along with
those ketones and spiking blood glucose,
which can have a little bit of an
inflammatory oxidative effect,
is not something I would do unless I
were like in a race or in a really hard
demanding workout.
That's where something like that you
can,
you can use like rocket fuel and that's
actually a very good mix,
some kind of like a fruit dose,
Maltodextrin blend,
which the gatorade sports science
institute has shown allows you to get a
really high absorption of carbohydrates
rather than,
you know,
just Maltodextrin or just glucose or
just fruit dose.
Then you add in Ketone esters on top of
that and then to stave off what's called
central nervous system fatigue,
the crossing of trip to fan into the
brain,
which kind of makes you feel,
you know,
Turkey dinner,
sleepy effect during exercise.
You throw essential amino acids into
that,
so you've got amino acids,
ketones and glucose,
and that mix is just pure rocket fuel.
Yeah.
You talked about that last time you said
it was like being on steroids that
having glucose in your system with
ketones.
It's just fucking crazy.
Yeah.
It's,
it's,
it's pretty amazing.
Now when you go on these fast,
if you drink coffee,
does coffee break your fast coffee or
the consumption of anything from a
circadian biology,
right?
Twenty four hour circadian rhythm.
You've,
you've got multiple Circadian Rhythm Qs,
one is movement,
so when you travel and you're jet
lagged,
movement helps you normalize your
biological clock.
Another is light,
right,
so exposure to high amounts of morning
sunlight or using one of these new
fangled hacking devices like the,
like the light or the in Ir Light,
that's another circadian q eating or
really the consumption of anything.
Supplements,
coffee,
tea,
etc.
That's also a circadian q.
There's a researcher dr satchin panda,
who's got some really good research on
circadian rhythmicity and what he says
is that the consumption of anything can
disrupt circadian biology.
If you're fasting for the purposes of
regulating your circadian rhythms,
maybe you've got insomnia,
poor sleep patterns,
inflammation due to lack of sleep or
lack of the glymphatic drainage and
consolidation of memory and everything
that occurs during deep sleep.
Your sleep is more or less fucked up,
right?
Like that would be a situation in which
you just wouldn't want to eat anything
during a fast.
But if you're fastest for the purposes
of,
let's say like fat loss or even some of
you know,
like the endogenous stem cell production
benefits of fasting and a caloric cup of
coffee is not going to cause any issues.
And furthermore,
if you're concerned about like the
cholesterol is in the coffee,
use the paper filter because you're
going to filter out most of the
cholesterol as well versus like a french
press or you know,
or steel filter.
Yeah.
What about water?
Water I think is completely allowed.
Now there are some people who do dry
fasting,
a that will be popular for people who
have like candida or yeast or fungi.
They would claim that a moist
environment would allow the bacteria to
flourish.
And so some of those people will do dry
fasting.
I know a guy who does dry fasting with
autologous urine therapy where he does
dry fast in the morning,
he drinks his urine and.
And that's some old ayurvedic cleanse
techniQue that I,
I don't personally,
we were trying.
I did
Try it.
It,
I try to do it.
Yeah.
It doesn't make sense.
It's not sort of the best.
Yeah,
actually the temperature got to me more
than the taste,
just like the warm hotness,
just it felt from the tactile to alive.
Yeah,
it was just,
it was.
So ultimately the coffee is not an issue
unless you're putting a bunch of stuff
in it.
Right.
and then even though it is admittedly
noninsulin agentic and it's actually
quite a kick in the pants,
as you know,
you know when you blend fats with
coffee,
you get the cough,
a stall on the hallway,
all they cross the blood brain barrier,
they amp you up psychologically.
You're also getting.
Your body has to burn those calories
before it burns a lot of its own
calories.
So that's not something you would do.
You would do well on a facet.
Stayed bent.
I to wrap this up,
you,
uh,
you're always a minD.
Fuck dude.
Every time you come in here I have to
pauSe after the podcast and try to like
capture little bits of information.
Now.
That's pretty much my main takeaway from
the Past couple of hours as I want.
I want to freaking steak,
tell people how they can get to your
website.
Tell people how they can watch your
videos.
Go read this article.
I just.
It's.
It's good.
Ben greenfield fitness.com,
or just google.
Ben greenfield and social media has ben
greenfield.
You just look,
there's not a lot of us.
Benjamin greenfields out there and find
the benjamin greenfield.
You're bad,
motherfucker.
Appreciate man.
Thanks for coming in.
As was officer,
everybody.