Oh Shit,
we go back from our entry hall,
from another country.
What up man?
What's up,
brother?
Good to see you,
man.
Yeah,
man
was in Montreal comedy festival.
Uh,
first of all,
Canada is right there.
Yeah.
But it's such a hard country to get
into.
It's very hard to get into.
It's crazy.
Yeah.
They don't want any douche bags.
They have a zero douche bag policy.
But.
But listen,
I saw the ex mayor of Montreal right in
walking down sunset in front of the
comedy store.
The one that was on crack,
right?
Is that the Toronto Gang?
The Toronto Board.
You saw that guy or that guy?
One day walking by the comedy store and
everybody took pictures with him and he
was the mayor and he did crack.
There's a tape of it.
Right.
So how the fuck did he get here?
But Canada won't even take a drunk
driver from us.
That's true.
Well,
I think I'm crack you probably better
driver when you're on crack.
He just more expeditious he get things
done.
Yeah.
That's a
like if you,
if you commit a crime,
you can't get into Canada.
If you have a Dui,
like Patrice had a dui on,
he had,
well not patrice,
but I know people that have duis that
can get into Canada.
Oh yeah.
Super Common.
Like work on it.
You can't work there.
You can't get in there and can't get up
there.
Sagan,
jts.
He can't get up there and get up there.
But he's got like some real shit.
Right?
He's got some real shit.
Armed kidnapping.
But that's why I say Dui because even
though Dui is a serious,
the ones where you get convicted but you
do your probation period and you,
you know,
you,
you get your license back,
you even when you get your license back,
you can't get into Canada.
But somebody who was the mayor and sold
crack and I know other Canadians that
probably committed crimes can be in
here.
Like why the fuck is this so tough for
me to get into Canada?
And when I got to the airport they uh,
I've been to Canada before.
So when I got to the airport they have
to try to fill out some immigration form
and it's three hours.
It was like two and a half hours early.
Thank God.
Then they want me to fill out this form
on my phone online.
It's like 40 something questions like
online is the new way to do it.
This a new way to do it?
Well again,
I got a British passport so everybody
that was just had a straight American
passport went in.
How does that work?
You have like a Jamaican passport.
Is that what it is now?
I've got a British one because I was
from England.
From England.
Yeah.
And so now when you're in a America from
England,
like how does it work?
They give you like a have a green card
so you're not a full American citizen.
Like a permanent place.
Certain Shit with you.
Why not?
Because it didn't like treasonous
careful.
I gotta be careful you from another
land,
another nation.
Robert,
I'm here.
It's not odd.
I mean that's really odd.
Like here,
here's a perfect example.
Perfect example.
I didn't know that you were born in.
If you told me I forgot,
right.
He probably forgot.
I probably will forget.
We forget about each other.
We'll especially that kind of fact is it
doesn't mean anything doesn't mean
anything,
but like automatically,
like in the grand scheme of things I'm
supposed to look at you like,
Oh,
you're on the other team here.
You can be one of those embedded people
I just read about these Russians,
Russians in New Jersey.
Did you hear about this anymore?
Do you not trusting English people
either anymore.
The Russians were in a,
uh,
wanna say Montclair,
like a nice area of New Jersey and uh,
they were uh,
a regular family.
This,
the Russian fan,
but there weren't really this regular
family.
They were actually embedded Soviet
spies.
Well,
that sounds like the American.
Look at that shit.
Russian spies,
New Jersey home heading for sale.
Damn,
don't buy that house.
What the fuck?
I want somebody to watch you.
Fuck with my money and shit in there.
There's gonna be cameras that watch the
shit come out of your asshole.
It was probably cameras everywhere.
They would watch the shit.
Come on,
man.
You can't get a Russian house from some
Russian spies.
You gotta be like a crazy person.
You might find some hidden spaces with
money I shouldn't have made me feel like
a total failure.
What does he said?
He said that he doesn't expect the
Russian spy connection to help or hurt
the sale.
Bitch,
you're out of your fucking mind.
I mean,
that's not the worst thing that can
happen to a house.
It's just a bunch of spies.
Nobody's.
Hopefully nobody was murdered in the
house,
but when someone's murdered in the
good luck selling that house.
You can get the PR,
you get price down,
you're better off just burning to the
ground,
smash in that thing and then rebuilding
a new house and even then people don't
want to live there because that's where
the old house where the dude got killed.
Used to be.
Let me ask you about how old is your
house?
It's a brand new person in there.
No,
no,
no.
I think it was made in the seventies,
Seventies.
Do you know if anybody was murdered or
died?
There?
A.
I've never seen a ghost so I have to
inform you,
but there's a moratorium.
What's that website?
You can look it up.
I just heard about it.
I'm not sure that that was going to ask
you if you heard,
if you knew about it,
a website where you find out somebody
died in your house when it was.
He had like a.
do you remember that?
That this one always got to me,
man,
that um,
those brothers that shot their commands,
Mendez brothers.
So one of them had a wig on remembering
it.
This glorious fake head of hair.
They may take it off when he went to
jail.
It was really crazy story because they
shotgunned their own parents.
Whoa,
man.
How the fuck does that happen to the one
on the left to one of them has a total
wig.
I mean,
you,
you look at it,
you go,
oh,
I get it.
Now.
The one on the right was just blessed.
Just straight
up.
Blessed with curly locks.
So various.
What the fuck man.
Those,
those,
those sons shotgun.
They're fucking parents,
man.
Do you know Kirk Fox used to teach them
tennis?
Oh,
that's right.
That's right.
I do.
Somehow vaguely remember that he has a
whole story about teaching them tear
tennis to.
That scares the shit out of me that
people could do.
That doesn't scare the shit out of me
nearly as much as people can get so
angry at someone that they could shoot
them,
but it scares the shit out of me that
someone could do that to their dad and
their mom to written.
They shoot the mom to Jesus.
We're adopted,
right?
Where they.
Yeah,
I think the Menendez brothers were
adopted.
Oh yeah.
And I think.
I think they're just trying to get
money.
Oh,
what is that?
Sexual and psychological abuse that had
suffered at the hands of their parents.
Oh,
well,
there you go.
I know.
It's like you always want immediately
blamed it on the kids.
Right?
Because they killed their parents,
but the parents could have been fucking
monsters.
Yeah.
You never know.
Oh,
well,
it's got.
They have to be monsters.
I mean,
if you think about it,
how do you make a kid that is capable of
shooting you in your sleep?
You gotta be you gotTa.
Raise that kid horribly.
Unless you just by dumb luck,
have to complete genetic psychopath from
birth that you could have done nothing
to fix.
You've got two guys that are willing to
shoot you while you're sleeping and you
raise them from the time they were
babies.
That's crazy.
Anyway,
I was going to say their house.
Yeah.
I wondered what happened to their house.
Burnt that fucking thing to the ground.
Probably.
I wonder what happened to it.
Like Nicole Simpson's house still there
for somebody lived there.
Wasn't Nicole Simpson's?
Was that a house or was that outside of
my apartment building or Condo?
Yeah.
Damn man,
that's a weird one because that's like,
it's a public building.
You got to just deal with it.
People just deal with it.
Is that apartment like still empty hers
that he killed them on the street.
He killed them outside,
but every time you go home you have to
step over a crime scene to walk into
your house and you've seen the pictures.
Yeah.
You know the history.
Every time Oj documentary comes out or
every time they have an Oj series on tv
or when his a parole hearing comes up,
you're like,
but a doorway into the house.
So I wonder if like I want to talk to
the person who's like,
doesn't give a fuck and listen that
motherfucker,
you know what I'm saying?
Like a deal's a deal.
Baby Sprint would listen.
She should have been nicer dorm.
Did you ever see the autopsy photos?
Uh,
did.
I don't know if you haven't,
don't.
It's not worth it.
You get it.
I saw the murder scene photos.
It's just so hard to believe that
someone could do that to someone that
was pretty scared about it.
They had babies with just people get
crazy game of thrones out here,
but just rarely.
That's what it is.
It's like every week it's the game of
thrones normal on the game of thrones,
which I just started watching in the.
Yeah,
I didn't know what the fuck was going
on,
man.
I started watching this new season.
I was like,
I forgot everything.
I've started watching it like a few
months ago.
I started watching it over from the
beginning,
every that's what you should do,
watch it from season one and you see how
much stuff you didn't know or didn't
understand or didn't realize and
[inaudible] game of thrones,
they don't give a fuck.
Like they'll introduce a new character
and having talking to a regular
character like they'd been talking for
awhile and you're like,
did I miss something?
Exactly.
But then if you go back,
you know,
now that guy is new,
I'm not supposed to know them and you've
got homework,
you've got to do research to understand
that show.
Well this,
these kinds of shows have kind of
stopped my interest in movies like
movies are okay,
but a movie is 90 minutes or two hours.
It's over.
When it's over know I'm done,
but these goddamn things get you in
faster.
Like I'm not like,
what is this?
A nerd HPO hacked upcoming episodes,
game of thrones data leaked online poll.
What you look at it.
So the results like the scripts that
they mean by data shows.
Oh No,
actual.
Oh No.
Some other shows got taken to.
Oh yeah,
they should just edit offline.
Oh my goodness.
Monsters.
How dare you.
Careful.
Yeah,
some Wizkid,
right?
Probably from China,
something like that.
So yeah,
we can't compete anymore.
Russia kicking everybody out of Russia
hear about that shit.
They are all the people that are working
at the embassy.
70 five American delegates or whatever
they would be called.
I'm sure they are happy to go home.
Yeah,
like Russia out of here.
Unless they got something going on.
Yeah.
Got some crazy fake Russian life over
there.
Just like the people in Montclair.
Seven hundred 55,
755 diplomats.
What does that mean?
We're going to war with Russia.
No,
come on man.
They've got mom in Montclair,
right?
They've got a house.
People just live in there.
What happened to those people in that
house?
Did they kick them out and put them in
jail?
I think they put them in jail.
Go back to that story like how did they
find out they were spies?
That's a good question,
man.
That's a real good question.
Just went to the house sale like,
well,
give me some.
Give me some explanation here.
Yo.
It says their story partially inspired
the fx drama,
the Americans to undercover Russian
spies living in the U.
s with two young children.
That's a fucking amazing show,
isn't really the Americans is so fucking
amazing.
Really?
Yeah,
man.
What's it on front of the Vladimir in
Lydia.
How do you say that name?
Gerta.
You have
led the merely in Lydia and lived in the
home in Montclair.
Under the name of Richard and Cynthia
Murphy.
Hi,
we're Richmond.
Cynthia Murphy.
Hi.
I wondered what,
what they talked like before they
arrested in 2010 along with eight other
spies accused of leading double lives,
complete with false passports,
secret code words,
fake names,
invisible ink and encrypted rate.
Invisible ink.
Dude.
What kind of weird ass life is that?
It's weird to think that there's someone
that could be a spy in your neighborhood
and that he thinks that you're the enemy
because you were born over here and he
was born over there.
You know,
just like what we were talking about
with you having a passport from England,
but what's in Jersey that they live in
Jersey and doing this shit like who are
they?
Close to?
Well,
Jersey,
close to New York,
first of all,
and there's a lot of very wealthy people
that live in Montclair.
I believe.
Montclair's a very nice area.
Google that should be.
My uncle used to have a pottery studio,
a pottery studio in the Montclair.
That is,
that is some rich white shit.
Well it was more like a hippie artist
stuff.
He's an art teacher who used to teach
art in,
uh,
in,
in school.
I don't think it was.
I think highschool.
What's up?
How do I look that up?
Like Montclair New Jersey.
Um,
what's that word?
They use?
Medium income.
Yeah,
look up that.
I think it's a baller place.
I think it's like Beverly Hills.
It's like the Beverly Hills of New
Jersey.
Maybe I'm exaggerating.
Hundred Sixty,
3000.
That's a lot of money for the,
the average,
that probably means that most people the
ratio and perhaps.
Yeah,
there's probably a lot of rich this one.
Poor rich person that brought that price
down.
It's maybe.
Why do you think they do it?
Okay,
let's,
let's take a guess.
Do you think they sneak in?
They become spies.
They get tight with rich people and then
you know like look,
I know a family that had ted fucking
cruise over their house for some event
that we're holding like a year or so
before the election,
maybe two years before the election.
Like these people were so baller.
They had ted Cruz give like one of those
stupid stump speeches in their house
for,
for money is raised to raise money to
raise money.
They're like big pro Israel supporters
that Ted Cruz in their house talking
about Israel.
Very trippy shit.
Like very trippy shit.
Like you're,
you're literally hanging out in your
house with a guy that might be running
the nukes,
right?
Yeah.
Like,
so if you're a Russian spy and you can
get tight with that dude,
you can hang out with that dude.
Hey Frank is a tanker.
Was really coming over with.
I'll tell you what,
it makes a lot of sense.
There's a lot of his policies that are
real.
I'm really agreeing when you just call
up the Russian embassy,
send me some money so I can throw in a
and get close at that cruise and you
just bring in a truckload of Vietnamese
hookers.
Just out
Ted.
All fucked up on that same method.
Rob Ford had solar can just get the
party role and start filming.
We need to know.
Start having a black male info on Ted
Cruz.
We need to know.
We can count on you.
Everybody keeps getting fired from the
White House.
Does anybody understand what the fuck is
going on over there?
It was anybody fired today.
Yet there's a meme that Scaramucci guy,
however you say his name.
Um,
there's a meme of him where he's gone
like that,
like with his mouth.
I'm like,
oh.
And it said,
um,
if you take,
if you get this job,
where do you see yourself in 10 days?
Hilarious.
That's funny.
That's like,
like how do,
how do you hire a guy who clearly looks
like he's done coke?
Does he?
He looks like a wolf of Wall Street.
It looks like a wolf of Wall Street
here.
Right?
This is.
This is the guy just on looks alone.
Like this.
Cocky.
He's a,
he's a hedge fund.
Jarque,
you know,
he follows everybody online.
He probably follows you.
Hilarious follows me.
He does.
Yep.
Yeah,
that makes sense.
I think he follows.
Everybody got $150,000.
Did you ever have him on the show?
Of course.
That's a great guess.
I would love to talk to one of those
dudes are.
Find out what it's like in there.
Especially the guys in there for like 10
days.
This guy.
We'll talk.
Well,
I have had a hedge fund guy I know that
Peter Schiff guy on before that
financial wizard.
He's coming on again.
He's an interesting cat.
He's a big time Wall Street guy.
I mean he's got some gigantic firm than
employees who knows how many fucking
people.
But he's uh,
he's also always on television.
Breaking down what's wrong with like
financial bubbles at the real estate
bubble?
He,
he called all that shit.
The subprime mortgage bubble.
He called all that shit years ago after
I'm calling.
I'm calling the Netflix bubble right
now.
Uhm,
up to hear you.
I'm calling.
It cannot be the only one in itself.
You're not the only one by the cool.
You know there was an article that was
out just yesterday about debt.
There was something about Netflix when
in debt,
something like does think it was said it
was good times did an investigation and
it was just like they found out their
$20,000,000,000
in debt.
How's that possible?
Because they're spending so much money
on these shows man and promoting them
and it's like,
listen,
they just celebrated a few months ago.
The $100 million a customer like
whatever they called it $100 million.
So that means that facebook will be
laughing because facebook's got how many
subscribers.
Right?
But there's a big difference.
Facebook doesn't get $9 a month from
you,
but each one of those,
100 million people are giving $9 a
month.
That's $900.
Million dollars a month.
That's not good.
That's,
that's almost a billion dollars a month.
That's $12,000,000,000
a year,
maybe 10,
$10,000,000,000
a year.
It's an insane amount of money.
You know what it is,
what it is,
what it is.
Human man,
man is so valuable.
Right?
I know even when something can work,
like they make systems at work,
but the problem with those systems is
that humans run those systems and they
are so valuable that they fuck shit up.
Is that the right way to say that word
valuable?
Probably not.
Sounds perfect though,
but yeah,
it sounds good.
Don't look it up.
People.
I always thought it was valuable because
it must be British.
Jamaican accent makes sing things sounds
different,
but there's always those words that you
never say,
but you see written and you know the
word and be like,
how am I saying this?
Like I know what this is,
but I can't.
I don't say it can't come up with a good
example.
That is one of.
I know what it's funny.
I don't remember ever saying that word.
Oh Roy.
Sometimes we're like,
I never say Reuters,
Reuters news source,
but when I look at it,
I go,
okay,
I know what that is.
I've read it a thousand times,
but how do I say that?
Routers,
routers,
Broida sounds right.
It is the right way to say that's what
everybody says it,
but when left to my own devices,
I'll just fuck ups pronounced this.
Yeah,
I,
I have way too much totally useless
information going around inside my head.
I got to do some spring cleaning.
I got to throw away your memories.
I to throw away some childhood memories
that are not serving me.
Just taking up space in my head.
I just.
You run out of hard drive space,
man.
Yeah,
you do every day you're looking at some
new story everyday.
There's a new thing going on,
you know,
and especially if you're trying to file
game of thrones and maybe how's of cards
to and maybe stranger things.
I remember when I used to remember
everything,
like I could remember every movie,
every part of every part of my childhood
and then now somebody said,
remember that time we did this and I'm
like,
you are there.
Like I remember the time,
I don't remember it that you were there,
but I guess you were.
Yeah,
like now it's my memory's full.
I need to go to the Mac store.
It had some shit added.
Yeah,
but if you were like an old farmer,
you remember all that shit.
It was just every day getting up,
milking the cows,
picking the eggs,
killing a sheep or something for dinner.
You would,
you would,
you would have those memories because
you're in that same spot everyday.
Thinking about your childhood,
your way from all the distractions come
in your head.
Yeah.
And no books,
no books,
nothing bro.
You gotta eat cheese.
They probably just read one book over
and over five days.
It's an amazing story,
but it is written in storybook for him.
Well,
it's what it was.
Yeah.
The Bible is,
you know,
a fascinating book in that it's,
you start,
you start off with someone telling
stories for like a thousand years before
you write it down
and then you've got a bunch of really
old versions of the story and no one's
sure which ones to use.
Like they got the version that's in the
Dead Sea Scrolls,
that's the oldest versions of some of
those stories.
And it's,
it's one of the only,
um,
like,
I think maybe the only one that's
written in Aramaic or they found it in
these clay pots and Qumran and Qumran is
an area in Israel.
So they have these like little caves and
they will find these clay pots.
And in these clay pots,
they've got these scrolls that are made
out of animal skins.
A lot of them.
So they take these scrolls out.
It's so crazy.
Takes like,
I think it took them like 14 to 15 years
just to piece it together.
Do they allow,
broke it up and shit.
And they couldn't figure out what goes
with what.
So they had to take DNA tests on the,
on the actual pieces of animal skin,
so they could tell,
okay,
well this is some skin from this animal,
so let's concentrate on this.
All these pieces have been genetically
tested to be from this animal.
So let's put these together because it
probably the same scroll.
Then they have to like figure out I take
these crumbs and chunks that are just
thousands of years old,
thousands of years of trust this.
Well not only that,
it's also you're reading it in,
in an ancient ancient land.
You're,
you're reading it in the also like the
references and the way people thought
back then.
Yeah.
Then they have like the oldest version
of the Hebrew Bible is like the very
oldest versions were written in ancient
Hebrew and ancient Hebrews.
Crazy because it has numbers as well as
letters.
So like,
like if you have a letter a,
it's also the number one.
It's all the same.
So linkedin.
So like when you have a word,
like words have like a numerical value
and if I'm butchering this,
if anyone's an ancient Hebrew
representative.
But Ari and I discussed this for a
couple of times because Ra,
you know,
went to,
what is it called,
like that thing that they send him off
to that religious camp when he was a
serious,
a Orthodox Jew.
Oh.
So that's why he's such a serious
atheist now.
Oh,
he's such a freak now.
But that's exactly why.
But so like their words had numerical
value.
So the word God and the word love,
they have the same numerical value.
So you know,
like with the letter n the letter o and
they all have like numbers,
like we can't even think like that
because none of our words have numerical
value.
But like the,
the actual meaning of a word has more
value with more numbers to it.
It's really interesting.
All that stuff's lost on our stupid
goofy language because when they
translated it to Latin,
it translated to Greek or English.
It's all kind of lost.
And then who was translating this shit
and what was everything is based off
like what your goal is or what your
perception of the world is and where
you're from or how you were raised.
And what you want this thing to mean
to people,
right?
So like you can't get away from that.
No.
So if you're the person putting this
stuff together and translate and it's
like,
how do you not let your influence
influenced this thing you do,
right?
You tweak it.
Little tweak it.
Yeah.
You want it to mean the things that it
means to you.
Even if you just want people to believe
this is an ancient scroll that you found
and this goes back to you finding it and
it goes to your name and to your legacy
like,
well this also massive amounts of
evidence of people.
I'm looking at something and then having
a distorted perception of what something
means and then having that band in their
favor.
Right?
Exactly.
There's so many points of evidence.
I do that with all my relationships and
all of them in my,
some of my favorite.
I mean how many people think that
they're the victim.
How many people were just running around
thinking the world's against the total
victim and yeah.
So that's just evidence of a bias
thinking,
right?
If you have bias thinking in regards to
the way that the god of Gods wants to
govern humanity and our behavior and how
we should behave with each other and
treat each other,
if you look in to let your own personal
ego and biases get in the way,
which it absolutely did,
there's still shit written in the Bible
that treats women as second class
citizens.
It condoned slavery.
There's no.
There's no like talking about slavery as
if it's some horrible thing that has to
be like banished.
Like there's in the ancient Hebrew Bible
condones slavery,
they just.
There's really nothing bad about being
about having slaves.
It's like God doesn't come and kill you,
but God will kill you if you were to
different types of cloth.
I know like,
like they'll burn witches,
like,
you know what you are,
which,
why?
Because I said you're a witch,
but you know,
it's not evil slaves.
Yeah.
The table,
the inquisition,
the during the inquisition,
they weren't torturing people because
they had slaves because they thought
they were witches.
They were torturing people because they
just didn't believe enough in a way.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
What caught you doing something or if
you want it to get rid of somebody that
say somebody had a job that you wanted,
a position that you wanted.
If you could prove that that person like
slandered God or blast themed or
anything,
then you're out.
That's the standard maneuver,
right?
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
You get the government to get rid of
this person for you.
That's how you get shit like North Korea
and that's how you get shit like Isis.
You know,
you,
you just.
Everybody turned it on everybody.
Everybody trying to figure out a way
that they can use their power.
But that's what's kind of happening in
America to a little bit.
Yeah.
There was an article in the new,
I think it was the New Yorker just like
two days ago with the senator.
Um,
was it a senator who wrote.
Is that what you just read?
An
article last night is a Republican
senator and he said when Obama was
president,
the Republicans made a concerted effort
to just push the Republican agenda,
make Obama a one term president,
and now that trump has hijack their
party,
they're kind of turning a blind eye to
things that they wouldn't have if Obama
was president just because trump is the
republican candidate.
Huh.
And he's like,
where our loyalties to our party or to
this country because we're kind of like
fucking up the country,
you know,
and it's Kinda,
it's Kinda like,
like when Obama was president,
no matter what you think of them,
like if,
if he,
if he was a good president,
right?
Say he's a good president because he's
not your person,
you're going to shut down the things
that he's doing to get your party in
power.
Like you don't give a fuck.
Right?
Because all you care about is your party
winning.
Like,
like,
and now that trump is president,
the Democrats are taken the same thing
from the same book.
And I'm not even saying trump is a good
president,
but I'm just saying everybody's turning
on everybody.
Yeah,
they're all trying to figure out a way
to win so they'd get their agenda
forward and that's not the country's
agenda.
No at all.
So destroying it,
destroying each other.
Well,
it's definitely like a battle between
the two sides right now,
you know,
I mean there's a lot of people that are
getting excited by it.
They take,
uh,
they have not just a vested interest in
it,
but it becomes like a part of their
identity to be a part of the resistance
fighting,
fighting against this evil empire,
but at the detriment of like,
maybe not.
I mean it really depends because like
when you put a tremendous amount of
pressure on someone,
like they're putting on trump,
whether you agree with it or not,
it forces that person to realize that
there's people like that out there and
you adjust accordingly.
It moves the tied a couple degrees one
way or the other.
It just does like the idea that we're
not culturally malleable that our
cultures and shift back and forth.
It certainly does.
Things that used to be totally
acceptable are now completely taboo.
And that's just over the course of the
last decade or so.
So I think that even the far left,
it's all necessary.
It just doesn't seem necessary because
we're caught up in it and we can see if
we just meet in the middle somewhere can
all be.
But if you just looked at this thing
objectively,
like not,
not like a human being even look at it
at like a mathematic problem,
right?
Like if you could see human culture,
you would say,
oh well there's this complete constant
shift of energy that goes left and right
and left and right,
like some crazy ping pong game
occasionally goes right.
And then right again,
very rarely like Reagan and then Bush
senior,
but then it balances itself out and goes
left again.
It's this weird battle.
And along the way if you look at
like if you really step away from it
along the way,
there are incremental changes that are
moving in a good direction.
It's just hard to see them.
No,
there's a lot of bad shit happened.
Yeah,
I get that.
And then we only hear about the stuff,
the bad stuff,
because each side is just trying to get
points from the other side.
But I.
But I'm just saying it's just that when
one party,
no matter what party is trying to do
something good,
even if it's something good,
then the people from the other party are
going to be against it because they
don't want that party to score that good
point.
You then they knocked that off the table
and that thing that could help people is
never going to help people.
I think it's also part of having two
teams.
If think if there was way more teams,
if there was like 20 or 30 different
parties,
we'd be way better off.
You're better off.
Politicians are spread across 20 or 30
different parties instead of jammed into
one or the other or the freaks that are
independent or green party liquid.
The Fuck Outta here.
Where your Green party,
it's a goofy right?
That's no one's going to elect a Green
party president.
All the bankers are going to put a stop
to that.
This guy's just going to steal money
from us.
Fuck,
this is going to give it to penguins and
shit.
You know what I mean?
That's going to give out money to
penguin.
So you've got really three choices.
You've got independent,
which is so rare.
The only person that I could think ever
winning as an independent right now
honestly would be someone like trump or
like elon musk,
mark Cuban,
you know,
trump is basically an independent who
hijack Republican Party.
Well,
he's,
he voted Democrat like his whole life.
He was pro choice like his whole life.
You know,
it's like he's been on the side of a
democratic issues forever.
Right?
I mean,
I saw the video where he said,
I saw the video right the day before.
I saw it twice.
The last time I saw it was the day
before the election where he said if I
was going to run,
I would run as a Republican because
Republicans are stupid and blah,
blah,
blah.
I saw that video,
like him being interviewed.
I tell you the next day that shit was
scrubbed from the Internet and if I tell
people I saw that video,
they said,
no,
you're crazy.
It was just like,
so he really had it taken down.
Yeah,
man.
Dude,
that's like some l Ron Hubbard type
shit.
Ron Hubbard was quoted as saying that if
you really want to make money should
start a religion,
and he started.
Scientology wasn't bullshit.
Tell the truth.
They got so much for coming.
Yeah.
He's a fascinating character,
man.
I mean obviously there's a tremendous
amount of issues with him not telling
the truth.
That might be the biggest problem.
The number one biggest problem might be
the line that we can't trust them.
That is so crazy that you have a
president that just lies all the time,
but if you step away from the lying part
and you look at like what he's doing.
What's interesting is this is,
I don't know too much about the
affordable care act or Obamacare,
but I do know that a whole lot of people
voted against it,
are now voting against repealing it.
Alright.
So it either means one of two things,
right?
It means trump's plan is so bad that the
people hated obamacare.
This is even worse.
Or it's a bunch of people that just
don't like trump and even though they
didn't want obamacare in the first
place,
no matter what trump comes up with,
they're going to be like,
fuck you,
we're going to fight against that.
Which maybe there's a few other.
It could be this or it could be that,
but those two to me are pretty
fascinating.
That's like childish shit.
Yeah.
That's the whole.
It's fitness child.
Just like.
I just feel like everybody's just going
after everybody.
And when you spend your time going after
people to remove them from their
position,
what are you doing for the people when
you're going after like a,
your own selfish gain,
you're spending your entire time in
office trying to get one step up.
Well,
he's got a lot of steps out.
That was not just him but everybody else
under him.
Plus him trying.
Now he's trying to stay up.
He had to spend his day fighting shit.
Right,
right.
Instead of solving shit.
Yeah.
He's,
he's,
well,
he fights people on twitter.
People on twitter,
on
world,
right when the president,
United States,
kind of the president of the world,
like you might not be running these
other countries,
but everybody knows is the country that
has all the fucking bombs and it's crazy
enough to use them.
Right?
So this is the president of the arguably
the greatest army in the world's ever
known.
That's the commander in chief right
there.
They talk shit about people on twitter
talking shit about people having plastic
surgery.
Scars bleeding badly from a facelift.
I see New York so crazy.
It's so crazy and people are so angry
and I get it.
I get it.
I get everybody being angry.
It's not what I'm saying.
I'm just saying it is.
The whole thing is so surreal.
It's like everybody wanted change and
then when change came you're like,
no,
no.
This change is making money.
Like,
no,
no.
We don't want that.
This guy's stealing money.
Like he's,
he's going to make billions of dollars.
Like what the fuck is he doing?
Where's his tax returns?
Show me the tax red turns.
But I think what's going to come out of
it is that there's so many people now
that are politically motivated.
There's so many people that are looking
at this whole thing on,
whoa,
Whoa,
whoa.
You can't just sit back and just let
this happen.
Then you get someone who doesn't tell
the truth as the president and that you
know how bad that fucks up kids.
Right?
When you're looking at like the highest
level of human being in the country.
Like if every kid says,
who?
Billy,
what do you want to be when you grow up?
I want to be approved.
Yeah,
that's the issue.
Yeah.
Jam.
You want to be the president.
You don't only want to be the vice
president.
You want to be the command.
You want to be the number one guy that's
an amputee.
So possible.
Yeah.
But it's also like if the guy who's the
guy at the top of the list is embedded
than people that you know,
like his mind is petty.
Petty.
He's,
he,
he goofs people that just don't like his
policies.
He'll talk shit about like their plastic
surgery.
Right?
A guy with fake hair is talking about
people bleeding from surgery.
Oh,
but it's just like the whole hurt your
feelings thing,
the lash out and hurt your feelings,
things like that.
So he's trying to do,
trying to hurt their feelings.
Like someone just needs to like sit him
down and
I think they tried.
He,
he ain't listening.
He's the one that's his way.
I know he is.
He won but he won that way.
So he's like,
that's how I won my base.
Likes that.
Got To let it in.
You got to let that go because you have
a,
you have a broader responsibility as the
head guy.
I think he's getting feedback that
enough that he has the amazing ability
to ignore,
to ignore things that I wouldn't ignore
and now I think most people wouldn't
ignore,
like,
like blow back,
like I remember.
So this is what happened when one time I
went to see a movie screening with Kevin
Hart was in it with Asha.
There's a long time ago and me and Kevin
with friends,
we used to hang out.
So we went to the screening and we sat
there and we watched the movie and the
movie was terrible.
So then after the movie I'm gonna see
cap.
So my worry is like,
what the fuck am I going to tell this
guy because I can't lie to him about
this movie.
And before I said anything,
he looked at me and said,
man,
that movie was bad,
but I was great.
And you know what he was right here.
So he brushed off like how bad the movie
and found something.
This motherfucker,
trump can find something like he could
heal here.
What he needs to hear from whatever is
done.
They've probably enough people,
events,
even one or a few million that likes his
tweets.
Like we only see the people that hate
his tweets.
Right?
Oh,
there's a lot of people that like sweets
at all have American flags in their
avatars.
So he's gonna go for that.
They have like eagles and Dobermans and
American flags guns.
Um,
what is,
uh,
the recent.
He gave some recent speech where I
thought was really truck.
No,
no,
no.
That was good one too.
But I think it was today where he was
talking about unemployment,
being down,
how I'm of the economy is up and all
these different factors,
and they were talking about how no one
mentions it.
And then I went to CNN and I was like,
yeah,
they're not even mentioning that he's
given this speech.
And he's saying all the like,
how much,
how much should that be?
The number one story.
Like what's the number one store when
you go to CNN,
go to the front page of CNN.
What do we got here?
What does it say?
Highest stock market ever.
Best economic numbers and years
unemployment.
Lowest and 17 years wages.
Rising.
Border secure.
Yeah.
But wait,
is that true?
Well,
I don't know if that's true though,
but I,
I don't know if it's probably true.
Right?
But these were the same things that will
happening when Obama was president and
he used to shit on it.
He used to say it's not rising enough.
The unemployed,
the unemployment level should still be
lower.
Or like when they put out the job gains
or whatever they call that shit.
Technically he would say that's not
enough growth,
so there is a way to shit on everything,
but look at all this.
Look at what they show on CNN.
Like right away you see on the top,
trump weighed in on sons,
misleading claim breaking news.
So you've got a negative trump ad,
no inaccuracy in Donald Trump's junior
statements,
about 2016 meeting with Russians.
White House says White House comments on
Donald Trump jr statements,
timeline of dot.
So none of that as anything to do with
unemployment being down or the economy
being up.
And this is like the front page of CNN.
It's all negative.
They're going to have to for sure,
but this is not good.
It's not good to do that.
Like you're not given all the news.
You got to give the news like he does
plenty of stupid shit that you can cover
your as short of stupid shit.
But when good shit happens,
like when the economy is up,
when unemployment is down,
he probably,
she'd be reporting that.
It seems like that's new,
but all right,
so if it's true,
if it's true,
right?
Okay.
Your,
your,
you know,
you have a powerful twitter,
your name is trump,
right.
And you know this and you know the game
by now,
right.
So you know,
if you tweet about some woman's plastic
surgery,
they're going to go in on you.
Yeah.
And that's what's going to be on CNN,
CNN,
but that's not CNN or MSNBC.
Right.
But he is going to be on every news,
all the media outlets that are not in
favor of,
you are going to put that.
Right.
So everyone except Fox,
everyone except Fox.
So it's like stop putting shit that
people can use to cover up and use
instead of the employment,
unemployment stuff being down.
You know what I mean?
When you mean stop giving people ammo
against you.
Right.
You know what I mean?
Stop giving them information.
Negative stuff that they can put on the
front of their website instead of
unemployment numbers going down.
Yeah.
But there's no way they're going to stop
that as long as their stories like that.
Like Donald Jr secretly meeting with the
Russians and not telling people and then
release in the emails and then saying
it.
You know,
all that stuff and then it turns out
that trump was the one who coordinated
the statement about it and like all that
stuff.
It's never gonna stop fucking up.
Yeah.
He's fucking up.
But here's the thing.
You got to write the good stuff too.
Yeah.
You have to have write news.
I mean I feel like if I'm going to trust
you for the news I want.
I
would like to think as a person who
leans very left,
I would like to think that CNN is going
to be better than right wing agenda
websites.
Well,
how can they not be?
That's,
that's very disappointing.
It's very disappointing.
Couldn't have both thing.
I don't trust none of them.
I don't trust the news or the because
you know why?
Because when Obama was president or just
in presidents before,
like a lot of shit was phony and false.
You know what I mean?
Like they just did it.
Here's a funny thing.
So they just did a study of like body
cams on cops.
Right?
And just did a study and they said from
the study they see that cops treat black
people that they pull over worst than
they treat white people say
motherfucker,
we've been trying to tell you that,
but now it's only official when white
people did the study,
they like,
you know what,
this thing is true,
but been trying to tell you that shit is
true for a long time,
but that's just a part of.
It's like you're not covering anything
that doesn't serve you.
You know what I mean?
You're not.
You're not covering anything that
doesn't serve you anymore.
Yeah.
But their news,
they're not cops.
I can understand like cops being racist
that I get that.
But if you're,
if you're the news source,
like you have to just distribute the
news.
You can't selectively decide after 10
and can't hear you when you focus on you
have to and you should never have.
Well they should.
They never.
They showed but then they just never
have obvious know what's really fucked
up.
That isn't really getting nearly as much
press as I think it should get.
Or people haven't really been talking
about that much is how many people were
concentrating on that white lady from
Australia who got shot unnecessarily by
the cop.
Right.
Because she was a white lady from
Australia.
Right.
That look,
no matter what you say,
what that is is.
I mean obviously it's a tragic accident
because she was the one that called the
cops and then they shot her,
but you know,
many times they've done that to other
people.
But that's my whole point is like the
news serves it.
Remember talking about the scrolls and
how you can't.
If you found a skull,
the scrolls,
you can't help but make a story that is
in your favor.
Right?
Like,
I forgot the exact words you used,
but it's just because your perception is
going to come through in this thing.
To me,
that's how the news has been all my
life.
Like whoever owns the news makes news in
there.
Faith always has been since William
Randolph hearst hearst publications,
so that,
that to me the news has always been,
even if it was slightly inaccurate
before,
it's just being growingly not accurate.
Yeah,
but that drives people fucking crazy.
You mean that it does people,
because like when I was a kid,
like a stupid little kid and I was
watching the news just stupid enough to
think like when somebody's telling me
what's going on in the world,
I'm like,
the news is God,
like because they thought that it was
all real.
That was like just like,
not just like a kid that's like you
don't know any better,
but how did these people know
everything?
They're telling you everything.
So you're kind of getting programmed to
believe this shit.
So people are getting programmed to
believe Fox,
MSNBC,
CNN,
and they don't know any better and they
get an angry based on what they're being
told and we're not being told
everything.
We're not being told everything.
Like you're saying,
they're not showing both sides,
right or everything.
They're not.
There's no reason for the people who own
the news to be fair.
That's true.
They just have to get people to pay
attention to get people get so they.
The third thing is how do I make money?
Right.
It'd be outrageous.
It got to be outrageous.
We've got gotta we got to,
even though we got to follow this Russia
story and we got to make money.
This is a soap opera.
This is game of thrones going on,
on fucking TV.
This is like when Katrina,
they milk the shit out of Katrina and
any tragedy and they're just milking
this.
That's like every like why is everything
coming out?
Like,
all right,
so there was a meeting to then it was
email.
So then like,
like it's almost as if somebody wrote a
script and we're going today,
we're going to give you this part of it
today.
We're going to give you this part of it.
Like it's like it's unfolding like a TV
show keeping peoples interest
in a lot of ways.
It is like that house of cards,
show house of cards.
Yeah.
I'm in,
in almost even less believable like
everybody was like in the house of
cards.
It's polar.
Um,
I can't even say,
I don't want to say what happens,
but um,
there's some moments on the show where
people go,
well that would never happen.
That's who would get elect.
Like look at the,
what the fuck is happening?
The president's daughter is always
behind him with a giant smile on her
face.
Every time he says anything and she's
clapping.
Like today,
it's like he's got his kids in.
Their kids are running shit.
Supposed to be running this company.
He's supposed to be away from his
company,
but that's not.
You wouldn't even show his tax returns.
The whole thing.
So gangster.
It's so poot NASC.
It's really fascinating.
And now with this thing that's going on
with Russia,
I mean,
who knows?
I might be just nonsense.
They might just be posture and with each
other.
Meanwhile they're doing deals behind the
scenes.
It's like,
I'll tell you,
what am I do bro,
Bro?
And I'm gonna.
Kick the delicates out.
I'm going to get pissed,
pissed,
and meanwhile they're making some crazy
deal to like tap into the oil and the
art Antarctica.
Sure.
They're kicking the delegates out.
Maybe maybe,
maybe to look like maths to look like,
Hey,
I'm not on.
If I was a friend of trump,
I wouldn't kick your delegates out exact
maybe.
Right?
Why would I kick the diplomats out?
Yeah,
if I'm working with them.
Come on,
man.
Yeah,
right.
they did.
Just going back and forth.
It's also strange.
It's so strange that people could still
rock it like that.
Like you still could be a dictator in
2017.
That is one of the last remaining like
archaic jobs.
Like the one dude running everything guy
with a giant army.
Everybody keep it together.
Keep it together.
You could have a safe life.
Don't fucking push me.
Just give me a little money.
Right?
What's it hurt you to give me a little
money?
You can't give me 30 percent of your
money.
Come on man.
Give me 50 percent.
It's not that big a deal.
I mean that's,
that's what a lot of countries are stuck
in right now,
you know,
and in,
in Russia with.
The crazy thing is if it doesn't go well
for you,
they just take your company.
He's a multibillionaire oligarchs.
They just lock these two top,
lock them up,
take the company confiscated,
just throw in a jail cell,
keeping there for game of thrones.
And it was that amount,
dude.
I was watching this documentary about
this Russian guy who was a,
and he was at first,
he loves working with trump and somehow
or another he disagreed with trump.
Now trump rather than two,
that's like,
that's some fraud shit.
Uh,
he was uh,
working with,
I'm trying to remember the full story,
but he had some sort of a business
arrangement with Putin and then he tried
to change it or he didn't want to accept
new terms or whatever.
They just locked his ass up.
He opposed something that Putin wanted
to do.
Good.
Yeah.
Sorry Dude.
He complained.
He protested.
Sorry Dude.
And they put some charges on him.
Yeah.
They put some charges on him,
threw him in jail.
And who knows,
man,
they might look.
If you get to be some crazy
multibillionaire dude in Russia,
they probably don't even let you in
there unless you've done some fucked up
shit with them.
They probably listened to like,
you know,
you've got good.
Don't vote with us on.
I mean,
even on the lowest level,
you have to get jumped into a gang and
you got to commit a crime to be a part
of the gang,
so they got to see you do some dirt to
see you get it.
If a gang would do that,
why wouldn't a bunch of billionaires who
have way more to protect?
Yeah,
make you do some dirt with them,
do some dirt,
and also show that you're crazy enough
to be down with them.
Yeah.
They like,
yeah,
I like you,
but I need to know if you're loyal.
You know what red told me that met his
dad do in the Israeli army,
what?
You've raised a kitten.
You raise it,
you take care of it by yourself,
you pet it,
and then when it gets to be like a year
old,
you've got to kill it in front of them
with your bare hands.
Grab it,
snapped its neck just to show that you
can do that.
I was like,
whoa.
Part of the game is that.
I was like,
Whoa,
just to show that you could shut it off.
Like you've got that ability to just
shut it off like you have this cat,
you love it.
Urine,
you're going to kill that thing with
your hands.
Well,
if you could do that,
they make you do that now.
I mean,
why?
Why you have to get coal signed to get
into billionaire club?
Yeah.
You got to kill people.
You think?
What do they do with like gala?
Guys like Jeff Bezos at Amazon guy.
You ever see the photos of him?
Solaris is a photo of him.
Like when he first started out like 12
years ago about this battle scene.
Dorky and then you look at him now it
looks like a fucking assassin.
He's got sunglasses on his walking
aggressive t r t,
t e r t hilarious.
He's got like a girl on each side of him
or something like that.
I'm sure.
I mean,
how much is he worth now?
He's looking at them.
It looks like a killer so that man,
he literally looks like a guy hit man.
I just hired.
That was like a former navy seal that's
coming over to give you advice on how to
secure your corporation.
You know,
like he would show up at apple and hire
a bunch of Hitman.
That's him now.
Is that what that is?
A little while ago.
He's pretty fit guy.
Yeah.
Now,
but he seems like a a fit guy.
Look,
he works out.
See?
Well there was,
but there was a before and after picture
man.
Goofy,
goofy town.
Okay.
Yeah.
He was a little goofy.
But look man figured out how to dominate
online sales.
I use Amazon.com
all the time there.
No camera in the diesel.
All three of them.
So the rock was at the fights this
weekend.
Oh,
well give him a hug.
It's like hugging a tree.
The big tree.
I wonder how much that dude.
Ways with two big rock to big Bro.
He's.
He's in the to 50 range for sure.
Yeah,
for sure.
He's gigantic.
Like you don't realize how big he is
until you give them a hug.
They old friendly guy,
but that guy gets bombarded.
Man.
He can't.
He can't go anywhere without taking
pictures.
They just,
they don't,
they don't give a fuck if you're talking
to them.
They get in between you.
They put their pump to hold their
camera.
It's ridiculous.
Like people just,
they don't give a fuck about decorum or
be in friendlies.
And I'm getting this fucking picture
with the rock.
It's my one chance.
Yeah,
they just swoop in,
man.
Anything for the grand man.
But it's weird.
It's like I'm all your um,
normal etiquette goes out the window.
Like the rock was sitting over there
talking to what demetrius mighty mouse,
Johnson pound for pound best fighter in
the world and they're talking back and
forth and having a good time and let's
do,
just swoops in between them.
One pops up and he's like,
can I get a picture bro?
Go get a picture bro.
And you know,
you see the rock has always been
friendly.
He's,
he's amazing at staying friendly,
but you know,
he's like,
God damn.
Can't even talk to the champ.
Yeah man.
I mean
if he wants to follow us,
he wants to.
Yeah,
I guess he's a nice guy.
He's a real lifestyle.
He's a real nice guy.
But the giant.
You're done bro.
Just needs to get bigger.
Nah Man.
You think you think he's done anything?
Stop lifting.
Yeah,
it's a project,
right?
If it's a sculpture,
I mean,
what's,
is he trying to go after this?
Like what's,
what's left?
But he's trying to stay jacked and he's
like 48 or some
shit.
How old was the rock?
I would say he's about 40.
You can take a week off.
No,
no,
no you can't.
That's the thing.
I'm 45,
so he's 45 and he's shacked just ready
man.
He's jacked.
He's wants to keep that and there's only
one way.
You got to do what he does that
motherfucker off every day.
He does.
He's a,
he'll make these videos when he shows up
in places like Germany.
He's got a film,
some fucking movie.
He's there at 5:00
in the morning.
They already have an elliptical machine
in his,
uh,
in his bed,
in his,
in his hotel room who get like a sweet.
So they have set up this elliptical
machine in his suite and he's out there
banging it out at 5:00
in the morning doing an hour of cardio.
I know him and a Kevin Hart videos
bugged me.
Did it make you feel lazy?
It just working out.
Doing.
They've done more by 7:00
AM then I'm going to do all day.
Yeah.
It's rude and they try to motivate
people like,
hey man,
trying to sleep over here bro.
Scroll up,
scroll up a little bit there.
The one on the far right hand side with
him pulling that rowing machine right
above that one.
That's a doing some rows.
That dude's I can't take.
That's a gigantic person.
Poor rowing machine does not deserve
this.
Yeah,
but if you want to put these things up
and get how many millions of views,
how many million views that have $6,
million,
630,
9,000.
Eight hundred and 98.
Overuse of him showing off.
Dealing paroles we get it.
You wake up in the morning,
but he's motivating people sometimes
like you'll be sitting at home and
feeling like a lazy bitch.
Like I just want to chill today.
I don't feel like working out.
And he goes see the rock to get changed
wrapped around his neck and Chin ups did
tiring.
Yeah.
Hit tires with missiles.
It's weird.
He's a crazy man.
But those are the dudes that like,
you need to know that like as hard as
you think you're working.
Drop one down from there.
That one was the other one that went to
jail.
Yeah,
we'll look at that right there.
You need to know as hard as you think
you're working,
you know,
working that hard.
I know.
Look at that guys.
So if you,
if you think you've done everything you
can to be prosperous in this life.
And then you go to the rocks instagram
and shut your fucking hippie mouth.
Fuck your day up.
Fuck it there.
This is what you didn't do today.
And I know people like,
well,
hey man,
I read a book to.
Okay.
Hey Man,
I've been writing poetry all day.
I've been writing songs.
Payment.
Okay,
okay.
But have you put the same amount of
effort into being whatever you want as
the rock has done and being the ultimate
meathead.
Whenever it's hilarious.
Ultimately I'll
get this.
Whenever I look at that,
that looks at the bar.
A bar has got to change things on the
side.
Don't.
Do you know why you have chains?
Makes the end of the rep harder.
She says,
as you lift the chains up off the
ground,
less of the chain is being supported by
the ground.
So it gets heavier and heavier as you
lift your hands up higher.
That's called hardcore.
I don't know if you boys,
you're aware of whole hardcore hardcore
can get that.
So hardcore that show hardcore.
Listen,
when I want to feel bad about my day,
I just go to the rocks.
Instagram.
It's a good movie.
Shit.
What's going on with this guy?
For that movie?
Rampage.
He has.
This guy's going to be a gorilla or.
Oh Wow.
Oh.
So he's got like one of those suits on
that.
Maps is video games.
Suits.
Isn't that weird that they still can't
completely just fake it.
They have to have a dude move around and
close.
I mean,
I'm at a hollow Lens.
Stuff that we were talking about
yesterday.
There's gonna be able to wear those and
see pretty much what they're going to
like the final CGI rendering.
Like they can just act with that stuff
soon.
It's amazing what you know,
like,
uh,
I watched a game of thrones first
episode and you know,
that that boat's not real.
They don't really have that giant,
massive,
crazy looking boat cutting through the
ocean.
That's not a real boat,
but God damn it looks like a real boat.
Yeah.
That shit was crazy.
That attack was fucking totally don't
say that,
but you look at it,
these boats mean the,
just the CGI.
It's just for a television show.
Yeah.
They spend millions.
I guess it's like worth it to spend
money on those episodes.
Oh yeah.
Each one is millions.
Yeah.
But I guess it's worth it,
right?
Because that thing will sell forever.
Yeah,
I like it.
If it goes down today,
like it's also timeless,
like game of thrones is timeless.
Like that'd be worth a shitload of money
10 years from now,
and I was like,
the soprano's is timeless to soprano's
is timeless.
Like if the soprano's like if you wanted
to start watching the sopranos today,
it would be a great show.
It's like the Godfather or TV timeless,
but it's better than the Godfather.
Italians all over the country screaming
at me.
Shit.
The Godfather is the greatest fucking
movie.
The Godfather is an amazing movie.
Don't get me wrong,
but it's limited by its format,
so limited by the fact that it's a
movie.
Even though you get godfather one and
two sopranos was on for like what?
Five years,
five years of episodes.
The depth that they can get into all the
crazy shit that they could do it just so
different than any other movie or than
any other form of music.
They could go off and talk about the gay
member author.
Goddamn gang.
Yeah.
Do anything they can do anything.
He's a fair with a psychiatrist or
anything.
Anything.
Yeah.
Remember they killed that dude.
A pool cue showed a pool cue up his ass.
Crazy gay guy.
Yeah.
That that was the whole thing was weird,
you know,
it was like you're,
you're getting deep into the lives of
these strange characters and sociopath
and you kind of understand their angst
because you started rooting for them.
Yeah,
I could.
Even in the Americans they're rushing,
but you start rooting for them.
You don't want to get caught,
you know,
you want them to.
And it's really are from another
country.
Maybe maybe,
but if you watch it,
watch a few episodes and see if you
don't like start rooting for the Russian
space is how.
This is how I picture the show.
Perfect APP.
You find out five minutes into the show
that they're Russian spies.
The FBI kicks the door down.
A bunch of white guys guns blazing,
pointed out them.
They immediately shipped them to
Guantanamo Bay and then put the House
for sale,
for sale and they make a profit off the
house by house.
I wonder if they did a scan to the spy
house.
Find out if they scan the spy house to
find out what kind of spy shit they got.
Because you know Russia's not going to
just let you have a spy house by herself
and you haven't parties and we've
googled the other day to check in.
We saw barbecue.
You'll have blurbing you working us by
which one?
Which one tends to be turned in American
easy blurb.
Acute time or spite time.
You'll get the spine.
Yeah.
So they probably like they gotta be
spying on the spies for sure.
Yeah,
I trust them.
Spy just moved to New Jersey.
Have a good time to start doing coke.
They know you could get turned out for
sure.
Why wouldn't you get turned over here?
You could do whatever the fuck you want.
Most people,
most people are not gonna kill you.
You don't have to,
but then they know you're there,
so they'll send somebody.
You wouldn't even know who the person
is.
It'd be like some La femme.
Nikita chick comes over your house
selling vacuums or something.
You opened the door.
She shoots you in the Dick.
Right?
Could be.
I just don't understand why they would
use that strategy.
Like they hire someone to pretend to be
American flying across the world.
Set them up,
go get information in Montclair.
You got to watch the Americans,
man.
It works.
Yeah.
What kind of information?
I guess that's my bay.
Uh,
so spoiled.
I don't know.
There's this.
So say say there's the FBI.
Okay.
So the husband puts on a disguise and
starts
dating that.
The secretary of the director of the
FBI.
Whoa.
So the husband,
is he a real husband?
They are married,
right?
They were pair together,
right.
They had two kids together.
Real well,
not in the show and the show in the
show.
They had two kids together in America.
They run a travel agency
and then
on top of that they're both spies on top
of that.
They both by.
So the traveling just bang other chicks
like baby,
I got it.
She gets the bang other dudes,
God,
like,
like if there's a target like it,
if there's a target
that they could get too emotionally,
then they just do what they gotta do.
And then sometimes they come home and
he's like,
did you fuck up?
Whoa.
And she has to say I did do differ
Russia.
Yeah.
I did duty.
And meanwhile the both of them have
fallen in and out of love and get
jealous.
Oh my God.
And then sometimes they liked the people
that they have to kill or like good
fucking show.
Yeah man,
it's so intricate.
Dam.
And then one of the,
the neighbor just moved in and he works
for the FBI.
So then their kids go over to his house
and his kids come over to their house
and he doesn't know that they are
Russian spies.
He's had hunches before.
Oh.
So it's just,
it's a crazy fucking show,
man.
Damn
good.
As good.
Better or not as good as house of cards.
I say better than a house of cards.
Oh my goodness.
I don't even know.
Now I know you are a foreigner.
You are some kind of a.
An agent yourself told you I was a
foreign.
Yeah,
but now I know I'm American foreign as
he pours his teeth.
Jesus Christ.
Fuck,
are you?
Everything's a crime.
Before,
who are you?
You don't even drink coffee.
You barely American,
Bro.
I know.
I know you.
You love.
You have the full foreign package.
Man.
You're into soccer?
Yeah.
Do you have a call?
Soccer,
football and.
No.
No Americans around.
Uh,
do you,
do you like it when they are around?
Sometimes.
Do you really?
But I just say soccer just so people
know what I'm talking about.
Right?
Yeah,
that's what I was thinking.
You'd probably say football when you're
around other people.
Yeah.
If I'm talking to somebody from,
sometimes I'm talking to a friend
from England and I'll say soccer,
then they'll get mad at you.
Now
some people have disappointed though
they'll correct it.
Uh,
but it won't,
it won't be a sticking point in the
conversation.
It's a sticking point in America.
Right.
So you just stick with soccer?
Yeah.
You've never said football to me,
but I always suspected it was packed and
I knew something was going on this
motherfucker so into that game.
I know he uses the proper terminology
when I'm not around.
Yeah.
Like someone will say you want to play
billiards and I'll let it slide.
Like,
okay.
And that's cool,
right?
Yeah.
Not really.
Pocket and pool billiards is a game that
you play with.
No,
there's no holes in the table.
They received that game.
I think so.
There's like,
there's like things in the table now.
There's others in Italian version of it
where they play.
They have these little pins.
You're thinking a bumper pool.
I think three cushioned billiards is a
very strange game where and that used to
be the premier game by the way back,
like in the willy hoppy days,
like way,
way,
way back in the,
I guess probably the turn of the
century,
the turn of the 20th century.
They had thousands of pool halls and
billiard halls in New York City,
but pool halls like where there's a hole
in the table and the boss to fall into
the hole.
Those were thought to be the,
that's the game of.
And like dirt bags,
gentlemen played billiards.
They played three cushioned billiards
and that was actually a part of the
scene in the movie,
the Hustler with Paul Newman and Jackie
gleason.
Paul Newman goes over this dude's house.
Uh,
I forget the gentleman's name,
but he's a very famous actors.
Great.
Great scene.
And He,
they're supposed to gamble because this
guy's a big fish and he has this big
mansion and Paul Newman is this hustler.
He goes over the guy's mansion and the
guy doesn't have a pool table.
He has a billiards table.
And the,
uh,
the,
the mob guy who's backing Paul Newman on
the bet doesn't believe that he could
beat this guy.
And so they have to figure out like what
to do because it's totally different
game.
But it was the game of gentlemen.
Three cushioned billiards is a game
where it's you have to hit a ball and
then your ball has to go three cushions.
That means bounced into three rails and
then come back and hit the ball.
It's really crazy.
It's a,
it's a,
it's an interesting game because it's
all about angles you ever played.
Yeah,
I played it,
but it's,
it's hard to do.
You have to really understand.
There's a lot of factors that come into
play.
Here it is right here.
This is the actual game.
You can do shit like that when you play
pool.
Yeah.
No,
I do.
I mean I,
I definitely moved the ball around and I
understand some angles,
but like this stuff like what this guy's
doing right here,
this,
this is like super complicated stuff to
be able to help you win this thing.
You just get a point every time you get
three cushions,
like see how he's doing this right here,
he's doing that.
It bounced off the railroad,
hits that and then it's going to hit the
other one.
Like doing stuff like that on purpose.
I mean they're doing it on purpose is
very difficult to do like you to to
really understand how.
I mean sometimes you're going four and
five and even six rails to make
something do what you wanted to do
because it was the only option you had
with the position of the ball on the
table relative to the position of the
ball you're trying to hit.
If you have to go three rails,
so you see like these crazy tricky shots
these guys do where they're calculating
the ball,
going three rails,
hitting another ball and then going to
rails and then hitting a third ball.
It's like crazy.
It's like the way they do it is amazing.
It's really amazing how many balls are
in the table that he's three balls.
Three balls.
Yeah.
It's really,
it's fascinating.
I never got into it because I would
imagine that it would become addictive,
just like pools addictive and I don't
have the time.
I just can't be fucking with some new
thing to get addicted to it.
Especially when you're going to start,
you know,
checking out some soccer I feel.
Yeah.
Isn't that weird though?
How they do this?
See he's going to hit that and it's
going to bounce up and hit the other one
and they are planning this out.
That's what's interesting.
And the guys who are real good at it,
a lot of times it translates very good
into pool too.
It seems like it would.
Yeah.
Well they figure out how to move the
ball better than other people.
Like there's a guy named Aaron Ray is
and he's widely considered to be
probably the best pool player of all
time and he plays this game really good.
He plays this game really good.
Any place.
Another game that the Filipinos like to
play called rotation and rotation is a
game like you know how you play nine
ball and shoot one through nine.
You got to shoot the balls in order
rotation.
They do that with 15 balls.
What?
Yeah.
Filipinos are some of the best players
in the world and it's interesting
because the the game of billiards,
pocket billiards,
I should say I guess regular billiards
to got brought to them during World War
II when they had a American.
Gis would be in the Philippines
apparently during the war when people
would go over there,
they would set up pool tables and Gis
would go to bars and they figured out
how to play pool and it became a great
thing for the Filipinos who love
gambling,
love gambling,
so they would just play pool and gamble
all the time.
So some of the best players in the world
have come out of the Philippines.
Manila has some of the best players
ever,
like,
like the top guys like that guy effort
and ray is.
He's from the Philippines.
Francisco boosted monitoring where the
best of all time he's from the
Philippines.
There's like you keep going on and on
and on and on and on.
There's A.
There's a whole gang of these dudes,
little tiny killers,
so I never played pool against the
Filipino.
That's what I'm learning there.
Real quiet,
real friendly.
They'll smash you.
Yeah.
Some of the best players in the world.
It's just a huge sport over there as
Jay.
It's on television all the time.
Over there.
Pool is like the first video game
because because it's,
it's a pool and just a table and you go
into a bar and it's there.
You put money in there and you start
playing it before they were graphics or
programs or anything.
It's just,
it's just a game.
It's like the first game you can play
without before video games.
You know what I mean?
I know what you're saying.
Yeah.
It was like an arcade game.
Like dark.
Yeah,
and darks here.
They would play I think.
I think they started calling it pool.
I know actually they started calling it
pool because it was a gambling thing.
The thing that they would pool their
money together,
bed on stuff and that's how,
uh,
that's how pool got its bad name versus
billiards,
but like darts,
they must bet on dark.
That's right.
And people would bid on dots.
Yeah.
Dots is a big sport in England.
Huge.
It's on TV.
I
saw it on TV.
I saw snicker,
snicker,
snicker.
They call it sneaker is pool or
something else.
Sneakers.
A totally different game.
And it's on a giant table.
Yeah.
The a pool.
A pool table is nine by and a half,
which means four and a half foot wide,
nine foot long.
That's a real legit pool table.
There's also 10 by fives.
Ten by five.
Pool tables are just starting to make a
comeback as a company called diamond and
they make a 10 by five.
Now it's a big deal because the real
high end players like the extra space at
the 10 by five,
they think it makes you play a better
game.
But snookers 12 feet.
Jesus.
Yeah.
It's 12 by six.
So giant fucking table.
And these dudes have a tiny little ball.
It's a tiny ass little ball.
It's way smaller than a pool ball and
the holes are really tiny and the cut of
the rails is very different.
Like you can kind of rattle a ball into
a pool table hole.
It'll kind of drop in,
but you have to hit like this is a
snooker table size of this fucking
table.
Now this is Ronnie.
Oh Sullivan who's one of the greatest of
all time and he's a fucking wizard and
this is the greatest game of snooker
ever.
It's because he just.
He does everything perfect and he shoots
his whole rack perfect.
But snickers a totally different game.
Like see how the sneaker rather that
goes in there.
A sneaker that he shot the ball in and
then the ball comes back up again.
It comes back up.
Yeah.
The black ball.
Oh,
every time he shoots the black that has
no scratching.
I don't know.
You can scratch.
I did don't.
I don't know the game.
I don't understand the game,
but there's a bunch of points and all
these different things that you're
doing,
but see how he knocks that a black ball
in after the black ball goes in,
the guy pulls it out and he puts it back
in the spot and then he has to shoot one
of the reds again and then after he
shoots the red,
then he goes and shoots the black again
and every time he's doing it see that
stack of balls.
He's trying to collide into those balls
to open them up and if he can open them
up,
then he can get it to a place where he
can separate those balls and make them
all.
So Watch.
He's going to make this red ball and
then he's going to pound up.
Now he see on an angle would that black
ball.
So as he shoot that black ball in,
he's going to smack into those other
balls being see that.
Alright,
see now again,
I don't know this game very well,
but I understand pool so I see what he's
doing with those balls.
I knew he was going to do that,
so now he's just going to pocket these
balls in the side,
but you're dealing with the tiniest
little fucking hole and they have tiny
little tips on their pool cues.
It's sort of like a pool cue,
but it's all.
They're all made of ash,
which is very different than.
Yeah,
Ashwood.
Whereas I'm most American pool cues that
at least the shafts are made out of
maple.
Like there's a lot of weird variables
like ash is very stiff but also very
light,
so their game is very different,
but he's also very similar.
He's also thinking very fast,
oh,
he's a wizard.
This guy's a super genius,
but like I wouldn't have taken my second
shot yet.
I know he's like clearing the table.
He's doing this every day.
You don't realize,
but you gotta think he's also.
I'm extremely wealthy because of this
game.
This is not a game like American pool.
This is a game like more akin to like
golf in terms of like purses and how
much money these guys can make it.
At least it was at one point in time.
I think somehow or another it's dried up
a think like snuckered doesn't,
doesn't have the same respect that it
used to have.
There's been also a few controversies in
England or guys got busted,
uh,
talking to people about fixing games.
Oh yeah.
That gets ugly.
That old man is like the ball boy in
tennis.
Exactly.
Grabbing the ball at the hole and
putting it on the table.
But he does it with gloves on,
like a gentleman that actually the
gloves have a purpose.
The gloves are so your hand oils don't
get on the ball because the balls are
made out of what's called phenolic.
It's like a type of thing.
It's like a composite plastic.
Um,
and they're super hard.
Like if you touch those balls that are
out there on that table and they're like
super hard and they used to make them
with either clay or ivory back then way
back in the day.
Yeah.
They,
a lot of times they made the cue ball
with ivory and then the other balls it'd
be made out of clay or sometimes the
whole everything would be made at clay.
But they were like these dead balls that
were really tough to move around.
And then when they figured out this
phenolic stuff,
you're dealing with these things.
It gets super slick.
So the greases from your hands,
if you touch a ball,
the oils on your hands will actually put
a residue on the ball and it'll affect
the way the ball moves.
So the game off.
Yeah.
So if you see dudes touching cue balls
and balls and you're playing pool,
like anybody who really knows how to
play is going to go,
that's going to fuck everything up.
Put your gloves on.
Yeah.
Or put a towel on and wipe them down.
Something like serious games.
They'll wipe every ball down after every
rack in regular pool.
Yeah.
Like guys,
guys that are gambling,
they want that ball to respond a very
particular way.
Like because you get this,
when you think about what pool it's
right,
you're taking a acute,
the average weight of accused about 19
ounces.
So it's a very light thing.
So a little over a pound and you're
taking this thing and just by how hard
you're hitting,
you're trying to control the revolutions
of a ball and also those revolutions
after it collides with a ball and knocks
it into a hole and then you're trying to
control the revolutions still like
literally within inches and you get a
feel after you do it for awhile and you
play for hours and hours,
especially after years and years of
playing.
You get this field where like the guy
like that guy effort and ray as I was
talking about,
he could just put that ball wherever the
fuck he wants it.
He goes wherever he wants it,
he makes a ball ball goes where it goes
for every once it was like,
can you watch him play?
It's like you're watching an art form.
Like it's.
If you know how hard it is to play that
guy plays.
I know I suck so bad.
I know it's hard to play.
See,
the thing about sucking so bad though is
maybe you don't even appreciate how
crazy it is.
What he's doing.
I could play a little bit.
Then you watch him,
you just go God,
like the people that really appreciate a
guy like effort and Razz or earl
strickland for that matter and he.
He's like world champion players.
The people will really appreciate him.
Are People that have played for awhile.
You know how you said you don't have the
time to learn billy?
It's.
Yeah.
It's like I up the Times I play pool or
you play against somebody good or you
watch somebody play.
You're like,
yeah,
that takes a lot of practice.
I don't have the time to get that good.
Yeah.
There's only so many hours in the day,
man.
Yeah.
You want to play golf?
Go play golf.
You crazy.
If you want to start golf today,
you must.
You must have like just extra time
coming out of your ass.
Right?
That's like a nine hour commitment.
Yeah.
You got to join a country club.
I know a dude who just joined a country
club that costs a quarter of a million
dollars a year.
How is he going?
That's what I'm saying.
What it costs a quarter of a million
dollars a year,
it costs that and then you have to pay
it on you when you go.
I'm sure there you have to get equipment
unless everything's free.
Other than that,
you just go there and it's all free,
but that doesn't make sense.
I'm gonna open up a country club.
I think they just.
It's what we're talking about.
Like the billionaire ballers,
right?
If you're a billionaire bar,
quarter million bucks ain't shit.
It's like if someone says,
Hey Ian,
we want you to join the comedians unions
$25 a year and you're like,
what's 25 bucks?
Right?
Yeah.
Here you go.
Twenty five bucks.
And if you're a super baller,
$250,000
a year,
it's like you go into,
you're going to run into other
billionaires,
you're going to do business and you
gotta make that money back.
That's what I'm saying.
It's worth it.
And business models and you can write it
insulated because everybody there is a
baller,
right?
Right.
You're only around.
People can afford a $250,000
a year membership shit hole,
and the people that work there,
they just want to keep their job.
They probably just probably pays good,
so they're just,
hey,
what do you.
What do you want?
Here's a,
here's your order.
Leave you alone.
You know what?
I don't get people that want to live on
golf courses that don't play golf.
Oh,
for real?
Yeah.
Like,
hold on.
You don't play golf and you want to live
on a golf course.
It does look beautiful.
It does look beautiful until some drunk
assholes or playing golf or outside your
bedroom.
There are people that live on golf
courses.
Oh yeah,
dude.
Everywhere.
There's a lot of these places are like
gated communities that are on golf
courses.
It's super common.
It's like the ultimate.
I'm a baller statement.
You have a gated community that's a golf
course and you're a member of it.
This is a place out here.
It's called Lake Sherwood Lake Sherwood
Country Club.
It's amazing.
You go to these beautiful houses.
It's amazing golf course.
Just everyone's solaris and it's a.
They actually have their own lake,
there's a lake out there,
you can go bass fishing in it.
They have like large mouth bass and this
lake.
Yeah.
And it's um,
it's a beautiful community and these
people have these houses that are like
on a golf course.
If it costs just a quarter of a mil to
be a part of a golf club,
how much does it cost?
I have a house,
probably the place you live in urban and
I'm out on the golf course.
Millions.
Millions dollars for sure.
I mean it's a wealthy community,
but
I think that's when you get those sort
of CEO dudes,
they start moving into that upper
echelon of finance and cash.
They uh,
they don't want to be surrounded by
people just like them and just kinda.
It's like us wanting to be around other
comedians.
Yeah.
Because I don't have any civilian
friends.
Really.
All comedians right now.
I've been in it so long,
like not funny.
We call it civilians will get mad at
that by the way.
They are they.
But people get mad at it like that.
You used military terms.
Sorry.
That's funny thing,
that term,
as soon as you say to a comic,
they know what it is,
even if you've never used it around with
them before and he get it right.
Yeah.
They don't understand true debauchery.
Like you think you get it.
You need to hang out with atheist
already.
Should fear.
Yeah.
In Amsterdam for a week.
What the fuck is really going on?
Yeah,
like when like if I'm a from around like
a friend from high school and I say
something,
even if the person that they just
introduced me to laugh,
they said y'all got to excuse him.
He's a comedian.
Like none of my comedian friends would
ever say no shit like that.
Like try to like make an excuse for
something that they feel uncomfortable
about that.
I said,
you know what that comes from where
human resources that comes from like
office rules,
keep that job.
You gotta keep your behavior in check.
You can't be yourself.
I mean how many people just live out
there under a vice?
Just a vice of repression,
right?
Can't laugh around Kent joke around
about shit.
Yeah.
And I take that for granted because what
I do,
I can say whatever I want.
Sometimes I think I'm not saying enough
based on the other people that are
saying shit to me.
Yeah.
I mean,
imagine if you're in an office with 50
people and you hate 10 of them and one
of them's your boss,
right?
Oh.
And there's a bunch of attention seeking
dipshits in the staff taking credit for
other people's work.
You can't say anything.
Oh,
oh,
your wife or your husband or whatever.
So many people live in hell.
How many people live in hell?
Like that just stuck all day with
dipshits saying dumb things.
But that's why people listen to your
podcast.
Like it's there.
It's like when you watch a,
like somebody on tv,
you watch a James Bond movie and he's
doing things that you can't do,
like just having a podcast where you say
whatever the fuck you want and just
living like people live in the office,
you get to live through you.
You know what I mean?
Through your podcast.
It's a lot of pressure.
I just keep doing what you're doing sort
of pressure.
I feel pressure.
You got to be careful.
All that pressure.
Yeah.
That's why,
you know,
that's why it may be partly why trump is
so popular because he's the first
president to just talk shit like it's
truly a powerful thing.
Like when you build a powerful man,
most powerful man in the world are
censored,
but this is the first uncensored,
most powerful man in the world.
He's truly exuding his power on a don't
give a fuck level,
but he knows a little bit of a fuck,
but not enough of a change.
Yeah.
He only gives a fuck if he gets dinged a
little bit,
but he's.
He not.
He doesn't pull back.
He just,
he swats back defensively.
Yeah.
In a way that a listener would want to
swap back defensively at work.
Yeah,
but still can because they.
Trump seems so less worried about his
job and more like,
I'm just going to be me and that's when
Chappelle quit the Chappelle show.
Like a lot of people found freedom in
that.
That's why he's so mythical.
Oh,
for sure.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Good point.
A lot of people make $50,000,000,
but how many people you know,
turn down $50,
million dollars.
There's fewer of those.
Yeah.
You know,
just one.
Just one.
Yeah.
And he also didn't do standup in any
scheduled performance for years.
He just would show up places.
Yeah.
And he still does that.
He's like,
so he just uses to.
Oh,
I'm gonna show up this place.
Yeah.
And then they put out an email or
however he just shows me about when I
was in Denver.
Oh Yeah?
Yeah.
Showed up.
I go to the greenroom.
Dave's in there.
I go,
what are you doing,
man?
Hey,
Joe Rogan.
Yeah,
he,
that's his way I guess,
of just being free.
Free.
Yeah.
Do it.
Whatever it was.
The only thing that he has scheduled is
the radio city thing and that's because
I guess it's radio city.
You have to schedule.
What does he do?
He does a regular show there.
He's going to do.
He did it a few years ago.
Now he's going to do like maybe a week
and a half or two weeks of shows there
and he's going to guess on it like
musical guests,
comics some days like as that's amazing.
And I have a comics ball party.
That's a great idea.
Yeah,
that's a great idea.
Wow.
Yeah.
I mean he,
he does represent what we all considered
to be like the highest standard of a
real comic artists.
You know,
when uh,
you get together with a group of
Comedians and you look at like who's
doing it the right way.
I mean there's other ways to do it that
are really like more commercially
successful.
Louis is more commercially successful in
terms of like constantly chasing it
down,
but David's just also has that mythical
quality to it as well.
Like you're talking about turning down
the $50 million.
That has a big factor in how we look at
it too.
That's his biggest TV credit.
It's turning down and John.
Yeah,
and also like walking away from the
greatest sketch show the world's ever
known.
That is still,
to me in my eyes,
the greatest sketch show of all time.
They had a lot of funny.
That shit on there.
Oh,
as far as like hit or miss.
It's the best ever.
Like you can't compare like Saturday
night live has some great sketches but
there's a lot of turds in there too.
Mostly turns.
Yeah.
Just over the accumulation of years.
You've got a lot of bullshit and it's
also because of the format.
I mean they're trying to come up with a
new show every week.
It's brutal.
It's,
you know,
it's also like,
like when I was talking to Phil Hartman
when he had just come from Saturday
night live and he was on news radio.
He was talking about how competitive it
is,
their back stabby in fighting and all
this and everyone's fighting to get
their stuff on the earlier do.
I was like,
I don't.
And they don't care if it's the best or
funny like rack of backstab.
Someone with a good sketch to get my
okay.
Sketch on.
So I get some,
some time,
some shine.
Fuck it.
That's.
Well,
listen,
if you look at all the people that have
been on Saturday night live,
right,
how many of them?
You're like,
that guy was on site live.
There's a lot.
There's a lot of Saturday night live
used to be.
Holy Shit,
it's Dan Akroyd.
It's Gilda radner.
It's John Belushi.
It was people that were just chevy
chase.
People that were giant because they were
on Saturday night live.
If you were onsite live,
you fucking made it.
Now it's maybe what?
One out of 10 that you even know who the
fuck they are after they leave.
There's a lot of exercise.
A lot of people.
How about Darrell Hammond?
Darrell Hammond was on Sinai live for a
long fucking time,
but if you come up to the average person
say,
and he's a funny comment.
Do you remember Darrell from New York?
I remember there was a funny guy,
man before Saturday night live,
but it didn't translate into like big
movies are a lot of stuff.
You know?
That guy was really good.
I mean he was into really good sketches.
Tim Meadows,
whatever happened to Tim Meadows.
He's the one standup and it gets jobs,
but he's not big like he was when he's
on snl time.
Right.
I know there was a time when him and
pharaoh would kind of like neck and
neck,
like they both leave snl and what
happened here?
Like a couple of duds?
Yeah.
Was that one called?
Oh,
movie who was in?
Oh yeah,
ladies,
man.
Ladies.
Man killed it.
Yeah,
like that was like a record deal.
It's like when you get out,
you drop your first album and if it
doesn't hit to rap,
rap,
show business,
be stone cold.
Look at a man,
ladies.
Man.
He was funny in this movie too and that
was his character on snl.
Right?
Which means it's not even his movie.
Like Lauren gets the.
He gets all the movies,
like you created a character on snl.
It's like,
oh bitch,
that's my movie.
Like you can't just do it on your own
and then you cut loose and then it's
like,
well good luck.
I mean how many of them are there?
How many,
how many,
like really successful comedians have
come from sm snl versus how many have
been on probably crazy numbers,
right?
Yeah.
Here's the list of
a lot.
Almost everyone that's ever been on it.
I think it's a lot of people don't even
keep scrolling.
Oh,
well,
there's probably hundreds of people
forever.
He's doing stand up now.
I forgot Al Franken was on it.
Oh Shit.
Yeah,
he's a.
he's a senator now.
Yeah.
You want people want him to run for
President Joe Piscopo.
That's right.
He was the Jersey guy.
I'm from Jersey.
Are you from Jersey?
Where's Rachel dratch.
She was killing it.
Garrett Morris?
Yeah.
There's a lot of them.
And you forget Janeane Garofalo was on
snl.
Oh Shit,
I didn't know that.
I totally forgot that.
That's right.
Gilbert Godfrey,
Dennis Miller,
uberconference.
Shannon,
whenever that happened to molly,
she was huge on there.
She was huge off of their members.
She had a bunch of movies.
What happened to her?
I think one of the movies bombed.
She had like two and a bombed tall.
Takes a bath.
I didn't know Sarah Silverman was on
snl.
She was for a little bit,
I don't know anything.
I really barely,
barely,
barely pay attention,
but yeah,
that's A.
I mean if you look at all times,
get shows.
I mean snl had to do a live one every
week.
They had to do all new material every
Do it in front.
The studio audience,
do it,
live on television,
a lot of impediments,
but as far as overall quality,
best one ever Chappelle show.
Then what number two might be in living
color.
People forgot about it in living color.
That was hilarious.
And also came out swinging.
Handyman.
They had a handicap superhero.
Why you couldn't do that today?
You could do the fire Marshall Bill.
Get the fuck Outta here.
You can't do that.
That's,
that's,
that's just time.
But when I think about that time,
it's just time and insight.
Alright.
Can you do a sketch show?
He's at the comedy store.
His brothers.
They're fucking Jim Carey's there.
David Allen greer is around free
killers.
You just kill us.
Like just waiting for a shot now.
David.
David,
what's his name?
He was a skinny guy.
Tommy Davidson.
That's all this talent,
just just needing a shot and a fly girl,
Jennifer,
Jennifer Lopez.
Wow.
And the other Puerto Rican leader.
The fly girls.
I forgot her name right now.
Rosie Perez.
Like how much shit came out of that
show?
Crazy.
Even afterwards,
Jamie Foxx came on just careers that are
still going man.
And then there was mad tv where you'd
Watch mad TV will be on like seasoned
Tanney Blake that chose to what the
fuck.
But Mad TV had a bunch of great sketches
to people just forgot.
They had really good innovative sketches
to.
And that was like when people were
comparing inside Schumer,
like a lot of the shows they were saying
a lot of the episodes that were saying
we were ripped off,
ripped off from mad tv,
but part of that is because you run on a
premises like didn't the simpsons like
South Park always used to joke around
about like simpsons late.
They had episodes called Simpson's
already did it?
Yeah.
Because everything.
You're stealing from yourself because
you've got new riders.
Yeah.
There's like,
since it's been almost 20 years,
maybe longer,
east South Park's been on 20 years now,
so somebody who's been writing,
I think the simpsons or Ron Haiti's.
Yeah,
they might've been close to 30 years for
sure.
So somebody who's just been writing on
the simpsons five years,
just five years,
which is a long time,
can come up with a premise that was dead
in year 10 or the simpsons and not know
and everybody there,
they might've forgotten,
just fuck it,
let's do it.
Yeah.
It doesn't matter as long as you could
do it right.
It's like,
yeah,
no one's.
I mean there's got to be someone,
but no one can probably recall every
episode of the simpsons.
That's I'm probably wrong.
It's probably some real super fans out
there that can do it.
I'm sure you do.
They go,
Jamie's like,
I've got blood.
Yeah,
no,
for sure.
Yeah.
It seems like you get to a certain
number of episodes of things for sure.
They've covered virtually,
at least close to every subject,
but maybe not,
you know,
but the thing about cartoons though is
that you could just do anything.
This,
it's so much more beautiful in terms of
like,
wait,
you can get away with kill people.
They come back to life next week and
I'll have to explain it.
You know like South Park can do anything
it could do and their animation is so
crude and simple.
They whacked together a show in a matter
of minutes.
They can,
something happen today.
They can put a show up tomorrow.
They literally could.
I mean I'm sure there's such a well
oiled machine and then knight,
those guys work ethic is just insane
that Trey Parker guys off the charts.
They got rock work ethic.
Yeah.
Like during their brain they bring you.
I wonder what that's about.
Like what keeps a person going that hard
for so long.
I know like because it can't be the
money.
I wonder.
I mean it's gotta be the creativity.
It's just got to be psych.
Just seeing the finished product,
but they're also like very socially
responsible.
You know,
like they'll,
they'll shit on people and things go bad
in the news and they'll,
they'll come after people know.
I liked that about them.
I do too.
Yeah man.
Well that Carlos,
when Kanye West Phish Dick's episode,
Jesus Christ,
and that was when he was on comedy
central,
there was like,
whoa.
They went hard and team America,
world police.
They do that on the side.
Like what?
In the book of Mormon?
Yeah.
Just just super creative guys.
Hey Man.
Makes you feel lazy.
Yeah,
there's a lot of people out there
apparently make me feel lazy.
Yours,
your schedule.
You keep going,
right?
How the fuck is he doing this shit?
Coffee,
coffee,
some deep seated desire to figure things
out.
I don't know.
I wonder.
I like to do a lot of shit that's not
work related to leaning more towards
doing more of that lately.
I think that after a certain point,
at a certain point in time,
I can't keep doing three things.
Can't keep working for the UFC doing a
podcast and doing standup.
I'm going to have to chop it down to two
or one some day it will be just stand up
occasionally standing occasionally.
Yeah.
I mean you get to a certain point.
You mean?
Do you want to just,
um,
I don't know.
I guess stand up,
I don't really have a burnout feeling
because I always create new stuff every
couple of years and it's always about
putting it together,
but I mean how many more years are you
going to want to do that?
Like so what's like,
what's your ultimate like later on
future goal?
Let's say even five years from now,
like what?
What do you think would make you happy
doing does the part of the problem?
I don't have any goals of zero goals.
This is my goal.
Do the best standup I could do.
Try to do the best podcasts I can do,
do the best job when I'm doing
commentary.
Just do the best I could do while I'm
doing it and enjoy it.
That's simple enough.
Yeah,
that's it.
I don't really have like a,
you know,
I wanna make x amount of money or x
amount of.
I don't,
I just don't want it to suck.
Right.
My,
my whole motivation is don't put
anything that sucks.
Put out things that people enjoy.
Figure out a way to make it enjoyable.
Do put all your effort into it because I
know that if I don't do that,
I will feel like shit.
Right.
I know if I like have a show that's not
so good and we've all had those,
or a podcast is not so good and I've
definitely had those just don't.
It does not feel good.
Right?
They don't always come out perfect.
There's no way around that.
Especially when we're doing these live
shows.
Man,
live shows have so many variables.
The time of the show,
how tired the audiences,
how tired you are,
how you've been traveling,
are you sick,
you know?
Um,
there's so many things that can affect
like how you performance comes out.
Even if you like consciously try to pump
yourself up.
I've had some bad shows when I,
when I wasn't feeling good.
That's hard,
right?
When you just don't have the energy or
the feeling in the bits the same because
you're feeling sick or bad.
Shows help you get better shows.
Therefore,
you know,
they're like,
you didn't do this,
do this next time.
They didn't do that work on that.
Also,
the sick feeling of like,
I don't let like a really good show.
I don't even like a show that's like,
that was pretty good.
I don't even like that.
Like if it's like,
that was pretty good.
I was like,
ugh.
Are we talking?
Standardizing it better?
Yeah.
I'm always like,
why isn't it better?
Why isn't it like my best show ever?
My last show might've been my best.
Whenever.
Why
isn't this one my new best one ever
different audience.
Different place venue.
I know,
but I mean that's,
I think that's my motivation.
That's what keeps me going.
Like trying to figure out how to weight,
uh,
and then also trying to figure out what
to do with my material.
Like should I be writing more stuff
here?
So I'd just be honing this down.
Like how do I approach,
should I toss some of this aside and
throw some new stuff in there and then
bring it back.
And it was constantly trying to make.
When you creating something like when
you created your CD,
don't you get that feeling sort of where
you're like,
okay,
I gotTa Kinda engineer this a little.
But I also got to kind of like let it be
itself,
right?
[inaudible] like just I'm,
I'm like that Kinda before I start doing
a joke,
like if I'm doing a joke and I'm like,
or if I think of a joke,
like my elimination process of what I
should or shouldn't do starts before I
started doing the joke.
The joke fits into my criteria.
Then I started doing it.
So then I'm not wasting time.
I don't feel like I'm wasting time from
the beginning.
Like I think creatively,
like I try to do the things that I
really like to talk about so then I
don't have to worry about later on
looking at the whole thing as much and
saying I got to lose this and I got to
lose that.
So I started early.
So then the things that I'm talking
about,
I'm already feeling them.
It's just sometimes when you hold onto
things a long time and you're doing them
for a long time,
you don't feel it,
then you don't feel it anymore and the
audience tells you you're not feeling it
anymore based on the reaction you get
now.
And from when the reaction you used to
get and you could feel that thing
getting tired.
That's why I always say that standup,
is it some sort of massive gnosis?
It's very similar.
It's not like someone's tricking you or
telling you what to do.
We're going to get you to quit smoking.
Not In that way.
But when the guys on stage,
like if I'm in the back of the room and
I'm watching you and you're killing.
One of the things that's really funny is
I start thinking the way you're thinking
when you crack a joke about something,
it's like I'm in your group and I'm
letting you do all the thinking for me.
Like if you watch a really good comic,
like,
like if I'm watching you,
if I'm in the back of the room and I'm
watching you,
I don't have any.
I just let you do all the thinking
because I know you know,
I know you know what you're doing.
I know you're going to take it down a
funny place.
It's going to be great.
Here we go.
Just let it happen.
But the moment that you don't trust that
person anymore moment they fuck up or
something goes weird and the spell gets
broken,
you know,
and then you're like,
oh,
that guy's just fucked up.
That joke.
This joke sucks.
Now this joke's not good.
I'm not gonna.
Let them think for me anymore.
Oh,
this,
this subjects terrible.
All the subjects.
Just gross.
I was just trying to get noises out of
me now,
you know?
Yeah.
You,
you gotta earn the audience's trust to
you copilot.
The evening 100 percent and take over.
Yeah.
And just relax and listen to you.
And you could take it and you bring it
back as possible to,
as long as you're like real honest about
what's happening.
Yeah.
Like when I was just,
when Montreal,
we did a show before,
so we have a warm up show so we're going
to tape the lol thing.
And so they give you a warm up show.
So I started.
So do you have eight minutes?
And there's other comics on the show.
So in the first,
I don't even know what jokes I'm going
to do for the lol thing because
everybody's like,
what is the lol thing?
It's like Kevin Hart's new network.
Oh,
okay.
And then you're going to do it an eight
minute segment on it and to network.
It's a network.
What's he going to put it on?
The thing is on the Internet.
Oh,
okay.
Yeah.
So there's a lot.
So it's a whole like Internet channel
and it's all comedy.
So he's doing scripted,
he's taping Mike stand up shows where
the host and the people who have half an
hours on it.
So I just went to do like an eight
minute segment and during the warm up
show some chick was just talking in the
beginning of my set and talking to you
or just talking,
talking to a girlfriend who sit in.
The first joke went well,
but then I have to stop and say,
are you going to shut the fuck up and we
should,
you know what?
I'm going to have you kicked out.
And nobody in the club moved.
And she's like,
no you're not.
She said,
I said,
all right,
we'll see.
We're going to have to kicked out.
And I said,
who's running this shit?
And this is the eight dot.
I only have eight minutes and I got to
get back on track.
She said,
no,
you're not.
Wow.
So she thought she could just talk.
Yeah,
she goes,
that's.
And you know what?
The club did not kick her out.
You see us do your whole set with her
sitting there?
Yeah,
but I got them back on track because
they did want her to shut up and she did
shut up.
But the defiance I've never.
And then some con Canadian comic later
on it's like,
you know what,
you should write the club because we
have this prop in the club every time,
but if you write a letter to the owner
and tell them they never have security
here.
And it was a comedy nest.
Oh,
in Montreal.
Montreal.
I've been in that spot before.
Does the comedy works.
So they're the little tiny spot I think
is still there.
That place is amazing.
Yeah.
It's like a place upstairs.
It's just like a little fucking room,
a hotbox dude.
There's like 80 people.
Yeah,
like maybe I did a one man show in there
like two years ago.
They're like an hour and they're fucking
amazing.
Yeah.
My Charles is an interesting place.
You know,
it's a funny thing too,
like during the festival,
it's like a becomes like this really
intense environment for comedians.
A lot of pressure.
People go there to be seen kill here to
make deals,
development deals and shit from
Montreal.
So weird.
We're thinking we got to go to another
country.
Going to a country that doesn't even
speak English.
I mean in,
in Quebec they were English,
French,
French chat refuses to speak English.
Well that one section,
one section,
but it is kind of like visiting another
land.
It doesn't feel like,
like if you go to Toronto it might as
well be Detroit or something.
I mean it's a nice city,
but I mean a little nicer than Detroit I
guess.
Sorry,
Detroit people get mad towards.
Come on Bro.
But okay.
Let's say Chicago might as well be
Chicago,
might as well be.
I mean it's just another big city.
It doesn't feel like you're in another
world.
If you go to Montreal you feel like you
might as well be in Europe.
Yeah.
Because people start instantly talking
to you in French.
Yeah.
And then then they realize you don't
know any French and then start talking
English without a French accent.
Yeah.
Like how do you know another language?
How do you know?
I get,
you know,
in another language,
but how do you do it without an accent?
Yeah.
How do you do it?
How do you sound straight up?
English speaking English.
How do you stand straight up French
without the English interruption in your
French accent.
It's crazy.
You.
Yeah.
How do you good switch.
I haven't been to Montreal on a wild
man.
Was there like a for a UFC maybe a year
ago or so?
I need to get back up there.
Yeah.
The women are beautiful.
They man.
It's an amazing place.
Amazing place.
Cold as fuck.
He in the winter?
Yeah.
I don't fuck with it in the winter.
I still winters up there.
Yeah.
So I could headline.
I've done shows up there in the winter,
but it's like in and out,
like they used to do shows that black
shows at this club called club soda.
Yeah,
I know club Soda.
I used to work there.
Yeah,
it was dope.
that was a nice.
That was a nice room.
It was a nice spot.
Yeah,
that's whenever I used to do the
festival.
I used to club soda are.
Oh Shit.
Oh,
club soda is great,
man.
I did.
Um,
I did,
uh,
the comedy from the danger zone,
but dom,
I rarer they're timing from club soda to
take to way back in the day,
way back in the day.
Dom irrera and I met in Montreal.
Have a great festival,
man.
It's like we call it like a comedy
summer camp for comics.
I,
yeah.
Talk about just all the comics pretty
much in the same hotel or spread out who
wrote a few hotels and you're just
hanging out laughing,
having fun in the lobby.
Everybody goes off to their shows.
Some people come to your shows,
he's just,
he's just having fun.
But when you're working,
how many go?
Uh,
it starts like two weeks,
right?
Yeah.
It's almost like two weeks.
[inaudible] they start like the ethnic
show and some other shows a week ahead
course.
Last week was last week was like the
last,
like the full full on like regular week.
The last week is.
Yeah.
It's um,
there's not another one.
They try to do a couple of the ones that
used to have an aspen ones,
which is really good.
I shut down.
You know why?
Because it was fucking executives.
They would just go skiing all day.
They didn't really want to watch the
shows.
They go to
the shows and be tired.
Fuck,
because there's no air and they'd been
skiing all day.
You know,
you ever been asking other than that?
Yeah,
and I caught the flu up there,
the worst flu I've ever had at the
festival because it was going around and
I was sick and I had to tape the TV show
and I mustered up enough energy to do
the taping and then I just slept in bed
for like two days.
And then I have to check out the thought
out of my hotel at 11,
but my flight wasn't till like seven.
Oh Shit.
So I'm like,
I'm like the worst flu ever that I've
ever had.
And you had to fly with it and had to
fly with it.
And when,
when I checked out this,
how bad I was when I checked out at 11,
the guy looked at me and I told him that
my flight was at seven.
He's like,
I'm going to give you a room so you
could sleep in.
Oh Wow.
Until your flight.
That saved my life.
Wow.
Let's lay down for like maybe three
hours that it helped.
It helped.
It helped me enough to have enough
energy to this.
And then you're at the airport and I
think the flight got delayed.
So now I'm like in the airport,
worst flu ever for like two hours.
When your immune system is compromised
like that to you,
it's amazing how little energy.
Yeah.
Like when people don't.
That's like a cliche.
That health is the most important thing.
You're like,
fuck up bitch.
Money's the most important thing.
The fuck out of here with your health.
I'll cough and count my cat feeling
great.
Not True.
Health is everything.
If you just feel a little shitty,
just a little shitty.
It markedly changes the way you look at
life.
If you cut your thumb right,
that changes your whole day.
It could,
right.
Especially if it gets infected.
Yeah.
That changes your whole.
If you stub your toe and that shit
hurts,
it changed.
Like any little thing could change your
whole day,
like healthwise,
stubbing your toe.
Don't judge Bro.
Nah,
but you know,
like,
you know,
like some type of hurt or cut or just
something he injury headache.
Yeah.
Changes everything.
Yup.
Yeah.
And um,
surgery.
Yeah.
In my buddy's wife,
got rotator cuff surgery just fucked up
for weeks apparently.
Just can't put your shirt on.
Ah,
agony.
I was like,
oh no that doesn't sound good.
Yeah.
Anytime something goes wrong.
But I think like overall health and
wellness is so fucking important.
Yeah,
for sure.
It's so important.
It's like there's so many people out
there that just don't take care of their
meat wagon.
You gotTa,
you gotTa take care of your meat
vehicle.
You have to,
you just,
you know what's really crazy to me,
like people that I know that don't take
care of their body.
And then they talk about being
depressed.
So what did you think?
You think you just say poor shit down
your whole and you would feel good,
right?
Like just no sleep and tons of
cigarettes.
Tons of booze.
And you thought you'd feel good,
right?
You shot right?
I don't know why I feel sick.
You don't.
Which has been filled with shit lately.
Doing the same thing over and over
again.
Taking drugs.
Wow.
So did you see
a walk to health?
I watched a,
a doctor's response to what the hell?
Watch this.
Because I had heard it was like some
crazy vegan propaganda is not based on
science at all.
Like they were trying to say that a fat
causes diabetes and fact that clogged up
and doctors that have looked at it,
there's been a ton of debunkers online
that have looked at it.
They said this is pseudoscience.
This is not real.
Like definitely a Vegan diet can be
healthy,
definitely taken a lot of vegetables,
can be really good for you and
definitely a,
it's good to have nutrient rich foods,
whether it's fresh vegetables or
whatever you want to eat and you could
absolutely,
if you,
if you're careful and you're smart about
your saturated fats and unsaturated fats
and um,
you know,
especially,
uh,
essential fatty acids and things like
that,
you can live a very healthy life is a
Vegan,
just do it right.
But these guys lie.
They went a little overboard.
They didn't just,
you don't just document what it is,
is a Vegan proselytizing like doc,
it's like you're trying to do is get
people to sign up for veganism but
scaring the shit out of with lies.
And you're saying things like saturated
fats and all these,
these things clog up your arteries that
causes diabetes.
That's not true.
Like in that in is what the health,
what is the same guys that made
cowspiracy exactly.
And they were wrong about that too.
When they came in here,
they were talking about how many acres
it takes for a cow to graze.
And all the negative aspects,
there's absolutely negative aspects when
it comes to animal agriculture and I
think it's super important to be honest
about those aspects.
Even when criticizing it,
you can't exaggerate it to make a case
look better because the actual facts are
disturbing enough.
Like especially factory farming when it
comes to like cows and chet and pigs,
it's disturbing to see them all stacked
up in there like that.
It's disturbing to see those rivers of
shit.
Where were people a run these pig farms
and the shit comes and he filmed it with
a drone,
one of these giant commercial places.
It's fucking disturbing.
That is straight up.
That's enough.
There's a ton of actual facts that are
disturbing and as soon as you have these
doctors that are just bullshit artists
that are saying all these things that
aren't supported by science and when
this one doctor goes over all the
different things and what the health
that are incorrect,
you kind of understand what it is they
mean.
Well,
I'm sure they mean what they're trying
to get people to quit eating processed
meat,
which is a very good idea.
Now,
processed food is fucking terrible for
whether it's a food with a lot of
preservatives,
meets with a lot of preservatives.
All that stuff is definitely 100
percent.
Not good for you,
but that doesn't mean that grassfed beef
is bad for you because it's not.
It doesn't mean that you can't have a
healthy diet with a salmon and fish,
different kinds of ocean fish,
scallops,
and use that as your primary protein
source and then vegetables and have like
a super healthy diet because you will.
You will have a super healthy diet and
you know there's a lot of arguments to
avoid dairy.
I think a lot of it depends on the
individual.
A good arguments,
a lot of really good arguments,
really good arguments in terms of your
immune system inflammation.
There's a lot of really good arguments
to avoid processed sugar.
There's a lot of really good arguments,
but I think it's like what we're talking
about earlier when you were talking
about if you found those,
those scrolls scrolls in Qumran,
you would kind of like,
wow,
this is what it's saying.
I get all the bitches.
You figure out a way to lean it towards
you will.
These people are clearly on team Vegan,
which is great and it's fine.
The way to be on team Vegan and do it
right is be healthy,
be nice and be honest,
be honest because it's good enough and
you're going to get plenty of those.
There's a lot of those out there.
No,
no.
I don't want to discredit them.
And there's a lot of,
uh,
there's a lot of crazy vegans to that
are just going to get mad at you.
And they just decided now that they're
Vegan to just attack everyone who's not
vegan.
I've seen those too.
But that's just humans,
right?
That's just,
that's just human shit.
Human Shit.
So I mean,
I know a ton of people that are very
happy being Vegan and you're one of
them,
you know,
and I fuck with you all the time about
it,
but you're a healthy dude.
You've always been healthy,
you know,
but you do it right.
Yeah,
I mean I've done it wrong.
Like I've been an unhealthy Vegan,
right?
Right now I got to stop fucking with
sodium.
What's wrong with sodium like this?
High blood blood pressure wise,
that doesn't really happen.
That's not the.
We'll know.
See,
that's another misconception.
The misconception about sodium is that
sodium is somehow or another the cause
of high blood pressure that was put
together by some bullshit ass doctor.
One doctor pull that,
pull up the myth of sodium.
This is crazy,
this story,
because so many people believe us as
high blood pressure.
A lot of it's genetic,
genetic,
genetic.
It could be,
you know,
dammit the sedentary lifestyle.
There's a lot of factors that sedentary
lifestyle.
Yeah,
you don't really work out.
I'm shaking up the salt myth.
Here you go.
Chris crusher was actually been on the
podcast before,
uh,
and all ages salt has been invested as
a,
with a significance for exceeding that
inherent in its natural properties.
I don't.
Okay.
That's a little wordy either.
I'm single,
most harmful.
Okay.
Here we go.
Uh,
it's been referred to as the single most
harmful substance in the food supply.
But it's salt.
Really dangerous.
New New News.
Taking up the salt myth.
Actually,
this is not what I'm looking for.
What I want you to do is just pull up,
um,
the conspiracy about how one doctor
wrote some bullshit paper about sodium.
You got that from scientific.
Okay.
Time to end the war on salt from
scientific America.
The zealous,
a drive by politicians to limit our salt
intake has little basis in science.
It's all bullshit.
Make that larger please.
Ms.
Dot shitty for so many are like,
how do we.
Yeah,
but we know what's real and what's not.
You know,
this is like it.
It started with a very clear beginning
for this.
There was a,
there was a bullshit study that someone
passed and you know there's also been a
ton of bullshit here.
It is 19.
Oh,
four French doctors reported that six of
their subjects who had high blood
pressure and known risk factor for heart
disease.
We're salt fiends,
worries escalated in the 19 seventies
when Brookhaven national laboratory is
Louis.
Dol claimed that he had unequivocal
unequivocal evidence that salt causes
hypertension.
He induced high blood pressure in rats
by feeding them the human equivalent of
500 grams of sodium today,
which is an insane amount today.
The average American consumes three
point four grams of sodium or eight
point four grams of salt a day.
A scroll up a little there.
Doll also discovered that the population
tends to continue to be cited as strong
evidence of a link between salt intake
and high blood pressure.
People living in countries with high
salt consumption such as Japan also tend
to have high blood pressure and more
strokes,
but as a paper pointed out several years
later in American journal of
hypertension,
scientists had little luck finding such
associations when they compare it.
Sodium intakes within populations which
suggested that genetics or other
cultural factors might be the culprit.
Anyway,
this 1977 study affected the US Senate
select committee on nutrition and human
needs and they released a report
recommending that Americans cut their
salt intake by 50 to 85 percent based
largely on dolls work,
so there's one dick fuck ruined it for
everybody.
The ones put salt in your fries like you
can get off of that,
but this is a salt is a mineral and it's
a natural part of being a human being.
It's an essential mineral essential
mineral.
It's like when you have endurance
athletes and they go on these crazy runs
and they do like a 100 miles.
They take salt.
That's one of the things they said.
Yeah,
they put salt in their body.
It wasn't data route.
It isn't gatorade a little bit.
We know what the best version of it
apparently health wise is that Himalayan
salt.
Right?
Because Himalayan salt has a bunch of
like natural based minerals in it.
Yeah.
They recommend you take a little bit of
him similarly and so I'll just drop a
little bit in your water in the morning
and put some lemon in there.
Right.
So,
so I,
I use data a little bit but I think with
Vegan food,
like probably based on my genetics
because they try to make it taste a
certain way.
They might put a lot of fucking salt in
there.
Oh okay.
So I think so,
but I could feel something towards
December,
like in my body whenever I ate.
So now that I've cut back on I like are
more and I'll just eat places that have
less salt because salt and shit.
But some people oversalt shit.
It also could be sugar,
sugar,
sugar too.
Well you should do honestly is I could
send you to a guy.
She gets some blood work done.
I did.
Some did.
What did he say it was?
It was,
it was the guy said salt.
Too much salt.
But that guy's a fucking idiot.
Jesus Christ.
You went to an idiot doctor.
Would you say you have too much salt,
but do you find sodium in your blood?
Like what is he saying?
Like my blood sugar was getting high.
What a fucking asshole.
This.
It's proven.
There's not a connection and this idiot
is telling you to cut back the salt.
How the fuck you supposed to trust
doctors when they're going to buy some
shit that they went to school with the
nitrogen in it.
But that's my point.
You can't trust anybody.
Everybody's.
If a doctor physician dot your age.
That motherfucker was in college in the
eighties.
Right?
So what the fuck?
That's a long goddamn time ago.
Today.
He was taught to shoot the,
you know,
10 years after the seventies,
people were idiots.
There were monkeys.
They had fucking bell bottoms on.
People were barely out of the caves.
Listen,
if I'm in the 19 seventies.
Yeah,
if you committed to be a doctor,
right?
And you learned everything that you
learned,
your,
your whole identity is being based on
what you know.
Right?
So if some new new shit comes up or if
you find out that something that you
were taught that's embedded in you is
not true,
yeah,
then you're going to fight that new
truth and stick to the,
to the old way because that fucks with
your identity and who you are and how
people perceive you to be.
There's also like peripheral knowledge
that people have.
And I'm guilty of this too.
Everybody is,
I guess,
but I'm guilty of it especially like you
get a little peripheral knowledge of
something that you think,
you know,
you understand what it is.
Like I was talking to a scientist and
actual scientist and uh,
I was talking about eggs,
you know,
we were talking about,
oh,
that's gotta be fun growing your own
chickens.
And he goes,
well,
what about the cholesterol doesn't end,
uh,
you know,
lead to high blood pressure.
You're taking in all that cholesterol.
I'm like,
Jesus Christ,
you're a fucking scientists.
Don't you understand that dietary
cholesterol doesn't even.
It barely even moves the needle on blood
lipids.
Like there's a lot of sedentary
lifestyle genetics.
There's all sorts of factors.
But like chickens,
like an eggs from chickens,
they're not bad for you at all.
In fact,
one of the healthiest foods you can eat,
if you're seeing that chicken eggs are
bad for you,
you're essentially saying that food is
bad for you.
You don't want to see what the bad
because they.
They shit all over eggs.
They're idiots.
They should all over the healthy grass
fed chicken or a a free range.
Chicken is wandering around.
Look,
Google egg might be the perfect food.
There's an article about eggs,
might be the perfect food because eggs
have a ton of nutrients in them and
they're also essentially pretty ethical,
like ethically free of any reservations
that chickens just lay eggs.
You don't have to hurt them.
Our eggs really?
Nature's perfect food.
Rotten eggs.
How a perfect food can go bad.
What is this?
This,
this,
the same article I don't think it is.
There's.
There's an article.
It doesn't matter if there's an article
that I read on how an egg is the perfect
food.
If you can find that.
It explains all the nutritional
properties of egg.
They just
so much shit from so many different
styles.
All I've learned to do is just trust
myself.
So the doctor telling me this thing
about salt,
right?
Fucking 80 was kind of like,
all right,
I could feel something wrong,
right?
I could feel something wrong.
So that data honestly felt so when he
said too much salt and then I know eaten
out a lot.
Let me stop you.
When you said you could feel something
wrong,
like what are you talking about?
Like what do you,
what are you experiencing?
Uh,
it's just a feeling like,
like in my veins or not,
I could just feel like I pay attention
to my body a lot.
You know,
alone.
Naked.
You don't know,
you're just after after I,
after I ate.
Okay.
I could feel something.
It wasn't in it and it was just,
just like,
this is,
I'm not supposed to feel this way.
And this was just from eating food.
Mostly.
Mostly
there are,
could feel this is carbo big fat snake.
Ribeye.
Fucking I don't,
I don't want to stay if I want some.
I want some elk.
Homie.
What'd you eat?
Yeah,
told you I would because it's free
range.
That's truly free range.
That's just free range to get the new
place.
When we have a new place set up,
I'm going to have one of these.
I'm a yoder grills,
like I want us pellet grills there.
I'm going to be able to grill on a spot.
We will document document in Edwards.
First meat consumption and how many
years will it be?
Over 10 for sure.
Wow.
Ten over 10 to do.
You might go crazy.
You might become a hunter is going to be
shooting shit off the roof.
Was fucking rearrange people.
Is that it?
Whole eggs are mostly.
That is it.
Whole eggs are amongst the most
abundant,
the most nutritious foods on earth and
so it made that a little larger there,
so you can see one egg contains vitamin
B,
12,
nine percent of the RDA,
vitamin B,
two,
Riboflavin,
15 percent of the rda of vitamin A,
six percent,
vitamin B,
five,
seven percent a selenium,
which is an important mineral.
Twenty two percent of the rda eggs also
contains small amounts of almost every
vitamin and mineral required by the
human body,
including calcium,
iron,
potassium,
zinc,
a Maganini.
I don't know what that is.
Manganese,
vitamin e full and many more.
A large egg contains 77 calories with
six grams of quality protein,
five grams of fat and trace amounts of
carbohydrates.
It's very important to realize that
almost all the nutrients are contained
in the yolk.
While the white contains only protein.
It's a fantastic food source,
and here's the thing about eggs,
man,
it doesn't hurt the chickens.
You're not hurting anything.
You're not harming anything.
If you have free range chickens,
you could just,
and I know a lot of people can't,
but know what,
if people buy actual free range chickens
or buy free range chicken eggs,
you're buying eggs from an animal that
just going to lay every day or every
other day.
It's not.
They don't get hurt.
And if you could figure out a way,
like the ideal thing would be like
communities having like co-ops,
we grow your own vegetables and you guys
have like a chicken coop that everybody
kind of helps take care of and these
chickens roam around and eat bugs and
worms and all the stuff they're supposed
to do.
And then you eat those chicken eggs and
it's like you get animal protein but you
don't have to hurt anything.
Nothing else to die.
And if you're getting a free range of
truly free range chicken,
egg,
it's super healthy and to SSA anything.
Otherwise I have to stop and now I can't
watch your show.
I can't watch your movie.
I can't listen to you talk because
you're not being honest like no one's
saying vegetables aren't honest.
There are.
Or a healthy rather.
Vegetables are super.
Beets are fantastic for you.
Kayla is amazing for you.
Carrots,
onions,
all these different things that come out
of the ground.
Yams,
sweet potatoes also.
Fantastic for you.
Nutrients.
It's all important.
That's where what's.
That's real food.
But.
So eggs,
nothing wrong with eating eggs.
Like my issue was I was just being a bad
vegan because you can be vegan and still
eat a lot of crap.
Yeah.
So and then like years of just eaten
crap is definitely gonna Affect you.
No matter.
Like,
like when somebody says to Vegan like
what are you eating because you could
eat bad shit.
Oh yeah.
So I just needed to cut back on the bad
shit,
you know what I mean?
Yeah.
Like stuff with sugar,
like the Vegan ice creams and just a
bunch of shit.
And so now I can,
I feel better.
It's like the feeling that you were
asking me about before.
It's almost like when you have a
headache but your headache is in your
body and most of the time I could
correlate it with when I was eating and
what I was eating.
So then now just like,
all right,
you've been eating some crap.
Like I think sodium is good,
salt is good for you,
but if you probably take too much it is
bad.
Let me stop you again because when
you're telling me you're getting blood
work done,
you're getting your blood work done to
check to see if you have high blood
pressure.
You're not getting your blood work done
while you're checking nutritional
levels.
I think they will checking for
everything,
but did they tell you you need more
vitamin B or Vitamin D or b,
12 or anything like that.
They took Niacin.
They never said that.
I got to call them.
I've got to call them a real.
A doctor that's going to do a real
nutritional profile of you is going to
concentrate on your nutrient intake,
is going to look at like tell you to eat
normal and then come in and do some
blood work and then maybe they do it
again in like six weeks or something
like that and they're going to check a
bunch of different things in.
Check your,
your hormone levels active,
a usable testosterone,
bunch of different things,
but it's really important is checking
your vitamin levels,
making sure that you really like this.
People have this weird idea that you get
everything you need from your diet.
You might,
you might get everything you need from
your diet depending on your hands,
on your diet,
and also depends on whether or not
you've checked.
Most people haven't checked or you don't
go to a doctor and check,
go get yourself checked out.
Find out like your nutrient levels,
find out what maybe you need some
vitamin D,
maybe it needs some b12 or b six.
Maybe they can find that your body is
low on Niacin or maybe they think that
consuming more essential fatty acids.
It'd be very good for you,
but you can go to a really good doctor,
a legit doctor that goes over that stuff
and is on the cutting edge of today's
modern science and they can greatly
enhance your ability to understand what
impact your diet is having my body,
because if you think you're eating
healthy and then they do like a
triglyceride count on you and they do
your blood sugar count.
Like Sam Harris.
A friend of mine just started.
He tried to be Vegan for a little while
and his.
He got his blood work done like on a
regular basis because he's smart guy and
wants to check his body out and he was
like,
dude,
it's not good.
Like there's too much sugar.
The glucose levels is a bunch of
different factors and forget like what
particular was,
but he had to switch to eating a wild
fish,
wild fish and then mostly Vegan.
Other than that,
cut out the dairy,
cut out the factory.
Farming.
Figured it out.
I mean,
I just think that there's a lot of bad
in modern diets.
There's a lot of bad in food
consumption.
We don't need to make stuff up.
We need to find out who's telling the
truth and the doctor telling you that
you need to cut your salt back and
that's what's giving you high blood
pressure.
That guy's an asshole.
He's an asshole.
Whether he realizes he's an asshole or
not,
he's not paying attention to the latest
shit.
He some dude,
it's probably
going or he's just a doctor.
Trust me.
I don't trust doctors per se.
You know what I'm saying?
Yeah.
Because a lot of them,
you know,
like everything else,
they like everything else.
It's like trusting a comedian to be
funny.
We all know someone,
some of them that just.
There's never going to happen.
Exactly.
And they called themselves can be.
Or even if they often they're being be
in the audience has no.
They got that shit from somewhere else.
That's true too.
Yeah.
So there's a lot of hacky doctors out
there.
Just bad doctors,
man.
There's a lot of really good ones.
Good ones too.
Yeah.
It's really good ones.
You just have to find them.
How old you?
Dr.
He must have been like maybe around 50.
Fuck him.
I hope he's on a treadmill right now and
he hears this so it just start googling.
Yeah.
Hypertension.
I don't know if he looked like he
doesn't google.
No,
I don't think he like just drank some
know.
What is this?
If you have high blood pressure,
salt still matters.
New Research examines these sodium
hypertension.
Mystery.
What does it say in comes from?
So if you have high blood pressure,
salt matters receptor that are.
Okay.
What does it say?
Her articles and yourselves and kidneys
continue continuously.
Where's this coming from?
First of all,
and this is an actual study goes well,
I don't like that to face.
We recently discovered a possible
explanation team study the hormone.
Angiotensin angiotensin helps regulate
your blood pressure when it binds to a
receptor called [inaudible] are and
turns it on the 81.
Our molecules in your cells of your
kidneys continuously regulate the levels
of sodium in the blood.
This relationship can be overactive in
some people,
which leads to high blood pressure.
There's hope in the forms of a drug
called 81 are blockers,
a true to their name.
These drugs block Ngo,
angiotensin from binding with our
thereby keeping blood pressure lower to
make these drugs even more effective.
Researchers want to understand the
molecular structure of 81 arm.
Okay,
so this is still important.
It's not a,
it's not the number one thing.
So it's not giving it to you,
but if you have it,
it may be a factor.
Correct.
So if you wonder what their levels are
they're talking about.
So like when you're talking about the
levels that didn't,
that test when they were given it to
rats and you give it 500 grams off song
wrap.
Yeah,
you definitely die from eating that
much.
So I think that we just need more
transparency and honesty and it comes to
what people actually know versus what
they're claiming to know.
You know when you're talking to a doctor
that's giving you shit advice.
Like I've,
I've talked to,
I've talked to a ton of doctors and say
like you can get everything you want
from the average American diet.
There's no need to take vitamins.
Your pm out.
That's straight up.
Shit.
I'll take b a to k,
take be twelfth.
If you take [inaudible] you know,
you're probably not really vague and
fuck it.
I'm trying to be,
I'm trying to be healthy.
I guess.
I don't care where it comes from them
this as long as a good sauce,
I don't feel good.
Baby eyelids.
Hey man,
babies should have defended themselves.
Those babies are here for a purpose.
Like what do you,
do you have like a main staple like a
that you like say if you're at home and
you cook it,
is there like a main thing that you
utilize?
Like wild rice,
wild rice or pasta?
Chemo was great and uh,
Chemo.
Chemo is one of those rare plants that
as like a full amino acid profile.
Right?
It's like hemp and a few other ones.
Yeah.
There's,
there's a few of those,
a protein rich plants,
like,
like some plants that have good amount
of protein in them.
I put hemp seeds in my,
in my,
in my smoothies.
That's good.
And Chia seeds.
Chia seeds are great too.
Yeah.
That also cleans your pipes out.
You know what I'm saying?
Whoa.
I put Kale in them so I,
you know.
Do you use coconut oil at all?
Yeah,
Cook with it or use it for other shit.
It's good to add.
Like if you make smoothies and shit like
that,
it's good to add because the Fascia put
something in there and helps the
absorption of the vitamins.
I had to learn that one the hard way.
Not the meat.
This adding mct oil to a shakes makes it
just makes it more nutritious,
but you've got to be careful because you
will shit yourself.
You have to be careful.
You can't,
you can't go too hard with the mct oil
or you can get like a few tablespoons in
a big glass of,
but anything more than that,
it's just something about it.
Your body's like just released the
house,
like your,
your,
your intestines.
A little bit,
but I think it feels like more than
that.
It almost feels.
It's not just like lube.
It's almost like your body's like,
what are you like,
ah,
too much shot him.
I'm not comfortable with this.
Let's go.
Everybody out.
Woo.
Yeah.
Just nothing like diarrhea that changed
your mind on things like if you had all
the money in the world,
but constant diarrhea,
diarrhea forever.
You could live like p diddy,
like two bottles of champagne,
one in each hand on a yacht,
but at any moment you could shoot
yourself.
That's not live.
It's not live.
It's not.
Nobody can accept that.
Yeah.
If you're on that yacht because you pay
some friends and hilarious and he was
like,
listen,
I'm rich.
We can hang out.
But occasionally I might shit myself and
know snickering.
Yeah,
you can't laugh at me man.
Running down as Miami vice shoes.
He's got those shoes.
No socks on.
Those white loafers dudes wearing shit.
Dribbling down or you have to wear those
diapers.
Yeah,
you'd have to wear the diaper.
But then everybody smells it.
The of the baby around me.
Oh,
what's good with dog?
And keep up the old dog shit.
So I was like,
what?
Come on baby.
It's not going to go change this baby.
Oh yeah.
If you have constant diarrhea,
that feeling that the only thing that
makes diarrhea,
okay is that you know it's eventually
going to go away.
Right?
Because if you just had to live forever
knowing at any moment you could just
shit yourself.
There's a lot of people that that's the
reality,
right?
People with Crohn's disease and shit
like that,
they're like constantly shitting
themselves.
That's where like butt wipes are very
important.
You can't be using like some cheap ass
costco toilet paper.
What's the thing where you just fall
asleep?
Automatically?
Narcolepsy.
It's like narcolepsy of the ass.
Controlling what if you had bolt just
fall down all the time whenever you had
to.
Shit.
Fall Asleep and that would be what would
happen.
You would have these ideas and shit,
man.
I just think I probably should get
through the fall asleep.
Wake up coverage.
Shit.
What the fuck?
It's like your body's trying to protect
you from the fact that it knows you're
going to shit yourself,
knows you can handle it.
It's like some drunks become blackout
drunks.
I think it drunk so hard so often their
bodies like,
look,
we can't handle this.
It's still be conscious if you're going
to continue to do this,
we're just gonna start blocking out
various.
When you wake up,
everybody's gone and you could just get
up and crawl home.
Yeah.
You just covered in without being
embarrassed every time you like,
you're in the middle of your kitchen.
I don't know if I'm going to make it to
the don't fall down.
Greg invited us over for dinner,
but uh,
he shits himself a lot.
Do you want to go to Greg's house is to
eat.
Greg shows up.
He could hear mostly his diaper.
Franklin sits down if you're a
narcoleptic,
like what's to stop you from banging
your fucking head off the ground and
that's a problem.
That's the scary part,
right?
The machine.
Someone Faint?
Uh,
yeah.
Yeah,
I know weird.
I've known people that have epileptic
seizures.
We don't know when those are going to
happen and you have to like stop them
from hurting themselves.
I've seen that on a plane.
Sorry.
The lady behind us just locked up,
thought she was just locked up.
Like her body just was like,
it wasn't working and she was trying to
fight it off and then they tried to like
calm her down and I think they tried to
get her to stop from swallowing or
tongue.
I don't know how they did they have to
do that.
Boom.
There was a bunch of people that's
around.
She was like a couple rows behind me.
Bunch of people jumped on the situation.
You stopped him from biting their
tongue.
Swallowing,
yeah.
Fuck.
And then,
uh,
it was like she locked up like you could
see like around people started,
like there was a commotion and turned
around and was like,
almost like she was like wrestling with
something which is probably what they
used to think right back in the day when
someone,
they thought you were possessed by the
devil.
Right?
Like if you believe in the devil,
he saw someone have a seizure like Satan
as her.
Yeah.
I wonder if they even bothered fixing
people back then they might have just
killed them,
or throw them in a dungeon.
Bright.
If you're having a fucking lockup
seizure during the inquisition,
they'd be sure there's the devil.
The devil is taken over you.
Dude.
That's the line that people don't like
to cross the believing in the devil
line.
Right?
Right.
What do you mean believing in it?
Talking about it.
Talking about.
Talk about God all day.
As soon as you talk about the devil,
you know,
like,
oh boy,
like he crossed the line.
People are afraid of that,
but people talk about God keep be
talking about God,
but you usually can't have one without
the other.
The devil is in the Bible,
so.
Yeah,
but it shows this the slow cultural
evolution that we were talking about.
We've realized how ridiculous it is to
think that some dude in a fiery pit with
a pitchfork,
unless you have one of the people that
listens to this,
still believes in that.
That's fine.
I'm not telling you right.
You might be right,
but for most people that's pretty
ridiculous,
right?
The.
Yeah,
that's.
He's going to torture you in the fires
of hell forever,
but there's a lot of religious belief,
but it's a package deal.
See,
that's what I'm saying is it's a weird
thing that will allow people to not
follow the package.
Like you know,
you don't have to buy the wax.
You can just get the,
the armor,
all the tires and you don't have to get
the wax part.
But this is where
the devil comes in.
The devil comes in to help scare people
into Christianity.
So if you're a preacher or a jail was
witnessed,
what somebody like,
if I'm going to scare you into being,
it's like scared straight.
If I'm going to scare you into being
good,
I gotta take you to prison so you could
see what prisoners.
Like if I'm gonna.
Part of being a Christian is not just
being good.
It's not.
You don't want to go to hell.
So I got to give you these stories of
people in Hell and paint this picture so
that you make this choice that I want
you to make.
So the devil is a very important thing
in making people.
Christians
used to be.
But now things are getting more and more
slippery because it's more and more
ridiculous because more and more people
are making fun of Christianity.
So now it's like you don't bring up the
devil,
right?
So like if the president could go on on
television,
say God bless America,
we are a nation governed by God.
Everybody goes,
yeah,
but if he says we have located the
devil,
he's in Afghanistan.
We're sending troops to that area.
And people were like,
what?
What the fuck are you talking about?
Man?
You can't say the devil is a real thing.
I know.
It's like a.
The problem is the devil.
If trump got on TV,
sorry,
saying when I said grab them by the
Pussy,
that was not me.
That was the devil speaking through me
and now I understand and everybody would
clap.
The devil is in our heart and our soul
and we need to stop him from ruining
life on earth before Jesus returns and
offers us eternal salvation.
Right?
You could.
You could almost imagine someone saying
like that,
but not someone saying something like
that,
but not quite.
They would like.
I always think like you ever seen those
core cases where somebody said they
heard voices.
Yes.
And then they killed somebody,
right?
Right.
So that's a of schizophrenia.
So that person's on trial.
That person's on trial and then
everybody's looking at that person like
they're crazy.
Right?
Right,
right.
But before that,
the people who testified against that
guy testified they have to put their
hand on the Bible and swear to God that
they can't see to give testimony that
this person is crazy.
What is the difference?
He said he heard voices.
Your swearing to something you can't
see.
So help me God.
So yeah.
What?
What's the difference?
Yeah,
you're,
you're swearing to an imaginary make
believe person,
right?
That may or may not have created the
entire universe and six days.
Okay?
So they might not be crazy,
but this guy's crazy.
Yeah.
This guy's hearing voices to tell them
to kill.
Fall off from this guy or you.
Yeah.
Who Have you talked to?
God.
I have a personal relationship with God.
I talked to God every night.
That was the thing about Bush to use
drive me crazy.
When you say talked to God,
like,
listen motherfucker,
you might be talking to Adam unless
God's talking back.
You're not really having a conversation
because people could be telling me,
I talked to Joe Rogan every night
because you just,
you listening to the podcast goes,
shut the fuck up.
God Damn.
You can tell that story again.
You're not really talking to me,
man.
Okay.
You're talking at me.
I'm not there.
The last thing George did was talk to
God every night.
The last thing he did,
every evening I talked to God.
He gives me my plans.
No,
I talked to Ian Edwards every evening.
I listened to his podcast about soccer.
Excuse me.
I mean football and I started screaming
at them.
So there's.
Yeah,
you don't.
You don't hear too many people saying
they actually heard from God because
that's where it gets slippery.
Like you could talk to God all crazy.
Yeah.
You sound like a nut.
Well,
I got a bit that I've been doing lately
about how no one likes new miracles.
Yeah.
You know that.
I don't even know if I heard that bit,
but you're right.
It's like we like old man.
He believed the ones that happened in
the Bible.
If somebody says this miracle happened
to them,
they were crazy,
but don't you believe in God?
Well,
we'll get to like Joseph Smith,
Joseph Smith.
That's the bounds of incredulity cause
that's the 18 hundreds.
I think it was 18,
20.
Was it 18?
He's found the golden tablets that
contained the work of the last work of
Jesus and only he could read them
because he had a magic seer stone that
he would look through.
The angels came and took it away.
Like all of it was like crazy miracle
stuff,
but it's all just long enough just long
enough ago where people go,
oh,
maybe it was still going on back then,
right?
Yeah,
yeah.
Maybe,
but not in 2017.
No,
you can't come.
You can come with that unless you got
some super proof.
But now people are not going to believe
that super proof anymore because of all
this three d rendering software and
adobe photoshop.
And have you seen that thing?
We were talking about it yesterday.
They're able to,
uh,
you could talk for 20 minutes and
they'll take your voice and you
essentially over 20 minutes they find
everything you've ever said,
all the noises that you can make in 20
minutes or 40 minutes,
40 minutes.
Actually they could do it in 20,
but they prefer 40.
So they could make you say words you've
never said before.
Like you could say,
uh,
hey,
joe and Jamie,
let's do a podcast.
And they could say,
hey,
Joe and Jamie and Mike and Steve and
Debbie,
let's do a podcast.
And he'd be like,
what the fuck?
I never said Mike and Steven,
Debbie,
they can make your voice say those
things with,
with new computer software and they
can't.
So what evidence is evidence now in
court?
That's the point.
The point is it's getting so close to
being impossible to tell.
If something's fake.
Like right now,
they can still kind of tell,
like still a little clunky,
but it's a few years away from being
indiscernible you're not going to be
able to tell me,
get manufacturer anything.
Yeah,
it's crazy.
It's,
it's really,
it's going to be really interesting
because they're also going to be able to
have people like you won't have to like
bring John Wayne back to life to have a
John Wayne movie.
You could have a fake John Wayne.
You have hours and hours of John Wayne
talking.
You take that,
you throw it into a computer
and it can.
You could write a script like you could
write a script or John Wayne is in some
new high tech Western movie.
Didn't they make a star wars rogue one?
Did they do some shit like that?
They added a princess Leia in it.
She was after she was dead.
She was and they made her younger than
she already was one of the guys.
The admiral.
Was it good alert by the way,
a son of a bitch.
I haven't even seen that movie bad since
Christmas.
Have you guys been paying attention to
all this shit stirring that William
Shatner has been doing online.
William Shatner is is at war with social
justice warriors on twitter.
William Shatner.
He's like shit.
Posting online and getting these people
mad at him and they're mad and they're
saying that your whole show star track
was about social justice and here you
are mocking social justice warriors.
There was an article in huff post which
is like the Super Liberal Rag,
like should William Shatner's like
abhorrent behavior or something like
that.
I have a race abberant,
a racist star trek legacy like that,
like literally bad behavior online.
Find that article because it's so
ridiculous.
But he's essentially.
I'm just fucking with people call them
snowflakes and shit and people going
nuts.
But
what's,
how bad is he?
What was he saying?
Nothing that bad.
Then they're,
you just want them to tow the line and
they also want him to be like humble and
grateful for being on Star Trek.
But he's like,
Hey folks,
it was just a TV show.
Lighten the fuck up.
And they're like,
it's just a TV show with social justice
as its primary values and here you are.
We expect you to be so with that TV show
dot.
Yeah,
he's Canadian too,
by the way.
Oh Shit.
Yeah.
No,
they're not foreign now.
He's wrong.
Yeah,
that's what I'm saying.
Um,
but uh,
I don't know like what they're arguing
about.
It's hard.
I can't scroll back far enough to find
out what they want to argue.
Oh yeah,
for sure.
I think he's awful.
I remember when you didn't know that
William Shatner was so awful.
I guess I'll people tweet that like all
these weird social justice warriors,
women I relax.
Why waste your time?
Those are got shit to do.
People 80 year old man living alone or
do you think he's all.
He's got all these models.
There is 80 isn't he?
Isn't William Shatner only should be
about this is what according to this
article,
this is what the fight was about.
Came from some show called outlander.
Okay.
An
outlander fans,
the actor calling them snowflakes and
social justice warriors is intricate and
fascinating in a way that only fandom
beef involving an internationally famous
cultural icon can be.
But to get the full picture,
we have to take a trip back in time to,
to,
to Schachner who acquitted with this guy
hugans you can you assist the prayer.
Okay.
Uh,
believe the two stars,
the show,
Sam Hugans,
Hewkin and Caitriona Balfe should.
And real life.
Huh?
There's a group of fans,
people that love the show,
that thing of shippers,
they call themselves fans of a show who
wants to see the two characters in a
relationship.
They believe the two stars of the show,
Sam and Catriona should date in real
life,
and it particularly hard line group of
fandom bolsheviks that believed that
they already are dating in secret and
Schachner who's acquainted with,
uh,
one of the guys waded into the fray,
labeling those shippers,
those people as bullies and calling them
out on twitter.
It was a move that many fans also saw as
its own kind of bullying with shatner
trying to kick a group out of fandom for
more nuanced,
a walkthrough.
There's an explanation,
blah,
blah.
Fast forward.
Okay.
He'd gotten a fucking goofy war with
trolls.
Yeah.
Here's some of the tweets and stuff.
Oh,
this is weird.
So he's.
What does it.
Hold it.
Stop back up.
Funny how an actress with an impressive
resume is belittled by same feminists
who say that an 86 year old man telling
the truth is a massage.
[inaudible] 86.
I can't believe that he's going to
check.
No.
80 six.
Yeah.
Google it.
Take a guess.
How old do you think he is?
I bet that's right.
That's it.
He's in his eighties.
That's correct.
It's got to be.
When you're that close to death,
do you really give a fuck enough to
argue with people on twitter about who's
dating who?
That seems weird.
It says 86.
Wow.
It's pretty good for 86 does,
but like what is that like wire.
Why are they going back and forth like
that?
Seems like such a waste of time.
You're 86.
Want to.
How much time do you have when you're
86?
If you're super lucky.
You got 10 years.
Sometimes.
Old People like to argue it gives them
strength and energy.
It's like a vitamins.
Yeah.
Excuse me.
Fucking something up a fight.
You know,
terrorism up the game.
Yeah,
like a fucking sport.
Yeah.
They get tired.
They just need that adrenaline rush,
need anger fueled,
fueled by anger.
Anger is energy.
It's an adrenaline rush.
You just don't do.
You don't dive into the fray with dorks
though.
That's where like that whole gamer gate
went crazy.
You know,
like when women were trying to,
uh,
there was a bunch of women that were
trying to,
they wanted to,
there was a bunch of stuff going on with
video games,
but they were concerned with sexism and
video games and they were trying to
censor video games than the,
you know,
are bullying people that believed one
way and bullying people that believe in
another way.
And then it became a,
uh,
dispute a nerd fight.
As soon as you get involved in any sort
of nerdfighter,
no matter what side you're on,
it's going to be some chaos.
There's a lot of angry,
repeatable.
Don't,
can't even waste time doing
that shit.
You fuck with video games or use it.
But I put that shit away like 10 years
ago.
What happened when you quit?
It was video games to take it up.
A lot of my time.
All this fun stuff.
Fuck video games.
Fuck me.
Fuck blow jobs too.
I was taking up a lot of my time but
then.
But then porn became accessible and it
took that.
Took that video game time away with
damn.
Really?
How much video games and jerking off and
you're doing that seems like I can't do.
Uh,
both.
Man.
Could you have got to choose one?
How could you swap them though?
I feel like you'd dig with.
I just think it's just time wasted.
Yeah.
Time wasted in and your hands are
involved.
That's true.
Coordination.
Have you ever fucked with virtual
reality?
Have you ever tried out any of those?
Those points?
No,
just,
I mean just trying those uh,
those headsets,
like oculus rift or any of that stuff.
HTC Vive tried those.
Like I don't remember the games.
I've been to places where they have the
samples and you could put it on and then
try it out long time ago now let's
recently like try to.
I try to game at south by southwest,
was trying to,
like the helicopter was over there and I
had the thing on and I was like flying
it and try to move it,
but I don't know what the name of the
game was.
What did you do at South by southwest?
I did a show there and then I went to
the,
to the in order main convention center.
Let me ask you this,
why shouldn't they pay you to perform at
south by southwest?
Yeah.
Yeah,
they did.
They have to pay now.
Yeah.
Dude,
they didn't.
They were not paying?
No,
they weren't for the longest time.
Oh Shit.
You would just go and it would be like
you'd performed.
There was a privilege.
I went there,
I went there twice.
I went there last year with and that
was,
I was taping a show for showtime.
Showtime paid you so time paid.
And then I went this year and it was
just a show at a club and uh,
they pay for that.
They flew out,
flew me out,
put me up and pay you for that.
I got an offer once and what they
offered me is if I came down there and
did their thing,
I would get a free pass to allow me to
go to all the shows and it was worth
like 1500 bucks.
I was like,
are you out of your fucking mind?
But they don't pay for your hotel.
They didn't pay for your flight.
They just offered.
I was like,
maybe this is just like one faction of
this organization that thinks it's a
good idea to offer that to people.
You know who's doing that bumper shoot?
What's bumper?
Shoot?
It's a music festival like I've done
bonaroo.
They pay you,
they fly you out and they put you up.
Bumper shoot.
It's in Seattle.
It's at the end of August.
Going into the August 31st going into
September third and basically what
they're paying me covers my hotel room.
I have to pay to pretty much fly there,
but I go to this music festival just
ridiculous.
It is ridiculous.
You're going to do it.
I'm just doing it for the fun of going
to the music festival.
Why would you do that?
You're going to,
you're going to be in Seattle this
Friday night with me.
Hey.
All right.
That's.
You have
to go back for that bullshit.
Yeah.
Friday night.
Paramount theater to shows.
No doubt.
Some tickets available for the second
show.
Joe Rogan.net
for this last tour.
Yeah.
Um,
Seattle's the shit though.
It's a place to perform,
but I'm not going there for free.
That's stupid because you know someone's
making money.
They wouldn't ask you to go if it wasn't
somebody is making money.
That's just gross.
That's what they were doing with south
by southwest.
Duncan did a video explaining it when
they offered it to him.
Hilarious.
He did a video with a,
you know,
that Hitler video where Hitler was like
yelling at a bunch of German and the
subtitles and Duncan subtitles.
We're all about like south by southwest
like,
oh,
they get people to work for free.
It's just,
it's a fucking airlines.
It's run by a giant corporation.
Like you can't pretend that it's like
some hippie sort of a.
They making good billions.
I mean he must be this giant right and
bumper.
She was making money.
So what are they doing?
I don't know.
They don't.
They're not giving it to the comics.
Fuck yeah.
Yeah.
We need to come up with their own
festival.
I've been thinking about this.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
To come up with something to do out here
that would kill.
Yeah.
We'll definitely run it through the ice
house to shows every night.
Both.
Both rooms.
A little room in the big room.
Do it for like a week.
Yeah.
You know,
there are definitely some crazy.
Yeah,
right.
Yeah.
But do an intimate,
small,
small venue.
Think about it.
I wouldn't want to organize that though
and I wouldn't want to like say no to
someone who sucks,
you know?
They're like,
hey,
yeah,
so here's a schedule.
And I'm like,
why is that guy out there?
That's the problem.
Yeah,
that's the problem.
Like I was talking to Al Magical about
that.
He's talking about putting together that
comedy network.
There's a couple of people on this
He's like
the fuck you gotta.
Be careful,
you know?
Got To be careful putting together a
network of people.
Yeah.
Because some people are either unaware
or just belligerently don't care.
They just want to get on.
Yeah.
And they'll try to force their way in
and yeah.
Do you uh,
that that's an issue with podcasts?
People try to force their way on your
podcast,
that corner you asked you.
I get that shit all the time.
People that just,
there's no way I would have them on the
corner me and want to get on the
podcast.
I'm like,
Jesus,
this way you think works and just get.
If I wanted you to be honest,
ask you they have nothing.
They have nothing to lose.
Yeah,
sure.
Act.
I want to.
I want you to watch her act with me.
It was go over together,
sit down there with a yellow legal pad
and go,
what the fuck is that?
So there is,
it's just a personality.
Conflict is a real problem.
It's not even like the material as much
as who they are.
Some people you just don't.
Some people are just not that aware.
They don't make good conversationalists
you don't want to be around them.
Right.
Especially some people like based on the
material,
like you're not a good
conversationalist.
Yeah,
yeah.
If you're talking about that,
it's just.
I don't know.
I get it.
People
want to promote themselves,
they want things to go ahead,
but like sometimes it's like how much
should we be promoting yourself,
how much you should be working on
improving yourself.
And there's,
there was always those people that were
like really good promoters,
but they didn't have a really good
product,
but they have enough of a good product
that the promotion sort of carry their
product and the enthusiasm behind it got
people into it.
I call it the Hustle Gino.
Oh wish I had more of the hustle gene,
you know what I mean?
But then I wonder how much of my
creativity would have to sacrifice for
the wholesale Jean.
And
it's a conundrum,
you know,
it seems like the people who really
hustle aren't as good as the most
creative.
That's what it feels like.
Yeah.
That's what it really feels like.
It does feel like that.
So that's the scary thing.
Especially the promotional gene.
Yeah.
The promotional genes.
And Weird one,
you know,
those dudes that like early on open mic
nights they were starting their own open
mic and putting up flyers and say like,
what,
how are you so confident?
You know,
I'm not inviting anybody throw it out of
here out at all.
It was the last time you showed up at an
open mic into the set.
Oh Shit.
Uh,
I went back to,
I didn't do a set.
We went to Madison,
Wisconsin to do the weekend at comedy on
state and then his pizza shop that has
an open mic.
So after the show on I think Thursday
night we went to the pizza shop and we
put our names on a list.
But then they ended the show before.
So it was like,
I want it to do it.
Was it too many people that signed up?
Is that what it,
is that what you're saying?
It was like we got there because we just
did a show.
We got there towards the end of the few
audience members were leaving.
That's the thing about open mics,
like some comics are new and they're not
that good.
So how much is the audience going to sit
through?
You know,
they might've sat through five back
conferences,
lot to sit through and you might have
sat through more.
Oh yeah.
So then they don't know who's coming up
next.
Well that's what's weird about the store
these days.
Even the open mic night.
It's packed.
Yeah.
Have you noticed it's crazy.
Go to open mic now.
There's 100 people in the audience and
you're like,
whoa.
But they're putting some of the store
comics on those shows too.
Smart.
They're smart.
It is smart.
But there's something about a like a
real regular open mic night.
It's just like the.
This is the first sparks from a piece of
metal and a rock.
When you start a fire feel,
that's a thing where people try to make
fire kill you.
Bang comedy.
That's like the first sparks and you see
it and you're like,
Ooh.
It makes me nervous.
Yeah,
it is kind of nerve wracking.
I used to do them a lot when I first
moved out here just to get stage time
because I,
I kind of refuse to like audition to get
in the comedy store.
At first I was like,
I've already done TV spots.
I got to audition to get
in the store until,
until I really got it and they said,
you know what,
you need to get them to the store and to
the laugh factory.
And then I was writing a lot so I was
like,
Yay.
But then when I realized that the night
I got into the store was like one of the
best nights in show business for me.
Oh yeah,
right.
It's like validation.
Yeah.
You're paid regular.
And I was like,
I can work out in 15 minute chunks,
right.
Material I call my manager has just
gotten to stories like I've never heard
you excited about anything.
What's the big deal?
And I was like,
Yo,
don't you understand?
I could work out.
Yeah,
it's the store.
He didn't get it.
You're in Mecca.
Yeah,
that's what it is.
Yeah.
When you pull into that parking lot and
you get out and you go say hi to
everybody and you want it to those
hallways,
you see,
oh,
ours kill.
And you go into the main rooms packed
someone's crushing,
you go upstairs to belly room poem.
Someone's upstairs smashing.
It's like you just stepped into the
comedy Mecca,
you know?
And to be a part of that,
to be allowed to be a part of that.
And it's funny,
it's like there's so many up and coming
young comics that want to get in there
and look up to it,
you know,
now and now it's like,
it's just,
just bananas.
It's interesting seeing it again.
Right.
We were talking about the other day,
what it used to be like,
what is what it's like now.
This is the golden age.
Yeah.
I got in there when it used to be like.
And I was still excited because I just
knew I'd be able to develop their right,
you know,
so that was,
that was useful like when I started
because before I kinda wasn't taking
comedy serious and then like I kinda
just got tired of it and kind of fell
out of love with it.
Well,
you're doing a lot of writing.
I'm going to do so much.
Staff writing,
you know,
and you're showing up at that job every
day.
Writing.
Sometimes it takes away your motivation
for sure.
Did the.
And then for some reason let's say he's
trying to get back,
get into these clubs,
the laugh factory and the store and
started my desire started increasing for
stand up.
You got to put it out.
Specials on.
Yeah.
No.
What are you going to do on?
I had to just shoot it myself,
like you've been telling me.
Yeah.
So hopefully by the end of the year,
a few months.
Yeah,
do it.
Definitely.
Yeah.
He's needs to happen.
People need to see your set and then you
need to throw it out and write new shit
to you too.
Good.
Yeah.
I'm saying I'm sitting on stuff because
I haven't used it,
but the only way to write new shit like
have new shit,
but I would have morning shit if I had a
special and got rid of the oldest ship.
Well,
you know what I want to do,
man,
after I do my next a Netflix special.
I want to do like a Rodney dangerfield
type thing where I bring up a bunch of
what I think of the best up and coming
comics and have like a special.
Like Rodney dangerfield used to have
those specials spiel.
Yeah.
I want to do something like that.
I'll just host it,
bring people up.
That's my next move.
The Nice House or something.
It'd be cool.
Yeah,
exactly.
Yeah.
Doing now that the ice house.
Because Rodney dangerfield used to the
danger fields.
New York City.
Yeah.
Man.
You ever worked that place?
Yeah.
Shit Hole.
It's not what it used to be fun though.
So great old place.
They had great cheeseburgers.
They had the best cheeseburgers in New
York City.
Man,
when you used to work there needs to be
able to get a cheat.
I was excited to eat a cheeseburger
there.
They had amazing cheeseburgers.
They like Ground Philemon neon or
something like that.
Good stuff was simple.
Like when I used to do a spot at the
strip,
like on a Monday night after you picked
a number out of the hat on a Friday and
you get one Monday out of the month to
perform and then me and the open mic
because we're like let's go to Jackson
hole and eat a burger.
Like at midnight.
Yeah.
And just like just felt so accomplished,
you know,
just just doing this artist thing or
this comedy thing and you eaten like you
heard about Jackson hole or just
someplace and you're eating there.
We used to dream about let's go to
Carnegie Deli because all these comics
used to sit there and eat and shit like
that.
Man.
I just romantic New York comedy,
Shit like that.
It was like that store too.
It's carnies a little,
a little in the standard going across
the channel.
The standard late at night after shows I
used to go to males.
Yeah.
When the fruit is kicked out of,
I could say the standard is set.
Fantastic.
Then as standard has amazing food and
it's open super late.
You can get like real good food at like
midnight.
All Right Ian,
let's wrap this motherfucker.
Sacramento will be there in Sacramento
on Thursday night.
Ian will be me.
Will be with me Thursday and Friday.
Sacramento on Thursday for two shows and
then fucking Friday we're going to do
Seattle for two shows.
Then a Saturday night I'm doing San
Diego.
Withdrawn.
Horton.
Okay.
On Saturday night after we land where
you're going to,
you're going to wear San Diego,
San Diego.
I ain't got to fly back that morning and
then get on a flight in the evening to
Australia.
I'll be there for like seven,
13 days.
Jesus in Sydney doing the comedy store
in some other places out there.
You do a stand up in Sydney?
Yeah.
Okay.
So I'll be there from the 17th through
the 20th.
Wow.
Well let me know.
I'll tweet that shit.
Everybody.
No.
Alright cool.
Alright Ladies and gentlemen,
we'll be back tomorrow with Ben Shapiro.
CEO.
Thanks.