Her freak bitches.
A lot of us right now,
we're going into alternate dimensions
via technology and hanging out there,
enjoying it,
experiencing the freedom,
uh,
from the confines of being constantly in
an infinitely located in whatever
physical space your body happens to be
inhabiting to suddenly remove that
weight and how I can pop these things on
and instantly translocate to some art
universe that some geniuses created.
Fuck around.
Shoot Arrows,
wander through minecraft,
have sex with two girls who I always
apparently gonna throw out of my house
if they didn't fuck me.
That's what the point is.
I have
never do that.
But in this universe,
I guess that's what I go.
Yeah,
so the kind of rapey what?
It's not rapey it's just like,
please,
I don't have money for the rent.
Can I suck your Dick?
Oh,
you know her idea.
Oh yeah,
you're not,
you're not raping her.
It's not like,
look,
you got,
you got to give up some pussy or
otherwise I'm kicking you the street.
You could say it if you want into the
porn.
I mean,
you could say whatever you want.
Wait a minute.
You have a microphone,
a microphone,
but you can talk to it if you want to be
a Weirdo,
but okay.
How long before you can talk to it,
how long before it talks back to you?
Well,
that's,
you're going to look,
you're looking at like a,
so we got to figure out a way to either,
I mean I imagine that probably exists in
some rudimentary way for some kind of
CGI style porn,
but to be able to like instantaneously
communicate with live video porn,
you're going to need some kind of ai
that I don't think we probably have just
yet or we are probably on the pr,
but yes,
that will add.
It's come.
Oh,
that's definitely going to happen.
I've watched x Mokena again on the plane
the other day.
I watched it for the second tire.
That's cool.
It's just as good.
The second time.
That movie freaks me out,
man.
Why?
Because the girl's so beautiful and
she's so,
she's so attractive.
Like you,
you know that guy.
You could see as much as he knew that
she was a robot,
as much as he knew that he wasn't a
robot as much,
as much as he knew that she was
artificial,
he was in love with her and she was
amazing.
And it seemed like she cared about him.
And when she was talking to him for
real,
like when the lights went out and the
camera was down,
spoiler alert,
and she was like,
don't trust him.
I'm like,
this is like a real person,
a real person.
She's thinking like a person.
It's a person.
Yeah.
And he's like completely locked into
this idea that it's a person.
He's hypnotized.
It's a person.
I mean,
I don't,
this whole distinction between
artificial intelligence and intelligence
is the same as the distinction between
virtual reality and reality.
It's just like another human attempt to
be in control of something.
You want it,
you want to say,
Oh,
I'll tell you if this is fucking reality
or not.
Oh,
this is virtual reality.
This isn't reality.
Reality.
But it's like,
oh really?
So realities compartmentalized into
places where there's,
if something is created by a human,
oh no,
that's not real reality.
Even though humans are reality reality's
reality.
Intelligence is intelligence because the
intelligence is inhabiting something
that isn't the human vessel.
It goes back to what we were talking
about earlier,
what,
cause it's not in a fucking meat body
now it's artificial intelligence.
How is why intelligence is intelligence
and then Rosa parks.
Yes,
but the Rosa Park one is real.
That's 100% real.
Is that when she,
that's when she got arrested.
You know,
she was,
a lot of people get that story wrong by
the way.
A lot of people think like she sat in
the front of the bus and then was asked
to move to the back of the boat.
Somebody else had done it before her.
Of course.
Yeah,
of course.
Of course.
Anybody even the front of the bus part
is incorrect.
What part?
What is it?
It's very mean.
My new thing,
but I'm like a history dude.
There was a white section in the front,
right?
African American and a book in the bag.
At the time they called black or colored
section.
Uh,
she was in the colored section.
But what happened was if the white
section filled up and a white person
went back to the colored section,
sit down,
you still had to stand up and give them
your seat.
Really?
Yeah.
And then she wouldn't do it.
And that's,
that was the start of it.
Wow.
I did not know it.
I know it's a small,
uh,
you know,
but everyone says,
oh,
she wouldn't go to the back of the book.
It's like,
well that's even grosser.
I agree.
It is.
Grocer just like literally just sitting
there and then just some guy just got
to,
yeah,
she's complying with your racist rules
and then you're like not racist enough.
Yeah.
So,
uh,
so then that's when she got arrested.
Parks original seat.
Wow.
You were totally right.
Am I correct?
Yeah.
Look at that.
What happened?
Ever seen,
I've never seen this picture is a
diagram like the Kennedy assassination.
It looks like the fucking magic bullet.
Rosa parks boarded the bus and sat in an
aisle seat in the designated colored
section.
College stops later.
The driver told parks and three other
blacks in her row to move to the back to
make room for a white man.
The three blacks move to the back.
Parks slid to an adjacent window seat,
refuse to move.
Wait,
so it was even,
it was like,
okay,
just so I'm clear on this,
now that I'm learning something,
I almost feel like now,
like they didn't even want him to have
to sit next to exactly what it was like.
That was an empty seat.
Yup.
That's exactly that,
right?
Am I reading that right?
You're absolutely reading it right.
It's interesting,
right?
That is.
It's awful.
That's awful.
That's another thing.
This,
not that long ago,
all these things that are not that long
ago.
The colored flag being on,
I mean the confederate,
the colored flag,
the confederate flag being on the state,
right.
Flag of Georgia.
This,
what year was this?
I want to say this is 60 what year
was it?
I want to say like 61 does that make
sense?
56 in the late fifties right.
Oh Wow.
I'm totally wrong.
Montgomery,
Alabama system was legally in the
graded.
Wow.
So good.
We learn a lot.
I learned a little something.
Yeah.
That's fascinating.
It's silly.
It's a stage photo then her right there.
Yeah.
Like how if there was a full bus and
there's a white guy behind her,
like how's this,
what's this photo from?
Oh,
I see.
So wikipedia photo,
they might've done that after the fact.
Right.
What's in the upper right hand corner?
What is that?
Is that the actual,
is that like no upper right hand corner,
upper right hand corner that,
yeah.
Mine never seen you yell at somebody
else.
Like I was like,
Yo,
this is the bus where it's at and that
you can actually go there and sit in an
extra of Obama there.
Oh Wow.
So they took the actual bus and put it
in a museum.
Well that's it.
Up in the above it someone should make a
tour bus so that,
hmm.
I think outkast or something.
Um,
yeah.
So this,
this tms thing,
transcranial magnetic stimulation
covered by Blue Cross,
huh?
Yeah.
Uh,
so yeah,
that's what like,
it's,
it was really,
really good.
Like I,
for a lot of my life I felt like I had
a,
I had like a,
a thing like a,
it almost felt like a metal weight,
like a bit of like five pound weight on
my upper left forehead,
my left.
And then so I went to this whoa dude,
that sound is like an Mri sound.
Yeah,
that's what it is.
It is.
Yes.
It's basically the same exact magnet as
an MRI.
They do your hey,
yeah,
they put it on your head.
It's pretty simple.
The first time they measure it,
they have to get to the exact spot.
There's another video where my finger is
pulsing that you'll enjoy.
And what is it doing to you?
Like what's the benefit?
Uh,
it's basically magnetizing and
electrifying a,
it's waking up basically dead,
uh,
synopsis according to them.
Really?
Yeah.
So it's,
it's waking up dead synapses and,
uh,
waking up dead,
waking them up so they're dormant.
Uh,
that's what they say.
Um,
you don't even look into it.
You like good.
Shoot me out.
Yeah.
What is it?
Can I do quarter one and this one time I
don't have kids,
man.
So I'm like,
yeah,
I don't give a shit,
whatever,
whatever it's going to cost me.
I'm happy to do it.
If you had kids,
you think you wouldn't do it?
I think if I had kids I'd be like,
you know,
sort of more,
more cautious about it.
Really.
Yeah,
probably.
Cause I'm not like reckless,
but I'm not,
I'm not like,
uh,
I do research.
It's also vague anyway,
the research,
it's also like we think it does it most
antidepressants,
they know,
they think they know what's happening.
They don't actually know.
Yeah.
That's a weird one.
When you think about how many people are
prescribed these things,
and then there's not really a direct
understanding of how it impacts each
piece.
Each person,
like they'll tell you,
hey,
we'll try this medication and if it
doesn't work,
we'll try another one.
Yeah.
Does this one work?
We'll cycle through it.
And now how do you know if it's working
for you or if you're having a good time
in your life?
And so you're feeling better because
maybe you started a new relationship but
a new job and it's going well and hey,
it's just a,
everything seems pretty
dude.
I was on medications that made me
nauseous for a year and a half before I
was like,
you know what?
I literally thought I was nauseous
because I was eating too many
lifesavers.
Not even fucking kidding.
Literally,
I was like,
I gotta take it easy on these life
savers,
because every night I throw up on the
way to the laugh factory,
and then I realized like,
you know,
Neil,
you're taking a pretty high dosage of
Zoloft,
or you might want to just take it down a
notch.
Okay.