Hello Freak bitches.
You're earning your keep.
That's one thing I rather know where I
stand and get fucked with.
That's the leg I'm talking about.
Really?
You need a tape of me.
You just saw him at the store.
What the fuck do you leave?
If I'm good enough for Mitzi shore,
why do you want to take,
who the fuck are you and your fucking
shit down to want to take from me?
I'm not the fucking major league.
Leave fucking comedy.
The comedy store.
You can me.
You want to tape?
Go Fuck Yourself.
I'm not sending you a fucking day.
It's against my fucking,
well,
it's like these people now with movies
and TV,
Joey,
they,
they want you to do a coast,
but they want you to send the real.
Don't don't send Shit Joey,
but they know it's a Costar.
They could offer it to me and if they
don't that's fine.
I'll do my podcasts and I'll live
another week.
That's the mind and eventually it will
go.
This motherfucker isn't gonna.
We might as well give it to them.
I'm not doing it for that.
You want me to fucking be a guest star
recur?
You want to give me a series regular?
I'll give you a fucking paper and I'll
fucking to come down and talk to you.
But for Costar,
we've been doing this.
Look at the IMD.
Be What?
Fucking tape,
you know to fuck are you to decide.
Let me see your fucking tape.
Hey,
you said that,
you know,
fucking tape.
Even then I had my fucking pride,
even that I wouldn't send the fucking
paypal.
I refused.
I finally send a blank tape.
He gave me that anti.
Never had respect for none of them
again,
because I found that it was a power
play.
It was like,
you're on my court.
Uh,
you know,
you want to give me some respect but
respect.
What do you do?
You're a pimp.
You take 20% of what people come to the
fucking door.
What the fuck are you?
One of?
You don't,
you can't even play the fucking Ukulele.
The fuck are you doing?
You can't put a fucking Ukulele.
What the fuck have you done?
That's my,
that's where I'm coming from.
I didn't want them to self club owners
are bad,
but they did great jobs.
It was the ship.
They bold that in fucking like,
and that's why I always get excited
about coming on this show cause because
this show is democracy in action,
you have millions of fucking people
listening.
And guess what?
Unless we say something,
unless we wake up from our volume and
booze induced stupor,
nothing's going to fucking happen.
So why the fuck are you doing it?
That's the question you should ask
yourself from 2015 not am I going to
lose weight now I'm going to read more
fucking books.
Not Am I going to go worse sketchers
instead of Nike's.
It should be.
Why the fuck do I get up in the fucking
morning and now we're very lucky
motherfuckers that were posted economic
and we can fucking say,
I'm going to get up in the morning
because of this.
I like how the 1% is relabeled
themselves post economic.
Well,
I'm the newest,
I'm the newest of the 1% and I'm giving
it all away.
Cause I,
I'll tell you one thing,
money means a fuck of a lot when you
don't have it.
By my old man told me the only thing
that ever made any sense about money,
he said life is like a shit.
The more bread you have,
the last sheet you have to eat.
But once you get it,
once you get that a plus,
you just say,
fuck it.
You know what I'd like to do?
I would like to buy 20 million acres and
say,
no one's allowed to fuck with that.
You can't fucking do shit with that
fucking line.
I'm just gonna fucking leave it because
that's one of the only things you can
do.
That's a pure good.
Just leave the land.
Don't fucking mine it.
Don't fucking pissing in,
don't shit in it.
Don't put Joe's tuna bards and Tequila
boom,
boom room in there.
Just leave it fucking gorgeous because
fucking that's,
that's,
that's God had to me is nature.
Yeah.
And I'm telling you,
if you think,
okay,
your wife has been happy when you've
called before,
after fucking three days on the road and
not being able to call,
you've never heard.
You tell a girl,
oh,
I was wrong.
You don't have herpes.
Okay.
They get elated.
Yeah.
Overcome with joy.
Now do you think maybe you should have
just waited till results came back
showing these girls and you just didn't
want him to fuck somebody else in the
meantime and then while I'm waiting to
side some other guy's life is ruined.
Right?
Well I heard this is this.
It'll suck it up and take my lumps also
on the other level,
I figured I could tell them I'm 90% sure
it was like a cop out.
So I'm not like fully sag.
Look,
I have it.
We fucked.
I thought it that uh,
from what I understood when I got tested
was that you can only test herpes while
the outbreaks happen.
Then they act to actually spoon a little
out of the outbursts that I could.
You can't really,
it's really hard to test for herpes.
So a lot of times you can get tested
during like not an outbreak and be like,
oh yeah,
to just positive for herpes.
No,
I think it was an old tests.
I think that was like 15 years ago.
Toast.
They need Olympic style Herbie's
everybody's time
for serious overcome his boy.
And
I heard if you do pop it like you could
actually taste it.
Taste herpes.
Yeah.
It's like a sweetness.
How many different fucking puss woes
before herpes is like,
I got it.
Yeah.
You can't just say it's the once.
That might just be,
that was solving your own blog.
This person's had it for awhile.
It's a burgundy,
burgundy is or on the culture.
Well,
I think that,
you know,
w with civilization,
part of another inherent component of
civilization did you have to be better
than someone else,
you know?
And so a lot of the things that we do,
um,
our,
our ways of delineating ourselves from
Sab,
like what we would call savages are more
primitive people.
Like you wore shoes,
you didn't want your skin to be too dark
or Tan you,
you know,
you wanted to show that you had more
affluence,
that you weren't as barbaric.
He didn't have to poop on it.
You could just poop it and push it
flusher and it went away.
And like it just,
that just comes soft hands.
Right?
Cultured demeanor.
You were less and less animal running
away if you were less animal.
Right.
And you're trying to be more animal,
but the word is primitive.
I am a primate.
Yeah.
What advancements the society make that
you think has society made that you
think are beneficial?
Well,
Gosh,
I mean I think medicine is benefit.
I mean,
I think everything is beneficial.
It's just that what I'm more concerned
of about is what's,
what has been,
what is no longer needed that is still
essential.
So it's,
it's my,
it's,
I don't,
I don't have really an aversion against
civilization and technology.
It's just that vitamin C is still
necessary.
Like we can't get around the fact that
vitamin C is still necessary.
So I'm just trying to figure out
diseases.
So when you're trying to figure out
diseases,
you have to kind of boil down to,
could this disease be a rising because
of some non input,
some essential input that we're not
getting.
And so as people get more and more
advanced,
the our,
our health,
again,
in the terms of biological sense isn't
getting better with us.
And so what happens to a species that
advances itself right out of being a
species?
You know,
like that,
that's more what I'm,
I'm interested in.
So I like it all.
I like all technology.
Netflix,
Netflix might be my favorite technology.
[inaudible].