Ready?
Five,
four,
three,
two,
one.
Mr.
Shock,
first of all,
thank you very,
very,
very much for being here.
I've been following your work for a long
time now and uh,
I'm,
I'm very appreciative of you and very
appreciative of everything you've done
and I've been fascinated by the subject
of ancient Egypt.
So,
um,
I really,
I'm really excited.
Very siloed.
Thank you.
It's a real pleasure to be here.
I've heard a lot about your show.
I've heard a lot about you.
My,
of course you'd like John Anthony West I
think was on with you a couple of times.
Maybe.
He was very proud that I guess you did
the only full skype interview with him.
Yeah,
that's the only one I've ever done is
with him.
Yeah.
He used to like to talk about that so.
Well I just had to talk to him and he
was in upstate New York at the time and
it was just,
he really didn't have any plans to come
down here and I'm just,
I was very fortunate to one day get them
in studio though.
It was really nice.
So it's been wonderful.
Well,
his work,
that DVD series,
he did magical Egypt was amazing and I
had seen your work before that in that
mysteries of the Sphinx thing that was
narrated by Charlton Heston,
Heston,
NBC,
1993,
I think in many ways it was the mystery
of the Sphinx that really broke
everything open.
It brought everything to the public
attention.
I've had many people tell me,
I'm not trying to brag or anything,
I'm just saying it's actually that this
really opened up a new field,
if we could put it that way,
a new way of looking at things in the
popular,
among the popular,
um,
public popular media that people around
the world versus the academic scholarly
journals and the back and forth,
that type of thing.
You have to remember,
I'm a faculty member.
I'm at Boston University.
I'm an academic,
uh,
and many of the academics have poo pooed
should we say over the years,
bringing things to the public.
But I think it's been important to do
now what we're talking about,
for the people that are uninformed is
the idea that some of the structures in
ancient Egypt are far older than
conventional wisdom or conventional
modern day archeology,
modern day egyptologist.
They would like us to believe that all
of this spawned from a very specific
time period and people like John Anthony
West and yourself and some other folks
like Graham Hancock are proposing that
it's entirely possible that there were
many different areas of construction in
Egypt and that there are some structures
that are far far older than we think.
Yeah,
exactly.
And this what I was alluding to is just
really opened up with our work on
reading the Great Sphinx and I think you
know the story,
but maybe just to summarize in the
smallest of nutshells,
John Anthony West,
before I met him,
he was became a followership.
We say I shouldn't say follower because
that sounds wrong.
That sounds like it's a religion
dogma,
but he became interested in the work of
the late Schwaller de Lubitsch who died
passed away in 1961,
but he had mentioned in one line that
the Sphinx had been weathered by rain,
I would say precipitation as a
geologist,
not wind and sand,
so this if it were true,
and it is true,
would put the Sphinx back to a much
earlier period which would tie in with
Schwab Adler's work and John Anthony
West sis subsequent work that there were
indications that dynastic Egypt as we
know it,
going back to about 3000 BC,
was really a legacy of what I call now
an earlier cycle of civilization or
something that goes back much,
much earlier,
which at this point I date back to the
end of the last ice age.
Ice Age ended 9,700
BC.
Just to put it in perspective for
people.
So when,
when did you first get on board with
this?
John Anthony West come to you or John?
Anthony West.
Okay.
So the story goes this way.
John Anthony West published serpent in
the sky.
His probably most famous book,
First Edition Nineteen 79,
he was then looking for someone that
could really validate or at least assess
from a scientific point of view,
this theory about this face,
which he had just barely sort of touched
the surface based on Schwaller.
That may be.
It could be older,
but this was really a geological
question.
He mentioned that in 1979 in serpent in
the sky,
John Anthony West went on to become very
involved with Egypt and he started
traveling to Egypt.
He led tourists to Egypt.
He wrote the travelers key to ancient
Egypt in 1985.
Also mentions in appendix.
I think it was just the older sphinx
theory,
but really looking for someone to at
least assess it scientifically.
He met a fellow at in in Egypt actually
at the time,
Robert Eddie,
who is a phd in English literature,
I believe,
something like that,
but he was teaching in Cairo and
American University in Cairo,
I believe.
Then he came to Boston University.
This is late 19 eighties.
I was and still do teach at Boston
University full time.
Robert Eddy and myself got to know each
other.
Robert Eddie mentioned me as a geologist
to John Anthony West and that may be.
This was someone who seemed fairly
knowledgeable,
fairly open minded about things,
the time.
Did you have any live on Egypt or.
Oh,
I.
my interest in Egypt goes way back.
I was reading about ancient Egypt when I
was literally six,
seven,
eight years old.
I had a grandmother who had a wonderful
library at the time and I would go
through her library.
She had books from British Museum on
Ancient Egypt going back to the turn of
the century,
so I.
I was prepared in the sense that I was
open to such things,
but I didn't imagine getting involved in
Egypt in any way professionally.
Did you have any thoughts about the
dating of the Sphinx and the pyramids or
anything back then before you looked
into?
There were two things,
so there were two things going on in my
head back then,
which may be prepped me for this number
one,
I knew the conventional story.
I knew that the Sphinx goes back to
2,500
BC according to the standard
Egyptologists in 1989,
which is when I first,
I believe it was 1989,
I first actually met western person.
I had in my mind that the egyptologists
must be correct because they've studied
it.
They must know what they're doing.
I was coming from an academic point of
view.
I,
I'm,
I'm not,
I'm just giving,
you know,
saying where I'm coming from.
I had gone to Yale University and get my
phd in Geology and geophysics.
I was very well grounded in the status
quo academic point of view.
So I thought when I first went to Egypt
I would just prove west wrong.
I would just prove that the egyptologist
knew what they were talking about,
but,
and this is an important,
but I was also trained in many ways,
both as a graduate student and going
back to my grandmother who I had great
respect for and was also very,
should we say liberal and open minded
but critical.
You always have to follow the evidence
wherever it goes.
And that's always been my rule of thumb,
that not everything is always the way
people say it is even if their
authorities and something I already knew
when I went to Egypt for the first time
was that some of the very old
egyptologists in the late 19th,
early 20th century had actually
suggested that just the way it looks,
the feel of the Sphinx,
not based on hard evidence really that
may be,
it was older than the pyramids.
That may be.
It goes back earlier.
So I felt that it wasn't all said and
done and you know,
pat and sound that the egyptologist
necessarily knew what they were talking
about in modern times because some of
the earlier egyptologist who they held
in very high respect supposedly had set
different things.
Secondly,
and I hate to bring this up,
but I will because it's part of the
background.
I,
my grandmother,
who I mentioned a second ago,
uh,
was uh,
theosophy and Thea,
if you know anything about theosophy,
it also suggests that,
you know,
maybe there's things that go back
earlier.
I don't theosophy theosophy it's,
it's a,
how do I explain it?
You have you heard of Blavatsky Madame
Blavatsky?
No.
Okay.
Well,
I'm losing my headphones.
Theosophy was founded in the late 19th
century.
It questioned a lot of the values,
a lot of the dogma of Science,
of the time,
of religion,
of the time it looked to the east in
particular to other philosophies,
other world views.
So basically it was a way.
This is what it did for me at least.
And I'm not a theosophist I don't want
to say I'm a theosophy,
uh,
but reading theosophical works on top of
everything else allowed me,
I think to expand my horizons and to see
that maybe this dogma of the day is just
that the dogma of the day,
that there are other possibilities and
not that we accept something just
because someone said it or it because
it's old or because it's this religion
or that religion or that supposed to be
ancient culture.
But no,
you keep everything open.
You look at the evidence and that's
really where I was coming from.
But my point is that even in late 19
eighties,
early 19 nineties,
when I first got involved with this,
if I looked at it critically,
the evidence was not that definitive for
the age of the Sphinx.
So I was going in with openminded
possibilities.
But honestly,
when I first went to Egypt with John
Anthony West in 1990,
I thought before I got off the plane
that this would be simple,
open and shut case.
I would prove him wrong in the sense of
his assertions.
That may be the Sphinx was older.
I had no doubt at the time that my
colleagues in Egyptology must know what
they're talking about and all of that
change literally within 30,
without exaggerating,
30 to 120 seconds of first seen
recently.
Reasonings.
Yeah,
it really did.
What was your first impression?
Because my first impression of the spanx
was now that I saw on the ground in
person,
there was something wrong with the Egypt
and logical dating.
Because when you look at the Sphinx as a
geologist with a geological I,
this was not weathered by wind and sand.
This was not desert erosion.
And weathering that I saw on the sinks,
the body of the Sphinx,
which is very difficult to tell because
it's been heavily repaired and reworked,
but particularly on the walls of what
are known as the Sphinx enclosure.
The Sphinx enclosure is important
because it preserves a lot of the
details and if you haven't,
if the audience has not been to Egypt,
they should realize that when they
carved the Sphinx,
it's all solid bedrock.
Only.
The head initially was above the ground
surface.
You carved,
they carved down into the rock to free
up the body,
what I call it,
the core body of the Sphinx in that core
body and the walls of the enclosure,
more or less the quarry around it,
if you want to use that term that showed
these ancient weathering precipitation
erosion or features that are
incompatible with the last 5,000
years of climatic history on the eastern
edge of the Sahara.
So immediately I knew there was
something wrong geologically had to
figure that out.
Either this was a weird geological
anomaly or something else was going on
and the Sphinx might go back to an
earlier period.
Also,
I want to point out that when you look
at the Sphinx and other geologists have
looked at this as well,
they did not just chip away at the rock
to carve the body more or less.
You could have chipped away at the rock
with pick axes and that type of thing.
Shoveled out chips of rock in baskets.
That would've been the easy way.
What they did is they carved out huge
blocks of stone.
I mean when I say huge,
we're talking multitenant,
tens of tons.
Some of them maybe over 50 tons or more
of limestone.
They moved those due east of the Sphinx
and built what is now known as the
Sphinx Temple,
which is still there in ruinous
condition and the valley temple.
So you had these two huge temples and
what is interesting and lot of people
don't realize this or they don't think
about.
I think those constructions which are
contemporary with the oldest portion of
the Sphinx in some ways,
are more impressive if you think about
the technology and what went into
constructing them than the age of the
Sphinx itself.
So it's not just the Sphinx.
It's also these limestone temples that
are associated with it and we're built
contemporaneously,
so jamie pulled up to photos here.
The first one that he pulled up was a
computer image that showed the Sphinx
and showed how I'm looking at it.
Yeah.
Yes.
And in this image,
what you can see that's a computer image
that's actually from mystery of the
Sphinx,
and then there's a inset that's an
aerial photograph,
the real thing,
and that shows how when they were
carving the body,
they cut out huge blocks and then put
them in position to make what's known as
the swings temple due east of the swing.
And the second image is the Sphinx
Temple.
You look at this,
it says this,
things faces due east,
the rising sun and right in front of it
is the Sphinx Temple.
So this is a humongous temple made out
of these huge blocks of stone which were
carved out when they carve the body of
the Sphinx.
And here you see in this image another,
a picture of the Sphinx Temple.
And so these erosion,
if you can see how big they are,
you can see how big they are.
They're enormous.
Okay.
These erosion features on the blocks,
don't worry about them for the moment.
Okay.
Let's go back to the Sphinx enclosure
itself.
It's a sphinx enclosure where you see
the rolling,
undulating,
profiled,
the Roche no features here.
You see it in that picture.
The vertical fissures,
and I know you're familiar with this
personally because I've heard you talk
about it,
finance they west,
that can only be caused by
precipitation.
The rocks are like a layer cake,
so it takes out the software layers,
it receipts the software layer,
some of the harder layer stick out
further,
but the water also finds its way down
crevices and cracks,
natural features that are slightly
softer and it forms these vertical
fissures.
I want to make the point because a lot
of people get confused.
They say,
couldn't it be rising Nile floods?
No.
Geologically,
that will give a very different
signature on the rockets,
not floods coming up from the bottom.
It's actually precipitation and rainfall
runoff coming from above and rainfall
for thousands of years.
Well,
there's two aspects here.
It could be thousands of years,
it could be much stronger rainfall,
you know,
huge flash floods,
that type of thing.
And part of the story that I hope we'll
get to is that initially I'm jumping
around here a little bit,
but initially I was thinking five to
7,000
bc that was very conservative based on
the geological data,
based on the seismic,
which we have to get to also.
But now I believe we're talking prior to
9,700
BC for the original construction of the
Sphinx and we can talk about why the
data and at 9,700
bc we have the end of the younger Dryas,
the end of the glacial epic,
the end of the last ice age.
I have now put together the story based
on evidence and when I ever I say if I
say I believe something or I think
something is always based on evidence.
I've been piecing together that what we
had ending the younger dryas ending the
last ice age was a huge eruption from
the sun.
A huge solar outbursts,
huge climatic changes which put among
other things a lot of precipitation,
allow moisture into the air which came
down as precipitation with huge floods,
huge centrally,
thunderstorms,
etc.
And I think a lot of the initial
errosion that we still see on the walls
of the sinks enclosure go back to that
period.
So you hAd the situation where you would
get thIs incredible weathering and
erosion and then it continued for
thousands of years after that and was
reinforced until you had the sahara
coming in in relatively recent times and
geologically in times desert that sahara
desert.
So before that it was some sort of a
rain forest,
a.
It's a vanity rainforest.
It actually varied over time.
And before that it was very fertile.
Savannah,
lots of plants there.
People have seen it even in popular
movies and whatnot,
how the sahara at one point had water
and all kinds of animals.
That's before end of the last ice age
before this.
These incredible changes that we have at
9,700
bc.
So that's where the sphinx,
I think the original sphinx goes back to
that time period and that's what the
egyptians called zep tepi.
This was a first time for them or what I
call an earlier cycle of civilization.
The last cycle,
the one that we're still part of in my
terminology is the last 5,000
years.
So civilization arising reemerging,
I should say about 3000 to 4,000
bc company into really what we have now
is high technology,
etc.
But before that there had been an
earlier cycle civilization that was
essentially snuffed out or brought to
its knees if you would,
by the end of the last ice age.
And just to map this out,
a period from about 9,700
bc,
this is what I'm reconstructing now to
about 4,000
to 3000 bc where we have civilization
reemerging between that period.
So thousands of years.
Ninety 700 bc to say 3,700
bc for round numbers,
6,000
years.
We have essentially a dark period.
And what I've been now calling siddha
solar induced dark age,
sort of ironic.
the sun will induce a dark age because
of brought civilization back to an
earlier stage,
if you would.
I'm not sure I follow that.
Well,
how did the son do this?
Um,
solar outburst essentially coronal mass
ejection,
huge eruption,
bigger than anything we've ever seen
laws,
these massive thunder showers and we
exactly in modern history,
modern history is even close to this,
but we do have isotope data,
etc.
That indicates this has happened in the
past at the end of the last ice age and
I'm sure it's happened many times over
and you have a lot of markers that
indicate this.
You have vitrification of rock.
I'm in fact a lot of the markers,
and I don't want to be debating the
issue necessarily,
but a lot of the markers that people
have used for a comment at the younger
dryas or during the younger dryas
through,
most of them are at the beginning of the
younger dryas.
That'S what they're claiming,
but loved that a lot of the dating is
very,
very iffy.
Um,
I found it interesting.
For instance,
someone will use something as a marker
for the younger dry ice.
And that will give a date of 12,000
plus or minus 4,000
years.
So,
you know,
this is just the way geology is,
but I remember,
I can't remember his name.
You had a guest on one of your shows.
he was when?
randall carlson,
not randall carlson.
I know randall very well.
Uh,
he was on with carlson and shermer and a
half,
but he came on by a skype.
You outcome malcolm.
I do not remember it.
But anyway,
he was one of the people that was quote,
comment proponent.
And he started pointed out a lot of the
evidence,
a micro spirituals,
glassy spheres on nano diamonds.
I don't think he mentioned biomed,
say shocked quartz,
et cetera.
And everyone has been assuming this has
to be from a physical impact in the
sense of something coming down like a
comet or asteroid,
that type of thing.
but the problem is you don't necessarily
find craters.
You don't necessarily find the pieces of
the comment.
You should find some physical remains.
And he mentioned,
and I found it very interesting,
he mentioned in passing what I've been
working on now for a number of years
that no,
and I was once on the comment band bike
and I'll put it that way and I'm not
trying knock good research,
but when you look at the evidence,
what is not being considered by a lot of
people,
and he mentioned this in passing and
said,
well,
you know,
something else that could cause this
lightning but you wouldn't have
lightning.
You know,
that's very localized.
We think of this very localized.
Um,
but if you have a major solar outburst,
mainers are coronal mass ejections and
astrophysicists who is now deceased.
He was at cornell,
thomas gold,
who did a lot of really good,
in fact,
prize winning work in astrophysics,
first pointed out in the 19 sixties that
if you have a major solar outburst,
major coronal mass ejection,
you would get essentially huge.
What would be like huge lightning
strikes over incredible areas of the
earth.
Simultaneously.
This would cost vitrification.
It would cause all these features.
And just as a,
within the last year,
there's been more work done showing that
full rights were lightning strikes in
modern times.
Even small lightning strikes like that
can cause,
can create things like shocked quartz.
Other quote impact features that people
have always said,
well,
it must be a comet or asteroid,
but you're not finding the craters,
you not finding other things.
So what I'm finding are my own research,
um,
is I'm coming to conclude that it wasn't
a physical object that hit us.
It was a solar outburst.
That's a general term I use possible
that it was both.
Um,
actually there's,
it's quite possible that it could have
been both.
Yeah,
there could have been fragments of both.
I can address that.
Um,
and there's a couple of aspects to both.
When you say both,
there is indications that comments
diving into the sun actually caused
coronal mass ejections a correlated with
disturbing the sun.
So in some cases you'll have the occult,
the comic group talking about how we go
through these comment streams
periodically.
I agree 100 percent.
In fact,
I talk about this in some of my early
books because I really was into comments
at the time,
four inches of the pyramid builders.
For instance,
I talk about how comments might have
begun and ended the younger dryas,
but I wasn't thinking about solar
activity at that time.
Seriously asked,
no one else was.
But we now find that commentS dive into
the sun when we go through comment
streams that can set off solar activity.
So in fact,
I think it could be both,
but it could be that the comments are
affecting the sun,
which is then affecting the earth rather
than directly,
if that makes sense.
Um,
and the other thing is that people have
to understand there's a couple of things
going on.
The younger dryas,
10,900
bc when it first begins is a cooling
period.
It's not as dramatic climate change as
you have at 9,700
bc when all of a sudden we go from deep
ice age climatic regime to modern are
even a little bit warmer initially.
Modern changes.
And this is it.
Oh,
there.
Yeah,
there we have some isotope data.
And what we have at 9,700
bc,
and this is based on sediment cores in
ice cores,
we also have lunar data that supports is
at 9,700
bc.
We have incredible climatic change going
from,
you know,
deep ice age to modern warming.
And this literally now based on what
they call micro stratigraphy from
greenland,
ice cores can be dated within.
Get this weeks,
two days.
Wow.
So thiS happened literally we're talking
virtually overnight.
When I was a graduate student,
we thought things had happened.
Suddenly we were talking thousands of
years or decades.
Oh god,
don't take decadeS for something to
happen geologically.
That'd be crazy.
Right now we're talking literally weeks
today.
So that's incredible.
Yeah.
So I think this ties in to support that.
There was a massive solar event in
[inaudible] 9,700
bc.
Uh,
what we had a,
just a slide a minute ago when I saw it
out,
the side of my eye was a graph of based
on isotope data is what they call
proxies of solar activity.
Again,
based on primarily ice core sediment
cores.
And the sun was incredibly active and
9,700
bc and shortly after there,
and it had huge,
if you think of anthropomorphically mood
swings,
will be very active.
Then would go very skilled and very
active again,
very still.
And this happened for some thousands of
years and then it evened out.
The sun cert became quiescent.
It was during this quiescence period
that tying back into human civilization,
civilization was able to reemerge,
redevelop again,
and we've had incredibly good conditions
should we say,
for the last 5,000
quite condition,
stable conditions on earth for
civilization to reemerge.
Tying back into that theme,
but recently the son has become very
active again and we have to be very
careful.
I'm not a doomsayer scaremonger.
I'm not trying to sell people on being
preppers,
but the reality is the sun is starting
to become active again,
just as it was at the end of the last
ice age.
And I think this makes perfect sense
because the sun is a star.
It goes through cycles like other stars
do,
and we're a little planet or retain it.
And we're like all the other plants
affected by this fascinating.
Now that we have this incredible need to
keep things exactly the way they are,
to the point where we were in denial
about any potential change.
If you're studying things that was like,
oh,
it'll be fine.
We're,
we're so inclined.
We are so inclined to do that.
It's very interested helion.
And in fact,
um,
I forget who it was.
One of the astrophysicist some decades
ago said about the sun.
It was sort of the last vestige of eris
julianism in modern science.
Everyone assumed the son is stable,
essentially.
Perfect.
Yes,
it goes through little sun cycles of 11
and 22 years and maybe some bigger ones
have a few centuries,
but no one wanted to think of it as what
it is.
Just a plain old star that goes through
periods of the equilibrium.
We've been in relative solar equilibrium
for thousands of years now,
but it goes through disequilibrium and
has,
we'll call hiccups in spurts and has to
recalibrate itself if you would,
uh,
and we feel the effects on earth.
And so at the end of the last ice age,
we had this massive solar event,
solar outburst,
what they call 'em,
a solar proton events,
um,
it would have messed up the ionosphere
caused all kinds of geomagnetic storms.
This tyson with earthquake activity that
we see at the end of the last ice age
because we now have lots of evidence
that solar activity upset,
said mac nita sphere and the magnate
magnetic fields on the earth,
the electrical currents in the earth.
It's A will trigger earthquakes that are
about to happen anyway.
Not unlike.
I was talking to katy,
my wife on the right here.
And a good analogy is when you have an
avalanche just about ready to go,
you can clap your hands in some cases
and it sets off this huge avalanche.
Yeah.
So solar activity is tied in with earth
activity,
earthquake activity for instance,
of volcanic activity.
So we see volcanic activity,
increased volcanic activity.
There was a major,
I'm super volcano that went off just at
the end of the last ice age.
Will why?
Probably it.
This is me speaking because of the solar
activity that set it off,
so when you start getting things like
platinum iridium osmium spikes,
that's not necessarily extra
terrestrial.
That could be from terreStrial volcanic
activity was occurring at that period,
so yes,
there's extraterrestrial causes,
but I think that there's a very strong
case to be made that this is solar,
that this is the sun influencing us,
which is really important to fast
forward to today.
Here we are,
we're on skype.
We're using all these electronic media.
What could be more vulnerable to a solar
outburst?
That kind of stuff.
Oh,
our grid power grids.
Power grids will be friday.
There was a,
and I think we're seeing the beginning
of this are we saw the beginning of this
because again,
I'm a geologist,
so I think in broad terms,
few hundred years is nothing.
Eighteen,
59.
Are you aware of the carrington event?
No.
There was a major solar outburst from a
human Perspective,
major solar outburst.
From an astrophysical perspective,
it was nothing but it was a coronal mass
ejection.
Actually two in a row that hit us in 18,
59.
It's known as the carrington event after
richard carrington,
who,
um,
first saw the solar flares,
a really bright solar flares that were
associated with it.
It was picked up on the primitive
magnetometers of the time that they had,
for instance,
in london,
etc.
Study by the physicists of the time and
18,
59,
there were electronics around.
It was called the telegraph system to
telegraph system.
Acted as huge antenna that picked up the
changing magnetic fields,
generated electricity along it,
burnt out the telegraph lines,
literally set telegraph,
um,
uh,
you know,
the places where the telegraph operators
worked on fire,
telegraph stations on fire,
that type of thing.
Um,
if we had a carrington level event now,
which is really quite minor from a
astrophysical perspective,
orders of magnitude less than what
happened at the end of the last ice age,
uh,
it would fry are grid lines that would
knock out all the huge transformers it
would be for it.
Did that as it's coming in and probably
knock out all the sound lights on the
gps systems,
communications.
I mean,
it would really bring us to our knees.
Is this an article from 18,
59?
Yeah.
The rural display in boston's.
Now the display of auroral.
Yeah.
There you go.
Brilliant.
At 1:00,
ordinary print can be read by the light.
Exactly.
Because one thing you get is these
bright auroras,
these bright,
what people think of as in northern and
southern lights,
but in 18,
59,
they saw them around the world.
I'm back at the end of the last ice age
because they were so powerful.
What?
They become more intense.
They take on very discrete structures in
the sky.
Here's some of what are known as a,
again,
northern lights,
right?
Rural displays.
But see how it starts to take on a
discreet structure on there right there.
and to describe it to the audience.
Do you see how it sort of looks like a
person with their hands up in the air?
They start to take on more and more
discreet structures.
Some of them looked like people with
their hands up in there and little legs
and some birds phenomenon.
This is basically the high charge
particles,
electrons and protons and whatnot
interacting with the atmoSphere.
Um,
and they form these figures,
so it's electrical phenomenon,
uh,
and it will ultimately come down if you
have a tense enough one as you did at
the end of last ice age,
it will look like if you were there
living,
you know,
12,000
years ago,
10,000,
11,000,
700 years ago at the end of the last ice
age.
And you saw this,
you would see these things in the sky.
Oh,
they look like god,
say,
look like stick figure humans in the
sky.
Uh,
you would see huge lightning bolts
hitting parts of the surface of
fascinating because that image on that's
in hieroglyphics and exactly find this
around the world.
and anthony parak who's along when we're
looking at,
but for the people that are.
Because a lot of people just listening
what we're looking at a discharge
formation.
Yeah,
this is plasma discharge formation.
Plasma is essentially think of is
electrically charged particles,
electrons,
protons,
that type of thing.
As it comes off the sun.
And this case,
think of a coronal mass ejection,
a huge ball of charged gas is one way to
describe it,
hitting the atmosphere,
driving down into the atmosphere,
causing these northern lights on
steroids.
If you wanT to put that image.
We're seeing very specific images that
looked like stick figures.
So these are things you would see in the
sky,
except they're in many cases they're
spinning electrically.
You wouldn't notice that they were
spinning generally and they looked sort
of like.
because we've tend to anthropomorphize,
we tend to look at like even clouds are
rocks formations and we make them look
like what we think they look like.
They look sort of like stick figure men.
Is any of this an actual photograph or
these just graphic illustrators?
Graphic illustrations.
But what we know because we haven't been
experienced this fortunately and since
photography,
but what we do have our petroglyphs
dating back to the end of last ice age
where people were seeing this in the sky
and they were drawing it on the walls of
caves,
on the walls of rocks.
And actually globally.
Anthony per rod,
who's a los alamos plasma physicist.
He is the world's expert on this type of
high energy plasma physics.
These are some of the.
It'll go back.
Go back,
jamie.
I'll look at this from all over the
world looking at it exactly.
Amazing all over the world.
Arizona,
Italy,
it's all the same thing.
It's all the same thing in notice to
that.
Spain see how they look like stick
figures,
but they have little weird dots on their
sides.
Donuts,
real humans don't have that,
but they're seeing this around the world
in this guy and recording it.
Also the motif of when these take on
search formed,
they take on what looked like birds'
heads,
so the bird headed man.
A moTif that you see around the world
going back and I believe it all goes
back to the end of the last ice age and
what people were experiencing,
what they were seeing,
if you will called gods in the sky or
whatever,
but they were seeing this and it was
having a real effect on their life.
What is causing that very specific
pattern,
that very specific shape that you're
seeing?
The way,
the way I would say,
the best way to say it is you've got
this,
this is simplistic,
but you've got these huge electrical
charges coming down.
they sort of focus like a tornado
focuses,
or if you think of,
um,
running water out of a spicket,
if you play with it,
you can sort of squeeze it and make it
form different shapes.
That served my analogy to it.
Um,
and it's the magnetic and electric
fields interacting with each other.
Sometimes they serve spin around each
other,
like a rope.
In that illustration here you see a how
to say his name,
perrott parent dr plots experiments
where he essentially reproduce that,
that shape over and over and over again.
That's right.
Exactly.
Reproduce that.
And then it gets even more fascinating.
And this is something that ties in well
actually with katie,
my wife catherine ulysse,
um,
and imparato team has confirmed it on
easter island.
You have the rango rango script,
which also duplicates this and seems to
Be a reCord.
You know,
the modern rango rango are only a few
hundred yearS old,
but just like any manuscript or
anything,
it was copied over and over and seems to
go back to it too.
And if you look at some of the rango
rango and I know a lot of your audience
can't see this,
but you look at some of them,
they're even more definitive.
Look,
you know,
uh,
showing what [inaudible] was able to
reproduce experimentally.
Um,
and they're,
they have it recorded from ancient
timeS.
So when you're talking about this event
that happened at the end of the younger
dryas,
you what?
Like put it in perspective,
like are we talking about like a
hurricane times a thousand?
Like what would this be like a million?
Yeah,
like huge thunderstorm.
Yeah.
I mean literally possible to comprehend
and possible to comprehend from our
point of view,
my perspective,
our perspective.
And there's more to it than that.
You would have incredible radiation
levels at the surface of the earth.
Paula violetta physicist I know and he's
published on this,
has talked about how during an event
like this,
you would have levels of radiation that
were so high that large mammals,
we are large mammals,
large mammals.
If they couldn't protect themselves,
they could die within,
you know,
three to six,
seven days a week or so.
How do you protect yourself?
You go underground,
you go Into caves,
you go into places because rock will
protect you from the surface radiation
under the circumstances.
Now you don't need to stay there
forever.
You can,
you know,
because these solar events probably
came.
Now this is hypothetical because we've
not experienced a huge one like this,
but they probably came.
Um,
and then it went back off a little bit,
but then maybe another one would come
again,
I'm a geologiSt,
so think of a huge earthquake and then
aftershocks after shocks that can
actually last centuries or millennia in
some cases,
smaller ones.
So something that was happening and you
see this around the world too,
is that we're people survived,
I believe in part because they had
access to natural caves initially.
Then they built underground structures
for when they came again and it also
encouraged our,
uh,
developed this whole tradition,
shall we say,
of having a place to go,
even if it's not occurring to the moment
they knew that these things do occur,
um,
at least for some thousands of years.
And we're aware of this.
So we're getting prepared and now gi
would uses during the cold war here.
What did a lot of people build in their
backyards?
Bonders bonkers.
So they were doing this also.
So you get areas here.
I see there's a slight of India up at
the moment.
Kappa dosha region is very well known
for those get underground.
How do they know to get into initially?
I think initially,
I mean you've got literally fire coming
down from the sky.
Think of the lightening bolts fire.
I mean if you've got a cave there,
you go into it.
It's the only thing that is going to
protect it.
Protect these houses are useless.
All that burns.
I mean you've got literally fire coming
down.
Think of his fire lightning that is
going to set things on fire and you're
entirely incinerate that.
Just lightening everywhere.
Almost like rainfall.
Yes,
yes,
yes.
In certain areas,
and that's why you have huge sheets of
glass in some cases.
Wow.
So that's.
Yeah,
and so you're incinerating everything
where it hits ice,
it's flash pricing.
It is hitting water.
It's vape to this massive flooding,
so it's causing massive flooding.
It's dumping all the ice ultimately into
the oceans,
which is causing rising sea levels,
but more importantly it's causing
massive precipitation,
massive flash floods and loss.
Are we talking about?
Incredible.
I think incredible because for instance,
we had can document linguistically,
and this is other people's work,
but I think it ties right in.
They haven't been explained it cogently
otherwise that there is.
For instance,
in Turkey,
middle east,
there is a constriction of the
population to the anatolia region,
kappa dosha,
where you have these underground
shelters,
you have a geology that was easy to go
into and escape and linguistically we
can map back into european languages to
a small pocket that survived there at
the end of the last ice age.
Wow.
So you know,
I think there was a massive around the
world,
you would've had populations being
constricted and then they spread out
again and when they were constricted,
there's.
I see the slight there for the
linguistic data,
when you constrict down in one area,
of course you lose a lot of the
technology.
You lose a lot of the high culture if
you go back to a much more primitive
stage,
and that's what we find.
So we find,
for instance,
in anatolia,
a western Turkey,
no near asia as it was called in ancient
times,
you find not only of course you go
things like comE back lay tappy,
which goes back before this huge
catastrophe with the monumental stone
mega list,
et cetera.
But what you find there are 2000 years
later in the same general area,
you find friends since childhood,
which is a bunch of mud brick houses all
clustered together.
Uh,
it's gone down.
It's gone into what I call an acadian.
I call sit at this solar induced dark
age where they lost a lot of it,
not unlike an analogy,
I think it's easy for people understand
analogies,
the end of the roman empire and
everything that was lost there and then
go into a much more primitive state,
um,
with the dark ages to the european dark
ages.
In this case,
uh,
you look at the,
um,
technology.
It was much higher during the roman
empire until maybe 1000 or 1200 a d
again,
in many realms.
Same thing here,
although this was such a mighty
throwback,
it took thousands of years for people to
reemerge and at least start to get up to
the status now.
And they had been before,
presented this in front of other
scholars.
Yes.
It's getting at.
Well,
there's a lot of resistance.
Look,
I'm an academic.
I,
I don't want to sound the wrong way.
I'm not looking for sympathy,
but going out on limbs like this going
just beginning with the reading of the
sphinx and that's what we,
we didn't even finish with that yet,
but that's okay.
We'll get back to that.
Got plenty of time.
Yeah.
Um,
there's a lot of resistance to anything
that's new.
Any new concepts,
new ideas,
textbooks have been rich and people I've
stayed.
Stayed robin given out.
Yeah,
pay a.
They've staked their reputation on it
and I understand that and I try not to
be that myself,
you know,
the old.
This is my pet theory,
but I do try and look at the evidence.
I think that slowly we're building up
more and more interest more and more,
um,
at least people looking at objectively
and uh,
I do see changes occurring.
Uh,
one thing I'll mention right now is,
as of relatively recently,
knots are still very,
very small,
but at boston university I've been
allowed to found what is called the iso,
see the institute for the study of the
origins of civiliZation,
which is really just me at the moment,
but I want to build it up and I'd like
To get,
I'm not trying to sound the wrong way,
but I'd like to get people to donate to
it,
etc.
ETc.
I'm also,
I've,
uh,
found it with some colleagues of mine,
including some academic colleagues or
cool,
which stands for the organization,
for the research of ancient cultures.
So we're bringing into the mainstream
both as a private,
not for profit foundation as a institute
through boston university to really be
looking at these things in a,
when I say professional way,
what I mean by that is,
you know,
evidenced based way,
um,
but also looking outside the standard
dog must have standard boxes,
standard paradigms and the standard
vested interest because so much science.
Now people say to me all the time,
they think science is supposed to be
objective.
Well,
maybe it Is supposed to be objective,
but who are the scientists doing it?
They have all their subjective biases
and notions and vested interest.
I'm not trying to knock anyone but,
but it's a fact.
It is in.
It's just a human fact.
Yeah.
Are,
we're all humans.
And one of the things that happened in
that documentary from 1993 that I was
kind of stunned by was the reaction by
the conventional egyptologists when you
brought up this evidence where he was
very dismissive,
almost mockingly in this weird sort of a
way where he was like,
what,
what culture?
Where's this?
Where's the evidence in this culture?
Absolutely.
And it's kind of gross.
It is.
Because that really should not have any
place in his mind.
He was in pain and being called.
I've been called a pseudo scientists.
Um,
look,
I,
again,
I don't want to sound the wrong way,
but I think I'm as well as well
credentialed as anyone.
I mean,
among my academic colleagues,
uh,
you know,
well that's why I appreciate you that
you have stuck your neck out for so long
doing this research and since that time
have I been punished?
Yes.
Yeah,
I'm sure.
Yeah.
Let's.
No,
I'll be honest.
You know,
I haven't gotten necessarily the,
I've
had colleagues say to me in no uncertain
terms very well,
meaning that I could have had a
wonderful career and had all of the
promotions,
advancements going up through the
academic,
you know,
ladder if you would,
with no problems if I just stuck to my,
you know,
some little specialty that no one really
cared about.
Hm.
You know,
I'm.
But you've had an impact,
a gigantic impact on people like me that
have a really about,
about
continue to work on.
For instance,
one of my specialties as a graduate
student was paleocene esc in malmo
evolution.
Would I be talking to you about that
now?
Maybe if it's a,
if it was interesting,
but less likely,
less likely from seeing your skeletons
and whatnot and skulls.
I might be.
He might be.
Now.
When you were doing that,
you were talking to that guy.
One of the things that he was saying in
this dismissive ways,
where's the evidence of this culture?
Well now we have go beckley tell.
Absolutely because is the evidence
because that
that was an american association for
advancement of science debate on the
sphinx,
which turned out I thought I was going
in for a real debate.
I thought it was going to be a great
debate.
We're really going to discuss the
evidence back and forth.
I brought all my data,
the seismic data,
which is very,
very important,
which we haven't even touched on yet.
Other types of data we haven't touched
on because I want to make the point is
much more than a little bit of
weathering on the sphinx and I've heard
so many critics,
even to my face,
they say,
well,
you don't redate civilization based on a
weathering profile.
No,
I've goT lots more than weathering
profile.
The weathering profile and erosion.
the easiest thing to explain and yes,
it's what I saw initially in that first
30 to 120 seconds because that's before
I brought in equipment and work with tom
to becky to do seismic work,
to do other types of more detailed
analysis.
I would not be talking to you today if
it was just a national profile.
I for my own self,
I wouldn't put enough stock in that yet,
but when it ties in with everything
else,
we have a coach and picture.
Um,
but getting back to someone being
dismissive like that,
that was 1992.
The beckley tap bay had technically been
discovered back in the 19 sixties,
but they misdated it completely.
They thought was maybe a thousand or
2000 years old byzantine or roman greco
roman period,
not end of the last ice age,
not,
you know,
12,000
years old.
And how did they make the distinction
that it was 12,000
years old is based on the soil samples.
That
was,
that was klaus schmidt.
Klaus schmidt went back to it in about
1994 95.
So a couple of years after that.
Dismissive comment from the egyptologist
mark laner,
who I think is the specific person
you're referring to at the american
association for the advancement of
science debate,
which I just went to make the comment.
I went into that thinking that was going
to be a debate.
I came out of it realizing that they
were just trying to set me up to put me
down and shut me up forever,
which they were not successful in doing.
Do you think that they're so reluctant
to just listen to the evidence and look
at the information and,
and,
and consider the possibility that maybe
there had been an ancient civilization
because it upsets the standard timeline,
the standard standard story.
And it also upsets a lot of people's
concept of progression.
And uh,
this is something John Anthony West like
to talk about the whole,
he called it the church of progress.
That we've gotten better and better and
better.
And I talked to so many people that
think that we are the end all and be all
were the best that there ever has been.
Well,
maybe we are in terms of certain types
of technology and I'm not making any
claim that people in the past could ever
do what we're doing now doing a podcast
with all the electronics,
but as I pointed out,
that also makes us really vulnerable to
things.
But I would argue that there is a not so
remote possibility that they knew things
that we don't know,
that they may have understood things
that we don't understand.
They may have had a worldview that would
benefit us to at least have a feel for
it.
Um,
I mean,
I don't want golf on spiritual tangents.
I could,
if I want to,
our philosophical tangent,
but I also have a training as
anthropologists.
Anthropologists,
I have an undergraduate degree in
anthropology on top of everything else.
and I'm fascinated by human approaches
to life and the environment and their
situation.
And I'm convinced that we do have thingS
to learn from the ancients,
whether it's the really remote ancients
or the more recent ancients for only
5,000
years ago,
even dynastic Egypt.
Um,
and that it's not all simply a one way
progress that there are fits and starts
that there have been high points and low
points and high points again,
and I'm not frankly convinced that we're
at the highest point when it comes to
certain aspects.
We might be a high point with certain
types of technology,
but I'm not convinced that we're at a
high point when it comes to,
um,
stone construction.
Whoa.
Certainly not with stone construction.
So there are types of technology.
We are not high point with much less gay
into this philosophical or spiritual or
whatever you want to call it.
And we don't think of it as technology
because we think of technology as being
something that's electronic.
That's right.
And there are other technologies and if
you asked me how did they build the
pyramids,
I will tell you,
I don't know if you asked me how they
constructed the sphinx temple.
They carved out those huge blocks of
stone that can waive 50 or more tons and
move them in such tight spaces with such
tight tolerances.
I don't know.
I mean,
I'm not going to.
No one really knows,
no one really knows and some paints
people say,
you know,
you bring in thousands of slaves or
whatnot.
Well,
there's no evidence for that.
And where would you have them stand when
you're building the sphinx temple?
You know,
there's not enough room to gather.
Round stones are so big.
Even thousands of slaves struggled to
move them.
It's not like something like that.
Yeah.
Just get a couple of buddies.
We're going to move this couch.
Yeah,
yeah.
We're not talking about that.
No,
no,
no.
And yeah,
you can try to hypothesize levers and
that type of thing,
but it's.
This has been said before and I've seen
it questioned there in person,
but I've seen off the record document,
you know,
footage of it when they've tried to just
construct a little pyramid with very
small blocks and then they end up using
modern machines and they still weren't
very successful.
I mean,
so they knew they knew a lot.
So there's a real resistance,
I find among allow my academic
colleagues to one to even suggest that
people could have known things in the
past that we don't know now,
or If they knew something in the past
that we don't know now,
it was so trivial that it was worth
forgetting.
Worth not worrying about all should.
There's this,
that concept.
I find it amazing and I hate to be
stereotypical,
some broad brushing,
but many egyptologists when I read their
works or I listened to them at
conferences,
etc.
And I get the impression that they might
love egyptology and studying the ancient
egyptians,
but they also have this view that,
oh,
these guys made wonderful temples and
had some fantastic art,
but really,
you know,
they're sort of primitive and
[inaudible] isn't that silly?
And you see what I mean.
It's like the very thing they station.
Yeah.
The very thing they study,
they put down in a sense to Build
themselves up and to build up this idea
of ultimate progress that we Can.
Exactly.
Exactly,
exactly.
Then you also have in Egypt tall g,
and I wouldn't give you another example
of this,
not just me bringing in scientific
evidence and data and the egyptologists
rejecting it,
but just recently in the last couple of
years,
have you heard about the project on the
great pyramid,
the big void,
they've been using mammography,
which is a highly sophisticated
technique using muon set come from outer
space or come from the atmosphere.
They go through the pyramid.
You can set up detectors longterm and
pick these up.
They're sort of like x,
think of x rays technology,
but using muons,
uh,
which are sort of exotic particle that
most people are not aware of because
they just pass right through us without
interacting.
But when you've got massive stone,
massive stone will block some of them so
you can pick up essentially image over a
long period of time.
So this is really high tech physics,
very expensive.
A consortium of physicists did work on
the great pyramid.
I think it's still ongoing,
but they put up,
you know,
tens of millions if not more worth of a
high,
you know,
sophisticate physical physics equipment,
gathered all this data.
I've seen the raw data.
I have a degree in geophysics,
geology and geophysics.
I have some aBility to evaluate this
type of data,
whereas I hate to say aloud the
egyptologist don't.
Um,
and I found that with my own data when I
shared my own data that not to be nasty,
but they didn't know what they were
looking at,
which is somewhat understandable since
it's not their training.
Right.
So you have with the great pyramid,
just recently in the last couple of
years,
published in nature of very prestigious
journal,
they found what they believe is evidence
for a huge void above the grand gallery
that has never been known before.
Um,
and yeah,
there we have a picture of it.
The egyptologist had been so resistant
to this saying,
this is nonsense.
There can't be,
we don't.
Basically we,
there can't be anything new that we
don't know about are.
If it is,
it's just trivial.
It's just some space between the rocks.
it's nothing important,
but what I wanted to say,
what's really important,
some egyptologists actually called for
the whole project to be closed down
because they don't like the results and
they called it quote propaganda because
down,
but you'll cut that closed down the
whole scientific project.
They don't.
Not only do they not want to look at the
data,
they'll want more data collected that
might contradict their standard.
That's fascinating that someone would
actually call for them because this
isn't even their study of their field of
study.
Right,
so you're dealing with physical evidence
that they're saying is nonsense,
but this is not something they study in
the first place.
So there's this void that we're looking
at here in these images.
Can you explain to people that are just
listening what we're seeing?
Oh,
what you're seeing is they call it a
hidden chamber there,
but you can see how it's parallel to the
grand gallery.
The grand galleries is huge gallery that
goes up to the king's chamber and the
great pyramid
and that's deep in the pyramid.
The pyramid in chambers above bobbitt
parallel shit is maybe close to the same
size of it.
It's hard to tell with until it gets
prob,
you know,
you'd have to dro into it and maybe put
a camera in.
But I've seen the raw data.
My point is I've seen the raw data.
I certainly think it's important they're
interpreting it correctly now.
The proof will be in the pudding as they
say if they ever entered or at least put
a probe into it,
but my point right now is to just
dismiss the data is nonsense to call for
the whole project to be shut down is non
client project and some of the Egypt
Egypt in Egypt.
Tologist.
I'm close close to the ministry and my
point
is they've done the same thing to me.
So for instance,
when we did seismic work and we found
the chamber under the left pog this
sphinx,
that's never been explored since,
at least not to my knowledge.
And they just dismiss it and say,
we know there's nothing there.
Um,
and that was despite the fact that we
also found the chamber at the rump of
the sphinx,
which I didn't know about the time,
but they already knew about.
So it confirmed that our data was good
because we were finding something they
knew about,
but when we find something that they
don't know about and they don't want to
be there,
they dismiss it and don't want to pursue
it further.
Do you have explored one of those
chambers?
Correct.
Instead they explore the one that's in
the rump.
The one in the rump?
Yes.
The one in the rump by it turns out they
already knew about it.
It's probably not super significant.
It probably is just maybe a greco roman
or late period,
you know,
burial or,
or some kind of excavation.
The one I believe is important is under
the left palm,
the sphinx,
which I believe is a archive actually
may go back to this very early period
because we now have hieroglyphic
evidence indicating that what,
what is the evidence indicates it's an
archive.
Okay.
So recently,
and this gets back to,
um,
the sphinx?
yes.
Okay.
So we started this portion of the
discussion with the sphinx in my initial
observations of the spanx and one of my
observations was that there's something
going on with the weathering and erosion
on the sphinx.
The second observation,
this is within the first two minutes at
most,
was that the head is too small for the
body.
The head is not eroded the way the core
body is.
It's not erode the way the walls at the
sphinx enclosure or it's not the
original head.
I hate to say it this way,
but I knew immediately that was not the
original head,
just from a geological point of view and
I believe that's now since been fully
confirmed,
that this is not the original head.
It wAs a recurved head.
So for a long time the question has been
in my mind,
and we talk about this event,
I'm mystery of the sphinx.
What was the original head of the
sphinx?
What was the sphinx?
Originally?
We've speculated and other people
speculate.
My have been a lion,
for instance,
leo,
because it faces on the equinox,
the constellation,
leo in the sky.
Not today,
but 10,000
bc or so,
more or less at the very end of the last
ice age.
Now I've had a lot of colleagues of
mine,
academic colleagues say that's nonsense.
You know,
it doesn't mean anything because they
weren't even recognizing the
constellations back then.
Um,
we now have plenty of evidence,
at least some of the constellations that
we recognize today.
A leo,
I would put in that category.
A tourist is in that category.
Uh,
ryan is in that core category.
Some of them,
we don't have evidence
for it,
but the ones I just mentioned,
the,
um,
they,
these are constellations that go back
well into the end of the last ice age.
We have documents of that.
We have mammoth bones where you have a
ryan carved on it.
We have tourists shown in cave walls.
We have leo shown.
So it's to me,
it's fascinating that some of these
constellations that we recognize today,
we're recognized tens of thousands of
years ago.
So to me it's not nonsense that they
carved a structure 10,000
bc approximately that was facing its own
image in the sky.
So one suggestion was that maybe it's
leo,
but recently manu safe today,
dr.
Mondo saves a day and another colleague
of mine,
he recognized initially that there is a
title,
what's known as a dual title in dynastic
Egypt that goes back to the fourth
dynasty and even back to the first
dynasty with the earliest writing and it
when properly translate,
it basically refers to the sphinx as the
guardian up an archive and not the
sphinx is we think of it as a lion with
a human head,
but as a lioness.
And there was a name for this line,
this method she was the goddess met hit
who guarded archive.
Um,
and we wrote a paper on that.
When I say we,
my new safe day,
myself and robert duvall,
who you may know us from a ryan
correlation,
some of his,
his work ties in with this,
the rko astronomy.
But we've now found that there is this
sign,
which we named the jaw signed and honor.
That's awesome.
Under John Anthony West.
Uh,
there it is.
There's the jaw sign and what you see
here,
it's a lioness met hit,
which was the sphinx originally based on
our reconstruction and interpretation
and can't go into all the details.
Now you can actually.
People can read the paper.
If I could put a plug in.
If people go to my website,
www dot robert schoch and that's r o b e
r t r o b e r t s c h o c h.
The main thing is my name is spelled s c
h o c h,
so www dot robert [inaudible] dot com.
They can go.
I did a popular summary of the paper and
they can also go and download the
original paper and the peer reviewed
journal archeological discovery where we
argue that what we have here is that
line has met him.
She has what looks like a bent rod
coming out of her back.
Then people look at the actual image and
then aBove it is a aCts.
So yeah,
it's,
it's a primitive acts.
Um,
when I say primitive,
even for the ancient egyptians in
dynastic Egypt,
that would have been sort of a symbolIc
acts if you would,
which was a sign of someone who was in
charge of things you oversee or that
type of thing that bent rod.
What is that?
That's a primitive key.
We would now call the primitive key,
but it represents a key and so it's
basically saying that this is the
guardian of the archives have met,
hit the locked chamber or vault of
method and we also have images.
I see it up on the board now.
If you look at,
you've got the linus with the key and
you also have a line not in that image
by different image that we had before.
If you look at that,
can you see how there's a linus a
diagrammatic shape over what looks like
a facade.
Okay.
If you then go to the stella that sits
between the paws of this finks,
you have the same image,
much more artistically rendered of the
sphinx sitting over a facade over what
looks like a building.
It's not really a building.
It's the archive underneath.
I believe,
which I know there's something
underneath because long ago in the early
19 nineties,
thomas to becky and I,
when we did seismic work around the
sphinx,
we found the chamber under the paws of
the sphinx and it's I'm sure an
artificial chamber.
It's very regular and this I believe
could well be.
I'm hypothesizing and in science we make
hypothesis that are testable.
This is perfectly testable.
All we have to do is enter that chamber.
Even if it's just to put fiber optic
down and we can see is it an artificial
chamber that's an archive.
Hopefully there's still things there or
maybe it was gutted and cleaned out at
some point,
but here we have the seismic work.
One of the seismic maps,
I'll call it to a data and what's label
is normally a under the left paw that is
the chamber we found under the left paw
that the egyptologists have to deny ever
since and they don't want to explore it
and we haven't gotten permission.
It doesn't make any sense to me.
Well,
I know,
but this is.
If there's physical evidence,
this is politics in Egypt.
God,
it's so squirrely.
Yeah.
So now,
okay,
this is 1991 or so early.
Nineteen nineties.
As of last year,
2017.
We have textual evidence,
ancient hieroglyphs talking about this
chamber,
talking about this finks talking about
the sphinx being alignness guardian,
a chamber,
and I want to point out that the
earliest hieroglyphs that we have that
refer to this are about 30 3030 100 bc,
which is hundreds of years before the
egyptologists claim.
The sphinx was even thought about being
carved,
which is somewhere around 2,500
bc.
One,
500 bc back sides with the construction.
The great pyramid of giza.
Okay,
well that's another question.
Oh,
so we'll come back to that because I
don't buy the.
It's more.
Can we come back?
Yes,
yes,
yes.
So the age of tall just claimed that the
sphinx was first car of 2,500
bc.
Yet there's no mention of the carving of
the sphinx.
Then they cite the inventory,
not inventory stella.
That's another step.
They cite the top most of fourth dream.
Stella,
which is a thousand plus years later,
which had one point,
a partial cartoon of kafra,
partial cartouche of coffer,
which has since flaked away,
was there reputedly in the 19th century.
There were drawings of it,
um,
which we to put in our plugin,
just if people are interested in gaining
more information.
Robert duvall and I wrote a book last
year published last year called origins
of the sphinx,
where we discuss a lot of this but met
hit is a more recent discovery.
Um,
so there was a partial cartouche of
kafra,
which egyptologists said,
aha,
this proves that kafra carved the sphinx
because the sphinx,
it's due east of crawford pyramid coffer
was the pharaoh and 2,500
bc.
Therefore the Sphinx must be 2,500
I contend,
and robert duvall and other people who
are in our line of thinking content that
this stella that's over a thousand
thousands,
sorry,
over a thousand years later,
does not say that it carved.
He carved the sphinx,
but that he restored the sphinx just
like most moses,
the fourth who was putting up the stella
was restoring the sphinx.
And when you look at the sphinx,
it has been restored numerous times,
including blocks of limestone that were
put onto it to restore some of the very
ancient weathering that when I asked sy
hawala,
while my biggest critics,
how old those blocks are,
he said they were fourth dynasty.
Now,
why would you restored in the fourth
dynasty when it had just been built,
you know,
literally a century or two ago.
You don't need to restore a meter worth
of weathering.
Um,
his,
his answer,
and I'm not trying to make fun of him,
is that it's rotten rock that wasn't
very high quality rocks was how somehow
it just crumbled away,
you know,
meter or so,
a couple of hundred years.
Graham hancock.
Yeah.
But that's another issue.
I don't want get into that.
Okay.
BeCause,
uh,
let me just say it this way,
there,
there's,
there was not just science going on
there,
there was politics going on.
So,
you know,
there's a lot going on.
There's a lot going on.
Exactly.
I've seen it too and I've known all
these people for a very frustrating
decades.
Yeah.
So I'm trying to keep just to the
science right now,
but so he himself admits that some of
these repairs go BaCk well over 4,000
years,
which makes no sense if it's always
4,500
years old.
Exactly,
exactly.
And they've always contended there was
no inscriptions or anything really
referring to the sphinx until new
kingdom times.
We point out in origins at the sphinx,
robert paval night that no,
you have to know what they were calling
the banks.
And now with matt hit,
we have inscriptions.
They find that.
And when did they find this lioness.
And when do they,
when you're saying this is very recent.
Yeah,
manu saves the day.
My coauthor just discovered that,
um,
I don't know exactly when he found the
inscription,
uh,
but he first pointed it out to robert
duvall myself about a year ago,
a year ago,
and we all worked on it and confirmed it
and put together the pieces.
I mean,
he really gets the most credit for it.
Um,
he's,
he,
he knows his heart gliffy really where
they find this higher glyphic of this.
The,
um,
it's shoWn in several different,
uh,
ancient artifacts.
So for instance,
there is a statue of vca,
uh,
from the fourth dynasty who may have
actually overseeing the construction of
the great pyramid,
or I would say the reconstruction of the
great pyramid because I might get back
to that.
I think the peer at great pyramid,
just like the sphinx was being
reconstructed refurbished,
if you would,
during the old kingdom,
not constructed de novo,
but he was overseeing that he must have
had something to do with the sphinx.
Um,
he was apparently the,
um,
given the title of being the overseer
for the sphinx,
that type of thing,
but it turns out this title was
something he had in cuckoo's time,
which is the,
the,
the pharaoh before supposedly when the
sinks is built to begin with.
So that messes up the Egypt logical
thinking right there.
Um,
but this title was something that had
been held by others before him back down
to about 31 or so hundred bc,
you know,
5,000
years ago,
again,
500 or more years before the swings was
supposedly built.
Uh,
so now we hAve this hieroglyphic text
that goes back refutes what the
egyptologist are saying,
and not only that,
but when you look at the way they wrIte
it,
this is the earliest writing,
so it's not surprising.
We don't have anything earlier.
Maybe eventually we'll find earlier,
you know,
the precursors,
but they are also in the context,
it seems abundantly evident they're
referring to it as a very old structure.
Wow.
Now how do egyptologists receive this?
Uh,
it's just making its way into the Egypt
logical community if we will see how
they received.
So far there's been no reaction.
No,
no,
I'll just put it that way.
No,
not that I know officially.
Well,
you've seen it all before.
So I've seen it all before and you know,
it's a classic thing to that in some
cases.
So I'll,
I'll put it related to the sphinx and
maybe hopefully somewhat analogous.
I pointed out decades should go and John
Anthony West and I working on this,
that this finks the head is not the
original head and I'm not sure if I'm
the very first one to ever say that I'm
not going to try to take credit,
but it was quite obvious to me when I,
as I mentioned,
without anyone saying that to me,
I had not heard that someone else
suggested that since then egyptologist
with,
of course out ever citing me or John
Anthony West have also been suggesting
that in some cases,
and some have suggested that maybe it
was [inaudible] face on the sphinx
rather than coffers face after we
brought in frank domingo who demonstrate
that's not coppers face a frank domingo,
if you remember from mystery of the
sphinx,
was a New York city police officer,
forensic expert who literally would
reconstruct faces,
compare faces that was his business.
And To present it in court,
uh,
he analyzed the face of the Sphinx in
the face of kafir,
also known as schaeffer on the pharaoh.
The egyptologists before our time,
before we got involved in this,
always said these were the same faces to
face of the sphinx.
The face of copper,
a frank domingo came out very
definitively that they're not the same
face and they're both competent artists.
They're not frankly the same ethnicity
of face.
Uh,
and for mark laner to publish in
national geographic that I'll
paraphrase,
some of the sphinx came alive when he
reconstructed with the face of chef ron
or face of conference just,
that's not science,
that's,
um,
you know,
wish fulfillment or something.
He wanted it to be the face of a certain
pharaoh.
He does computer construction with it,
having the face of the pharaoh he wants
it to be.
And then past the ad off is somehow,
um,
I guess science.
So there's no egyptologist not
necessarily science either.
And I'm not saying that a nasty way,
but it's an important point because
egyptology,
a lot of egyptologists classically come
more from a art history background,
that type of thing.
So tying in with the question you asked
before,
I literally.
It's funny how things work.
I literally,
when I was in graduate school,
took a seminar in sciences
and other disciplines,
you know,
this was because I was being trained as
a scientist and one of the papers we had
to read at the time,
this was long before I ever thought
about going to Egypt was how
egyptologists are resistant to
scientific information and scientific
data and how to help try to overcome
that.
If you're working with egyptologist
basically what's the answer was it's
very difficult and it's not to put them
down because I have lots of colleagues
and other fields that are not sciences,
but classically I would contend
egyptology is not a science.
It comes more from art history or from
linguistic studies,
you know,
translating hieroglyphs,
um,
historical studies and those are all
very important academic studies.
But you do sometimes get people in a
certain field and they're resistant to
outsiders from another field,
especially when they think it's a field
that's so far apart and so diverse from
what they understand,
what they know,
their own mindset.
Yeah.
And their mindset is not geared towards
scientific data.
And I'm not.
Again,
I'm not trying to be nasty,
it's just have to explain yourself.
Yeah,
you're not coming across nasdaq.
So when you initially saw these erosion
features and and you the first 30 to 90
seconds or whatever,
you said it was 120 seconds when you
first looked at it and new,
did you have any idea that your life
would take the turn that it's taken?
I mean,
did you have any indication thrown into
such a shit storm?
All these years later?
We are in 2018.
You're still fighting the good fight.
I know as John Anthony West one said
introducing me.
Um,
he ruined.
He ruined my life.
Twenty five years later after that
documentary,
you're still swinging.
I dunno,
I dunno.
I'm still getting attacked and I'm
still.
The answer is no.
I was naive.
I was incredibly naive at the time.
I still was not that far out of graduate
school.
You thought you could just present?
Yeah.
Stand on its own and just present the
said man,
what a great new discovery.
Exactly.
That was it,
and I was so naive
and so we first present the evidence at
the geological society of America annual
meeting in 1991,
I guess it was.
Yeah,
1991,
and I want to say bluntly,
the vast majority of geologists,
hundreds,
literally thought,
oh,
this is amazing.
This is great.
it made,
started making some headlines around the
world.
Literally,
there were one or two geologists there
that turns out.
Turns out we're working for
egyptologist.
They didn't think this was so great
because they saw the implications for
the Egypt illogical colleagues and they
started,
you know,
a little rumbling there.
Then the journalists come in back then
you'll know internet like we have it
now,
just phones and the journalists start
calling egyptologists that we're not
there,
had not seen the data,
etc.
Immediately they were telling the
journalists at this has to all be
nonsense that hundreds of egyptologists
have studied this for,
you know,
two or three centuries,
which is total nonsense.
It turns out I knew every egyptologists
because they're so few that have
actually stayed the sphinx personally,
surely just to.
So.
So yeah,
they were just trying to dismiss it and
then the egyptologists come back and say
we know this is nonsense essentially.
I'm paraphrasing,
we know that the pyramids were not built
by aliens so they start bringing aliens
and you have photos.
So essentIally just to dismiss,
dismiss me and I wasn't talking about
total straw.
Yeah,
I wasn't talking about pyramids,
number one,
we could talk about that if you want to.
And I wasn't talking about aliens.
They hadn't been there,
they hadn't seen the data.
It was so bizarre in hindsight.
And I'm so frustrated trying to defend
their positions and they were just,
they were really just attacking.
And then in Egypt at one point they were
um,
putting things in the arabic press.
Little did they know,
I have friends that would read it to me
and they were saying that I wasn't even
a faculty member at boston university,
which is outright lie since I had just
been tenured.
So there Was no doubt I was a faculty
member there.
But this was other academic saying this,
but they never thought we'd get back to
me.
I mean really,
really mean.
And nasty,
I'm so game back to the evidence.
So they set up in,
this was I think unprecedented within
months.
They'd set up this debate at the triple
a s american association for the
advancement of science.
And I thought again,
I was so naive,
I thought,
oh,
this is wonderful.
Fine though.
We'll get rid of all this nonsense in
this name calling and you know,
the stuff in the popular press that no
journalists,
you can't blame them.
They don't know what's going on
necessarily and will really get the
evidence out and we'll be able to
discuss it.
Um,
sanely and objectively turns out that
wasn't the case at all.
It was just from my perspective,
they were just calling me more names and
trying to set up straw men.
And
is this the egyptologist who was in that
documentary who dismissed everything was
still around.
Oh yeah.
And has he amended his position at all?
Not to my knowledge.
I haven't spoken with him for years and
years and years.
Did yoU ever speak with them off the
record personally alone?
What is this?
Oh,
I,
I'll tell you this,
but he didn't say was off the record.
I was,
I guess was off the record.
I don't think I would have said this
years ago,
but I'll say it now at that debate,
at that debate,
aaa's debate.
He,
I just suddenly found myself in the hall
with him and there was no one else
around so he could totally deny this.
But it's true.
My perspective,
at least he,
um,
said something to me like,
you know,
you don't really believe this.
I know you don't really believe this.
You just want to be on television and,
you know,
be famous or something like that.
He said,
I said,
no,
I really do believe it.
Or you know,
I really go by the evidence and I do
think the evidence says this.
And he served.
He was telling me that,
no,
you don't,
you know,
he was like,
I don't know.
I analyze what the sizing you.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
And then he lead in and then,
and then what he does is he starts
asking me a question of some detailed
question about the geology and well,
if that's the case,
how can such and such and I think in
hindsight might have been fed to them by
some geo archeologists.
They called someone who does archeology
but knows a little geology.
Uh,
and I,
I realize in hindsight it was meant to
be one of those gotcha questions.
I guess they say nowadays where I
wouldn't be able to answer it,
but no,
I had,
of course I'd thought about it.
It was to me as a geologist,
very obvious.
So I start giving him this detailed
explanation as to why that's not the
case and why,
you know,
my evidence stands up,
blah,
blah blah.
And we're standing there face to face.
I'm explained this to him and I see his
face turn and it goes blank and I'm in
midsentence.
He just turns around and walks away.
He's the one
he couldn't,
he couldn't refuse,
can refute what I was saying and he
wasn't really answered.
My takeaway is that he wasn't interested
in discussing it rationally or aunts,
you know,
he just went to,
um,
when the debate or whatever,
he.
No,
when he knew that he
wasn't going to with you,
he just got out of there.
Yeah.
And again,
you know,
it was a,
just a personal thing.
There was no other witnesses to my
knowledge of this,
but if he had really wanted to discuss
things,
I was willing to discuss it with them
and it's so disturbing that someone
would put their own egos so far above
the information that needs to be
distributed to scholars and people and
students and all these folks out there
that have questions about the history of
the human race.
it's someone would put their own
reputation and eagle above all of that
and not have the,
the,
the mindset to realize,
well,
we have new evidence and what we thought
of before.
We're going to have to apply to this new
evidence and create a new timeline.
It doesn't dismiss all the things that
they learned in the past.
No,
no.
That's something.
In fact,
I'm glad you brought that up because I
long contended that people talk about
rewriting history,
etc.
Well,
yes,
I understand that argument and I think
we do need to rewrite good chunks of our
very early history,
but I've never denied dynastic Egypt in
the basic chronology for dynastic agent.
Now what I say that we've got a whole
new chapter to add to it going back in
time plus,
and I won't mention the great pyramid
here,
plus things like the great pyramid,
the standard dating for the great
pyramid,
let's say 20 5:50
bc or so,
the pharaoh khufu also known as cheops.
Just in case people hear those terms.
I don't deny that he had something to do
with the great pyramid,
but when I study it geologically and I
don't want to get into great detail
here.
When I study a geologically,
I think there was a older structure
there.
I think there was something else there.
For instance,
a subterranean chamber I suspect goes
back much earlier than the time of
fourth dynasty khufu.
So for instance,
to bring in robert [inaudible],
he has his awry in correlation of the
three pyramids to the belt.
Stars have a ryan,
which correlate very well at about
10,500
bc.
So he'll talk and we talk about this in
our joint book,
origins of the sphinx,
how there was a master plan going back
to that period.
A lot of people have said that,
well,
that's nonsense.
Why would they be following a master
plan?
Thousands of years later when they
finally got around to building these
structures.
I don't think that's the case at all.
I think there were earlier markers are
structures at those spots.
The pyramids in this case,
those three major pyramids were built
over or enhanced or restored older
structures,
if that makes sense.
So for instance,
under the great pyramid is what I call
the sacred mound.
It's actually literally a stone
outcropping mound and John Paul move
wall.
I'm robert [inaudible].
Older brother's actually architect
robert paval himself was trained as an
engineer.
They both make the point among are
things that if you're building the great
pyramid,
I mean this is a humongous structure
with incredible way.
It's much easier to flatten the plateau
at that point.
Again,
nice level base rather than try to build
over and around a mound that's to this
day incorporate within the great
pyramid.
This takes a lot more energy and work
and it's a much more difficult
engineering feat,
but it makes sense if you're.
You want to preserve that.
If it was sacred to them or whatever.
That older structure.
We have images of the soldiers
structure.
Oh,
you can't see it at this point because
it's totally covered,
but we have something very analogous,
and I know you mentioned this when John
Anthony West was on the red pyramid,
is also built over an older structure
and you can see that to this day in one
of the chambers where you have this much
older structure.
I'm talking geologically now based on
the evidence.
Then we have some images there where you
have this older weathered structure,
which I believe goes back.
I don't know how much older but
thousands of years old or let's just
leave it that and then they built the
pyramid over it and around it,
I think marketing it,
you know,
refurbishing and much older structure
and you can tell by the weathering and
the stuff,
whether it's stone,
whether constructed.
Exactly.
And you can see the sharp divide between
the older structure and the newer
structure,
which is nice.
Finally cut stone.
And that newer structure goes back
earlier than the great pyramid.
I mean,
this is snefru.
This is even earlier by a generation.
Uh,
so you have this where they're using and
dynastic Egypt older structures there,
reappropriating them.
You have the case here.
I believe you have that with the great
pyramid.
I believe you have to have that with the
second pyramid.
You have that with the sphinx.
Most definitely.
And the valley temple and the sphinx
temple.
The first piece of evidence that really
convinced me that something was going on
with the sphinx.
So the first evidence that I saw that
made me suspicious that the egyptologist
did not have it right,
was within that first 30 to 120 seconds.
I described the weathering and the
head's too small.
The first piece of really solid evidence
was looking at the walls of the sphinx
and valley temple that were constructed
from the stones that came out of the
sphinx.
Enclosure,
we talked about that they are weathered,
but then they were cut back a little
bit.
That weathering was cut back and they
were resurfaced or re faced with granted
in dynastic times.
It's believed.
So what you have is a older structure
and here's a diagram a for anyone that's
looking at,
but what you have is older limestone
temples,
which are massive,
which were then faced with granite,
but what they did,
they did it the hard way.
They preserved as much of the older
limestone temple as possible before
refacing it with granted.
So they actually took the time,
in some cases to cut the backs of the
granite blocks to fit the weathered
surface of the limestone.
Wow.
Whether it would be much easier,
you have plenty of rock there.
Just skim down the limestone.
Totally make a nice flat surface and
then replaster so speak regranted it.
Hmm.
What you all chipping away the old rock
that shipped with the new role because I
think it was important for them.
It's like if we have a national monument
now that goes back to
evolutionary war days.
He wants to preserve as much of the
original structure as possible,
even if it makes it more difficult to do
the restoration.
Now you put the effort into it.
Just to clarify,
so you feel that this time period of
the,
the coronal mass ejections mass
ejections was somewhere around 10,000
bc.
Well 9,700
bc and I say that very specific
because based on greenland ice core data
in particular,
you can literally count back year by
year and the best estimate is about
9,700.
See,
you know,
give or take a decade or something.
So from that point to 2,500
bc,
which is where most conventional
egyptologists date,
the construction of the pyramid,
you believe that the great pyramid was
probably built on top of this great
mound which represented an older
structure,
but these are the people that their
civilization was destroyed and then
thousands of years later we're able to
somehow or another rebuild
thousands of years later.
Why don't know if they were rebuilding a
nut pyramid as it was before or they
were building new pyramid on top.
The,
they obviously had retained some of the
incredible
wisdom and knowledge.
Well,
think of it to this day,
I'm a,
I'll think of judeo christian islam.
Uh,
I mean we still have a,
like the temple mound.
We have places where we know that there
were older structures,
solomon's temple,
et cetera,
and maYbe only a fragment of it is left,
but we still held in high esteem
veneration.
Modern structures are built around or
over these relics.
I think that's a somewhat of an analogy
of what the parthenon.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
So you have veneration of older.
If I could use that,
and I'm not used necessarily using it in
religious terms,
I mean,
could just be respect.
Yes.
Uh,
so I think that for all three of the
major pyramids on the giza plateau,
we have evidence that there was
something there,
whether they were pyramids as we see
them now,
which is quite a possibility and they
were just refurbished or something else.
Uh,
we have evidence that goes back to that
much earlier period before the demise of
high civilization,
if I could put it that way at the end of
the last ice age.
And then it was reappropriate re-used,
rebuilt,
restored,
whatever term you wanna use in dynastic
egyptian times.
Uh,
when give you another example.
Have you been to Egypt?
No,
I have not.
I didn't think you had.
You need to come to show thIs to you in
person.
I wanted to go with you.
Your chicken chicken.
Scared to go to Egypt.
Hurt is dangerous.
Not with me.
Not with me because I take care of her.
No,
no.
I buy have enough context.
I have enough context that I'll go with
you immediately get we have to make
something happen.
Yeah,
definitely,
definitely.
Points of the mountain and digital to
give people a perspective of time that t
2000,
500 years ago,
the conventional dating of the
construction,
the grandparents,
cleopatra is closer to the construction
of the iphone than she is to the
construction of the great pyramids.
That's just how long a history you're
dealing with when it comes to ancient
Egypt.
So we're talking about thousands and
thousands of years for sure.
And this is for sure for sure.
Like where we absolutely know,
forget about all the speculation just
from cleopatra to the 2000 fIve hundred
bc,
which is what almost all the
egyptologists except you're dealing with
just a giant leap harris,
right.
Here's the.
we could see it here.
That's right.
And,
and so,
and we are closer to the dynastic
egyptians.
Even the old kingdom dynastic egyptians,
we are closer to them in time than they
were to the end of the last ice age and
the demise of that earlier civilization.
So a dynastic egyptian dynastic Egypt
arose.
Rough terms,
5,000
years ago,
that was about 3000 bc.
That was,
they arose over 6,000
years after close to 7,000
years after the end of the last ice age,
so that's crazy.
Yeah,
that's hard.
Hartford were talking real spans of time
here and you're looking at.
We're looking at a chart right here.
Is there any way,
is there a place or were other people
can go and see this because it's
ongoing.
A chart like this is on my website,
in the article,
if you go to my website,
robert shocked again,
www dot robert schoch,
s c h o c h.com,
and go to the website.
You'll see charts like this,
but what you should do is go to the main
page of the website and then I believe
it is a research highlights,
go to whatsapp,
hauled research highlights actually I
think for those on the podcast are
seeing here and then go to what's called
the cita article as did a,
and this is what we're looking at a
standard on the website now which stands
for solar induced dark age today and
again,
it's ironic.
I think that the sun,
which of course is pride,
couldn't induce a dark age,
but when you have a major eruption like
this,
a major outburst from the sun hitting
the earth and all the ramifications we
were talking about,
it's going to bring any civilization
down
to its knees.
Thousands and thousands of years of
rebuilding civilization and rising
backup to some still unbelievably
incredible technological level.
So even if they did rebuild the pyramid
at 2,500
bc,
it's still this incredible feat.
Oh,
it's incredible.
For years,
why 500
bc?
Before if I could just finish a thought
that I started to have,
I was saying we have to go Egypt
together and I could show you something
that we could do a podcast there.
Snap.
Yeah.
I could take you.
Among other things around the second
pyramid,
the second pyramid.
You can see evidence.
I would point to you that I interpret as
going back to an earlier structure.
Furthermore,
the second period pyramid few people
seem to pay attention to this has a
ring,
a ring of granite around the base.
That's significant because they were
using granted in many cases and
conventional egyptologists who have
confirmed to this,
confirm this verbally with me.
They would use granted when they were
indicating they were restoring an older
structure and there's no question that
granite goes back to the fourth dynasty,
just like there's no question that the
granite on the valley and sphinx temple
goes back to at least the fourth
dynasty,
if not earlier,
but they're using it to restore.
So we have all of this indication that
dynastic Egypt acknowledged that they
were restoring older structures.
Um,
so getting back to where we were just on
the great pyramid.
So no matter how you look at it to try
to do,
build a great pyramid today,
whether you're talking 2,500
bc or earlier,
I mean,
how were they doing it?
how were they doing?
I don't know.
I told you I am not going to try to get
into how they did.
I'm,
that's,
they did it.
It's there.
Uh,
you know,
it's,
it's.
I have,
I thought about a lot.
Yes.
Whether I'm there in Egypt on site or
elsewhere.
I mean,
it's incredible.
I don't have any answer for you.
Is it possible that the people in that
part of the world somehow another
survived the coronal mass ejection in
and they came out better than the people
in other parts of the world that were
really knocked into the stone age?
No,
I don't think there's any evidence for
that because,
because we seem to have a huge gap
around the world,
around the gap,
but they still historically
now what they were doing in Egypt is
incomparable.
One could argue,
so it may well be that they found all
the right materials,
all the right environments,
a nile valley in its height,
which is nonsense height.
Now,
um,
you know,
at the end of sydney,
let's say for a reemergence may have
just been,
I hate to say the goldie locks words,
but just right for everything to come
together for this to,
you know,
come together.
It's a very fertile area.
It's very easily,
uh,
defended that type of thing.
Um,
and also I do want to tie in with what
you were saying it is,
and I've certainly thought about this.
It is possible that a,
we are electrical and um,
the fluctuating and electric fields,
magnetic fields.
Did they have some influence if I'm
brain development or you know,
that's real speculation,
but I wouldn't say it's impossible
either.
So,
so
these people,
is it possible they retained some
of the knowledge from thousands of.
I think they definitely retaining
knowledge,
just like we have monasteries in europe
during the dark ages retaining
knowledge.
And what's interesting is in some cases
you would retain chunks of knowledge
that don't even make sense out of
context except that they know they're
important.
They're no,
they're valuable.
What kind of examples?
Well,
I think in europe where you would have
um,
uh,
pieces of technology that would be
retained,
but you don't have the whole complex or
thinking literary terms.
That's probably the easiest where you
have parts of like a history of
alexander where the whole thing did not
survive,
but you know,
six out of nine chapters or whatever
survived.
And even Though they knew it was an
incomplete manuscript,
they would make numerous copies of the
incomplete manuscript.
Knowing that it was important,
sort of like the goals.
Oh yeah,
there's another example,
although the dead sea scrolls
potentially were absolutely complete,
or at least most of them are complete
when they were buried and you know,
put away for storage.
A lot of them,
the incomplete lists there may be
because they degrade it because they
were discovered by,
you know,
locals who have been tore them apart.
And so pieces here or there,
I'm referring more to a situation where
you have ancient knowledge,
our ancient manuscripts and even though
say the monks and a monastery knew that
this was not a complete manuscript,
they knew that even in its
incompleteness,
it was important to maintain as much of
it as possible.
It's just stunning that civilization
that was knocked down like every other
civilization,
somehow or another 2,500
bc rose to this incredible level of
construction that is just unparalleled
anywhere else on the planet.
And it did it very,
very quickly,
very quickly.
Uh,
which I think does,
is it indicative potentially that they
were reusing knowledge that had been
passed down and somehow maybe things
just clicked together.
Maybe it took one genius to start
putting things together.
And that set off a renaissance if you
would.
I mean we've seen that historically and
much more recent times that maybe
perhaps the understanding of how it was
built and designed is more prevalent
amongst the civilization amongst the
community than maybe it would be today.
Yeah.
So I mean there's still a lot of
unanswered questions here,
obviously.
Yeah.
Obviously it's incredible incredible
stuff,
but I think we're starting to get more
toward an answer or at least getting the
broader outlines of what is going on.
Wow.
This is so fascinating to think that
this could potentially happen to us.
Well,
that it's not the only fast dane.
I hate to use the term.
It's scary and I think we're incredibly
vulnerable and people are not
addressing.
This is not the type of thing to address
for some reason because a major solar
outburst and coronal mass ejection and
all the related phenomena.
We've mentioned this earlier would bring
down modern technology as we know it
would fry the grid system.
YoU'd have high radiation levels.
You'd probably have all the flooding.
I mean,
look what happens now when you have
lIttle floods,
and I say that as a geologist,
not to downplay the horrible disasters
we've had,
but other factors.
For instance,
we have nuclear power plants all around
the world.
We've seen that with a few isolated
instances.
Chernobyl,
three mile island fukushima recently.
What happens when you have problems with
those?
If you cut off power to a nuclear power
plant,
it's ironic.
Lot of people don't realize it.
Yes,
they generate power,
but they need a power supply going into
them.
IF you fry the grid system,
you're essentially going to have
meltdowns and radiation.
You're going to have problems.
And on top of everything else,
we're going to bring on this artificial
radiation around the world.
Uh,
I mean,
it's,
and again,
I'm not saying this,
I don't have anything to sell.
You know,
sometimes I hear people talk about this
because there was.
So they're prepping kid and now they're
going to,
oh,
for so much money,
I'll sell,
you know,
jim baker style.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
But no,
and I,
I hate to even talk about it except I
think it's important and I think that
one of the things this gets back to
that,
it's not just sort of academic to study
ancient civilization,
it's not just fun and interesting,
but I think there are things to learn
from this and one of the things to learn
is that they survived incredible.
Well,
I don't know if they survive,
but they were knocked to their knees,
but we,
they went through natural catastrophes,
which are not unrealistic that we could
go through them again and be potentially
much more vulnerable than they are than
they were at that time.
Uh,
because we're so reliant on silver.
Yeah.
Are there any hieroglyphs that are
convincing or at least point to some of
the construction methods of,
of the pyramid or of any of the other?
Well,
you said convincing,
I would say no.
Now I would say no.
Uh,
and this gets into the problem to that.
Why would you expect that I'm serious
because what we have surviving are
generally religious,
somewhat literary,
um,
things in tombs.
Now I don't buy for a second that the
great pyramid was a tumor initially too.
That's like saying a huge cathedrals
just to tune because you find a couple
of bodies there and you've never
actually found bodies in the great
pyramid oriented,
the major pyramids and as you know,
I know you know this,
the pure construction goes down hill as
you go into later dynastic Egypt.
So they seem to have either gotten
sloppier or just lost some of the
technological finesse they had.
So you find in some of the tombs these
what almost seemed silly pictures of
them dragging huge statues on sledges
where they're supposedly pouring oil or
water in front of it to lubricated.
And you know,
the egyptologist say,
aha,
this is how they built it all.
We'll try doing that in real life.
It doesn't really work.
So I think some of that may just be sort
of artistic license or metaphor,
that type of thing.
Do you have any images of that?
Uh,
but not.
Not that I brought with me,
but my point is that you wouldn't even
expect them to be leaving detailed
construction plans are that we wouldn't
necessarily find them.
Maybe we'll get lucky find someday,
but put it this way,
if they find a bunch of iphones 12,000
years from now or 5,000
years from now with whichever period we
want to find,
talk about will they know what they are
and even if they know what they are,
will we,
will they find the plans of how to build
one and the factory specifications of
all the engineering that goes into it?
No.
So why would you expect it for the great
pyramids?
Right.
But well,
you know,
it'd be a lucky,
it'd be a lucky find different bid,
but how much would that odds are against
it?
And,
and not to throw out too much academia
type stuff,
but one of the things I study is a
graduate school,
so I took a series of courses in
taxonomy which is basically how did
things get preserved focusing on
fossils.
Um,
but the principles apply to other things
as well.
And as you go back in time,
what you expect to survive
logarithmically drops off,
you know,
so you go back to these earlier periods,
it's amazing.
We have much of anything and what'S
going to survive big,
massive stone structures,
not the plans on papaya iris or sheep
skin or whatever of the details of how
to build it.
That's why what I found particularly
offensive about that,
um,
egyptologist saying,
where's the evidence of this culture
from 10,500
years ago?
Like,
what?
What do you expect to find?
Yeah,
exactly.
This is what we're talking about.
You know,
what we find from that earlier period,
if you think about our massive stone
monumental structures,
everything else would be grounded.
It was incinerated,
it was,
it was ground into dust or it was reused
in some cases.
Sometimes people say,
well,
they,
how could they do that without metal
tools will,
maybe metallurgy does go back further.
Maybe it was lost and then reinvented
again.
So again,
I don't deny the standard timeframe,
but there could be a lot of things going
back before that.
And you have metal.
And I'm not trying to focus on metal now
and I'm not making any big claims about
metallurgy a earlier time,
but let's just say for instance,
as a thought experiment,
if you had metallurgy much earlier than
conventional timeframe says,
and you had a natural catastrophe like
that,
are they just going to leave their metal
tools all over the place?
No,
they collect all the scraps of metal
possible and recycle and reuse and
reuse.
we do that to this day.
I mean people got,
in Massachusetts at least if you have a
warehouse and you're not paying
attention to it all the time,
it's an old warehouse.
There have been cases where people have
found.
Someone broke in not to steal the things
in the warehouse,
but to steal the copper piping.
Right?
yeah.
That's very common.
Now there's some of the more interesting
pieces of evidence that came out of the
great pyramid and a lot of the other
structures of Egypt had been the pottery
that's incredibly difficult to reproduce
those stone.
Well,
you just made a mistake.
I'm not criticizing you.
I said pottery.
You said padre,
because it's Important distinctions,
not monitoring,
it is fired in a kiln and fired dearly,
carved out really hard stone,
which will crack easily if you don't do
it just right,
so it looks like pottery and that's you
used a term colloquially put it that
way.
Looks like pottery because that's how
people imagine,
you know,
it looks like a beautifully shaped pot,
but some of these they go and they go
back to the earliest dynastic Egypt and
probably much earlier they are carved
out really hard granites and schists and
nice,
you know,
these really hard stones and two
Incredible tolerances and incredibly
thin,
incredibly beautifully carved and most
importantly to very small opening.
Very small openings is.
Exactly.
And how do you do this?
I mean it's just incredible when you
have to come to Egypt with us and when
we do,
we'll look at some of these onsite.
There's a bunch in the museum.
There's some at a museum at sakara where
they had been nice one.
Yeah,
that's amazing.
It looks like a mace.
Headers are destined jar,
but that's not what we're talking about.
That's not.
There's much,
much nicer.
I'm a much nicer in the sense of the
finesse of how both arterial,
theY were carved out of marble.
Different marbles.
Two easier ones to do.
They would grab them out.
diorite granted.
Nice.
Which is a metamorphic stone schist.
These are really hard stones.
He's called direct.
I'm d,
I o r I t e,
I believe.
Try that because that's what I'm pretty
sure I saw one of them.
It was carved out of that.
And so what we're saying is that these
are really hard to carve,
that use very narrow openings,
like you said,
sometimes they put handles on them so
they're not just spinning them.
Allow lave because how will you get the
handles on it because that's not put on
separately.
It's all car from one.
Look at that.
There's a nice one,
a then on vessels and these thousands of
these have been found going back to the
earliest dynastic times.
But what suggested the.
Yeah.
There's um,
how they were carved according to the
standard egyptologist.
I try to do that without cracking it,
without making a mistake,
et cetera.
Oh,
we'll explain what we're looking at.
we're looking at some sort of a,
um,
it looks like a little like amazed that
they use scratch out the inside.
YeaH.
To,
um,
and maybe they did it and just took a
log until.
what's the speculation?
Other than that,
we'll get the one right above it.
Jamie,
that red one,
the red one right above your cursor.
That one's incredible.
Yeah,
they're,
they're absolutely incredible.
And we can see these on site.
So what,
what's the circulation?
The uh,
the,
the speculation is that they weRe doing
it the same way.
They were doing a new kingdom times.
So when you look at them and new kingdon
times as a general rule,
you get things similar to this new
kingdoms that say 1500 bC just for round
numbers.
You get similar types of vases and
whatnot,
but they're actually to my eye,
much cruder.
Generally they're made out softer stone,
more your calcites sites in limestones
and marbles,
that type of thing.
They geneRally are just not.
They'll have the same artistic finesse
to them,
the same perfection to them and the new
kingdom.
Egyptians did show diagrams as we just
saw how they did it or supposedly did it
and that may well be how they were doing
it,
but I questioned as a geologist whether
that would really work for these
beautiful harder stone,
muCh more perfect in my assessment.
Older ones that you find going back to
the earliest dynasties and you find in
some cases thousands of them.
So at sakara,
at the step pyramId,
generally considered the oldest pyramid,
although I would question that,
but it's definitely an old pyramid.
Even by Egypt biological standards,
you found thousands of these really well
carved ones from the harder stone,
the more artistic ones,
if we could call it that sort of a huge
horde of them.
I don't even think they were necessarily
carved at that time.
I think this may have been a horde that
they had preserved from thousands of
years earlier.
Service stock poweR museum,
if you would.
In fact,
what we're finding for as many of these
quote tombs and temples,
not temples,
tombs and pyramids,
that type of thing,
is that maybe the.
Essentially they were stockpiles.
They were um,
the equivalent of,
you know,
fall out shelter.
So if you were you stuck away supplies
type of thing that may have been part of
the original structure.
Some of these are very long next to a
very long neck bottoms.
Exactly.
Sanely difficUlt,
like the ones that you've told them,
there's ones that are difficult and they
have all kinds of curves.
And what you have to be careful as I was
saying is that you have the really well
finished very ancient ones and then you
have ancient ones that are from the new
cayman only 3000,
3000,
500 years ago.
Yeah.
Uh,
and then what you have,
and I Could show you one,
and if it's still on display in the
egyptian museum,
I say still on display because they
changed the displace and they're
building a new grant Egypt museum as
they call it.
So it's hard to say in Egypt,
in Egypt when we go to Egypt now going
say,
I can show you one where I'm convinced
that it's a very old bowl that was then
reused in later times.
So you see this crude or hieroglyphic
inscription on it and you just look at
it and you say someone that incredible
bowl would not have done such a crude
inscription on it this year.
I mean,
so,
and then when we go through each with a
megalithic statutes and whatnot,
you can find over and over where they
would carve on them later.
So reappropriate them in later dynastic
times,
which is still thousands of years ago.
So very ancient from our personal
perspective,
but they were reusing older structures
and older,
older artifacts.
This,
the whole subject is so fascinating to
me.
But this bowl thing is very weird
because it's almost like one of the
crazier pieces of evidence,
but it's dismissed.
It's like right under your nose.
Oh,
it's absolutely dismissed and it's not
unlike.
And I only think of this because I know
you saw it.
If you remember when,
because I watched the recently to
refresh my memory,
the podcast where you interviewed John
Anthony West and he showed a picture
which happened to be my hand.
Um,
but in mY hand was a little bead that
was founded come back.
And the thing is,
remember that little beat had this,
it was a very hard,
I'm probably volcanic stone and little
teeny hole drilled all the way through
it,
the long way.
So you had a drilling that's,
you know,
a centimeter or more long going through.
It's not just a little hole punch
through,
but a little tunnel going through.
There it is.
UM,
and you know,
how do you do that with quote primitive
technology that to me is as amazing as
the erection of the pillars,
you know,
so you have to look at both small scale
and large scale and like you say,
the bowls may be something you hold in
your hand,
but they're just justice.
Incredible technology.
Just like if people were to judge us
today,
10,000
years from now,
they'd say that iphone is incredible
technology even
though it's small scale,
just like,
I guess they would maybe say if anything
survives of them,
uh,
some high rise was a incredible in this
is good beckley [inaudible] that would
just pulled up jamie.
These images.
And what are these images of?
Looks like a nail or something called
earplugs or Bugs.
Some people claim that no one really
knows exactly what they are.
Airports.
Yeah.
Well,
you know,
not ear plugs and plug your ears are
like,
oh,
your earrings.
I don't know exactly what needs to be.
Yeah,
they call them buttons there sometimes.
What is the speculation,
the construction methods of those
complicated bowls.
What?
What do people believe they did,
but the bolsa Egypt.
Is there any speculations or any
installation is that they may have been
using some kind of lave for it at least
in part,
but the problem is you can't turn it and
still have the handle sticking if you do
standard workout,
you know,
spinning late type of thing.
so there's something else that has to be
going on there.
I was going to say part of the problem
with any of this knowledge being passed
down right up into at least the 16
hundreds,
early 17,
you know,
there were guilt systems where you would
retain knowledge of how you do search
and technological things and I think
that may go back to very,
very ancient times that you don't want
to just give out.
Right.
You know,
the knowledge to anyone,
but you know,
again,
I've,
I've heard no good compelling and my
mind explanation as to how these things
were made.
Now one of the things that they found in
the king's chamber was what they
referred to as.
They call it a sarcophagus,
like what they called the chicago
fergus.
I preferred the term coffer and it's
made out of granite.
Aswan,
granite.
The coffer meaning like almost like a
treasure chest treasure chest or a big
chest or brock's that type of thing.
It's missing its lid and the sarcophagus
represents something that you've put a
body in.
You don't think that's correct?
No.
Correct.
That's why I don't like calling it
fergus coffer is more generic,
should we say.
Right.
And doesn't,
the king's chamber has some of the more
complicated stones,
right?
Larger.
Oh,
it has.
It's lined with granite.
So the primary construction material of.
There you go.
The primary construction material for
the great pyramid is limestone,
right?
Some of the limestone was quarried
pretty much onsite and you can still see
the quarries there,
other high quality limestone known as
tour limestone,
which brought from across denial and you
can still see the turro limestone
quarries and then granite which used for
parts of the construction,
particularly to line the king's chamber.
And this grant,
it was brought from southern Egypt,
brought up,
brought down the nile,
I should say,
from the south to the north,
now flows from the south to the north
and it's asked one grant and you're
talking about huge blocks of stone up to
90 tons or so have been the estimates
for those particular stones in the
king's chamber.
So when you go into the king's chAmber,
it's totally lined with this beautiful
red as juan.
Granted,
you've got this big coffer there that,
you know,
they give you permission,
you can lie in.
And,
uh,
it's a neat feeling,
to lie in and a lot of people have,
you know,
all kinds of experiences,
et cetera.
It's really incredible.
But it is these,
this lining is so perfect and so well
fit together and you have this,
uh,
you know,
all the sides,
a roof,
the ceiling,
the roof,
the ceiling of it,
um,
the walls of it,
the floor of it,
the coffer there,
and then you have,
um,
what they call star chefs are air shafts
that go out to a north and south.
That's what robert has worked on in
part.
And then above the king's chamber,
you have the so called relief chambers
or relieving chambers,
which you can't get into normally.
I've been in there a few times,
uh,
but you have to get special permission.
they have to put a ladder up from the
grand gallery and you go through this
little snake hole,
so to speak,
um,
to get up there.
But there's these chambers above it
which seemed to serve no function.
That's why they're called relief
chambers or relieving chambers because
there was early speculation that somehow
they help distribute the weight of the
great pyramid,
but engineering from an engineering
point of view,
they don't seem to work or it doesn't
seem to make any difference.
I mean the rest of the pyramid solid and
other pyramids are solid and don't
collapse without.
Why do they copy these chamber and It's
called the king's chamber.
Basically the arabs called it that
because their concept was,
if I remember correctly,
that men will have a chamber with a flat
ceiling on it.
The queens chamber,
which is lower down in the,
um,
a pyramid has a inverted v shape change
a ceiling to it and they thought that
was for the queen.
That would be female.
The king's chamber would be for the
male.
It's also the more impressive chamber
speculation.
Purely speculation.
Yeah.
It's purely spec.
Now,
the coffer,
this giant stone box.
One of the things that I read was that
the way it was built,
they believed that it was possible that
cores were drilled out.
Yeah.
Probably the corn.
And we have good evidence for that going
back to earliest dynastic times of not
earlier that they,
um,
I forget what you call it in modern
times,
but uh,
you have a drill bit that is circular in
shape and it drills out a core.
So you know,
they were drilling granite.
You,
again,
if it's on display,
I could show you in the egyptian museum
in cairo,
sarcophagi guy,
which probably really worse or carf a
guy or at these big granite boxes where
they were signed the granite.
In fact,
not only were they saw you,
it looks like they were using high speed
saws because in some cases they would
make a little mistake and then have to
back off and then go at it again.
You don't do that if you're,
in my opinion,
if you're doing it by hand,
you know,
back and forth with a,
there's some sort of machinery involved.
There's some kind of machining they were
using.
And very ancient times.
There's,
once you open your eyes to it,
you see it.
Where you see it seems to be high speed
machinery.
There's no regulation as to how,
oh,
there's lots of speculation.
I mean,
some people say they had electric motors
and electricity and all that type of
thing.
Some people.
Yeah.
Some people I don't go there because I
want real evidence,
so I see real evidence that they were
doing things that seem really
unbelievable from a standard status quo
conventional point of view.
Say that standard Egypt logical point of
view of how cool,
how primitive they were.
Right.
But I'm not into speculating in
ordinarily as to,
well what kind of technology they might
have had.
I just don't know at this point.
Yeah.
So there are images of the inside of the
sarcophagus,
like we could get a look at what that
looks like.
Oh,
it's not very impressive.
I'm sure he can probably,
I don't know if you can see the drill
marks they have essentially.
No.
Um,
but you know,
they're there.
You can see other places.
So for instance,
when we go into the valley temple next
to it,
there's one of the doors that was on
huge hinges and I don't think you're
going to find pictures of this on the
internet because it's very hard to
photograph a,
but when you look at that in person,
you can see how they drilled out,
you know,
the hinge several,
several inches in diameter and did a
core drill because you can still see,
if I remember there,
you can still see the sort of the stub
where it broke off.
Oh wow.
Yeah.
You can see how they were using
sophisticated techniques to do this,
but no idea whatsoever.
But I don't know what cad.
Well,
put it this way,
if we,
and this is.
I'm not speculating that they had such
things,
but you can tell in modern times that
someone used a power,
saw a power drill or this type of tour,
that type of tool.
Thousands of years from now.
You might be able to still see that in
this table.
Yeah.
I'm like beyond interpreted,
but you don't have a single example of
the tool that was actually used for.
Right,
right.
We know these guys.
I sometimes almost find it silly when
people say,
well,
here we go.
No,
this how could out there.
That's a nice example of it.
Okay.
There we go.
That's a good example.
Yeah,
that's actually probably the one I was
just talking about us as a bore hole and
you can see the,
how it was spinning.
You can see how they were cutting down
quite a bit in each turn.
So,
so,
so I almost find it.
I don't almost find.
I do find it silly sometimes when people
say to me the critics or skeptics,
oh,
you know,
if they were doing all of this stuff
will,
where's examples of their tools?
Let me.
How many guys just leave,
you know,
they walk away from a site and they
leave their buck toolbox.
There are even our.
Forget.
I mean,
all the,
all the mechanics I've ever known and
people like that,
they're very careful to pick up every
tool and put it back and make sure
they've got all their equipment will go
to the building and try to find a
hammer.
Right?
Yeah,
exactly.
Yeah.
No,
that completely makes sense.
But man,
I would just like to know,
like what were they doing and how did
they make that whole.
That's,
that's a massive,
massive mr right in front of everyone's
face.
Yeah,
yeah,
exactly.
What's the standard eds egyptologists
explanation.
They just really,
they just shrug their shoulders all we
see that all the time.
Well,
great.
You see it all the time,
but it reminds me of,
um,
this is maybe silly,
but I'm going to say it any way.
Uh,
no,
I don't know.
Well,
I'll say it anyway.
A supposedly a analogy.
You know,
if you,
if you're used to something,
I'll put it this way.
If you're used to seeing something on a
regular basis,
you start,
you stop questioning.
It just becomes,
um,
common to you,
but you don't really question it.
It's like technology today.
How many people could explain how even
the most rudimentary sense,
how some of the technology works that we
have today.
The egyptologist seemed to.
They just get immune to it.
They see all this fabulous stuff and
they just forget that will this was made
somehow we don't really know how it was
made.
Then they again go back to the
simplistic explanations of,
oh,
you know,
on some new kingdom or late period we
have this illustration.
This must be how they did it and I'm not
convinced that that's always how they
did it.
Almost just to look a little cartoon.
Right.
Did they have any illustrators?
They would have a drill and some stones
around it as a wage to keep it spinning.
No,
I haven't seen that.
Yeah.
You might have had.
I mean there's.
So you think that's just purely
speculation?
Yeah.
Or it could be sort of the equivalent
modern cartoons of a,
you know,
simple explanation of how something
works and a lot of that is really more
to say,
okay,
if you're a watchmaker,
I say 200 years ago,
you're a watchmaker,
you might have some sign that indicates
but don't try to take that sign is a
blueprint of how you actually made
watches.
Right,
right.
That makes sense.
No,
it does.
It does.
Um,
so the,
when they constructed that coffer,
they somehow or another board,
yeah,
they probably board down maybe board in
the quarters board down,
broke out pieces,
this a speculation now and broke it out.
And then once you've got it roughed out,
then polished the surfaces,
that type of thing.
Um,
so you know,
if you leave any traces of how it was
actually constructed,
that's not as good as if there are no
trace.
It's more or less,
you know,
it's not as good a job.
You look at something like the statue of
kafra or chef ron.
This is credible statue and the egyptian
museum,
again,
it's the one that has the face of the
pharaoh that supposedly was the face of
the sphinx,
which they don't match up at all as the
hawk control has a haka shoulders.
Uh,
that statue is absolutely incredible.
You know,
it's so smoothly polished,
etc.
You have to look very hard to find a
tool marks or evidence of how it was car
because you know,
a really good work and ship,
you remove all that ultimately.
So that's part of the problem with some
of this really high quality egyptian
work is that they would remove the
traces.
Yeah.
There,
there it is.
Um,
the,
they would remove the traces of how it
was made in that image.
The thing on the side of it,
you see that sort of plasma formation.
Yes,
absolutely.
Because this ties in.
This is why I brought image of this
because it ties in with that whole
scenario.
Well,
it has the circle said,
well,
exactly.
Very observant.
And think about the bird headed man,
the hoc and this incredible statue.
If you feel it face on,
you don't see the bird from the side.
You see the bird.
God,
it's incredible.
All of this stuff is so fascinating,
so I think it really all goes back to
this very early formative period.
If you would this really important
period for humanity and what was
happening.
There's a head on view and there you
don't see the bird at all.
Of course.
Incredible.
And tammy carve something like that
today.
I don't know what it would cost,
who you could pay.
I've heard,
you know,
this is anecdotal,
but I've talked to his stone cutters and
that type of thing and you know,
to try to duplicate some of what they
see in Egypt.
I mean it just would take them so long
and so much work and it would be so
expensive with modern power
tools that they basically say,
you know,
who could do it?
Do you have any fear that this is going
to?
Disinformation is going to be lost.
I mean that you're so far down this
track of sort of explaining these things
and these revolutionary theories about
what happened and I don't.
This is a,
I been,
I've been studying this for a long time
and this is the first time I'm hearing
it,
so that's why I need to be on your show.
I'm so glad you're here to get this out
into the public.
Yeah.
You're so far down this road.
Is there anyone else is doing the same
kind of work?
Does anybody else's with you on this?
Well,
I think I'm the one that's doing this
right now,
but I think there are a lot of other
pieces that tie in.
So per dr parata work,
but he served,
been,
you know,
he had some health issues and other
things.
She's older.
I'm the electric universe.
There's what's known as the electric
universe community,
which ties in with this that a
electrical phenomenon,
plasma discharges are more important.
There is a whole group now,
um,
that I think are starting to think about
what if we had another carrington event
in the new future,
how would that affect our grid systems?
So what I'm saying is I think there are
a lot of little pieces that are starting
to come together and you know,
starting to come together,
weaving this together,
but what I'm trying to do right now,
it's to paint the broad picture,
the broad strokes and I think it goes
back to the end of the last ice age and
what was happening then,
right up until now and what the
implications are
and how is this being received.
Are people picking up on that for
picking
up on it and sometimes the,
you know,
people are picking up on it.
When,
how did they say it,
the sincereness,
was it copying someone or is this
sincerest form of flattery,
imitation that should imitation.
And I do find and I'm kind of sometimes
get a little annoyed.
Yeah.
People are starting to talk about a lot
of these things,
especially the plasma and the sun and
solar events and all of a sudden by
chance they're talking about it.
Not necessarily mentioning me,
but I think,
you know,
I know they tend to lecture or they
maybe read my book.
But yeah,
these things take time and I'm not
asking for a lot of,
you know,
everyone has to acknowledge me,
uh,
but I think it's important to get the
information out and I think as we have
things like your podcast and people read
the books and I'm able to talk at
conferences,
we slowly get this out.
Well,
you know,
it takes time.
It all takes time.
Made me put it this way.
Copernicus,
and I'm not comparing myself to
copernicus,
but copernicus and the um,
heliocentric view,
now he publishes that on his death bed.
That was a view that actually went back
to,
um,
there were predecessors in ancient
times,
of course,
but he published his on his death bed
and um,
you know,
a couple generations later they're still
persecuting galileo for supporting it.
So these things,
yeah,
things go quicker now.
Yeah.
But it still takes some time.
I see a big difference now,
uh,
than I do in the 19 nineties for even
the reading of the sphinx,
you see,
is because of the internet.
Uh,
I think it's not just,
yes,
the internet helps.
I have mixed feelings about the internet
because the problem with the internet is
you can disseminate information,
you get information out,
but it doesn't mean it's good
information.
So you get the naysayers,
the critics,
the skeptics,
they have access to it,
to fake news,
fake news,
and genuine
news versus real fake news.
It seems that so many times they're
flipped.
They're very much.
So it's very confusing.
So one of the problems I see
with all this information and
misinformation and all these factoids
out there is,
it's very confusing for many people if
they're not involved in something.
And again,
I'm not trying to claim you have to go
to experts and authorities because
that's part of the problem too,
when you have the pseudo authorities who
just are pushing their own agendas and
frankly don't know what they're talking
about.
And I see too many of that among we'll
say certain academics and skeptics,
that type of thing.
Uh,
but it's also confusing when you only
take information and you don't know how
put altogether.
So I teach,
you know,
I teach in university,
I teach college at boston university and
what I find with students,
and I'm not picking on them,
I'm saying this with all due respect,
they have so much access to facts and
factoids,
we'll use that term,
but they have to understand the bigger
picture.
They have to be able to understand
critically and think critically about it
to put things together.
Um,
and how does it all fit together and
that that's so important.
And that's not something I think you get
just from surfing the internet,
right?
Of course.
Quickly,
no.
Watching a couple of youtube videos by
someone that's not necessarily reliable,
that's a problem,
right?
How much misinformation that's been
spread through youtube more.
More than good information probably.
I mean,
we could put on some fake lab coats
right now and just make some nonsense
video views by not exactly.
And see,
I've had the problem too in my business,
you know,
what I'm talking about is that they say
you can't please everyone all the time.
But it seems like in some cases in my
career,
in this field,
I've been able to displease every one
because I'll come out with position.
Sorry I'm losing my headset.
I'll come out with position sometimes
where I'm not pleasing my academic
colleagues,
but I'm not extreme enough for the.
Should we say other sites either also
like caught in the middle because I'm
going by the evidence I actually have
it.
It's not jiving with.
So to speak.
The foil hat brigade.
Yeah.
So what,
how is that received by the people that
mean there are those ancient aliens type
folks that really want everything.
They want everything to be ancient
aliens.
And I've been accused of how could I not
accept this or that,
you know,
because they get really mad at me and
they say nasty son.
They'll even tell me,
well,
this supports what everything you've
been saying.
I don't care if it supports everything
I've been saved.
It's not real.
It's not real evidence isn't there?
It's not.
It is fascinating.
They do dig up these ancient structures
and the machu picchu and all these
different places were like,
wow,
these construction methods are really
pretty impressive.
Incredible.
It was going on back then,
but they always want to tie it to
aliens.
They always want to tie it to aliens,
which I think is a.
I hate to use this term,
but sure of a cop out.
Yeah,
it's a business.
That's where it gets down to a lot of
this is business.
People want to sell their books.
They want to sell in their conference.
Just they were settled their dvds.
They want to sell their youtube videos
and in some cases they want to sell for
money.
In some cases they want to sell for
promotion,
self promotion,
and they want to be famous.
I told you I was accused of that back in
the early nineties.
Oh,
I just doing this place.
I want to be famous.
No,
I'm not that type of person,
and people love those shows.
Those ufo in ancient alien type shows
and they love those conferences.
They go to those conferences and they
all just mentally masturbate together.
Very bizarre.
It's like they're all like,
yeah,
there's not,
but I think it was exCiting,
but I think it does fill a void for some
people and one thing I'm trying to do is
to fill that void with something real,
something important.
Something thAt has evidence to back it
up because there are a lot of the
questions.
There are a lot of mysteries and I will
admit I've been on the ancient aliens
show,
but I've never proposed ancient aliens
have never supported that.
I've always been clear.
People actually listened to me,
but they asked me to be on in a number
of other academics have to.
Do they kick you out of context a little
bit?
Well,
yeah,
the context is not slippery,
slippery,
but the point is that there are real
mystery to this day.
Things that we don't really understand
that you and I have been discussing
about and there's so many more we could
discuss,
but those are real and so many people
that I know that watched shows like
that.
When I talked to them and I'm talking
academics who would never admit that
they watch it,
they watch it because they find it
entertaining,
number one,
they don't quite say it this way,
but I think it fills a void and it does
raise issues that if they're perceptive,
then they might become aware of and
realize that these are real issues.
No ancient aliens or some other easy
answer is not the way to go,
but they are real things that need to be
looked into.
So even when I speak at a conference
like that,
there are so many very intelligent
people that are there besides the other,
but you know they're different types of
people.
Sure.
But I know many people,
they'll have phds and stuff and they'll
go to it for a serve between
entertainment but also to get exposed to
things they're not going to be exposed
to by the standard academic community.
You're not going to get exposed to a lot
of this.
These types of questions.
If you just go to the standard closed
academic conferences,
they're going to be washed over.
So,
you know,
I'm part what on trying to do with
oracle,
the organization for the research of
ancient cultures,
which is not just me.
I want to be clear on that.
In fact,
we,
our president is a,
uh,
he,
he's actually,
I guess heavy metal guitar player.
He's really berkeley trained.
He's excellent.
Yeah,
no,
I mean seriously,
but he's,
he's a really bright guy and he's
fascinated by these things.
We have people like jocelyn godwin from
colgate university who's a world
renowned scholar on the visory board.
Uh,
but what we're trying to do with things
like oracle and I will encourage people
to actually look at it because we've got
a website up that you can go through my
website,
www.robertschoch.com
to get there or um,
go directly to us@www.oracle.
Oh,
there it is.
there we go.
Or coal online o r a,
c u l online.
Oh,
you know,
all one word.org.
And what we're trying to do with this
and also through the institute for the
study of the origins of civilization,
iso,
soc,
which I'm trying to do at boston
university,
is to have a forum where we can look at
these real topics,
these topics,
these topic seriously using evidence,
but not all but also not be dismissive
just because we have to uphold the
standard dogma.
So I don't want to go with just a
nonsense,
you know,
flippant or easy out to sell someone's
book that,
you know,
this crazy book or yeah,
I'm not being nasty about anyone,
um,
or you know,
just stick to the standard pair of time,
but thinking out of the box,
but as they say,
using real evidence and using real logic
and using real rationality to look at a
number of these issues,
they're more resistance towards a
redating
Egypt and Egypt technology,
particularly ancient Egypt versus other
cultures like go,
go back,
like tap a and some other ancient
structures that they're finding a tap a.
The Beauty of rebecca tap bay is that
there's no cd attached to it.
That's right.
The dating of rebecca tap is the dating
that is based on hard strategic rfi
radiocarbon dates,
german archeological institute,
correct me if I'm wrong,
it's because it was pr.
It was purposely purposefully covered
10,000
plus years ago.
And in that case,
this ties back to our bigger picture.
You have evidence,
we have evidence of catastrophe at
rebecca beckley tap bay.
We have evidence that the pillars were
knocked down and hastily re-erected.
Um,
and you can see that in the pillars they
built these.
There.
We have a picture up there.
If you can see the pillar on the far on
the right side,
that is not an archeological
reconstruction.
That pillar was knocked down.
It was put back into position,
but you can see how it was put back into
position crudely,
using fragments of another pillar.
Then they built these crude walls to
serve.
Hold the pillars up.
They butted against it.
Well,
to me,
this is happening and the dating
confirms it in the aftermath of the
initial solar outburst at the end of the
last ice age when you had all this
tumultuous,
um,
you know,
things happening,
uh,
earthquakes.
And this the precipitation,
the rain,
the fire coming down the thunder.
So you have this incredible situation
where we have captured at beckley tap
bay the catastrophe that was going on
and how they were trying to reconstruct
it and I think,
I don't want to say that gave up,
but for whatever reason that was
probably just so much.
They ended up covering the whole thing
artificially.
Maybe to preserve it.
Maybe they intended to go back to it
maybe for posterity.
I don't know what their thinking was.
We could speculate about that,
but tying in with what you were just
asking,
beckley tap bay is not tied to some
other later civilization as is dynastic
Egypt.
So there's a lot of dogma involved.
correct.
It's a dogma there is involved.
How sophisticated is is good.
BeckleY tap a and you know those that
want to uphold the standard story
saying,
well yeah,
it's pretty,
but it's not that sophisticated,
dismissive data as hunter gatherers.
Yeah.
They called hunter gatherers and they
say,
oh,
hunter gatherers are thereby primitive,
and therefore they,
you know,
they just try to wave their arms and say
it served like saying it's a normally
but not much of a nominally,
so we don't need to really worry about,
but they've only correct me if I'm
wrong,
they've only uncovered as very small
fragment of it.
Yeah,
very,
very small.
This is an enormous structure structure
and in that picture that's up.
We'll describe it for those that don't
see the picture,
but there's pictures like this in my
book,
forgotten civilization.
In fact,
I think that's right out of my book,
probably are very similar to what you
can see the pillar in the back on the
left.
Do you see how that was knocked down and
it's propped up and it is been put back
into position.
Then they built these crude walls
against it before they buried the whole
thing.
So this whole site underwent dramatic
catastrophe was being put together
quickly again.
And then the animals as well.
There's,
yeah,
there's one right there.
It's beautiful.
The serve,
I call it a fee line,
sir.
Feline going down and theY had a carved
the stone around that,
so much more complicated,
much more complicated.
And when they were,
when they were carving these originally,
taking them out of the quarry to get,
say a 15 ton pillar,
I think we're looking.
Oh,
there we are there.
It's so beautiful.
I love that.
Now,
if you saw that in a museum of modern
art,
it could fit right in.
Uh,
uh,
two points I just wanted to make before
I forget them.
One,
when you're carving these pillars to get
10 or 15 ton pillar like that finalized,
you have to cover a much bigger chunk of
rock initially because of course you
have to leave the rock where you're
going to have the animal.
You have to leave the rock because
they're not in sizing these in.
They're carving them and relief.
So that's a lot more complicated kind of
way.
All the rock,
etc.
so this is an incredible technological
feat.
Also off the record.
And this one,
if you look at that one,
do you see how it's got weather,
pig pigs and whatnot,
but you also see the weathered surface.
I'm going to teach you a little geology
that is a older pillar that was being
reused at the end of the last ice age,
I believe,
so some of these structures actually go
back earlier and before klaus schmidt
passed away unexpectedly.
He was talking about this too,
that even there they were maybe you
reusing some structures that were a
little bit earlier or maybe several
thousand years earlIer,
so this goes back.
The origins of get back late.
Teppei may go back thousands of years
earlier when all said and done,
once we get the evidence in a well into
the end of the last ice age,
I'm stuffed out about 9,700
bc.
I was going to say before I forget it a
lot going on here,
off the record,
of course they would never admit to
this,
but off the record,
I've spoken to archaeologists when
they're in a giddy mood and and,
and asked them,
well,
if you just found,
say that animal on the glabella tip a
pillar in isolation or you just found
one of these pillars are part of one in
isolation.
You were just looking at how do you
think it would be,
and I've heard the answer 600 bc,
a thousand bc based on the technology,
you know,
the technological finesse,
the beauty of the carving,
not eight,
9,000
years earlier,
right?
Yeah.
But they would never say that on the
record.
Right,
right,
right.
Yeah.
Because it's so complicated to monkey.
And then.
But I've had them say that,
well if I,
they just found,
say that little feline type thing on the
side of the pillar just broken off and
just an isolation,
they'd probably say one told me,
yeah.
Oh maybe it's a thousand bc at most,
right.
Most but not 9,000,
700 bc or whatever.
That's crazy.
Now are,
have they Identified the quarries?
Were these stones?
Yeah,
some of them happen and they're not
super far away as a kilometer or a bit
more.
I mean it's,
there's limestone around there,
so it's not a situation as you have in
Peru for instance,
where they're dragging this stuff,
you know,
tens of kilometers away.
but I don't think that detracts from.
No,
no,
no.
What they were doing it sort of,
yeah,
it's still crazy and um,
you know,
it's easy for me to say this,
but once you've quarried a block,
if you're moving a kilometer,
it's not that much harder to move it 10
kilometers,
it just takes more effort.
But the same technology,
it's really korean.
Be able to move it to begin with and
then be able to carve it into these
beautiful structures.
And something I want to point out too is
that a lot of times when I talk about
Rebecca Lee bay,
I'll make the comment about stone henge
because people are familiar with
stonehenge.
Stonehenge,
when you look at the blocks,
they're,
they're so much cruder than what we have
at beckley tap bay and the tap pay stone
pillars.
The central ones particularly,
they are so beautifully carved,
but if you look at them,
they're also very,
very thin and their smallest dimension
there you can see it how thin it is and
that one's anthropomorphic with the belt
and the hands.
And that sure looks like a,
some people would say a metal buckle on
it.
So that's very similar to like those
easter island Is very similar to easter
island there.
I think there are definite connections
there,
but why shouldn't there be.
We were just talking about rango rango
in ours to ago and how they were seen
similar things in the sky,
but I wanted to point out that when you
carve a pillar like that that's so thin
and narrow,
that's much more difficult to keep it
from snapping to keep it from breaking.
Also,
if you see in that pillar how it's said
into the bedrock,
it's said in just literally very,
very shallow.
I'm the set into the bedrock.
Klaus schmidt commented to me that,
and he published this too,
that they seem to be using some kind of
concrete or cement to help set them into
the bedrock,
which is untold up at such an early
period when he fIrst was excavating them
before he got down to the bottom.
I think he said this to me verbally.
He estimated that about a third,
at least a third of the pillars should
be set into the bedrock.
Just to hold it up,
prop it up,
not just on the order of centimeters as
you find.
Is this a sturdy construction like a,
was it?
No,
no.
You can't touch it now.
They won't touch it and it probably
would fall over.
They have to do all kinds of supports on
it.
Now.
My suspicion is that initially it was
not roofed over there,
that they were free standing pillars and
they were very,
very carefully set and balanced and
everythIng was in perfect order.
This is total speculation,
but like many of the habilis and
whatnot,
they may have even had a vibration to
them.
They may have purposefully vibrator
picked up some kind of frequency.
You can see the.
Yeah,
how shallow it is,
but they were finely tuned,
whatever you want call that,
and I'm not trying to claim it.
Some kind of weird machine or some
people have called speculated,
but I think there was something there
and resonance.
An audio cues.
Audio frequencies are historically very
important in both modern structures.
Usually you think of as religious,
but you know,
it affects your mental thinking and
abilities and that type of thing.
So something may have been going on
there with that.
This may also be why they broke so
easily during the catastrophe.
I shouldn't say easily.
It was a huge catastrophe.
Um,
but they were trying to redirect them.
What is the timeline in terms of like
the total uncovering that site?
Oh,
in modern times.
I mean,
no,
what are they trying to do?
Like how much time do you think it's
going to take for them to completely
uncover?
Oh,
if they do it carefully,
century century.
Oh,
could be.
It's a huge site.
And,
and klaus schmidt when katie and I were
there,
um,
I think he waved his arms and he talked
about how there's all these other hills
out there that probably have more under
them.
I mean,
you're talking a huge complex and we
know that in some cases because you see
little fragments sticking up and that
type of thing.
And also remember when you're doing
archeology and I have training in
archaeology despite what some of my
critics would say.
When you're doing archeology,
it's inherently destructive because you
can't put it back together.
So if you don't do it carefully,
you don't do it right.
You're destroying evidence.
You are inherently destroying evidence.
So a lot of people nowadays,
professionals,
they don't want to excavate the entire
site at one time.
They want leave
parts on,
excavate it so that other people have a
go at it.
As you develop new technology,
you can apply that to a different part
of the site,
plus practical things.
This is in Turkey,
it's close to the syrian border.
Um,
and we know how the political situation
there is with this l'amec state,
etc.
They would love to destroy this site.
I'm sure.
Really,
it's very close to earth,
uh,
which is the city of abraham.
It's a very sacred holy site,
um,
for judaism,
christianity.
But more than anything else,
islam get beckley.
Teppei is just outside psychic power
drive by taxi.
I'm from earth in earth.
Uh,
you have the,
um,
sacred cave of abraham.
You have the pools of abraham,
you have big mosque there.
And I bring this all up because this is
a very ancient city when they excavate
in earth,
uh,
not archeological excavations,
but say they build a new road or they do
build a new underground garage,
they often hit 12,000
year old or there abouts remains.
So there's this beautiful statue called
earth,
a man,
which is now in the museum and five,
which also has just lots of artifacts
from beckley tap bay.
And it was found right near the,
um,
modern pools of abraham when they were
doing some construction project,
but it represents an image of the people
supposedly are at least it's an image of
a man or person that gates back to go
back 10 times.
It's about full sites.
It's about the same size as me,
but lucky legs very similar actually has
a lot of comparisons to the moai on
easter island.
Got a picture of this.
I think we do.
Is that beautiful?
Wow.
Look,
he's staring at you with obsidian eyes
and he is from beckley tech time,
but he was found in earth.
Uh,
and you're not going to do it.
We're not going to do it,
but if you could just wipe out the
modern city and excavate there,
who knows what you would find
potentially erf.
Uh,
uh,
this is me speaking as one of the oldest
inhabited cities on earth.
I'm going back to the late ice age.
Well,
this is something that goes on in Mexico
city as well,
right?
Yeah,
sure.
Building apartment building,
all kinds of things on an aztec temple
and,
and in cairo and other parts of Egypt.
There were families that lived for
centuries because their little huts or
the community was on the top of ancient
ruins and they would dig in their
basement and pull out a gold statuette
or whatever,
sell it and you know,
eat for the six months.
So
is this earth a place?
Is there any consideration to like
picking isolated spots and starting to
dig in?
I think there's some consideration on
the part of archeologist and turkish
government,
that type of thing,
but you've also got a very strong
religious elements you mentioned placed
into all of this.
Of course.
And also,
you don't necessarily want to destroy a,
uh,
ancient islamic temple,
say islamic mosque,
a mosque that goes back to,
I don't know,
I'm just making this up.
Eight hundred 80 or something to
excavate something that's a few thousand
years old,
a thousand years older or 10,000
years old or more,
I mean,
yeah.
Again,
on the one hand,
which am I more interested,
it might be one versus the other,
but other people are interested in the
other car.
I mean there's all these factors that
play into it.
So it gets very complicated,
very messy.
And then of course You have this
situation and this ties in where,
you know,
I know christians are more interested in
the birth of jesus and where the mangers
and we can see in Egypt of one's
interested to suppose that place where
the holy family stayed when jesus went
to Egypt,
you know,
whatever.
Um,
and you can see things like that in
earth,
uh,
for abraham and whatnot.
And how do you respect that with.
But also why excavate underneath.
And then some people would say
excavating underneath is sacrilegious
to,
you know,
what their main interest is,
so it gets very,
very complicated.
I've met phds in Egypt,
uh,
one in particular.
Just to tell you a quick anecdote,
I'm sitting there having breakfast.
This was in the 19 nineties and um,
it was in a hotel where it's overlooking
the pyramid and sphinx.
I'm looking at them,
nice.
Having a nice breakfast.
That guy comes down and sits with me,
joins with may,
start making conversation.
Turns out he said,
I'm cairo university,
you know,
economics.
I think he's a professor of economics or
whatnot.
And he starts telling me because it's
obvious I'm not a chip shit,
why am I there?
I'm staying the pyramids.
And then he starts telling me his
opinion of all this was opinion,
was that the pyramid should be
dismantled.
Get rid of this finks don't need any of
that.
Used those raw materials on site to
build a cupboard over air condition
shopping mall bigger than the one in
dubai.
And that would really benefit Egypt
economically and otherwise.
Who said this?
He was a professor at our university.
I might not know his name,
but I have no question.
He was genuine and real and I didn't or
anything
because it was serious,
but where's he coming from?
Impart Egypt.
Didn't mean anything to him.
Dynastic egyptians.
Lot of egyptians do.
It means something to them,
but there's a lot of egyptians in Egypt.
They're muslim.
If it's pre muslim,
it's not a big deal.
If it's pre arab,
it's not a big deal because they're
arabs.
They might've been in Egypt for over a
thousand years,
but the native egyptians is not their
culture.
Culture.
Wow.
Well,
but it's not.
Think about America,
how many native native american mounds
and raves and whatnot get bulldozed over
with that.
Maybe the most preliminary archeological
salvage to build a shopping mall or a
neW development.
It's the same thing.
We think it's really crazy when someone
like that would say that about the
pyramids and sphinx,
you know,
because everyone knows about them,
but from his perspective,
if I quizzed him,
he could have turned around and said,
well,
look what you do in your country.
Well,
it's almost human nature across the
planet when they're inconsiderate to do
something along those lines.
So my point is not really to criticise
him.
He had very different perspective.
Um,
it's,
I don't agree with that perspective,
but I could understand where he was
coming from.
He wasn't coming,
he wasn't some crate,
he didn't strike me as some crazy
fundamentalists or anything like that.
He was just thinking in different terms
and for him,
and he's not the only one I've spoken to
in Egypt.
Egyptians a who'd take that perspective
now.
Others will say we have to save all
these,
but not necessarily because they could
care less about pyramids and sphinxes
and tombs,
but because they're good for the economy
because it brings in tourism.
But then there's the counter argument
which I've heard many times that Egypt
has to separate itself from tourism.
So you need to cut off the nipple.
Yes,
because I've had egyptian say to me in
no uncertain terms,
and I'm not joking or anything but
pointed out that depending on how you
count it,
you know,
25 percent to 60 percent or more of the
egyptian economy could be based on
tourism because it's not just the direct
tourism,
but it's those that supply the people
who deal with the tourists,
et cetera,
and when you have a situation that you
have something happen in the middle east
could be far from Egypt,
but people get excited,
you know,
americans all of a sudden tell me,
oh,
I can't go to Egypt.
That's my interest to go to Egypt
because something happened in Syria.
That's what I heard and it has nothing
to do.
No,
but I think if our country and our
economy was dependent upon tourism
solely,
not solely,
but portion of
it was tourism and then something
happens in Brazil and all of a sudden
because something happened in Brazil,
no tourists are coming to America and it
cripples our economy.
I mean,
I can Understand that perspective dog
and completely understand their
perspective.
What is the perspective in Turkey when
they're dealing with go beckley?
Tempe and the.
Well,
I think it's a mixed too.
I mean,
I think they're in Turkey,
unfortunately from my perspective,
you've got more and more rise of should
we say radical islamic fundamentalism
that doesn't really worry about such
things,
but you also have people who seek of
beckley tap a as potentially someday
vine with the sphinx and pyramids for
tourist dollars and for a destination.
I mean turkeys.
Wonderful.
My opinion,
I love both Turkey and Egypt.
Just to visit them,
to travel through them,
that type of thing.
Within the country you have to know what
you're doing by people travel with me,
I know what I'm doing.
I don't mean that nasty way.
I know and I will not take risks.
I'll take risks for myself and I've,
as I say,
been on the wrong end of a garden
center.
Yeah.
But happened.
Oh,
the worst was Pakistan,
but that's what we do in Pakistan.
I was collecting fossils.
This is when I was a graduate student
and at one point,
um,
I was accused of carrying plastic,
plastic explosives and all of a sudden
had for um,
ak 47 point myself.
Not point.
I felt that.
Yeah,
they were touching it and I know enough
about small arms.
These were loaded in the cocktail.
I mean their fingers were on the
triggers,
not on the trigger guards.
Yeah.
It turns out I didn't have plastic
explosives and you know,
I'm a mild mannered guy and I said,
you go whatever you want to.
I didn't do anything wrong and I
explained and I was carrying back then a
little bricks,
little things of a oil based clay that I
guess have the texture and feel of some
of the explosives they would use.
We would use these when we collected
fossils and you find a bunch of
fragments to prop it up and put it into
position as you glued them together.
But explaining that.
Yeah,
yeah.
I had to explain all of that.
And um,
someone came from the Pakistan
geological survey.
Explain that.
Yeah.
I really was who I was,
but you know,
it's a situation where people get
excited and that was back in the battle
days of,
you know,
well I don't know if it seemed better in
Pakistan now,
but you know,
they're tough situations,
but if you know how to behave and you
know,
how deal with it,
you know how to avoid it,
you'll be okay.
And uh,
right now I would say Egypt is very,
very safe.
It really is.
People have all kinds of misconceptions
about Egypt.
Turkey,
we were starting to talk about Turkey.
Turkey may be going the other route a
little bit.
I'm being very honest.
Uh,
but I have no problem going with Turkey
and I have no problem taking people to
Turkey,
but at this point there are certain
areas I might avoid just to be on the
safest,
a little more slippery.
Yeah.
But I would never endanger anyone else.
In fact,
I always err on the side of safety when
it comes to anyone.
One else.
I'm not that I want to take great risks
with myself either.
But you know,
sometimes as a geologist and I read that
I have,
I feel I have to do what I
do.
Do you have any plans on releasing this
theory of coronal mass ejections and all
the things that we've talked about today
into something like a documentary?
something that I might be a little bit
more.
I would love to do a documentary.
Something that john,
Anthony West and I,
we're often talking about documentary.
We also would like to do a film,
a full length feature film if we could
get back in and whatnot.
serve a,
how should I say it?
Semi popularized a semi fictionalized,
but always based on real science,
real data,
real evidence.
So yeah,
I've seen so many films where they're
about geological catastrophes,
whether it's huge asteroid city know or
you know,
san andreas fault and they're so faked.
Yeah.
But because it's not real,
what really happened,
it's not really what happened and what
I'm saying is what has happened in the
past and what really will happen in the
future if we get hit again,
which I hate to say this,
but from a geological perspective,
there is no doubt these things are
unavoidable.
It would be like saying we'll never have
another volcanic eruption or earthquake
again.
Of course we will.
So it's better to be aware of it and
prepare for it.
So yeah,
I'd love to do.
I'm a good film and this film would be
something that would really catch on.
Well,
if you could help us.
I'll connect you to people.
Maybe that would be excellent.
I'm serious.
This is something that katie and I,
katie,
for those that just tuned in,
katie's my wife and uh,
I think you heard when we were talking
to me for,
she has some background in um,
you know,
she was a dancer and entertainment and
broadway,
but film connections.
We really need to connect with them,
put it out there for contact information
if someone is in that.
If someone like
to take hold of you,
absolutely.
The best way to get ahold of me would be
through my website,
www dot robert schoch,
s c h o c h is how the last name is
spelled.com.
Or if they want to email me directly,
and this is on the website whole with
this thing you're given.
I know.
Why should I give out the email to the
contact page that my wife is to my left
there.
And she said the contact page.
Nailed it.
Um,
she said the contact page.
Did I say too much?
No,
no,
you're good.
Okay.
Um,
so if people go to www.robertschoch.com
and then go to the contact page,
they'll get my contact information
there.
I think we have a fairly direct way to
contact me.
I fall,
so I believe got my business address,
their boston university address office
because I really am at boston
university,
full time tenured faculty member.
And,
uh,
I'm interested if people want to contact
me about film,
if they want go to each with me.
I do tours periodically.
I'll arrange something if people have
enough,
you know,
if they want a private,
if they have enough people that would
want come to make it viable or yeah,
these things cost money.
If I were independently wealthy,
maybe I just take people for fun at my
expense,
but I just,
I don't have that.
Well,
I built a to you.
You Have stimulated a lot of people's
imagination.
And I mentioned one more please
chamber that chamber under the pod,
the sphinx for a quarter century.
Now.
I want to continue the serious research
on that.
I have Contacts in Egypt.
I've talked to the ministry of
antiquities,
the um,
uh,
actually director,
I guess he is of The grand egyptian
museum,
the new museum.
I think we could make inroads there to
actually explore that if someone has
money or interest in that.
The problem is,
and I want to say is bluntly,
a lot of people say,
oh,
well why don't you just raise money by
crowdfundinG doesn't work for Egypt.
You have to have the money upfront,
they don't want,
you know,
crowd funding type money.
So that's another thing.
So my point is that there's film project
love to pursue,
there's research,
love to pursue.
That's why we've set up the oracle,
the not for profit to do this.
Alright.
And legitimately that's why I'm saying
the institute at bu institute for the
study of the origins of civilization.
So lots of possibilities and I'm hoping
we can make some of this happened.
I'm hoping we tend to uh,
really appreciate you being here man.
It was really awesome to talk to you and
you blew my mind this,
this whole theories.
It scares the shit out of me,
but it also,
it's very exciting.
Well thank you.
Thank you.
And again,
I'm not trying to scare anyone
but I think we have to be real and we
have to be realistic and there's no
point in hiding and you know,
closing your eyes to.
And it's just an awesome theory.
I mean it's just,
it's very cool.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Gentlemen.