Every day life.
Four,
three,
two,
one five.
And we're here with the Arnold
Schwarzenegger of competence.
Mary Lynn Rice Cup.
When,
how many people have ever on one shot
spelled your name right or pronounced it
right.
Hey,
never,
never.
Right.
Like if you're at the DMV now that you
mentioned it because they're going to
introduce me and it's just,
uh,
it just gives like an instant obstacle.
Like when you were coming up as a comic,
that had to be a big issue for the MC to
bring you up or the,
the,
the Dj when they bring you up as you
were the MC or the DJ or the MC.
I don't know.
I never really looked at it that way.
Well,
somebody had an inner introduce you.
Yeah.
Right.
Like I think I was in such a,
uh,
a bubble.
I didn't really,
and I wasn't on the road hardcore and I
wasn't,
I don't know.
I wasn't identifying with me as a
performer so much.
What does that mean?
That means I was doing performance art
and people were laughing.
I didn't know why they were laughing.
Right.
I moved to La.
I was like,
yeah,
let's do shows.
Like I didn't know,
I didn't think about it as like you're
introducing me.
I'm a,
I'm a performer.
I would say only in the past couple of
years if I'd done the road proper.
But I came in the back alley for
everything,
for comedy,
for,
for acting.
Like if I had come to la with a stack of
head shots,
like,
Hey,
I'm ready for acting.
It would've never happened.
I just came with a group of people like,
Oh to do some live shows and like no
business being in La,
no business,
just doing weird shows cause that that's
what I was compelled to do.
Like I could not have done it had I
said,
all right,
you're going to do acting and
performing.
Especially not comedy.
Like I didn't identify with that at all.
I had to figure out why people were
laughing.
That's fascinating.
So when you first got into show
business,
what was the goal?
It's a weird bird show business,
isn't she?
Isn't she a special lady?
I'm,
I'm audition ready today by the way.
You notice I have a good brow in a good
eye shadow line.
I'm such a woman.
I'm really more of a woman now than I've
ever been.
What's sad about what's that about?
Just growing up,
letting it go,
letting it go.
And I look back in my twenties and I'm
like,
you were up hot bitch.
Like what was wrong with you?
But I was so incapable of anything like
so socially.
I mean I still am,
but I'm much,
much better now.
But it's awkward,
awkward and just,
but that's um,
I don't find you awkward.
So it's odd.
Like every time I've talked to you,
we've had very fun,
comfortable conversations.
I never found it to be awkward.
I don't find you to be awkward either.
Maybe we just don't make each other
awkward.
Is that weird?
My mind just went to an instagram APP.
Ah,
that was creep tastic in my own mind.
That one that goes in close and it does
the little stars.
Sorry.
It's all right.
Honestly,
don't find you to be awkward.
Every time I've ever talked to you,
it's been very,
very comfortable.
Very easy.
I agree.
But I would also say that's kind of a
recent development that you and I are
speaking was when I started coming back
to the comedy store,
which was what,
a couple of years ago?
Yeah,
three now I guess.
Three something.
14 November of 14 I think it was because
we've been in each other's orbit since,
you know,
since news radio.
Yeah.
But we didn't really get a chance to
like,
yeah,
hang out or be friends til the store.
You know?
That's such an interesting little
community.
Right.
It's like everybody just kinda like,
like what I'm talking about a positive
community.
Like I was just explaining,
explaining this to someone the other
day.
Like when I first started going there in
1994 there was a lot of conflict between
comedians.
There's like comedians.
It didn't like comedians.
Like,
Oh,
this guy doesn't like this guy and she
doesn't like her and they all fucking,
yeah.
Duked it out with each other a little
bit.
There's none of that now.
Yeah.
It think about it's amazing quarter of
that places.
It's amazing.
Like everybody's friendly.
Yeah.
I love it.
Like,
there might be a hundred of us there on
a regular basis,
like in and out doing Sunday through
Monday.
Yeah.
And there's no conflicts.
It's really fucking cool.
Um,
did you,
I'm sure you've talked about this a
million times.
Did you eat,
did you ever stop going there for a
chunk of time where you stopped for
seven years?
Yeah,
I stopped for seven years after I had
that dispute with Carlos Rensea.
Yeah.
That was when he was way more popular
than me,
like,
especially as a comic and the comedy
store took his side and I was like,
all right,
fuck you guys.
And I,
I took off.
It wasn't really the comedy store
either.
It was this one guy who was the manager,
cause Mitzi,
actually I called Mitzi and gave her the
whole rundown of what was going on.
Um,
I told her and she's like,
well I'm ain't gonna just stay away in
front of mom.
And then she gave me a spot that night
and then they called me up two hours
later telling me that I was banned.
So I said,
wait a minute,
I just talk to Mitzi.
Like she gave me a spot.
She told me when to go up.
So if,
if she's not running the store,
like who's who's deciding on band?
You are like,
what are you doing?
Like do you guys understand what this
is?
I mean this is like a little,
you're having a little battle for like
whether or not you're going to let
people profit off of crime.
Like this is really what's happening.
You have thought crime,
he have intellectual crime,
you plagiarism and you're allowing one
person,
you knowingly allowing them to profit
off it and no one's doing anything about
it.
So when one of us does something about
it,
then you're going to punish that person.
You're basically highlighting everything
that everyone was afraid of.
That's a good point.
What is like,
what were the,
what was the reason for your being
banned because you were,
well,
because become their end of it was
because we had made a video with me and
Carlos arguing on stage and then we put
it on right now that all that this was,
you know,
somehow or another and in violation of
that should have been kept inside the
club and I'm like,
you don't get it.
You weren't protecting us.
No one was protecting us.
My fucking agents dumped me over that.
Oh yeah,
over that.
Yeah.
I was with gurse.
They dropped me.
They'd call me up to tell me they
essentially,
in this long roundabout way,
we're trying to say that I either had to
apologize or they couldn't work with
anymore though.
That was the gist of it and I had to
make them spell it out.
Okay.
Let me say this really clear.
You tell me if this is what you're
saying.
You're saying you want me to apologize
or you can't work with me anymore?
Well,
we're done now.
There's no apology and we'll never get
to work together.
I appreciate everything you've done for
me and I,
it was really nice to the guy who was a,
it wasn't his idea.
My agent said,
you're a great guy,
bye.
See you.
I'm giving you a hug.
But you guys have to understand that
you're making a choice.
It's going to affect the rest of your
life.
This isn't just a small thing.
You,
you only have a few.
How many years do you have in this life?
Well,
this year is going to be highlighted by
this decision.
This is going to be at why the agent
take that stand.
Did they represent him as yes.
Yeah.
Okay.
Um,
all right.
So they needed to make nice with that
thing.
He goes,
it made way more money than me.
So it was,
he was way more valuable to them.
And so I'm like,
you gotta make this is you sell art.
It's all you guys do.
Can you not making anything?
You're just,
if Mary Lynn comes up with the show,
if this guy has a tour,
if she's doing this or he's writing a
book,
you make money off art.
That's how you make money off.
Now here,
you know a guy stealing other people's
art and your answer to that is we got to
stop people that are exposing it.
Did he ever change or not that I even
matters him.
I hope he did.
He's got to find Jesus.
We just talking about this last night
sort of.
Yeah.
Sort of.
And then he kind of took it back.
It's hard to admit.
Should I try?
This is insane.
I actually only have like one set,
right?
Crazy.
Do you know my friend Tate Tate
Fletcher?
Probably seen him around the store
before.
Big giant gorilla.
Uh,
it's his company.
They're very good,
but don't drink the whole thing.
Mary Lynn.
I like it,
but I'm going to do it if it's a grand
day coffee.
Yeah,
that's about it.
Chronic and coffees where the caffeine,
but it's strong.
Yeah.
Oh,
she fog.
I got to go work out in your isolation
tank.
Find Yourself.
I just found myself and I peed a little.
That's okay.
Um,
so you started out as a performance
artists.
Like that was your idea.
What did you want to do that was your
eye?
That was your big idea.
I went to art school for painting and I
was uh,
um,
got really frustrated when people
started to,
uh,
critique the paintings and I was
supposed to be,
you know,
getting more serious in art school and
more conceptual and everyone was doing
something different and everyone was
critiquing it in a different way and
none of it made sense to me.
And then the idea of having to sell that
object that you made,
so you're going to make something that's
useless.
I mean it makes it sound like I don't
like our appreciate art.
I just,
for me,
I didn't,
I couldn't grasp what the next thing to
do was.
You know,
you're poor,
you're an art school,
you're making something and then you
have to go sell and market that thing.
And uh,
I also was frustrated and,
and kind of like boiling inside and
needed to express myself.
So I started doing performance art in
school.
And then when you say performance art,
that's a pretty open ended description.
Oh,
it's so open ended.
There were so many like weird
performance art things that would
happen.
We,
I mean we had performance art class,
there was the guy that like taped his
genitals to the side and put on lipstick
in a mirror and that was his performance
art piece or the girl that,
and we would all sit there and watch it.
Did you see his genitals?
Did he'd go naked and pull it aside or
how did he do that?
That's a really good question.
I like how your mind just went there.
You're like,
what actually happened?
I think I blocked it out because I think
you could probably get away with doing
that under the guise of it being
something you're doing,
you know,
in a class somewhere.
Yes,
yes.
You get away with us.
So pervy I think I was focused on his
beautiful lips.
I was trying to be polite and not look
down there.
Another woman was obese and her piece
was,
she had preset up.
We weren't it where she was doing the
performance,
uh,
butter pats in like dominoes,
like a,
you know,
a few thousand of them in a line.
And she was obese and she crawled on the
ground.
She didn't actually eat them,
but it was something that's weird.
My mind kind of drops off.
I remember specific parts of it,
but I don't know.
I think she just was collecting the
butter pieces and crawling and that was
her performance.
He's another guy.
Uh,
the,
uh,
this was,
I went to Detroit and then finished in
San Francisco.
And San Francisco is known for being a
real performance art history.
A lot of the,
you know,
the most famous performance artist.
Nobody knows where that was.
The scene was in San Francisco.
So,
uh,
it was two story really beautiful
campus,
uh,
overlooking.
You could see a Lombard street on one
side.
You could see the water on the other
And uh,
another guy's piece was to jump from the
second story to a tree to is like that.
He may or may not have made the jump and
that was his art,
his art pieces.
Jumping from a window to a tree.
Yeah.
What the fuck?
I know this other guy,
the room where we had our class,
he had a bread machine.
This was back,
you know,
bread machines where new technology had
a breadmaker.
You know those machines you can make a,
I guess it just does the dough,
right?
Right.
Maybe it bakes it.
I think it just needs the dough and then
you bake it or I don't know if you bake
it in the machine or no,
you bake it in the machine.
It's all coming back to me.
He bakes it in the machine.
We come into the classroom as he's
baking it.
There's always like a reveal and these
pieces.
Right?
So we come in,
he's taken plaster from the wall and put
it in the bread.
He's Fed us the bread.
Half of us get it,
half of us don't.
And there's plaster in the price.
Why did you put plaster in his bread?
It was something about communism.
Some get the bread,
some don't.
But even if you get the bread,
there's plaster.
And so in your face,
what the fuck?
Oh my God.
See there's something about like
performance are in slam poetry.
I did slam poetry to that was when Mike
did.
No,
I did.
Here's the best part is I got Zeros.
Zeros.
Yeah.
You didn't get any why?
I never really wrote any poetry.
I was just into the performance of it.
And I see you didn't have to poke.
I was doing comedy.
Oh No.
And I was doing like an awkward thing,
which was very real for me,
but I think I just wanted to express my,
I also had an ex boyfriend who
he said the comedy was his life.
This was when I was like 19.
And I think I attached to people,
like I thought he was the shit because
he would be rude to people.
Like that was his version of comedy was
like bossing people around or one of his
bits was like having a whistle and
directing traffic.
I mean really adolescent like,
but for some reason I was really
attracted to him and uh,
like I wanted to be him.
Anybody who was like extroverted or
something that I wanted,
that I was attracted to that.
Right.
So,
right.
So he was like,
comedy is my life and I do this open
mic.
And I was like,
I'm going to do that open.
Mike and I had taped like phrases to my
body and phrases from commercials or
snippets of conversation that I had
heard and I went up and I started
reading them and then I would improvise
a little bit and I'd be like waxy build
up or whatever and just repeating,
just letting it all filter through and
come out my mouth for five minutes of
whatever the open mic was.
And I started getting laughter,
but it was like awkward laughter after
the fact of that uncomfortable,
like what?
What is she doing?
But my commitment level was so high that
the fact that it didn't make any sense
just because laughter.
Right,
right,
right.
Well that's us.
That works sometimes with just even with
comics.
Yes,
absolutely.
There's a lot of people that are just
really odd and if you saw them you would
get it,
but if you,
you saw what they
wrote on paper is or what they said just
written down on paper,
you'd be like,
what?
That doesn't make any sense.
Yeah.
Well,
I thought you were going to say,
which is a similar point that,
that,
that it comes in the pause and after
what they're saying,
even if it doesn't make any sense,
but you're saying sometimes people write
things and it makes its own sense when
you hear them say it,
but it's also just about being fully
commit.
Yes,
yes.
Yeah.
And those pauses.
That gives you,
especially with something's really
absurd,
gives you that opportunity to go watch.
Yeah.
You don't want to just hammer them over
the head with it.
So you just started doing that.
And how did it lead to actual stand up,
stand up?
MMM,
it was a really fun time in San
Francisco because the comedy clubs were
closing,
so a lot of comics were coming to these
open mic poetry rooms.
And one of my favorite rooms was in this
bar.
And also I was from the suburbs of
Detroit.
And so just being in San Francisco,
that was a real city and a friendly
city,
you know,
like it's small enough and it's
beautiful and they have a real arts
scene.
And it was the first time that I had
seen like a real counter culture and
people that would hang out in coffee
shops and,
and a lot of young people that looked
like I did.
So I would go to bars for this open mic
and there'd be um,
you know,
like I transvestite who was semi
homeless,
but it was,
you know,
made up who was like reading her poetry.
And I was like,
I'm in like,
I'm done.
And I had no money and I would sit and
crouch on the floor and drink like a
half a beer and be like,
oh,
those,
those crazy.
And I would watch her read from her
journal and I did a similar thing where
I would just,
and then it was always,
I didn't,
I didn't know my own mind or my own
thoughts really.
So I would write down random words and I
would perform it.
I mean it's still now it's,
I've progressed a bit,
but it's like,
it informs you how the audience reacts
or it begins to,
and I just love seeing all these like
different people and what,
what they thought they were saying
versus what they were really saying and
what they're intended effect was and how
people were really seeing them.
Anyway,
so,
so comics started dropping into these
rooms like Patton Oswald and,
um,
Jeremy Kramer and blink a patch and you
know,
uh,
Greg Bear until these,
Ron Lynch,
people that were more San Francisco
affiliated that were there at that time,
we'd start doing these open Mike Nights.
Um,
but because a comic is so versed in
their own voice that watching them was
so,
I was like,
oh,
that they know how to speak and they're
more polished.
And then that was attractive to me.
So,
so I kind of gravitated towards,
and there were all these alternative
rooms that weren't comedy clubs.
And that was like,
I loved that.
I just loved it because there was room
for mistakes.
There was room for the in between,
you know,
it was like that,
the real allseen of that time.
Yeah.
That all
seems interesting.
It's always interesting when like a
little branch of a style of comedy
breaks off,
you know?
And some people do it because that's
like it's,
it feels more true to them.
Right.
And then some people do it because it
seems like the cool hip thing to do and
then some people it's just a combination
of bolts.
Right.
The all teens.
An interesting scene,
you know,
cause it also is attached to that one
place.
It doesn't pay anybody.
The UCB.
Yeah.
I was always like,
wait,
what?
Oh you mean cause they're making money
and no one else's Nikki.
Yeah.
I was always like,
what?
Huh?
Like how does that make sense?
People don't get paid at comedy clubs as
well.
Well sure they do.
Comedy store pays you,
you mean like 25 bucks,
25 bucks for regular sets.
And then do you get a lot more than
that?
If you do the main room,
the main room,
they pay your real money.
You're saying,
why doesn't ucb throw 25 bucks to people
that you have to pay if something people
are paying to go there,
right.
Paying for gas there,
they're traveling,
they're right,
and you're selling tickets to see them
do their art.
Right.
That's how it ain't to take that line.
Then everybody should be paid a lot
more.
There should be genuine percentage.
It's really only the comics.
Going back to that argument from a
comedy store from the 70s that was a,
it's a legit argument.
I mean,
it's not legit that,
look,
this is where we live and it's a really
important place to work out.
Right,
right.
So we need it and we want it to be
there.
Yeah.
And they pay you a little bit.
But if they didn't pay you anything,
like the comedy store went ucb and just
didn't pay anybody anything.
Oh,
that's interesting.
So you're saying isn't important.
It's something.
Yeah,
like especially it was important when
the club wasn't making any money.
So if the club,
I'm in the old days,
the,
oh,
or you know,
you got that 25 bucks.
Like,
look,
they've given 25 bucks to 15 people.
Fine.
How much money are they really making?
I get what you're saying.
You're saying has that vibe of like a,
it's a workshop and then you're like,
you guys are making money off of their
opening up new places,
right?
I mean this is a business,
I'm not telling them what to do or
telling anybody your performance or what
do I performed there before?
Right.
It's just,
it's kind of weird.
It's like these festivals,
I got invited to one of those festivals
once they offered to give me a pass,
like a gold pass where I could watch all
the other acts.
That's what they were going to pay me
with.
They weren't going to fly me.
They weren't gonna put up right in a
hotel.
They weren't going to give me any money.
It reminds me of that thing and Steve
Martin's book where he's,
where he made that choice and again,
a very different time,
very different scene where he's like,
I'm only headlining for money.
But he made that conscious choice that
would not work now.
And like you said,
we,
you know,
I work out in town,
I don't expect to get paid,
but it does,
it makes a difference that the comedy
store,
there's a,
that system that is in place really
works.
You know,
it's like I'm a paid regular.
That was a big deal.
Yeah.
Cause I remember I had been on,
on the road doing comedy really for the
first time in the club proper,
even though I had tons of stage time.
But you know,
back connecting back to that all seen
where it would be a different thing
every time.
And I did not quite know what I was
saying.
So,
you know,
in the past four years was when I did
the six shows per weekend.
And you're like,
I'm your entertainment for the night.
And I,
you know,
learn how to do that.
Like people came out to see you.
Yes.
And like you don't mumble.
Tell them what you're talking about.
Repeat your theme,
you know,
smile,
talk to people.
Uh,
you know,
I learned how to do that.
And um,
what was my point?
Oh,
in any way confined by that
because you,
your beginnings were so sort of free and
I think it's like a reverse.
The confinement of that is serving me
because I needed to do that.
It took me,
I went about it like completely
opposite.
I was so organic that now I'm finally
getting some structure.
I'm Mike for the first time.
Like,
oh,
that's a joke.
I read a joke.
I honestly,
it was like,
like I said,
I had no idea why people were laughing.
I knew I liked it,
but I wasn't exactly sure where it was
going to come.
And I knew that I had a deep connection
to it.
You know?
That's what propelled me to do it.
I had a need to,
to do it.
It was the only thing and it kind of
saved me.
I needed to,
I mean not to get all overly dramatic
comedy kind of saved you performing.
Yeah.
Cause I just was really,
um,
uh,
didn't know how to express myself.
And it's still to this day is like in
ever kind of deepening thing,
you know?
Yeah.
It's a,
it's a very weird discipline,
right?
Yeah.
Okay.
It's a weird thing to get involved with,
you know,
chase down these ideas and try to figure
out how to flesh them out.
And
do you structure that you feel like you
were always,
um,
cause I see you as somebody who's like
so powerful and such,
such a strong point of view in both
strong belief system.
Do you feel like you've always kind of
been that way?
No,
I don't think so.
I think comedy for sure.
It makes you chase down those ideas.
Like what is,
what is your real feelings on things?
Yeah.
Because you're thinking about things so
often and then as you're saying things,
you think about people's reaction to
them.
That's a big one.
A big one is the comedy has allowed me
to really pay attention to other
people's reactions more than like I
think our wanted to because I think if I
had my own way and I had nothing to do
with stand up,
I probably would be way more antisocial,
way more guarded and protected and way
more insecure because I hadn't answered
those questions.
I didn't pose them up myself cause it
made me uncomfortable.
Yeah.
So what standup allowed me to do,
it's like I wasn't the most outgoing
person.
Oh really?
Yeah.
I was very insecure and uh,
even so I would get like social anxiety.
I've talked about this before,
but I would like talking to a bank
teller.
I'd be no,
I'd know that I'm next to talk to the
bank tower and I'd kind of freak out and
I wouldn't know how to,
I would,
wouldn't exactly know how to talk and
say things and do it right.
But it changed from teaching martial
arts.
I want to start teaching martial arts.
I learned how to project in front of
this big room full of people.
It's something I never imagined I was
going to do any public speaking before
that it was never on the menu.
I never even thought about it.
But when I taught classes I had to teach
them and I was teaching like in
universities,
I've taught at bu and I taught at some
other places,
some other gyms and stuff.
And you know,
you have to get these people's
attention.
You have to be clear and you have to
have confidence and,
but I knew what I was doing.
Martial arts ask you that.
It probably helped a lot for sure.
If you were nervous,
you were like,
let the skill kind of takeover.
We would oftentimes,
if we opened up a new school somewhere
where we'd do a demonstration and then
we did give a speech afterwards,
explain what the martial arts were.
But we'd do a demonstration for us.
Like people would hold like boards and
shit and he'd kick him and stuff like
that,
which we never did in real life.
We only did for demonstrations.
Like we never trained that way.
But my point was like getting into stand
up.
I didn't have a particularly clean point
of view.
I think I was 21 years old.
I was,
I think it was a moron.
You know,
I didn't have any life experience other
than martial arts and girls.
Like that was all I could talk about.
And I didn't,
I knew martial arts weren't really
funny,
so it was just relationship stuff.
But um,
hey guys,
how about when we hit that block?
We don't really do that.
I'm all right.
I was kicking those blocks of wood guys.
Seriously.
Yeah.
I mean,
I had a similar thing of it.
It helps,
yeah.
To just even say anything and to be
like,
oh,
I exist.
I have a voice and I'm just now starting
to,
I mean,
I've a lot of material that's true,
but I'm just now kind of starting to
build that deeper,
um,
the belief system thing.
You know,
like I talk about my personal life and
there are kernels of things in there,
but it's,
it's scary to kind of come out.
Yeah.
But it's fun because that's what people
want,
you know?
That's what,
like,
that's what gets it going and that's
what gets everybody excited.
And that's what,
uh,
that's cool.
Yeah.
You know what comedy is Tommy?
One really important thing as a person,
you're not done.
Like there's no,
there's no like you're a finished
product.
Yeah,
I did it.
No,
your change,
depending upon your attitude about how
you look at your very existence right
now,
I get you in shift within an hour.
It could shift back and forth.
You could,
it could shift in a day or two.
It's like if you take a few weeks off of
standing up,
can I ask you that?
Do you,
is it hard for you to get back?
Chat always feels weird.
I haven't done it very often,
but um,
I did it a couple of times in my career
where I got like surgery or something
like that and I had to take some time
off and then I got burnt out once,
maybe like five years ago and I took
three months off.
And also that,
that was crazy.
That was real weird.
But then when I got back into it,
it was before I came back to the store
too.
So it was a real issue with me.
Like going on stage,
like the Improv never felt like home.
It was like a place to fuck around.
It's a nice club,
but it never,
I didn't hang out there.
It just felt weird.
Didn't feel the same.
So I'd just do a set there and then I'd
get out of here.
So I was missing like the camaraderie
aspect of it and I had just finished a
special and I just didn't want to do
anything for awhile.
I wanted to chill and so I took like
three months off.
But then when I came back I came back
with like a lot of purpose,
like a really was enthusiastic about it.
I had been thinking about coming back
for like a couple of weeks before I
actually did it.
But um,
you,
you're always working at it like always,
it's always,
you're always,
you're always in,
in,
in the process of like reaffirming,
thinking things through,
understanding who you are.
It varies with your health,
varies with how you're eating.
It varies with who's in your life.
Like your comedy radically varies.
Like how you interface with an audience
radically.
How you look at yourself.
All that vary so much.
It's never done.
Have you ever been on stage and just,
uh,
been,
not angry but like not enjoying,
kind of not wanting to be on stage and
it shows in your performance there.
Do you always get out of it through
performing then you can get upset.
There's,
there was a woman who kept heckling me
in the front row of the comedy store
just interrupting to stopping bits
before I had a chance to explain them.
And then finally I had to kick her out
and it was so annoying.
The way she did it was,
it was so entitled,
like she was entitled to voice out her
opinion in the middle.
It wasn't what I was doing.
This chunk last year on my last special
about this guy who broke into the White
House,
that a guy just broke into the White
House.
You would think there would be all these
things in place to keep someone for
breaking the White House.
The guy just humped across the lawn,
ran across lauren gods in the front door
and there was only a girl sitting there,
one unarmed girl by herself.
He smacked her the ground and just ran
to the fucking White House.
And I had this whole bit about who's
idea it was to have this leave a girl by
herself.
I've seen.
Yeah.
And then then I said that this is the
part,
like this lady interrupted me.
Um,
I said,
a lot of people think that women can do
anything men can do.
Right.
And I go,
well that doesn't make sense because men
can't even do everything men can do.
So I was in the middle of saying that
doesn't even make sense because,
and the joke is an idea.
Explain it.
Do I go I,
the joke is lady,
I've met Shaquille o'neal and his Dick
is where my face is and if the White
House has experienced in a shack attack,
I'm the wrong dude to save the world.
He's going to run me over.
But you know,
and that I tried to explain that and
like she just wanted to interrupt
anything that had to do with men or
women.
So that was annoying.
And I did not have a good set that night
cause it was like Jesus Christ crisis,
get the fuck out of here and had a kid.
And she had apparently had done that to
some guys that were on before and she
was so drunk when I was looking at it in
their eyes,
weren't focusing just just some smart
lady that was drunk that thought she
could stop what she thought was sexism
probably because she was drunk.
But there's a difference between like
you then overcoming it and being like,
ha ha,
that was awesome.
And then the feeling of I think what
I'm,
I was tense.
Yeah.
Like that where you're just inside your
own head going,
I don't want to be here like
that sacked like it's not fun that it
was just like I shouldn't have allowed
myself to get so upset.
But I,
I came into the stage upset.
That was part of the problem is that I
had a crazy day with a lot of fucked up
things happened and I carry that energy
onto the stage.
There was a lot of weird shit that
happened in my life that day.
It was just like enough,
enough fucking enough and then her own,
yeah,
it was like weird shit with friends and
a couple of weird business things.
It was like a compounding day and then
this lady was hammered and just,
and,
and I,
I gave her the bed,
I tried to talk her into just release
and explained there,
this is how the bit would have gone if
you didn't know rob.
I go,
okay,
get it.
See,
I'm gonna say something outrageous.
Then I'm going to say something more
fucked up about myself.
This is what I do.
So I did it again and she interrupted
again.
I'm like,
get the fuck out.
Just get out.
And I was,
but it was really upset and you
shouldn't really get upset.
So when you allowed yourself get really
upset,
it's usually because you came into it
unbalanced.
And again,
right?
It's always you're death,
you're never done.
Like you might think,
well,
I understand how to behave now.
I've got my shit together.
I get it.
But you don't,
you do,
you get it right now.
But if you let it slip,
you won't get it tomorrow.
If you have the wrong attitude or the
wrong approach and the wrong dude cuts
you off,
you're like fuck off.
Like,
ah,
that come from shit.
You know?
And yeah,
going back to what we were talking about
earlier,
that when you said you're not awkward,
I you two things,
you are,
you're much more of a teddy bear now
than you used to be.
Don't you think?
I've never thought of myself as a teddy
bear,
but,
well,
when I see,
and now you're just like,
you're just not,
I don't,
I'm not saying you weren't like this
before,
but you just are so like positive and
loving,
loving and kind of like,
you know,
you can feel it and whereas,
there's a lot of baggage in the past and
we never,
not baggage,
but like,
I was like,
oh,
that guy hates women or that guy hates
me.
But that was also when Duncan was
hanging out with you.
You know,
he and I,
he just broke up.
So that was the baggage I was referring
to,
but like,
oh,
you know,
I just thought,
you have such a strong energy that I was
like,
oh that guy and I,
not that I,
it's weird because I wasn't like,
I just was,
I just never pictured us talking easily.
Yeah.
Not saying that it wouldn't have
happened then it cause it just didn't,
but I was like,
Whoa,
what's up with that dude?
I get it.
I've said odd onstage a bunch of times.
I like,
I look like a sexist.
Like I look like
that I would be a dick.
I just,
that's what I look like.
You know,
there's like not much you can do it,
but if you lift weights and you have a
fat head,
you know,
you look like a dickhead.
There's just right.
There's no way around it.
I was like kind of watching some of your
recent podcasts where it was like one of
the shirts,
the feminine for the future is feminine,
Feminine.
I want to where I want to,
where the future is masculine and you
where the future is feminine.
And then we just walk around or
whatever.
And opposite.
Like if I built my compound it'd be like
crystals and lavender and soft.
You know what the problem with that
statement,
the future is feminist is the problem
with every single statement.
You cannot boil down the future of one
fucking sentence.
You just can't be funny.
Preposterous.
It would be fine.
I would like to just where the future is
masculine and just not acknowledge it.
What's up?
Yeah.
The future's masculine guys get used to
it.
I should roll pack of cigarettes.
And what are your sleeves like?
The fonz fuck you man.
Is that masculine?
Yeah.
No it makes no sense.
No silly.
Oh and then the other thing that when I
was talking about going on the road,
um,
which I was going to mention coming back
to the store,
cause I was there in the 90s to when it
was just like a terrible place and a bad
vibe and like dark and Dank.
And what year did you get there?
Uh,
I moved to La in [inaudible] 94 and I
was in San Francisco,
Cisco for a couple of years before that.
[inaudible] 94 or 95 or six.
You perform at the clubs in San
Francisco as well?
I did.
Um,
we did bars.
I never did the punchline.
You still done it?
Have you done it?
So I have,
yeah,
it's fun.
It's great.
I love it.
Yeah.
COBB's was a little strange.
Big Ceiling.
It's so big and the people were way back
there that are in the balcony there way
back.
Oh my gosh.
Hi.
Hi back there.
My husband who like he used to before we
had a child,
he used to come see my one woman show
that I did.
I think he came like,
anyway,
he saw me at cobbs and he sat back there
and he,
it was a great assessment cause he goes,
you've gotten really good because I had
met on the road,
but he goes,
that's a really hard room because these
people,
especially that late show,
like they've just had dinner and they're
there and it's so dark and it's,
it's like a room.
I don't know.
Some people love it,
but it's a room that's sort of seen its
heyday at a different time that it would
be packed out.
I don't know.
Maybe you like it if you pack it out
there to see you.
I do like that room,
but it's a different room than it used
to be.
Do I used to the old cobb's?
That's where I met 'em man.
I did.
That's where I met Alma.
I'll juggle all magical.
Started working together and like 1919
fucking eight or some shit.
Yeah,
it was a long time ago,
but I'm,
the old one was tiny,
like just a little bit bigger than the
belly room.
I mean it was like like a hundred seats
or something like that was really
ridiculously small.
I think I might be off by a little,
it might be like 130 but they would
stuff everybody in there to get 130 and
it was this tiny little club and I used
to work at,
even though,
um,
it would actually,
I could make less money there then I
could at at the punchline.
I liked it better.
I was like,
this place is better.
It's like,
it's grimy,
it's tiny.
And then Tom saw,
or the guy who ran it was like a s a
huge comedy nerd,
like a dude,
really love comedy.
And so I liked that and they're like,
good,
he's supporting good comedy.
Fuck it.
So I started going there.
So then when they turned it into the new
place,
I was like,
this is the opposite of what you guys,
right.
You guys were the most intimate club and
now you're the cavernous.
That makes sense.
Cause it,
yeah.
Clubs have to be like,
there's got to be right on top of you.
Okay.
I came back from going on the road for
the first time and doing the six shows
and I was on 24,
which I love the word just full on
comedy shop talking by the way that we
do that all the time.
I do that a long time.
Does it feel unusual?
No,
no.
I know,
I like it.
Um,
I just got a little self conscious for a
minute anyway.
The rooms and the ceiling.
That's interesting.
Funny thing.
I think people enjoy it too because
they're like hearing people who were
professionals talk about what makes it
good and what makes it bad.
Then when they're there themselves like,
oh yeah,
the room's Kinda high on this place.
Oh,
this place is intimate.
Okay.
So I was on,
uh,
you gave me the confidence to get back
in it.
So I was on 24 when it came back and we
filmed in London because it had been
done for like two years and they brought
it back and it was the end of that
airing and it was the first time I was
going on the road as a comic.
So because my face was on TV and people
were super into 24,
my shows packed out the first time I'd
ever gone on the road.
Right.
My first 45 50 minute show and I first
hit the stage at like side splitters
Tamba or whatever,
you know,
he's like,
use all your shows are sold out.
And um,
first of all,
my opener and my middle are like,
this is great.
It's sold out.
But then when they got on the stage,
they come up,
they're like,
your audience is weird because they're
24 fans and they were all,
they don't come out to clubs.
Right,
right,
right.
Like I would sometimes have somebody
sitting,
like with this guy had an article of
clothing that I had worn and season
three,
so I'm like trying to do comedy.
Like,
oh,
okay,
like you just want me to sign your
thing.
But you know,
in my approach was,
because I'm in my own head,
so I'm like,
hi.
So my name's Mary Lynn and doing,
doing my like I'm uncomfortable.
And that's where my comedy comes around.
And the whole vibe was like,
what?
You know,
like your TV star.
Like we came to see you and I,
and I had to adjust and like take that
in and then not only take it in but talk
about it,
you know,
like,
yeah,
you know,
and I would just be like Jack Bauer and
they'd be like,
ha ha.
Like losing their shit and like,
wow,
I would just make somebody in the
audience like my Jack Bauer
and then I just,
you know,
how to make it like five,
10 15 minutes of like,
let's talk about it.
Because it was such an amazing thing,
you know?
And it was to me too,
but I had this hope that was the only
drama I had ever been on.
And I have this whole other world of
comedy that I had been doing,
but the intersection of that was just
like bizarre.
But,
but then I,
you know,
like you said,
you're never done and you never know
what's going to happen and you adjust to
it.
So I would do the 24 stuff and then I
would go into my stuff.
That's my stuff about my life and my
personal life and my point of view.
And then that became really gratifying.
You know,
once I sort of brought them in,
did the thing that they needed to hear
about,
which is also part of my life.
So you know,
how long did it take before they stop
coming to see you?
Because you're from 24 and started
coming to see you because you're a funny
comic.
Oh,
I'm still waiting for that to happen.
I'm still hoping for a career in comedy.
No,
seriously.
Then it dropped off.
Right.
So I did that same circuit a year and a
half later and there'd be some super
fans or be some comedy fans and there'd
be some people that didn't know why the
hell they were there.
So then I would have,
yeah,
the guy that knows me from always sunny
in Philadelphia at the lady that knows
me from 24 and the guy who was out of
his mind on drugs going,
you're not funny.
And I'm like,
this poor person's like,
she's the superstar.
Like why is she in this shit hole?
And then other guys,
like I don't know who she is.
And then that guys like,
you don't get what I get because she's
from always sunny in Philadelphia.
And then I would pit them against each
other.
I'm like,
she doesn't get it.
But you get it.
And it's like the burden of being so
versatile,
you know,
such a cross to bear.
It must've been a fun transition though
once you got through the initial stages
because a lot of people would have
bailed like a lot of people.
Okay.
Fuck,
fuck doing in the road.
This is just too crazy.
Yeah.
I love it.
I mean it sucks,
but I love it.
It's awesome.
But it's sorta changed who you are then
what you think of you.
So you're like a real comic now.
Yeah.
You know,
for so many years I had that little
like,
oh,
you haven't done the road,
like you haven't really done it.
And now I'm like,
no,
I,
I know how to do the fuck.
There's so many people that don't do the
road that I wish would leave.
You know,
like God,
you got to experience it.
You've got to go out there,
you and,
but they don't want to do like the
Shitty road.
Well,
you have to do the Shitty road.
I also learned something about myself,
the Shitty road,
um,
because I,
I would not have a car and I take the
hotel that they gave me that would be by
the freeway,
that would be not even near the city and
a little bit from the club.
And I just hold up and then I,
it took me a while to realize like,
oh,
you like that.
Like I like a certain amount of
suffering and like,
uh,
so shitty here.
I'm going to go like walk along the
freeway and then,
you know,
someone would be like,
why don't you,
why didn't you get a car?
And like,
I don't know,
I just walked over to Chili's for lunch
and uh,
along the grass and the side of the
freeway.
I like it.
So you actually like
the dinginess of weird cities.
So are we saying yeah,
or I don't know.
The part of me likes the shittiness of
it,
just to like,
there was one house gask I don't know
why there was one hotel room that had
like
got a dining room table for 10 and like
this big,
these big plastic flowers with dust all
over them and this weird hot plate with
foil on it and a walk in closet.
But it was the shittiest most run down,
like who's who's partying in here?
Like who's fancy hotel suite is this.
It couldn't have been shittier.
Yeah.
And it was,
yeah,
I guess it's just fascinating.
And,
and I,
I like being comfortable,
you know,
I like having my things,
but I guess I like that too.
Yeah.
I like feeling the pain of that.
What?
Whatever.
I'm just not being comfortable,
but it also,
because it's in contrast to your life in
La,
right?
I mean,
yeah.
Fucking TV star.
Got some cash.
Hmm.
All right.
So then you can do it on the road all
the time.
I've seen those pictures on instagram
and you just throw it and gold.
She's throwing it up in the air.
Ooh.
Um,
but here thing is isolation tank.
Mine is,
I get in one of those blowers where the
money,
that's what I do in the morning.
I just get my little room.
I'm like the money,
it's just a cycle and have hundreds of
around me.
I get up money massage.
Yeah,
it's so great.
But when you're in the road and you're
in like a shitty hotel in Pittsburgh or
something,
it's in the middle of January.
You look out in the skies.
I got shitty dark,
smoky gray.
There's not even a hint of Sun.
It's noon.
You look out nothing.
Yeah.
Everybody's got this look on their face.
Everybody just sour puss,
just wiping dust off the window.
So
I like that weird air conditioning or
heater that doesn't really work and just
crank on.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
In the middle of the night.
You can't control them.
An asshole man.
I once had a lady in a hotel room.
Uh,
how did this go?
She was the receptionist.
God,
it's all a blur.
I don't even remember what city it is.
Um,
one of those low,
mid hotels.
She calls me,
I'm napping.
It's like after you do the radio or
something.
I'm napping.
Oh,
hi.
Um,
there's a fan down here with a bottle of
wine for you.
Can I send him up?
Swear to God.
I've never felt more unsafe or on the
verge of a breakdown.
First of all,
you woke me up.
Second of all,
you're,
you're the gateway between,
but it was such a small town and it was
so,
such a foreign concept to her.
To me,
I was like,
that's inherent.
Like you're right,
you're the protection that I have from,
should I send him up a stranger who
stopped at the hotel,
drugs with a bottle of wine,
got a bottle of drugs for you.
Should I send him up?
Seemed like a good move.
And then you know what I did as I
actually took his car,
I could hear him in the background go.
No,
no,
no.
That's okay.
Like he actually was a nice guy,
but nice enough of a person that would
do that.
Wanted to bring a bottle of wine.
That was,
I think that was her idea.
And so then I started like,
instead of going,
what the fuck are you talking about?
I just went,
oh,
okay,
well I'll come down and get it.
And then I came down and met him and,
but it was so unsettling and that was
her idea.
It wasn't his idea.
But instead of saying don't do that and
setting her straight,
I took the middle road.
And how well did you go back to sleep
after that?
Not so good.
Right.
I drank that bottle of wine and had the
best show of my life.
I'm over at the show.
Yeah,
that's creepy.
It's,
um,
Ali Wong has a great bit,
I'm not going to do it justice.
Uh,
and I don't want to paraphrase it either
and I want to tell anybody what it's
about,
but it's essentially the difference
between life for a woman comic on the
road versus a white,
young male comic.
You know,
it's a big difference.
Yeah.
The uh,
the danger level,
like that's like guys that get to get
obsessed with you.
You know,
I want to bring you wine shit and like
that stuff that's gotta be weird.
I had another guy,
it was the guy who held the sweater.
He's like,
it's your sweater from season three but
you want somehow online.
He bought it and then after the show he
won.
He showed me,
I don't know what's wrong with me
because I'm like,
he was a really nice guy.
Like this is a terrible situation,
but I,
for whatever reason I'm like,
he needs me to listen to him right now.
And I stood there like,
what is wrong with me?
He had two thick photo books of the
thousands of dollars of memorabilia and
the pictures of all the items and the
itemized of shit from the show.
And again,
I'm there.
I'm looking around like anybody seeing
this,
not just me and him.
Okay.
Yeah.
You guys continue cleaning.
Cause that's the weird thing too,
because I'm a superstar on one end,
but on the other end it's like,
not really,
I don't have the money.
I'm not bringing anyone with me.
I'm right.
You know,
I'm like a regular headliner on the
braces.
Do have security though,
right?
Most places they,
yeah,
sure.
Yeah.
They just probably weren't aware that
they should be paying attention.
Yeah,
maybe.
maybe they thought,
yeah,
that's a friend of hers.
That's also a weird thing,
right?
When do you step in?
The guy's got a bunch of books filled
with memorabilia.
Okay.
Like when that seems okay.
Like that doesn't,
it's just a,
he's a very,
very,
very enthusiastic fans.
Yes.
But lego,
what point in time is that right?
Hey,
hey,
hey.
Why don't,
you know,
ultimately,
I'm glad I did it because I feel like I
validated him even though I wanted to
go,
like,
what happened?
You spent $75,000,
all that stuff like,
but
what can you do?
So it was like,
that's,
this is great.
Terrific.
You did a really good job.
She just reached out with a pair of
scissors.
This is for you.
And if you're listening,
you did do a really good job and you
have a lot of really cool stuff that no
one else has.
There you go.
And I'm happy for you.
Was it,
it's always weird when you're a comic
too and your or your comedian in nature
and um,
you,
you do something that's not comedic,
right?
Yeah.
Like if you're a comedian and you do a
drama show like 24,
it was basically like a drama,
right?
Slas.
What are the most serious shows ever,
ever write super job?
I think I messed up.
I should have just rolled into another
drama.
I had to open my mouth and show
everybody how not the computer genius I
am like,
what is wrong with me?
I'm a Wa I've set up obstacles.
You know her from 24 what welcome the
comedy stylings of what?
Do you remember what Richard Belzer
going on?
Law and order.
Oh yeah.
And everybody was like,
what?
And then stop being funny.
Like he doesn't do any common anymore.
I don't think,
I think that should clean up my act.
Should I only be funny now or should I
get another drama?
Well I think you should stay funny.
Just be the funny,
just do that.
Oh,
I never completed this.
Whatever the story of going through
being on the road.
And then coming back to the store and
thinking like I got it cause I've been
on the road.
Right.
Coming back doing the main room,
don't got it at all.
Dry Mouth,
terrible set guy in the front row is
mining falling asleep and mouthing to me
how boring I am because I'm like wow,
his intense.
But that's also the beauty of the store
because you cause you're like,
oh that was one thing on the road and
this is another thing.
Like you got to go deeper and get real.
It's running with a weight vest on.
That's what I describe it.
You can run faster.
The weight vest on if your legs are
strong,
but otherwise you're going to be fucked.
Yeah,
I love it now.
it's,
it's an intense place.
I remember you and I were talking about
something there once,
like fairly recently within the last
year where you're like,
I don't know what I'm doing.
Oh yeah.
I told you I might get the quitting.
I quit.
What?
Are you serious?
I couldn't tell if you're serious or
deadly.
Let's meet every six days or if I take
more than two days,
awesome,
I'm done.
I need to talk to anybody or go anywhere
or do anything.
I'm done.
Like that's my nature.
That's what I fight with.
What brings you back?
What gets you from there to fuck it.
I'll just go do it.
I just force myself.
But you don't have a hundred percent
confidence and your future resolve
like you don't know in the future.
Do you think there's gonna come a time
where you just a week turns into a
month,
turns into a year and then 24 again
comes on?
We didn't.
They do 24 for the black guy.
Was there a reason?
Is that still okay?
It's still good now.
It's done.
I did it with a whole new cast.
I think it went one season.
Well that's what happens.
Fucking white people.
You ruined it.
Thanks.
White people,
white people.
He didn't promote it good enough.
You promoted great for Kiefer
Sutherland.
I didn't understand what you're getting
on with that black actor and you fucking
halfass and cancel it before people grew
to love it.
I think that was a pretty tough act to
follow.
I'm sure.
Yeah.
People get angry when you reduce
something,
you know,
you call it the same thing like fuck
off.
It's not 24 I will come up with another
name.
Oh yeah.
I think that was the higher world's in
trouble.
I like that.
Cool Black Guy.
Who was the guy that played the Corey
Hawkins.
Is that right?
I don't know who that gentleman is.
Great.
They fucked him.
Goddamn white people.
Fuck Ah,
white people.
That's my take on it.
So are you going to do a specialty
thing?
I like to.
He should.
I want,
yes.
I think you're very funny.
Thanks girl.
I do.
Thank you.
I think you're hilarious.
I'm glad you're doing it.
Still.
Like when you were telling me that that
you were going to quit.
I'm like,
you know,
you are my angel that night.
You really where you lifted me up from
the depths.
I love that.
You're like,
where are you serious?
It make no you,
you lifted me up and the depths of hell.
Well,
I could tell you a really down.
I was like,
that's crazy.
I know,
I know.
Who's funny.
You're hilarious and you really nice.
You know.
So it was like,
you know,
it's a weird thing to do.
It's weird thing to do and maybe you
don't have to.
None of us do it really.
I mean,
there's gonna come a point in time in my
life for,
I'm probably,
I'm not going to do this anymore,
but for right now.
But that's cool that you,
um,
uh,
pretty love the live show as much as you
do.
It's a struggle I would love.
I really enjoy struggling.
I do think it's very important.
It's very important for my balance as a
person,
especially me,
I have maniacal genetics.
My brain is just constantly,
constantly overrun with things to think
about and do.
My brain just wants to go,
just come up,
let's go.
We need more fucking stimuli shot.
Let's go.
There's no to,
we'd always need something.
So what I do is just stuff it filled
with information,
work it out,
get it to run hills and do Jujitsu and
yoga and burn that motherfucker out so
that I could be calm.
And so what you've lot of what people
notice today versus how I was like 20
years ago is this,
this,
I understand myself better.
I'm better at managing my,
like whatever are the things that make
you,
I'm better at managing those to be very
positive,
to just be just overall in my attitude
is very different to it's overall just
nicer to people.
And how did you become nicer?
Just realize that when I'm at my best,
that's who I am.
And the only variation between that and
when I'm at worst.
You weren't nice before?
Yeah,
it was nice.
I just wasn't as Nice Sam now I've
always been nice,
but I've always been nice.
I,
I'm quicker to pull the trigger back
then.
Right.
You know,
and I'm,
I'm less
must remember we were at the comedy
store,
this is pretty recently.
And uh,
that guy came into the bathroom when I
was in there.
You totally pulled like the best male
like strong guy.
It was,
it was so good.
Your leg.
Cause I,
I think the guy was like on coke or a
combo of something.
And again,
it's like do I not have regard for my
own being because a part of me kind of
left my body and was like,
wow,
this guy is crazy cause he's like,
give me a kiss.
And this is like in the women's
bathroom.
Right,
right,
right.
And then I think someone that he had
done it to someone else,
so it was kind of going around and then
I ran into you and I was like,
yeah,
that just happened to me.
And you were like,
what?
Where is he?
And you were immediately like,
I'm going to beat his ass.
But simultaneously you were like,
get security to get this guy.
It was so awesome.
Well that guy was a creep.
It was so creepy.
I was upset that I wasn't there as it
was happening.
I now,
yeah,
that's unfortunate that you're always
going to have to,
I rarely like enjoy or or that like that
bonds that you had.
I was like,
that was awesome.
I like that as you rarely can be a lady
after all.
I just don't know how to do it.
Well.
I miss the boat,
but I
only reason why you can enjoy it is
because it is in stark contrast to how I
behave when people are nice.
So you realize there's a difference,
right?
It's like it's break class,
break glass in case of emergency,
you know that was an emergency.
Like this is a real creep.
It's cool to see that coked up assholes
at that fucking store.
Lately there's so many coked up.
Weirdos cook must be making a comeback
and Hollywood,
it must be kind of like put my blinders
on to it probably.
Sure.
There's a lot of people with fucking
bright eyes and ideas and business
plans.
They want to fucking
pitch away.
That's what I need.
If you're the overactive,
I'm the opposite.
Like if I see a bed out of the corner of
mine,
I'm like,
ah,
that can be great right now.
Like that's my avoidance tactic.
Just like this.
Got To sleep.
Yeah,
I can't do that.
Does work.
I just lie there and think,
but my sort of route
of the discovering like my hidden anger
core,
I'm like,
oh,
like peeling off the layers of like,
she's uncomfortable,
she's quiet,
she doesn't react.
And it's like,
oh no,
no,
they're in there.
You've just buried them like all of your
feelings in like politeness.
And so that's comedy has helped me with
that too.
Cause I early on I was like way too
reactive.
I'd be like,
Oh,
what do you think?
Like talking to an audience member,
it's like,
no,
you're in control.
Like you tell them where it's going,
you steer it like yes,
you can listen to it.
But um,
so that's,
it's teaching me that as well.
How to like drive the train instead of
like,
I'm going to be open to you and listen
and go wherever you want me to go,
you know,
and just react to you.
There's also like,
there's a weird feedback loop thing
going on there because people like it
when you go,
oh well what do you think?
So you liked the fact that they liked
that you do that and then you avoid the
conflict that way,
but then you have to swallow it for the
rest of the day.
It was,
you know,
he's totally,
that's true.
Yeah.
Well I mean it's like I said,
like being a person and being a comic,
very similar in that you're never done.
There's never done.
You know,
you're always trying to fix that thing.
Was trying to tweak it,
make it a little better.
And then that's like one of the big
arguments for writing new material to
the idea is that every time you write a
new act,
especially when you have to like really
so special or something like that,
you're going to be better.
Cause you,
you understand comedy better than you
did two years ago.
You're just going to be better.
If you've really been paying attention
and you really are looking at it
correctly,
you're going to be better.
But God,
it's so hard cause you right.
You want to avoid it.
You want to go to that bed.
It's right there.
It's right there in radio land.
CHICAGO,
Zee.
Hello.
Oh,
you get your pets in the bed with you?
Oh yeah.
They keep 'em out.
Cause my allergies.
But then when they surround me,
what are you allergic to?
Everything.
Do you have any cats and dogs and you're
allergic to them?
Yeah,
my husband got the cat.
That's what put it over the edge.
I had two dogs for the longest time and
I ignored it.
And then it's the weather and the cat
and I just went over this edge where I
always had like this really bad cold.
And then I finally had to go and I tried
to all the organic things and I finally
had to go and get the like twice a week.
But when they tested it,
it was like everything just like paper
and pollen and pets and a paper.
You're allergic to paper.
Yeah.
Wow.
Uh,
but then I got those shots twice a week
and with the shots do I kind of Miss My
allergist?
We would have little four minute chats.
Uh,
it's like you're an ocular rating,
so you start doing a little bit and then
you build up your tolerance so they can
inoculate you for cat dander.
Real.
Yeah.
That's sort of an allergy shot is I
didn't even know that there were allergy
shots.
Yeah.
And He,
it's like a little cocktail,
like all the things cocktail for me of
all the things that I'm allergic to and
then I just build up my tolerance.
Wow.
So now if you're around a cat and
nothing,
yeah,
I cuddled him.
No Shit.
We make out.
Yeah.
And it used to be if a cat just like
licked you or touched your hand or
something like that,
you would get like little,
little rub.
A little red area.
Yeah.
Or like,
yeah.
Inflamed.
Yeah.
One of my daughters is allergic to cats.
We had to figure it out.
It took a while.
She'd like wake up with puffy eyes and
then we got a tested and realized it was
a cat.
So what'd you do?
She takes a pill?
No,
no,
the cat went to,
uh,
my other daughter,
my oldest daughter.
Okay.
So she's got it.
Her apartment,
I used to be allergic to feathers.
I remember sleeping over someone's
house.
It depends on like where my system is of
how it affects me sometimes.
Yeah.
Like the other pillow.
Whoa.
I know people that are allergic to like,
like Styrofoam.
I've heard of people who are allergic to
like certain types of plastic and shit.
Yeah.
Just coming in contact with certain
plastics,
make them break out my,
my making this up,
it feels like bullshit.
I got the Epi pen once.
Whoa.
From getting the shots.
That was really exciting.
So you got the shots,
your body went into shock because of all
the allergic shots.
And then they had a fucking boom right
in the thigh.
And My allergist was like,
he did it in my arm and he,
he said,
I didn't even raise it that much,
but I went home and I was reading and
I'm like,
God,
I itchy.
Oh,
I must,
I must have been sweating.
Like I worked out and I need to,
I didn't for like a full 10 minutes.
I wasn't conscious.
I was just subconsciously gone.
Man.
I gotta go take a shower or something
and then I lift it up and it was like
traveling and then I just was like,
I'm having a attack.
Like I need a Benadryl.
And like no one was listening to me and
I'm like,
Hey,
I think I need a Benadryl.
And I,
I didn't,
I was looking for the Benadryl,
couldn't find it.
Called my allergist.
And he goes,
yeah,
I just come here right now.
And then I drove there just like so
scared cause I could feel it traveling
and I'm like,
you know,
panicking but also trying to like manage
like when you panic and it's a good
thing because you have to act fast.
And then I thought,
are my eyes going to close up?
Is my throat going to close up?
And then went in there full on Epi pen.
It's awesome.
It was really good.
It felt like,
it honestly felt like I was about to go
onstage.
Ooh,
like a rush.
Yeah,
it was kind of great feeling,
but it's almost like it like feels like
tinny and like real trevally like,
like you get like for a few seconds and
trevally bless Augusta.
Yeah,
like not even caffeine,
like beyond caffeine,
but,
but yeah,
like a pure,
a dry,
it felt like a real exciting standup
show.
Wow.
I'm really excited to go on stage
right now.
And that immediately stops the allergic
reaction.
Yeah.
Wow.
That's incredible.
What do you got it?
That's what it is.
The EPI pen is adrenaline.
Oh Wow.
That's a crazy,
I've done that on an episode of 24 where
the character dies and the Epi pen in
the heart and they wake back up.
So epinephrin is adrenaline.
Wow.
It was awesome.
I liked it.
I wouldn't do it every day if I could.
You should do it every day.
It's a hormone,
neurotransmitter and medication.
Epinephrin is normally produced,
but both of your dream of glands and
certain neurons plays an important role.
The fight or flight response by
increasing blood flow to the muscles
output or the heart trouble feel.
Oh Wow.
Pupil dilation.
Wow.
And then then other stuff that you get
from luck,
cold shock proteins.
That's norepinephrine.
Is that what it is?
That's the way that Doctor Rhonda
Patrick was a,
she's a giant proponent of a sauna and
also of cryotherapy.
And she was talking about the benefits
of cold shock proteins.
And one of them is,
uh,
your body freaks out when you go into
those cryotherapy chambers,
cause it's like 250 degrees below zero.
So you get this big powerful burst of
norepinephrine.
You get cold shock proteins.
These sidechains cause your body's
trying to react to the fact that you
have this massive cold environment that
you're just trapped in.
It's like so fucking cold.
Your body freaks out and it produces
this really radical anti inflammation
process.
And one of them is this stuff.
Okay.
And that's as a trend that known also
known as noradrenaline.
Oh,
it's also,
no,
because adrenaline is epinephrine.
Okay.
So nor epinephrin that it makes you feel
so good.
It's like one of the reasons why I
really liked going to the cryo chamber
just to get out,
get out.
Yeah.
You get out,
you're like,
whoa.
Putting your body under stress and then
it releases that Doctor Rhonda Patrick
is also a big proponent of that in the
sauna.
And that's why I installed that sauna
here.
Call it a protein.
Yeah.
Heat shock proteins.
He chocked proteins and cold shock
proteins.
So proteins that are produced by your
body to deal with the effects of extreme
heat or cold.
See your body reacts to stress.
Too much heat will kill you for sure.
Too much cold will kill you for sure.
But a little bit is actually very good
for you because your body has a response
to that and that response sort of
invigorates your entire system,
kind of speaks to what you're talking
about performing and a ceiling stressing
yourself going through that stress in
order to,
um,
yeah,
I listened to a chunk of that ell and
um,
Joey Diaz.
Yeah.
Which by the way,
it was amazing the way you guys
communicate it.
That was like,
it's pretty cool.
Uh,
but the,
yeah,
the,
the pyramid of athletics.
Yeah.
Every day.
And you're living there.
It just made me think about my own life,
which you know,
my parents really hard to like make me
comfortable and here's your TV and you
go to school and you come home from
school and how that's the goal in like
suburban life is to just be coffee
counter ball.
We don't realize it,
but this is all because people before us
weren't we just only living in the
environment where people are supposed to
be comfortable,
but you know,
just two generations back,
everyone's an immigrant and everyone's
really concerned about starving,
so I have to do,
go back to the 1920s everyone's worried
about fucking dying.
There were millions of people died.
Like even during World War Two millions
of people died by starvation.
That was a real concern.
I remember you saying to him,
you're like,
yeah,
it produced,
it produces really good athletes.
It might not be like the nicest
situation,
but there's no way you get really nice
situations that produced the world's
best combat sports athletes just doesn't
happen.
You have to be strong as fuck mentally,
physically.
You have to have experienced adversity
on a level that most people can never
comprehend so that when the shit hits
the fan that you could look at the other
guy on the other side of the cage like
Yoel Romero does and goes,
I'm going to go fuck you up cause I've
been through everything already.
Even then the other guys the same way so
he doesn't even work.
Yeah,
I don't really relate to that.
Like China fuck up the other dude and
going through so much adversity.
Well I,
well I'm,
my point of view is like,
I'm going to do my chores and I'm so
comfortable right now.
Now I'm going to deliberately make
myself uncomfortable in order to do what
I know is good for me and that I enjoy
doing and that I want to have success
in.
And that takes me to another place in my
life.
But it's,
you know,
I do it in a very small way.
You know,
you do,
but it's still really honestly the same
thing.
What [inaudible] is doing and what
you're doing is the same thing.
You're doing something very difficult
that you,
it's,
you struggle to do it.
It's hard.
You push yourself visit [inaudible] want
to do it and in through doing it you get
a little bit better at everything.
Did he talk about,
I only watched the first chunk of it.
Uh,
did he talk about his desire to do that
or not?
Yeah.
Like yeah.
Yeah,
he dead.
And how does that,
how does that match with kind of being
put in that system?
I think you asked that early on too was
like how do they choose,
how do you choose?
Is it just want someone who has what?
If you have the natural ability but you
don't want to do it,
well then you won't perform.
And if you don't perform,
you get knocked out of the system.
There is the desire.
It does,
it has to be to be as good as he is.
There has to be desire to compete.
He wanted to be a boxer initially said,
but his father was a boxer.
I think his brother is a world champion
boxer as well.
He's just a genetic for reek.
Like there's genetics and Cuba,
and he was explaining it to me too.
He's during the podcast,
he was like,
anybody that thinks that everyone's on
steroids just go to Cuba where everybody
is so poor and look at the regular
people,
just the regular people.
Forget about the athletes.
He said,
I'll take you to Cuba for two weeks and
you'll come back.
You're like,
I get it.
There's just really,
it was a slave colony.
They,
they had a hard life.
I mean it's,
it's,
that's their Africans that speaks
Spanish and they live on an island
that's off the coast of Florida.
I mean,
it's a crazy spot.
The whole thing is crazy.
It was run by a dictator forever and
they had some of the best athletes in
the world in boxing,
in judo and wrestling,
just world class athletes that had
mental toughness.
The likes of,
I mean it's hard for the average person
even comprehend with those people are
capable of,
and a lot of it is because of that
really brutal system that you all talked
about on the podcast.
Amazing stuff.
Amazing.
You know,
just,
just imagining that this guy went
through that,
you know,
it's fascinating because that's not what
I want to do.
It's not what you want to do,
right.
But you just think like that there's a
person out there that can do that.
And look what happens on the other end.
You get that guy like Jesus.
He was just being in the room with him.
It's just,
he's like a fucking superhero.
It's like cheese us that,
that is the product of genetics,
ruthless training,
ruthless environment.
You know,
one of the most complex and
sophisticated sports training systems in
the world with boxing and with wrestling
and with Judah.
I mean they're just phenomenal over
there.
It was cool.
It was really inspiring.
It's amazing for way for someone like
me,
like I don't relate necessarily to what
he does is like foreign and amazing.
But through my own life it's like,
oh,
I can be not comfortable.
And that's why it seems like a
contradiction,
but it's not like that's what we're
supposed to be doing.
Um,
and when you get through that you have a
sense of satisfaction and then it feels
bad.
It wasn't something that was introduced
to me or taught to me really.
I mean,
I did sports a little bit.
Did you figure it out just through the
pursuit?
Yeah,
I don't,
there was nothing that I really
committed to that much or knew how to,
or if I did it was maybe one small
aspect.
It wasn't really a thing.
It was,
you know,
the messaging was try to get by and try
to try to get some shitty job,
you know,
it wasn't,
um,
it's weird because you know,
at the not,
not like woe is me,
but like just knowing the,
even that you had choices that you could
try to beat something great.
That wasn't really something that was
discussed or on the table.
Well wasn't that does not,
that's one aspect of all comedy.
Like they're not a lot of people that
talk about success or the process of,
it's more of like playing everything low
key.
Right.
Or like a sarcasm or a,
it's not like that's the sincerity.
Yes,
yes,
yes.
Of being a hipster is that you've got
that distance.
You're not really,
that's why I love the comedy store as
well because it's like the opposite.
It's the opposite.
It's like what's your thing?
And every been super honest and open
about like bombings and good sets and
bad sets and jokes had just fell right
in their face like that back bar area.
So brutal with the people who just come
back there and go,
oh,
I just ate a fat,
played a shit.
Like people are just so honest about it
when they come downstairs,
you know,
it's great place.
I feel super fortunate in it.
Yeah,
I missed it so much coming back.
I mean there's a place for that.
Sarcasm and the,
and the,
sure Thomson [inaudible] does that all
the time,
but he's also sincere as well.
Yeah,
there's a,
there's a thing that's a,
it's an insecurity.
Um,
it's like a defense mechanism and that's
what a lot of people do it for.
They pretend they're above it all,
but no one's above it all,
man.
You can't,
don't pretend you're above it all.
It's ridiculous.
You can do it for fun.
But pretending you're actually above it
all you're missing out like nobody
believes you.
First of all,
it's like pretending you're psychic.
Are you ho?
You know magic.
Nobody fucking believes you.
All right,
so you keep down,
act going,
keep your fucking fake mustache on your
Cape and your top hat.
I feel that's like,
that's silly.
Like it's doing it occasionally.
Every now and then it's fun.
We all do it to each other all the time,
but if you have a complete lack of
ability to communicate sincerely,
that's not being hip or cool,
right?
That's a defense mechanism and it's a
stupid one because you don't have much
time.
You have a hundred years.
If you're lucky,
they'll go,
they go by like that.
If you have $100 you spend a dollar a
day before you know what?
You're fucking broke.
That's life.
My son was like,
where did Michael,
how old was Michael Jackson when he
died?
I was like,
ah.
In his fifties he was like,
oh,
okay.
Like that.
Like that sounded right to him.
I'm like,
ah.
People don't die until much,
basically.
That's me.
Well,
Michael Jackson's a craziest case of all
time,
right.
Cause he was giving him,
they was in administering anesthesia
every night so we can go to sleep.
Dude,
I was playing that.
I was playing a want to be starting
something and uh,
thriller in the car on the way,
taking my son to school and I start
crying just because it's like,
how do you explain
what he was and how monumental,
what he did was like,
I can remember seeing him dancing the
Billie Jean and like how kind of like
broke the mold for music and the persona
that he had and that level of
creativity.
Um,
yeah,
it was weird to be in the car with us,
with my kid who doesn't really know the
name but didn't,
you know?
Right.
It's just,
that's not part of his life.
That's not part of his life.
Maybe she introduced him to that movie,
that documentary.
Was that the one documentary that did
this is it?
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
Does that get into the drugs and stuff?
And how many years was he doing it for?
So,
so sad.
Not Very Long,
but here's one of the more fucked up
things is,
this is something I speculated a long
time ago.
His doctor who went to jail for giving
him the anesthesia also testified that
Michael Jackson was chemically castrated
by his parents when he was young to
preserve his voice.
That's what I suspected.
I suspect that I talked about on the
podcast like years ago,
I was saying this,
that I think he was a cast Strada,
which is they take young boys and they
used to do this with opera and they
would castrate them at a very young age
and because of that their body never
developed testosterone.
So they would do at this high piercing
like haunting voice.
It's very strange.
Like we played some of the,
there's only a few recordings of actual
castrol does that are available or cas,
stratos,
one of those.
Um,
but the,
when you play them they're haunting
cause you realize like this is a kid
that was castrated as a baby so that it
can be a singer.
Like this is fucked up.
And that's what Michael Jackson's doctor
said they did to Michael.
They did it through chemicals.
They chemically castrated him the same
way as judy pedophile.
I'm just trying to regulate a situation
that was already far gone.
Is that his,
uh,
defense?
No,
I mean there's no defense.
The doctors just fucking,
you know,
he's just killed me.
It killed Michael Jackson,
let them get anesthesia until he died.
His defense wasn't that he was just
saying there's something else,
right.
Like Michael Jackson was fucked up.
Like his parents literally chemically
castrated him to preserve his voice
because he was the lead singer of the
Jackson five when he was a baby.
And that was part of what was great
about him was like,
oh baby one not chance.
Like that voice,
that voice was nothing like anything
that he would be capable of doing as an
adult.
If he grew into a man,
he would have this big old man,
I want to get some pussy voice.
And he was like,
no,
where's the little Michael?
He would have like a,
you know,
like,
um,
a barry white voice or something like,
fuck,
you can't have that.
Like you're Michael,
you know,
your ABC,
it's easy as well.
He may not have gotten that deep,
but this voice,
but the guests,
if you get that,
that's the belief.
Be believed that he'd never had the
chance.
I believe it.
You know,
I believe it cause his voice didn't
sound anything like a regular mans and
it didn't sound anything like his
brothers,
his brothers all look like regular grown
ass men.
Michael Jackson's deep voice.
That's not deep.
So that's fine.
Cold.
That sounds like John Rivers.
It rangy I was looking it up.
All those places,
I'm seeing that story about him being
castrated or like tabloid eats the sun
and that kind of stuff.
Right.
But it was,
wasn't an an interview in like,
uh,
the,
which was a UK paper and I just grew,
it was the sun,
which is like not the best,
not the worst.
Right.
The Daily Mail is the worst.
But both of them actually I did the
same.
The equal.
I don't think so.
I'm hoping that's so true.
And the last time you talked about this,
I got some messages.
I don't know.
Again,
like what's getting videos like this of
showing like examples,
his deep talking voice that's not deep.
There's a lot of chicks that have
weighed deeper voices.
Yeah.
Listen,
that's his deep voice.
Come on,
let me tell you.
You mother Fucker,
you listened to the wrong people.
I mean think of how many women have
ruthlessly deep voices.
Yeah.
All right.
I can tell you a couple of right now.
Yeah.
I think,
I think they did it to him.
His voice was just phenomenal acumen
nature.
Like as an adult,
that is such a fucking phenomenal song.
It doesn't sound like anything that
irregular man is capable of saying like
the notes that he hits,
like that voice that he had was just
haunting.
Right.
Trying to think of who else is a
natural,
uh,
star who has a high boy hold.
He used to sing in Falsetto,
but it was very obvious when he was
doing it that he was doing it.
Yes.
Whereas Michael Jackson like that human
nature songs,
one of my favorites because it's such a,
like a slow,
smooth holding of those sounds.
These are natural sounds that are coming
from,
you know,
it's like this natural,
like a warm affectionate tone to it.
It just doesn't seem like a man's voice.
It doesn't seem like a woman's voice
either.
That's my point.
You kept the wrap way talk and that's
different.
That's like falsetto.
Are you saying that's like a four?
Sounds like a caricature.
Yeah,
you could say that it's in that way.
What does this feel like?
Dancing.
Whoo.
Puberty.
Phoneokay yeah.
Known as Ma mutational false.
I had a call on my penis.
It's a type of voice disorder
characterized by habitual use of high
pitched voice after puberty.
Oh,
so that some people get that.
Yeah.
It's like a psych psychogenic in nature.
So the other thing is you look at his
body,
he had no muscle like his body was like,
I mean he was a very active guy dancing
all the time,
but it wasn't billing a dancer.
He was billing a stick.
You know,
it was a very,
very thin guy.
That's what you would expect from
someone who didn't have any
testosterone.
You wouldn't be able to develop any
muscle.
I'm sticking with my theory.
I might have biases,
but they're mine.
They're mine.
Okay.
I'm sticking with it.
Dig 'em up.
Dig Him up and check the nuts.
Degas mop.
Summerlin.
Yes.
Is there anything you'd like to talk
about?
Anything cause report to in this day and
age?
Geez,
you just turn it over to me.
I was just trying to figure out where
you stand on.
Thanks.
Um,
what,
what uh,
Whoa,
whoa.
Um,
told you I cried to Michael Jackson.
Yeah.
Good reason.
Uh,
I
think I'm a hypocrite.
In what way?
The gun control,
um,
March that is happening.
I,
part of me was like,
I had a friend,
a mom who said they're the,
the march is going on right outside our
house,
like who wants to join?
And as soon as I clicked on the email
and saw what it was in the pit of my
stomach,
I was like,
no,
no.
And then I covered it up with,
I should do that.
This would be a really good thing to do.
And I was then fighting with myself
because I was like,
well,
you can't have both things at once.
Either you want to March and do that or
you don't like,
those are conflicting things.
MMM.
I don't want to do it.
I don't think it'll help.
But then there's another part of me that
really likes when people march,
because I do think it changes the
attitude.
Like I'm really happy that the women's
March happened and is happening,
but I didn't go and I feel like it's
like a dirty secret and I've started to,
I have a bit about it.
That's sort of an unformed bit where I
say,
yeah,
I live in Encino because that's where
you go to give up.
Like next,
next time you see me,
I'm going to be like,
I live in thousand oaks,
I'm allergic to the sun.
And I,
and I described like the moment I knew I
had given up was,
and this is just an exploratory,
I still don't have it figured out.
The mom and I knew I had given up was I
was making my stairway from my vagina
poster with glitter and then I marched
out to the curb and was like,
it's too hot.
Right.
I don't think there'll be parking at the
march.
And went back inside.
Did you really?
Yeah.
I mean that's the joke version,
but I was very conflicted and like,
oh,
I should go.
And both times I was doing stuff with my
kid and it was,
you know,
a very small,
mundane day.
And I was like,
I'm not doing it.
And then I saw the women that did it and
they talked about being in this crowd
and how uplifting it was.
And I was like,
that's amazing.
Like I'm really happy this is happening,
but yet why is it because I don't care
and I'm weak?
Or is it because I,
there's a part of me that believes it's,
I,
I don't want to do it and that it's an
actual belief.
And then I was like,
you're a hypocrite.
I'm tired.
You can't think about it anymore.
But yeah,
the,
uh,
I don't know.
I think what I'm saying,
I'm a hypocrite is what I'm saying.
I don't know if you're a hypocrite,
you just have you decided when they
knock over,
I just decide what you want to do and
what you don't want to do.
You know,
and you didn't want him to go Marsha
Day.
It doesn't mean you're a hypocrite.
It means you just didn't want to do it.
You're a hypocrite.
If you were saying one thing and voting
for another,
that would make you a hypocrite.
That just makes you a person.
You're just just decided that's not what
you wanted to do and also look,
it is.
It would be nice if you through your one
and two,
the 600,000 that were marching through
the streets of downtown La,
but there's still 600,000 people.
Even if she just watching it from the
news and go,
you go girl,
it's not,
you're not helping,
but I don't think you're a hypocrite.
It doesn't make you a hypocrite.
Does it help?
Do you think those big marches,
and I'm wondering,
I think it empowers people.
It gets people very excited about the
cause.
There's a lot of other people that think
like minded,
gets people to watch,
gets people to put it on the news.
People at home watch it.
Maybe people feel like,
hey,
even though some fucked up things have
gone down with Harvey Weinstein and all
this other shit,
it least it's turning around.
Maybe people are bummed out that this
guy became the president,
but now people are active.
Maybe people are paying attention more,
maybe people are more engaged.
So ultimately it's almost like we were
talking about before.
You get past that adversity and there's
actually a benefit to it.
And sometimes I think even as a country
we might need that cause we don't have
any war over here.
Everything is over there.
We don't see it in terms of like right
in front of us on a daily basis.
But this is like a cultural war and an
idea of war.
And so I think that these things
happening right in front of us and
having these uncomfortable moments
forces these conversations is just going
to be peaks and valleys in the
conversation where people are rude and
people are calm and maybe there's going
to be some breakthroughs,
but ultimately it at least four and
probably,
well,
I'm pro progress.
And I think that all of this comes from
people being disfat dissatisfied with
how things are currently.
So the best way to,
to add,
to very,
very inspiring to me that you know,
that there's kids came out and our
talking and that's like,
I love that about guns.
It's also sad that sa so,
so little is happening.
Yeah,
there's,
it is sad,
but there's two things that have to be
addressed.
Guns have to be addressed for sure,
but also mental health has to be a
trust.
We have to address psych medicines.
We have to address how many of these
people,
whether it's correlation equals
causation or not.
How many of these fucking people have
been on psych medicine?
And the answer is almost all of them.
Now,
does that mean that they're,
they're mentally ill and so that's why
they shoot people or that doing the
psych meds,
a lot of people call these the effects
of these things very disassociative that
they allow people to do horrific things
they might not have been able to do
before or inspire them to do that.
There's a real argument there.
It's not exonerating the people that
have done these horrific things or
exonerating the people that got the guns
in their hands,
it's not doing that,
but it is a factor.
There's a fact that the people aren't
taken into consideration becomes,
it comes,
it becomes a one or the other thing.
It becomes an either we need more gun
control and we need stricter gun control
or we need to do something about the
effects of psych medication.
It's not both and I think it's both.
I really did say,
well,
yeah,
based on how you just presented it,
it definitely seems like both and it,
there was an article,
there was,
or I'm sorry to interrupt you,
but there was an article that was
written,
I got to remember this.
There was written recently that was
really ridiculous and it would say,
and contrary to popular belief,
most of these mass shooters are not
mentally ill.
Well what the fuck defines mentally ill
if they're on psych medication,
they're all on anti psychotics and
psychiatric meds and Ssri.
They're almost all so if they not,
they're not mentally ill.
How are you shooting people?
And that in itself,
that was the next [inaudible] you can
just go and do a school and shoot 19
children.
You have to be mentally ill.
But the point is if they're not mentally
ill,
why are they taking medicine for people
who are mentally ill?
There's a bullshit article and it's an
article or who knows what the fucking,
whether it's a contrarian point of view
that's is designed to get clickbait hits
or whether it's someone who is trying to
set up a narrative that's contrary to
what the pharmaceutical drugs companies
have known for years.
There's real effects to those things.
I can,
and they're not always positive and it's
a God crap crapshoot.
Whether or not a pill's going to work
for you or not work for you.
I mean that that's why they have
abilify.
Abilify is an anti psychotic.
They prescribed to people who are on,
they're on Ssri but they think about
killing themselves.
They're like,
well if you're thinking about killing
yourself,
try this first.
Try to stack these two together.
Maybe that's your mixture.
And Ryan wasn't it the most number one
most prescribed drug in the country.
See if that's true.
Still a bill of an antipsychotic was the
number one most prescribed drug in the
country.
Look,
we've got a fucking problem now how many
of these people are taking medication
cause they really need it.
I'm sure if some of them,
how many people are taking medication
because drug companies are pushing this
shit.
I bill fise top selling us drug.
There you go.
That's fucking crazy.
The top selling us drug.
See this.
Don't blame mental illness.
Blame men.
Well that's true too.
No,
she's right there to the guy.
Have a bit that I'm doing about all the
different fucked up things that men do.
Like it's an anti men's rights bit and
it's like that Ma,
I don't want to do it on the air cause
they'll fuck it up for before my
special.
But it's that we have to pay attention
to like all the shit that we do wrong.
Like men,
like when we look like mass mass
shootings is not just one.
If you want to take credit for the good
things and men have done,
you have to take credit for all the war.
Like that's also what they'd done.
Men have cause all of it,
you know.
And in the bit I go into detail about
all these different things,
it's,
it's a build up to something else.
But this,
this also has to be addressed that it's
always men.
That's real too.
It's not not blaming every man that
didn't shoot up a school.
We have to figure out what the fuck is
it,
what is it?
What combination of psych,
drugs,
guns and being a man is causing this.
And if we just want to blame only the
tools,
that seems to be to be fucking crazy.
They also want to blame the NRA.
Well,
I'd see him one point because you think
the NRA is helping people get drunk or
get guns rather more easily.
I get that.
But also no one who was a member of the
NRA has ever committed a mass shooting.
So you have to think of that.
Well,
well what does that mean?
I mean,
are you really blaming the group of
people that want gun safety to be
paramount and the group of people that
doesn't want their rights to be
infringed?
Or are you going to attack the group of
people that are actually shooting these
people?
That's the real problem is that people
that have actually done it,
and I guarantee you there's something
wrong with every single for that.
Yeah,
they're right about now.
Sorry.
No,
no,
no it because everything you're saying,
I'm just thinking that the person that
shoots a bunch of people,
whether they're on psych drugs,
whether they have access to a gun,
mental health issues there,
they're isolated to the point where they
can do something like that.
Yeah.
And that quiet little statement that
someone is isolated is something that we
can't address because it's so
complicated.
And it's such the fabric of how we live
our lives.
It's so much easier to like blame and
fight for all these things,
but how do we fix,
you know the one guy who his brother was
just found with all that porn.
It's like,
yeah,
the guy that shot all the people in
Vegas.
Yeah.
How do we address just how fucked up
people are in general or the contraband
story about I'm jumping topics,
but the horrible story about that,
can't even talk about it.
The couple that had all those kids that
they open their basement,
nobody knew.
Nobody said anything.
People.
Yeah,
I thought they seemed weird,
like how do we address our disconnection
from each other that we that were so
fun.
There is,
you're definitely going to be people
that feel alienated and they always want
to,
they see these people having a good time
around them and they want to just flip
over the game.
They want to say fuck you and burn the
whole thing to the ground.
There's always going to be people like
that.
There's a lot of that that you can see
people having a good time around and see
people that are happy that,
that are enjoying life.
Like especially if this kid felt
alienated in school and bullied and cast
out and targeted and then he gets free
and he sees these people that are having
fun.
He just wants to go back and just punish
everyone.
This is a very common theme,
you know,
people,
how do we pain that theme?
How do we help people who are in pain?
We are going to have to do a lot of
things right?
Because like,
think of the people that uh,
had their children locked up.
Who are these monsters and how'd they
have a kid?
How was it so hard to get a car license?
It's,
and it's easy as fuck to have a kid and
raise another member of our culture,
of our society,
our community.
How's that possible?
You've,
you've introduced a poison and toxic
member to our community cause you did a
terrible job of raising them.
And one of the oldest ones,
I went to college and then they would,
I can't remember.
I think it was a dude would come out and
the mom would be waiting for him and
like,
so the oldest one was out in the world
and still no one could help.
Like whatever,
mind mallards they had,
this one was out and he didn't say that
his younger brothers and sisters were
locked up.
I had gas.
Oh God,
he should be in jail.
Yeah.
I don't know the whole,
the details of that.
I mean it's,
I guess it's not his fault.
He's probably what?
Beyond fucked in the head,
but just the fact that he could keep
that a secret.
It's like what?
It's horrific and you and you just think
about,
I mean,
how many people are fucked by the time
they have children?
Like it's not even that they're doing a
bad job of it.
They're incapable of doing a good job of
it there too fucked up there,
too fucked up from their own upbringing.
But they still get horny.
I mean,
does this as is what happens in this
world?
People like to have sex.
They have saks boone,
there's a person got a raise it,
but I'm fucked up and I love math.
What do you do in men?
Mra?
Yeah,
it's fucking men.
It's everybody.
It's definitely men though and that's,
that's my issue with all this.
A masculine bullshit is a lot of these
guys that are proclaiming masculinity or
really bitches and that the,
that real men wouldn't be doing this
stuff in the first place.
You would look past most of this stuff
in the first place.
You know,
there's a lot of people in this world
that don't have personal sovereignty,
whether it's men or women and they're
not,
they're not raised correctly and then
they didn't go on a beneficial path
through life that left them in the
current state,
whether they're a helpful member of our
community.
That's the show about family values.
That's what you're really about.
It is about community values,
life,
friendship.
You know like what we were talking
about,
the comedy store,
friendships giant.
It's very important and some people
don't have any fucking friends and
that's a dark place to be bullied.
You're whole life.
Don't have any friends.
You're on medication,
you're all fucked up and you're one of
those guys out there that just wants to
go out with a bang,
you know,
just want to walk into a mall with a
fucking shotgun and go out with a bang.
There's a lot of people that think like
that.
They just don't have the courage to do
it.
I mean,
even going back to that one night that
we,
when I said I don't know if I can do it,
I mean it's a smaller example,
but,
but still valid,
you know,
and you just looked at me and said,
you can your guide,
like you're doing it or you know,
whatever you're responsible as those
little moments of like,
those are big,
a real connection.
Yeah.
When you know someone really does care
about you and someone who really does
like you and we're not,
you know,
talking every day.
It was just a moment of and commonality
and seeing that other person,
we fixed it,
everybody and we fixed it.
We did it well.
I never had
never knew that you didn't think well of
me or,
or I did.
Yeah.
I never felt like he didn't like him
sedated by you and I didn't I,
well I didn't know you,
but I just like your vibe to me was
like,
oh,
like he doesn't like me very much.
But that wasn't because of anything
years ago though,
this is probably would have been 2000
whatever.
Right,
right.
But it was never anything where like I
didn't like you.
I'm sure I probably was not even really
on your radar or not even a thing.
I'm not liking or liking that.
I know we never really had any
interactions.
No,
I just felt your power took it first.
Personally.
I felt your power.
That's pretty silly.
Well we got through that too.
Yeah,
we did.
So if you do a special,
yeah.
When you think you'd be gearing up for
that,
have you thought through it?
Like to be ready in a year?
We were ready in a month.
Oh my gosh.
Too much.
No,
it was the bed.
Or has that been mad?
Um,
nap,
nap.
I have to figure out,
cause so many comics I know do it
themselves.
Yeah.
I think I could have the material I want
fairly like within the next six months,
but then I need to figure out the how,
the,
how
how.
There's a few companies that do you need
to make,
I need to make it first.
Right?
That's how you do it.
Yeah.
Just make it,
yeah,
that's not a bad move.
The just making it first is not a bad
mood because when you just make it
first,
then you could just sort of sell it
somewhere.
And if it's good,
everybody is always looking for new
comedy.
You know,
there's,
we were just talking earlier about the
Amazon.
I heard a
little bit of scare because I had teed
up for it when I first went on the road
and had had an hour.
And then,
um,
my manager at the time,
I think tried to sell it on a high
level.
This was before Netflix is what it is
now.
It was a few years back when they were
first started doing hours,
I think.
Um,
and they were like,
no.
And then she,
you know,
all,
all the top tier people were like,
no.
Like,
no one knows her as a comic,
like we're not buying it.
And then she was like,
let me sell it at the second tier.
And they're like,
no.
And then this whole time I was like,
you should have just done it myself.
But I think I've been lucky enough to
have get a lot of acting jobs.
So whenever I'm like being myself
starter and then a carrot comes along,
I'm like,
Oh,
do that acting job.
That'll work.
So,
so I've never had to sort of grind it
out in that way.
And that's why it scares me.
So then at the,
when it didn't sell at that time I just
went,
oh,
I should have done that myself and now
I'm tired of this material.
And then,
you know,
time passes.
I'm like,
maybe it's
for the best because you know,
once I do that,
then I'm really out there as that.
It might be a commitment issue on my
part.
I know that film.
I know what you mean.
It's just hard.
It's hard to just fucking dig your heels
in,
decide to do something that's tough like
that.
And then also the financial investment
if you decide to do it yourself.
Yeah.
Like you got to spend a lot of money and
hire crude.
Make sure the director doesn't fuck it
up and make sure it all comes out well.
You know who do I know the did one and
they fucked up the shooting of it and he
had a wind up putting it online.
Was it rory Albany's did.
He said that he did one that someone
fucked up and he wound up putting it
online or he hasn't released his,
yeah,
he was thinking about doing it soon
sound my throws him somebody else then
Kurt Metzger.
Hm.
Whatever.
Yeah,
someone funny.
Did you do yours yourself?
I did one of them myself.
Yeah,
I've done two of them.
Two of them myself.
Yeah.
Um,
but the best was last year doing it with
Netflix.
That was the best because they're just
so easy.
They just like,
go ahead.
They used to let you do it.
They're like,
we like it.
Yay.
That's awesome.
There was zero feedback,
you know,
they just wanted to make sure it was an
hour long.
Not too long.
Not too short.
I kind of want to do a 15 minute special
cause I have this thing that I've done
for years and I don't do it every very
often,
but it's a in a throw down.
It's like,
hey guys,
take a hey guys,
take a break.
Hey ladies,
fucking guys.
Am I right ladies?
Take a break.
What's up with these bitches?
But like 15 minutes like bitches and
they're scented candles.
They're always like,
smell this,
try these sheets.
Uh Guys,
take a break.
Ladies,
give us a ring if you want to be that.
That's funny.
I like it.
15 minutes.
So that's just something they're doing
now,
right?
That's what I heard.
Yeah.
No,
I'd love to do an hour for sure.
But that's more of a commitment to
things and ideas that you wanted to have
some girth to.
Well,
you could definitely do it,
but we were also talking about how
Amazon's doing specials now too.
They did Bob Saget special and they ere,
they bought a bunch of other people
specials that they bought.
Brian counts special,
they bought all those specialists.
And so all those specials are now on
Amazon.
A lot of places for you that's pretty
swollen.
Just do it is what you're saying.
Sure.
Yeah.
The only terrifying thing is once you do
it then you have to write new material.
That's where it gets scary because then
you're doing,
you're left without weapons.
He started from scratch and you've got
to grind and dig,
claw your way back up to the top of the
hill.
Oh okay.
He never done that before.
Huh?
Especial.
Most special when you have to abandon
all the materials and start from
scratch.
Now as you were saying that,
I was thinking,
cause I've done one woman shows I've
done but I'm still pulling from like
that show cause it's,
you know,
if it's
stuff that I still like I'll pull it up.
I have stuff about,
you know,
my son being an infant and he's nine
years old.
I still talking about my csection if
it's late at the comedy store,
I'm like let's get into it cause I know
they don't want to hear it.
I'm like let me,
let's talk about it.
It's 1:00 AM with second with a c
section.
Those are strength training.
That's like running with weights on like
a weight vest,
weights on your back and like a ankle
weights too.
I've learned to really love him.
It took me so long to just even leave
the house.
I would,
I would be standing there at the comedy
store.
Like I had to train myself to be like,
no,
this is part of it.
You have to be awake,
you have to want to be here.
Yeah.
It was a weird psychological,
cause I'm part of me is like just want
to do my set,
but then I'm like resenting that I'm out
of the house.
Like I come some sort of princess or
something.
How dare.
It's like,
no,
you made this choice.
You want it.
But connecting the want with what it is.
I don't know.
I mean I've talked to other people who
are like,
oh,
like,
well don't do midnight shows,
you know.
But,
but clearly I wanted it and I wanted it
at the comedy store and once I got used
to it,
I was like,
this is the best.
Like,
I love doing those late spots.
Not that I wouldn't mind an 8:00 PM
shot,
and my slot.
Nitrile it makes you talk and I'm only,
I didn't even get halfway through.
I'm taking it easy.
Well then you were about 135 milligrams
caffeine and it's good.
It's not bad.
Right.
And it's really good.
Espresso.
Do you drink that kind of stuff?
Yes.
Black coffee.
Yeah.
I'll go.
I go both ways.
Wrong.
I like a latte.
Vanilla sweetener and shit.
No,
not sure.
no,
no.
Like a straight up nonfat.
I'll do it all.
I'll drink a vanilla latte.
I won't turn my nose at it.
I'll do a shot of a sham.
So yeah,
it's all yummy.
Yeah.
You're um,
you're kind of on a path of self
improvement through comedy.
Do you realize that?
I like that because it seems like it,
right?
Yeah.
Like if you seem like a more empowered
by this I,
I definitely am.
Yeah,
that's true,
isn't it?
It is.
It's,
it's helping me.
He said so reluctantly.
So decision,
a strange thing.
Well,
it's what it is,
is you're fighting your alt roots.
So it is,
you're fighting the smugness and the
sarcasm.
You're fighting it.
Fighting sincerity.
Like Saturday self improvement coach,
is that what I'm doing?
Sure.
I'm like,
ah,
if I could just get on a pilot that I
back to
work anymore.
No commitment.
This is a zone out.
You're not even there.
You know?
And he like,
you do your best,
but Simon,
you're writing whatever.
So what's easier,
so much easier for no good sitcoms.
Dropping some logic.
When I was on news radio when it was
trading on a pilot,
so about yeah,
go on.
When it was smooth,
so easy to show up script.
Good.
Got a couple good lines.
Remember him,
deliver him,
sit in the makeup chair puts what's
wrong with that?
Boom.
Nothing wrong with someone's bringing
you a drink.
It doesn't feel as good.
It's not as good problems.
You already killed Mary Lynn.
You've already crossed over into the
dark lands.
Ah,
okay.
When you kill like Saturday night on the
road and you're fucking crushing,
right?
When you put it all together and you
remember those dark days and you first
started doing it again,
now you're killing.
Yeah.
How good's that feel?
It feels great.
It's amazing.
But then I will it all chip away.
Like,
how long will I let that feel great?
You know,
maybe double the next morning and then,
uh,
then it starts all over again and then
you got to do it again.
Yeah.
I have to.
That's how,
that's the thing.
There's never a point where like,
oh,
I made it.
Let me sit down.
There's no,
that doesn't,
that place doesn't exist.
Okay.
Well,
he always have the bed,
Delaware,
you can always take those down.
Is there,
you can always enjoy those naps.
Ah,
a pillow is always there.
He got now with all your shots,
the cat can crawl in bed with you.
No problem.
Okay.
I mean,
I still have a lot of fear with even
last night we,
how was your,
uh,
your standup on the spot?
It was great.
I loved it so much.
I spent the entire day going,
why did I do this?
I'm not clever enough.
Like I can't think of jokes.
I'm like,
just say the opposite.
Just get angry.
Go on around like I'm coming up with all
devices because I'm like,
you won't,
you won't write a joke on the spot.
You don't know how to write.
Your brain doesn't work like that.
Oh,
like a crazy person.
A nightmare.
A living nightmare.
I spent the day going,
Oh really?
Oh,
you're going to just come up with Joe
because on the spot,
like good luck with that.
The voice in my head,
once I got there,
it was delightful.
It was like,
oh,
this is my real life.
This isn't the life in my head.
Yeah.
It was a delight.
I had to call my friend afterwards and
go,
I think I just experienced pleasure.
I hate to say this,
but that was
shareable.
Well,
that room in particular that that set
for people don't stand up on the spot.
As Jeremiah Watkins show,
he used to have a show called
Thunderpussy I guess.
Oh really?
Yeah.
That was the same show,
but they called it thunderpussy for some
reason.
Uh,
now,
um,
what you do is you go on stage and uh,
people just have suggestions like I met,
I make people put their hands up,
I point to someone and then they give
you a suggestion and right away you just
start talking about it.
And I have some real potential leads for
bits from last night,
like two solid ones where I,
what I do is I don't want to,
but I do when I get home,
I'm fucking tired.
I've had a long day,
but it's still sit in front of the
computer and I play the recordings and I
go back.
I have to have to,
it's part of the job.
Have to clean your room.
It's like those things like got to brush
your teeth.
I don't want him to go to sleep
pressure.
Fucking teeth got to do it.
And so I'm sure this is fairly normal.
How many sets I have in my phone that
I've never listened to.
Yeah,
it's really normal.
Um,
I listened to the mall.
You have to,
that's the only time.
I don't listen to the malls when I'm on
the road,
I'm doing four sets.
Erase it after.
No,
you save it.
I'll show you.
I got all these bitches in here and
you've listened to all of them and they
stay there.
Look at them all.
How do you know which one to go back to
for stuff?
I don't really mark them.
I edit the name.
See at the bottom.
That's good.
Yeah.
But then you won't know how do you
remember which bit in this one?
You just kind of just record it and I go
over it with a notebook.
But the thing with me as the big thing
is,
um,
I know when something happened,
like if I do a sat and I'm like okay,
I went on a totally different chain of
thought.
Yes.
And this,
if this branch of the bit might be a new
bit,
I have to listen to that bit again.
And so I'll clearly go over there and
make sure that your common sense,
but it's so hard to do.
Yeah.
You're giving me the training right now
of this stuff that's like,
obviously you remember when you went off
on that thing,
go back and listen to it and write it
down.
Think about the things that you've said
today that have helped you,
right?
Like how you've had to speak clearly,
do all these things and what did that
come from?
Well that come from,
that comes from trial and error and
focus like you're focusing on your act
because of that.
That next level of focusing on your act
is being like super diligent about
recordings and writing and that's what a
lot of comics don't do it.
There's a lot of comics that think
they're grinding and they'll say that
I'm out there,
I'm doing a lot of sets.
They're not writing any new material
though.
You can't.
You have to write.
You have to actually write.
That's what I believe.
Maybe maybe you can just write all on
stage because you can trick yourself
into thinking that you're grinding it
out and maybe you are doing a lot of
sets and maybe doing the same set.
You're doing it differently so you can
and that's it.
That's fine.
That's its own thing.
But you're not going to come up with new
staff from that.
You're doing something,
but are you doing like everything you
could be doing?
It's like it's like anything else.
The more time and enthusiasm you put on
something,
the better you're going to get at it.
If you're a guy like save your bowler
and you only like the bowl 40 minutes a
day,
but you want to be the best in the
world,
turn not gunna be,
I don't care what you want,
but the time and enthusiasm is that
tricky part that goes back to like
discipline.
Well also I was trying to make a bigger
jump,
which is how do you connect to being
enthusiastic?
If you don't,
we'll think about how you were bummed
out about your set,
right?
And you got to the store and you had a
trick your brain into being more present
and more pumped up for your set.
Right.
And then when you did it was a joy.
I guess I'm trying to connect it to what
we were talking about earlier about
people who get isolated and don't have
friends and don't have a feedback and
don't have those like tendrils of like
being able to make that leap so that,
you know,
you start like eating yourself alive and
well,
I think with everything,
it's like a little stuff climb out of
the barrel,
right?
If you're 300 pounds,
do not run a marathon,
right?
Walk around the block.
And if you're a person who's been living
your life with a bunch of fucking
negative thinking in your head,
take steps in the right direction,
you know,
take a step back and you have to
acknowledge that step today.
I mean,
I remember that.
I need to remember it and I need to
build on that,
you know?
And you can do that.
Anybody can do that.
You could just do it incrementally.
I had a great podcast with this guy,
David Goggins.
Did you ever heard of him?
So,
um,
he's a navy seal who's also a famous
tech podcast,
but yes,
yes.
I heard a bit of that.
And he was talking about how,
you know,
he was a fat loser who kept making
excuses for himself and just like
drinking chocolate milkshakes every day
working for an exterminator and he was
fat as fuck.
And they just decided I don't want to do
this any more.
And he had these moments where he went,
he went running,
he ran three quarters of a mile,
then he turned around and walked back
home.
That was his first time running.
Like it wasn't quick that it became,
this guy runs a hundred miles at a time
and he was doing,
how many fucking a hundred milers did he
do in a year?
Wasn't it crazy every week or every
other week or every month?
It was insane because when he played it
for,
he showed us the website and he was
like,
these are all the ones he did in a year.
And it's like,
what the fuck?
Like every week or two weeks he was
running a hundred miles like in the
mountains and shit.
A hundred that's a 24 hour race.
Yeah.
And he was doing it every week.
That's fucking insane.
But this guy started out running three
quarters of a mile and then he quit and
turned around and walk back home cause
he was fat and he's eating milkshakes
every day.
Like that's the same guy he be.
He with these little incremental steps
and then just deciding this is who I am
now.
I'm a guy who does what I say I'm
supposed to do and I'm fucking serious.
I'm going to change my life.
I always shredded just guys a fucking
animal.
I mean he's just a pure a machine made
out of like motivation and discipline.
Like you don't get more disciplined than
I am now,
but he wasn't at one point in time in
his life and by him expressing that on
the podcast and it's really
inspirational podcasts.
I think it gives everybody hope cause
you like to think that,
oh that guy who is really good at this
thing or that guy was really mentally
tough or this girl who's super
disciplined who just get accomplishes
thing
after thing.
She's always been like that,
don't,
no,
no.
She's,
nobody's always had been like that.
No one has you.
You start off fucking up,
you fail,
you move up,
you figure it out,
you make some mistakes,
you fall back,
you get back up,
you go,
well,
that's not me.
I'm me now.
I realized,
don't do that anymore.
Now instead,
don't quit after three quarters of a
mile.
Now we're going to drink water instead
of drinking chocolate shakes,
we're going to eat healthy food and
tomorrow we're going to do a whole
fucking mile.
Let's do it.
And then you do that mine like,
Holy Shit,
I did it.
Mark it down,
write it down,
did a mile,
and then maybe take a day off and then
maybe the next day tried to do it again
and then build with everything with
comedy,
with fucking,
I'm sure that's the case with music,
with everything,
right?
And to recognize that that's your
choice.
And I think of myself,
there are some mornings where I'm like,
I'm gonna sit and have a latte.
And you know,
now there are mornings where I'm in a
workout.
Those are all my choices.
Maybe that one day you're going to be
that person that just kind of sits there
and stares out the window.
Um,
you know,
that would not be work towards my
hundred miles that I'm trying to run.
That would put,
it might be a day where you daydream,
he'd come up with an amazing idea and I
kind of loved that.
I spent the day leading up to that
standup on the spot.
Actually I thought we had our podcast
was yesterday.
I had to go back into my text and I kind
of like,
you know how you do when you like have
something to do at one so that I get 11
you're like,
well I can't completely go do something
else.
So I kinda just agonized.
And then it was like 12 and I loved and
I was like,
oh,
it's not even today.
So now I like kind of like,
you know,
didn't do stuff.
I could have done it for a couple hours
and now you know,
I thought we were podcasting,
so now I have all that time.
So I'm just like,
well,
have that stand up on the spot show
tonight.
So I really was just looking down.
You go [inaudible] if worked out.
Yeah,
but this lady here she is.
Who Was it?
Pretty girl?
Uh,
yeah,
so I weirdly,
but it was kind of a productive day
because then when I got to the end and
was so appreciative,
it made me so aware of the nightmare of
my own head that I was the,
I was very conscious of what I,
what I was doing.
That got me to that.
Then when it was so easy,
it really was like waking up from a bad
dream when you're like,
oh,
this is life.
It's not that being engaged and being
present and going to do this thing.
It was nothing like what I was beating
myself up.
Like,
why are you doing that?
What is that?
Why you say you've done so many shows?
But I wasn't even acknowledging that
history.
I was just stewing in almost because I
had the time and I just let that run
rampant in my head.
That voice of like,
Oh really?
You think you,
you think you can construct a joke?
Good luck.
You know why?
Right?
Why did I just feed that monster?
Yeah.
It's just a common strategy that people
do to avoid accomplishing things.
Right.
And you do it subconsciously to give
yourself a little bit of a break because
the pressure of like being disciplined
and doing things,
it's hard.
It weighs on you.
Right.
So then that becomes an excuse to not,
we were talking before the podcast about
yoga and I was saying how,
um,
when I did that 15 days in a month
thing,
I decided to end it with nine days in a
row.
So I just did nine days.
He,
I ended like a week early.
I finished like a week earlier,
like five days early,
but I did nine fucking days of yoga in a
row to end it.
And I was like,
this is crazy.
I never would've thought,
not only that I could do it,
I mean I know I could physically do it.
It's not impossible,
but I didn't think I'd ever like fall
through and do that.
It just seems too extreme.
And that was the beaker him that the
half.
Yeah.
Which people are like,
Ooh,
I do it everyday.
I did 60 days in a row.
Yeah.
But I do like eight other things.
It's not easy to carve out an hour and a
half a fucking swinging dick off in this
workout.
Oh yeah.
I'm still,
I'm still lifting weights.
Yeah.
I'm still doing that too.
I'm not just doing yoga and I'm also
doing writing and the podcast and
whatever.
UFC shouldn't have to do.
Like I made myself do it too.
But in doing so,
I realized like,
Oh,
you just got to just do it.
Like you just got to say you're going to
do it and just do it.
Like I did a thing a while back in like
2009,
but when I was writing,
um,
I was up getting ready to do a,
my comedy central special at the time,
or it was on spike tv than uncommon
central.
I,
um,
I wrote every day for a month in my,
in my blog.
I just decided I'm gonna and I committed
to it online.
I said,
I'm gonna write every day for a month.
And in doing that,
I'm like,
oh,
I could do that.
Like you just got to do.
Let's,
uh,
let's,
it has to be just a thing you do.
Like,
oh,
I brushed my teeth.
Oh,
I comb my hair.
I right.
Oh,
I get up and I run an while.
I get up and I lift weights for an hour
or whatever the fuck it is.
Did the or did that yoga tip you one way
or the other?
Like make you more thirsty or more like
tired or more in the day?
Yeah,
it definitely makes you thirsty.
He fucking does.
I sweat so much.
I can be like,
I couldn't drink coffee.
I just was like,
I need oranges and water and lemons and
oranges and water when you sweat so
much.
But does that,
did that affect your other workout that
you do?
Like was your body just like stop?
No.
Drink a bunch of water?
No,
I mean it's,
it's easier because,
um,
if I was going to do the yoga,
I would,
uh,
I would just do stuff like lifting
weights or something that night and
lifting weights is,
um,
as opposed to running.
Yeah.
Sometimes I'd run,
I'd do.
I'd like to run though in the morning
and do yoga later.
Like maybe I'll run at eight and then do
yoga at 10 30 I've done that because
it's not a cardio thing really.
You know yoga and also like I like doing
yoga and my legs are burnt out cause
then like I'd get more flexibility out
of them.
I feel like your tissues get really beat
up and then they become more pliable.
If you could just force past that little
pain barrier,
you know?
I really like lifting weights and then
going to yoga is amazing if you do like
squats and stuff like that because your
legs get like super warmed up and it
just feels like they're exhausted and
you just kind of pull that tissue a
partier.
Yeah.
Yes,
yes.
Hashtag yes.
Hashtag fuck yeah.
All right Marilyn,
should we wrap this up?
Yeah,
I'm glad we did.
It shows you it again.
We should do this again.
Yeah,
I would love to have you on.
Have you thought about doing one of your
own?
Oh my gosh.
I'm going to leave here today going,
I got a podcast.
I've got a special on it.
Doing Yoga twice a day.
You should do a podcast for sure.
You could do it.
I would like to,
was talking about the second time you
come back.
Okay.
Thanks.
You good?
Bye.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Goodbye.
Got It.
Okay.