Hello Rick,
we'll talk to you when you're surviving
animal food in plastic and then eat it
and then poop it out and eat it later.
Like I'm take the plastic off and eat
it.
Jesus Christ.
It seems like it could work.
That's a technique I've never thought.
I mean if you're going to be like on
your own for five days,
you can eat a bunch of food but wrap it
up in plastic and then later poop it
out.
Then untaken out with.
Then how would you get the nutrients
from the food in the first place with
your stomach and a piece of plywood is
this poop it out.
I don't understand it.
And then you poop it out and like before
you leave for your trip,
go to and go get stuffed like Boston
market or something.
Conversation.
Don't ruin this when you're poorly
thought out ideas and they get a bunch
of plastic.
Don't tell him stop.
Can't,
can't tell you how to eat his poop.
No,
no,
no.
I'm saying like eat like on big meal
before you were about to leave.
He would eat his own food.
It's called the things called second
harvest and then native American maybe
take a bunch of like protein bars,
wrapped them up in plastic,
eat it,
and then poop it out in a couple of
days.
Then unwrap the plastic they need what
kind of shit you really think a fucking
whole protein bar in plastic can make it
through your digestive tract and carry
the bars in my backpack and just eat
them three days later,
poorest understanding of the human
digestive tract ever exhibited on a
podcast.
I was trying to figure out what you were
saying.
I thought you were saying eating poop.
You're not talking about a little Baggie
of heroin that a drug.
I was thinking like,
we're going to make you survive.
You'll.
You'll get another hour's worth of
energy from that little heroin bag.
What about Petite Finlaison?
Eight ounces wrapped in plastic.
You're going to die.
People get diverticulitis because they
get a fucking watermelon seed.
Freaking word diverticulitis,
she says signifies word.
Well,
Brock Lesnar for the UFC got diverted
because I had a serious operation when
they removed 12 inches of his colon.
Found out about it.
I looked into it and I thought it was
just because of eating meat,
but Anthony Bourdain and informed me
that you can eat a seed,
like you get like a sunflower seeds or
something stuck inside your tract,
your digestive tract,
and it starts an abscess and you get
sick.
Yeah,
you could.
You can die from a fucking seed getting
stuck.
He's like all kinds of stuff gets stuck
in there,
so it's not necessarily just protein.
There's also contributed to the game is
like a Gi track.
Dr. Now you can't eat a petite filet
minion should it out in the woods.
That's all I'm saying.
You gotta have to have a better strategy
than ever.
I guess I was thinking survivor island,
like trying to find a way to cheat.
You can't.
You can't carry it in your backpack.
You'll know you're pregnant if you had
enough food for a day,
all the food backed up with your body.
What can a calorie consumption are you
thinking you have to have.