And
An action,
ladies and gentlemen,
your response to your complaints about
the horrible audio quality.
We figured it all out.
Folks.
We have,
um,
first of all,
we have these mics that you have to
hold.
We're going to hold them this week.
Next week we're gonna.
Have these little clip on things,
but we have a mixer now and we're
listening to headphones and we
understand your complaints.
See the problem was these things,
these microphones were in stands and
they were over here and it makes a huge
fucking difference how it sounds here
and here.
So me,
buddy,
to fellow,
someone always has the laptop on volume
on.
But uh,
we're live and uh,
was that,
it's not me fella to.
Oh,
it's my other computer.
We had two computers that were on.
Hold on one second.
Yeah.
So how's it sounding guys that are in
there?
It should be nice and loud.
I would imagine.
Much,
much better.
Okay,
we're back.
Sorry.
Sorry for everything being retarded.
I'm drinking coffee that came out of an
animal's ass.
Oh,
that's one of those ones where they
filter it through something.
It's called a Kopi Luwak.
That's the name of the coffee and um,
there's a,
an animal called a palm civet and this
animal eats these coffee beans,
eats the bean itself,
you know,
like what it looks like,
a little fruit.
Shits it out and then they take them and
clean them.
I guess hopefully they cleaned them and
then they make coffee out of it and it's
smoother coffee.
It's like a,
like a different sort of a different
flavor to it because they went through
this animal's digestive tract now.
Now if the animal ate a lot of berries
and stuff as it have,
like hints of other different things in
it,
you know,
it doesn't,
it just tastes like coffee.
I mean it's,
it's really kind of gross when you think
about it.
But I was curious.
I had it once before.
Remember tate nine.
We're in Florida and they had it at a
restaurant and I,
I'd heard about it.
So we tried it out.
Apparently it's the,
whatever the stomach acids or whatever
it is inside the civets body changes the
actual chemical structure of the coffee
and it just makes it much smoother and
it's okay.
You know what I mean?
It's not really.
It's the price.
A lot more expensive.
Yeah.
It's super expensive.
It's way more expensive than regular
coffee.
Yeah.
Way more than.
I remember the restaurant was like $90
or something stupid like that.
Yeah.
Animal.
But how's it?
How's it sounding for everyone?
What's the people saying?
Oh,
I think it sounded good.
I think we're golden with this thing.
This,
this shit is so much louder.
Cool.
Yeah,
it's way,
way,
way better.
So,
um,
anyway,
sponsored by fleshlight.
By the way,
I haven't talk that it's sponsored
by poor.
Sponsored by a rubber vagina.
Yeah.
Do you ever fuck the asshole and.
No,
no,
no.
I don't think that's necessarily.
Well,
it's just tighter.
It might feel good.
It doesn't have to be fleshlight tight
enough.
Yeah,
I think it's good.
And think you need the butthole one
unless you're just a freak and your wife
will let you have the butthole.
You can have a rubber butthole,
you know,
she should be happy.
You get your butthole fantasies out of
the way.
Did you know about the bottom?
Uh,
that it unscrews and it's like a suction
because like,
I didn't know the first time I fucked
it,
it was like this really suction like
crazy blow job and it was just too much,
too intense.
Couldn't take it because Brian's got a
giant hog is hitting the back.
Brian's got a fucking oatmeal quaker
oats box.
That's his dick.
I unscrewed it and I guess that adds air
to it and makes it a lot better.
So you get the fuck a slut.
Yeah.
So it's either a girl or a slut or a big
giant slot.
Right.
And by the way,
it was awesome.
I fucking love it was crazy though,
is that at first I started out putting a
bunch of juice in it and it was a juice
or whatever that oil is the loop.
I'm like,
what are you fucking oranges and shit.
I wasn't that impressed.
I was like,
all right,
this is just too much,
you know,
this is like fucking bitch.
And then you took the lube down,
took it down a notch and now it's
fucking fantastic.
So you have a formula they use.
How many courts will loop?
Just a teeny bit around the lips of it.
Really.
That's it.
Just that their water party started
right?
Spit on it.
If you're feeling dirty,
fucking whore horn the ticket right back
on there.
No,
but you know,
I tried warming it up in the microwave.
And you're not supposed to do that
already.
No,
no,
no.
The juice or the liquid stuff.
I'd put it in a cup.
It was like get a melted and stick your
Dick in there.
It's gonna fucking fuse to your Dick.
That hot molten plastic.
And you'd be screaming.
Third Degree Burns all over your Dick.
Could you imagine somebody must have
somebody must have nuked something.
Got It.
Too Hot.
Fuck it.
And ruin their deck.
That's happened.
Totally.
If you thought about it,
it's happened.
You know.
So like I was saying,
I put this picture up on my twitter the
other day.
Somebody,
somebody sent me this twitter.
Hey Joe,
have you ever seen a triangle like this
before?
So I click on it,
you know,
thinking that it's probably a guy caught
somebody in a triangle.
Well,
it Sorta,
what it is is this site called
[inaudible] dot com.
Do you know that site?
It's a site that is dedicated to all.
It's all white guys like nerdy white
guys and they're making these black
ghetto,
cigs gagged from fucking their mouths.
And so I tuned into this picture.
I clicked this link.
This guy sends me and it says white
nerdy dude with these pale skinny white
legs with black socks and black sneakers
on and he's got to know arm triangle
like this around this chick's head.
This chick's head is like right here.
And she's,
you know,
he's shoving his dick in her mouth with
his triangle and she's like literally
throwing up all over his balls and his
asshole.
And I'm like,
he said so much to me though that what
kind of a strange world do we live in
where it's so normal to just click a
link and it takes you to a guy stuff in
his dick into some chick's mouth and
she's throwing up all over his balls and
asshole.
And all I do is giggle.
All I do is go,
ah,
you got me a fuck.
You know what I'm saying?
I mean if this was just 10 or 20 years
ago,
that picture would fucking freak you
out.
There was no pictures like that.
You could net.
When I was in high school,
the most you got is like hustler where
they spread their pussy lips apart.
You're like,
wow,
there's pitches crazy,
dirty,
like they weren't even allowed to show
penetration.
They would show like a guy,
they would have like a sex scene and the
guy would be like grabbing his dick to
try to keep it hard and looking at her
and it would look totally fake and posed
and it didn't look like real sex at all.
They,
you know,
it was hard to find pictures of,
of fucked up things.
But now what's,
what's the link with the website?
Ghetto gaggers,
ghetto ghetto.
If you just go to twitter.com/Joe
Rogan and look at my past tweets,
you'll find that a few days ago,
I forgot how many days ago it was,
but this motherfucker got me with this
picture and it's just so crazy that that
it's so easy to find images like that.
There's so many out there.
Kids today,
dude,
they're growing up in a totally
different fucking world.
A world where you can click a link.
I mean how many kids subscribed to my
twitter,
how many kids click that link and went
to that guy stuffing his dick in that
ghetto girls mouth and she's throwing up
all of it's not fair and I wonder if
it's like.
Because I mean I,
I got off it like sears catalog,
looking at underwear ads and stuff like
that and now you can just see the inside
of a girl's asshole.
You know,
anytime you.
I used to be able to beat off to like a,
like a,
like a workout,
like vhs cover,
you know like girl bent over trying to
look sexy and it used to be able to beat
off something like that.
Like you dirty bitch,
but now it's like peas dudes are
desensitized.
These kids are gonna grow up and not to
be able to get off unless like somebody
like goats sees them and like shits in
their face and stuff like that.
You know what I mean?
Cause they're starting.
Some people do get to like really crazy
points where the only thing that gets
them off it was like really fucked up
shit.
There's porn to the caterers.
Just to those dudes.
I told you about the time that tate nine
went to see a porno being taped.
We walked in,
we walked in.
This dude Salami that we stood Jujitsu
with,
great guy and he was a.
He was directed porn and I told him to
come on,
do this shot,
come by and check it out.
And all right,
we're,
we're on our way back from a Gig land at
the airport will go before we even go
home.
Let's go check out this can go to this.
Watch this dude's Bournville.
We walk in and there's this one guy
fucking this girl in the asshole and the
other guy's fucking this girl in the
mouth and they're spitting in her mouth.
Everyone's spitting her mouth,
both guys and the director and he was
like,
grab her by the hair of spit in her
mouth and this gal spitting her mouth.
I mean it was like,
it was fucking.
It was rough,
man.
The Guy,
the guy's fucking her in the
asshole and then he stuffs it in her
pussy and he goes,
yeah,
I'm an asshole to your pussy.
Hats.
Real fucking healthy.
Like whoa.
I remember like not porn is this.
I remember watching porn and then first
seeing how people spitting on the girl's
crotch before fucking in it.
So I tried it with my ex girlfriend back
in the day.
Did you just spit on my trunk?
I think I goofed on her crotch.
I didn't just say,
Oh,
I'm sorry.
There's something dudes like that.
When girl spit on Dick's,
they had lived those pornos with girls.
Spend a dick.
I'm like,
that's just showing me this like anger
there or something.
It's like craziness.
That's,
you don't need to spit on it and you
know,
you want to lick it and want to get it
all sloppy.
Wet.
That's all good.
You don't need to get crazy.
The worst is when they spit in a girl's
butt and it's like disappeared.
See little bubbles.
Shit.
Like come on.
People will never find the end.
There's no end.
You know,
it's just advancing and escalating and
it's the more exposure to this shit that
we have,
the more it desensitizes people to like
regular sex crows were taken in the ass
left and right now there's like reports
about it.
Like all these doctors are having
problems with girls having but VD,
they're shitting themselves by the age
of 30,
you know,
it's fucked up.
It's fucked up.
Get yourself a rubber butthole.
Fleshlight if you got that,
the whole thing inside you.
I tried to warm up the juice and uh,
so then I,
if I had to do the microwave thing,
I went into the bedroom,
put they put it and I didn't have a
boner anymore because I was like doing
like kitchen shit.
Then I had to like get myself hard again
by looking at some porn and then I went
over and the juice was not warm anymore
and it was just like,
ah.
So I,
I've reached a point in my life where if
my dick is not hard,
I'm not gonna even try to get it hard to
jerk off.
I do not set aside time to jerk off.
I don't like sit down and my Dick's not
hard to go jerk off and start rubbing
myself.
You've got to be born.
He didn't do it.
Now you've never done that?
Oh,
I have in the past for sure dude.
I've had days where I jerked off like
four and five times a day where you
just,
you don't even know why you're doing it.
It's like,
this doesn't even feel good anymore.
Like why do I keep doing this?
You're doing it just because you're
obsessed,
you know,
just because you got to a wacky bug,
and you just want to keep jerking off.
It relaxes me.
I,
you know,
it's like when you say,
when you talk about how you take a big
shit and then you're like,
I can't believe I had this shit.
Me.
That's how I feel like the sperm,
it's controlling me.
Know for sure.
But not when you do it five times for
one shot.
Yeah.
One day.
Even two shots that they might give you
a feeling crazy,
you know,
you,
you just got a text message from your ex
wife and she's having a hard time with
her husband and I know you think,
Gosh,
fuck this dirty,
but she didn't hate her and she took all
my money and just beat one off real
quick.
You know,
you might get a second one out of it.
It's exciting.
Right?
But other than that one is one a days.
All you need when you start jerking off
five times a day,
you're just a fucking Weirdo.
You know?
What do you do?
I used to get blisters on my dick from
jerking off too,
and I really would
just hold it another way.
I would figure out another way.
No,
on two separate occasions in my life I
jerked off so much that I developed like
a little sore spot on my,
so there's no way you could be enjoying
that.
Like why you jerking off that much
because you fucking crazy.
I mean that's what it is.
It's like you just get it in your head
that you have to check off.
When I used to fuck pillows,
what was so bad?
His accent ever used my hand.
I would fuck pillows.
The worst is watching my mom.
Like you draw so much when you're
talking about just go in the laundry
room and she's like taking off pillows,
sheets that we're sticking to it and you
just look at my pillow and it looked
like,
you know,
fucking has for sure.
Touched your loads.
Totally.
How does that feel?
I don't know.
I just can't believe.
How weird is that?
Your mom has touched your,
your semen?
Yeah.
Well she made it.
That's true.
It all came from her,
right?
She cooked it up inside of her.
It wasn't for her.
You wouldn't be alive.
You wouldn't have any sperm.
Totally.
And I just got a three d TV,
one of those new.
Uh,
yeah.
You were telling me about this and he
watched porn on this.
How does this work?
So explain to me,
this is what company makes this.
Just a Samsung TV.
It's because I saw Sony,
but Sony said it's not even out yet.
Tony's on out until the summer.
It was very impressive though,
right?
Yeah.
That Samsung.
What it does is it right.
I got a three d TV in a Red Blue Ray
player and it converts first.
You could watch anything on TV,
any show,
any TV and it will convert it into three
d if you want.
How the fuck does it do that?
It has like a smart technology where it
detects what a background is and what
the main character is in.
Tries to layer it.
And that's a really good job.
Actually.
I was so impressed.
I thought it was gonna be like bullshit.
But it was like I watched bill and Ted's
excellent adventure and it looked like
it was made for three days.
That's insane.
Yeah.
It's pretty crazy.
And you wear goggles A.
Yeah.
You were these little glasses and what
are they gonna fix that?
Well,
supposedly they were already invented
the technology to do it and when it
does,
it's like this great that goes over your
tv and it detects where you're sitting
in the room and it kind of like splits
the images up for you,
like from left and right eye and it
makes it three d,
but it's too expensive right now.
They said that in the next five to eight
years you'll start seeing it coming out
in it and then it will be integrated
into television and be a part of it.
Right.
And what's weird about it is that you
using the three d,
you immediately get it.
Like I get it,
like you're going to have a TV that's
going to be three dimensional soon where
it's going to look like you're a window,
but you're going to be able to kind of,
you know,
it's,
it's crazy when you,
when you start really getting it now
just tvs themselves are insane.
We're just so used to it.
The I just the idea of capturing image,
capturing any image and I mean you're
literally taking a snapshot of what's in
front of you and somehow or another you
can send that,
you can put it in you and you don't even
have to connect it to anything.
It goes from your phone and it can go to
the whole world.
You'll put it on flicker,
right?
And someone in Nicaragua
can look at it.
Not to mention that TVS are like this
skinny by the way.
Yeah.
And so pretty soon you're just going to
have a look at an IPAD 3d.
How nuts is that?
Those things will fucking crystal clear.
Those really awesome image and it's this
little skinny ass thing,
like a piece of paper,
you know,
it's like a couple pieces of cardboard
stack together,
right?
That's fucking nuts,
man.
Tvs today,
you know,
you go and look at these tvs and just
think about how long ago was that?
You know,
you have like this stupid looking like
rounded circles,
rounded edges on the corner and it was
big as fuck.
And you had to.
Everybody had to help you move it.
Did you have those new routines?
You remember what my grandmother used to
have,
like where it used to be a record player
on the top and then the speakers on that
side have been there.
It the.
Yeah,
and it was black and white and it was
tiny.
It was like fucking smaller than your
laptop.
It's a piece of furniture,
you know?
It was a coffee table that was super
long and that was just a lifetime ago.
I mean,
that's what my parents grew up with.
My parents grew up with that shit.
That Shit's bananas.
It is.
It's pretty fucking insane where
technology's headed,
but it's just as insane just thinking
about where it's gone.
You know,
if you ever wanted evidence of
evolution,
it's evolution seems to be a pattern
that everything follows.
You know,
people want to like get angry whether or
not evolution exists and whether or not
evolution is real.
And very few people even truly
understand the argument.
It's a very,
very,
very complex argument,
but the argument really isn't,
is there a god?
The argument is everything seems to
evolve.
Every single thing seems to change and
human beings are the clearest example
that just based on our culture,
if you look at just the shit that we
have now in comparison to the things we
had a few years ago and the movies,
if you like,
watch movies and listen to songs from
like the forties and the fifties and
then you listen to some new shit even if
you don't like most new shit or you
think it's stupid or you think it's that
the I,
I'm with you on all that,
but just the technical level that
they're able to like the kind of music
they're able to make now,
you know,
it's very,
very different.
It's incredibly powerful.
Like you might not be into pink,
listen to a Goddamn pink song and then
try to go back in time and listen to
some Jefferson airplane and shit and see
the,
like the,
how they recorded it.
Even if you love that song,
it's like they did a terrible job of
like putting it all together.
The evolution of music,
the evolution of television shows like
try watching father knows best.
Try watching any of those fucking stupid
movies from the fifties.
Those goddamn things are terrible.
They're terrible.
It's like everybody falls in love
immediately.
The bad guy.
Super obvious.
There's like everything happens.
It's so corny and phony and now you
know,
it's,
it's very clear that things are moving
in a certain direction,
but everything is not everything though.
Like when you go to a gas station and
you,
you prepay for like 20 bucks in that
last dollar takes down.
Why does it do that?
Because they want to make sure it
doesn't go over.
You think they need technology to fix
that because.
Because,
because when you do it yourself,
you could just turn it off like that and
then it's like three cents spam.
You know what I mean?
They don't want you to go over because
if you go over just a little bit and
everybody goes over just a little bit
and you add that little bit altogether,
it's probably millions of dollars,
but there should be a technology where
it just turns it off at this time.
Well really the problem is the real
technology issue is that this fucking
fuel issue,
the real technology is the gasoline
thing.
We need gasoline to make every single
thing on this earth and we need gasoline
to move.
No,
that's the real technological.
That's the hurdle.
The hurdle isn't your last dollar when
you're prepaying for gas.
The hurdle horses,
the real hurdle is the fucking oil,
you know,
that's frightened shit man.
Whether there things,
what my point was there is things that
you're just,
I'm amazed that,
that,
you know,
such things are so different from 20
years ago.
Other things like that,
it's just like,
come on gas pumps a.
well yeah,
I hear you,
but I don't think overall,
I don't think it's important for that.
There's no innovation as far as like the
fuel does that eventually they're gonna
have to come up with something new and
then when that happens then then,
then we'll,
we'll reach some new point where,
you know,
we're,
we have to abandon a gasoline entirely,
but they're going to have to make some
gigantic discoveries.
But that's so possible,
man.
People,
you know,
people don't even think about how
possible it is.
They could,
they could come up with some new way to
fucking make hydrogen tomorrow and it
would change everything you know,
or some other new type of new way of
making batteries that makes batteries
last longer.
They could figure out some weird shit
man.
And then instantly everything changes.
Yeah.
Battery technology is slow as fuck.
I mean Mac just released a new refresh
of their Mac book this week and it added
two or three more hours to the last
model.
So that's,
that's pretty good.
That's a big job but usually to do that,
but making the batteries larger and
making it so you can't pull them out.
Yeah.
But they didn't want this one.
No,
this is the same size.
I know what I mean.
They didn't change anything.
Yeah.
The new Mac books can get 10 hours
supposedly nine,
10 hours.
I have done this,
this 17 inch Mac book pro,
whatever it is,
but this thing doesn't get nearly as
much as they said if you're actually
using it.
I got this one which was last model.
You know,
and this gets,
it's supposed to get five hours.
I get two hours and this is a brand new
battery.
Yeah,
well it's like you have to like turn the
volume on the,
the brightness on a screen way down,
you know,
that saves a lot of it.
You can't be cranking volume,
you can't be watching movies if you used
Wifi,
eats it up if you have a cellular car to
eat it up,
but yet the ipad seems like you can do
all that and not even take a dent to
that.
Amazing.
That's what the battery.
What's up with that.
But that battery's crazy dude.
I use that battery for a whole weekend
and so it's like 50 percent.
I know they should just get like three
of those batteries and then when I'm in
a hotel dude I sit with that thing.
I'll get on the net and I don't do it
for hours,
you know,
I'll,
I'll read,
I'll even write some shit on there,
right?
Like little notes and then I look at it,
it's like 96 percent
battery liking that ipad by the way.
That's the future son.
The future is some new fucked up thing
that's even easy to transport around.
The Nat [inaudible].
That right now is the portable
typewriter.
The future.
You can totally know.
It really is.
It's God.
I miss typewriters.
Did you type?
Oh yeah.
I had to do it for school and you know,
you make a mistake and you have to like
take that white marker thing,
you know,
and go over it.
What a fucking pain in the ass it must
have been to write a book back.
Then you have to actually click,
click,
click.
That TV though,
has this,
uh,
that new Three d tv I got has this thing
called the 240 megahertz mode.
It's auto motion plus mode and it is the
most fucked up thing.
What it does is it,
it's so fast that it actually makes up
frames in between frames and what the
outcome is is awful.
It makes any show or any movie look
completely fake.
Like when you watch,
if you take titanic and if you sit there
with a movie camera and film titanic,
it looks like a movie because it's a
movie camera.
You'd take that same scene and record it
with a video camera.
It looks,
it would look fake and like kind of like
cheap.
And that's what this does though to
every show.
So you sit there and watched lost or
anything you get pissed off because it
looks like a soap opera.
Isn't that kind of weird that video,
like people that don't use video for
things and one of the reasons is because
it makes stuff look fake or make stuff.
Look,
it doesn't look as cool,
but what it means is it doesn't look as
good.
Yeah,
exactly.
It's not as clear an image.
It's fog,
it's not as foggy.
It's also that you can focus like in
film you can focus on the guys in the
foreground,
whereas video kind of just captures
everything.
Right.
And that's what this,
I guess this TV does is it takes each
frame and makes everything in focus.
So it makes everything seem really
phony.
Like like if you watch loss,
it looks like a soap opera from Mexico.
That's fucking crazy.
It ruins everything.
So I don't know why if Samsung made that
mode,
but now I want to make everything look
fake.
That sounds awesome.
It's,
it's pretty bad man.
It's want that though.
It sounds like it's what's great is
doing it and not telling somebody and
going,
dude,
what's your favorite movie?
Godfather.
Okay,
let's watch it.
Okay.
This doesn't seem as good as I remember
it.
Like it will make you free.
And he been godfather movies or any
movie.
So it's some sort of a software thing.
It's a,
it's a,
it's.
It just takes every frame.
Makes it a harder conversion.
Yeah.
It's a hardware into the TV.
So the TV is,
is actually making you can take an old
movie and it will add
frames to it and make the.
It makes it look,
it speeds it up to the point where it
adds extra frames.
It's kind of like a really fast monitor,
you know?
So it doesn't look fast or anything,
but it looks crisper and clearer and it
looks great.
Is fake.
How much time do you think there is
before they make movies?
Just completely artificial.
That looked like real movies where it's
like,
you know,
like a video game,
like video game style.
Like what was that one movie they did
where they did a whole movie.
Like that final fantasy.
Is that what is
a Scifi movie?
But it looked kind of fake,
you know,
kind of goofy fake now to right now it
looks stupid as fuck.
Right.
But back then it was like,
wow,
this is kind of impressive.
What they did not really good enough
though to warrant making a whole movie.
Right.
But how many more years it's going to go
by before they can make like Humphrey
bogart movies,
like make a fake Humphrey bogart movie,
recreate his voice,
recreate his intonations is,
you know,
that's gonna Happen,
right?
Yeah.
Oh I,
I think it's only a few years off to be
able to make porn with anybody.
They're going to be able to make any
Sarah Pailin.
Hillary Clinton are going to have
lesbian porn,
so I'm going to fuck each other and 50
each other.
That's gonna be a video game,
choose your character.
Obama looks so realistic,
but totally be unrealistic like it could
look exactly like hillary is just armpit
deep into Sarah Palin's pussy.
I mean you can make that splattering.
Just pussy juice all over the website,
splattering pussy juice all over the
wall when you could.
You're going to be able to recreate.
Beowulf is another one that someone just
said that.
Yeah,
it was terrible.
I like that movie.
It was all right,
but it didn't look real.
It didn't look real at all,
but it was cool.
It was a fun little fantasy movie.
I think they should have done the Lord
of the rings that way.
Actually,
the Lord of the rings like Gollum is
fake,
but everybody else was real.
It's like there's.
There was some fake shit there that was
hard to swallow even though they were
awesome movies.
Don't get me wrong.
I think it would have been cooler if the
whole movie was kind of fantasy.
I don't need real actors,
you know,
plus real actress look to human.
To me.
I want it to be fucking weird looking.
I want it to,
you know,
I don't want you to just be some dude
wearing like furry shoes that look like
feet,
but yet,
yeah,
I just watched that Alice in wonderland
last night and that,
that was actually kind of cool how they
took real characters,
but they distorted them.
They've made their head's bigger and
smaller.
It was cool.
Yeah.
The uh,
the main,
uh,
the queen of hearts.
Who was that lady?
What's that lady's name?
Halina.
Bottom corner.
She had the big giant fucking head.
That was pretty trippy.
I love that cat to cat was bad.
That was a movie to only go to see if
you're really high,
you know,
it wasn't,
it was okay.
It wasn't a good is not good now.
It was interesting because I was
barbecued.
I had a pot cookie like an hour before I
went to see that and moving.
So when I went to the movie I was just
was by the time to first frame started
to fell out full blown.
I was like just completely blown out.
So it's fascinating that the cat was
really interesting,
but like as a,
as a,
like a plot and everything.
I was like,
so you didn't give a shit.
They didn't give a fuck what happened?
I don't know.
But yeah,
getting really baked and watching your
favorite movie and get fucked up by that
motion plus thing.
You should check it out.
Little creepy lab.
Well I can't change my TV.
That seems really know that's what the
TV for back here.
Three d one.
I don't want to do it.
And,
but you know what's also cool about it
is how this TV is so connected to the
Internet.
Like I hit a button and it tells me like
Yahoo News,
my Gmail,
my flicker hit another button and I got
and Amazon video on demand all through
my TV remote.
Like it's.
Yeah,
mine does that.
My um,
my VCR VCR,
my DVD player can download.
Netflix can store things on Netflix,
it can stream things,
it can go to youtube and watch youtube
clips.
It's pretty crazy.
Yeah,
I like it.
it's the future.
So in the future is,
you know,
Shit like this,
I mean probably there's somebody right
now that can watch this,
there's probably some sort of an
application,
some sort of a way to watch this on your
actual TV.
Oh totally,
totally.
I mean you can do it on your iphone.
If this was a real TV show,
by the way,
I was watching here,
this would be called dead air and people
will be yelling at us.
It was boring as fuck right now son,
I was watching you guys last week on top
of a waterfall and it's so weird.
It's like I'm in the middle of nowhere
in Portland,
Oregon watching you on an iphone.
Did you do any math when you were out
there in Portland?
Oh no,
but tell you what man,
Portland,
Oregon.
I was in a costco and I always liked to
play this game when I'm out of town.
And I was like,
all right,
I have 15 minutes to find one person in
this store that I would,
I would fuck,
you know,
like I,
you get to fuck one person in the store,
who would it be?
And I could not find one person in that
store,
not even like a mediocre person until
right when I was walking out one of the
employees,
she looked like an la too.
And I was like,
okay,
I'll pick her because I have to pay to
fuck that one.
Wow.
Well,
you maybe you have really high
standards.
No,
no.
I mean it's.
Every single person in Portland is fat.
They're,
uh,
they looked very depressed and sad.
Uh,
they,
they just.
And again,
I guess it's the meth capital of the
world,
but yet nature everywhere.
Beautiful.
Everywhere you go.
Amazing hot people that live in
Portland.
Don't feel bad for Brian.
Doesn't want to fuck you.
I didn't meet.
I didn't,
I did not meet you.
Now you might be the shit.
He might've just got to a real ugly
spot.
Tons of armpit.
Harrison,
all the chicks.
What do you think though about all the,
uh,
not only that I've heard a lot of leg
hair to was something I read on forums
where women were complaining saying that
men should know that women have hair on
their legs and armpits.
This is silly.
Yeah,
I went to a Sushi place,
first Sushi place I've ever been to
where they gave you forks and then I was
like,
wait,
where's the chopsticks?
And I had to go to like the hostess
stand and it had been looked for
chopsticks at a Sushi place.
Like they were like,
oh America son,
I know,
but what?
I'm fucking go back to China.
You can use those chopsticks.
That's what kind of Sushi place they
have their,
what do you think about all those people
that get depressed?
We want to kill themselves because it's,
you know,
75 days a year.
I believe it.
I lived in Ohio and it was like that
everyday and I wanted to kill myself and
I just wanted to go to work and get done
with the day and go back home and play
on the Internet and that was because it
was cloudy.
It was just discussed.
Great.
Everyday that sky was gray.
I would say 50 percent.
Sixty percent of the days were gray.
The other were like partly cloudy to
sunny,
you know,
but 60 percent was like gray sky,
like nothing.
Just death.
I've been there,
man,
I've been to Columbus a bunch of times
doing stand up and that's what I've
found.
It's a real gray there.
There's a bunch of parts of the country
that are just real gray for like a long
part of the year.
That shit ain't good for you now.
It's not sucks.
It's weird,
right?
We're,
we're kind of programmed,
you know,
the human body needs a certain amount
from its environment and one of the
things we need is sunlight.
We literally need sunlight for vitamins.
We need it for vitamin D,
but we also needed for happiness.
There's something about skies that are
gloomy,
that are depressing and it's encoded
into your DNA.
It's like your DNA is telling you,
hey,
you're,
you're living in a place where it's
going to be uncomfortable.
You're going to get drenched.
You're not going to get that vitamin D
that you need,
but if you can get past that,
you'll be okay.
If you can go to the sun and get the
sunny parts,
then you'll be happy.
Like you can literally literally changes
your state to be indifferent.
Whether you know,
like,
physically changes it and if you live in
a place where it's just you don't get
that son,
you don't get enough of that son.
Yeah.
And it's also different.
People have different needs to.
I think genetically,
you know,
I bet if you're black,
I bet living in a place where it's never
sunny,
it was fucking terrible.
I bet it's terrible for you because like
the whole dark skin and dark skin,
it's supposed to be in response to
bright sun and you know,
living in a hot climate.
So yeah,
dark skinned like Brazil,
you know,
they're dark skinned and that's supposed
to be because they have to deal with the
hot sun and,
and you know,
and that kind of a climate.
And if you go to places like Siberia,
people are pretty fucking white just
because no one's ever outside in the
sun.
You know what I mean?
It's like you,
you,
you get,
you grow accustomed to it.
So maybe if you're a person that like,
you know,
it's got super pale skin,
it would be way easier to live in a
place where it doesn't get sunny.
You know,
maybe there's like genetic needs.
Hmm.
Very possible.
Right.
I mean,
I,
I wish I knew about those lights before
that when I lived in Ohio.
Like there's the sunlight lights.
Have you heard of those?
Who knows?
There'll artificial lights.
The lights.
Yeah.
They have alarm clocks.
They have that built into them too.
I really,
I was thinking about getting one.
That's a trick though.
How the fuck would that be?
As good as going outside on a sunny day.
Some days are awesome because everybody
else is happy to.
I guess that's tricky.
When I lived in Boston,
I,
I appreciate the fuck.
I live sunny days,
but now in la you're just so used to it.
It's like sunny days or just what you
get every day.
Yeah.
It's actually the opposite today.
It's cloudy and you get fired up when
it's cloudy,
you get,
Oh,
we're going to get some nice rain
because it literally is sunny here.
Three hundred and 60 days a year almost.
I mean,
it's fucking crazy.
I mean how many,
how many days a year?
I'm exaggerating,
but it's maybe three.
20,
right.
It's pretty high.
Definitely.
Was like a month though that it rains
like every day sometimes.
Like every other year.
Tiers.
Yeah,
it's fucked up.
You can.
You can get used to that.
Yeah.
But it's a terrible for your skin.
You know in Australia when I was in
Australia,
they have all these ads for skin cancer
because Australia doesn't have a fucking
ozone layer.
Remember when there was the big hole in
the ozone layer?
Worry.
Well it's all over Australia and
apparently Australia doesn't give a shit
but they have all these ads everywhere
you go.
I'm being careful because if you go
outside without sunscreen on,
you could get skin cancer.
So they have these really graphic skin
cancer ads on the side of buses or
stitches and shit and see big pieces of
meat cut out of people.
I hate that.
Like or when it gets cigarettes and like
Canada and it shows like some guy with
throat cancer on the back of your box.
Yeah.
Just like rough about that too.
You see people smoking in England,
they have big giant warnings in the back
of their cigarettes.
But you need that son look at you.
You got,
you got illnesses right now.
You ready to die?
Brian's been shitting blood.
No,
it's in black.
It's blood right,
isn't a blood stomach ulcers.
Brian's got a stomach ulcer.
He's fucked.
It's great.
I have this doctor that I was talking to
today and he's just like a,
so what?
Your stool is black?
And I'm like,
yeah,
it's last night.
I felt like I was gonna throw up.
I have an eight and 24 hours and I feel
really light headed and my stool is
black.
And he goes,
man,
we need to get you to the emergency room
quick.
All right,
I'm going to call you back and schedule
an appointment.
And I'm like,
okay,
okay.
And he's like,
and you're not going to have to drive
home.
I'm like,
all right,
that's cool.
Four hours,
five hours later.
He hasn't called me back,
so this is going on right now as we
speak.
I might just die,
right?
Kind of a trooper is Brian.
This dude is bleeding out of his
butthole and then just hanging out.
It might be stomach cancer.
Somebody just sit.
It might be cancer.
I don't think it's cancer.
You don't smell like you got cancer.
Smell like you got some your dogs that
you said.
Let your dogs smell nice ground at your
asshole.
Like angry.
Imagine that dog locks on your ass.
It's happened.
It's happened before.
There's dogs that can smell cancer.
They can.
They can take test tubes and lines like,
you know,
they did this test with them where they
just have this big giant like 20 yard
line and down the line and there's a
different test tube and you know,
at increments and each different tests
who has a different thing in it and then
they'll go right to the ones with cancer
and they bark.
That's crazy.
That's nuts.
They can smell fucking cancer.
I love that.
I love that whole thing where there's
stuff we don't know about.
Things like dogs and like that.
Just that they know that.
And like earthquakes.
Just the fact.
Yeah,
they,
they know tsunamis are coming.
They go run in the Thailand tsunami,
that last big one that happened.
Very few animals tied.
Man Deanna,
if,
if any.
I think the animals all escaped.
They all saw common and got the fuck out
of dodge,
like way,
way in advance because they don't have a
language.
I think that the earth itself probably
has some sort of a language and if you
have a language yourself,
you know,
like human beings do and we have this
ability to communicate.
We're so wrapped up and communicating
with ourselves that we don't receive any
communication from animals or plants or
from the world.
You know,
I'm not talking about like,
like words like dogs talk to you,
but did you ever meet a dog and you
know,
you can't fuck with his dog.
He never meet a dog and you're like,
what's going on buddy?
And you're looking at him and he's
looking at you and you're like,
okay,
let me get the fuck from you.
That dog is sending.
There's somehow or another.
I mean it's not even his,
his demeanor.
He's not growling at you.
He,
but he's just giving you a look and
you're getting a message.
You,
he's communicating with you,
but you got all sorts of shit inside
your head.
The stock market and your divorce and
your fucking homework.
And this and that and language and
English and I'm learning Spanish and
you've got all this shit going on in
your head.
I bet the earth itself actually has like
some sort of a way of communicating
with,
with beings and with animals that don't
have languages.
Like they can tune into shit that we
can't tune into.
You know,
how dogs can smell things and tune into
things.
And I mean they have a super,
super,
super powered senses.
Yep.
They can sense that they,
that if they have cancer,
you know.
Right.
Well that's.
Maybe they can,
you know,
maybe we don't.
They just can't communicate.
Yeah.
You know,
but dumb dogs,
you know,
it's funny when,
when,
when the doctor is asking me if it was
black and I'm like,
I don't know,
it's like very dark,
dark brown.
He goes,
well dark brown and black is completely
different and I'm like,
it's not really different.
I'm like,
do you want me to take a photo of it?
He goes,
no,
that's not necessary.
Like,
well are you talking about $10,000
difference?
Like if I say no,
it's black,
or are you gonna like make me go to the
hospital and do all this shit.
That's why I just don't get doctors,
you know,
that's like,
while he's just probably tired of
people,
man.
Do everyday deals with people that are
broken.
Could you imagine what that'd be like?
That'd be like psychology.
I was a psych major for awhile in
college and I was thinking like maybe
there should be a psychologist.
I give people good advice and then I
thought about it and I was like,
you're going to be dealing with fucked
up people every day.
Every day you're on fucked up energy and
the best you can do with these people is
make them not fucked up.
You know,
that's the best you can do,
but you're not getting any fucking
happiness and joy and excitement and all
powerful feelings all day.
Creativity,
you know,
you're just dealing with fucked up
people and some people want to do that.
Some people want to help you,
good on you,
good on you.
But man,
that would have to be a fuck
drag.
And also in La,
I think it's completely worse,
like if
so self indulgent out here.
Yeah.
And plus there's just so many people,
so many people and so many people trying
to do something completely unrealistic.
Right?
How many people out here want to be
famous,
you know,
and I live out in the burbs and you run
into people and you don't think that
they're the type.
And then as you get to know them,
you find out,
oh,
I came out here to be an actor.
It didn't work out.
And then I got into plumbing,
you know,
hey,
I was wanting to be an actor.
I always wanted to do this.
And how'd you get your spot?
What?
I always wanted to do that,
man,
how'd you get?
How'd you get on that show?
I just wanting to do that.
And you find out that like literally
like,
you know,
the percentage of people that move out
here for even in the back of their hand,
they have some weird show Biz dream.
It's like fucking 60 percent,
you know,
that's a completely unrealistic number.
If you think about how many people there
are out there that actually become
famous from acting,
especially acting man,
I mean it's fucking who.
Who's to say you're a good actor.
I had a hell.
You get good at pretending to be someone
you're not.
You know what I mean?
I guess there's some methods to it and I
guess you know,
it all depends on personality,
what kind of energy you're packing
inside of you,
but then somebody has to agree to put
you in a movie and somebody has to agree
they like you and what are the odds
that's going to happen?
Fuck man.
So those people are.
All they have is an unrealized dreams
and that fucking chips away at them.
And then the reason why they wanted to
be actors in the first place,
a lot of,
almost they're fucked up because they
didn't get any attention as a chat.
Woo.
I coughed up.
I was getting broken up with a story.
They didn't get any attention as a
child,
which is the same reason why people
become comedians and you know,
any kind of extreme attention performer
like that,
you know.
So then you're,
you're dealing with like so many people
with that.
So many people with problems,
so many people that need to be fixed.
Just give him some pills,
just give them a fucking pill and shut
them up.
You know,
after a while I think these doctors
could just tired,
just tired of dealing with shit.
Could you imagine being the guy who has
to deal with your problem every day?
Every everyday someone comes to them and
has got some sort of an ulcer or
something.
See when it's like a butt doctor.
And can you imagine what that is like
seeing buttholes all day?
You gotta fix him.
Nobody's coming in with the perfect
butthole and you're like,
I have good news for you.
Your butthole is perfect.
Now if you're going to see the doctor,
you got a butthole problem.
Yeah.
Fuck.
You could be dehydrated.
It depends what color your shit was.
Do you drink a lot of water?
Yeah.
I had two gatorades already today,
so I'm not dehydrated.
That's not.
When did you know that you could pinch
your hand and you can tell if you're
dehydrated.
If your skin goes back slower,
you know,
did you know that?
That's a good way to tell if you're
dehydrated.
I've heard about that from dudes to cut
weight.
Yeah.
When they know that they're ready to die
has been cut so much weight that their,
their body's failing on them.
Well,
a lot of guys who cut weight get really
crazy with it.
Like um,
they'll go down from like,
you know,
there's dudes that go from well over 200
pounds and they go all the way down to
one 70.
Tiago Alvarez.
You've seen that guy before,
right?
He's huge.
When I stand next to that guy,
I can not believe that that guy gets to
170 pounds.
He's so much bigger than me.
I weigh 185 pounds and that guy is way
bigger than me.
He is gigantic and somehow know that
heat dries himself out totally to one
70,
gets on the scale and then rehydrates
and gets to like 200 pounds by the time
it comes to fight.
That's crazy.
I don't know how they do it.
I don't know how they do it,
but it's dangerous and when dudes are
like at that last drop,
you know what I mean?
Tiago has never looked bad,
but I've seen some guys look real bad.
I was like Travis Luder once didn't make
weight for the Anderson Silva fight and
he was trying to try and try,
but he could not cut the weight for
whatever reason and he's walking towards
the scale and he was shuffling because
he couldn't even pick his feet up and
his cheeks were all sunken in.
He looked like he was going to die.
He's lips were all chapped and broken
and I was like,
whoa.
Like this dude looks like he's in a
goddamn concentration camp.
This is crazy.
All just to be bigger than the other
guy.
What are you doing,
man in the head?
You're going to die losing composure,
son.
Pull it together.
Boy.
So I'm wanting to talk about that.
A,
the Miss America,
Miss USA.
You don't want to confuse them because
apparently ones legit.
Mrs.
Rogan was telling me that one of them is
legit.
One of them's important and the other
one's silly ones like which one?
Trombone.
Then the fucking same thing to me.
I don't see how Miss America or Miss
USA,
but I guess one of them is like the
cooler one and like Ms Dot USA wishes
she was Miss America or Miss America
wishes.
She was at Ms Dot USA and the other one
is like cheesy.
Yeah.
Once I hooter girls I heard one of them
I think has.
You have to like talk and give like a
speech and shit.
And the other one you just fucking
flirtier baton and miss.
What's it called?
Flip your.
What's the word pure for protons.
Flip your lid.
They're all they are is who I'd most
like to fuck contest.
And the fact that we still give a shit.
Who Wins?
The WHO I'd most like to fuck contest in
2010.
That's very strange.
You know.
And this one is very controversial
because the last woman who is in the big
controversial was that carry predawn
chick who hated gays or didn't want them
to get married or whatever.
She didn't hate gays.
I mean,
I'm just putting words in her mouth.
She was just upset.
She only wants.
She only thought regular marriage.
She wasn't.
She was opposed to opposite marriage or
she was opposed to to,
to same sex marriage,
but she supported opposite sex marriage.
That's it.
That's how she described it.
Like opposite marriage as a train wreck.
Well,
and she was just a dumb check who's hot.
You know,
if you're a dumb chicken,
you're hot.
How hard is it to have your shit
together?
Virtually impossible.
You know,
you're around people that tell you
you're awesome all day long.
Everybody wants to fuck you.
You have.
You don't even know what color the sky
is.
What the fuck do you know?
You know,
could you imagine what it must be like?
Like how,
how hard is it to be enlightened and to
be free and to be like without ego.
If you're a hot chick in,
let your twenties,
dude,
everywhere you go,
everyone treats you.
Like you have the Willy Wonka golden
ticket.
Everywhere you go,
guys are willing to leave their wives.
They're tripping over themselves,
trying to buy you things or trying to
take you out everywhere you go.
That's sex dating as girls too.
Why is this?
Because then they're still used to a
certain way that you're.
You know what I mean?
I can keep the pimp hand strong,
son.
You got fuck them.
Right.
And then don't call them to make them.
Make them know that the game's different
now.
Okay?
I'm not that 60 year old man that bought
you a Ferrari.
All right,
I'm here to give you some Dick and then
we're on equal terms.
I'm not.
We're not getting crazy.
I'll have to buy you things.
Settle the fuck down.
They'll get mad if you don't buy them
things though,
right?
You don't care.
The last boyfriend cared liquid.
He bought her.
He bought all these diamonds.
He her all these things and they get to
walk around with them and the walking
around with them.
It's very important.
It's more important than having them to
want everybody to see that someone loves
them so much.
They spent all this fucking money so
that miss year,
so I check that she was a big problem
because she,
she didn't like the gate,
so the fucking Christian's got all crazy
weather and they were like,
yes,
you're on our side.
Then it turned out she did some porn.
She made her own home movies with the
big Dildo and shit.
She was had a Dildo in her ass or
something.
There's all these different versions of
what actually happened,
but she went into sue.
She was trying to sue Miss USA and she
was like talking crazy lawsuit talk and
they're like,
really want you to sit the fuck down?
We're going to show you this video of
you with a big black rubber dick in your
ass hole or whatever happened is strap
on.
I don't know.
We just should clarify for the
broadcast.
We don't know what exactly was on that
tape,
but apparently it was some,
some shit that you're not supposed to do
if you're Miss USA,
which is hilarious.
You're in a who I'd most like to fuck
contest and it can even be a video of
you out there.
Fucking we can assume that you fuck,
but if you capture on video that's,
that's in violation and you're gonna
attract undue attention to our cause.
Our cause of the miss who I most like to
fuck contest.
Like what the fuck is wrong with people.
When I was in high school,
I would go to hooters and just be
complete assholes.
We would like all right,
since it's called hooters,
we're allowed to look at their hooters
so we're just going to go in there and
stare at their hooters and not even look
at their face as a joke.
Let's do old 15,
16 years old.
And so we just go there and take the
whole time just staring at their tits.
I hope you feel bad about that and I do
feel bad about it.
When you get really stoned as it haunt
you does when you eat like a Brownie
chicken wing,
you ever eat a Brownie and in your
childhood haunt you and you think did
some Douchey Shit?
When I was in eighth grade,
it was like the baby cardinal once where
it was like fell out of his tree and I
was hurt.
I just remember being a kid throwing
rocks at it and I'm just like,
haunts me like little cardinal.
Yeah.
Me and my friend Tim,
we went hunting for squirrels and uh,
no it was my friend David.
We went hunting for squirrels with
slingshots and we tagged the squirrel
and he fell out of the tree and then we
killed him and I was like,
what the fuck are we doing?
Like why are we killing the squirrel?
The Squirrel didn't do shit to me,
you know,
it's just like we wanted to see if we
could do it.
And we did it,
you know,
we played baseball,
throwing baseballs at squirrels on power
lines.
Oh Dude.
It's so fucked up.
The things you do,
like,
you're so inconsiderate when you're 15,
you know?
And then I don't think I was 15.
I was 14 and I never did it again.
I was like,
God,
I was like one thing about eating that
squirrel,
but I just killed that squirrel with a
marble.
I shot him in a marble,
like,
for what?
What the hell?
How stupid is that?
You know,
there'll be,
you know,
you learn from those experiences and
then you know,
you learn from that terrible feeling and
you never do it again.
But God,
I wish I didn't have to do it in the
first place to learn that.
You know,
some people are so fucking
like some people,
like how many people do you see?
Just throwing cigarettes out the window.
We were talking about that this all the
time.
All the time.
That's so inconsiderate,
man.
Funny.
I used to do it though.
That really sucked.
When did you stop doing it?
When he moved to California.
Really?
Yeah.
It's like a California thing I think.
Why did California make you stop doing
it?
Because in Ohio it was normal.
It was normal and in California cops
would do it.
Oh really?
Yeah.
Cops that you would be smoking a
cigarette while they're writing you a
ticket and just flick it on the ground.
Do you know who the fuck is?
That is?
What is it about smokers that makes them
think that the world is the garbage?
Because up to recently that was normal.
You know,
but why is that normal?
Why is it normal?
I had a friend who used to do it.
He'll say a fucking taxes.
They pay to clean the streets.
Like that was his thing.
He would smoke.
He'd flick it on the ground and I go,
why don't you just pick that up?
Why do you,
why do you have to throw that on the
ground?
I was like,
Hey,
fucking taxes.
This is a guy whose job is it because it
decomposes?
Is that what it is?
Like compose.
Oh man,
there's a fucking.
There's plastic in that thing.
Who knows what the goddamn shelf life is
on a cigarette filter because I mean
like you know how you can like throw
like a banana out the window and that's
an organic thing.
I never had a cigarette filter is not an
organic thing.
I mean there may be biodegradable
cigarette filters,
but when,
how long does it take them?
How many of them are biodegradable and
how long does it take them to dissolve?
Flicking her cigarette out.
The window creates jobs.
Yeah,
that's what my friends are good.
Was someone saying that on twitter?
That's what my friend's argument was.
It was a fucking guy justice for a
living.
What he does,
just to clean it up,
is his argument was that there's
somebody gets paid to do it,
so it's like cleaning up at a
restaurant,
washing you clean up,
you know,
you don't clean up the waitresses there
to clean up.
That's her job.
His,
he thought the city streets where there
to be clean,
so he would just flick his,
his ashes everywhere.
Yeah.
I guess I never got.
I never understood.
I just did just did it because everybody
else did.
When did you start to feel bad about it?
You?
The one that made me feel bad about.
Because when we were at the comedy
store,
I flipped on the ground and you're just
like,
pick that up.
What the fuck?
He took women and I'm like,
what?
What are you talking about?
You just don't throw it on the ground.
And it was you who were like,
I don't think really.
Yeah man,
I haven't.
You're the first person to say it that
way.
Like ever.
No one ever told you not to litter.
That's ever.
Not from that cigarettes really ever.
You're the first person to ever do that.
I'm very,
um,
I'm very sensitive about like mess,
like leaving a mess.
Like I don't ever want to inconvenience
other people because I'm lazy and then
consider it.
So it's like I don't ever like throw
garbage on the ground.
If I dropped something I'll chase after
a little receipt because I want to make
sure that I picked that up and throw it
out.
You know,
I,
I'm very sensitive about that shit.
I just think that that's a gross fucking
characteristic of human beings.
I don't ever want to see that in myself.
That inconsiderate like lazy litterer
know.
It's just a gross characteristic.
Like we need to fucking move past that.
I see people in fucking hybrid cars all
the time.
Flicking cigarettes the window.
That drives me nuts.
I was talking about that.
I did a whole thing about it like a year
and a half ago in San Francisco.
I was screaming at them because I saw
like four of them in a day for guys and
hybrid cars just throwing cigarettes out
the window.
It's like,
this is,
this is ridiculous.
Like,
what,
what the fuck are you doing?
What,
what makes you think that that's okay.
You know,
you're,
you're fighting the oil companies and
you're trying to be conservative and you
know,
with gasoline and everything like that
and make sure that you leave a small
footprint and you're throwing cigarettes
out the window.
It's weird.
I'm like that with a lot of things where
I'm like,
I'm ashamed of myself and how I act
like,
especially when I'm in a hotel room and
I like flipped.
Come on the walls and stuff.
I'm like,
yeah,
fuck this.
Come on.
Do that.
Yeah.
I don't know why you did that.
Still get all the time.
Oh,
you're gross.
That's what the deal is,
is a reason why hotel room has so many
washcloths.
Okay,
so you supposed to come in a few of
those.
You're not supposed to be flicking on
walls.
I can't do it at home.
You know what I mean?
I'm like,
Yo,
I went through my career everywhere.
If you've ever seen those,
uh,
television shows,
like inside edition or whatever the fuck
they are,
you know,
with a 20,
20 where they go to hotel rooms,
we're going to take you into hotel and
find out what's really going on and they
use a black light and they find ges
everywhere to Tj's.
And then on the glasses,
I guess those glasses,
they don't really clean them.
It's just like that.
The woman like rinses it out and then
puts the thing on it.
So I guess they did it.
They swapped all these glasses and like
90 percent of the glasses,
like had fecal matter on the fucking
black light to this one,
a comforter and it looks like a Jackson
pollock painting.
It was just all just,
it was just dried judges all over this
fucking thing.
It was like a God,
that constellation.
It was disgusting.
It was just loads all over it.
And they were like talking about what
the different things was.
This is blood,
this is pro,
and they were saying that it was one of
them was period blood.
They were very specific.
This is menstrual blood.
Most likely this is,
this is sperm.
Like what the fuck?
You know,
if you think about it,
that's what you're sleeping in.
You know what?
All the lows that you've blown on,
hotel sheets and those sheets just get
washed.
They probably do a shitty.
What's crazy is they don't even wash the
comforter once a month or something like
that.
That's the thing.
Yeah.
That's where all the loads are.
That's what they found the show.
It was the comforter and the headboard,
you know,
especially those,
those beds that have lighter cloth
headboard fucking home.
It's just like,
like,
like the back windshield and pulp
fiction bolted shut.
That loads all over that fucking
headboard.
Oh,
is that his named Kenny?
I forgot to shut Kenny in the head or
something like that was the really
uncomfortable seeing where Quintin
Tarantino tried to be down and said the
word nigger to Samuel Jackson and kept
saying it.
I got a dead nigger in my house.
Like why do I have a dead nigger in my
house?
And it was like,
what?
Who the fuck talks like that,
you know,
who there was not even gangsters.
Even there's no white guys that,
that
talk like that too.
Black guys,
why do I have a dead nigger in my house?
I mean that scene was so fake and it was
so like him living out some weird white
boy fantasy where he wants to be able to
say nigger to a black guy because he
wrote a script.
Yeah.
It used to be a big Quintin Tarantino
Fan.
But you know,
when I see,
I saw that TMZ video.
You ever see that?
Where he attacks like the cameraman?
No,
and he just came off.
That's it.
Like a dick.
And I was.
I've seen them come off really cool and
interviews.
I've seen him come off like a Dick,
but I think these are volatile God
because he's a creative guy and he's
probably super fucking busy all the time
and a lot of stress.
And if you catch them at the wrong time
and you're trying to talk shit to him,
be stupid.
He's very likely to talk shit back to
you and come off all Douchey,
but you've got to think what's the
situation?
It's not him forcing his penis on
someone.
It's someone wanting to videotape him.
When I was wanting to be video,
someone coming up to a member,
but I think it was just somebody,
a hammer.
I wish I could find that link right now.
I think it was somebody going,
hey,
I'm a big fan of your movies and stuff.
Got.
And he was just like,
really?
Yeah.
I think it was something like that.
I remember thinking,
wow,
that maybe just has a huge aversion to
all that Tmz Shit,
you know?
Maybe that just drives them nuts.
I don't know.
You know,
I'm a big fan of pulp fiction.
I love that fucking movie.
But then I read all that shit that Roger
Avery said.
You Roger Avery who's in jail.
He claims that there was like a movie
that,
that Quintin Tarantino did when he was a
star in the movie where he had this
whole scene about top gun.
Do you remember the scene?
He had a.
um,
it was a whole scene in this movie about
top gun being a gay story and this is
why it's gay.
And like,
you know,
like he,
he goes into this whole rant.
Well apparently that was like Roger
Avery's rant.
Roger Avery.
Yeah.
Roger Avery wrote killing Zoe,
which is an awesome movie if you've
never seen it,
really interesting cool crime movie.
And he wrote pulp fiction with Quentin
Tarantino and you know,
they would collaborate on things and
then,
you know,
he would tell.
He would say,
tell me these stores.
I slapped him.
Yeah.
Well maybe that guy needed to be one of
the audio real quick.
Okay.
Let's play the audio,
play the audio and put it up to the
microphone.
And so Terentino's slaps a camera man.
This is what it's called.
Let me pause this real quick
and okay,
let's play it.
So he's walking through this parking
lot.
What's going on here?
What are you doing?
What are you doing again?
Yeah,
that's good.
Just keep going.
Go,
go,
go.
Yeah,
because you're filming yet.
But if that was off,
I'd be whooping your ass up and down
this tree.
Yeah.
That's interesting.
And if you look at that.
All right,
so if you haven't seen it,
Quintin Tarantino slaps a camera man on
youtube and it's some guy who gets
douchey with him.
I'll put it in your chat on the stream.
But if you look at the,
the,
the other videos like the related
videos,
like Quintin Tarantino spits on some
guy,
the reporter he fucked with.
Maybe that guy just came up to him
camera and he wouldn't tell them what it
was about and he just sticking a camera
in his face and maybe he felt like he
was being violated and he felt like that
guy was a dickhead.
You know?
I mean,
look,
I could see his point,
you know,
look when,
when someone's fucking with you like
that,
you know,
you don't always catch you in the most
perfect of moods.
You know?
I mean,
he could easily be involved in some big
stressful fucking thing with some movie
he's doing and he's in the middle of
this shit.
And then he steps outside.
Some guys got a camera in his face,
he's like,
what are you doing man?
Why?
Why are you doing this?
And the guy won't say anything to him or
the guy.
I want to explain it to him and he gets
mad.
It's possible.
Maybe just sends the guy was a Douche
bag.
We're not seeing the guy with the
camera.
You know,
I just posted on my twitter red band
back on or Red Band Red Ban Terentino's
a bad motherfucker.
Well,
pulp fiction was an awesome movie,
but I don't know.
You know the,
the whole Roger Avery thing is,
it's an unfortunate.
Roger Avery says that that whole top gun
rent was like his rant and the
Tarantino,
he said it in front of Tarantino and
Tarantino.
Tina went and put it in a movie with
Tara Tito.
That's what he does with his movies.
Like a lot of his movies are like old
stories that he kinda like redoes right?
Yeah.
Well have you been.
We were talking about earlier about the
hurt locker,
how that guy suing the writer of the
saying that he took a article that he
did for playboy,
I guess about his time in the bomb squad
and they re wrote it into the movie,
the hurt locker
and it's really similar,
like the guy had like blonde hair blue.
I came from a trailer.
The whole deal,
like his story is exactly that story,
but in their defense,
like how many guys in the military or
blond hair,
blue eyes come from trailers.
There's probably a lot,
you know,
totally the fact that he was actually a
bomb,
you know,
specialists and detonation specialists
in this guy was as well.
Yeah.
And,
and what's crazy,
even as the creator,
those movies are supposedly going to
sooth thousands of bit torrent users.
People that downloaded the movie
illegally on the Internet and they're
going to go after all of these users,
which I thought was very metallic.
Metallic.
Yeah.
Like the old napster earlage.
Very Douchey,
douchey.
I think it is douchey.
Well,
if it's his movie,
right?
Right.
If he's losing money because all these
people,
he's really losing money from it.
I
don't know.
I mean that's an argument,
right?
There is an argument,
but it's,
you know,
look,
no one has a right to it for free.
That's an argument as well,
right?
You don't have a right to be downloading
someone's work.
These guys worked.
They did all this time,
put a pause time,
put all this effort,
you know,
made a script,
cast it,
got funding the whole deal and all you
do is just press a button on bit torrent
and white and you got it on your desktop
and you watch it for free.
There's something fucked up about that.
It's not like a band,
you know,
like if you go see a band,
like say if you download a band's mp3s
and you got them offline wire assumption
and then you go,
well I'm going to go support these guys.
I'm going to see them in concert.
I'm going to buy the CD because I liked
it so much.
You know that I'm going to become a fan
of this band because I downloaded their
shit for free.
Is that really going to help you with
this guy with his movie?
I mean,
when's his next movie fucking a year
from now or something like that.
I mean,
are you really going to be excited to go
see his next work?
Is it advertise him?
Is it,
does he get
deal in a shit?
Depends if he was how good this movie is
and how good of a directory is.
If he was Quintin Tarantino doing pulp
fiction and I downloaded that,
like,
Holy Shit,
I'm buying that shit on Blu Ray,
I'm falling.
I'm watching every movie this guy does.
Um,
you know what I mean?
Oh,
I see that argument.
Or
just decide to steal his next shit.
Shit's coming out.
Like you really do support them.
Do you do that?
Like if you download something and you
like it,
do you support the artists?
Absolutely.
Yeah,
I do too.
I think that's important,
man.
It doesn't happen quite as often.
That is shit though.
I don't think,
you know,
like you do that with movies.
Like if you download a movie and you
really like it,
do you buy?
Oh yeah,
yeah,
totally,
totally.
Beowulf was one of them.
I download Beowulf and I liked that
work.
What if you have a legal copy and your
house and then you also have an illegal
copy on your computer?
It should cancel it out,
but I don't think that's how it works
it.
You're totally right.
Yeah.
You should be able to have a copy as
long as you're not putting it up on some
sites or something like that.
If you have your own copy.
What the fuck is wrong with?
Yeah,
you know,
it would be cool.
It's like if you got in trouble and I'm
like,
all right,
you're going to go to court for
$100,000,
but you have 24 hours to buy this movie
on DVD.
Yeah,
that would.
That's how it was actually a good move,
right?
Move.
Yeah.
Just just sue everybody,
but you have to buy it on Blue Ray in 24
hours.
It's a tricky argument,
man.
It's a tricky argument because you know
what,
what?
What's going on in the Internet now is
that anything can be broken down to ones
and Zeros.
I mean,
these,
these images,
these videos,
these song files,
audio files,
it's all just ones and zeros flying
through the tubes and you know,
anybody can put it up there and anybody
can pull it down and when you can
convert a movie and you know,
you do all the time into,
into something digital that's
downloadable.
It's like,
how the fuck do you control that?
You know,
you have to just hope that you make
enough movie,
enough money when the movie's out and
that enough people get excited about it
to buy the DVD for other extra features
and all that shit.
But then people take the dvds after
they're released and they put those up.
What I don't get is a friend of ours
actually just got a letter from their
isp saying,
um,
ABC has caught them downloading a bunch.
The Jew a that ABC has caught them for
downloading a bunch of shit.
And they're like,
this is just a warning.
Nothing's happening right now.
But we just wanted to let you know that
ABC sent us this letter and they know
about you downloading.
So chill the fuck out.
And what was crazy is it wasn't
anything,
it was TV shows,
free tv,
it was like lost and stuff like that.
It wasn't even a movie.
So.
But was he downloading illegally?
Yeah,
he was downloading them illegally.
Supposed to do that because they have
their own sites and there's pay
services.
I know,
I just thought it was crazy that they
got,
they it some free instead of him getting
caught for like Avatar.
And did he do this through?
I'm a bit torn on how you did it.
Yeah.
Wow.
They busted them.
He's one of those guys.
Yeah.
But you know,
he's one of those guys,
I don't know if you do this either,
but he's one of those guys that like
downloads a movie and then keeps it
seeding for like two months.
You know what I mean?
Because I'm one of those people like,
oh,
that's probably what they caught them
doing it.
Seeding the.
Yeah.
So that's why they call it.
Let's see.
But uh,
I am one of those guys,
like once I download the seconds,
download,
delete,
torrent file,
you know,
and just wonder how many people do that.
Like they look at their shit and they
go,
okay,
what,
how many,
you know,
we're,
we're all these coming from,
they're coming from this one and what is
this guy doing?
Oh look at this.
He's put up all these things that we
have and it's coming from this one user
it let's find out who this isp belonged.
I think a lot of people don't even know
how to use the torrent system.
So like you get a lot of like young kids
or moms that are like downloading sex
and the city and they just keep the
torrent going for life.
You know,
what do they do?
They,
they get your Ip from them or they find
out your isp or your Isp,
your Internet service provider.
The Internet protocol is your specific
number that every,
everyone that gets online,
if you don't know this,
you have a very specific number.
It could be static or it could
fluctuate,
it could fluctuate.
If you have dialogue,
like every time you do it,
you get a different Ip,
right?
Right.
So what it is,
it's these movie places putting out
their own torrents and seeds and
collecting Ip addresses from like
they'll put their own movies out,
you know?
Really?
Yeah.
So they put their movie out on purpose
to see if you download it.
I think that's how one of their ways
they're doing it.
That's the dumbest Shit I've ever heard
of that's like,
that should be,
let's see what they're doing is
entrapment.
I think that's a lot of it though,
is a lot of it is a.
If you download,
like I downloaded an m and m cd once and
it was just like all these songs or
loops and I think it was,
it's like bait.
So they put out shitty versions of it.
But that's ridiculous.
This didn't Madonna put out one.
I wish I got ahold of that one.
I would love to see that because Madonna
put out one where it was like her music
or her new CD and she's like,
if he fucking download music,
I'll kick your ass or something crazy
about that.
If you download music illegally,
I'll kick your ass.
I'm speak.
That to me sounds like,
you know,
just the fact that they're doing that,
putting out bogus versions of it or
versions of their shit where they can
track you from,
you know,
it sounds ridiculous.
They're just trying to arrest people and
scare people now.
I think that's dumb.
They putting out versions of it to track
people.
Like really?
You thought it's like that's like you
putting out the bait,
you're putting it out there.
You know,
even if people are already downloaded
it,
you're actually putting it out there
hoping people will do things illegally
with it,
but it,
it's out there because of you.
That seems to me to be fucked up.
There's a funny story man,
about these undercover cops that
arrested other undercover cops.
There was this whole drug deal that was
set up between these undercover cops
that were posing as drug dealers and
these other undercover cops that were
posing as buyers to the drugs.
Yeah,
and these fucking dummies.
They,
they went to arrest each other.
That's so awesome,
man.
I want to see that there are both
undercover.
It's A.
I don't know what state it's in.
I want to download that,
the uh,
or Dell County,
I don't know where that is.
Um,
I should find out just so everybody
knows.
But the story is that these guys,
they went to their superiors and they
said,
hey,
we're about to make a buck North
Carolina there,
there were about to make this bust.
So they said they wanted to find out if
they had anybody else.
If somebody had anybody working
undercover and they always say no to
that shit because they could be dirty
cops and the dirty cops could pay off
drug dealers.
The drug dealers find out that these
guys were undercover and they kill them.
So they always say no.
Right.
Do you have anybody undercover?
No.
So they say,
okay,
there's an under covers.
We,
we've,
you know,
approved it,
let's arrest him.
So they use all these resources and they
had the whole thing is them.
They're the drug dealer,
the drug buyer,
fake fake drug dealers and fake drug
buyers arresting itself.
We should get that money back.
We should find out how much that costs
to do all that that you just did.
Roscoe Pico,
that's a ridiculous clusterfuck.
That's one of the dumbest cluster flux
of all time.
Undercover cops arresting undercover
cops.
Wow.
Yeah,
it's hilarious.
That's what's hilarious.
Is that a volcano?
It's like taking all those planes and
grounding planes still,
right?
Yeah.
And what's great is Lindsay Lohan was at
out of town and she's supposed to like
finish all these alcohol classes by like
tomorrow and she's just like four more
to do and she was going to come back
today and I do like four classes and one
day she got grounded because of that
said Nancy's going to jail.
It's really,
she's going to go to jail because she,
she had to be here for that.
She's supposed to be here tomorrow and
he's supposed to have had all these
classes done and she can't even get home
to do it.
So they're saying there's that many
plans are still being grounded because
of that volcano.
Yeah.
Whoa.
Fucking.
By the way,
when I was in Portland,
how crazy was it driving down the
highway,
seeing that Mount Rushmore.
Rushmore.
What's the one?
What's the one that blew up?
Fuji.
Mount Saint Helens.
Mount Sinai crazy,
seeing
that thing in the middle,
just this huge volcanoes.
It's fucking crazy.
People died from that one,
right?
I think so.
And they had to.
Is that in Oregon or is that in
Washington?
State of Washington state to state,
but it.
But you can see it.
Yeah.
Well we were at,
we were on the corner of I guess
Portland and Washington.
It's like right next to each other.
So because we're going to Washington
over this bridge back and forth all day
long.
So I was watching the show on tsunamis.
We were talking about the Pacific
northwest and how many times over the
last thousand years it's been jacked,
you know,
but civilization,
they're so recent.
We don't even realize it.
Civilization on the Pacific northwest of
the United States has only been the last
300 years,
you know,
so unless you know what I mean.
Before that there was Indians of course,
but I'm talking like big buildings and
shit.
So like the cycle of them getting hit by
giant tsunamis.
I mean it happens every thousand years
or so.
The whole side of the country gets hit
with some fucking 1000 foot high wave
and everything gets crushed.
Wow.
I guess it gets what with Tyler durden
do.com
and looked up flights and there's tons
of fights still going on.
So she was lying so she's just.
She's fucked even more.
Oh,
that dirty bitch.
She's probably don't cook.
Didn't want to fly.
Get his lying sources.
Say she can.
She can't get a flight back to the
states because of the volcanic ash from
Iceland.
Airports all over Europe are jam packed
and it's impossible to get a seat is
what she's saying.
But delta has five nonstop flight from
Paris to New York City and like I guess
they just went through and found all
these flights.
So flights not only there are flights
but they're not booked I guess.
So that's what tyler durden do.
What would tyler durden do?
He says that the whole thing is very
funny that people even give a shit fall.
This poor young kid.
It's all fucked up on drugs and
everybody thinks it's a funny deal,
you know?
Do you know what you would be like if
you were hot and you were Lindsay Lohan?
You were 23 years old and you're a
multi,
multi fucking millionaire.
Just out there doing drugs,
getting stuffed every night.
You know,
he'd be fucking crazy to who the fuck
would not be crazy.
I want to know what person could keep it
together as Lindsay Lohan,
who,
who could,
who could live that girl's life 23
fucking years old.
Looks like she's 40,
been doing drugs and she was a little
kid.
I mean who?
The,
who could keep it together,
you know,
became famous as a child.
She went from basically from like junior
high school to fucking superstardom
multimillions of dollars.
Totally unrealistic life in the toe the
whole time we were supposed to be
developing.
You're supposed to be growing as a human
being and figuring yourself out and
being insecure and establishing yourself
in the world while the whole time that's
all supposed to be happening.
She's getting millions and millions of
dollars for being famous and for
pretending you know who the fuck could
do that and do it right?
Um,
the Jonas brothers,
Miley Cyrus and yeah,
those are,
those are ticking time bombs,
my friend.
Those are guarantees.
Those are social guarantees.
No,
no doubt.
They're going to be fucked up.
Corey Haim and Corey Feldman.
Neither one of them could stop from
being fucked up even together.
They weren't strong enough brand
together.
Do you know?
He even lived by me.
I didn't know that when he died he.
Him.
Yeah,
he,
that when all the people were like
mourning him outside of this apartment
down the street from me.
And I'm like,
Oh shit.
He lived there the whole time.
Yeah.
That dude had it.
Bad drugs are a motherfucker.
People thought I looked like him growing
up.
Really?
I don't see it.
No.
Nope.
Don't say it.
Do you see it?
I did back in the day.
So back to this,
this fucking Miss America.
Because what I want to talk about is how
many people were upset that this Miss
America chick is a.
she's Armenian.
I guess something like that.
Lebanese.
Sorry.
Armenians would be pissed right now.
Carl Breezy and was right here,
Bro.
You can't fucking say Lebanese Armenian,
Bro,
but uh,
this,
this chick,
the most important thing is that she's
American and she's hot as fuck.
Like,
that's the dumbest thing ever.
Like you,
you,
you can't be from another country.
You,
you know,
your family can't be from an Arab
country and you can't be considered an
American just because we have issues
with Arabs and other parts of the world.
Like,
guess what?
Fuck it.
Those aren't the same people like w,
W,
how dumb are people that becomes an
issue and that these,
these are people that are actually
debating whether or not she got this
job.
She became Miss Usa because of political
correctness and the open border Nazis
like,
look at some of this shit that these
people have said.
Like this shell,
this chick right wing pundit.
What?
Right wing pundit and Fox contributor,
Michelle Malkin ranted that the girl's
name is fucky Fucky,
f a,
k,
h.
I don't know how to say any of fuckees
cheerleaders are too busy touting the
identity politics horn to care what
comes out of her mouth and that the Miss
USA pageant didn't want to risk the
wrath of the open borders mob.
What the fuck are you?
You're saying that one of the other
checks should've won the who?
I'd most like to fuck contest.
And you're upset that this chick one,
because of the reason why she won is
because everybody's super sensitive and
wants to support Arabs.
Like really?
Like how dumb is it that even Miss Usa
becomes like a topic of debate with
these fuckheads shit.
I got political correction,
topic of hair.
She's fucking high.
She can be a terrorist.
She's hot as fuck.
And she,
she grew up going to Catholic school
man.
I mean the whole thing is so fucking
poorly researched and you,
you're not even making any sense.
So you're saying that anybody,
even someone who grows up and goes to
Catholic school,
they can't be on the team because
somewhere in their past there's someone
who lives in some other part of the
world and those people are still there
and it really.
Is that,
what is that how we're rolling in 2010.
I mean America is a gigantic group of
immigrants and this chick and her
family,
wherever they lived
sucked.
And that's why they came here.
And the fact that they would actually
argue that she doesn't deserve the
window.
Who I'd most like to fuck contest
because of that.
I mean if she was fat,
disgusting,
you know,
she was like some Susan Boyle can
chicken.
It was totally ridiculous.
Then I could see the argument,
but how the,
how the fuck could you argue that that
check's not hot.
You can't.
What else do you have to do to win Miss
USA?
What is,
what are the,
what is the.
Do you have to dance?
Do you have to talk?
Yeah,
I think you have like a bathing suit
contest.
I think you have to do like some kind of
like.
We definitely have to talk.
That's how Perez Hilton busted that
Kerry [inaudible] check sheet.
He asked her about gay marriage.
Right?
So you have to talk.
I think you're only allowed to have like
small nipples.
You can't have that big aerial as a
like.
You have to have like a certain breed
look.
Kind of like a dog.
This other chick,
Gretchen Carlson,
bunch of hate and bitches,
bunch of hate and bitches
and all on Fox News.
Fox News is awesome because they're
awesome.
They're awesome and they're stupidity.
We already talked about why.
How is,
how is it?
It's hard news.
How is it that they're allowed to call
it news,
but how is it that they're so like,
like that,
but yet they have some of the most edgy
cartoons and TV shows on their shows,
you know,
like simpsons and family guy and get
their news is so like,
you know,
right wing Rupert Murdoch doc
is super,
super,
super fucking rich and when you get that
rich,
there's only one way to be that rich.
The way to be that rich is,
you know,
you've got to be a ruthless motherfucker
businessman and that's what he is.
He's a ruthless motherfucker businessman
and when you're like that and super
shrewd and ruthless,
you want conservative politics,
you want people that are protecting your
money.
You want to be able to do things that
are going to earn you money.
You don't want to have to hear about
liberals and windingness and fucking
environmental freaks and all,
even assholes.
They're going to stop you from making a
good return this quarter.
You know,
and that's what it is when you get to be
that super rich and very few guys like
Ted Turner that are,
that rich,
you know,
ted Turner's like this,
humanitarian and you know,
it's always like giving the charities
and you know,
very liberal in his network is thought
of as like a liberal network.
CNN is like the only.
I mean that's the one that I guess Msnbc
is pretty liberal too,
right?
But you know,
you don't watch any of those new shows.
Cartoon network and that's it.
I like Fox News sometimes.
Man.
I like it just to know that there's
people out there like that.
When I hear bill o'reilly and his
fucking dumb smugness,
I'm like,
there's really a guy out there like that
that is that satisfied with himself and
he says,
fucking Dildo that got busted.
Leaving a message on his assistance
machine about how hot she is.
He's a total hypocrite.
He's a fucking creep and,
you know,
and yet he's somehow or another,
he's found this,
this,
this niche on tv where people enjoy
watching them.
This niche.
Does that mean and,
and these people enjoy watching this
fucking buffoon rant and rave and yell
at people who go on a show and have
dissenting opinions,
you know?
Did you ever see that one where he went
on about,
uh,
some kid whose parents died in nine
slash 11.
And he was saying that it was,
the kid was saying that this is Bush's
fault
and the reason why they're attacking us.
And he just fucking went off on the kid
and it was just,
the whole thing was just so dumb.
He was,
he kicked him out of there.
And it's like the whole,
the whole,
the way he has conversations,
he just fucking infant tile and you got
to wonder whether or not it's like,
is he doing an act or is he that much of
a Douche bag?
Is it a combination of both?
And why the fuck is it so entertaining,
you know,
like listening to Christian radio when
you're driving,
you know,
it's,
it's sued a lot of people like that Bill
O'reilly Guy.
I think this because there's a lot of
Douche bags out there and douchebags
want to hear from other Douche bags,
you know,
when you,
like one of the things he had Richard
Dawkins on who's this renowned
intellectual and atheist and he wrote
the God delusion and a couple of other
books about religion and he thinks that
religion is bad.
And so he was saying to Richard Dawkins,
now you can't prove that God doesn't
exist.
So I'm throwing in with God.
Like he literally said it like that.
Like,
you know,
if,
if it's true and there is a god I'm
throwing in with God,
you can't prove that there is no god,
which is like how you can't prove.
There's no cheshire cat.
You can't prove there's nothing,
there's nothing that you can't,
you can't prove anything.
You can never not prove.
You know,
especially when you,
when it comes to things like,
people like science has never disproven,
you know,
the existence of Christ.
Well,
you can't disprove someone's existence.
It's impossible.
Like,
how the fuck do you know who,
who existed and who didn't.
You know,
science isn't there to disprove sciences
there to show me some evidence.
If science finds evidence and they
examine the evidence,
that's what it's all about.
When there is no evidence and there's no
way to determine one way or another,
you can't disprove,
you know,
you could take something like the shroud
of Turin and you know,
they say,
oh,
this is Jesus's burial cloth.
It's sacred.
And then you could do well,
okay,
let's take a little bit of this cloth
and find out how old it is.
Oh look,
it's only 500 years old.
How could it be?
Jesus was cloth.
You disprove it that way,
but he's fucking dummy.
So this guy has a huge presence on that
network and he's got.
He's got the number one show on cable
and it comes to those kind of stupid new
shows.
It's a huge show and it's retarded.
It's so bad.
Don't watch it.
Is Nancy Grace on that?
She on CNN or is she?
She's on CNN,
right?
She's brutal.
You know you fucked up.
If Nancy grace was talking about you,
if Nancy grace was talking about you,
there's a dead baby or you know you
drowned your wife or something.
Right?
It's something serious.
There's some serious shit and she will
hawk on the same subjects for weeks
waiting for the next disaster to pop up
the news so she could switch gears.
She talked about tiger woods for two
weeks.
Can you imagine being poor fucking tiger
woods,
just trying to tune into some CNN,
find out what's going on in the world
and you've got that hatchet face,
old con just talking shit about you for
two weeks.
Like he would've figured,
well,
she talked about me yesterday.
She's done.
No chance dude.
She's not
done.
She's not done for weeks.
He's going to keep going.
Tiger.
She the blonde haired girl.
Sang girl.
Shannon girl.
She's a woman.
Blonde hair whole.
She's an older woman.
I don't know what I mean.
Not,
not that much older,
but she's older.
She's not.
That's one thing that Fox News does
well.
They put on a bunch of hot chicks.
There are some hot bitches.
Hot angry,
mean bitches.
Fox local news.
No,
I'm talking about Fox News period.
All Fox News.
Like local news.
They're straight up.
Hookers really talk to me.
Telling me what's going on.
I have collected a bunch of clips about
the local Fox news channel and not only
does the weatherman dance,
like every time he's given the weather,
he does like a straight up dance.
Like he's dancing.
Yeah,
it's pretty hilarious.
I guess they're on my facebook.
I can.
Yeah.
You've sent when you put one of those on
the message on the message board.
And it's funny because I have danced
when every time he does the weather,
right?
And then like that,
uh,
why not,
right?
Why not let them fucking dance?
But it's so funny how bad it is.
Like there was the other day something
like,
Eh,
it's going to be wet outside there.
You know a lot about wet,
don't you,
Tina?
And she's like,
oh,
that's disgusting.
And like to go there,
it was just like,
are you really serious?
Have you seen that video clip where the
a black guy is sitting with these three
white chicks and they're talking about
some new graft and Berg spot shot.
It's like a shot of Collagen.
They shoot inside a chick's pussy.
They live with a needle.
They jab her fucking snatch and stuff
this liquid up there.
And apparently it makes sex feel better.
It like in it,
in it makes the,
enhances that g spot.
Wow.
And so they do this,
this whole thing and I'm,
the black guy goes,
well,
so I guess she's enjoying penis now.
More like he said that and all three
chicks were like,
oh yeah,
okay.
Yes.
She's enjoying sexual relations again,
like you know,
she tried to somehow under that,
cleaned it up.
Even though he used,
he used the right terminology.
I mean he used the medical terminology
and he didn't say anything really
inappropriate.
I mean that's what sexual intercourse
is,
right?
And she's enjoying his penis,
but somehow the fact that he mentioned
it,
it was like he said,
fucking candyman three times or
something,
you know.
So in shooting joe his penis and he was
black too.
And so there's this black dude would
probably a half a heart on three white
chicks talking about their spot getting
pumped up.
I bet he fucks him.
Anyway,
that's probably what's going on.
It's probably trying to keep it
together,
but really fucks all three of them.
Ladies,
let's talk about what happened on the
air today.
I want you to meet in my locker room.
Go in.
His dresser just got candles,
lit and Shit and pulls out that big
black fucking snake.
They all just go ask them mouth with
them.
I don't like when you talk about cock
and you're staring at me if you weren't
looking away comfortably,
I'm watching it on the web camera like,
oh my God,
he's to really close to me.
That is that not the worst thing that
could ever happen when chick breaks up
with you.
So it's getting drilled by a black guy.
There could be a lot of good scenarios,
you know,
use for a lot of dudes,
man dead,
black male equals just sexual prowess
that you will not reach,
you know,
they,
they equal big black Dick and
athleticism and just just gorilla
fucking your woman just doing it right.
Doing things to her that you can't do.
She's Kinda like it just got to love it.
It's going to get addicted to that.
Just getting stuffed.
Just you're just going to stick your
little fucking three quarter hard,
sad,
a little depressed boner in there and
thinking about getting,
going to therapy and maybe I should take
antidepressants.
Maybe I just need to start yoga and
jogging.
He's not thinking about that.
He's got a big giant black hard monster
Dick.
And they just.
And she's so fucking wet,
she can't believe how well she is.
She's just,
she's leaving a big puddle under her DNA
is crying for that big giant Dick and
he's fucking the shit out of him.
And he,
he doesn't,
he ignores her and doesn't call her.
And so she gets sad and so she calls you
up and I'm sorry,
what happened?
It was a lot of it was my fault and you
know,
I just,
we don't have to look.
I know it can ever be together again,
but can we just talk?
Can we just get together and talk?
And you're like,
hey,
what's the harm?
I ain't got shit to do tonight.
And you go over house and next thing you
know you're on the couch together.
You start making out and she grabbed
your Dick and she starts kissing you and
she squeezes your deck a little bit.
Like she's looking for more.
Where's that?
Where's the ass?
And she stops and then she goes,
we shouldn't do this because we
shouldn't do this.
And then you look over on a nightstand,
there's just fucking hulking black guy
and a picture frame that God has been
delivering the Dick to her for the past
few weeks.
And you just go,
who?
Who's that?
It's nothing.
Can't they take nothing fixed that now
technology to fix that.
Like a gas pump they haven't fixed.
That can take like an ankle out of your
foot or grow your Dick.
Yeah.
They cannot fix dicks.
They can't extend it.
They can take something out of your butt
and put it in there.
And so they can make a fake dick if
you're a chick.
Apparently chastity Bono who used to be
shit and when she is still shares
daughter,
but now she's a boy because she went
through a sexual reassignment and they
give her a bunch of hormones and they
make her a dick.
But I don't think it's.
It feels the same.
I don't think it shoots loads.
That's grossest.
When they take the Deq and make it a
pussy where they split it out like an
apple.
I've seen that or what's that?
China really have a man.
Wow.
How fucked up is your wiring that you.
You don't even like your part.
You want to switch to a girl part,
you're embarrassed,
you really wish you were a woman.
Do you think that they really are women
trapped in men's or did you do.
I do believe that,
but what about the possibility that
throughout their life they've just
experienced so much sorrow and so much
stress and so many fucked situations
and so much trauma in their life and on
top of that they're probably gay and
they're probably,
you know,
more at the very least bisexual,
you know their orientation naturally.
So it's like this natural sexual
orientation that leans towards
homosexuality and massive depression and
craziness and they just decided that
they want to be a girl.
That's possible too,
right?
Yeah.
Too much.
I have Nami at a mom makes you A.
I think there's an either or.
I think.
I don't think it's either or rather.
I don't think there's any one scenario,
but I think with some people they
become.
It's a man who becomes a woman just
because they're fucked up and whether
they're getting late either and there's
full.
I'll just get dixon me trick people and
then from others I think others are
just,
you know,
that's just,
I mean,
look,
there's a broad spectrum of human
behavior.
It's very,
very,
very likely to me that somehow or
another just someone gets a wacky gene
and they just,
shit,
why don't I have a vagina?
You know,
what the fuck?
They just,
they have this feeling like they're
missing something because they have a
penis,
but that's a goddamn commitment.
That is a God damn.
I don't remember what the movie was,
but there was some movie where there's
this guy in a tranny were yelling at
each other,
you know,
and,
and you know,
and she's like in the train,
he was yelling at the guy and the guy
goes,
you don't even have an addict anymore.
You're so fucking stupid.
You chopped off your Dick.
Just like,
I didn't chop up my dick.
I fucking turned into a pussy.
And the guy's like,
that's not a pussy.
That's a dick.
That's addicted.
It's been cut in half.
What movie was that?
I don't remember.
But there were paraphrasing obviously
because I don't remember where it came
from,
but some movie or something,
but God damn,
that's got a burn.
Those words,
you don't even have a date.
You chopped your Dick off.
There was a guy who was a ladyboy in
Thailand and was kicking a lot of ass.
It was a Thai boxer and he would go out
a lot of lady boys and Thailand
apparently.
And this guy was a Thai box or go out
there and fuck dudes up,
you know.
And it was a lady boy,
we were fucking dresses and shit,
but it was a dude.
So we'd get in there and throw down,
fuck guys up.
He was a bad ass Muay Thai fighter.
But then he went to the operation and he
got his balls removed and when he got
his bowels removed,
that's a wrap son.
No more testosterone.
A baby.
The,
the,
the flow stops completely.
And he shriveled up and got a woman like
and started getting fucked up and had a.
yeah.
I don't know how many fights you had as
a woman at an actual woman after they
took his balls off,
once they took his balls off,
he was useless.
They beat the shit out of that full.
Well,
that's what makes you a man with cancer
and stuff like that.
You automatically start getting more
woman like a wonder.
That's a good question.
Um,
you know,
I think with,
with some guys,
they,
they wind up supplementing the
testosterone because their balls don't
work.
You know,
I've heard of bodybuilders having to do
that.
Like bodybuilders get to a point where
they,
they shoot so much testing to their by
their bowels just shut down for life.
Their balls won't come back.
Right.
So they have to like
give themselves testosterone shots.
I was watching that China porn the other
day.
I was looking for a video and it just
happened to come up and I was like,
oh,
I forgot about the video that you do
that.
But that's like the Mexican drug dealer
getting his head cut off.
Did you see that?
Same thing to me.
She has a huge Dick Dick.
It's a dick.
Yeah.
Well,
that's what I was saying,
what they can,
they can grow you a dick and when they
give you testosterone,
your clit grows to the size of a thumb.
It grows big.
Like how big would you say her?
Her dic is to treat long.
Yeah.
It was pretty bad.
It was like a thumb,
like two inches long.
Right?
It appears to have.
I remember it.
No,
she didn't really.
She did have.
I remember dude,
she was on fear factor and she completed
this,
this stunt and after she completed this
done,
she flexed and she goes,
who's the man?
No way she did in town right there.
Yeah.
She said,
who's the man?
What pitch are you crazy?
How crazy are you?
Would you.
Would you have sex with her if I had to?
Yeah.
Yeah,
if I lived in Michigan or some shit
standards lower though.
You lived at Ohio,
you had lower standards,
right?
It happens.
Lived in Portland.
Your standards would drop.
Know Dude,
Portland be impossible.
Really?
If you want to talk a trick with hairy
legs,
sure,
I'd shave him,
but that was even gave them first 40
fucking.
That was even the problem though.
There wasn't even like hot chicks with
hairy legs.
It was no chicks.
It was fucking weird.
There was no Mexicans or black.
She refused to let you shave her legs.
She was like,
listen,
you have to accept me as I am.
Can you think you could fuck a chick or
would you go live in Newton?
John on her leg work.
I guess I don't mind too much if it's
like light hair,
but like dark hair.
Like what's that?
That precious chick,
her legs just make me want to fucking
throw shit at her.
Like what the Fuck's wrong with you?
Splatter of Shit.
It looks like tree trunks to her fucking
husband.
That's just like.
I like to show you.
Do you just like not working?
You're ridiculous.
Whew.
That was what we were talking shit to
people.
Everybody likes everything.
There's people that like things,
but man,
if you.
If your grill doesn't shave her legs,
what does she do with her pussy in her
butthole?
That's the question.
What kind of a fucking environmental
hazard is that thing?
What kind of a wasteland?
What kind of odiferous reaction are you
going to get when you get near her
panties?
Oh,
the funk of the 19 seventies of fucking
just just animal hair,
just for butthole and the inability to
completely clean everything because
there's hair all around your bottle,
so every time you're fucking had just a
slight smell of shit every single time,
especially when sweat starts dripping
down there and those big fat and bd
thighs start heating up and body wants
to cool them down.
That perspiration drips down to her
butthole and it just wafts up some fresh
new fumes and it's pussy,
funk and old butthole hairs and fucking
toilet papered thing.
Go berries and you're nuts.
Slapping against it all and just like
you're fanning the fires and then right
when you're about to bust it night,
you look down or hairy feet.
Oh,
you didn't go soft and her China Dick
and you've got to close your eyes and
plug your nose at the same time.
Try to regain your boat club people.
She's got to be so gross.
Ever talking about that.
When we're at the Strip club and I
thought the young chick was behind me
and I was so drunk.
That Strip club member.
Oh my goodness,
this is like 2001 and Brian's defense.
This is a long,
long time ago.
We were at a strip club and Brian was
hammered and there was a woman who sat
next to Brian and Brian started making
out with this woman.
Let's first talk about there was a cute
waitress that Brian was flirting with.
This is what happened.
First there was just cute waitress at
blind.
Brian was flirting with and she was come
and talking to him and she.
She gave him a drink and she said,
I'll be back to talk to you in a minute,
and Brian was so shit faced that he
leaned back and closed his eyes and this
haggard old wizard woman,
this which,
this,
this bitch just appeared out of nowhere
and the whole deal is attacked me or
something like,
yeah,
like in her fifties.
Okay.
And not well kept like ragged,
ragged in her fifties with bad tattoos
and a cutoff shirt like where her
stomach was exposed and there's stretch
marks from the 19 thirties on that
fucking weathered old leather saddle of
a stomach.
And her voice was cigarette.
Oh,
just stinky breath.
And she didn't have all her teeth
either.
Man.
She was missing a couple of teams.
I mean it was ridiculous.
So she sat down next to Brian and Brian
Leans up against her like this and when
Brian Leans up against her,
she grabs his head and he turns towards
her and they start making out.
I thought it was the way chin.
I'm like,
I gotta get this fucking kid out of
here.
How drunk is he?
This is ridiculous.
Like this bitch just saw him hammered,
and by the way,
we're at a table,
we're at a private little table,
so we didn't know her.
She just came over and sat down at our
table and no one knew her and she just
came over,
sat down like she's like a monster.
And she saw a victim and she saw that he
was weak.
She saw he was like so sloshed.
He couldn't keep his shit together and
he was leaning back and when he closed
his eyes and leaned his head back,
she just moved in for the kill.
She made the physical contact and he
didn't know.
He thought it was the girl and she had
an arm on him like this.
So he just responded to the physical
contact thinking that it was this hot
waitress.
Next thing you know their tongue in each
other and you have it on video until I
got it on video somewhere,
don't fuck around.
We both have shit on each other.
So He's,
he's tongue in this chick.
And then he looks at her and he looks at
her and he goes like this
in the middle of it,
the middle of it.
He goes,
he looks at her and then he just turns
away and she's like touching his face
and everything and he just goes like
this.
I got to go to the bathroom and you get
up and go to the bathroom.
And she got up and walk away and you
came back and go,
did I make out what?
That old lady.
What the fuck was that about?
Dude?
I thought it was the waitress.
I totally thought it was the waitress.
Like,
oh,
why didn't you stop me?
We couldn't stop you.
How the fuck are going to stop you?
She,
she sat down next to you.
You lean towards her and that pitches
planned it perfectly.
How many times does she
done that?
I don't know.
But the next morning when I was driving
her back to her hotel,
did she.
She never moved in again.
Right.
She realized that you realized that she,
she took off right after that was her
thing.
Freaked her out.
Yeah.
Because you freaked out and she was
like,
what the fuck did I do?
She realized that she had tricks,
some poor young man.
It just how gross it was that that chair
I was on at a strip club was a cloth
chair now wanted to scrape the,
the taste off my tongue.
So I started licking and dragging my
tongue on the chair of a strip club.
You get the taste of her mouth off of my
tongue.
Is that bad?
Why don't you just use liquor?
I don't wash it.
It's like,
Oh,
you were so horrified.
It was hilarious.
It didn't even seem real.
It seemed like you were punk at us like
you were.
You were doing a sketch list.
You had hired this actress to come in to
make out with you.
Just to freak us out.
I remember looking at your guys' faces
and you were recording me for one.
I'm like,
why are they recording me?
That's kind of rude.
But then you guys were all freaking out
and I'm like,
I just remember then looking at her like
backing up a little and look at it and
just,
ah,
what,
what an awesome strategy and
her part,
she recognized that you were ripe for
the taking,
you know,
she like,
she just,
she smelled blood in the water and she
just plopped herself right next to you.
Took Great God damn story actually
deleted it.
You did.
You tell her.
I told you I will delete it.
You're freaking out.
Do whatever you have that in your
private.
No,
no,
no.
I don't have the flashlight and the next
day or you likely please delete that.
I said I'll,
I'll do it.
Don't worry.
I showed it to you though.
Remember I showed it to you.
Really Watch it.
You watch it for a couple of seconds.
Got To hate that in depth and look too
late.
That's the worst feeling.
The next day when you wake up for being
drunk and you're like,
oh,
it is the worst feeling.
Slap on the forehead.
Well,
how about like Eddie Bravo when he,
you know,
he gets really hammered.
He,
there's a couple times a year,
like two or three times a year.
Well,
he will not remember the night.
He really does not know what happened.
He's talking about was like every week
at least.
I don't know.
I don't think it's every week.
Did he get a lot?
Dude?
I don't know how many times he blacks
out when you asked him.
He says a few times a year.
I believe him.
Maybe sometimes you forget to blacks
keep blacks out about the black and out
for the Best Eddie Bravo blackout story.
I told this in my blog,
this is a totally true story.
It was like 8:00
in the morning or our car was picking us
up at nine.
We were in Germany and I get up,
cause I'm gonna get some breakfast.
So I call Eddie to see if he wants to
get some breakfast.
And he goes,
what's up?
That's how I answered the phone.
I go,
what's I go,
are you drunk?
He goes,
he's hammered.
So I go,
okay dude,
I go,
our car is gonna.
Get us in like an hour.
Are you going to be ready?
Who's dude?
I'm ready.
I'm just going to power to.
I'm fine.
I'm ready.
All right.
I'll see you in an hour.
I'm going to get some breakfast.
So I go and get some breakfast.
Hour goes by.
I call him Santa answering.
I call his hotel room,
not answering.
I have someone go knock on his door not
answering.
He's not in this fucking room shit.
And I'm like,
did he never come home?
Did he get lost?
What the fuck is happening?
God dammit.
So I'm calling him.
He's not answering.
I go outside and I said,
well let me just throw my luggage in the
car.
So I say it to the Valet Guy.
I go,
there's a car here for Rogan.
And he goes,
Joe Rogan.
And I go,
okay,
that's my worst German accent ever.
What is that?
What was the Indian or something?
Now I'm Colonel Klink.
Anyway,
this fucking guy.
He goes,
Joe Rogan.
Joe Rogan just left.
I go,
no,
I'm Joe Rogan.
He goes,
no,
a guy said he was Joe Rogan and gotten
your limo and left.
I said,
what does he look like?
He goes,
long hair and tattoos.
I'm like,
that motherfucker,
because I knew it was eddie.
Right.
There's not that many long haired
tattooed dudes in Germany.
Right.
It's like,
oh fuck.
So I call him up and he answers the
phone.
I go,
what are you doing?
What's up?
I go,
what are you doing?
You're in my fucking car.
And he was looking at his watch and he
goes,
sir,
we're,
where are we right now in the driver
says,
we're on our way to the airport.
He goes to,
I guess what I'm wondering here probably
will come back and get me.
He goes,
how close are we to the airport?
five minutes.
He goes to.
I go,
how long you been in the car?
He had been in the car for an hour.
Wow.
It's like an hour ride.
Was he sleeping when he got like when I
got the phone with them at eight in the
morning,
he went down there.
The car was already there.
Just told the guy he was me,
got in the car and woke up like an hour
into the drive on the way to the
airport,
woke up without any memory of the night
whatsoever.
Woke up in the car with his phone
ringing it literally.
That's like an old man.
He literally had no idea what happened.
He doesn't remember a fucking thing
about the night.
Wow.
That's crazy.
How terrifying must be to have like some
like just like litter of behavior around
you and you don't even know what you
did.
Like you created all this problems and
caused all these people.
Get all fucking angry at you and shed.
You don't even know what happened.
You were just shit faced.
Blacked out,
gone.
And then he had to get on a flight like
I really long asked flight back home
with that hangover fucking 11 hours in
Germany.
Being drunk and hungover on a plane is
probably the worst thing ever and I hate
it so much.
Is it though,
because you just sleep well?
What's the big deal?
Is it harder?
Is it really like.
Do you feel like you're at high altitude
when you're on a plane?
Obviously you're at high altitude,
but the cabinets pressurized,
is there the same amount of oxygen there
is if you're at high altitude,
obviously not because like when you're
at 30,000
feet,
that's like Mount Everest.
Like you could fucking die up there.
There's no oxygen.
So that's a stupid question.
Alright,
so this is obviously way more oxygen
than at 30,000
feet.
That was a dumb question.
I can't believe I asked it.
I believe in the weed,
but when you're,
when you're in a plane,
does your hangover feeling any worse?
To me it always does and it's usually,
well of course I have acid reflux and
all this shit that's fucking with me and
so maybe it's worse for the Gremlin in
your asshole.
So criminal in my Bailey Bailey.
Yeah.
There's something about planes,
man.
Even if you sleep on a plane,
even if you,
you know,
you go and you come back.
There's something about just getting up
there,
traveling and coming back.
That leaves you feeling fucked up.
You just definitely feel a little off.
What is that?
What is a plane?
I think it's the change of pressure.
The pressure or is it just getting in
this tube with recycled oxygen and
everybody's bringing their own Ehr?
Is that what it is?
I think it's that because I actually saw
a report saying that those,
that recycled air summit,
the best air and it's actually just like
an old wives tale that,
that it's bad for you and it's actually
the filtering system in those planes are
so amazing.
That's pretty well.
What the fuck is it that makes you so
tired from flying?
Cause that Shit Jacks you do.
There's no getting around it.
It checks.
You know what I always like to do when I
land somewhere,
if I have the time,
I always have a hard workout.
One hard workout seems to reset
everything,
but if you don't have that hard workout,
man,
you're gonna.
You're gonna be fucked up for a couple
of days.
It takes a couple days to feel normal
again.
What is it?
It's not good.
You know,
I was talking to thinking about this the
other day and it's kind of on subject,
but about workouts where you say,
I like how you know how you can even
imagine.
To me when I forget who it.
Jimmy Kimmel was talking about this the
other day where he,
when he gets done working out,
he does not feel great.
He feels awful.
He wants to go sleep.
He feels sad.
He's.
He hates it and stuff like that.
But when you work out,
you have the exact opposite feeling.
You feel like,
fuck yeah.
Yeah.
You know,
you're fired up and feel great and you
feel great and like a natural.
I am like Jimmy Kimmel though.
Like when I work out,
I'm not happy.
I'm miserable after I work out.
Well,
why do you think that is?
It'll be two reasons for that.
One,
because you're out of shape and working
out as painful and then the recovery is
even more painful.
No,
but even when I was in her shape,
better in shape and that would work out
I never have.
Were you ever in really good shape?
Yeah.
Really?
I've been in shape a couple times in my
life,
like pretty good shift.
Were you working out and you feel I was
working out every day,
six days a week,
five days a week.
When you're working on what kind of
exercise you're doing,
how much exercise are you doing?
Like 45 minutes to an hour of cardio and
then like 10,
10,
15 minutes of that was my prime was 43.
You like really fucking sweating and he
even in Hawaii?
Yeah,
yeah.
Yeah.
But I never,
never enjoyed it and always hated it
after it was done.
Just a runner's high when it's over.
Oh Wow.
That's the.
I was just wondering like,
because like I've heard you talk about
it before and then Kim was talking about
it,
how is the exact opposite for him?
And I'm like,
yeah,
that's same.
I tell you how your body works.
Everybody's body has its own different
thing.
You know,
everybody's body works differently at
different levels of efficiency and some
people's bodies need extreme amounts of
exertion.
They need exercise.
And mine could be because I grew up
doing it because you know,
my whole life I've,
I've,
I mean there's never been a time in my
life except like in between surgeries.
There's never been a time in my life
where I didn't have some sort of extreme
exertion,
whether it's kickboxing or Jujitsu or
lifting weights or something,
or boxing for a while.
Everything was always just explosion.
Always.
There's,
my body's always been forced to behave a
certain way.
And when your body's forced to behave
like that for over 20 years,
you know,
it becomes accustomed to it.
And when I take a few days off,
I take three or four days off.
I have this buildup of energy where when
my body is used to producing a certain
amount of money,
I don't get any of that energy.
Zero.
That energy.
I actually have the opposite.
Like I think it's because hired 99.
I've never really been in the kind of
shape that kinda shape.
Yeah.
I think for me,
and it's different.
Bio mechanics are not biomechanics.
Bio,
I'm a bio.
Rhythms rather biochemistry.
Different people need different things
out of life.
You know,
some people need extreme exertion,
you know,
some people just need a walk,
some people feel great when they just
walk up a hill,
you know,
they just go for a little walk around
their neighborhood and they feel
refreshed.
They don't need that extreme physical
exertion.
It me,
I need to hit the bag,
I need to do Jujitsu,
I need to do some kettle bells,
I need to do it.
And when I do it it's like,
like I can be myself again.
It's like I blow it all out and then I'm
on myself,
but if I don't,
it builds up and builds up for one day.
It's tolerable.
Two days it's a little less tolerable,
three days a little less and then by the
time four or five days go by where no
workouts at all,
I start getting very edgy,
you know,
I feel like people were talking to me
and they're not,
they're not talking quick enough and I'm
a rude.
I'm like,
okay,
okay.
I get it.
I get it because my patients has gone.
I just have no patience.
It's weird.
It's caveman jeans.
I've got way too much caveman in me,
you know,
there was some sort of a study recently
that about people that have neanderthal
genetics and they have a certain
percent fucking for sure.
I do for sure if there's people out
there that have neanderthal jeanette
genetics and their system.
I've got some of that shit for sure.
Somewhere in my life.
Somebody fucked an eight man,
you know,
somewhere way,
way back in my family's ancestry.
Someone fucked one of those little crazy
eight men where I'm like a lesbian
trapped in a man's body.
You are very feminine.
You're very feminine,
but you liked girls.
What's that all about?
I'm a lesbian trapped in a man's body,
but you like fuck them.
I know that lesbians like fucking chicks
to do.
They do.
They put strap ons on and just get sad.
I would get fucking sad.
It was chicken.
I want it to be a dude and I'm putting
this rubber Dick on a girl group with a
paper.
Really fucking add one.
I could really just fucked the shit out
of you with my real dick to those rubber
thing.
I got up.
Tie on and strap in place and it wiggles
and doesn't,
but yet says scissoring probably feel
good because you open sores rubbing
against each other.
The most sensitive part,
they want to get stuffed.
They're missing a whole.
They're missing something in the middle
that want to get stuff,
dude.
Yeah,
but I mean you could throw a fucking
dildo and you're probably feels the same
or better.
I don't think so.
Flashlights,
they feel pretty fucking good.
I mean,
I don't know how Lesbians Vagina feels,
but I think heterosexual woman
desperately need to get stuffed.
That's why dudes desperately need to
stuffing in them and it just makes
sense.
What feels the best to you?
The magical fucking promise land to get
your hard supersensitive Dick inside the
word pussy.
And that's nature.
That's the.
That's the great reward.
The great reward is this intense
pleasure because that's the way you make
babies.
So for a woman,
the intense pleasure has got to come
from getting stuffed.
It's the owning that makes sense from
getting a big fat dick to shoot goo
inside you.
You know?
That's what it is.
I mean,
it's,
and it's a,
it's a staple of our life and it's this
big important part of our desires and
our motivation to do things,
but really it's just a trick to make
people you know,
and that,
that trick is got to be set up
correctly.
I mean,
people have been around for a fucking
million years in this form.
That trick is good.
They got it down and if it's,
if it's down,
they got a good,
then that means chicks must love big
fucking dicks inside them.
And if they do,
then scissoring is not going to be
enough.
It's gonna feel good,
it'll feel good.
But the reality is that actually wants
to get filled up and once you get
fucking stretched out with Cox on you
and looking at me and talking about
coffee all day long,
try to make it uncomfortable.
So I try to make you uncomfortable.
I'm damn well is that,
that's me laugh.
It was an earthquake.
We have much better sound now,
so when I'm laughing and what used to
not be annoying now it will be annoying.
This week we're using these microphones,
but next week we're going to have some
clip on jammies because this is
ridiculous.
You don't want to be standing here like
a standup comedian.
I do kind of like it though for the fact
if I need to like drink water or do
something,
I could go like this.
Yeah.
Maybe we should just leave it like this
because maybe getting a mic stand.
It goes right here though,
so we can.
Yeah,
we could totally do that,
but I just don't want anything that
knocks around it.
As long as we have the headphones on,
that's the move because for the longest
time we were doing this and I just look,
we're,
we're a couple of retards and we shoe
string this shit together,
but now it looks pretty killer.
We got like we had a mixer board and
shit.
I'll show you guys all this stuff.
By the way,
the autofocus is not something that you
could turn off.
It doesn't look like it.
We got all this shit here.
We've got a soundboard now connected to
the two laptops connected to this high
level MP3 recorded.
Jamey and it's all just mishmashed and
fucking sea of wires and that all
creates this podcast.
Hopefully that'll be enough.
So now that we have the sound issues out
of the way,
eventually we're going to have to deal
with this goddamn green screen.
That's step two.
I've.
There's a couple different options to do
it,
but all of them seem super fucking
complicated in a pain in the ass.
Yeah.
I think we just do a TV,
get a three D tv.
We can check shit out.
We can turn it on.
Things that we couldn't do it through
this ustream producer if we're going to
do it right.
The caster,
the fucking track asked her.
I think you can go through that.
I think you can do it through that.
So then we would have this entire,
the same audio setup.
I think that's just way overkill and you
do a tri caster,
three ustream producer now it just seems
weird post on twitter,
if anybody knows to give us a simple way
to do a green screen.
If you know,
if anybody knows,
throw me up some message or a link on
twitter at Joe Rogan,
there's got to be some tech audio visual
wizard out there that knows how to use.
We should tell you stream what's the
best hookup.
I don't think ustream knows.
Now.
They stopped doing those ads.
They have these ads that would pop up
every 30 seconds.
Remember there was a bunch of people are
complaining.
Well,
ads.
It wasn't just an ad that popped up.
It was like took over the sound and
audio and video.
That was ridiculous.
Who was it for?
Was it macy's?
Macy's.
Which macy's want to have anything to do
with me too because they have fucking
guns.
I'm talking about ghetto gaggers.
Where did you hear about that Dildo that
was discovered.
Twenty 8,000
year old though.
Did you hear about that?
Do you know?
How do they know that it was a Dildo?
Not just like an ear cleaner or like a
year care massager.
Big is your fucking ears side.
You know what I mean?
Because it looks like a big stone Dick
and it's eight inches long.
Maybe it was the preferred site was used
for something else.
What was it was used to strike flint's
too.
They had all these marks on it from
someone's striking flint's,
but that just could have been the
husband like,
give me that fucking vibrator.
GimMe Your Gimme your dildo.
I need to make a fire.
He got all angry and shit and he was
attacking the Dick,
you know,
it could have been that because that's
the reason why he used it as a dual
purpose instrument.
But that'd be a smart move to have,
you know.
I mean if you don't want to have that
many stones land around the cave,
you know,
why not use it for dual purposes.
I was in Portland and they had the or
that,
the biggest top rex with all the bones.
The best selection.
No.
T rex o,
t,
o really had the biggest collection,
a t rex,
and it was like,
I forget how many,
like 70 percent real bone.
Whoa.
Like the whole thing was up and it's so
weird sitting there by that skull of
this dinosaur and just thinking,
wow,
that used to be a fucking monster,
you know,
that was a real thing.
So weird that you're allowed to like go
up to it and touch it,
see it and wonder how many things
existed that there are not fossils of.
Because one of the things when you start
reading things about fossils and about,
you know,
archeologists and all these different
people are trying to dig up the past is
that it's really difficult to make a
fossil.
Like fossils don't just happen all the
time.
Like an animal has to get trapped in
mud.
They have to die and you know,
some sort of a landslide or something.
They have to be somehow or another
preserved,
which usually doesn't happen.
Usually when someone dies,
they rot in.
Their bones,
get eaten up by animals and their tissue
gets eaten up by animals and bacteria
and then they're gone.
They dissolve.
How many fucking things existed that
aren't in the fossil record,
you know,
properly.
There's a lot.
Probably the majority really thinks so.
You would think though that species
around for millions and millions of
years,
right?
Most of them,
you know,
they're around for a long period of time
and then eventually they die off and
before they die off for whatever reason,
we've had plenty of opportunity for at
least a few of them to get stuck places.
Right?
Right.
We did.
We know so little.
It's so crazy that we try to reproduce
the past or figure out what happened in
the past by studying what was left
behind.
It's like a giant crazy puzzle.
Wouldn't it be more?
Wouldn't it be incredible and maybe this
will be possible some day if they figure
out like say if they make a model like
of,
of the,
of the earth,
like they know like what existed as far
as like if you could do like a core
sample of the earth,
you can determine what the temperature
was like,
what the environment was like,
what animals and plants existed and what
if they could put all this data into a
computer.
What if they could put like core samples
and what we know about climate illogical
change on the shit,
put it into a computer with the known
all the known animals that exist today
and literally run a computer program
that goes backwards and evolution and
takes us to what existed tens of
thousands of years ago to 100,000
years ago,
a million years ago,
10 million years ago,
and you have to account for known
asteroid impacts,
known craters,
known things that probably wiped out
almost everything that they're going to
get to a point in time,
computationally,
scientifically,
technologically,
where they're literally able to recreate
the past with a computer.
Totally.
What the fuck son?
What kind of crazy world we live in?
A won't see it will be dead.
You think so?
I don't think.
I'm not that confident.
We might see the beginning.
I think we're going to see some crazy
shit.
Dude.
I think you with your bloody butthole.
You might not,
but me.
I'm going to live to be a couple more
decades for sure.
I've got a few decades semester still on
a 62 years old.
It looks like he's a fucking stud.
If he's alive,
he's alive.
I'm not going to last till next poet.
You know?
When do you think when you think you're
going to go Sunday,
Sunday,
don't say that I'm going to miss you.
Don't die to be reborn in your new
child.
Wow,
that's creepy.
Really creepy.
Cause I'm about to have a new child.
You don't even know it.
Brian died tomorrow.
Then my daughter woke up or came out of
the Pussy and looked at me and was like,
Hey,
I got with me at a strip club and
started saying things like that.
Brian says like first words like shit.
Brian says all the time.
We find a way to do it.
Don't come back as my child.
That would be just rude.
Very rude.
Let my wife soccer sucking on my wife's
ticks.
That's creepy.
Fucking Weirdo.
Why would you want to come back as a
baby?
A baby girl.
Start this party.
Can you imagine just coming back as a
baby girl and you have the mind of a
man.
Thirty four year old man trapped in a
baby girl that's fake dicks on Brian.
Oh Brian,
what's your fake Dick Talk.
Let's go to the chat.
See if there's anything interesting that
anybody has to say.
I'm going to urinate and what's this?
This is what's wrong with the Internet?
What's for me?
Link.
What the fuck is that guy saying?
If you survive the next 30 years,
you could possibly immortal through cell
regeneration.
Yeah.
That is possible.
Or it might even be weirder.
What the Ray Crets we'll idea is that
we're going to be able to download
consciousness into a computer.
That's a very possible idea.
You know,
if they can figure out a way to make
some sort of a reproduction of the human
mind,
like like some,
some sort of a computer that actually
whether it's a software or a hardware
issue where you reproduce all the
functions of a human brain and then
somehow or another download
consciousness into that computer and you
could use that and replicate it and you
can.
You could like literally exist in a
bunch of different fucking computers.
That would be very strange if it was all
happening,
like say if you downloaded your
consciousness into computers,
but your consciousness was still
attached to those computers,
so instead of you know,
you being able to live a different life
inside this computer would if like that
life is going on at the same time,
I can echo in your head and everything
you do is like doubled and tripled and
it's like you go fucking crazy because
your consciousness isn't a bunch of
different computers and all these
different things are going on at the
same time,
but it's all inside your head and you
can't fucking get away and you ruined
it.
So you gotta find the computers that
have your consciousness in it and
fucking killed them.
Just to stop the madness in your head
because there's a fucking crazy echo
because you're living a thousand
different lives all at once inside
fucking computers.
I didn't smell
like pussy.
I forgot to take a shower this morning.
It was like,
this is awesome.
How bad is it?
Good.
It's all good.
I love that she's not supposed to.
It's pussies to smells none or awful and
not supposed to smell,
but just that slight pussy where you had
slight pussy.
Yeah.
I think you're thinking that it's just
like pussy,
but really it's your dead loads.
That's what I think it is.
I think you're getting all excited
smelling your own loads.
That's what it is.
It's your own loeser trapped in your
underwear.
You might be right.
I think that's what it is,
man.
Probably my butthole smell
these rampage versus Rashad.
Who's going to win?
Listen,
Ladies and gentlemen,
I'm never,
never going to answer.
I don't know who the fuck is going to
win.
That's why they're fighting,
man.
That's the whole deal.
I'm not doing a comedy when I'm coming
to Vancouver this time because I was
supposed to do the Red Robinson theater,
but apparently they have some sort of a,
a,
a corporate thing that they booked out
for three days in a row and they can't
cancel it and that's the only time I'm
going to be there and they didn't want
me doing another club because I always
do their club.
I sort of have an agreement,
so it's a big theater.
So uh,
this time I'm not going to be doing
shit,
so I'm going to go find bad.
Bobby.
We're going to go eat steak like men
essentially around Vancouver.
Alright.
Other questions here?
See,
talk about overeem.
You don't even know overeem is.
You only follow UFC,
right?
You didn't see the strike force on
showtime.
You portfolio.
You missed out on everything.
I didn't know how.
Showtime Dude.
Alistair overeem is a motherfucker.
He beat the shit out of Brett Rogers.
Brett Rogers was that guy that fought
fate or last?
You don't care.
Don't give a fuck.
I don't care about something.
It's not that.
Not that fight.
Bumper sticker idea.
Real Catholics.
Fuck kids.
Wow.
Okay fellow.
So a lot of bad questions here in this
trap.
Do you know what Mark Emery is?
[inaudible] you know that guy's there.
Extraditing him or have extra added him
to America or just to spend five years
in jail for selling seeds.
Seeds that make people happy.
Pot seeds.
Meanwhile his own country.
Not only the,
not prosecuting him,
he was roaming the streets free.
You know,
he was fine and his own country,
he was fine and there extraditing him
because you know,
they're saying he's responsible for
millions dollars of sales of seeds here
in America and you know,
I ran a drug empire by selling
seeds.
You know what?
I pretty fucked up.
It's fucked up.
But you know,
I don't feel bad about because that's
the risk you take when you have to do
shit.
Like selling seeds and stuff like that.
You know what I mean?
You don't feel bad.
I mean I feel bad,
but I also like if I was selling
marijuana seeds,
I would know that hey,
there's a slight chance that I could be
fucked somehow.
But in his country that is not in his
country.
It's totally legal.
The problem.
He was shipping them to America.
If he never shipped them to America and
just sold them in Canada,
he'd be gold.
It sounds like he's dumb for Canada.
They don't give a fuck.
I mean they do when they have to deal
with shit,
but the reality is like,
it's like it's not really legal in
Vancouver,
but it's legal.
I mean they tolerate it,
they just let it,
let it happen.
Dad smoke shops
and shit,
just like answer them up there,
you know,
when you could just go and smoke weed
and this motherfucker was just out in
the open with it and selling seeds to
America and now they're,
they're extraditing him.
He's gonna have to do five years in jail
and he's not a young man.
That's a long ass fucking time to be
locked in a cage for a plant that makes
you a silly,
you know,
the fact that that's still even debated
in 2010 that would be wasting any
resources at all processing,
prosecuting anyone for pot.
It mean even a little bit.
Even if you know they're saying he broke
the law.
So what the thought is fucking stupid.
It's a dumb fucking law.
The law is stupid.
But he knew what he was doing.
So what?
It doesn't matter the laws.
Dumb.
Well then do it.
Yes.
But no,
he should be able to do it.
Know you shouldn't be able to put a guy
in jail for that.
That's ridiculous.
That in 2010 we got so many
discrepancies,
so many fucked up hypocritical
situations in our culture.
How about gambling?
How about the fact that dudes are
getting busted,
having poker games,
you know that people are getting busted,
like they're breaking open private poker
games and cops are coming and taking
money and shed.
I've read a bunch of stories about shit
like this happening where people are
getting in trouble for gambling,
playing poker with their own money.
I mean this is one of the reasons why
you have to go to these God damn Indian.
Not that there's anything wrong with it.
Any casino,
but you have to go to Indian casinos.
You can't have one.
You can have a casino like down the
street from your house.
It has to be in certain places and the
only place,
certain games in them,
you know,
I mean there's a lot of them in
California and was bellflower and
there's a few in most parts of the
country it's very difficult to find
casinos and you can't play poker online
because it's illegal.
So if you want to play online,
you have to go through like a third
party and it's like you have to like
send your money into someplace.
It's fucking all cryptic and weird and
you don't know what the fuck is
happening.
And it's all probably illegal anyway.
If you got in trouble for doing it the
way you're doing it,
even if you do it through a third party,
you could probably get some sort of a
fine or something for it.
I mean,
I don't know what they could do to you,
but it's illegal,
you know,
but me of the government has a fucking
lottery.
I mean,
you know,
the lotteries,
the worst odds available ever for
gambling.
You ever been stuck behind someone who's
a lottery?
Some poor fucking lady was in front of
me the other day at the gas station and
uh,
I'm,
I'm getting a gatorade with my gas was
gatorade theme day.
Notice that you had some gatorade and I
had some gatorade.
I'm going to gatorade and this poor lady
orders like 10 of these things and she's
like furiously scratching at these
tickets and you're like,
this lady's like addicted man.
Like,
look at her.
She's,
she's playing the worst odds ever.
She's bought 10 tickets.
What are the odds that any of them are
going to be any good?
Pretty fucking low.
Ever won anything from this before?
No,
I've won like 10 bucks.
I want a free ticket once I play the a
lot.
The lottery.
I won a free ticket.
I played that free ticket.
I lost.
I was done.
That was it never played again.
But the fucking,
the odds are astronomical.
And the,
you know,
the hook is that if you do,
when it's so much money,
oh my God.
You could do a dollar a dollar a dollar
for a hundred days.
Then all of a sudden you win $5,000.
Whoa.
And they put $100 investment in,
but it was worth it.
And then once you get that one,
$5,000,
you're like,
oh,
you get addicted to come in to win the
super fucking power ball jackpot.
$400,
million dollars be set for life.
You know,
still the government is the biggest
fucking dealer when it comes to addicted
gamblers.
You know,
the government is dishing it out.
You can,
you could,
you could gamble,
lottery and every fucking state
probably,
right?
Because they're a state where you can't
gamble state where you can't go to the
lottery thing.
So how about the Gundam stock market?
That's a fucking gamble.
That's a gamble.
It's legal.
Why can't you fucking play poker?
It's ridiculous.
We live in a goddamn nanny state.
The nanny state,
Brian.
So you think you're going to die.
Okay.
You look like shit.
It's getting worse.
Is it?
I don't know if it's just because I have
an aide in 20.
You haven't eaten in a long time,
man.
There's a low energy show and that's why
this guy won $500 and got a new flat
screen TV.
Well congratulations.
Quit now.
And you're way ahead.
That's a good move.
Taxes,
taxes.
yeah,
but here's the problem with the idea of
taxes,
when it comes to poker,
just made people pay taxes just like
strippers have to pay taxes.
They're not always right.
You know what I mean?
You know,
you just make people fucking make them
accountable.
You know,
if you really want me,
the whole tax situations,
pretty disgusting as it is,
especially if you're in a 48 percent tax
bracket.
Look,
a lot of people are.
It's gross.
The government should never get half of
your money.
That's fucking completely ridiculous.
You make 100 bucks,
they get 50 or 48 bucks.
That's stupid.
That doesn't make any God damn sense and
you've got to protect yourself and set
up a bunch of different shit so that.
So that they only take a small slice out
of your pie,
you know,
you gotta move to Nevada or you know,
open a corporation or do a bunch of
different stupid things so that you can
have a less money out there that they
get to steal from,
you know,
or
are you just taking an ass like me and
just give them all the money that you
got audited?
You got audited like a motherfucker what
happened son to make a video.
But the irs and it's sexy is gonna.
They're gonna audit me again this year.
What you did it because you use one of
those programs and you tried to take a
lot of different things on turbo tax and
then I used a home office and Blah Blah
Blah.
And they just don't like it when you
have a Home Office.
I guess they don't like it when you have
a lot of exemptions.
Is that what it is?
Well I would like right off,
like,
you know,
like electricity right off,
like gas and you know,
driving because it's a home office and
stuff like that,
you know,
or whenever I buy batteries and stupid
stuff like that.
But uh,
I thought Mike because I buy everything
online.
So what I was thinking is like,
Oh I have receipts for everything
because I use credit cards and I buy
online.
Well Visa and mastercard and all these
guys decided to hey,
we're not going to save all your stuff.
We're only saved the last year.
So they changed it where it used to be
like you'd have,
you could go back back.
I was able to go back like three years
and check out my statements like three
years ago,
but they stopped it.
So now it's only one year.
So I just lost like all my receipts.
So then when they never kept anything in
hard for them,
everything was online.
Yeah.
So I got kind of got fucked by that.
I wonder if they did.
They're
in cahoots.
That's what I'm saying.
What if the IRS tax rates contacts?
Mastercard says,
listen,
you don't have to keep that shit right.
Twelve years,
12 months,
that's enough.
Dude.
You don't have the whole shit for 10,
12 years.
Fuck them.
They should have.
They should have files.
It's not your responsibility.
I agree.
She's not ours.
I mean we were just providing the
service and yeah man,
fuck them.
Fuck the records.
Burnich hit.
What are they running out of?
Hard drive space over at Bank of
America.
I thought,
that's ridiculous.
Twelve kilobyte file.
You can't the fuck you fucking in bed.
The irs in itself is supposedly illegal.
All these wacky people that don't think
you should pay taxes.
What are the fuck does the money go?
That's the crazy thing.
When you really look at taxes,
there's no,
there's no receipt.
It's not like,
hey Mr Johnson,
you spent $30,000
in taxes this year and this is what we
did with your money.
We spent x amount on your local middle
school and x amount on this and you
know,
x amount went to that.
No,
you don't get a fucking receipt.
They're not accountable.
That's the problem.
That's why when you hear about like
crazy no bid,
you know,
contracts and you know that they're in
bed with these fucking Halliburton and
all these different companies that are
getting these crazy fucking contracts.
Then in money winds up missing and it's
like well they can't account for
billions of dollars and it's.
This is mad cluster fuck of money and a
big grab like who is stealing when it
comes to this bank thing,
this whole bank bailout thing.
When you look at the money and they talk
about $700,
billion dollars and all this money
flying left and right and people still
getting bonuses and is there,
is it really a.
They have an accounting system for all
this.
I mean,
can we really tell like where your tax
dollars went to this bailout and how it
was used?
They don't even have to fucking tell.
You don't even have to tell you,
but yet if you file a tax report,
motherfucker,
you better have receipts for everything.
You better have receipts for every God
damn thing you want an exemption for.
But when you ask them like,
what did you do with all my tax dollars?
What you,
you,
you used it to get these bankers.
Wait a minute.
These bankers set it up.
Do you know that they were shorting that
we're making sure that they were
protected on both ends.
There were selling clients a certain
stock and then gambling that that stock
was going to fail.
You should probably not talk about the
irs.
I should probably be quite right.
It's amazing.
Duncan trussell to gave me the best
advice.
Don't talk about the look of it is.
I'm talking about the whole system,
man,
man.
It's just,
it's incredible that it's set up that
way and that politicians don't do a
goddamn thing to change it.
Obama was swearing before he got into
office that he was going to end no bid
contracts and it just gave the former
company known as Halliburton.
I guess they changed their name to
something else,
but he just gave them some $500,
million dollar.
No bid deal.
Exactly what he said.
He wouldn't do that motherfucker run two
hours and 10 minutes Joe.
Well,
that's what Brian is saying that his
vaginas hurting.
It was buttholes bleeding and he's
tired.
Man.
Everybody's saying,
wake up.
People saying wake up or advantage at
that time.
Make up people are sad.
Fifty percent goes to the military.
Does it really?
Who the fuck knows?
Does anybody know when the actual
numbers are of money going into the
military?
All right,
let's take a couple of questions.
We go to the board,
see if anybody has anything interesting
to say.
And uh,
this is a trial and Hoodie,
by the way isn't mean the movie tron.
Look at you.
You really are a fucking Nerd,
Huh?
You're for real.
So a lot of dudes.
Fake nerdom,
right?
Stone Cold,
Steve Austin and Bruce Buffer.
We're unsure dog radio today.
Oh,
good times.
Good Times,
Ladies and gentlemen.
I think we went through the entire
broadcast without me saying bananas.
I said I tried to say like as little as
possible as well because like,
that's annoying.
Like man,
uh,
um,
is the feed usually choppy?
How many people on this stupid thing?
A thousand people.
That's all we ever get.
That's where we're good for her,
good for a thousand people.
Other than that,
people are going to bail out eventually.
I think these guys are just stirring.
You have anything planned?
They're just reading questions now.
It's been going on for two hours.
This guy says,
oh,
he's quoting me twice in my life.
I've developed blisters on my Dick from
jacking it and my suspicions are
confirmed.
There are others.
What does that mean?
Other suspicions?
Just trying to say
what do I think that e-cigarettes,
I think that chemical they use for the
smoke dries out your throat and causes
your throat to get fucked up so it
doesn't.
Yeah.
I mean I was spitting up blood from
using e-cigarettes,
so.
But that's you dude.
If you google it,
the chemical that they use for it is the
same shit they use in a.
it's an FDA approved chemical bites used
to make fog in nightclubs and one of the
things that does is dries out your
throat and my shit started getting
jacked up and now spitting blood and I
was like,
fuck this.
I'd rather smoke a cigarette.
Then this nonsense.
Really?
Yeah.
So I don't know,
so they're not good,
but don't they?
They help you quit because they just
fucking get patched.
That's helped me quit one day,
two days and I'm good.
Two days is all it took.
Now you were smoking for awhile before
this new girlfriend.
You have the old,
the old girlfriend?
No,
I don't mean about your situation.
I mean she smoked,
right?
Yeah.
Now I live with somebody that doesn't
smoke so it's easier.
But yeah,
when you live with somebody that smokes,
it's impossible to stop smoking when the
other person's smoking.
Yeah,
I can imagine.
You know,
if uh,
I get addicted to certain things.
Like for Awhile I was addicted to clean
out my ears at q tips.
I fucking love.
It feels so good.
You get in there and sardines,
sardines I was but wasn't really
addicted.
Sardines.
But the q tips,
man,
it's hard for me to walk by a box of q
tips and not want to stick one of my
year,
you know.
But if you live with someone and they're
all cleaning their ear,
making moaning noises like that,
it makes it even harder.
You know,
like I'm trying not to fucking my doctor
told me not to be sticking shit in my
ear.
I'm trying to do the right thing and you
overhear digging into your ear and Moan
and one time for real though,
I did put two q tips in my ear at the
same time and I took a shit.
It was the best feeling ever.
I was one of the best feelings ever.
My,
my ex had one in her ear and she
answered the phone and she went,
oh my God,
you tip shoved into her ear and a peer
stir here drowning.
Well,
she's retarded.
That's a dumb thing to do,
but yeah,
I could feel it.
That's painful.
Puncturing your eardrum.
I've heard of dudes getting your eardrum
punctured and fights a ruptured from
getting head kicked or punched in the
head,
punching the ear.
Your ear ruptures and then you can't
hear your ear and it's got to heal up
and sometimes they have to do surgery on
people's ears.
Guys have like an ear problems from
Jujitsu to like that.
A cauliflower ear BARF.
Sometimes it actually goes the bleeding
and the swelling goes inside the ear and
the insight ear can get infected.
Do Dave Terrell guy fought for the UFC
for awhile and um,
he's a very,
very accomplished grappler.
He's had some serious problems with his
ears where he's actually had to get his
ears cut off of his head.
They actually had it like peel his ears
back,
fix whatever the fuck was in it,
and then sew them back on his head.
Wow.
Yo,
that things like that make me not want
to stick a q tip of my ear,
but I couldn't imagine if I had a
cigarette thing,
if I had a cigarette thing and I was
living with someone who's smoking all
the time,
especially when they're stressed out and
they fucking fire that cigarette up and
you see the relaxation come across their
face.
I've seen it with you,
dude.
I've seen you talking about.
I've seen that.
Look on your face many times where
you've been freaking out.
Simon's been driving you crazy and you
got it sounds delicious right now.
And I see the relaxation.
Just the calmness wash over you.
What an evil trick,
and you know what the Communists
actually is.
It's actually just satisfying that
monkey on your back.
That's really all it is.
It's not like cigarettes make you calm.
It's that the lack of cigarettes makes
you tense.
And when you get that cigarette in your
system,
then you become calm.
Like what a terrible trick.
Like it's so goddamn addictive.
We're not talking about something that's
so addictive you have to do at once a
week,
you know,
that's addictive.
You know,
some people are addicted to certain
things and they have to do them like
once a day.
We're talking about every 15,
20 fucking minutes,
man.
That's crazy.
It's like twirling your hair.
It's nuts that it's so popular.
And how many people in America smoked
cigarettes?
Like 40.
It's a big fucking number and not a
single
fishing.
Never says that God damn thing about
stopping it.
Whatever.
Do what you gotta do.
Ladies and gentlemen,
that's my,
that's my advice to you next gig.
Um,
I don't have anything coming up to be
honest with you.
In America.
My next gigs are um,
June 17th and Saskatoon Canada,
June 18th at Grand Prairie,
Alberta and June 19th in Winnipeg.
So those are,
those are my next comedy gigs.
And then the next one,
the next big one in America is a.
well in June,
I'm at the,
um,
the Improv in Irvine,
but Brian doesn't have that up on my
calendar.
That's on the eastern counters.
Not been until fucking ustream calendar
updated son,
but that's a,
towards the end of June.
I'm at the Irvine Improv.
I don't remember.
20 something,
something something.
And then July second,
um,
at the,
house of Blues in Las Vegas,
if you want to find out the actual full
schedule,
you can go to Joe Rogan.net
and get it there.
They found a hole in space.
This guy says,
what are you talking about,
son?
You can't just say things like that in
capital letters.
They found a hole in space.
Do you mean a floating vagina?
What do you mean?
Is it a monster?
Butthole?
Why do you need to wear headsets?
Why?
Why do you care?
Why do you care for were headset,
sir?
What's wrong with you?
What is this whole in space or can I
Google hole in space and will you,
will you be vindicated or will it be
some fucking snopes debunked article
where there really isn't a hole in
space,
huge hole found in the universe?
Well,
these things take awhile to get to this
guy.
Maybe he's in Ohio.
The universe has a huge hole in it that
dwarfs everything.
Anything else of its kind.
The discovery caught astronomers by
surprise.
The whole is nearly a billion light
years across.
It's not a black hole,
which is small sphere of densely packed
matter rather.
Well,
fuck that old news.
Look at that.
What San Diego,
huge earthquake.
Just hit really that maybe a five point
something.
It looks like that's not huge.
Faggot.
Five point.
That's nothing.
That's the cow.
Is that California Nevada fault line?
Yeah,
exactly.
Where I was telling you last time.
How is your million?
Look at all these earthquakes,
so don't move to San Diego.
San Diego.
Oh,
that is pretty nutty.
They say the Pacific northwest is due
to.
They were talking about that in some.
I read about Oregon that Oregon's due
for another fucking gigantic blast.
Anyway,
there's a fucking hole in the universe.
The universe is populated with visible
stars,
gas and dust,
but most of the matter in the universe
is invisible.
Scientists know something is there
because they can measure the
gravitational effects of the so called
dark matter.
Voids exists,
but they're typically relatively small.
Well,
this fucking voice,
this Gargantuan whole was by examining
observations made by using the very
large array,
the Vla telescope in Chile,
funded by the National Science
Foundation.
Yeah,
there's,
there's some shit out there folks.
There's so much more shit out there than
we have mapped out and understand.
It's,
it's one of the reasons why we tune into
Fox News.
It's one of the reasons why we're
fascinated by who tiger woods is fucking
because the universe itself is too scary
and too much of a gigantic reminder that
we ain't shit.
And with that note,
ladies and gentlemen,
thank you very much for tuning into the
podcast,
the fleshlight.com.
Go there and buy something and fuck it.
It's,
it's way better than your hand and I
don't think it's that expensive.
How much are those things like 69,
79 bucks?
Is that really all it is?
It's worth it.
Thinking about how much money you spend
on dates with girls that you don't like,
hoping that you could fuck them when you
could save that and use that flashlight
over and over and over again.
It's people who go to clean it.
It's really not that hard.
Now.
I know.
You just hook it up to the,
put up to the faucet,
turned the faucet on your squirts out,
squirts out the back.
It's no problem.
It's not hard at all.
And then you get like a little squeegee
in there and ram it.
And how's the book coming?
The book is coming.
Good.
Um,
it's,
uh,
it's doing very well.
It's um,
uh,
it's weird and it's taken a long time.
Its takes a long time to write,
to actually write something out.
It would have been probably way easier
if I tried to transcribe it and just
talk,
but you know,
use like maybe a dictation program or
something like that.
But I don't think it'll be as good.
I think it's better to the.
It's a slow process to write things out.
But when you do just write things out,
you're forced to edit them and you're
forced to like go over them again and
see the.
Like the poetry of the,
of each sentence.
It's much,
much better for reading.
I think if you actually write it out,
if you actually just talk it,
sometimes you're,
you know,
you're going to.
It's not going to be as smooth as if
you've reviewed it.
It won't be done.
Its due in October.
That's when it's due.
It takes a long time to these fucking
things a lot longer than I thought.
Blogs are easy,
you know,
I blog put a blog up the most,
it's like 2000 words.
That's a giant one,
you know,
and that takes like six or seven hours,
but it doesn't matter because no one's
paying me to do it.
So it's like I try,
I do my best,
I do what I think it is and I throw it
up there.
Whereas,
like this,
I'm trying to put more attention and
focus to.
So,
uh,
that's it,
you know,
my twitter,
it's Joe Rogan,
you know,
my um,
website,
Joe Rogan.net.
And uh,
I told you about the upcoming dates in
June in Canada and in the Irvine Improv.
And then July second in Las Vegas at the
House of Blues will be a fucking party.
Looks like Sam Tripoli is doing that
with me.
It shouldn't be fucking crazy.
Sam Tripoli,
if you've never seen him.
Home areas.
Very funny guy.
Shout out to medic Hershey.
All right folks,
that's it for this week.
We will see you next week.
Same Bat time,
same bat channel.
It's almost always around the same time,
which is three P,
m pacific.
Thank you so much.
Red Band.
Love you,
bitch.