Young James or in the long form we can
do it.
One we can do on Papa is a motherfucking
author.
I'm a man of letters.
Now you're an author.
I'm an author.
I've always admired that and secretly
wished that I had not even so secretly
wish that I had the discipline to write
book.
You do have the discipline,
you just have to focus it on Mac.
You can do it.
How long did it take you to write this?
About two years.
That's too long.
No.
Cut that shorter.
Oh,
okay.
Like a little pamphlet or flyer?
Just make a short.
This is all I could do.
How long before you started writing the
book did you think about writing the
book?
Uh,
I've always kind of wanted to write a
book.
I know.
Well yeah.
I'm this one.
I had pitched doing a book,
I don't know,
like six years ago.
Pretty much the same concept and no one
was into it.
And then a couple of years ago through
two,
three years ago,
a publisher contacted my agent,
whatever,
and they had interest.
So we made a book deal and that changes
everything because now someone is
waiting for you,
you know,
you've got to turn stuff in and they
make books and it probably smart and you
don't want to seem like an idiot.
Did you have an editor that like went
over your stuff and said this is too
long?
This is too short?
Yeah.
They were pretty great.
They were pretty.
They just left the material alone.
There was a couple little things where
they're like,
you know,
you're repeating something or a that.
But mostly it was a,
a grammar kind of things.
Do you want to say it like this?
This isn't technically grammatically
correct.
Typos,
that kind of stuff.
They were pretty hands off about the
actual material.
And does it,
is it a book of essays?
Is it your life story?
What is it?
It's all on family.
It's called your dad stole my rake and
other family dilemmas and it's broken
down by,
uh,
by everyone in your family.
Like the basic thing is,
as a comedian,
I've been writing about family.
I'm looking at all everyone's families
for so long.
So I'm going to write about all of them.
So it's moms,
dads,
cousins,
aunts,
uncles,
all broken down chapters like that.
And uh,
so I talked a little bit about my family
and then I just talk about funny essays
about just life in general,
like going on family vacations or why
are you eating your shirt?
Um,
I don't know exactly.
There's a really cool photographer,
Sam Jones who's decided to get wacky.
He just,
uh,
this guy is like this amazing
photographer just done like clooney and
Damon and all these people.
And uh,
I asked him if he would help him when I
showed up.
We just taking some regular shots and
he's like,
I have this idea and brought out this
giant and put a tie on it and,
and just shot it.
And it came up pretty funny.
It looked like dilbert or beaker.
I was just trying to figure out what
you're doing,
I guess.
I guess what you're doing there is get
people to try to figure out what you're
doing there.
Yeah.
They stare at it and they're like,
maybe if I buy the book I'll figure it
out.
I'll understand the puzzles deep inside
I was being goofy.
When you write a book,
you have to think,
man,
someone could be reading this 30 years
from now,
50 years from now,
that is as Comedians,
you write something in the morning,
you bring it on stage,
they tell you if it's funny or not.
You know what you're working with,
you go back and forth.
This is like,
it's permanent and no one gets to review
it until it's done.
So the nerve wracking part of it was
like,
okay,
it's done.
I'm pretty proud of it.
I like edited it like crazy.
I've worked on it for a long time.
Will people think it's okay?
Will they not think it's hackable?
They think it's good with is the writing
okay.
All that other stuff and it's been out
now for a week and uh,
the review,
I can tell the reviews are good.
Like the people are reviewing it and
writing about it and calling and just
people just randomly.
And it's,
I'm over the hurdle.
The anxiety of is this a good book is
over?
Yeah.
People like it.
It's funny and it's people are saying I
can,
right,
so that is huge.
It's just calm me down completely
because you know,
like you said for 30 years,
whatever,
everybody's like takes a dump on it.
You'll have some that are really fucking
bad,
mean some comics,
someone should have just walked in while
they were running and grabbing them and
you're doing something terrible for your
future.
This is going to be around for a long
time.
People are going to refer to this
forever.
People in these like really self
righteous defensive modes and they're
writing things down and maybe like five
years from now they'd be like,
what the fuck was I thinking?
Yeah,
they're in the middle of writing it and
I've read some,
some shit.
Oh my God.
Really?
Tab.
Yeah,
just horrible stuff.
I,
uh,
no.
I'm,
I'm relieved.
I'm not excited.
I'm just relieved like Oh,
okay.
It's good.
It was good.
I thought it was good.
I hoped it was good.
My editor said it's good.
People are saying that the laughing when
they're reading it,
like editors who don't normally say that
kind of stuff.
So writing a book,
writing with writing stand up,
like how do you.
Ah,
how,
how'd you divide your time?
It was um,
it was tough.
You stand up whenever I'm working on
something else,
stand up kind of.
I work on it at night,
you know,
and the book was,
I got into this rhythm of going in every
morning,
get up at seven,
go in with my coffee and sit there and
that was booked time until noon.
I would try and just just work on that
and make it a.
But that wasn't for two years.
That was like the last,
you know,
year to eight months kind of thing
before that.
It's a little looser.
I'm trying to get it done and stuff.
But that real discipline of like coming
in every morning,
sitting down and seven days a week just
writing,
just write wherever I was,
whatever I was doing,
I had to make sure that I had that time.
If I'm on a plane with him in a hotel,
I'm on the road.
I was just writing the thing all the
time.
It just became.
Because he's,
you know,
the biggest challenge for me,
and I think a lot of writers is that you
judge yourself as you go,
you're like,
is this good?
Is it to.
But you have to just get it down and
know that it's bad.
Just just get it down.
I want to write this chapter on crazy
ants,
so I'm just going to write it and spit
it out and then I'm going to go to work
on it like a bit,
you know,
like,
uh,
like stand up and just go back and just
start editing and peeling back and
peeling back,
getting rid of,
using when you're doing this.
I did it all on word,
Microsoft word and
scrivener.
Do you know what scribner and scribner
is really interesting.
I did my last special on scrivener.
Oh yeah.
It was the first time I've used it for,
uh,
for running standup.
And what's good about it is on the left
hand side you have a,
like all of your different subjects.
Yeah.
And you click on each subject and then
there'll be a whole column.
So like I had the title strange times
and then the left hand side,
this is,
this is what it looks like when you're
looking at the chalk,
the cork board,
the corkboard is one aspect of it where
you have these little cards like index
cards and you said these index cards up
and you know,
you're right.
All the different things on the index
cards,
but you can organize it outside of the
index cards.
There's also on each index to index the
corkboard.
It corresponds to each individual
subject,
like say like say if I'm doing a bid on
desks,
right?
So I have desks on the lefthand side and
then I'll write out all the stuff on
desks,
but there's also a corkboard tab.
Right.
And then so I have all the different
things to make sure that I covered all
the notes.
Good Dude.
I like it a lot.
Yeah,
I'm going to try that.
What I like in life,
this is not really showing why I like
it,
I like it is because you can have.
You can move all those little chapters
around and move all the bits around.
Like for standup.
That's great.
That's really good.
Yeah.
The organizing it gets so in your head
starts bogging you down.
But the good thing about this was that
it was essays,
so each one's like four or five pages,
right.
So I would just be like literally just
open up the file and go dad's,
alright,
I'm going to go to work on this one,
Dad,
no gifts for dad.
And then just boom,
just edit that,
put it away,
go to the next,
you know,
just I could just bounce it.
I didn't when I'm trying to say is I
didn't have to keep track like a novel.
It didn't have 300 pages of flow,
you know,
they were all just hits so it was kinda
similar to stand up that way.
You know,
like I could just go to work on them.
But it's fascinating.
I,
I really loved it.
Like I've had friends that have written
books,
like Collin Quinn came and did a book
event with me a couple of weeks ago and
he's like,
and he wrote a book.
He's like,
I'll never do it again.
I just hated it.
I couldn't stand it.
I hate it,
and he's a prolific guy.
He writes a lot for his one man show.
He's always right and showing US
history.
Yeah,
the guy writes a lot,
but the writing for the book drove him
crazy.
I really loved it.
I couldn't believe that you could look
at a five page essay and find something
wrong with it.
Every time you looked at it,
every time.
Why am I saying this?
They know this.
Why do I have to say he?
He sat down at the table and ate his
breakfast.
He ate his breakfast.
You know,
like you could just peel stuff away all
the time and get it as as a direct as
possible,
and I started to really just love the
love that Jordan Peterson told me.
He wrote his first book and it took him
15 years because he went over every
single line every single day,
like a critic trying to find fault in
everything that he did until he felt
like he got it done.
It was on a cold war.
She really wanted to make sure that he
had the subject matter completely locked
down.
Yeah,
that's daunting.
You're dealing with something that
people can fact check.
People can fact check what happened to
me and putting my sister in a garbage
can in fourth grade.
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
It was family.
It's all about family.
It's all about like the joy of being
with other people and,
and the aggravations and all that kind
of stuff.
So it was just.
And I write,
I,
you know,
I have a lot of that in my act,
so it was definitely in my wheelhouse.
Like I'm not reading,
I'm not reading books about the Cold
War.
You're going to write another one?
I am going to write another one.
Have you started yet?
Uh,
no I haven't.
Which is a,
I have a couple ideas and uh,
and the publisher wants me to write
another one already.
Didn't want you to write another one.
Yeah,
I think a good sign.
that's a good sign.
It's,
we're the number one new release and
family humor.
Ooh.
So it's like you had any potty words in
there?
Very little.
Like 10.
And it would be a lot cottony see words
in there.
Which one?
The cunt word.
Oh my Lord.
Yes.
There's a whole.
There's a whole chapter.
This is the problem with family,
female,
just period now it's uh,
it's actually pretty clean.
I don't know if there's A.
I don't know if there's anything in
there that I think there might be one or
two words.
One or two.
Questionable.
Yeah,
there might be a shit or A.
I don't think so though.
It's pretty clean.
Yeah.
Good for you.
And he put anything in there on bread?
Yes,
there is.
Yes.
The final chapter is a.
just eat the bread.
Really?
Yeah.
It's called just eat the bread and it's
all.
It's all a chapter of basically using
bread as a metaphor for just enjoy your
life.
Right?
Don't,
don't turn it away.
Don't get all balled up.
Once in a while.
Just a little.
Just do it.
Should I segue into my big announcement?
You've got a big announcement.
I have a huge Joe Rogan podcast
announcement.
What is huge?
The book is huge and it's a great
father's day gift and everybody should
buy it.
But as we all know from being on the
show that,
uh,
I am the salt and of sourdough.
Yes.
And my reputation as a baker is because
of the show hands down from doing your
show.
Your fans are so awesome and started
just sending pictures of their bread.
We have this nonstop relationship of
help.
Fred,
they show me their failures.
They're constantly sending these
interactions.
I'm in cities.
People are bringing bread.
And when I would travel I would go in
and visit bakeries when I was on the
road.
So the big announcement is the food
network,
uh,
asked me to do a show about bread and
baked goods.
Whoa.
So I have a new show coming out on the
food network on Labor Day called baked
with Tom Papa.
Wow.
And I travel around,
kind of like a diner's driving kind of
thing,
but with all baked goods and meeting
these amazing people that make the
stuff,
getting their stories,
these families,
these Turkish families in Italian
families or whatever.
And then,
uh,
showing all of this amazing,
amazing stuff that they're making all
because of this show.
Why?
I have to thank you.
One hundred percent.
It is,
it was a hobby of mine that I completely
loved and got into.
But after doing this,
it just kind of exploded.
And uh,
and now we're going to be.
I just finished shooting them all.
That's awesome.
Yeah.
How many do you shoot?
We shot eight into ward eight different
cities,
New Orleans,
New York,
Detroit,
La,
cleveland,
a Philadelphia,
New Jersey,
northern New Jersey,
which is where I grew up.
Uh,
yeah,
eight different ones.
It's going to stay in labor.
It so silly.
I mean,
literally,
you know,
how many.
I've been writing scripts.
I've been auditioning,
I've been acting whatever to compete on
television.
I started making bread with my daughter.
That's,
that's my show.
It seems like that's the best way.
Anyway.
It's the thing that you actually enjoy
and really love,
you know,
a 100 percent.
Find that thing that you're really
passionate about and turn that into a
show rather than.
Yeah,
some Sitcom that you're really not that
excited about other than being on
television.
That's exactly right.
Like I had no,
I was doing this anyway.
I didn't have any of the,
of trying to get a show on the air.
Like when I've written pilots and you're
like,
oh,
I hope it go.
This was just so natural because it's
just what I'm doing.
So it completely.
And you hear that a lot.
We'll just will come from something you
love and something and you hear that a
lot.
You're like,
well I love working in an office and
having a girlfriend.
I'll make a show about that.
No,
you don't.
Not really,
you know,
really.
But uh,
but that,
this actually just it,
you can't force it.
It's just,
it's just organic.
And this one was organic.
Did you link up those different cities
with comedy shows?
Did you do standup in those cities when
you were traveling?
I did just like pop in and Neil Brandon
and I did a show in New Orleans.
I did a show in Cleveland when I was
there just as like pop in.
I didn't like promote it.
And do it while it was there.
So you just concentrating on filming?
Yeah,
I was just concentrating on film and
we'd go in for like three days.
I'd meet like four or five different
bakers and uh,
it was cool.
Just,
you know,
just dealing with these people is
amazing.
That's awesome man.
No one gets into baking because they're
an asshole,
you know what I mean?
No one says I'm going to bake cookies
and they're an idiot.
These people bake them cookies and they
got to like it.
Oh No,
it's.
I mean,
it's a.
food is a fascinating thing to me is a.
I mean,
I guess this is a good time to bring it
up as any.
Um,
you know,
obviously Anthony Bordain took his life
last week and um,
he was a friend of mine and it was real.
That was real hard.
Friday was real hard.
Uh,
woke up and I got a text from my friend
Maynard from tool.
Maynard said so much for the Keenan
versus bordain celebrity Jujitsu match.
And he was like,
fuck.
And I was like,
oh no,
what does that mean?
And so then I googled it and I saw it.
I was like,
Oh shit man,
I can't fuck what?
Yeah,
just why he hung himself.
Like,
what?
Yeah.
I don't know.
Were you,
did you know his demons?
Was friends with them?
Hung out with him,
got fucked up with them.
Did you get a feeling that he had that
in him?
I didn't know that,
but what was really weird,
it was like he'd been saying really
recently that he'd never been happier.
He was talking about his girlfriend and
saying that it never been happier.
Didn't know it could be that happy.
Didn't know someone could make them that
happen.
Oh man,
I have so terrible.
But who knows?
They might.
Might've been.
Might've broken up.
Who knows?
I don't know.
I don't.
I mean sometimes people when they say,
I've never been that happy,
you're catching them on these ups and
downs.
You know,
some people,
you know,
people get manic,
right?
I don't know if he was,
but some people get,
they get up and down.
I'll tell you what,
he,
he liked to get fucked up,
you know,
he liked to drink.
Yeah.
You know,
and he enjoyed it.
It was,
it was something that he enjoyed.
But we,
um,
we did an episode of this show.
We went hunting for pheasants in
Montana.
We cooked over this campfire.
He cooked tastic and really,
and then afterwards we drank whiskey and
a smoke weed and he goes deep.
He goes,
Dave,
really where I'm sitting down,
I'm like,
I'm going to just try to catch myself
real.
The world spinning,
deep breath,
deep breath.
He's like,
where's the fucking weed?
They just kept going.
He just kept going.
But I knew he drank.
I didn't know he smoked weed.
Yeah.
He,
um,
he had a heroin problem when he was
younger and he kicked it,
but he didn't feel the need to just be
sober.
Yeah.
That was kind of interesting about him.
That's a,
that's a thing you would get sober from
a drug.
They feel like they have to get sober
from everything.
Yeah.
That did not feel like that.
And he,
by the way,
like he would drink,
but when he was home,
like with his kid and he's homeless man,
he didn't drink at all.
Like he would only that,
he would only do that when he would be
on the road.
Right.
So He'd be stretches of time and he
didn't drink at all.
And he was addicted to Jujitsu.
That was,
that was.
Oh really?
Yeah.
He was doing Jujitsu like literally
every day when I was hanging around with
him,
he was um,
he went,
we were in Montana.
He went to Bozeman to find a local
Jujitsu club and trained with them in
the morning.
She just trained with everybody.
I never,
I hardly ever did that on the road.
Find a place I would just go to the gym
and workout wouldn't.
But he was so into learning and getting
better at Jujitsu.
Do you know if he was on prescription
for depression or anything like that?
I do not.
That's what I'm so suspicious of.
Like when you heard of like Robin
Williams and Chris Cornell?
Yeah,
there's like he was on anti anxiety
medication,
anti anxiety medications,
a big one that stuff like it even,
you know,
in their,
in their long list of side effects.
It's always suicidal thoughts and then
if you mix it with other things like
alcohol and this,
and I don't know at all who was on what,
but it seems what bothers me is that
it's not part of the conversation.
Well Robin is a different take because
robin had lewy body disease.
Um,
he had a heart attack.
He had significant issues with that.
Um,
my friend Dr Mark Gordon actually wrote
a paper about long term Cesia
like when you're under the longterm,
but like long duration for things like
open heart surgery,
right?
That there's a high instance of
depression afterwards and a lot of
people coming of these
big time operations where you get
anesthesia for long periods of time and
have significant dips in their hormone
levels afterwards.
It's very,
you know,
it's not like a free ride getting put
under and having your heart opened up.
And I mean your body goes through
massive trauma.
Your body body's like,
Holy Shit,
we just had our chest plate split open
and your heart gets worked on or inside
of us.
Yeah.
And there's a significant correlation in
Mark Gordon's opinion between
depression,
postsurgery,
postsurgery depression,
and I think it's something that people
need to look at.
He had that obviously because he,
he did have heart surgery for a long
period of time.
The depression.
Lucky enough to that because I know
people get.
I always thought it was just a mental
thing of like,
you know,
surviving something.
Like I remember letterman on a show like
weeping and like bringing in his staff
on and stuff.
I always,
I didn't know it was a hormone thing.
I was thought it was just the trauma of
surviving that I think it can be both.
And I mean,
I'm sure.
I mean I'm obviously no doctor,
but he was,
I'd say you're closer to a garbage man.
But he was uh,
explaining it to me the,
that there is an issue with this.
And so robin had that and he had some
serious neurological disorders and um,
and there was quite a few other things
too,
right?
They're also complicated.
Yeah.
And then whatever medications,
this is the thing,
right?
Like what are these medical,
what's on,
you know,
you don't really don't know,
but I'm chester from Lincoln Park.
He was on a shitload of things and he
was.
But he was very troubled me.
He was a guy that was,
he had some real problem,
but he was also very medicated.
I mean,
look,
we have the highest suicide rate among
middle aged people in America than ever,
like the numbers.
The numbers are through the roof and
there's also this pharmaceutical opioid
crisis at the same time.
And I just feel like,
you know,
people are on this shit that's really
affects your head and your mood.
And it says right in it.
Like I remember I had a friend whose
brother was a depressed,
and this was the eighties when we were
kids and the the game,
lack of a better word of trying to get
the right medicine for him because when
he,
when they prescribe the wrong one,
things got out of hand.
I mean like really dangerously out of
hand,
and then they finally find the right med
for him and then he kind of groomed
like,
no,
there's no obvious path.
The problem is it's like say if you have
some particular type of infection,
they give you antibiotics.
If you have poison ivy.
Yeah.
They,
they know what kind of cortisone cream
to put on your what have you when you're
depressed.
Yeah.
There's
so many different factors involved in
depression.
There's your actual life,
right there is what's going on in your
life.
Like are you taking care of your body?
Are you exercising?
Do you have loving relationships with
your family and close friends or do you
feel distant and detached,
you know,
do,
do you not have anyone in your life like
romantically do you not have a job that
you enjoy?
All those things factor into the way you
feel about life and from the time you
were a kid.
Sure.
Jared whole life,
your whole life and then on top of that
you have like legitimate mental illness
and then you have depression because
your brain is not producing enough
serotonin or dopamine and there's so
many factors and people try to self
medicate and I know a lot of people try
to do it with extra exercise apparently
seems to be as effective or more
effective than most ssri
antidepressants.
I heard that.
I don't know if I'm right,
but I remember hearing that whatever
your body manufacturers or secretes when
you exercise is similar to what a lot of
these drugs
having them.
Well,
you definitely get runner's high,
right?
Right.
Yeah.
There's high.
You actually,
um,
your runner's high.
I don't know the exact mechanisms
involved,
but it has something to do with the
cannabinoid receptors,
so it literally gives you a high.
That's similar to almost like a
marijuana hot,
right know?
Yeah.
You get your euphoric.
Oh yeah.
You get like,
I love it.
Yeah.
I love running and just feel even when
even if it's not identified for me as a
high,
like,
like smoking weed,
my whole rest of my day is better.
Like there is.
There's a happy little thing going on
that's,
you know,
not flying,
but I'm definitely not balled up and
anxious the way I was before the run.
Yeah,
that ball up an anxious thing.
I have my own theory about that.
I think the human body has physical
requirements and I think if you don't be
just because of the design of it,
the fact that human beings have lived
for thousands and thousands of years
either hunting or gathering or running
away from danger or your body's like
constantly inaction back then.
We essentially have the same bodies as
people that live 10,000
years ago.
Our DNA is very,
very similar and I think we have all
these requirements that we don't meet
them and there's so many people that
just sit down all day and that's all
they do.
They walk to sit down and they sit down
again and most of their time of sitting
down,
whether they're watching television or
sitting in front of their computer and
that shit is terrible for you.
Terrible.
Yeah.
And you feel it.
You just feel shitty.
You just,
you feel bad.
I was in after the,
after the Bordain News,
I was traveling outside of Chicago and
it just kind of clicked in my head like,
you know,
you're just thinking whenever you have
someone that inspires you and especially
if your friends like you were,
uh,
you know,
it's just,
you can't get it out of your head kind
of a thing and you're balled up.
Anxiety is even worse.
And I just instinct instinctually got
in,
put on my running shoes and just went
for a run because I didn't want to sit
and think about all of it so much and I
just felt better like I was.
It wasn't euphoric again after the run,
but I was definitely better than before.
I feel like,
especially when you're traveling and
stuff like that.
But he did Jujitsu all the time.
Cds or puzzles.
These are puzzles we can't solve.
Well,
yeah.
Who knows?
I don't know what was going on.
Yeah.
No,
and there's no way to ask him obviously.
Um,
yeah.
When I,
when I traveled,
one of the first things I do,
whether I'm coming home or going there,
it's workout.
Yeah.
And I didn't this weekend because Friday
when I got there I worked out Thursday,
so I'd worked out that day already.
I ran that day and then I got there
Thursday night,
woke up Friday to that text and I was
just like,
fuck man,
I didn't want to do anything.
I cried.
Yeah.
I felt like shit.
Got a bunch of phone calls from some
friends and then I had two shows that
night and I was like,
I just got a,
just got to get on the horse her up.
And it was a little worried.
I was a little worried that I was going
to be like moody or weirded out.
Yeah.
But once I got there I was fine.
The emails with the San Tino and Tony
Hinchcliffe.
Nice.
So those two guys are great.
Just had a fun time.
We talked a little bit about it and
smoked a little weed.
Nice.
Got Up there and just had some fun
and the energy of the crowd.
I saw your instagram of the crowd and
this beautiful theater.
That's an amazing theater.
You can't have it.
It'd be tough to be depressed and do it
with all those fans in that 100 people.
Yeah.
We did two shows.
Two,
they were both great.
Oh,
they looked killer font.
Awesome town man.
Great food people.
It's a combination of in the big city
and like Midwest,
like friendly people.
Yeah.
And the summer becomes a totally
different city too.
I was old.
I'd always gone my whole career in the
winter and then literally just like
three years ago,
went in the summer and I was like,
Oh man,
this place is amazing.
The parks and the festivals and it's
great.
Even in the winter,
the winter's gigs there
in December and January I,
yeah,
it's like they're happy to be inside.
Exactly.
And that you came through the cold to
see them.
Yeah.
But the,
but,
but back to the food thing.
Uh,
I mean the stories that Bordain told
through food,
whereas just,
I mean,
amazing.
That's why he reached so many people.
You could sit with that show and he
really took his time and you've really
felt like you were,
you had been there.
Well after he,
after he left us an episode.
Yeah.
He made me think of food as an art form.
I never thought of as an art form before
watching no reservations,
his original show.
I've watched that show and I just
wouldn't feel like,
oh,
this is not what thought it was.
I thought it was
just like,
oh,
this guy knows how to cook yummy food.
That's great.
But then then watching his show I was
like,
oh,
this is art.
Like these guys are treating this like a
painting or sculpture or something like
that.
And then they're passionate and they're
all tattooed up and Weirdos that they're
artists.
They're just artists that cook.
That's right.
It might as well be making music or
painting,
whatever it would be,
drawing their artists
at its best.
Yeah.
You know,
in the same thing with like within any,
any other art form.
Then there's people that just crank it
out and see a way to make money and you
can tell there's a difference,
but once you stuff from an artist,
you're spoiled because then you're like,
oh,
these people don't care as much.
This is technically,
this is Lasagna,
but ah,
the same.
I know.
It's fascinating.
It's,
it's,
it's interesting.
The approach is very,
um,
it's very contagious.
Yeah.
You watched the way they cook and you
watch like their,
their passion for the food.
It makes you hungry.
You want to eat and you also want to try
it.
Yes,
I do.
Yeah.
I always want to try it.
Always,
always.
It's fascinating.
Like,
you know,
going around and meeting all of these
bakers.
It's like they all got into it because
there's a love there and then it's
really hard work.
Like these people work there,
you know,
2:00
in the morning,
they're baking,
they're like in there,
like,
I know it sounds so silly,
but anytime I'd walk into a coffee shop
or a bakery or something and just see
that whole,
like a whole display case filled with
stuff seems like it's always been there
and you don't now meeting the people,
these poor bastards who are making it
every day at 2:00
in the morning.
It's hard,
hard work and the only way it seems that
they can continue to do it is because
there was that initial love of it.
The deep,
deep love.
They learned it from their grandparents
or they just went to school and figured
it out and they just hooked them and
that like,
it's enough of a big bang explosion of
love that they stay in it for like 10
years and make a business out of it.
My grandfather used to walk to get bread
every day.
We would,
uh,
he lived on North Ninth Street in North
New Jersey.
Oh yeah.
And uh,
which was at one point in time and
Italian community,
right.
It wasn't when he lived there,
when he died,
but,
but when I was a boy,
we would go,
um,
we would leave his house,
wound visit,
stay there,
we'd leave his house,
we'd walk like three or four blocks down
the street to this bakery that he had
been going to for probably 30 years.
And these people,
this was like an old town in bakery.
Those white paper bags put the loaves in
and you go there.
They would go there every day and get
Italian bread every day,
every day,
get fresh bread.
And the bread was good for about a day
or two.
Like if you got the second day I was a
little dry and
stale,
but if you got it that day boy sliced
the bread and you know,
my grandmother made a homemade pasta she
made from scratch,
from,
from flour and eggs,
add the whole thing,
make Lasagna,
make these.
And it was just fucking sensational.
It's the best.
He's the best.
And you know,
there's the thing like when someone
makes something really good in the
community,
it changes the community because people
will walk to get it in the morning,
just making something real quality.
All of a sudden it's like,
it just starts attracting people.
It's fascinating.
It is fascinating.
Did your parents,
your grandparents come over from Italy?
They were born there.
Oh yeah.
What part,
mom?
Well,
different parts,
but cecily and Naples.
Mine says and Naples.
Yeah.
That's funny.
So is Rogan,
which that's Irish.
That's my grandfather came from Ireland.
My grandfather on my father's side came
from Ireland.
My grandmother on my father's side came
from Italy.
So one quarter,
one quarter.
Irish.
It's funny,
we were one quarter German all the rest
of Italian and it's amazing.
So did they speak Italian?
Yeah,
yeah.
They spoke dialect to.
Oh yeah,
you would.
You'd know what the fuck they were
saying.
Even if you spoke Italian,
like if you spoke proper Italian and
listen to my grandmother and my
grandfather yell at each other,
the other know what the fuck they were
saying that each other is so much to so
credit.
They really,
yeah,
it was when I was a little kid,
I'd go over the house,
I'd have to hide.
They would start yelling.
My grandmother was late for everything.
Everything she ever did,
she was laid for and my grandfather's
name,
my,
my family was very unoriginal.
My father's name was Joseph.
My grandfather's name is Joseph.
My Grandmother's name is Joseph.
My name is Joseph,
so it's like a lot of fucking jokes.
But you call your grandmother grandma,
grandma,
grandma.
But when,
uh,
when I was over there,
I remember my grandmother was always
yelling at my grandfather's whether we
got to leave,
we got to leave and she would get crazy.
It would fucking get crazy.
I was always scared of marriage because
it was part of the reason why I was
scared of my grandparents were always
yelling at each other.
I was wanting to get the fuck away,
man.
I was just how they communicated back
then though.
I remember my,
my grandparents too,
like,
just shy,
like veins popping out.
Well,
they,
they grew up in the hard times,
man,
when my grandmother had a stroke and um,
when they were taking care of her,
they started finding these little
pockets of money that she had squirreled
away in the house right over the house,
like coffee cans,
passionate,
because during the depression,
yeah,
people just,
they,
they realize like,
oh my God,
it can get to a point where there's no
food,
like nothing,
nothing
and people starved to death.
That's really possible.
It was the reality in the United States
going through that was far better than
like say Europe post World War II or the
Soviet Union where you know,
it was worse there.
Oh fuck man.
People Starve to death.
Who knows?
Untold,
how many people starve to death in the
Soviet Union,
starve to death.
I know that sounds selfish,
but I only thought of it in terms of
America.
Of course the whole time.
Oh,
of course.
Well,
you,
Russia,
Russia took it really bad.
Russia to World War Two.
Very,
very bad.
And these people that grew up during
that era.
When my grandparents came here,
my grandfather came here.
I think when he was seven and it was
during the depression,
so it was like the worst.
Yeah,
of the early thirties and you know,
my grandmother was similar age.
They just had this,
this mentality like it could all go
away.
They had a,
they had seen it yet it was burned into
them and you know,
kids today,
everyone's like fucking leaving food on
their plate.
No one's worrying about where it's
coming from and everybody thinks they
had a totally different mentality.
They were scared big time.
Yeah.
I mean they had,
they had nothing and they would save
everything.
Every little piece,
every little something like,
well,
tin foil and think about how messed up
it is that they go from that.
They go from the depression,
they get out of it and then you roll
into World War II,
like these people,
they dealt with a lot of different
levels of stuff that we didn't have to
deal with.
Yeah.
I mean,
Tim Kennedy,
who was a guest of mine recently,
a friend of mine said something very
profound.
He said,
hard times make tough men.
Easy Times make weak men.
Yeah,
but hard men make easy times.
Nice.
You think about it that way.
Yeah.
Hard,
hard times.
Make tough men.
Tough men make easy times.
Easy Times.
Make weak men.
Yeah.
It's like a fucking growth cycle when
people are always like,
kids today,
kids today don't know.
Well,
it's because they haven't gone.
No you can't.
You can't manufacture that for them.
My Grandmother,
this is a funny story.
I'm on nine slash 11.
I was a in New York.
It was at Newark.
You don't hear that a lot.
By the way.
This is a funny story.
Nine slash 11,
but I was at Newark.
I was flying out that day and we watched
the second plane fly into the.
You saw it.
So the second one I saw it saw it on
television.
No.
You know what Newark,
you look right across it.
You were looking at you actually
literally across a 100 percent.
I was the first planet hulk was going
through your mind when you saw it hit.
Well,
the first one hit on before we got
there,
before I got there and I walked with a
pilot down,
like through the airport and he said,
hey,
I think it was assessing,
uh,
you know,
just kinda crazy.
And um,
so I'm down there and I,
I was at the,
at the desk and I said I was going to
Chicago and I said to the woman working
the thing,
I said,
do you think we're going to fly out
today?
You know,
do you think we're going to actually get
out?
And a guy yells,
here comes another one,
this man,
just like a businessman.
And we all turned and you could just see
it streaking across right into the small
plane.
Look small but just so insane.
So I sit down,
I just sat,
we just.
And I was sitting with an artist,
a middle aged man who was an artist and
then we heard about the Pentagon as we
were sitting there.
And he opened up his little art case and
it had all these razors in it,
like razor blades and stuff from his
artwork.
Like,
you know,
he's a commercial artist and he's like,
this is all going to change.
He said,
you know,
people are just,
they let me on the plane with this and
we're just sitting there like,
just freaked out,
like calm but freaked out.
And I was calling my wife who was in New
York and woke her up and we were trying
to talk and she was going to the thing.
And uh,
at one point that the artist I was
sitting with just looked at me like in
my eyes,
like we're trying to understand what was
happening.
He said,
I think we should go home now.
I was lucky.
Yeah,
yeah,
right.
Of course we should after sitting there
for 20 minutes so I can't get back into
New York.
I can't get back into the city.
Time's gone by and I'm in a cab going up
the parkway in New Jersey and there's
just dust where the towers were.
And I'm like,
Holy Shit.
So I can't get in.
So I go to my Nana's house who lives in
by giant stadium and uh,
because she's the closest to the city,
I can't get into the city.
So this a driver takes,
takes us over and I get to my Nana's
house and she so excited to see me
because her grandson was visiting and
she lives alone now.
My father,
grandfather had passed and I'm sitting
in front of the TV and I'm like,
Nana,
like I first I hugged her and I was
like,
oh,
weepy.
Like I was shaking,
you know,
I didn't know what was happening.
And she's like,
oh,
it's so nice to see you get in here and
visit.
This is so great.
Like you see what's happening second.
Oh,
I know it's a crazy world.
And I sit in their little tiny living
room den area and we have the TV on and
she's trying to talk to me and I'm
trying to watch the television.
And she,
this is the world war mentality.
Uh,
I am again and I'm kind of avoiding
talking to her.
And she goes,
all right,
well look,
I have a bridge game or a card game with
my lady friends here.
Take half of my sandwich.
She reached it,
opened the tin foil,
gave me half of a tuna fish sandwich
goes,
you eat this,
I'm going to go play cards with my
friends and we'll have dinner after.
You'll be okay.
And she walks out.
Wow.
But they were tough.
They dealt with so much.
I hadn't dealt with anything.
I'm freaking out.
Not freaking out.
She's like,
it's a crazy world.
She wasn't like,
you know,
Alzheimer's.
She was just,
hey,
you know,
we lost a couple of buildings and a few
thousand people.
Here's half a sandwich.
I'm going to go play bridge.
I'm going to play bridge.
We got to keep moving.
Tomorrow's another day.
But that's how they live.
Both my grandmothers were that way.
Just completely like plow ahead.
Go ahead,
don't get caught up thinking about
everything that's happening because
there's no sense in it.
We've done that before and you get
nowhere.
So let's just keep going this way.
Well,
having a war that affected people the
way World War Two did,
where the entire need,
not just the entire nation was involved,
but the whole world was involved in this
conflict to stop evil.
Yeah.
It was a different time.
You had an evildoer yeah,
you had a real.
I mean,
obviously Isis is evil.
Obviously North Korea,
there's a lot of evil in the world.
It's not like this evil empire that's
invading Europe and dropping bombs on
people.
It's not the same.
It's not no Nazis that believe in
eugenics and want to create an area in
race and like that was handling camps
and not stopping,
spreading,
telling people were coming and they were
the most sophisticated in terms of
engineering and like,
I mean they,
they to this day,
I mean,
where do you get all the fucking
engineers in terms of,
uh,
like automobiles,
top end,
Audi,
BMW,
those people were making shit for Nazis
back then.
Yeah.
I mean that's another co opted by the
regime.
Do you ever see like one of Hitler's
cars,
there's a Audi from like 1930,
something was made for Hitler.
Yeah.
It's like they,
they were designing engines,
planes,
and they were super,
super advanced or super advanced now,
and you have this real,
you have this real evil focus.
Like it was like,
okay,
the world has got to come and go get
this one guy.
It seemed,
I don't know.
I mean I wasn't there but it seems more
black and white and the way the world is
for sure.
I mean there was a thing called
operation paperclip that happened where
after the war we scooped up all these
Nazi scientists secretly and some of
them were like legit,
like Wernher von Braun,
the guy who was in charge of NASA,
he was a Nazi rally,
a hundred percent.
The Simon Wiesenthal Center said that if
he was alive today,
they would prosecute him for crimes
against humanity and he was the head of
NASA who's the head of NASA.
She,
they took monsters when they brought
those monsters over here and those
monsters helped us make the Apollo
rockets.
She.
Yeah.
And then some of the monsters went to
the Soviet Union.
They took some of those monsters can
hills where I mean,
and there's no reason to whitewash that
either.
Those were real monsters were real,
like they hung the five slow as Jews
everyday in front of the,
of the rocket factory in Berlin where
Wernher von Braun was making rockets
for,
for the Nazis.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
They had these Jews that were slaves
that worked as well.
I mean,
there's people that were alive today
that have those tattoos on their arms
at,
talked about meeting him there and she
hit me and they,
they would hang the slowest workers.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
In the front of the factory and just
getting this keeps going to work.
It doesn't leave the country.
What did you do?
And then get out in Nazi Germany.
Yay.
You know,
how the fuck could you get out?
You were a slave.
No,
not the chooser.
Baron,
the guys who were working on were
working for the,
uh,
for the company.
Like to see the people being hung and
still hang in there.
They were Nazis.
I mean,
he was,
they were all in.
Yeah.
I mean,
whether or not he agreed with the
ideology wholeheartedly mean I didn't
have a conversation with them.
I don't know if he was doing for
pragmatic purposes because he was
frightened or whatever,
but get a disguise,
get out of there.
I don't think they could,
you know,
one of those glasses with the mustaches
is that work?
Go to the airport.
He can come to you.
Take it off like,
oh,
it's like a NASA guy.
Well,
this is like a suburb.
There was a slow slide,
I'm sure into that.
I mean the,
the,
the slot wasn't that slow.
But from World War One and world war
two,
as it escalated,
I think it just got to this point where
they're like,
oh my God,
like what are we doing?
When they started having concentration
camps and killing all the Jews got
terrifying and those.
So he took a lot of.
Those guys brought them over here.
They worked for,
worked for the US government man.
Oh Man.
I have a [inaudible] 67 Volkswagen
little beetle sweet little car.
Sweet little car.
It was a little 10 pounds now,
but it's solid and yet you can't get
around like every time we meant it,
you think,
you know,
this was the people's car.
This was the,
this was the early Nazi Germany.
Hitler on the,
uh,
at the,
at the plants,
you know,
being very proud of at this car and
stuff.
Well,
here's a good way of looking at it too.
You have a 67,
right?
Yeah.
That's like,
if I had a 19,
98 car that was produced by Nazis,
what do you mean in 98?
Because it's 20 years old.
Twenty years from 67 to like literally.
Yeah,
it,
it's that era.
Yeah.
I mean it's so close.
So close.
Twenty years.
Yeah.
That's nothing.
God.
Yeah.
Think about it that way.
There is that,
that car is 20 slash 20 years removed
from Hitler being empowered.
Did you literally.
Did you do that randomly?
Google that because that's my car.
My car is literally,
as you're actually adding back color,
different wheels,
different hubcaps now,
but I mean the activity.
My friend Jimmy Lawless had one of those
when were in high school.
It was so light.
It was crazy.
So he had a tiny ass little engine in
the back.
It's got a little four cylinder.
That's a big.
When you see this little beetle,
you don't think Nazis,
you think,
think it's cute or adorable.
Have you seen what they do?
They take an older nine slash 11 inch
and put them in these things.
Make them fast.
I know they do that with the buses too,
but you look how little those fucking
tires are.
I know that thing ain't got any
traction.
No going around turns with that thing.
It's like,
Hey,
they were smart back then though.
Their engineering with.
They put the weight of the engine in the
back.
Yeah,
and it has such a different effect
there.
It's kind of amazing to look at all
automobile manufacturing in the thirties
before the war come like there was
enough metal for everybody.
There was enough ingenuity.
The French card,
all the design is so amazing.
There was a real moment of,
of uh,
inspiration and creativity and then the
war came into this,
like all the resources and all the
people and everything got dampened down.
But man,
they were flying in the thirties.
What's interesting though is there was
another resurgence in the sixties,
like,
especially in America.
American cars in the sixties were
fucking amazing.
And then the gas crisis got them right.
The Seventies.
They dog shit.
Yeah.
Were terrible.
So bad.
So useless.
Oh my mom had a pinto.
It was a bad car.
But like I'm a muscle car fan.
Right.
Like for me the golden era was like 19
sixties to somewhere around 71.
But the last of the great cars,
like 71 Barracuda's still pretty bad
ass.
But then 72 starts to look a little
shitty seven mustangs.
Yeah.
Once you get to 75 their dog shit.
But by the time 1980 rolls around,
just fucking like those things on fire
because of the gas.
Well,
the gas crisis came,
they started making cars cheaper and
they were just lighter.
They try to make them more fuel
efficient and something happened to the
way they look like shit.
Yeah,
look at that.
That's a 79 Mustang.
So it's terrible.
Now I want you to.
So this is a 1979.
This piece of shit.
Now I want you to Google 1969.
Mach one.
Get ready for this motherfucker.
Nineteen 69.
Mach one.
Boom son.
Click on that black one right there.
Click on that.
Come the fuck on.
Do you go from.
How do you go from that?
And 10 years later you have that box a
piece of shit.
Look at that red one.
The upper right hand corner and that
looks like it should come with Steve
Mcqueen and good glibly Mowgli at that
thing.
What a fucking car that his.
God.
Damn.
That doesn't get your dick hard.
Doctor comes a steve McQueen and a naked
gal in the back.
Steve McQueen at a 68.
Go with a 19 gold.
Nineteen 68.
Steve Mcqueen mustangs.
The green one.
Yeah,
it
is.
Boom.
Look at that.
Come on man.
What did they do?
Fuck,
that's more than the gas.
That's some bad.
Something happened in the company.
Something happened with life.
Yeah.
Something happened in Ford.
Look how gorgeous that is.
Cad.
I mean that is a fucking work of art
that there's the.
The lines on that thing.
Seventy six Toyota Corolla.
One 1976.
I want to show you what a bad ass
vehicle I was driving around.
Yeah,
that yellow baby.
But yeah,
mine was baby shit orange.
Here's the thing.
That thing would start up every day.
Yes.
One hundred percent.
That's the difference.
It might look like a piece of shit and
it most certainly does.
That was it.
That was the color baby.
Shit orange and I put a racing stripe
along the side and I had a horn in it.
The plate,
200 different tunes.
Really?
Like dukes of hazzard or happy birthday.
I had everything.
I had a CB in it.
Why?
I contact my friends on my CB.
You had a CB regarding to the dairy
queen.
Cover your friends at CBS two or just
getting out into the abyss?
We had like three friends with cvs
because he had no regard for a party.
I'm not sure we're going to pick dairy
queen.
Okay.
Grab me here.
Roberta finger blizzard in a minute.
Explain that to me.
How do you choose what channel you're
on?
A you just choose.
We just all were.
We all knew we were on channel,
you know,
for whatever.
How many channels are there?
Not that many actually.
So how close do you have to be?
Um,
like 10 miles.
Within 10 miles.
You could use it.
Yeah.
Weed.
And that's all.
That's all you're doing is back then we
weren't thinking I had a Toyota Corolla
with a horn that play 200 songs.
I was inhaling curve ahead of the curve.
It was having a blast.
I was so happy to be out of the house.
But isn't that amazing?
Like I'm thinking about this now,
how often people use cell phones and
such.
What are people thinking back then?
Like why didn't they get CBS on their
car?
I don't know.
It's a good question.
Why wouldn't everybody have one?
I don't know.
And it especially then it was like the
big trucking era.
It was a convoy dude.
It was a big convoy.
Yes.
Smokey and the bandit had it come on.
Come on.
Smokey and the bandit had it in his
trans am.
Yeah,
that's right.
They were talking to each other.
What year was that?
I think he was.
He had a [inaudible] 79 trans am.
Yeah.
I was going to put it at seventy eight
cents at a CBS exploded in the seventies
when the oil crisis caused the miles per
hour on the highway to go down at 55 and
truckers started using them until each
other where the best gas prices were.
A network started with people using CBS
rubber duck.
That's funny because I would have
thought that they were excluded because
they were using them to tell each other
where the cops were.
Yeah.
Like smokey and the bandit.
Dude,
when I was in high school,
it was 55 miles per hour is the speed
limit,
which is just fucking torture.
It's torture.
We need doing,
uh,
people.
Who Do you think you are telling people
to go?
Fifty five miles on the highway,
the highway,
and with a 400 horsepower engine that
Steve Mcqueen Cook.
What the fuck is that all about it?
My Toyota Corolla.
It was just fast enough.
We've Sanjenis speed traps was like the
third thing listed.
Yeah,
I would imagine that would be a big one.
I mean that's what ways is pretty good
for that ways is like police spotted
ahead a snitch.
They blocked the freeways to in protest
of the lower speed limits to do.
I remember that.
That.
Well.
Idiots blocking yourself.
Stupid fucking remember when these
morons.
We're.
We're blocking the highways.
You remember when people were doing
that?
Like San Francisco.
That was recently.
They walk for approach protest.
They would walk out,
just walk on the highway.
What the fuck was that about?
God,
people have stopped doing that.
You want everyone to hate you?
Well,
it's not just that.
It's like you're stopping people from
being able to get to a hospital.
You might cause people loved ones' lives
and they did.
Well.
That's what happened with the governor.
Christie,
when he closed down the bridge,
he has a couple of people died because
of that,
because they couldn't get to the
hospital.
They were.
He not in jail for that guys.
The worst housing non jail.
You should totally be in jail.
Other people went to jail for it.
That is just fucking straight
corruption.
Just to,
to make that call.
The audacity that you'd have to have the
balls to make that fucking call and say,
shut.
Yo.
That guy was so some m and m's.
So arrogant.
Do you remember seeing when he with a
closed the beaches and he,
him and his family were the only one on
the beach.
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Dispatch says everything.
Just his body says everything.
Let yourself get to that state slob.
And he had an operation to.
Oh,
he had a stomach stapling.
Did he really them through it.
Look at that fucking every beach was
called.
Every state beach was closed I think on
the fourth of July.
And Hammond is fat family.
We're just sitting there on the beach.
Just what an f you to everybody look at
that is extreme.
Nobody else allowed extreme arrogance.
And why would the beaches closed down?
Uh,
for the budget?
He,
he ordered him closed because they
couldn't pay for people to watch the
beaches.
It was like one of those pissing matches
between,
you know,
who's gonna cut what for the budget for
July sand portrait of him.
Look at that.
Someone made fun of him in the sand.
That's hilarious.
Yeah.
The fourth of July,
looking at him in his little shower
sandals.
So I think the kids call those slides.
They call them slides,
you know the kids call those slides.
Slides.
I call them flip flops.
No,
no,
no.
When I see someone in the airport with
slides on,
I,
we just want to punch him.
It's a lot of dudes have slides in the
airport with socks on.
A Mike.
Okay.
What are you doing here?
Why is that annoy me?
Because it's lazy.
You don't like lazy.
It's lazy.
Yeah,
but I have those Solomon running shoes
that don't even have.
They don't have laces.
They have like this little tab you pull
and you pull it down and it tightens up
and you open it up and it's like velcro.
Yeah,
but you're still pulling a tab.
At least there's a little something,
just stick them in your feet and flop,
flop flop like that.
White people don't like that because
they're lazy.
As comfortable as possible.
Very,
very excited about this.
It makes me so angry,
but why?
Because you're a 25 year old man sitting
on the floor of an airport waiting for
your thing next year.
Shower sandals.
A lot of people do it though.
It's not a lot of people do it,
but enough people do it with the socks
and the slide bothers bothers me so
much.
I don't know.
Why does it bother you?
More or less than flip flops?
I'm a little bit more,
which is pretty crazy because I really
railed against people with flip flops.
Like Bert Kreischer wears flip flops
everywhere.
Disgusting.
These kind of gross.
It's so gross and people act like their
feet on your feet have a real bacteria
between the toes.
There's like a real,
a real germs in there and then they're
just slick.
Slipping them off and putting their toes
in the magazine rack.
But bird is like this life of the party
type character.
That's part of his thing.
It's his thing.
I love him.
I love him too.
He's disgusting.
He was.
There's a video of him on a fucking
skateboard flying down his street with
flip flops on it.
I'm like,
dude,
do you understand the damage to your
toes that you could do for the rest of
your life?
Your toes.
That'd be fucked up if you crash flying
down the street.
The flip flops on.
He's hilarious now.
I mean,
at least at least he's a character like
bigger than life character.
You just flip flop and you don't care
and your pants are hanging off.
Just to get on a flight to boise.
Just come on by Boise.
Boise.
I love boys.
I'm just.
What's the issue?
Because it's a shorter flight.
I didn't want it to be like,
you can't even get it together for a
short flight.
You know?
It's disgusting.
It is weird.
It's just come on.
His ideas about footwear.
I judge people when I see them with ease
on.
Yeah.
Including Jamie.
Have something right there.
No,
I don't know.
You gave me some.
I don't know exactly where sat right
here when he was like six months ago.
Right when he gave him to me.
They were in the box right there.
I've contemplated running and I'm
running through like Korea and filming
it because people love these things so
much.
But uh,
I don't want to run it them.
Are they expensive?
Because I like running shoes that are
actually supposed to be running in.
Yeah,
they're expensive.
He's,
he gets a look at him.
He's upset.
Jane.
Jane is one generation younger than me.
So his idea what these things are,
is different than my.
I feel like they're mad at you for
saying that now.
Some people are.
Some people think it's hilarious that
you would do that.
Would run with them.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I know another mad at me,
but they're dumb.
It mad at me for what I would do with a
pair of sneakers.
You're a fucking idiot,
right?
And you need to get your shit together.
You're thinking about sneakers too much.
Are you happier that they just sit in
here and there's fucking people think
I'm joking.
What do they look like?
They're sitting here and this fucking
box.
I'm not joking.
I mean I didn't plan this out there.
Here,
this part here.
People who are into them are like,
oh my God,
you got up there and you know,
you go to them and you not even flossing
who should be out frost and man,
he's taunting me.
Mock his all the time.
He looked like some sneakers from the
eighties.
It's like they look like the sneaker
version of that Shitty Mustang from
1979.
No Man.
The cool whole back end sticks out like
this.
The heel has like a duck bill behind
you.
It's so stupid.
It's so bizarre.
Yeah.
But um,
that Kanye West has a large effect on
humans.
Very interesting.
The family feud.
They were on family feud.
Well,
very good.
I have no idea.
I just heard Howard stern talking about.
I hope they asked tough questions just
to see the ballpark is try try being a
book in that house.
You will collect dust motherfucker.
I don't care.
It's broken up into chapters.
Read Shit.
Steam reading tweets.
Elon musk wants to do the podcast right
back here on the feud.
Really messaged me.
Can I come in as your,
as your cohost?
Um,
no.
I'll just listen like everybody else.
Uh,
that's really cool.
Yeah.
Should be interesting.
He wants to get his mall three up to
some high level production and once it's
done the time away.
No.
Model three Tesla model three.
Yeah.
Close concentrating on.
Once he's got that,
they just delivered their first 1000
flame throwers this weekend.
Yeah.
What's up with that?
Why?
Don't know.
I almost bought one just to do it just
to see what happened.
Like on it's by one and you couldn't do
it.
Take it out back.
You couldn't do it as a flame thrower.
So he named it not a flame thrower.
So what it's called?
Yeah.
It's called not a flame thrower,
so that way you can actually company not
a flame thrower.
Wow.
Like some airport hangar to pick them
up.
I deal with people get killed by these
things.
Wait a minute,
there's a Mariachi band playing.
They're having a good time.
Flame thrower thing.
Yeah.
It's the big unveiling.
That's where you picked them up.
No,
no,
no.
Is that real?
Yeah.
Sorry.
Go back up to that of the flame thrower.
That's Jesus Christ.
Look at that fucking thing.
Pretty cool.
Oh my God.
That's amazing.
Obviously gotta buy propane maybe to
refill it and connect it and it's good
because it's like it's going to cause a
housewife.
That's the purpose of that.
Um,
to when you,
when your enemies come close in,
run out of bullets.
You hide behind the couch and you're in
the movie alien.
They had flame throwers.
Yeah.
You need to burn them instead of shoot
them because it's a.
you're on a spaceship if you live on a
spaceship.
Oh,
right,
right.
What are you going to do with a flame
thrower?
My boyfriend asked me.
That's her.
That's the author out there blasting.
She doesn't even know the stock against
her fucking armpit.
She doesn't even know what she's doing.
Look where she's got the stock.
Terrible technique.
Tuck that into your arm,
honey.
But there's not a lot of kickback.
I don't do that like a,
like you're a goddamn professional.
You've exercised with trigger control
to.
What about his title?
Discipline.
What about all those tunnels?
Well,
how about I didn't realize how many
tunnels he wants to do.
He wants us.
He's doing everything.
He's making flame throwers.
He's making these gigawatt factories,
these gigantic batteries that are
powering Australia.
Yeah,
I mean Nevada.
He's a very,
very unusual human being.
It's amazing.
It's just little balls.
Just do it.
You gave me an idea,
just do it.
She just not know how to handle that
gun.
Somebody told me they saw him,
they saw him speaking and it about the
tunnels because he's got to get
approval.
Like there's different things.
He's got to get past and he doesn't just
want a tunnel like from here to lax,
he wants multiple tunnels,
so like if you're going to the united
terminal,
it takes you right there.
If it goes to the American one,
it takes you there and it's going to be
a whole like ant farm of tunnels all
through the city.
What happens if we get an earthquake?
What happens if there's a tsunami?
Do those things fill up with water and
is everybody drowned inside those tubes?
It says the tunnels are weatherproof.
Hmm.
It means when it rains.
Yeah.
That's cool.
What about an earthquake?
I don't think earthquake is weather.
MMM.
Now I know.
I'm looking to see if they have any.
I been getting claustrophobic lately.
Why?
I don't know.
Like in what way?
I had a couple of little instances where
I was
and we never been claustrophobic before.
Nineteen 94.
Northridge Earthquake.
No damage to la subway tunnels in 1989.
Loma Prieta Northern California
earthquake.
No damage to tunnels.
Nineteen 85.
Mexico City earthquake.
No damage to tunnels which are then used
to transport rescue personnel.
The tunnels were in shape,
but there's a big rock over the hole
that gets you out of the tunnel.
A building fell on it.
Try to.
The elevator won't take you up and now
you stuck in that little elevator living
in a tunnel for the rest of your life to
death in there and you get clipped by
some other guy in a tesla going 120
miles an hour in the tunnel.
Get run over,
it was turning into rat tunnels.
Not Big enough for you to walk in while
there's cars in now.
I think they recently changed the plan,
which is going to be these things called
electric skates.
Which people get on like a subway car.
Like a pod?
Yeah.
Instead of your car getting in there,
but small,
like only like 16 people shoot right to
the airport.
Shoot.
Right to downtown.
Yeah.
It'd be pretty cool.
But I don't know if I cluster,
probably it will kick in.
And then there's another thing,
the hyperloop,
he's doing that hyperloop thing to the
hyperloop is the uh,
that's the fucking train that goes to
San Francisco.
That's him too.
Yeah Dude.
The fuck.
Just keep doing it.
But this is the crazy thing.
It's one guy.
Like how is this one guy that
innovative,
that smart?
I don't know.
He's a.
But is he funny sometimes he's a comedy
fan store.
He,
yeah,
he's been to the store.
It was at Largo with Johnny Dep secs.
Oh boy.
Got that loose though.
That's the only.
Oh,
he did good.
Smart Guy.
That was my only time I worried about
him.
I saw him like,
you know,
some events was like,
oh no,
what is he doing?
You'd probably just get some of that
crazy posts.
I just googled hyperloop.
Beautiful.
Not being associated with him.
I know he is doing that,
but I might not be the only person.
Or are you just involved in the project?
It's a different.
Could be.
Well he's also involved in the fucking
rocket project to space x.
he's going to Mars.
Yeah,
that's what I wanted to ask you.
Uh,
if you talked about Three d printing a
couple times we've talked to.
I just watched the recent vice on three
d printing.
Pretty amazing.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
They wanted,
um,
who has one?
That guy,
um,
with crazy.
You're fucking puppet guy.
Jeff.
Jeff Dunham.
Yeah.
He makes puppets with him.
He makes a lot of shit with them.
He was on Opie and Anthony back in the
day apparently.
He's like a super tech Geek and he was
on Opie and Anthony back in the day and
he was talking.
He had like one of the earlier three d
printers.
Really?
Yeah.
They're getting really,
really complex.
Mike,
they're making human hearts.
They're making human ears there is
making the mobile controlled chaos.
Jeff Dunham,
so he does all this stuff himself.
He's a fucking character.
Jeff Dunham.
Yeah.
Interesting guy.
That's amazing.
You put anything in the computer like
actually there was showed like a
dishwasher and the guy wanted to
manufacture the part that's inside the
dishwasher.
The computer says,
no,
we can improve on that part and we're
going to alter the shape of it and have
it be like this and then it makes that
and then you use it.
It's getting so crazy.
You won't see human cells in there
making ears and skin and it's amazing.
They think that in the future you won't
be buying things.
You'll be downloading schematics and
then getting the raw materials,
the raw materials you'll have like in
your machine somehow or another and
it'll make whatever you need.
Like say if you need a French press,
it'll make
a French press.
It will three d print,
a French press for you.
You won't go to the store and buy one,
you'll just download the whatever it is.
You don't need a manufacturer and no
one's going to be in this business of
making presses less.
I mean less and less and.
But the thing is like more and more
demand will be for things like this
table or craftsmanship or someone makes
something for you.
Right,
right.
Yeah.
I mean,
which is kind of seeing that now like
people are getting,
you know,
there's all these restaurants that are
like kind of farm to table.
They have wooden metal and everything
like rustic and everything's kind of
retro.
Everyone his armpit hair.
That's not what we're talking about.
They had razors along.
There's no excuse for girls to have
armpit hair isn't a funny guys.
It's fun.
I have on armpit hair.
Do you have armpit hair?
Do were men.
If you don't have armpit hair.
I'm like,
what happened?
You got a disease bro?
Where you in a fire and alopecia?
Does your friend have a flame throwing?
It's like a,
like girls with their junk,
like,
okay,
here's a perfect example.
Butthole hair on girls.
Like when we were kids can't get enough
standard.
It was normal.
It was there,
it was chaos,
right?
It's just how you grew.
It was just a big fucking pile of
whatever.
And nowadays if you're a girl,
you're young,
single gallon,
got bottle hair,
you're taking some risks,
right?
You're like,
I don't care,
love me who I am.
He must be an older man because that's
the only one that can accept me for who
I am.
Like,
no,
we're not doing that anymore.
We're trying to evolve.
And first thing that's evolving is
women's hair.
You gotta start somewhere,
right?
Like how many women when you go to the
beach,
how many women shaved their legs?
All of all of them.
That's fucking crazy.
Like it's weird like the grooming
standards that we've imposed on women,
like the culture is imposed on women.
It's pretty crazy.
It's fucking crazy.
It's so crazy in comparison to us like
you and I fucking hairy armpits.
Shit.
I've one patch of hair on my back.
Oh yeah,
like a wolf.
Just like one side.
Like when the American Werewolf in
London,
the transformation sequences stopped
quarter way through.
It's funny,
I mean the,
the standards.
Yeah,
it's weird.
It's very weird.
It's weird,
but it's,
it's also weird is that uh,
people who are really poor women who
were really progressive,
still like doing certain parts of it.
That for me as a man watching it is
always like,
yeah,
we're all the same and let's own it and
stuff,
but I'm still going to put this big,
big line on my eyes to make it look like
I'm going to put extra lashes on to make
it look like it's weird.
Like the,
what you choose to sculpted eyebrows and
shit.
Eyebrows.
Some dudes.
Sculptor eyebrows.
Yeah.
Got To work for those guys because they
were in.
Starts with an F,
ends with a t in it rhymes a faggot.
A cabaret star.
Yes.
It's a bundle of wood.
Know it's,
uh,
it's,
yeah,
it's very bizarre.
I always feel like.
But they also like,
it's empowering to feel good and it does
make women feel good to be in heels and
well then there's different standards
for gay folks.
Like gay guys,
they do it way different and by the way,
when I use that effort,
I should not use that and definitely
wouldn't use it for gay guys.
We know.
Consider the source.
Had to be careful though.
Got To be careful in today's day and
age.
Yeah,
but people know you're a good person.
Some people don't.
They know you're making it.
Show people are.
It's a dangerous time.
Any of the Lampanelli thing.
What happened?
She was screaming at a an audience
member,
like,
like really?
Completely.
Which charts?
I think it just happened last night.
I don't know.
I mean I heard it on the radio.
She's like screaming yo up bed.
Did you see that?
She yelled at them,
call them bitches onstage.
Nuclear meltdown.
Fan hands or a $100 to shut up.
She goes on.
She have blue on her hair.
She's got blue on her hair.
Nuclear meltdown.
Someone tried to say something in the
middle of her set and she just goes
batshit crazy what?
She went nuclear on a fan who gave her
$100 to shut up in the middle of her.
Good.
Here's the thing,
like why would someone,
why would someone pay her at a show to
go try to get her to shut up?
So after someone from the balcony,
he called her a cunt.
It all went downhill from there.
How long is it going to be before you
can't say that word anymore?
I'm probably good to like next
Wednesday.
Yeah,
we're.
We're running in the sand in the
hourglass.
Yeah.
Like I said,
like when I just said Faggot,
I felt it.
I'm like,
Ooh,
this is a dangerous time to say that
word.
Yeah.
Say it anymore.
No new,
new,
new.
Even as a joke.
Even not even calling an individual
person.
It just saying the noise.
That is that word.
Like it's get down to the like you'd
have to call it the other f word for
word.
It's clearly established,
right?
Say it all the time.
People even say it on stage and a comedy
set.
They'll say the n word say the n Word
Ran,
where they won't say no,
no,
no.
And if they do say it people.
Oh,
gas.
Yes.
Forget it from the crowd.
Get it now.
That's gone,
but Jane retarded about.
Yeah,
pretty much.
Yeah.
I'm retarded is.
I think it's probably bad,
but you can say it,
but the way you're saying it,
you could say retarded,
right?
Right.
The end where we won't say that now you
want him saying I'm too scared.
It's the word bigger,
but without the bee with a different,
with an end in it.
I can't even do that.
I'm done.
I can't even say bigger,
but without a B,
with an end.
That's how tricky it is.
I'm just feeling for the keys in my
pocket.
Damage.
Terrified.
Jamie,
you were telling me about who,
what was the rap concert where the girl
got on stage and she was saying,
yeah,
the Kendrick Lamar concert.
Which uh,
so I guess there's a song that happens a
lot.
You can see lots of videos if the
crowd's singing all the words,
which has a lot of words in it,
including white people in the crowd.
Correct.
Yeah,
lots of.
Well that's the way mainly.
Well,
yeah.
So,
uh,
yeah,
I'll,
I'll pull one up as Alabama.
The hangout fest will to grow up on
stage.
She was obviously drunk,
kind of almost set her up to to do it.
He said like two or three times he
stopped.
It.
Stopped the whole thing.
Well,
what did she say in reference to?
Just.
It's a.
it's in the song.
So she was doing like Karaoke,
like a song lyric.
Yeah.
I'll pull up the videos and then he
turned on her.
No,
no,
no.
That's not for you.
That's only for.
Oh wait,
wait,
wait.
That's meme were up.
I had a bit from 2009.
Yeah.
My Spike TV special here.
Woman gets onstage
when you're ready.
Oh,
and she's going to do it.
Oh my God.
She's set her up.
Yeah,
it's terrible.
She said,
well we started.
We started mocking her already.
Yeah.
Wow.
She must be.
So are we playing this over?
You get pulled out.
What happens?
Jesus Christ.
That's terrible.
Crazy.
Everybody was just really cool,
bro.
You gotta you gotTa make one single
word.
Oh,
I'm sorry.
Sorry.
They're all up.
The Sun's down.
Get up.
You said the noise.
He says that we love.
You can't say the noise.
That's mostly it.
Hilarious and preposterous times mean
that is so strange.
That is his song.
He wrote a song,
he wrote the word says she loves him,
she loves him.
She's at his concert.
He gave her the microphone,
played the song,
she's singing the song that he loves,
that he wrote.
Now audience loves and everybody's like,
you did the wrong thing.
You made the noise.
So wow.
Crowd doing it though.
This whole crowd is mostly white.
Okay,
so how's that word?
I ain't got a double standard.
I know.
This is why I stayed home.
Wait a minute.
How does that work?
So there's a lot of people there.
Yeah,
you can do it.
You can do it if there's a bunch of
people there.
If you can't do it,
if you're by yourself.
No onstage by yourself in front of those
people,
you can't do it.
But if you're in with them you could do
it.
Yes.
And that was mostly white.
There was a lot of white there in the
course in that white people are
ridiculous.
So confused.
I mean this is a strange time.
I was gonna say I did this spike TV
special in 2009 and there was a.
do you remember that old commercial with
the guy or the girl comes home and her
dog started talking to her.
Like,
Lindsay,
I really wish you wouldn't smoke pump.
You're not the senior smoke pot.
And I miss my friend.
I had this whole thing where I was like,
I was like,
first of all,
whatever that checks on,
she's not on pot because if you were on
pot you'd be like,
wait a minute,
my fucking dog and talk.
How long have you been able to talk to
Daddy?
My whole fucking life.
This is the first shit you said,
right?
You know,
and I went through this whole thing that
I call my dog a faggot.
This guy,
this was like in the beginning of
political correctness,
right?
Because it was 2009.
He,
this is a gay guy,
said to me.
He goes,
you can't say that word.
That's our nigger.
That's our word,
right?
That's what he said,
He literally said,
I go,
wait a minute.
What'd you just say?
Yeah.
And he said it again,
you said it's our nigger.
We're allowed to say it.
You can't say that.
I go,
that's the gay shit I've ever heard.
He started laughing.
I go,
that's so crazy.
You can't go.
I'm talking to a dog.
I'm talking.
I'm angry at a dog because I've had this
dog my whole life.
His first words out of his mouth.
I tell you I love you every day.
And,
and what do you say?
You say a wish.
You wouldn't smoke weed.
Hey,
fuck you stupid.
I smoke weed.
Not go to work and I pay for your food.
Faggot.
Like that was.
That was the joke.
And he got.
He got like,
these rules are preposterous.
Isn't it supposed to be about intent UK?
Isn't it supposed to be like I'm
supposed to be conveying how I feel and
the words are supposed to mirror my
thoughts.
Like when you have magic words that you
can't say in this case with the n
word,
it's even crazier because it's like some
people could say it,
you could say it sometimes.
Sometimes you can't say it's too heavy.
What bought black people could say it,
why people can't,
but white people can say it if we're in
the crowd and they're yelling it out,
but as long as there's an a on the end
of it.
Yeah,
right.
Exactly.
The Er is what gets you in trouble.
Well,
look,
racism is disgusting.
All Racist.
Racism against Chinese people,
racism against white people.
Racism against every.
Of course against black people,
of course,
against everyone judging someone on
something that they have no control
over.
That's what it is like you are when
you're born,
whatever.
You're born,
Irish,
German,
Italian,
African.
You're born.
It's not you.
You're just who you are.
Right?
So racism is disgusting,
but is that,
is it racism?
When you have that girl on stage and
she's singing that song that she loves,
that you sing,
it's your song like that's not really
racism.
No.
So when she's singing along and
everybody's you racist fucking Nazi,
like what are we doing?
Right?
Because this is what we're doing here is
we're,
we,
we've gone into some ridiculous zone
where it doesn't make any sense because
we know that's not her intent and know
exactly right.
Actual exercise.
Exactly.
It becomes like a word game.
It's a little puzzle kind of thing that
we're doing to trap this person.
You say she's very innocent up there.
They all know she's a little drunk.
It's kind of like setting someone up to
do something.
Yeah,
it's pretty gross.
It's just weird.
But it's weird that it's so universal.
Like that crowd that was probably 20,000
people.
No,
they had a weird thing on,
you know,
I,
I'm,
I'm on the show live from here,
the old prairie home companion show and
uh,
you know,
I'm the writer for it and stuff.
Had writer on it,
appear on it and stuff.
Anyway,
I'm very involved with the show.
Uh,
Chris,
who's this bluegrass guy who plays a
mandolin,
who's amazing,
the kindest person you'll ever meet,
like super,
super sweet,
sweet person,
like,
like Mr Rogers in a way.
Like it's to that level of kindness and
he sings everybody's birthdays and
stuff.
And he sings different songs and as
attributes,
everything.
He loves all music.
He loves everything.
He sang a Kendrick Lamar Song,
he sang a little bit of it,
uh,
in like,
because it was his birthday that week
and he got so much hate online that a
white person can't be singing that song.
What is the song about?
It's,
I don't know,
but it wasn't,
that wasn't the thing.
It was the word.
It was that he was,
um,
what's the thing that you take some
cultural appropriation that he's not
allowed to sing.
And meanwhile he's singing bluegrass
Indian music from all around the world.
This is a kind soul celebrating
everything.
And it really freaked him out because he
is so nice.
He couldn't believe the
hate that he got from it.
That now he's super sensitive about
singing that music at all.
It's not logical.
It's not like you have to put your foot
down and you consider the source.
Culturally,
we have to put our foot down because
we're going down this very strange,
illogical road where you could just
decide what's evil and what's bad and it
doesn't have any bearing on the thought
or the intent behind it is.
Look,
they went after Bruno Mars,
like,
get in the.
Just get the fuck outta here.
They accused Bruno Mars of cultural
appropriation.
What culture?
He's everything.
He's like the per meanwhile,
what is he doing where anybody would
accuse him of cultural appropriation.
He sings these beautiful fucking songs.
Oh,
he's a light.
A light in this world.
He's amazing.
I love that guy.
Oh,
the guy's amazing.
Voice is fantastic and his songs are fun
and they're catchy and I love listening
to them.
I saw them in Vegas in concert.
It was just the most uplifting,
bright thing.
You know what made me happy though is
that a bunch of black artists said,
fuck you.
He's great.
Like the original charge,
just fucking social justice warriors.
We're going after him for cultural
appropriation.
All these super progressive angry
fuckheads will decide whatever man.
It doesn't have to make sense.
This is the thing,
they're just looking for targets.
It doesn't have to make sense.
This is not like a logical progression
like,
oh,
Bruno Mars is still.
It's not like,
oh,
he's stealing from these old blues
singers and he's not crediting them and
he's a white guy from Kentucky.
That's not what we're dealing with.
Right.
We're dealing with a multiracial guy who
sings these beautiful songs that they
don't.
They're not cultural appropriation.
Even if he was white and.
Yeah,
no,
exactly.
It's just a joy of music and music is a
mix of everything.
It's a mix of all of us,
of everything that is good coming into
saying like his style,
but if that's the case,
then here's the case.
I'm a fucking huge fan of the black
keys,
the black keys,
a whole lot of their shit is blues.
A lot of his old blues,
like it sounds so similar to some great
old blues.
Sure is that cultural appropriation?
I mean,
I love them.
I mean you saying they should stop doing
what I what I love to hear now.
Come on.
What are we doing?
Yeah,
that's crazy.
But what is it?
What did you know what the other part of
it is?
How many people are really complaining
about that stuff?
It's a very small amount,
but it's so small,
but it's enough where your friend got
scared.
He did get scared and it literally
amounts to probably three tweets.
You know what I mean?
It's like,
but those people,
that's the only noise.
People aren't saying,
wow,
I love that version because they just
like it in the normal people.
It's these haters that just want to do
it and the people in control of it have
to calm him and make him realize we've
got your back day Bronco.
They'll fucking fire him if it gets loud
enough.
It doesn't have to make any sense.
That's where it's squirrely today.
Fired speaking to prairie home
companion.
They fired garrison keillor.
I know they fired him,
removed his name for everything because
he hugged the lady and his hand went
down her back and then he apologized,
sent her an email.
She said,
it's fine.
They went back and forth with it.
Didn't do anything else.
No history of sexual harassment,
sexual assault,
no.
History of anything terrible.
Years later when all this stuff comes
out,
she comes out with that.
It was dirty business,
it was dirty,
it's dirty,
but it doesn't.
It's not logical.
Right?
It's like there's this fever feeding
frenzy that goes on with these things.
It's mob mentality.
Yeah.
That just wanted to tear people down.
They want to tear people apart,
really believe that you have to,
in all these situations is considered
the source.
Like you really have to consider.
It's like when the steroid thing went
down,
there were like,
people came at Barry bonds harder than
everybody else because he had a rap for
not being a good guy.
He people did not like him regardless of
that.
So when it happens,
people kind of come after him.
Harder than the came after San Francisco
a yes and yeah,
and much harder than like Andy Pettitte
or you know,
he's a pitcher for the Yankees and it's
just like a nice guy and he doesn't cut
it,
you know?
But if somebody is a problem,
Jose Conseco,
it was a problem because he ratted
everybody out.
Oh yeah,
that's right.
That book called juiced.
Yeah,
boy dogs,
everything that made him persona non
grata,
like he kind of disappeared.
He got written off from that book,
but people just decided,
fuck you.
Yeah.
That's interesting.
Right?
It is.
Yeah.
Too much of a snitch I guess.
Yeah,
man.
People just didn't respect him after
that because there was so many people
that were also doing it and he was the
one that ratted everybody out and
profited off of it.
Yeah,
there's some,
there's some justice,
some street justice in that.
I just think that there's a little to be
really careful with,
but it's just there's also an issue that
everyone has access to social media and
everyone has the ability to complain
about things.
Yeah.
So buddy,
there's a world,
right?
So there's a lot of noise kind of it.
Yeah.
You get the real sound like,
like there are things that happen that
are really bad and when something
happens it's really bad.
Yeah.
The,
the twitter mob and the all the people
that go after these people for something
that's legitimately awful.
Sure.
It makes sense.
Yeah.
I mean it's,
there's,
there's justice to it,
but there's also like this constant
looking for targets.
Yes.
It seems like that's kind of like a
hobby of some people like that is $100
just to go out and pick people off.
Yeah,
it's awful.
It's a horrible thing.
It is up because then it's [inaudible]
at its best.
It's a really wonderful thing.
It's a celebrate story thing that you
have this community that you share with
and think about.
Like you can see things from all around
the world.
You could see cultures,
you could see young people doing amazing
things in all these different little
tiny spots around the.
I mean in so many ways.
It's beautiful,
but then there's just like this little
dark underbelly of like
hate.
They're really just is good and bad in
the world and there are,
there is good and bad in the world,
but there's also people that are just
very frustrated and looking to vent that
frustration as often as they can.
Whatever targets they find to be viable.
It's not like they've carefully
considered the issue and carefully
consider this person stands on it.
Like,
no for me,
one of the big ones was the Roseanne
Barr thing because Roseanne Barr,
what she said seemed racist,
right?
You look at it on the surface,
she called that lady something like a
cross between the Muslim Brotherhood and
the planet of the apes and like what
Jesus calling a black woman and eight.
Yeah.
She said she didn't even know that woman
was black and then you see her photo and
you go,
oh,
okay.
That woman is very racially ambiguous.
Like I talked to her on the phone.
She told me she did not know that when
she goes,
you really think that I would call a
black lady planet of the Apes.
I'm not fucking stupid.
And that was her literal words.
She goes,
I didn't know.
I just was fucked up on Ambien and
drinking all weekend and tweeting a
bunch of stupid shit.
Her own words.
She's like,
I didn't know what I was saying.
Right.
And no one cares.
No one cares that you got to.
A lady who has mental illness,
like a history of mental illness is on a
host of different medications,
is on Ambien as well and drinking and
smoking pot.
No one cares.
You compared a black woman to planet of
the apes and then all these people made
these memes where they put a photo of
that woman next to that woman from the
planet of the apes and like,
you know,
you see like why she was joking around
about it,
but it's totally off limits.
So they've decided she's this horrible
racist,
forget about all her years of people
loving her and she also has,
if you go back to the source kind of
thing,
it's like there's a picture of her just
like a Nazi.
There's Jewish.
I know,
but there's like,
there's enough.
She's always tweeting bombastic stuff.
So when she's got issue it's not.
Yeah.
So it's not like.
It's not like somebody like Rachel Ray
just making muffins and all of a sudden
one tweet comes out.
She's in that area and I think when
you're in that area and you're spewing
hate and you're throwing fireballs and
stuff,
whether you have good intent or not,
you're in that arena.
You can get burned by it.
Yeah.
She's.
Yeah,
she's in total shitster.
Remember the national anthem?
She grabs her crotch and spits on the
ground and apparently everyone fucking
was super.
She was scared right after that because
that's a patriotic thing.
Oh yeah.
You don't fuck.
Got To go home.
People were mad.
I remember that.
The the issue that I'm with,
Rosanne to me is not even that tweet.
Not even even the recent planet of the
apes one,
it's an earlier one that she made five
years ago,
which is much more racist.
Were hilly about.
Yeah,
about Susan Rice where she said Susan
Rice is a man with big swinging eight
balls.
Well that,
and you're talking about an absolutely
black woman.
There's not.
There's something there.
There's the.
That's the thing.
It's the source.
It's like there's this person that has
all of this kind of stuff and she's
always showing up to the line and not
crossing it,
but maybe sometimes crossing and then
you do it.
You're going to get popped.
Do you remember when imus got kicked off
the radio for sand about some.
Some gals who were athletes,
he called them nappy headed hos.
Oh yeah,
of course.
And that was like,
whoa man,
you know,
look,
you want to play in those fire arenas,
you can get burned.
You know?
Occasionally you drop some bombs and
it's great.
Yeah,
let me make some.
But if you're a shit stirrer right,
if that's you're trying to drop bombs
occasionally,
but the one shift going to land on you
sometimes racist bombs are the ones that
get you burned the most.
We have not healed as a nation.
We're this very confused.
We know.
It's like,
you know,
we grew up like with a alcoholic,
dysfunctional fathers and there's like,
there's a sickness.
Like when you talked about how there's
only 20 years between Hitler and my
Volkswagen coming out.
There's not that much time between the
most heinous part of that too.
Today.
I mean it's what's less than 200 years,
which is two lifetimes.
It's raw.
There were a lot of times between us and
slavery.
I think like just recently,
like the last person,
last African American person who was
around during slavery just passed.
I mean,
it's,
you know what I mean,
where we never healed.
We never had a discussion.
We didn't go to therapy and forget about
just slavery.
How about the civil rights?
Yes.
I mean,
how about in our lifetime hosing people
down with fire hoses and sicking dogs on
them.
That was in,
if not our lifetime,
just before we were born and still
today,
there's still,
you go to certain parts pop and stuff
off and people,
you know,
as a white guy,
you walk around,
you hear people say Shit that because
they think you're safe around you and
you look around you and like this guy
has bred this guy.
He just bakes bread and stays home.
That's why I do it.
I,
uh,
it's tricky.
You know what I mean?
Like we have a,
that is our disease in our,
in our culture,
there is a disease that we haven't met
it out yet.
So of course like any.
If you're going to pop off about that,
you're going to be.
That's why.
Why are you,
are you,
what's in you that makes you feel like
you need to turn that off?
Well,
if you're Roseanne,
that's her whole thing is getting this
little reaction to other people.
I mean a lot of comics,
that's their thing,
right?
Little little,
little controversial things to get a
spark out of people.
That's fine if you and look,
you know,
I have a sensitivity that I don't even,
I don't want to go in that arena because
it's just,
I don't even do well.
So when people yell at right,
when people yell around me,
I don't like it.
It's not me really.
But anything about anything,
I just don't ha.
We're only here for a little while.
Why we going to fight?
Right.
That's where I live.
But people that do
it and they.
Yes,
and they and they can read.
There are people that do it who can read
tweets,
calling them horrible things and it just
Kinda,
you know,
bounces off and they don't really care,
but I don't think they read it.
That's what they do.
Well,
if you read tweets that are about people
that say horrible things to you,
I mean you're going to respond to them
and you're going to engage in dialogue
and then other people are going to join
in.
You can respond to all of them.
You won't have any time.
There's no.
There's no time.
You won't.
Your whole day will be just speeding up
with new people jumping into the fray.
It's like if you want to have a
fistfight with a mob,
a mob of people,
you can't really do that because he's
going to have a discussion with a one on
one person,
but if you fight a whole crowd of people
like that,
Kendrick Lamar,
if that lady was like,
fuck you bitch.
I say that word like knuckles up and
dives in the crowd starts throwing
haymakers going to get fucking killed.
But if she has a discussion with one of
those white guys is doing this booboo
that was just yelling it out himself.
If they put them alone in a room and she
said,
okay,
tell me why what I did was wrong.
And he was like,
Ralphie May,
it's just fucked up.
You shouldn't use that word.
You know,
you can't use that word.
It's like,
motherfucker,
you were saying it.
She's saying no,
no,
no.
I say with everybody else and I make the
noise with my face.
I was like,
I opened my mouth.
I almost say about it.
Don't say no,
don't say I don't say it.
I kind of started and then I let other
people end it.
Like do the end part or I'll do the god
part.
I don't do the in between.
I don't do a whole word because that way
I'm not racist.
It's so complex.
It's too crazy.
But it's not complex.
It's stupid.
It is complex.
But what's complex about that?
Well not that just that issue,
but what,
what's complex about that to me is that
you have a whole crowd of people
yelling,
responding this way.
Like it's on their minds,
they're having these discussions that we
are trying to move things forward.
Other people trying to move in,
get back,
that is complex.
Let's try and move it back who's
actively saying,
I mean other than like white nationalist
groups that everybody pretty much hates
other than themselves I guess and move
it back and then other people who think
that maybe that they're being that is
being reversed and that they're being
hated on now when they white like young
white kid who just wants to have a good
time at the concert and the single wait,
wait,
but why are you attacking us?
I were.
We were trying to be this way.
Someone put up some fitness at a school
that was criticized by a dean and was
taken down.
They put up these signs that say it's
okay to be white [inaudible] from Google
that because this was kind of crazy and
that this whoever this dean was,
or whoever it was that he said,
these people,
they put up these signs that said it's
okay to be white and people were angry.
Yeah.
It's like white lives matter kind of
thing.
No,
just that statement.
It's okay to be white.
Like why would have a problem with that?
Like you didn't say that.
What are you thinking about people that
aren't white?
What are you going to?
Yeah,
that's what I mean.
It is complex.
It's complex.
Or is that fucking stupid?
Here it is.
Sign saying it's okay to be white.
Found at Maryland.
Highschool.
Found.
Found bomb.
Yeah.
Uh,
what does it say?
Something at 5:45
AM and removed by staff before students
arrive for classes also say,
discovered them.
We're taking this seriously.
Oh my God.
They sent a letter home to families
informing them that the signs were
discovered on 10 doors at 5:45
AM and removed by staff before students
arrive for classes.
We're taking this seriously and are
investigating this incident.
Wrote Renee Johnson,
the school's principal.
Our research so far has indicated this
may be a part of a concerted national
campaign to format racial and political
tension in our school and community.
The same flyer was posted in other
cities and communities this week.
Okay.
But here's the question.
Do you disagree with the sentiment of
that statement?
It is okay to be white.
It's okay to be Chinese.
It's okay to be Indian.
It's okay to be whatever the fuck you
are.
Not Okay to be racist.
Maybe if they wrote it's okay to be
right.
It's not okay to be racist.
Maybe if they did that,
would that be an issue that would've
been.
That would've helped write.
That would have helped.
When you,
you know,
you walk into your school campus and all
of a sudden there's signs up everywhere
that normally there are no signs.
Well,
if they feel if they're a white person
and they feel like they're being openly,
racially discriminated against,
is it okay to say,
hey,
it's all right to be white.
Is that okay?
Yeah,
there's.
Yes,
of course.
So what's wrong with that sign?
Because you pop them up in the middle of
the night and put them all up on it and
keystone come in with your little lunch
bag and you're going to teach her
Spanish class and on your doors a sign
that says,
okay,
to be white,
you just,
your knee jerk reaction is,
whoa.
What?
What are you doing?
The fliers appear to be a part of an
online campaign that is detailed on the
web forum.
Four Chan.
Okay.
But is it a that.
But is that saying that for chance,
talking about this online campaign or
this saying that four Chan started this
online campaign.
I would lean towards that because it was
Halloween night and they discovered on
the article was posted November first.
So it's not like it's just a fun
halloween prank,
but like people do do that stuff,
you know?
It's like,
yeah,
it's totally okay to think it.
And you know,
it's like the guy with the bumper
stickers all over his car there.
Those guys are a little more unhinged
than the other people.
It's like,
yeah,
I think it's okay to be.
Why do I have to make a sign?
Do I have to go get copies?
Do I have to get some tape?
Do I have to sneak on campus?
Do I have to put it up there?
There was an article in Washington Post
Google this.
This woman wrote this article,
why can't we hate men?
And it was published in the Washington
Post and of course had a photo of Harvey
Weinstein.
Who's a disgusting man.
Right?
And this is the perfect example,
but that is literally like.
It's like,
what does that mean?
The worst
white man?
Hitler,
right?
Why can't we hate white men?
Because all white men are Hitler,
right?
Can't we hate white people?
Is that what the article was?
The Article?
I don't know what the article says.
I didn't read it,
but I mean like how could you write an
article that says why can't we hate men?
Because you want to get.
Unless you're trying to say we can hate
men because men are human and we got to
give everybody a chance and we can't
generalize.
Even if men have done horrible things,
I'd have to read it.
I don't.
I mean,
it's definitely the headline is made to
make you want to read it.
It's click baity.
Yeah,
it's it.
Exactly.
It's fascinating.
How about we just take the hate out
guys?
Can we just do that?
What's wrong with just Tom pump,
sweetie?
Come on.
Can we just get along?
You are a big sweetie.
Come here.
How much time?
I would much rather live in a world
where you go with your grandfather and
get a little kid a little bread and you
come back home and they yell at each
other and you make a meal.
You know what I mean?
Like why are we spending all this time?
Because I mean there's people that need
to spend the time to move the culture
and do things and protect themselves.
That's not what this is.
This is people trying to get attention
for their work.
They're trying to get attention for
their click baity little articles and
click baity little things,
little campaigns against people.
That's what it is.
I mean,
people love that shit.
All I would've had to do with this book
is,
is right.
Something about trump in it and that
people could sound bite.
Right?
Right.
And I ended up and have a lot of people
be like,
what is and get everybody talking about
it,
right?
That's what they're doing.
They're trying to make up make noise.
So people look at them and they make
more money.
Well,
and then there's also mean there has to
be a thought behind it like that.
Men have done some horrible,
shitty things.
So the.
But the idea of why can't you
generalize?
Of course.
Well,
you can't generalize because you're a
nuanced human being,
right?
You're supposed to be able to understand
full well every one is different.
Literally every,
every sing,
there's hundred and 50 million men.
The idea of why can't you hate all of
them while you can if you want to,
but it's a ridiculous way to live your
life.
No,
exactly.
Exactly.
So you means if you are,
you are you straight and you were
attracted to men and you have to hate
them all in quarantine yourself away
from just a lot of those guys,
right?
There's a lot of really good people out
there.
It's father's Day.
How often does that have to happen with,
with people who are homophobic,
who hate gay people,
rally against gay marriage and rally
against gay rights,
and then you find out that they're
really gay.
Yes.
Oh my.
All the time.
Almost every.
Everyone per religious guy.
Yeah.
It was anti gay.
Some scandal always comes out.
Oh,
he was sleeping with theirs.
So common.
It's cliche.
Yeah.
Right,
exactly.
It's that many of them.
Look for it.
When someone talks about gay is a sin
against men and yeah,
we should lock them up and we should do
this from.
Oh,
someone sucking Dick on the sneak dip.
Right?
Let's follow that dude around them
behind.
We're going to find this on.
We're
going to find it.
Yeah,
I'll find it.
I mean,
that's that.
That is what people do.
I think what I like about what you're
saying and how I feel too,
is that we need to be nice to each
other.
We this,
this whole idea of this gotcha bullshit
and this attacking people for things
that don't necessarily make sense
without,
without nuance,
without the understanding of complexity
of human interaction,
with no concern for that at all because
you just want to target,
you know,
I mean,
we have to shun that stuff.
That stuff is just pure foolishness and
it's bad for discourse.
It's bad for community.
It's bad for the way we communicate with
each other,
generates more hate and it's,
it's also a generalization,
a gross generalization,
which is just the same thing as sexism.
It's the same thing as racism.
It's the same.
It's the same thing.
Why can't we hate men as a gross
generalization like that state.
I don't know what the article said,
but that statement,
that's a gross general.
You can't because you're a nice person.
I assume you're a nice person.
Yeah,
because we don't hate.
How about that?
How about we try not to hate him.
You Hate Justin Trudeau.
That kind of seems like a sweater,
I seems awesome.
Yeah.
Trump trump week.
Yeah,
and an amazing suit.
He's trump called a week and dishonesty.
Yeah.
No,
I mean,
you know,
the culture has enough hate it.
I think the campaign has to be for more
kindness over that.
That's a great picture of him sitting
there with his arms crossed and they're
all leaning on the table,
listen to us.
Just listen to angry.
It was like,
no,
no.
I wonder what they're talking about
right there.
Like,
should we go to lunch?
I like Spaghetti,
but we don't have Spaghetti Donald.
We don't have spaghetti.
Spaghetti like some fucking spaghetti
could.
Someone gets spaghetti making me a
fucking pizza.
Can't you just get what everybody else
gets a wonder what they were talking
about that.
That is a great picture though.
That's great.
With him being the only one sitting
down,
arms crossed books so spoiled and her,
the look on her face,
she's like,
oh,
is that the woman from Germany?
Merkel.
She's got her own.
I have to deal with this on the table
and anger.
Anger fist.
Yeah.
What are you doing for Fathers Day with
nothing.
Nothing.
Just kinda hanging out.
Everyday is father's day.
It's true.
Yeah.
I don't want to.
I don't want any special treatment.
I don't celebrate my birthday,
I don't want anybody to give me
Christmas presents.
Do that anyway.
Of course,
but I don't.
I'm the same way.
Dad is just supposed to be there.
I like having them around.
I always tell them I want to see your
faces.
That's all I want.
I got all the gifts.
I got all the love.
I got everything I get.
If I get hugs every day,
I'm more than happy.
Totally.
I don't want like some fucking cake or
some stupid shit.
Brunch.
There's no father's day.
My Day.
There's no father's Day brunch.
There's no like,
you know,
having to race through the mall and
get flowers for father's day.
There was just let us be and be around
from some woman heckled in Chicago.
There was,
as I was talking about,
is actually,
it's a pro woman piece.
It's a piece about how we forget that
women make all the human beings and so
this idea that women are supposed to do
everything that men do.
Plus they also make all the fucking
human beings.
So I.
it's a lot.
It's this complex or twisty road that I
take people down with this.
There's a lot of like misdirection and
in any way I say it and then later on
I'm talking about something else and
this girl yells out,
we make other people and I'm like,
I just said that.
I said that five minutes ago.
I go,
that bitch is one of those chicks that
celebrates her birthday all month
and everybody went crazy,
but it's like,
that's what I don't want to be.
I don't want to be the person that wants
the attention.
Like,
this is my father's day.
Father's Day,
week,
the whole month.
His father's month.
Finally we're getting.
No,
no,
we got it easy.
I'm the same way.
It's that easy.
Yeah,
just I just want them around in the
house.
Let me see.
Your face is the reward is not a hard or
a cake.
The reward is actually in being a
father.
It's the greatest thing ever.
Yeah.
Just hold my hand for a minute just to
come up and just be like,
yeah,
hug me a little squeeze and we're good.
And I think they like that too.
Like I don't want dads don't want you
running through the mall trying to find
stuff for us and also dads by
everything.
Anyway,
dude,
I went to the King Tut exhibit.
Oh yeah.
Downtown.
Amazing.
Oh yeah.
Crazy.
They have things there from 3000,
300 years ago.
Wow.
They constructed them 3000 years ago.
They have jewelry and these,
these wooden boats that they found in
King Tut's temple or his tomb.
The.
Yeah.
And they um,
wow.
That's,
that's a bow and Arrow that they add.
Here's how stupid they are though.
Whoever put that thing together,
it says compound bow.
Hey,
you fucks you museum fucks.
That's not a compound bow.
Hey.
It's just not.
It's a traditional bow.
You asshole.
A compound bow has cams on it and it
works on a totally different system.
The fact that you fucking people are
running a goddamn museum and you don't
know what a compound bow is really
pisses me off right now.
There's a Guy Mr.
Rocha connected.
We just thought it with a bow and arrow.
I took a photo of it and I took a photo
of what it says,
what it says there,
because I was like legitimately angry.
I was reading this thing where it says
compound bow.
Here it says is what it says.
It says gilded wood in compound bow
with glass and calcite inlay.
It's not a cop.
Well Jim,
if.
Oh,
can we did.
We just thought it with a bow and arrow.
Ceremonial Boa Account.
Compound bow with one of those bose that
I have in the back there.
There,
there.
This is.
This is a very new modern creation.
You can fuck heads in this big Egyptian
thing with comedy or like I got angry,
obsessed with the bow and arrow.
Well,
I do get obsessed with it because a lot
to you,
but yeah,
and it makes me angry.
Wearing an archery shirt right now.
Nobody has archery shirts.
Nobody wears archery practice everyday.
To me,
I'm a person who's just like,
if I was looking at a,
a Jujitsu diagram and they said this is
a Kung Fu,
I'd be like,
Hey,
you fuck yeah,
this is important.
This is Brazilian Jujitsu.
Go back to that.
Yeah,
that's why I love boomerang boomerangs.
The boomerangs,
the shape of them,
they were not designed to come back.
It's interesting like I wonder like when
they figured out that was designed to.
As a weapon.
Yeah,
but just not enough of a curve for it to
return to the thrower.
So it was just means a hit somebody a
hundred yards away.
It just a good way to throw something
and hit it.
I love boomerangs.
They're pretty dope.
How they're cool.
It's cool design.
Oh,
I would go find open fields and you
don't catch it like it doesn't come
right back.
It comes back and like sales slowly
down,
like in a spiral at the end.
You know what's fucked up though about
this a tent King Tut exhibit is you
really got the sense that he was an
inbred first law.
Really.
His of his head was all fucked up and he
had a club foot like he was in.
He had two children that were all
mummified with him that were stillborn,
so.
And he married his sister.
He,
he,
his father had a baby with someone else.
And then he married his half sister
who's banging his half sister.
What they did,
they,
they were constantly inbreeding in the
royal families.
Try to keep the bloodline pure and to
try to keep all the money in the family.
Yeah,
that's true.
Did you ever see his head?
What is headed plank?
Jamie?
Pull up a photo of King Tucking.
Ted's been head skull.
He had this weird shaped deformed skull
and a club foot and all the depictions
of his body.
Yeah,
because it's a weird head.
Like look how big his head stuck up in
the back.
Oh,
we're.
He was essentially inbred like there was
something wrong with him.
Was he a good king?
Was only around for a little while.
He was just because we found his stuff.
I mean,
it's not like he had that much global
impact or did he?
That's a good question.
I'm not,
I'm not sure,
but it's got a weird little stories.
Amazing of how they found it and the,
the exhibit.
They have this imax movie that goes
along with the exhibit a
fucking bad ass because the imax screen
is gigantic.
Right?
So when you're there,
you get a real sense of how big these
structures actually are.
Right?
But they were looking for it for five
years.
This guy,
this British guy,
and this kid named Hussein who was the,
uh,
like,
he would get water for all the workers.
He was clearing,
like he had these water pots and they
set them into the ground so that people
could come scoop water while they're
digging and trying to find these.
Yeah,
well they're trying to find this tomb.
And uh,
he found a step.
He put the water bottle down,
he cleared some dirt away and he found
this flat rock just randomly flat rock
was the steel.
This one of the stairs that lead down to
the tomb.
And it was the only time that they ever
found that was completely untouched.
Really?
Yeah.
That is grave robbers.
Grave robbers had found every other tomb
because they,
oh really?
They've tombs were miles away from the
pyramids because,
I mean,
they probably had tombs in the pyramids
that were rated.
And then they realize after a while,
a quick,
we've got to hide these things.
So they took them way far out,
miles and miles away and they put them
in these hillsides and they put them.
Thieves found them there too.
She.
So when.
So it was that one like underground.
Did they build it that way or over time?
No,
it was underground.
It wasn't again.
That's crazy.
It's amazing.
Cool way to discover some.
Yeah.
One kid and he was the first one in the
tomb to because he was tiny.
So when they busted the whole,
they busted a hole through the wall and
he climbed in with a light around and
you see anything down there,
billy?
Well yeah,
that's part of the film is the
archeologists like looking through the
hole and seeing like the goals and all
this stuff.
First chip through the whole God.
Thousands and thousands of years
completely untouched.
Amazing.
It's amazing.
And then you've take that one thing and
a big giant rock ball starts rolling
after you like Indiana Jones.
It was a remarkable moment.
Is really interesting because like they
had like a glove,
a linen glove that was 3000 years old.
Really?
And you're looking at this linen glove,
that sandals,
they had the sarcophagus and sandals,
like he had like these sort of,
um,
you know,
decorative sandals.
So how long were they making that stuff
even been before then,
if that's 3000 years,
thousands of years.
So even before that,
I had a guy recently Dr Robert Schoch
from Boston University and he's a
geologist and he is one of the,
he's one of the first people to propose
the idea,
like one of the first,
like real scholars to propose the idea
that the sphinx is far,
far older than people think it is and
that it's not from 2,500
BC,
but it's from way before that,
perhaps maybe 10,000
years old in that because it has water
erosion.
All of it can only have come from
thousands of years of rainfall.
Yeah,
dude,
it's crazy.
So what's the implication of that?
The implication is that his,
he,
his take on it,
which is really interesting and he
really scared the shit out of me and
blew my mind.
Um,
mass coronal inject a ejections.
So something from the sun,
some gigantic solar flare that created
unbelievable havoc on earth.
He was talking about lightning storms
that were like the lightning coming down
like sheets of rain in a hurricane and
that it just covered parts of the earth,
lightning and killed everything and
killed off mass.
Just mass numbers of human beings.
Large mammals.
It's responsible for.
There's a,
there's a big mass extinction that we
really don't understand what caused
somewhere in that range of around 10,000
years ago.
And he attributes that to this mass
coronal objection and that this,
this huge sun,
this burst of energy from the Sun caused
these unbelievable chaotic storms that
killed.
Who knows,
count he.
I said,
so is it like,
like a thunderstorm times 100.
He's like,
no times a million.
He was like sheets and a million sheets
of lightning coming down like rain in a
hurricane.
Oh my goodness.
Imagine lightning just cooking the earth
for a long period of time or just one
big storm long period of time.
Like still sun just kept people that
studied living in caves and they built
these dwellings inside the earth because
that was where they can survive,
they can survive where the radiation
wasn't coming down,
it wasn't going through the earth to get
to them.
So houses,
tents,
and I think that you lived in that was
outside that those people were dead
because the only people that live or the
people that lived there had their houses
carved into hillsides.
Is there evidence of this?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Evidence,
geological evidence.
Which was it a mainstream thing or is it
his kind of wells?
He kind of knows that that's possible as
mainstream.
Whether or not it happened then is up
for debate.
It's also the end of the ice age and he
thinks that's the reason why the,
the all these ice caps melted.
This was what caused that.
It was part of that has a massive shift
in the massive shift in the,
uh,
the global temperature.
She's.
Yeah,
it's crazy.
I was just reading a thing about the
message yesterday and the Times that,
uh,
about how the Ice Change Manhattan,
all the five boroughs,
like that's kind of where the ice kind
of came down to,
was around there and seeing how receded
and what it left behind we were,
but the civilizations weren't really
living around them.
Right.
What do you mean during the Ice Age?
Of course there were,
they were,
well,
there were some civilizations.
I mean there's established civilizations
like there's some stricter Africa or
while there's some structures that are,
that have been absolutely linked to
that.
A big one is go beckley tap eight,
which is in Turkey and they have,
they've absolutely dated that to 12,000
years ago.
So what's fascinating about that is they
didn't know that people are capable of
building these gigantic stone structures
12,000
years ago and they've only uncovered a
very small amount of gold beckley
tapping.
It's a huge,
huge site.
So do you think that there's still tons
of stuff we could discover that hasn't
been tapped yet?
Like under the oceans or.
Yeah,
for sure.
Well,
if people find it,
if these guys are right,
and here's the thing,
they what they think is that there's
been,
there was a big dip and I forget what
his term that he used to describe it,
but it was the.
There was a dark age that was created by
these mass ejections and that
civilization particularly in Egypt had
reached a very high level of
sophistication when they are capable of
building these gigantic stone structures
and they had all this amazing
architecture and engineering or to move
these huge stones and then there was a
big die off and that for thousands of
years people essentially were knocked
back almost down into the stone age and
then regrouped and this is but this
cataclysmic story.
This story is in Noah's Ark.
It's in the epic of Gilgamesh,
which is,
which is where I rack is like they all
talk about the floods and cash in is
chaos and God punished everyone and
everyone died.
This is like a part of human history,
many different versions of of like,
right.
What exactly happened?
Yeah,
but he's pointing to geological
evidence,
which is fascinating because at one
point in time,
nine around 9,000
BC,
the Nile Valley was not all sand the way
we see it now,
but it was a tropical rain forest and so
for thousands of years before that,
it was torrential downpours and rain and
all this was the reason why the Sphinx
enclosure has these deep fissures that
are indicative of rainfall and water
erosion for thousands of years.
Not just instantaneous flooding from
some giant event,
but from thousands of years of rainfall,
of rain,
just constant rate.
And so that would predate the.
The idea is the current established
timeline is that the great sphinx was
created somewhere around the time that
they believe the great pyramids were
created.
Now the Great Pyramid of they've,
um,
they've,
they've done carbon dating that
indicates that that was somewhere around
2,500
BC.
He thinks that that was built over an
older site that was for many,
many years before that.
And he has all these photos,
similar construction methods that
they've done where they've taken a
really old site from maybe many,
many thousands of years ago and put
something over that like sort of like
the analysts did build on top.
Yeah.
But the Parthenon Necropolis,
they built it over the Acropolis or an
old thing that they don't even know
where the fuck it came from.
Where that old thing where it's from.
So the idea is that this old thing in
Egypt in particular is a product of an
old civilization from many,
many,
many thousands of years ago.
So long ago that the distance and the
gap between the people who built the
pyramids and the people who originally
built the Sphinx is far greater,
far greater than that.
Our distance between us and the people
who built the pyramids.
Oh really?
Yeah,
man.
That's amazing.
This is how fucking crazy it is.
It's about this.
Cleopatra is coach.
She's closer to the creation of the
iphone than she is to the creation of
the pyramids.
That's the real deal.
That means that yes,
that's established egyptologists
archeologists.
This is not controversial.
Yeah.
This is just a fact.
She then they cool,
but they think that at 2,500
BC that represents only the new
construction in Egypt and that before
that if you go to 10,000
BC and before there was a whole nother
civilization there.
She's,
that's amazing.
Yeah,
it's amazing.
And that this is when 10,000
plus years ago,
this is when these cataclysmic events
happen and all these people died off and
much of what they knew back then was
lost and they rebuild.
What's so scary about that is that,
uh,
it sounds like it could happen any day.
Something can happen with the sun and
all of a sudden we're dealing with some
other big solar flare comes at us and
we're in trouble.
What did it say,
Janet?
There was an article in business insider
about coronal mass ejections hots
coronal mean.
Go back to that is a different thing
though,
coronal.
Sounds like.
Yeah.
What did you just say?
High speed solar winds.
Increase lightening strikes on earth.
Yeah.
But what,
what was that last one though?
Coronal mass ejection.
Was it,
you have to
scribe or something?
It was,
I had it up for five minutes.
It was all red,
but it was saying that like they could
put it in that article.
Come.
Let me go back to it.
What do you mean?
What's it doing?
It's not.
It's acting weird.
I gotta find it.
It's King Tut.
This is what happened with Indiana Jones
and then he can't go back.
Why isn't it
there were shockingly unprepared for an
extreme.
Oh,
oh,
looks like you're using an ad blocker.
Just dissembled the ad blogger business
insiders.
Here it goes.
We're shockingly unprepared for an
extreme weather event that could fry
earth power grid.
Now.
That's something that.
What did he say had happened?
What year did he say he don't want that
to happen.
Carrington event was 18,
59 in 18.
50 nine event.
Oh yeah.
If it happened today with completely,
and this is a documented event,
if it hadn't been,
we're like,
transformers blew up all these
different,
um,
where they would do the Morse code and
Shit,
all that shit express and exploded
because of this coronal mass ejection or
gigantic solar flare.
And this is a documented
one and they're saying if this
documented one,
this Carrington event happened today,
we'd be fucked.
All the electric would puke.
Yeah.
We wouldn't have to go on twitter
anymore.
Yeah,
that would be amazing.
Yeah.
But you will also wouldn't be able to go
to the grocery store and your Tesla
wouldn't work.
But I would get my compound bow and go.
Not that piece of shit in the museum.
That's so crazy that we've.
What's crazy is that you,
these civilizations were able to build
up and they get knocked all the way back
and then build up a similar way.
Right.
If,
if you're talking about the Egypt one.
Yeah,
right.
They came back kind of in a similar way.
If the Pyramids and the Sphinx are that
far apart,
that there was something in the DNA in
the,
in the brain space that was that evolve.
They tried to come back the same way.
Was pretty interesting,
if not the same way in.
In a similar way.
Yeah.
I mean some of the people survived.
Right.
And some of the people that survived
must've had some knowledge of the
construction.
They pass it down from generation to
generation,
but you know,
you're dealing with thousands and
thousands of years where they weren't
building things like that and then they
figured out a way to do it again.
Yeah,
it's interesting.
How the fuck did they be?
So how did they become so smart?
That's what's interesting because the
great paramedics per perhaps maybe they
just had superior genetics,
but it's also what they were showing in
this video that I watched it in the imax
thing yesterday,
was that the area was so unbelievably
fertile that there was so much of an
opportunity for them to grow food and
there were so many animals there for
them to hunt and agriculture,
that they had a chance to sort of
establish a civilization because it was
such a rich area with natural resources
and established civilization and that
civilization just kept advancing and
moving forward and that it was all
eventually weakened by civil turmoil.
That civil turmoil in the Pharaoh's lost
their power and as the Pharaoh's lost
their power,
then they were invaded and yeah,
from across the sea.
Well,
no,
from inside of Africa over inside
Africa.
If you look at,
um,
yeah,
the Nubians took over Egypt at one point
in time,
sense of,
well different,
you know,
different people in Africa.
We're going over there and looking at
all the shit they had and also the
library of Alexandria was burned by the
Muslims.
Was it a lush area like when I picked
your Egypt I picture like a desert.
No,
right.
Is it?
No.
Denial was a river right.
And the river where the wetlands,
where it's filled with the animals and
they grew food there and what they're
thinking by this predating of the Sphinx
with Dr Robert Schoch with his,
his proposal is that it was initially
created back when it was rain forest and
was unbelievably lush,
so incredibly fertile and then slowly as
the climate shifted and that climate
shift could have corresponded with that
coronal mass ejections.
So it could have been some sort of a
massive event that's slowly or even
rapidly shifted the climate.
I would like to go over and see it.
I always,
I'm a little scared to go there.
To me both buddy.
Yeah.
That would be a cool.
I mean,
where,
what else would you want to see that's
that profound?
It's when they're walking.
When you watched the imax movie,
I can't recommend enough.
It's quick too.
If you have a short attention span,
it's like 45 minutes.
Right?
But when you watch them walk next to
these enormous statues mean these
fucking statues of the pharaohs are so
big that you see these little tiny
people walking by and you realize like,
oh my God,
look at this.
These people had done something
unbelievable.
The this,
the Pyramids and the Sphinx.
There's so much crazy.
There's so much.
And why just.
They're exactly right.
Exactly.
What did they figure it out?
Yeah.
How did they.
What happened?
Why were they the only ones at the time?
I mean,
it has to be connected to resources,
right?
Like because if you go today,
there's parts of the world where people
are,
you know,
and some impoverished parts of Africa
and particularly where they don't have a
lot of resources or people are fucked,
right?
And they don't have any opportunity and
they're in a terrible place and it's
just really,
really shitty time to be alive.
You're not advancing at the same time.
You can go to like the bay area,
some teasing cheese shop and right
around your electric car and you know
what I mean?
Seeing that on earth.
Yeah.
Simultaneously.
It's just purely what's available.
Yeah.
Like,
and what minds,
like how many Elan Musk's did they have
the Egyptian times,
right?
Because it was just us.
You and I were kind of dumb to be
honest.
Not that bright.
Yeah.
We're not venting tunnels under the
fucking.
Just getting by.
If we smoked a joint and started talking
about this is what we do,
we make fucking tunnels and then your
car goes into the tunnel and shoots
around that idea.
Fucking crazy,
bro.
Fucking love that idea.
But nobody would take it seriously and
nobody would let us dig and then we'd
just fall asleep.
Forget about it.
But yeah.
Must have been a bunch of Elon Musk's
back in the Egyptian.
Well,
that's what's amazing is there's this,
there's like this,
a genius Iq where all the magic happens,
you know,
like where the Einsteins live,
where the.
Yeah,
where those big leaps kind of happened
and everybody else,
he can be really smart but not to that
level where you're actually shifting the
world,
you know,
and maybe that's what happened.
Maybe there was just one genetic freak
in me,
a Egyptian world that was there because
their diet and stuff,
they were able to survive and it could
have been a slow process too because
you're dealing with thousands of years
of prosperity to over thousands of
years.
They have many,
many,
many generations to think things
through.
I right?
Think about what's happened on this
continent just over 200 years,
just 200.
Go back 200 years ago.
Nothing's here.
That's crazy.
It's crazy.
Just 200 years ago.
Yeah,
I go to where are we going to be like
2000,
3000 years ahead here who just here,
especially if you let elon must make is
tunnels everywhere.
There's going to be so many tunnels,
so anytime you can get to the Grand
Canyon and 10 minutes,
little pod,
but that is what is this?
Chandler wasn't 18.
18 of the United States.
Missouri territory.
Wow,
that's nuts.
Only 100 years ago.
Look how much they owe.
How much Spain owned new Spain.
Vice royalty of new Spain is all Texas,
California.
Arizona.
Nevada.
Yeah.
That looks like Montana,
Colorado.
She's looking at Oregon County Oregon
country.
Wow.
Shared with United Kingdom.
The whole north.
The northwest.
United Kingdom.
Nobody had the country.
Michigan territory.
Missouri territory.
Michigan was on both sides of the lake.
Look at that.
Is it?
Yeah,
so Michigan is on the left and the right
of the lake.
You upper peninsula.
Oh,
but not the right side where it says
Michigan territory.
That's not Michigan anymore.
That's Michigan.
The other side is Minneapolis.
Detroit and all that stuff isn't under
the upper peninsula up above Wisconsin.
Right,
but they're not both Michigan.
Right.
That's Minneapolis right here.
It is up there,
but where it says Michigan territory,
this Wisconsin.
Right.
That's what I'm saying.
I'm on my bed.
Sorry.
I said it says it right there.
It says Michigan on both genders was
just hit with a solar flare.
He just lost his mind.
Look at is disputed between
Massachusetts in the colony of New
Brunswick.
You K.
So that's main,
right?
Because they have Massachusetts
grabbing,
but Maine was like,
we're not sure what,
what,
what?
We might keep it.
We might not have realized how fucking
far up their maintenance.
There's a lot of mosquitoes up there
like Maine,
Massachusetts.
When you look at like where
Massachusetts is,
you know,
and then you go above Massachusetts.
Yeah.
Mains means big first place that gets
sun.
Sunlight in the morning.
Fucking giant man.
Yeah.
Huge.
Right?
And where's New York?
New York,
right down there.
Look at that right next to,
on New York goes.
Yeah.
So look at Massachusetts and
Massachusetts was two places.
Look,
it was Massachusetts and it was Maine,
right?
Look at that.
See?
Because there's two Massachusetts then
just like there's two Michigan.
Zara.
I'm going to keep all of it.
So this is 18,
18.
I want all of it.
Is that Ted Kennedy,
Kennedy.
I'll look at all that.
Man.
Arabella territory,
Georgia,
South Carolina,
so all those fucked up southern states
were still.
They're all filled with native
Americans.
We just came in and like,
let me have this.
I'm taking that.
Well,
Texas,
so brutal.
I mean Texas,
they were fighting off the Cheyenne.
I mean those ranchers,
they,
they.
That was not established territory yet.
That's one of the reasons why Texans are
so fucking hard,
man.
They,
yeah,
they were at one point in time,
they were a republic before they were
estate.
They were like this weird thing where
they were kind of like,
not even a part of the United States.
Oh really?
Yeah.
Just so wild that just happened.
We're talking thousands of years for
your little toots and comments.
A little fucking guy with his club foot.
A little bonehead.
Yeah.
Thousand.
That was thousands of years after King
Tut people were taking wagons and going
across the route.
Just going,
yeah.
Yeah.
How crazy is that thing?
Thinking back 3000 years later,
people are still shooting bows and
arrows at each other.
Yeah.
Three thousand years later.
Just completely wide open thousand.
Yeah.
So why?
Right.
So why weren't the native Americans
before we got here?
Putting up those big statues?
Well,
they lived a very different life.
They lived in nomadic hunter gatherer
life.
They have this incredible spiritual
connection to the land and to the
animals that they hunted and they had a
very,
very fascinated.
I mean there's a bunch of different,
of course,
native American cultures per data,
very fascinating connection to the earth
and to the animals and the worship that
they had,
the reverence they have for the animals
and for life,
the trees.
It's just crazy when you think about how
people were living in Europe at the same
time.
Yeah,
yeah,
exactly.
Just completely a totally different
thing.
Getting syphilis,
wearing powdered wigs,
banging their sisters.
Yeah.
So when they showed up and had gunpowder
and all the rest of the native Americans
didn't stand a chance.
What's crazy to me too is how many
people that were Westerners,
they joined a native American tribes and
we're living with them.
So really Kevin Costner.
Yeah.
It was really.
It was common.
It happened and no one,
no one moved the other way like no one
went the opera.
They were forced to.
American cultures decided I am going to
move to the city.
No,
those are the saddest pictures of all
time.
When you see those native Americans put
in suits and ties and hats and standing
there having to take pictures.
It was pictures of hard shoes and a
city.
Brutal.
Oh,
bad.
You know what?
It must've been a really interesting.
You know,
we're talking about your,
your vw,
which was from 20 years after the war
with the Nazis.
Yeah.
What about those wild bill wild west
shows?
Yeah.
They had those wild west shows where
they had men who had killed a bunch of
colonists.
Yeah,
and like there's a guy,
I think his name was mall.
It was this giant Indian guy who's just
fucking murderer
who killed a bunch of the settlers and
he was.
They would tour with him.
Wild bill would tour with this guy and
they would do on their wild west show
that shoot guns and do like show,
pretend to fight each other kind of
thing for people.
It was like a recreation of what it
meant.
What must have been like,
Geez,
when they captured territory from the
native Americans,
like they do these wild west shows.
Man,
that's how they made their living.
She became a big thing.
It's like the movies.
See,
pull up the wild west shows from the 18
hundreds.
Fascinating time.
Crazy.
They just,
after this had all happened,
I was telling stories.
Nobody knew about it.
You will get your little weird newspaper
to read a little story.
No one really knew what was going on and
how little you knew what was going on.
Thing you knew nothing.
The town crier would come in here.
He here,
he main game up the top of it.
It's now Massachusetts.
No one knew anything back.
Nothing that pawnee bill shows the only
genuine wild west touring America this
season.
Over 1000 people and horses employed
every equestrian nation in the world
represented.
Wow.
Two performances daily.
Weird and startling.
Free Street parade.
That name Calamity Jane.
I love this.
This is just the show business guy.
I wonder if there was a comedian in it.
Wild West shows.
Man,
and this was like early 19 hundreds,
late 18 hundreds.
When was it that says 19?
Oh,
two.
Nineteen.
Oh three.
Wow.
So this is,
you know,
that'd be pretty cool.
Like for a young kid,
years after the,
you know,
they were still going to war with the
native Americans.
Is that a picture of whatever.
They're crazy.
Yeah.
There's another one that had a
reenactment.
They did like custer's last stand and a
train robberies and to see that like 19.
Oh one.
Sure.
New York,
yet no movies.
He had nothing.
This was your movie.
Oh my God.
It must have been amazing and you still
had to try to make sense of it all.
Like what happened?
Yeah.
Do we get here?
And especially like you said,
having the real guy there who you know
could at one point just turn on
everybody and start killing people in
the audience.
There was one guy who was a giant and
see if you could find that native
American wild west shows.
I think his name was Mall Mall.
I think that was his name,
so I don't remember his name.
Look at Buffalo Bill.
Look at that,
just a showman and sitting bull.
He was a movie star hanging out
together.
She's Jesus Christ.
Look,
I'm sorry we took all your land,
but let's just hear me out.
I've got an idea.
We put some makeup on each other and we
go out.
We do these shows.
Listen,
we got whiskey.
A lot of white women or white women.
A lot of whiskey.
We tour around.
We make money.
We charged these dopes.
Do two shows a day and we're out.
Do you think women were like crazy?
This guys had seen him.
Fuck.
Oh my God.
Look at him looking like probably
scalped people.
Yes.
The avengers.
Custer by killing and scalping yellow
hair.
Also called yellow hand,
which he called the first scout for
custer change.
She's.
Yeah,
big ass show.
But here's the thing,
man that just happened.
All of this just happened.
We're talking about 1900 9,118
years ago.
It's almost a human lifespan like this
is this,
this convergence of human beings was so
recent.
Killed these more probably like movies
and radio people like for sure.
Probably looks like a movie production.
Like when you see each other a bunch.
I'm sure there was some venereal disease
involved.
Oh yeah.
They probably all died of fucking
herpes,
didn't they?
They had guns.
They were actually shooting guns.
They had like competitions and shoot.
Shoot off to the last three to four hour
show.
Well that's why the Western was such a
popular movie for decades because it was
still so fresh in people's minds.
I mean you had,
you had grandparents that knew this
stuff right.
When you think about like the 19 fifties
western zone 100 years after the fact.
Yeah.
Right.
That's like us watching something about
something that happened during the
depression.
Yeah.
Right.
Like once upon a time in America or
something like that.
Right?
Yeah.
Right.
That is the coolest.
But it's what's so funny about it just
show business.
It's like the beginning of show
business.
Yeah.
Well he figured out posters.
I mean all of it.
How much of it has really changed?
You know,
he put on a big show.
You make a cool poster,
you get these people to come and buy
tickets.
Two point 5 million tickets sold.
Wow.
You know what's really fucked up dude?
There was no comedy back then.
No,
stand up.
Well,
that's what I was going to ask Mark
Twain.
When was Mark Twain running around?
Because he was kind of like the first
stand up.
He would go do these shows and he read.
He writes about it like it's a standup
performance.
When was he has around?
Well they do.
He was talking about probably the first.
Yeah,
he was talking about things that didn't
work for a laugh.
Oh yeah.
Hal Holbrook's touring as him.
He's always torn.
I didn't know that was like what?
When did he live?
What was was the lifespan of Twain.
So that's an interesting case in Mark
Twain.
Yeah.
They use the n word all the time in
huckleberries.
Oh yeah.
Big Time.
And they're removing that now.
They were moving it,
removing it.
Who is editing it and removing it from
the books.
The publishers.
Come on.
That's.
I mean,
you know,
you want to learn about a culture at a
time.
Well,
one of the characters in Huckleberry
Finn,
one of the main characters was nigger.
Jim knows his friend that they removed
that.
The n word.
Really?
Yeah.
That's not weird.
Accurate.
Well that's.
Well that's sanitizing history and that
stake because you don't learn from that.
Jamie,
pull that up,
pulled up the censoring of Tom Sawyer or
huckleberry Finn.
Mark Twain had to build a little writing
room out in is out on his one so he
could smoke a cigar is out there because
his wife wouldn't let him smoke cigars.
So he built himself a little shed to say
go sit out there and smoke.
Good for him.
I just want to see when his life span
was old twain.
Yeah.
He was funny.
He ever read Twain?
Yes.
He was really like,
they're cutting.
Um,
what does it say here?
Jamie?
Place the word with the word slave.
Whoa.
Okay.
Look at this.
A new effort to sanitize.
Huckleberry Finn Comes from Alan
Gribbin,
professor of English at Auburn
University at Montgomery,
Alabama,
who has produced a new edition of
Twain's novel.
The replaces that word with slave peers
in the book more than 200 times was a
common racial epithet of,
okay Duh use by twain as part of his
characters of vernacular speech and as a
reflection of the mid 19th century
social attitudes along the Mississippi
River.
There is a,
so an effort,
but that doesn't mean that it's been
done.
There's a ride at Disneyland,
I want to say it's either splash
mountain or I think it is,
splash mountain,
splash mountain at Disneyland,
which was based on a really racist old
cartoon that you can't get anymore
called southern tails.
I think it's called southern the
Himalayan thing.
No,
no,
no.
That's,
that's the matterhorn.
Oh,
splash back in the briar.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Right,
right,
right.
Yeah.
That was good.
Prior Briar bear.
Briar Fox.
Yeah.
Brian Bear.
Fox.
Yeah.
The whole thing is like,
it's a southern ride and we'll just all
be singing ducks.
And uh,
we,
uh,
we went with a guide and the guy was
explaining to us that this is all based
on a really racist old thing that you
can only get like bootleg copies of now.
Oh really?
Yeah.
So this is super racist old cards.
I had like the tar baby and the target.
Right?
The tar baby thing.
Well,
what is it?
It's southern tails,
right?
Is that what it's called?
To find the name of it?
I'm just keep seeing firefox listed a
bunch of times.
A song of the south telling the song of
the south.
I think that's the name of it,
right?
It's called Song of the south.
I think that's it.
I think that's the name of it right now
that I think about it.
Yeah.
But it was a super racist.
Yeah,
I believe it.
There's a lot of bad stuff back then.
What does it give do that?
Yeah,
this is Zippity Doo Dah.
They sing this in the movie.
It's pretty dude.
Is
this,
why is this racist?
Well,
that's what they're asking is this
racist song of the south right now.
It's just a guy singing it.
Yeah,
I don't think this is the racist part.
I think the reason why you can get this
online is because it's not the racist
stuff because this is just a guy singing
Mr.
Blue Bird on my shoulder.
Myeloma.
So Song of the south.
The move.
See if you could find song of the south.
Yes.
With the clip that popped up when I
grew.
Yeah.
80 one percent.
Like to look at rotten tomatoes.
Seven point three on the imd being.
So it's on imdv 1946.
Wow.
Maybe it wasn't Mark Twain died in 1910.
So that means that he was walking around
as an old dude doing these performances.
Uh,
you know,
late 18 hundreds.
And so maybe that was the kind of the
beginning of a standup comedy.
Go back to that,
go back to that page you were just on
and that snopes article on it where they
do a fact check on the song of the south
to see it up there.
Yeah,
I was gonna say I was going to double
check it before I wanted to see what it
says.
It's true,
wasn't safe.
Uh,
pull it up.
I had it up.
Oh,
song of the south and Naacp Song of the
south unavailable on video in America
because of the Naacp threats status.
True.
Wow.
So it was that racist and wonder what it
was.
There was so much racist shit back then.
Try or rabbit,
right.
Or Fox bear bear.
Why Breyer?
What does that mean?
A briar like stuck in a Briar r dash e
are briar rabbit burrow sprayer bear.
So that was the idea that they're stuck
in briars the minstrel tradition of
uncle remus stories.
The major objections to the song of the
south had to do with the live action
portions filling been criticized for
making slavery appear pleasant and
pretending slavery didn't exist even
though the film that's kind of.
You're caught in between lunch.
That potential what you just said,
even though the film,
like Harris original collection of
stories is set after the civil war and
the abolition of slavery still is
folklorist Patricia rates.
Yeah.
That's fascinating.
So that's kind of interesting,
especially when you talk about the,
when you talk about,
uh,
the huckleberry Finn Part,
like they're saying,
okay,
take that out.
And then this one,
they're saying they had an objection to
making it seem like slavery didn't
exist.
That's why you can't take it out of
huckleberry Finn because you need to
know that this existed.
We need to deal with it and understand
it rather than sanitize it.
Problem is defending it.
Like,
like you can't do it.
You really.
It's almost impossible to defend that.
The use of that word
I'll give you wanted to defend the use
of that where you say,
well,
we want to put that word back in a book.
People like,
what are you racist?
Right?
But you can't.
You know that rationally this is
history.
Yeah.
Right.
Exactly.
Rational.
Right.
There's no rationality when it comes to
dangerous.
Forbidden words as you saw from the
Kendrick Lamar concert.
Right,
right.
I mean that's.
I wonder what Twain would say.
Do you think that ultimately like this
is all going to sort itself out like
this,
all this political correct craziness and
this kind of shit,
that this is just a little rough patch
of chaos that we get through on our way
to establishing a new way of
communicating with people a new way of
appreciating each other and that,
you know,
all this.
Even the anti white racism and anti male
sexism and all this stuff.
It's just a,
you know,
the wave going this way and then it'll
go that way and then it'll settle in the
amount of.
Yes,
and then we're learning from even these
missteps.
Like why can't we hate all men or
anything like that that we learned from
these missteps and the outrage that goes
to these missteps.
And we say,
Oh,
I understand why this woman feels this
way.
She's probably abused by men and dealt
with asshole men and asshole bosses and
see these people like Harvey Weinstein
in the mainstream media that have abused
and violated and victimized women and
that it is going to balance itself out.
And the only way it goes is you have to
have outrage and then correction and
yeah,
I mean that's the way history seems to
go.
It seems like,
you know,
there's,
you would think in certain ways like,
oh,
we don't have to work that hard to
abolish these evils,
but then evil pops up again and it feels
like,
okay,
no,
it's still here.
We still have to deal with it.
Yeah.
And you just hope at the end we all end
up like Bruno Mars.
We all look like Bruno Mars and
everybody's happy because no one knows
who,
what anybody is.
Yeah,
just having a good time and we're all a
little darker and not totally white,
not totally black and everybody's but
it.
But what about white people?
I like looking at white people.
I like people I like.
I like the whole,
I liked the fact that we have variety in
the way people look.
Like some people look like seal and,
and some people look like,
um,
it was like a super white lady.
I'm like a cool kid.
Nicole Kidman.
I bitches white.
Yeah.
White.
Almost red.
Yeah.
Yeah,
it is good to have a nice mix.
Fuck man.
It's fascinating.
We're still these very tribal,
you know,
when you're talking about all these
thousands of years and what we've done
and where we've come seal this,
this just instinctual tribal element to
a lot of humanity.
You got to get out of a Dick luck,
an axe handle to wear your shirt like
that at that shirt shirt all the way
down to his belly button with gold
chains hanging out with the white trench
coat.
Yeah,
no,
you're packing and he's got sunglasses
on at night,
which is a bold
move that really only black people can
pull.
Yeah,
exactly.
Just owning it.
Slang and Duke and sang songs.
Dude.
Uh,
he um,
he,
you don't hear about him anymore man.
Well,
you never know
dude.
When I first moved to California,
when I first got some money,
I was on this television show,
one of the first things I bought as a
stereo.
So I always loved good music.
So I bought the Stereo and uh,
I bought seal and I remember listening
to kiss by a rose from the grave or
whatever the name of that song,
that song I'd never realized.
I never heard it on a good stereo
before,
but I have these two speakers and like
there's all these like layers and piano,
tuned sex.
She's,
there's all this stuff that comes out
of,
you know,
when you're sitting in front of like
good speakers.
Yeah.
You hear all the layers,
the music.
And I'd be like,
wow.
It was like hearing in zoo all over
again.
Oh,
it was so like hearing it knew he was.
I mean,
I guess he still is.
He's still alive,
but he is so fucking talented.
A real artist.
It's so different than like try naming
someone who sounds like seal.
Yeah.
Um,
I can't.
The black keys.
No,
no,
no.
He's a fucking original man.
Yeah.
Super.
For essence,
I don't know,
it's just,
he's kind of a very unique style.
Yeah,
there's was a lot of those.
What's unique about.
There are a lot of artists that have
really crazy kind of unique style,
but they don't become accepted from the
mainstream.
By the mainstream.
Yeah.
Right.
Like there's,
he listen to kcrw in the morning and
there's like a lot of weird experimental
stuff,
but not that many people know they
exist.
CEO was able to make that like a.
So you're one of those hipsters listens
to that show.
You and Henry rollins or kcrw like kcrw
in the morning.
I don't know.
What morning sounds into radio in a
decade.
For Real?
Yep.
Where do you get your new music?
I don't know.
Come on right now.
I know.
What gets you for father's day gets you
some albums.
Performance though.
Is this recent?
No,
no,
no.
This vh one.
Vh One.
This one of the things is when he was
peeking.
Vh One.
Still around.
Still around the real housewives and
all.
Yeah,
I think they do.
Maybe that's Bravo.
All right.
Well then I didn't know that they used
to play those like reality shows and
stuff.
Yeah.
Loving basketball or love and hip hop or
something.
Do that stuff.
Why did he have faced bubbles?
You mean this scarring?
Yeah.
I don't know.
Was that acne?
There's an article from three days ago
that had that info.
Oh really?
Just three days ago.
Still thinking about it.
People are still asking him.
Well,
he was so good,
but was the coolest body of work is just
radically off a lesson that lupus had
lupus.
Oh Wow.
Yeah.
That's where he's got the scarring from
his face from lupus.
Interesting.
Is that amazing?
You'd have it all down your face and
still be like,
no man,
I'm beautiful and you're going to think
to.
Well,
not really.
You don't get new music.
You listen to new music.
I don't even know what it is.
I'm on Joe.
I told you.
I like Bruno Mars.
He's new.
That got somehow could cut.
He just dropped a new album this week
too.
Moody,
Moody with your white privilege.
You son of a bitch appropriating it.
Cut.
Is it mute?
Moody.
Depression based music.
He's getting his feelings out kind of
stuff.
Yeah.
He bought a lot of deals with mental
illness.
You don't lucky you liked bake bread and
cookies and shit.
Oh,
I love it.
So you,
you don't like Moody Shit,
Dude.
I do love moody stuff.
I like,
I've listened to him.
I get every,
everyone,
he's one of those prove themselves so
early.
Like I just loved it.
So they don't just get whatever he puts
out Wilco's like that.
He's like that.
It's just like.
So you're into the hip hop,
eh?
A little bit.
I try,
but I,
you know,
do like old,
older stuff.
Older hip hop.
Do you like Gangstarr?
No.
How dare you put down and get the fuck
Outta here?
Not like Gangstarr.
I don't even know.
Gangster.
So you hurt my feelings.
Come on.
Or were you in the nineties?
I was uh,
I was around.
I was running around in the nineties,
early nineties.
Grateful dead.
That's the end of the dead.
Uh,
you liked the grateful dead almond
brothers.
Did you like the grateful dead?
Allman brothers and brothers?
Gangstarr?
Uh,
I was listening to yourself a favor.
Download a decade of it.
I was listening to tribe called quest
and you know,
here's another one that went away.
De la soul know.
They were so great.
They were de la de la de la,
so they were amazing dude.
They were great.
They were hot like right when I first
got into comedy.
Oh,
that's so cool.
Dude.
Three feet high and rising run DMC.
Well that's great that they released all
their music,
but their music came from like six
months,
six months of music.
Like what the fuck man uses.
I Love Nas.
Yeah,
Nas fan,
but here's what gets me.
How does someone put out something?
How does a group put out something
that's so good?
Yeah,
for a short period of time and then not
bump bump.
Bump three had a great fucking song.
They were really good and they were
interesting.
It's hard to keep a band together and
they were.
Yeah,
they were good to get high too.
You know?
We probably did a man,
some white bitches,
white girl,
son of a bitch came along,
fucked everything up.
I just don't like the way he looks at
you.
When you saying I liked hip hop and
stuff and I still do,
but it's a very,
you know,
old white guy waves doing and find it.
When I find it,
I know it must be over.
Like why that,
that I found Kendrick,
I was like,
oh,
so this is done right.
Once you find it,
it's over.
Interesting.
I don't think it's enough to kill
Kendrick Lamar has momentum,
but you know,
he's got too much momentum.
Yeah.
But it was like,
okay,
why?
I mean if it got to me,
you know,
and I tried like I tried to listen to
music,
you know,
it's different when you're young and it
just hits you and you from your friends.
And I have to like really try and find
music now because I have no friends.
I go to Jamie and then I have to throw
it through a filter that's throw it
through A.
Yeah,
but he wears yeezys.
Exactly.
He's making it all becomes on two weeks.
Doesn't really.
Kanya is producing nozzles,
new albums.
I'm not saying that it doesn't produce
good music,
I'm just saying it's sneakers killer
Mike.
I like killer Mike Jayco A.
Yeah,
like a lot of stuff,
but you know,
it's a big,
it's a big range.
If you listen to bluegrass and hip hop,
it means you're just tasting it all.
I feel like music is a lot like movies
in that people are constantly making new
stuff and you can't see it all or.
Yeah,
it's true.
I mean think about movies.
They have been making movies since
whenever the fuck they started making
movies and every week they come out with
new movies.
You're right.
No one ever says,
Hey folks,
you know,
we just realized that we keep making
movies.
You're never going to watch the
godfather.
We're going to watch taxi driver.
You never going to watch the classics,
so we're going to stop making movies for
awhile.
They'll let you fuckers catch up 10
years off now we'll start off and again,
10 years he just cranking them out.
It's going even more because now you can
just make them on your phone,
like via technology to be able to make a
movie.
So you can just do it.
Dude.
You mean the phones that we have now are
dog shit compared to the phones will
have in 10 years.
Soderbergh just shot a whole horror
movie on his iphone.
Did he really?
Yeah.
What is it?
It's called unsane.
Whoa.
Yeah.
Girl trapped in a mental institution.
Isn't there a horror movie that's out
right now called hereditary?
What is that about?
Is that a good one?
Let's be really good.
I'll play the trailer trailers
sometimes.
Sometimes the trailers.
The most enjoyable part of the movement.
Sometimes a lot to give you too much
though.
Oh yeah.
They do that with comedies,
man.
They.
They give you too many God damn
punchline.
Give me some volume.
Crank it would get in trouble for this.
I don't will get pulled from youtube
trailer.
We're helping them.
I mean if you're honest,
you guys were like talking over emoting
them.
It can maybe stop at 37.
Give me some books.
Scary.
It starts with a doll house that is a
scary dog or an architectural design.
A model.
A minute.
Man
Walks in it.
That was cool.
It made it look like a real room under
ground.
It's hard to production companies and
exchange new faces here today and I know
my mom would be very touched and
probably a little suspicious.
Gabriel Burns in it.
My mother was a very secretive and
private woman from the producer of the
show,
which,
which I didn't see a favorite.
It was good though.
Oh,
and what's your name?
Baby Shark at?
No,
she was a very difficult woman.
Damon wins.
Maybe explain to me from your mother
sometimes.
I swear I can feel a kid.
She cut her head off a dead bird.
If it's crazy.
You got a kid with mental problems.
She says,
look at what demons.
She looks good.
Private friends.
Generations.
The exercise took care of me.
You don't think I'm going to take care
of you when you die.
Just coming up with real hard.
She wasn't altogether unspeakable kind.
This looks good at the end.
Wow.
Very scary.
I just don't want to put any more.
It looks good.
That looks scary.
I can't see it.
Why can't you see it?
Because I can't see anything.
When do you see things I'm talking
about?
We just said,
look,
do you ever watch stuff?
I'd go to the movies.
When do you do that?
Whenever I can see you're writing books
and Bacon bread.
Take a couple of hours off.
Go to the God damn movies.
Writing is killing.
I really haven't.
My father said that to her the other
day.
Watch it on.
Watch this movie on the plane.
I'm like,
I haven't watched a movie on a plane in
two years.
What was the movie that Eddie Bravo city
saw for like six minutes and then he
left.
Oh yeah,
some not.
It was one of the new,
uh,
was a big blockbuster movie.
Oh yeah.
Was it Black Panther?
No,
no,
it was the avengers.
Damn.
Oh,
they,
uh,
that new one.
The uh,
wasn't deadpool because I think it
might've been the avengers or something
that new avengers one that everyone
loves,
but doesn't make sense that he would
have walked out of that so quick.
I don't remember what it was because
everyone loves this will make sense.
Period.
He's got a weird taste.
Do you go to the movies?
How often do you go to the movies?
Once a month,
month,
maybe once.
Yeah.
I watched some on flights,
you know,
when they come out,
I don't really get too much of a chance.
Um,
you know what?
I really enjoyed that Tom cruise movie
about barry seal made in America.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
I was pretty.
It was good.
Yeah.
I was pretty surprised by that.
That's a good goddamn movie.
You forget how good Tom Cruise's too.
He's,
he's great.
I mean all of the crazy talk show stuff
aside.
That guy's amazing.
Well,
it was a scientologist.
He's got his own stuff,
but he makes good movies,
but people who are out of their mind
make good shit.
Yeah.
That's part of the thing.
Yes.
Part of the being good at stuff.
Just some of the crazy assholes.
Yeah.
Good Shit.
They really do.
A lot of times you can harness it word.
If you can harness it and put it into,
into something.
It's good movie,
man.
Yeah.
All right.
I'll make it impossible to come on.
Cruise comes out in a couple of weeks.
I'm just going to live.
That's what I hear.
Go cruise gets to the end and he lives.
He does all his own stunts of shit.
He's going to drive that thing.
Oh,
he just.
He just does that.
He does a lot of stunts.
Pretty crazy for a dude who's.
He think he is 53 or 54 and he's still
doing all his own stunts.
Yeah,
it's pretty bad ass.
Yeah.
He was in a.
What was that Jack reacher movie though?
That one was a Turd.
Making another one?
No,
I think it might've been John Wick.
They're going to have doing a third one.
Of course.
Doing it right?
Yeah.
He got killed.
I repeat.
He was in with an awesome movie.
I think it changed the name of it.
I don't think that's what it was
originally called,
but now we have to keep redoing the
scene.
He goes back and they ended up like
killing everyone in.
What's that movie?
The day after tomorrow.
Oh right.
Wasn't that used to be called killed?
I repeat Egypt tomorrow.
Edge of tomorrow.
That's right.
That movie was fucking bad ass.
That was a really,
really good science fiction movie,
but it was one of the ones that came
out.
What year did it come out?
14.
Two thousand.
14 was just a few years removed from him
being wacky when he did that.
Uh,
Matt Lauer interview on the today show
where it was like,
you're being Glib,
Matt,
but he's talking about Brooke Shields
taking psychiatric medication and you
understand this.
I understand this.
Yeah.
Scientology is highly critical of
psychiatric meditation.
They prefer you stay crazy.
They don't.
You don't know what you're talking
about.
Matt,
have you done the research?
I've done the research.
You're Glib,
Glib,
but lauer didn't handle it that good
either.
Now you're supposed to go.
We'll explain to me the mechanism of the
what's happening with the psychiatric
drugs and what do you pose?
Yeah.
And why do you think that you understand
the biological makeup of all these
different human beings and that none of
them should be taking psychiatric
medication now?
That's a crazy thing to say that you're
smarter than all these biologists and
medical scientists and all these people
that have concocted
these SSRI and different.
Have you done the research?
Have you done,
you done the research or you glib making
top gun to right now to ever tell you?
The first time I did Letterman,
when Cruz was on it,
they ever tell you that story?
No,
I was doing my first letterman.
I'm super nervous and I'm just trying to
tell myself,
you know,
just like any other show.
It's just like any other show,
you know,
Tom Cruise is this first time.
He's on the show in like 10 years,
15 years,
and he's on and I'm watching through the
monitoring.
He's running up and down the uh,
he's running up and down the hall where
the theaters,
like saying hi to people at during the
break.
No.
Yeah.
He's like,
hey,
was just like running up and down and
having this great time.
Like it's just,
it's just another show,
it'll be okay,
and then they bring you down stairs and
you're standing outside this door,
like to go onto the stage and he says
goodnight during the show and he,
the door swings open and a very sweaty.
Tom Cruise is like nose to nose with me
and he's like,
you're next.
And he hugs me.
He's like,
Woo,
it's great out there.
It goes bouncing up the stairs and I'm
like,
what's going to happen to me out?
This is terrifying.
He totally took all of my coolness.
Just chew a little strange guy.
Yeah,
but the energy just,
he was like an electric eel and I'm just
like,
it's all right.
I can get through this.
He's such a strange,
strange guy when he gets into that,
like I'm laughing.
Thing is just gets weird.
Oh God,
no.
It wasn't such a high altitude that it
would've,
you know,
death.
Right.
I'm standing in the wings right now.
What are you thinking?
Like what am I going to say first?
Yeah.
Just to think with those things.
Those things are such a little weird.
Sprint has my tie.
How's my tie?
Right?
What's my first line?
What am I going to say?
Try.
Did I go out casual?
Yeah.
There's a heated interview from Matt
Lauer.
Play that.
It's right there.
I was coming up next.
Here it is.
Here's Matt,
Matt,
a full head of hair back.
Then we'll get back.
He's got all that hair.
Two thousand 14.
Looking at my handsome bastard radio
play.
It was my first exposure to this story
than just an alien movie.
The story breaks down on a lot of
different levels and in one to each
other already not the best father in the
world when we are working on the story.
Originally,
three years ago,
Steven,
I came up with this idea of nature
keen about a family.
That was a good movie.
I'd love to.
Yeah,
me too.
Okay.
You want to go inside?
Of course you do that real sense of like
where we're going to go.
Well,
that's what I think it would probably be
like if we did get invaded to be robots
like that.
Yeah.
That'll be cool.
Play some of.
Before I was a scientologist,
I never agreed with psychiatry and then
when I started studying the history of
psychiatry,
I started realizing more and more why I
didn't agree with psychiatry.
And as far as the Brooke shields thing
is,
look you,
I understand.
I really care about Brooke Shields.
I here is a wonderful and talented woman
and uh,
I want to see her do well and I know
that a psychiatry is,
it's a pseudo science,
but Tom,
if she said that this particular thing
helped her feel better,
whether it was the anti depressant or
going to a counselor or a psychiatrist.
Isn't that enough?
You have to understand this.
Here we are today where I talk out
against drugs and psychiatric abuses of
electric shocking people against their
will of drugging children with them not
knowing he's got good,
good effects of these drugs.
Do you know what adderall is?
Do you know Rhydlin?
Do you know now that Ritalin is a street
drug?
Do you understand that the differences.
This was not a.
This wasn't against your question.
I'm asking you a question.
I understand there's abuse of all of
these things.
Now.
You see,
here's the problem.
You don't know the history of
psychiatry.
I do aren't.
There are examples in my book shields be
an example of someone who benefited from
one of those drugs.
All it does is mask the problem,
Matt,
and if you understand the history of it,
it masks the problem.
That's what it does.
He is pretty aggressive on Lauer.
Makiko not getting to that wasn't being
shitty.
He's just.
He's just like intense.
Meanwhile,
he's right about a lot of it.
He's definitely right about adderall and
Ritalin that some people abuse it,
but abuse.
Just because someone abuses it doesn't
mean it doesn't have uses.
You know?
It doesn't.
I don't.
I've met people that are on adderall and
they see they need it.
I don't know if they're right.
Yeah,
but the guy who developed adderall says
that it should be for about four percent
of the population.
That's a lot like four people out of 100
and a room full of 100 people.
Four of them are cranked out and doctors
are cranking it out like 30 percent
patients.
They say,
yeah,
it's like super high that he.
The guy who made it so that it's being
abused a while,
I'm sure it is.
And amongst Germany.
Have you done the research?
Joe?
Well,
I know a lot about time about.
I understand this standard,
I understand that,
but he's right about little kids and
Ritalin and I had a neighbor.
They drugged their kid up fucking
Ritalin.
It was weird.
It was nothing wrong with the kid.
He just had energy and the parents were
working all the time.
They just didn't want to deal with it.
They put the kid on Ritalin.
Terrible.
They were bad parents.
That's terrible.
It was.
I was watching it happen.
I was like,
whoa.
And then they.
They zone the kid out.
They got a monster shit and he was just
like,
like a weird little Zombie kid after
that.
Oh Man.
Say Hi to him.
He's like,
hi.
Oh my God,
that's terrible.
It was.
We could have been an artist.
It could have been something great.
Right.
That's
taken away from him.
You put a kid in a classroom and you
make them listen to boring shit all day.
They don't want to do it.
You think,
well,
there's something wrong with this child.
Yeah.
Right.
No.
These kind of actually a free thinker.
He's actually gonna do some really cool.
Yeah.
He's got energy.
Let them figure it out and do something
great.
He's bouncing off the walls.
Yeah.
Let them go outside.
Yeah,
because he's not turning into a robot
like the rest of the class,
but that's what we need.
We need robots.
We need workers.
What we can do with three d printers,
we can make them totally with human skin
around the outsides.
They're going to ship the three d
printers to Mars and have them make all
the stuff we need on Mars right there.
You don't have to ship it.
Do you think in our lifetime someone's
going to fly to Mars and live there?
Yes.
You're looking at him.
I've already told my family.
I might not come back,
but I'm going to be a pioneer.
Come back.
If you go there,
you're not coming back.
I know.
Die On Mars.
Pretty cool.
No,
you won't be able to do sets up there.
Yeah,
I will.
Because by then is going to be all
holograms,
so you'll be able to like beam you into
a room.
Yeah.
It will be made at the comedy store
doing a late night set,
but ours.
Is that good enough?
No,
you don't.
For us,
we won't feel a log.
You won't feel it.
It's an analog experience.
Yeah.
There's no energy transfer yet.
Think someday.
Yeah.
They're going to harness your energy.
It will be that good.
You think you'd be able to bang people
weren't there?
Yeah.
I'm going to make them with my three d
printer with human cells and then bang
them.
We're setting up.
This is why I made you pay.
Well,
that's.
That's an interesting question.
Right?
There's people that are.
They're considering the ethical
implications of making a headless person
that you would harvest your organs for
like say right.
If Tom Papa decides I'm going to make a
headless Tom Papa and I'm just going to
drink like a fish and scoop the and
liver out of this asshole sticking into
my body.
It was pretty cool.
It was great.
Yeah.
It.
Your grandpa needs a liver and you want
to keep grandpa live,
harness all those parts.
Yeah,
but what are the.
What's the ethical considerations?
Someone just told me that there's.
If you need a part,
if you need an organ or something,
you go to the states that have no helmet
laws.
Jesus.
How crazy is that?
I was just in Chicago.
Chicago doesn't have helmet laws.
Oh really?
Dude.
Watch these people running the highway,
but you know when it goes to your liver
at home and then in Chicago they don't
have helmet laws but they can't split
lanes right at home and these fucking
guys are just driving right next to cars
whizzing in between lanes and I'm like,
what's more dangerous?
Is splitting lanes more dangerous or is
it riding around with no helmet?
No.
Scary though.
Both of them.
Have you ever ridden a motorcycle?
Yeah,
for years,
like 15 years?
Yeah.
So my kids were born.
I went around the whole country on my
bike,
my wife and I on the back for five
weeks.
Wow.
Did we talk about this?
I think we must have.
It's one of my big story.
I remember you saying that.
I do miss it.
Like I see bike.
I've been looking at it more.
Would you emote a glitzy had like say if
you had a summer house in big bear or
something like that or a main.
Nobody up there.
You just drive around,
get a nice bike up there that I would do
that in a slow.
I would do that.
I got to get a house freedom.
I love it.
You're so focused because you don't want
to die.
It's one of those things that you're
just so focused on.
You forget about the whole rest of the
world locked in a.
it's so nice to sound good.
I know I've been looking at bikes
lately,
but you see people that get fucked up.
Our bikes,
it's not good now.
Especially here.
I know you don't listen to the radio,
but if you do out here,
you hear about radio a motorcycle
accidents.
Like everyday there's traffic on the
five.
There was a motorcycle accident.
I know because it's music.
That's what you.
Let's do well on the radio.
Well,
they break in once in awhile and say
there's an accident or something.
If I'm not listening to the Sirius Xm or
podcasts,
or you listen to Sirius,
what do you listening to?
Sometimes they'll listen to comedians
sometimes listen to the news.
I have a Sinatra station,
a coal train station.
Oh,
um,
yeah.
Music.
You know,
I'm a hip dad.
Yeah.
Do you think your kids think your hip
dad?
No.
Humiliate.
Totally.
Just how it's always going to be.
Which is cool.
They liked that.
They liked knowing that the door is
there and he loves them.
Yeah.
That's the whole key.
You're stupid.
Don't you love making your kids laugh?
Oh yeah.
Oh,
it's the best fun.
A lot of dads can't make their kids
laugh.
Really?
Yes.
They can make them laugh in a goofy way,
but when you can make them laugh in a
way that you know is really funny.
That's like,
you know,
my youngest standup up funny.
My youngest is fucking fun.
She's really into it too.
She's really into saying funny shapes.
Got good timing.
It's good.
It's funny.
My little ones.
Those same way.
Yeah.
Well,
they realized that's how they get
attention.
Yeah.
You,
your y's assets.
Yeah.
You say something.
They say something funny.
Everybody laughs and they're like,
whoa.
That felt good.
Yeah,
it gives them a little charge.
And what's funny too is,
uh,
probably the same thing that she has
mine has,
is that they're not doing it for you.
They're doing it purely for them to mock
you.
They victimize you.
Yeah.
Your mock you.
What's it like being old and mock you?
They'll have to mark the fact that I'm
bald.
I know they mock that.
I can't see any glasses.
Yeah.
Daddy's eyes were fading.
Watching me to use a cell phone and not
be able to navigate.
Just Dad just give it to me.
Oh,
they know how to use electronics in a
weird way.
Oh,
look to it.
Like they know how to edit videos and
shit like that.
I'm like,
how do you know how to do that?
Like,
and then they don't even have a phone
completely feel like using my wife's
phone and they're making videos
mccullough.
Fuck.
Did you know how to do that?
This is a little video editor.
Programs and shit,
cause I have a young brain,
I can learn things very quickly,
very quickly.
Eyesight is killer.
I can learn things quickly.
I say killer is a big deal,
but I think it's uh,
the,
the brain is so plastic.
Yeah.
The mental plasticity is just,
they just,
they figured out,
oh yeah,
you swipe right.
Oh you do that.
And then you highlight that and he
spread this out and touch that and edit.
You don't want that.
You want to filter so you go down to the
bottom.
I always.
My kids were uh,
with my wife at a party,
at a relatives when I got home
yesterday,
they weren't there and I facetime with
my daughter.
I said,
how's mom doing it?
And she was bored at the party.
She's like,
how's mom?
I said,
how's my doing at the party?
She's like,
she's doing okay.
She's inside.
She's her to repeat a couple stories a
couple times,
but she seems to be having fun.
They're all over us.
One day there'll be us.
Yeah,
it's great.
We'll be their version of US raising
their own kid going,
what the fuck?
I've got kids now and you'll be like
with this new baby that they made kids
cute hair.
Take them fishing responsibilities
anymore.
Let me have a little kiss.
Let me get some sugar for that baby
cheek.
Now I'm out.
Bye.
Good luck.
Changing the diapers.
A uh,
can I babysit Friday night?
No,
no.
That's for you.
I'm working.
Do you think you'd be working to the
bitter end?
To the end?
There's no part.
When I hear people say that they're
going to retire,
like anybody just in the world and say,
I here retirement.
I know that's one thing.
I'm not doing bright.
There's no why.
Why would you retire?
I want to make stuff until I go.
I want to put out stuff and see what
that stuff will be later on.
Who knows?
Well,
it's also,
you've chosen a path that it's just
perfect for you.
You actually,
you're not working because you have to
go to work.
You're working because you enjoy what
you do,
which is really what I encourage
everyone to try to attempt to do this,
this,
this thing that we're taught in school
to try to find a good job that pays
well.
That's wonderful advice,
but it's not the best advice.
The best advice is try to find the thing
that you love to do because if you can
do that,
then you never have that feeling that
most people have when it comes to work.
Most people have that feeling like,
oh,
I've got to go to work.
Right?
You never had that.
Never.
But that's also,
I think,
uh,
there's some luck involved in that for
sure.
There's also decisions you make if you
don't have that luck to try to make that
luck happen.
Yeah.
You know,
and then there's also,
talent is also like,
some people want to be a comedian and
they really would never will be.
You just can't.
I think being self aware of what you
really,
really want to do as the person,
not thinking of it even in terms of
work,
just but being looking at yourself
enough to know what you're good at and
what you enjoy,
right,
and then follow that path.
Whether it makes business sense or not,
that's the best thing you can do.
You don't know where it's going to leave
it.
At least you're heading in the direction
where it's stuff you like and it's stuff
you know you have an aptitude for,
so wherever you end up in that area will
be pretty close to happiness.
You know,
words of wisdom from Tom,
Papa,
author,
your dad stole my rake available.
Now,
is it an audio version?
There's an audio version too.
Did you use your voice?
Nine hours,
nine hours in a big God.
You did though.
Reading my book some for.
I read a lot of books on tape or I have
a lot of books written read.
To me,
the real problem is when you know that
it's not the author and you hear someone
have some sort of bullshit halfass
connection to the words they're saying,
now I know I'm good.
That's why it was hard to do actually
because it's nine hours of reading me.
I've got to read a whole book,
but also I have to be me behind it.
I got I wanna you know,
they don't want me doing a phone
inversion.
How many hours at a time did you do
these sessions?
Broken into two,
so like four and a half each day.
It's hard.
It's hard to do,
to stay on point for that long.
It was a thing like when you get out of
there,
but also,
you know when you go in those booths,
like even in this show,
like times different here,
it's different here than three hours.
Somewhere else.
Three hours is up.
We did three hours.
See?
See,
there you go.
Crazy.
Exactly.
It's different.
You.
There's something going on with the
timing.
You're engaged.
It's not like three hours out in the
world,
you know timewarp.
Yeah.
It's a total time warp.
It's whenever,
whenever I say I'm doing this show is
people who he us like three hours.
I'm like,
that's not a thing it's doing with you
and I,
you just doing the show.
Believe me.
It's a thing with some people.
Some people you just squeezing blood out
of.
You know?
I could do this for four hours.
Easy,
easy,
easy to show your beautiful man.
You too,
man.
I'm sure your book's hilarious.
Although I haven't read it.
It's a great father's Day gift for you.
I'm giving it to you.
Thank you.
Because you don't get gifts from your
family time,
Papa,
ladies and gentlemen.
Sale.
We did it.