I could keep it in check for three,
two,
and we're live.
First of all,
Steve,
thank you very much for doing this.
I really appreciate it.
Oh,
thank you for having me.
I've been a big fan of your work for a
long time and um,
you,
you bring up some really fascinating
subjects and we were talking right
before the podcast about social media
and how weird it is that you got lumped
in with the outright for a comment
saying something along the lines of that
you find what was the exact quote
something along the highly intelligent
people seem to,
which is not saying they're good people.
No,
that's right.
And I think a lot of people who are
ignorant to the outright equate them
with a,
uh,
the skinheads and the Neo Nazis carrying
the Tiki torches.
But when I was referring strictly to the
outright from its origin in internet
discussion groups and I,
you know,
I,
I know some of them,
some of them are former students and
some of them are highly intelligent and
highly read.
So,
uh,
but,
but that's not what people often think
of when they think of the alt right.
And that's what I was referring to.
I certainly,
there are people in tech,
there's some people in universities is
stay under cover.
And uh,
I was,
uh,
made some remarks on how to starve that
movement,
not how to feed it,
but
so many people jumped on it as if you
were endorsing the alt right.
It was the exact quote you were just
basically saying something along the
lines of there's a lot of intelligent
people that are involved in this.
Well,
it wasn't so much that it was also that
because of the,
uh,
the various taboos in mainstream
intellectual culture because of
political correctness,
there's certain things that are just
kind of not discussable,
but then when people in the outright
discover them,
they feel tremendously empowered.
Like we are now privy to the truth that
the establishment can't handle.
You can't handle the truth.
And since it was never discussed in the
open,
there are no counterarguments to some of
the most toxic interpretations.
And so the outright can run with the
never having been in a forum where these
things that are debated and criticized
and put it into context,
they take like one fact and then they
draw the most extreme conclusions.
If these things were debated in the
first place,
then you'd realize that those
conclusions are not warranted.
Oh,
it's.
I mean an example is there are average
differences between men and women and a
lot of psychological traits now if
that's.
And that's often quite taboo in
intellectual circles for I think bizarre
reasons.
So I had to get people who think that
somehow women's rights depend on men and
women being indistinguishable.
I think it's a bad equation in the first
place,
but as soon as you come across the fact
that men and women on average are,
are different.
You also come across the fact that men
and women overlap in a lot of these
traits that whatever trait you name,
that men on average are better at that
women or vice versa.
There are a lot of women who are better
than a lot of men or vice versa,
and so you can't really judge an
individual from the average of,
uh,
their,
their sex.
Also,
even though there are some traits where
men score a little better than women,
there some traits were women score a
little better than men and that that's
the complete picture.
But the thing is that if the entire
subject is out of bounds,
you never get to present the complete
picture.
And some people run away with all men
and women are totally different.
What are your thoughts on how the
subject got out of bounds?
Because it's very confusing to me that
certain subjects like the differences
between genders are so taboo when they
seem so obvious.
I mean,
you just could go to a mall and just
look at the way the men dress and the
women dress and you go,
well,
there's some obvious distinctions here.
There's a history to it because there
were,
there were a lot of khaki,
maybe theories and the 19th century,
and in a lot of the 20th century that
men were intellectual and women were not
in.
Women were governed by their emotions
and their women thought too much.
It would take blood away from their
ovaries and their womb and they wouldn't
be fertile and then they'd be all
miserable.
I mean really like crazy stuff.
And as a reaction to that,
in the seventies when the second wave of
feminism became prominent,
it became almost an article of faith
that there were no differences between
men and women.
Uh,
and so if you say that there are
differences between men and women,
you're sending women back to the,
to the kitchen in the nursery.
So this is a total non sequitur because
fairness is not the same as sameness.
So obviously women should have equal
rights to men,
whether or not they're exact copies of
men or have a distinctive profile as men
have a distinct profile.
So I think it's just a mistake to,
uh,
to conflate the issue of women's rights
with men and women being identical,
but that's the way it kind of shook out
and it became kind of an article of
faith in a,
in a lot of,
in some feminist,
some kind of left liberal circles that
men and women have to be identical.
And if they aren't,
that means you're a trader you to,
to a women's equality.
Yeah.
And the articles of faith are always
dangerous.
Dangerous,
especially in that regard.
It's articles of fairness are always
important.
I mean,
fair being fair to each other and being
fair is also recognizing differences.
That's right.
And not assuming that any differences a
deficiency,
if you're really doing an honest
comparison of the differences between
men and women,
men wouldn't come out looking so good.
Right?
No.
Yeah.
I have a whole bit about that in my act
when we're looking at the reaction to
this though.
What was strange to me was how many
people seemed like they wanted to jump
on board and criticize you.
And I think a lot of it is almost like
to take away some of the potential
criticism of themselves,
like it's instant claiming of the moral
high ground virtue signaling and it's
just very disappointing when you see
this from intellectuals and college
professors and it should know better.
I
mean,
to be fair,
I did not get into much trouble from,
from,
you know,
my peers and among the professors and
Grad students and so on.
There are a couple of trolls who,
uh,
who,
who ran with it,
but by and large,
the mainstream reaction was,
this is almost a sign of a,
as a New York Times put it,
that social is made
stupid.
Yeah.
That was the article,
the name of the title of the article and
the time.
Yeah.
So it was by and large,
uh,
you know,
I came out of it.
Okay.
But it was a real indication of how
these mobs of outrage can corrupt any
kind of intelligence
discourse.
Yeah.
Well,
subtle discussions,
the discussions that involve nuanced,
complicated issues that are there.
They're complex.
They require a long dis sort of
description of the issue.
And I'll,
I'll a very complex sort of take on
these various differences between men
and women and the alt right and the left
and political director.
These are,
these are long discussions.
I mean these aren't something that you
can smash into a very short sound
soundbite and completely cover your take
on things
hold the more reason that they shouldn't
be taboo because if you can't discuss
them then the only interpretation you're
going to have as the simplistic one.
If you could bring them out in the open,
then you can start to have that
discussion.
Yeah.
I'm hoping that this is turning around.
I'm hoping that what's happened is the
outrage culture,
the outrage culture has become almost a
parody of itself has gotten so
ridiculous that people will sort of shy
away from outrage seemingly like the
same reason why people are terrified of
talking about the differences between
men and women is because they don't want
to be grouped into the people that
literally are legitimately rather were
sexist in the,
the,
you know,
the 19 hundreds and the 18 hundreds.
And these people that did have these
terrible ideas.
So now we're trying to go so far away
from that that we've become a little bit
ridiculous and I'm hoping things,
I'm hoping it's a swing and they'll just
kind of bounce back towards the middle
again.
Yeah.
And in fact,
there is some hope that that would.
Eddie medium is new,
there'll be these excesses and it takes
awhile for the system to kind of re re
equilibrate to have an immune response
that damps down the worst of it.
I mean,
I've been on the Internet a long time
and in the eighties when it was mainly
academics and computer scientists who
are on the Internet,
there are these discussion groups.
This was before the worldwide web,
so it was all text and there's this
concept of,
of flaming.
Yeah.
I don't know if the word is all days.
Well,
it came from the,
uh,
there was an award given a jokey award
called it the flaming asshole award.
Oh really?
And the,
the,
uh,
to the,
the,
the worst insult or in these
intellectual discussions.
And the,
the uh,
uh,
the,
the trophy was supposedly his bestest
cork,
but from the flaming asshole award there
was the,
the,
the flame,
the adjective flame wars,
the verb to flame dam down.
As people became aware of flaming as a
phenomenon in the discussion groups,
it was,
well,
let's not turn this into a flame war or
in flames.
And when people realized that this was a
thing,
then they could push back against it.
And let's hope that that happens with
this social media again.
Yeah,
I hope so.
It was a sport in like the late
nineties,
early two thousands.
It was essentially like an online
support.
Like someone would say something about
you and you'd go,
Oh crap.
And how do I attack this?
And it was,
it was more fun than anything.
And I felt like there was very few
people relatively speaking,
involved in discussion groups back then
in terms of like the mass amount of
people that are on social media now.
It's certainly like everyone is in some
form of,
or most people are in some form of
social media now.
Whereas back then,
the number of people that were on
message boards was so small.
Yeah.
So smell.
That's right.
And you're right there.
There is an art form of ritual insults
in Shakespeare and you know,
African American snapping a there when
people realize that this is a sport that
no one gets hurt.
It's just like,
you know,
right.
It's like martial arts,
it's part of the fun.
But the thing is that when it goes out
of control and it really does attack
people's reputations and then you've got
a problem.
We have a thing in comedy called roast
battle.
Yeah.
Roasting another example.
Yeah,
absolutely.
And Roast battle is this,
uh,
this great show that they do at the
comedy store.
Every Tuesday we're,
comedians will prepare insults against
each other.
But my friend Brian Moses who hosts it
at the end of everything,
they always hug it out,
right?
Like,
it's always like,
no,
this is a joke,
writing exercise and a fun joke writing
show and no one really,
no one means any of this and not really
mean.
It hugs me,
just like a,
like a professional boxing or ultimate
fighting yourself.
So whatever you can,
there are rules,
there's an arena and when you're done,
it's over.
You don't plot revenge,
but sometimes people can misunderstand
it.
There's that famous press roast where a
Obama had some fun at the expense of
Donald trump when he was still just a a,
a reality show and you could see
famously the camera zoomed in on trump
and he was not abused at jokes,
at his expense.
And there's,
there's a theory that one of the reasons
that he plotted his presidential run was
to,
was to get revenge.
Well,
that's one of the things that Obama said
during that roast,
and here's one of the things that I am
that you'll never be president of the
United States and crazy and cheered on
history.
We could have turned out very
differently if he hadn't made that one
joke.
It's amazing,
isn't it?
Well,
yeah.
Apparently he had been thinking about
being president for a long,
long time,
but that might,
might have been the straw that broke the
camel's back.
So Barack,
what have you done when you see social
media today,
like as a psychologist and you see this
thing that people do when they can
behave anonymously in the absence of
social cues,
not in front of each other,
not,
not seeing that.
How the cruel things hurt each other.
How does that make you do?
Do you think that this is just an
unnatural
way of communicating?
Well,
there is something.
The anonymity is certainly a natural and
relaxed face to face contact.
And I think one of the big discoveries
of psychology from over the last couple
of decades is that we're moral animals
to the extent that we have reputations.
Uh,
going,
going back to Richard Dawkins,
his famous book,
the selfish gene where he posed the
question,
how could niceness in generosity and
cooperation evolve given that in
Darwinian competition you'd expect the
most aggressive,
the most selfish to predominate.
And there's an answer to that question
in Docklands,
worked it out back in 1976 based on work
of other biologists,
which is,
if there is reciprocity,
that is,
if I,
I remember the nice things that you did
to me and I feel compelled to,
uh,
to,
to repay them.
And conversely,
if you do something that harms me and I
threatened revenge,
then people can kind of settle into
cooperation because we really are better
off if we extend favorites to each other
that,
uh,
do a lot of good to the other in
response to a fairly minor inconvenience
to the self.
If everyone does that,
everyone is better off.
And that's only stable though if
everyone has a memory for what everyone
else did.
Therefore that sets up a pressure to
cultivate your reputation as someone who
is trustworthy and will reciprocate at,
but without the reputation,
without the memory of who did what.
And uh,
and how generous and trustworthy someone
is.
The whole thing can unravel when you get
back to what people think of as
Darwinian competition.
Namely nature,
red in tooth and claw.
Just a bloody battle.
So reputation is really,
it's not just a matter of kind of ego or
burnishing your credentials,
that's really what makes all
cooperation,
niceness kindness a possible.
And so when you have an arena in which
the,
uh,
first of all you don't have face to face
contact so you don't have the kind of
evolved responses that we have to,
to getting along a namely it's a,
it's a big deal to a insult someone to
their,
their face.
Some people do it,
but,
uh,
you got to do it very carefully.
You take that away and it just,
you know,
typing a bunch of characters at a
keyboard and especially if the person
doing the typing has a handle,
they just anonymous then that kind of
eliminate some of the constraints on
civility and generosity and then
maintaining a reputation as a credible
cooperator.
I also feel that there's a,
there's a selfishness and being nice and
being generous because,
uh,
the way I describe what I think it feels
good,
it feels good to be nice,
to be bold.
It feels good to be generous when you
give someone a nice tip at a restaurant
and they get happy,
like that feels good.
Like it's good for you too.
It's not just a one way street.
What
kind of a benign selfishness?
Yeah,
it's the kind that is,
although it's not,
uh,
the,
the irony is said it can't just really
be calculated if it's really that I just
do exactly as much.
That gets me gratitude and recognition.
Then,
you know,
other people see through that.
And so the,
I,
the,
the paradox is that it's kind of got to
be sincere for it to be credible to
someone else for the most effective way
to prove to someone else that you're a
nice guy is to actually be a nice guy
because if you're just calculating,
if you're just doing the bare minimum,
you can get away with.
Then since we're,
we're pretty good.
We're all pretty good.
Intuitive psychologists were always kind
of thing.
Did he really mean it?
Is he just kind of kissing up?
Is he trying to get,
you know,
curry favors and we see through that.
That's the person who actually isn't
doing that calculation,
but we really admire and respect.
Right?
And it's very unusual.
It's one of the reasons why we admire,
like look at this completely altruistic
person.
Like,
I mean,
it's clearly remarket the marketplace,
have reputations,
kind of selects,
can select for true niceness.
Goodness.
Yeah.
You've got enough information and enough
interactions.
I mean,
here's a crude analogy.
Um,
so in the business world,
uh,
you know,
you can have cutthroat fly by night
businesses.
They just try to squeeze everything out
of the customers and then take off the
students.
The cheating is discovered,
you know,
they don't last very long.
They don't actually make a lot of money.
It's often the companies that will take
back the product,
no questions asked,
even if they lose a little bit of money,
but they earned the loyalty of their
customers.
Those are the companies that often do
the best and stick around the longest.
It's kind of an analogy to the way that
being honorable,
even if you have little losses.
Well,
I did a little bit more for him than he
did for me,
but over the long run,
that's what makes you desirable as
someone who other people want to hang
out with.
If the reputations can spread.
Yeah.
It's kind of amazing.
If you think about how cherished true
generosity and kindness out cherished
they are,
like it's a,
it's an amazing thing.
Like you see people that are truly kind
and truly generous and we've,
we value that so much.
It's kind of amazing.
There aren't more of them because it's
such a virtue that we admire and you,
you,
if someone does behave in that manner,
like people gravitate towards them.
It's like it's a real trait that is
attractive to people.
It is.
And there's a,
you know,
there's a misunderstanding of the
evolutionary explanation of the,
uh,
of appearance,
of altruism and generosity.
I had a misunderstanding of,
of,
uh,
the message that Dawkins conveyed in
that book that it predicts that we're
all just kind of calculating a favorite
traders that we do just enough to,
uh,
get a favor in return.
And if we don't think someone could help
us in return,
then we just cut them off.
Kind of a cynical view of generosity.
But it's actually the reason that that's
not true is that as soon as the game
begins,
uh,
you kind of get to higher and higher
levels of eat.
People psyching each other out,
seeing through them because it's,
if I have a choice between who I'm going
to hang out with,
who's calling to be friend,
there's one person who's going to do
exactly for what,
for me,
what will help him in the long run.
There's someone else who's really is
generous and he's really going to help
me.
And he said he's not going to keep a
long memory of who did what for whom.
Well,
I'm going to pick the second guy and so
he's going to actually be better off for
being the better person.
Now that you can take that to an extreme
and it means that we're all infinitely
generous,
which of course we're not a.
and so there's kind of a tradeoff in
equilibrium between,
you know,
not being a total sucker or not giving
so much away that you just harm yourself
in the long run and being the kind of
person who is generous and honest enough
that other people want to affiliate with
them.
And the reality is that all of us are
probably mixtures.
I mean,
we're not cutthroat sociopath's.
Most of us have,
some of us are a nora.
We are totally a sane self sacrificing
saints.
We're somewhere in between and different
people are at different points in that
continuum.
When you look at social media and you
look at this,
uh,
this,
the,
the nastiness that's so common,
um,
and obviously in some ways it's got to
be connected to the ability to be
anonymous.
But I feel like I've thought of this
more and more lately that this
negativity is as probably a temporary
thing.
I feel like people are realizing that
this isn't an unnatural way of
communicating and that it's so relative,
really relatively recent in human
history and such a small window.
I mean 19,
94 is essentially when people started
getting online and here we are in 2018
and you're seeing people switching to
flip phones,
deleting their facebook.
It's a very common thing and almost a
chic thing to do,
like people were talking about it on a
regular basis.
All Man.
I.
Yeah,
I just get email.
I check it once a day and that's it.
Yeah.
No,
I think that's right.
We're there.
Whenever there's a new technological
innovation,
it takes society awhile to adjust to it
and say people got online in 1994 with
social media or even more recent than
that.
It's more probably like smartphones
started to become ubiquitous around
maybe 2011 and facebook took off in the
two thousands,
but yeah,
I think that's right and similar things
happened in when other media were
introduced.
There was a big panic when television
came in that families would never talk
to each other,
they'd all be staring at the screen like
zombies and you'd never have a
conversation over the dinner table ever
again.
Even before that,
when telephones were invented,
it was,
you know,
families who'd never a sit down together
because the phone constantly be ringing
in attention spans would be disrupted
because the phone could ring anytime.
Was there similar conversation about
books?
Actually there was,
yeah.
And about writing,
going back to the ancient Greeks,
uh,
who were,
when,
when writing was considered to be kind
of um,
uh,
you know,
degenerate and decadent because you
know,
you,
you'd let your memory go to pot to know
how are people to cultivate their
memory.
They could just write things down and
look at them.
That's crazy.
Is that interesting?
Why do you think we were always looking
to dismiss some new fantastic
technology?
It's partly because we don't understand
it yet.
I mean it's new and also a lot of the
adjustments that you were just talking
about,
you know,
you can't really predict them
beforehand.
A lot of what happens in a society is
there like hundreds of little
adjustments that people make.
Not Spend too much time on facebook or
email and leave this platform for that
platform where if you were starting from
scratch and asked to kind of imagine how
it's going to play out,
you can't really anticipate these
things.
Uh,
it's like thousands of adjustments that
people make.
They happen when they happen with
billions of people making decisions.
Uh,
but you,
you can't just deduce them beforehand,
like a logical proof.
And so we just don't know.
We know what the threat is.
We don't know what society's
responsibility.
Maybe whether this a fascinating time
when it comes to social media and just
human interaction because this is so
new.
And because it's uncharted territory.
I mean,
I think this is one of the reasons why
so many people have so many concerns
about it.
They're like,
where's this?
Where's this going?
What's it gonna do to our children?
We walked down the street and everyone's
just staring at their phone.
Really is I,
I've said this,
that imagine if there was a drug that
came along that this drug made you only
think about the drug.
You were,
uh,
you were likely more likely to get into
car accidents because this drug,
you're more likely to sleep late,
cause more anxiety and,
and soak up immense amounts of your time
with very little reward for it.
You would go,
wow.
What kind of crazy drugs this,
it's robbing people of their lives.
Well,
that's cell phones,
that's social media.
I mean it does give you something.
I mean if you use it correctly.
Most of the time I try to spend on
social media.
I try to spend or most of the time on,
on my phone I try to spend off social
media,
but reading things like tried to read
articles and I try to,
I try to in some way justify like,
oh,
I'm doing something productive on my
phone.
But a lot of ways I'm just addicted to
checking that thing.
Yeah,
you got,
you have to develop habits of self
control and balancing life.
I had a student,
so I teach at Harvard and what time of
freshmen came into my office beginning
of the semester,
so she looked at the shelf of books that
she really said,
wow,
professor pinker,
how do you find time to write so many
books,
and then she looks at my office and sees
all the books on my shelves.
Wow.
Professor Pinker,
how do you have time to read so many
books?
And she paused for a second.
He said,
I bet you're not on facebook,
but this got to be some good that comes
out of those communities as well
throughout the baby with the bathwater,
undoubtedly.
Yeah,
absolutely.
And you know,
I confess I'm on twitter.
I sometimes look at my twitter feed and
I learned really interesting stuff from
it,
but I also say,
okay,
enough,
get back to work,
get back to reading,
go outside.
See some friends,
spent some time with,
with uh,
with your family.
Yeah.
I will go down twitter hall.
I went down to twitter whole yesterday
about these Mont New Mayan Ruins that
they found in Guatemala who amazing,
crazy thousands of structures swallowed
up by time.
And they're just now realizing like,
oh my God,
this was a city.
So that stuff's good.
Yeah,
no,
absolutely man.
It's a question of are all finding the
balance between getting the advantages
or disadvantages?
Well,
it's just so new.
Yeah.
When,
when you see all so much negativity
though,
and this is a big problem with anonymous
accounts in particular,
you see it in facebook,
in facebook,
there seems to be repercussions.
Like if you're Tom Smith and Tom Smith
writes something horrible,
like Tom Smith could get fired from his
job for it.
We've seen that people will write
something racist or sexist or whatever
and we'll see them get fired from their
job because of something that they put
on facebook.
Because your profile represents the
actual you.
It's not anonymous.
Yes.
I feel like there's benefit to that.
Yeah,
that's right.
There's some.
I mean the problem is that can also be
outraged.
Bob's where someone will post something
and it's taken out of context and made
me realize what they've entered as a
joke.
Like the woman who went to,
took that trip to Africa Qa,
kind of a self effacing comment about
racism and people thought it was racist,
but she was actually making fun of
races.
I think she was drunk and she was being
racist.
I just thought she was being funny
because Kummete look,
I'm a comic and I have a lot of comedian
friends that are not racist,
but they will say hilarious racist
things.
Right.
Because it's funny.
It's not because they're racist,
but.
What was her name?
Justine Sacco.
Thank you.
This was the uh,
I hope I don't get aids,
but a lol.
That's what she wrote.
She woke up 12 hours later after a Xanex
and wine hangover,
I'm sure.
And her life was a living hell.
Yeah.
I mean,
and she still to this day is,
I mean Jamie knows her name is not
racist.
It ironically she meant it.
She herself was not racist and she
become controversial after that as well.
She was like the PR person for
draftkings or fanduel or stuff when they
were going through some issues a couple
of years ago.
Draft kings is an online gambling thing.
It's kind of controversial.
Gambling on sports and stuff like that.
Yeah.
I just,
we look for people to also,
we were talking about this before
without getting into details about who
we're talking about,
but there are certain people that are
very flawed individuals that looked to
find people and attack them to take away
some of the spotlight on their own
flaws.
Absolutely.
This is a thing.
This is a big part of virtue signaling,
right?
Like a big part of,
uh,
going after people and outrage mobs,
as long as the mob is attacking someone
else,
they're not attacking you.
That's right.
Yeah,
that's right.
And there is,
I mean,
it is a interesting question over a
history is how do,
how do some of these things called
extraordinarily extraordinary popular
delusions and the madness
of crowds to Tulip Bulb Mania in Holland
in the 17th century.
It's that,
oh,
there's a,
this,
this kind of bubble where people started
to outbid each other on tulip bulbs and
the,
you know,
the price of a single tulip bulb went
like through the roof and then it's
suddenly crashed.
People lost fortunes because everyone
was expecting everyone else to keep
bidding up the price,
but there,
oh yeah,
the tulip bulbs,
Tulip Bulb mania,
nutty,
but then they're also witch hunts where
when a woman would be accused of sinking
a ship or causing a crop failure or
making someone's child gets sick,
they're the pogroms in Europe where Jews
were accused of poisoning the wells are
killing Christian voice to make
Mozzarella their blood.
Where the lynchings in the,
uh,
American south where African Americans
were accused of raping a woman and I are
based on just a rumor spreading and
they'd be tortured and hanged.
There's the McCarthy era.
There were,
uh,
there's the,
the,
the daycare,
satanic ritual abuse.
Amenia of the 19 eighties were these
daycare workers were accused basically
by coaching kids to embellish these
fantastic stories of how they were
sexually molested and tortured and
forced to take part in satanic rituals
mean all totally nonsense.
And people went to jail.
So initially the question is how do
people kind of lose their collective
minds in every once in awhile in
history?
And a part of the answer is if you start
a,
a kind of vicious circle of denouncing
people and then denouncing people who
don't denounce people denouncing people
who call the whistle on a and other
people denouncing people,
then you can get a kind of circle of
terror where no one wants.
Everyone is so afraid of being denounced
that they wanted to announce first
Stalinist Soviet Union as another
example at Mao's,
China.
And that's somehow some,
one of the ways in which dictators could
often,
uh,
enforce their power by turning the
citizens against each other.
So everyone's denouncing everyone else
out of fear that they'll be announced
first that's going on right now in North
Korea,
right?
Absolutely.
Yeah.
North Korea,
they have this thing where they each
have to report on each other.
Like when people are together,
they report on each other for different
things that they did that were
violations of whatever code that they
follow.
Absolutely.
And so governments know how to explain
it,
but it isn't just governments that can
happen spontaneously too.
It's a weird human trait,
isn't it?
It is.
It's a combination of a kind of a human
trait and a kind of dynamic when you
have a kind of a network of people,
uh,
and,
and they all are kind of trapped and no
one can be the first person to escape
from this vicious circle because they
don't want to be the one who is
denounced it,
imprisoned and tortured or whatever.
The consequences may be a,
what do you think?
Where do you think,
if you think at all about this,
where do you think this is all headed?
Like it,
especially
in terms of social media and.
Yes,
it's hard to tell,
but I,
you,
you mentioned the possibility that
there's been such a growing recognition
of the problem that we will mount a
response that it'll just seem ridiculous
of the outrage mob once it's recognized
that there are outraged mobs and virtual
signaling fanatics.
Once we have a label for them.
Once we know that it's a thing,
a,
it'll seem so ridiculous that people
will be less tempted to do it.
I mean,
that's the optimistic of a outcome.
Well,
there's just such a flaw in there.
There's a real issue in writing things
and one of the issues,
especially if you're writing about a
subject where there's a lot of people
involved or perhaps an even an
individual,
is that you're the only one that's
writing.
Like if you were having a conversation
with that person,
they would be able to say something
back.
You'd be able to say something and they
will go,
well that's not exactly how I was
thinking.
Actually.
I was looking at it this way and the
other person would go,
oh,
okay,
so your take on it was,
you know,
and they would go back and forth and
exchange information.
Hopefully come to some sort of an
understanding of what's going on in each
person's mind.
Absolutely.
Whereas you can define someone in a
tweet or a facebook post or a blog post.
You can define someone without them
having any ability to respond in the
moment.
So you have this whole uninterrupted
chunk where you could talk about,
you know,
fill in the blank,
some celebrity or some politician or
whatever and you can define them and
some really horrible,
nasty way and they just have to sit
there and read it.
Like it is just your thoughts.
But that's not an accurate method of
communicating ideas with a person.
It's just your one uninterrupted take on
things.
Absolutely.
So I,
my,
my second to last book,
the one just before my current book
enlightenment now,
but the previous book was called the
sense of style.
It was a writing manual way began.
Began.
It is.
I said,
why is so much writing so bad?
How come there's so much writing where
you just can't understand what the
person is talking about.
And I mentioned some theories.
Some people think that it's academics
and intellectuals trying to show off how
profound they are.
My how incomprehensible they are.
Like if people could understand it,
it can't be that complicated.
So I ended up right.
The stuff that no one will understand
that nothing.
I'm really smart.
So that's one theory and you know,
there might be some truth to it,
but I think that the main theory is that
that writing is,
as you just as you described it,
it's a one way channel of communication.
It's very unnatural.
You know,
when we speak,
you and I were having a conversation,
we're looking at each other in the eye
and our eyebrows go up and they get
needed and if I say,
if I start to become too obscure,
you're going to give me a quizzical
look.
Terrified expression on their face where
you can interact and say,
well,
what the hell was that?
When you're writing,
you have none of that.
And so I think part of the skill in
writing what I least,
what I argue in the of style is to
become a kind of enough of an intuitive
psychologists that you can try to
anticipate what your reader knows and
what your reader doesn't know and that
because you have no way of determining
that as you're writing because you're
just sitting there tapping away whoever
was going to read what you write there.
You never get to meet them.
It might be,
you know,
three years from now they might be
halfway across the world and it's just
one way and so,
and there's another kind of
psychological problem that we all have.
It's just part of being human called the
curse of knowledge.
Namely when you know something,
it's really,
really hard to imagine what it's like
not to know it.
You just assume that everyone knows it,
the,
your,
your understanding is everyone's
understanding and so you right away,
you know,
write.
Right,
right,
right.
And it never occurs to you that the
reader doesn't know your abbreviations
or your jargon or can't visualize what
you're describing.
It's so clear to you,
the writer and a lot of bad writing
comes from the curse of knowledge that
is a writer not getting into the heads
of his reader and a lot of the cure is
either to at least at least know that
it's a problem and think of what can I
read it would be reasonably expected to
know because we're not even that good at
that.
I mean,
none of us remind readers,
just showing someone a draft of what
you've written and you're often
surprised at how often they'll say,
I don't know what you're talking about.
Maybe that's what we should force people
to do at twitter.
Maybe we should have like a team of
people that you send your tweet to a
circle of confidence.
Well,
that,
I mean,
that's the way it works in publishing.
You know,
you got,
you have an editor in academia,
you got peer review before it's
published.
They send it out to other people just
like you and they,
they,
they write a little review and you've
got to modify it if it doesn't make any
sense.
Right?
So Justine Sacco had sent that to a team
of confidence they would went.
No,
don't write that.
I'm sorry,
I'm on a plane.
I'm drunk.
I'll call you from Africa.
Well,
this is,
you know,
what are the big themes in my new book
enlightenment now is,
um,
how is it that we're simultaneously in
many ways getting smarter but also seem
to be getting stupider society.
So I think part of it is that none of us
is individually are that smart.
Uh,
we all and,
and cognitive psychologists have shown
that humans have all kinds of biases and
fallacies.
We,
um,
we,
we rezoned from stereotypes.
We assess risk by how easy it is to
imagine something.
Uh,
so,
you know,
we're afraid of getting on a plane
because it's very easy to imagine a
plane crashing and plane crashes,
make the news.
We don't worry about texting while
driving because there's never a headline
on page one of the hundred people who
died in the past week because they
texted while driving a certainly a lot
of fallacies.
So,
but the thing is,
we,
as a species,
they've done some amazing things.
I mean,
we discovered those Mayan,
a buried city.
So,
you know,
science is amazing and because
democracies are amazing and it's because
none of us solves a problem all by
ourselves.
We're part of our kind of collective
brain that works by rules where all of
the excesses of one person get kind of
balanced out by,
uh,
by other people.
And that's why you have a,
you know,
things like a checks and balances in a
democracy where instead of having a
supreme leader who just runs the country
the way he wants,
he's got a worry about the legislature
and the courts and the judges and you
know,
and in an impeachment and so on,
in science,
instead of having one genius announcing
the way the world works,
you know,
he or she has to subject themselves to
peer review and get,
let other sciences criticize.
Scientists,
criticize him or her.
And,
uh,
whenever you get people acting
intelligently,
it's often because they belong to these
institutions with rules that are
designed to make up for the idiocies of
any individual person.
Hmm.
That's fascinating.
Um,
I,
I completely agree with that.
That makes so much sense.
I've also felt that there,
there's not a lot,
there's not,
we have difficulties.
Obviously people have difficulties in
this life,
their social difficulties,
economic difficulties,
but when,
in terms of survival difficulties,
it's,
it's way easier to get by today than it
has ever been in human history.
And I wonder if human beings have a need
for adversity and complexity and problem
solving and all these things that are
less.
They're less present today than ever
before.
I think things are just almost too
simple.
We've made it to ease.
We've nerf the world and in doing so,
it's easier to just kind of be double
minded and drift through and follow the
herd.
The herd is so big and there's so many
people in the herd.
If you just do what most people are
doing,
where what most of the people are
wearing,
say the things.
Most of the people say you'll survive
and you'll survive and you'll find some
other dimwitted person to breed with and
you'll make dimwitted children.
And I'm being dead serious.
I think there's a certain,
when you're dealing with this massive
pack of humans,
300 plus million on a continent,
there's just.
There's so much.
I've always said like if you have a
group of people,
if you're being very generous and you
have 100 people in a room,
what are the odds that one of those
people is a moron?
It's a hundred percent.
That one is going to be a moron.
That leaves you with $3 million morons
in the United States of America if
you're being really kind and 3 million
geniuses.
Yes.
Yeah.
Well,
probably I.
I'm an optimist.
I would like to thank you.
Dealing with probably 6 million genius.
Okay.
Well,
my book is often described as a book on
optimism enlightenment now because I
have 75 graphs,
almost all of it showed the world
getting better,
including what some people think of the
most incredible.
A graph in the book on a phenomenon
called the flynn effect,
which is that,
believe it or not,
and I know most people do not.
Iq scores have been rising for most of
the last hundred years,
but three points a decade.
Now this I know,
it seems totally unbelievable,
but yeah,
they discovered it with Flynn.
A philosopher discovered it when he
realized that the people who make Iq
tests had to keep re norming the tests
to keep a 100 as the average because the
average kept creeping up and it was like
110 where we keep that.
That's what most people score.
We say that the average is 100.
We got to adjust the scale downward and
flint realized,
Hey,
wait a second,
they keep doing this over and over
again.
That must mean the population's getting
smarter now,
not biologically smarter.
It's not that people's brainpower has
somehow magically been increasing,
although probably a little bit of that
through better nutrition,
better sanitation and health care and so
on.
But a lot of it is just that,
a lot that ideas that used to be kind of
sophisticated and restricted to
professors and scientists and
statisticians kind of trickle down to
the population.
And so we things like,
um,
a placebo effect or trade off or cost
benefit analysis or win win situation,
all these things that actually came from
pretty fancy schmancy theory originally,
but they kind of are loose stone the
whole population and they become part of
everyone's conventional wisdom.
Also.
We have to think more and more in
abstract ways just to deal with things
like a subway map or a smartphone.
Uh,
watching TV is,
it used to be,
you turn on your TV would be on,
now you got to kind of program that
bloody thing.
So the demands of life have become more
sophisticated and ideas spread more
quickly and so we are quite literally
getting smarter up to a point,
things that can't go on forever,
don't.
And the flynn effect is starting to
level off,
but there has been this,
this,
uh,
this drift upward in intelligence.
I don't think that's surprising at all.
I think if you look at the amount of
information that people are subject to
today and just the sheer raw data,
I mean there's a lot of the data is just
nonsense and twitter and that.
What is the quote that we produce?
More content in two days.
The entire human history every two days.
Something crazy like that.
Is that right?
It sounds,
it sounds plausible,
but most of it is like,
lol,
I just went to the mall,
you know,
this is a lot of nonsense in there.
But the sheer amount of interesting
information,
like those newly discovered Mayan Ruins
in Guatemala and things along those
lines,
or you know,
some,
uh,
there was some interesting new
information on the history of human
beings because they found some new teeth
and some throwback the date of modern
humans and they keep moving that back,
which the point is we're constantly
getting more information and more data,
more things to think about.
And I've just got to assume that the
amount of information that comes to a
person in 2018 is just vastly larger
than the amount that came to them in
1978.
Oh,
absolutely.
And there are as idiotic as a lot of
public debate is today.
There's a lot of idiocy in the past.
Sure.
I mean,
in the,
uh,
you know,
as recently as the 19 sixties is that,
that movie on the first interracial
couple in Virginia where there was a
court,
a judge who said God didn't mean for the
racist intermarry that's why he put
black people in Africa and yellow people
in Asia and white people in Europe.
So the judge,
the judge,
hilarious.
The judge said this in his decision
eventually overturned loving versus
Virginia.
I'm now,
I mean,
no one would make that stupid an
argument today,
even even people that we think of as,
as kind of racist,
they'd be embarrassed and you're just
too stupid and people on the,
on the left made some pretty stupid
arguments as well.
Uh,
when Castro sent all of the gay people
to concentration camps in Cuba,
you had Susan Sontag respected leftwing
intellectual who's saying,
well,
this is,
you know,
you got to forgive them because a Latin
America was such a sexualized culture
and they were prostitutes.
It was decadence that of course it was a
little bit of an overreaction.
Now today,
I don't think anyone on the,
on the left or the right would say it's
okay to send gay people to concentration
camps because they were a lot of
prostitutes in Havana.
But that's the kind of idiotic statement
that we kind of forget that people used
to make in the past too.
So it's way reassuring ourselves.
Whenever we see a debate getting a
seemingly getting stupider and stupider.
You got to remember there's a lot of
stupidity in the past too.
Oh yeah,
a massive amount.
And I think,
I think you're right that the,
you know,
it's hard to tell day by day,
especially when your attention is
concentrated by the worst things that
happen.
And again,
this a big theme of,
of,
of uh,
enlightenment now that your picture of
the world when it's.
Because the human mind really is driven
by anecdotes and images and stories and
that's what the news gives us.
But if you look at trends,
uh,
he follow the trend lines and not the
headlines.
You see that a lot of things really are
getting better,
uh,
gradually.
But that accumulates over time.
And one of the things with the flow of
information,
we are actually getting more.
We meaning Americans,
but also worldwide.
There is this trend of getting more
liberal,
more tolerant,
more progressive,
you know,
hard to tell day by day.
But when you think that in the 19
sixties there was a debate over whether
there should be racial segregation,
whether African Americans should drink
out a different water fountains or stay
in different motels.
There's debate over whether women should
be allowed in the workplace that,
oh,
what's going to happen to all the kids
if they,
uh,
if they're all working,
debate over whether gay people should be
allowed to be teachers.
Uh,
and we've kind of forgotten these
because the progressive
side kind of one and the debate has
moved on and that happens worldwide as
Pete,
as information flows,
as people start to meet each other as
ideas proliferate,
uh,
there is this gradual trend toward more
tolerance even in parts of the world
where it seems to be totally absent.
Like in a lot of the Islamic world,
which world survey show this is the
least progressive part of the world in
terms of attitudes towards women
attitudes towards gays,
attitudes toward child rearing.
But even the Islamic world,
there's been a drift in the liberal
direction.
We just thought two weeks ago when Saudi
Arabia allowed women to drive.
I mean,
it's kind of modest form of progress.
Kind of Hilarious,
hilarious.
But you know,
the progress,
but it.
But it shows,
I mean,
they just could not live in this absurd
situation forever.
The world really did drag them kicking
and screaming out of the Middle Ages in
this,
in this way,
and that kind of tends to happen over
the long run.
Yeah.
I'm,
I'm an optimist and I,
I really do.
Look at all these trends.
You'll,
you'll,
you'll like the book then 75 or 75
optimistic graphs.
Oh,
excellent.
I,
yeah.
I think that if you look at just the
overall human rights,
I mean,
one of the best indications of that is
go and look at media representations of
life from the 19 fifties and sixties.
Watch movies,
especially from the fifties,
and just see how people behave.
I mean it's,
you're,
you're getting sort of a,
a timestamp of human interaction from
1950.
It's obviously an artistic
representation of a time.
Doesn't have that time,
but you get a sense of how people
thought it was okay to behave.
There was a lot of smacking women.
Yeah,
that's right.
Yeah.
Really common in movies,
right?
And children.
You remember the scene where you know,
junior would misbehave and mom would
say,
wait till your father gets home,
and then dad comes home and he pulls the
belt out of his pants so he could use it
as a weapon.
So buckle would really hurt the child
and the child would tie up a,
a pillow on his behind and it'd be stars
and go off into the corner.
Now you'd call social services and they
take the child away or something.
Yeah.
Well,
I mean I think this idea of being
dragged kicking and screaming into this
new age,
I think we're all doing that and I think
you're seeing that in so many different
parts of our culture today.
You know,
I think that's one of the things that's
happening with this meat too.
Movement is it all this mass public
shaming of sexual harassers and sexual
assaults and all this different thing.
It's like forcing human beings to
reassess the way they interact with each
other and like this really radical,
very quick sort of a movement over just
a short period of time.
Is that a giant impact on culture?
Yeah,
and like a lot of social changes,
it,
it happens really quickly,
probably mixes some good things and some
not so good things,
right.
Um,
and it's really good that men no longer
have a license to just expose themselves
or,
or
harass a woman who,
who worked for them and treat them these
crude and ugly waste,
you know,
when there is also a legitimate concern
that,
uh,
you just can't really believe all
accusers.
I mean,
we kind of learned that through history
from,
you know,
witch hunts and lynchings and a pogroms
and there's got to be proportionality.
Not all infractions are,
are the same,
you know,
the punishment should fit the crime.
So we haven't quite settled in how to
balance the very necessary corrective to
two men harassing women with a kind of
rule of law and standards of,
of justice.
I'm
correct me if I'm wrong about this,
but this is one of my theories is,
uh,
we,
our brains,
our capacity and our understanding is
relative to what's necessary at the
time.
And one of the things that I use is
Dunbar's number.
Dunbar's number is this idea that you
could only have these intimate
relationships with 150 or so people or
in terms of intimacy of understanding
who they are,
knowing their name,
knowing things about them,
but as our circle of people that we
interact with grows and expands.
I wonder if that's going to expand as
well.
When you think about the amount of
information that people can hold in
their brain and what people are used to
knowing about this is a radically
different world in 2018 than it was in
1960.
The amount of things that you were aware
of in 1960,
just by virtue of not having social
media,
the internet,
Google,
all the different ways that you could
get information from.
It's just so different.
I mean it's.
I don't know what,
how many times more information you're
getting,
but it must be much more much more and
over an incredibly small period of time.
When you think about the,
you know,
the relative time span that human beings
had been here a few hundred thousand
years or whatever.
I wonder if this is.
I wonder if we're changing and I wonder
what we're going to be like if this
continues to grow and continues to be a
part of our life.
This,
if we're going to adapt our abilities,
well we can't.
We're not going to change the neuro,
biological structure of the brain,
you know,
very much because even though we all
learned through our lives,
there are limits as to what our brain
brain can do.
But what I think happens is there's a
back and forth between our brains and
the technology.
So the technology adjusts to take into
account how the,
how our brains work.
So the,
the,
the restriction of can't know or feel
that,
you know,
more than 100,
150 people in kind of helps define the
set of top,
top,
rank friends in a social network.
Uh,
the fact that we're visual creatures,
you know,
we're,
we're primates.
We get a lot of our,
to our eyeballs.
It's one of the reasons why computer
technology has changed so much since the
eighties and seventies.
Like when I first learned to program a
computer,
it was just all text and a or use a
computer.
I mean they're just 80 characters and
aligned and you had the letters of the
alphabet and that's all there was and it
soon became clear that a,
that's not a very efficient way of
getting ideas into a brain.
It's really laborious and tiring and so
you have graphic user user interfaces.
I mean the apple was the first to
commercialize it,
but it had been developed beforehand at
Xerox,
but it's really exotic at first when you
saw a screen with these windows and
pointers and icons and a mouse and
computers don't work that way.
Naturally you took a huge amount.
Still does.
Takes a huge amount of programming to
get a computer to pretend that there's a
sheet of paper up on the screen,
but that because we're visual creatures,
the technology adapted so that we could
feel comfortable using it.
So some of it is how much do we adjust
to the technology and how much is the
technology forced to adjust to us.
I'm thinking in terms of the actual
capability of the human mind and when
you read about the modern human brains,
like there was an article that was
published recently that was trying to
read a map,
the timeline of the modern human brain
and I think they were pointing to about
35,000
years ago now and see if we can find
that.
Trying to figure out what exactly they
were saying,
but essentially they were saying that
the human,
the modern human brain was far more
recent or interest.
Again,
I'm not surprised.
Yeah.
Well I would have guessed a little bit
older than that,
but yeah,
in the tens of thousands of years.
Yeah.
So with the.
One of the big mysteries,
right is the doubling of the human brain
size over a period of what it was like 2
million years.
This something had happened to cause
that some change in our environment,
some changing our behavior and our what
has been a bigger change in the
internet.
Like what has been a bigger change and
the access to information that people
have today.
And I'm wondering if like we're not
experiencing,
when you're talking about these rises
steady rise of Iq,
obviously it's not just the internet,
it's education,
the cumulative data that people just
keep piling onto and more people learn
more things and people get wiser and you
know,
our,
the way we interface with information is
better than it's ever been before.
But I wonder about the capacity and the
capabilities of the human mind.
If it's happening right now,
it's just a very gradual thing.
This 10 percent tick or 10 point tick
per,
per decade,
if this is going to lead you,
you extrapolate,
you go 100 years from now,
200 years from now,
we.
What are we going to be looking at?
The thing is that what happened over the
last few tens of thousands of years,
it is not going to be replicated anytime
soon because that was driven by
Darwinian natural selection,
which just meant that smarter people had
more surviving babies.
That's a process that as a speed limit
measured in generations,
uh,
and it's,
it may not be that coping in a modern
society makes you have more babies.
And maybe the other way round,
you know,
as you're more educated,
you have fewer children.
Um,
and so I think a lot of the,
uh,
there's going to be a certain amount of
plasticity of what you can master in
your own lifetime,
especially if you start in childhood a,
you're going to,
a lot of these skills become second
nature.
How to look things up,
how to,
uh,
how to use these devices efficiently.
And then that will,
can,
can reach limits that only so many hours
in the day.
And there was only so many neurons in
your brain.
But in conjunction with that,
the technology becomes more human
friendly.
And there are new ways of getting
information into the brain.
You know,
as I mentioned,
we've gone from just lines of characters
to graphic user interfaces and video
and,
and more like creative data graphics
where you see moving colored graphs as a
way of getting a bunch of variables into
a human head more efficiently.
And virtual reality might be the next
step where we bought three d
environments that we can explore.
Uh,
and that may be a way of,
of getting our puny brains to experience
more information.
Yeah.
I was going to bring that up to you next
[inaudible].
That's one of the things that concerns
me the most is how good virtual reality
is now,
but how relatively crude it is in
comparison to the potential.
And have you experienced it at all?
Have you used like an htc vive or any of
those?
No,
I've used more kind of lower tech kinds
of like,
you know,
Google cardboard and uh,
that's Kinda interesting too.
It's still pretty interesting,
but the vibe will freak you out.
There's one of the things,
and I,
I used,
uh,
several years ago,
his version,
I think my friend Duncan trussell had
one,
two or three years ago that I used and I
was blown away by that where you're
underwater and there's a whale swims up
to you and you know,
and it seems so real and it's get
nauseous.
No,
I didn't,
but it was,
it was,
I,
it,
it's obviously fake.
Like I'm looking at it and I can make a
distinction quickly.
Like when you see a movie and in the
movie there's like fake dogs or
something like that or fake monsters.
You're like,
oh,
that's a fake thing.
It's fake,
but it's really good fake and I'm,
I'm.
I can recognize it as a fake,
but I was like,
wow,
what is this going to be like in 10
years?
What is it gonna be like in 30 years
it's going to be and how much better is
the interface going to be?
I'm really concerned that there's going
to be a just a giant section of our
population that completely checks out of
the regular world and lives in some
strange fantasy land.
Most of the time they just consumed food
and water and figure out a way to feed
themselves and spend most of their time
locked into a helmet,
living in some fantastic artificial
environment that people have created.
Yeah.
Well,
although just putting things into
perspective,
there were that,
those fears when television became
popular even before that with movies,
this is the question of what kind of
balance people will,
will find.
I mean,
clearly it's going to be more of exactly
what you describe,
but you know,
people do.
People do like reality to,
uh,
you know,
people,
uh,
in huge numbers go to the national parks
and just seeing a picture book isn't the
same thing.
And people care whether,
you know,
when they buy a work of art,
they care whether it's real or fake.
I,
so there's a lot.
There's one part of the human mind that,
uh,
as much as we're seduced by just sensual
sensory experiences,
we also,
we have a sense of reality and we value
it.
And uh,
you know,
we don't like being fooled too much.
And uh,
uh,
the question is what balance we find
between the desire for authentic
experience and the pleasure of these
cheap artificial ones.
When you chose to write a book about
enlightenment and you chose to write a
book,
the showing all these positive graphs
and all these trends that seem to be
optimistic.
Are you,
I'm writing that obviously you feel this
way and this is the data and this is
your interpretation of where we're
headed.
But are you also kind of like
encouraging people in a way to have a
more rose colored view of the world and
just understand that
not so much rose colored but a bad
description.
I know exactly what you mean,
but have a kind of problem solving
mindset,
namely,
we have solved problems in the past,
or at least we've,
we've reduced them and that I think
emboldens us to say,
look,
the problems we have now and think,
well,
we can handle those two if we decide to
do now what our ancestors did in the
past that led in the right directions.
And I,
I credit this to the,
a mindset of the enlightenment,
namely that with reason and science and
a concern for human welfare,
we can gradually make people better off
and as long as we maintain that kind of
philosophy of,
of,
of living,
uh,
then we,
then there's a reasonable hope that we
can solve the problems facing us.
It doesn't happen by itself.
There's not,
you know,
magic escalator.
There's no,
you know,
uh,
a arc of history or dialectic or any
mystical stuff that just makes us better
and better.
There's a recognizing problems and
figuring out how the world works and
doing our best to solve them.
So that was,
that was the message and the fact that
we have had progress contrary to the
impressions you get from the headlines
shows that this is not a crazy
idealistic,
optimistic pipe dream.
It's happened and some more of it can
happen.
Yeah.
That's where I was going with this is
that why do we have this desire to
concentrate on the negative?
Like I have a friend,
my friend Ian Edwards has this bit about
the news about renaming it to the bad
news and he goes on this whole rant
about the news.
Check this out,
but he's right and it is a thing that
we.
Is it because we have this concern like
we have to recognize danger and we want
to know what's happening so that we know
that we're safe.
But the reality is we're dealing with a
world of 7 billion people with 7 billion
stories.
You know,
so you're,
you're gonna be able to see negative
stuff all day long if you so choose to
do that.
If you so choose to concentrate on
negativity and it gives you this bizarre
portrait of the world that the world is
just this horrible place,
and the bill Hicks used to have a bit
about CNN,
about watching CNN and it'd be death
aids,
pit bulls.
You go outside
Chirp and where's all this shit
happening?
I think there's a lot to that.
That's good.
That's a great,
great examples.
We concentrate.
What is our desire to concentrate only
on the negative or mostly on the
negative?
Well,
there is a phenomenon in psychology
called the negativity bias that bad is
psychologically stronger than good.
So we dragged that.
We dread losses more than we enjoy gains
and criticism hurts much more than
praise makes you feel better.
Uh,
we're our,
uh,
our,
our minds are attracted to possibilities
of,
of death and danger and so on.
I think it's because we are really,
as you say,
we are vulnerable.
There are many more things that could go
wrong then could go right.
And that's kind of a implication of the
law of entropy.
A,
there's a tiny fraction of the way the
world could work that works,
works out well for you in an awful lot
of ways that things can go wrong and so
our minds are attuned to things that
could go wrong and that kind of opens up
a market for experts to remind us of
things that can go wrong,
but we may have forgotten and so the the
news tends to gravitate to the negative
and there are actually studies that show
this.
You give editors a two different
framings of an event and optimistic one
and a pessimistic when they pick the
pessimistic one and that's a trend
that's actually increased.
I have a graph in the book,
one of the 75 graphs that shows a an
automatic analysis of the tone of the
news.
That is how often are there positive
words like improve better?
How often do their negative words like
crisis disaster,
catastrophe.
The news has been getting more and more
negative for about 70 years.
Is it uniform on both sides?
Right,
and left.
A good question.
I don't know the answer.
I suspect it is,
but I don't know.
I don't know the answer for sure.
There were there fluctuations,
there are ups and downs,
but overall the trend has been downward.
So partly it's all,
even though,
by the way,
all the other graphs in the book show
that in reality the world is actually
been getting better.
There are fewer deaths from war.
There's fewer homicides were making some
progress in a pollution.
There's less poverty than there used to
be more education.
Uh,
but the news has been getting more and
more morose.
Part of it is also that there's an,
there is an ethic of journalism that to
be responsible as point out what's going
wrong.
One editor said,
a good good news isn't news.
It's advertising.
And it's also because of the timescale
that it's very easy to destroy something
really quickly.
I mean,
something blows up and uh,
that's news improvements tend to be
gradual day by day and there's never a
Thursday in March in which something
happens that is,
uh,
as,
as Max Roser,
an economist Paul pointed out,
newspapers could run the headline.
One hundred and 38,000
people escaped from extreme poverty
yesterday,
every day for the last 30 years,
but they never ran that headline even
once because there was never a
particular day in which the hundred and
38,000
people were different than 138,000
people the day before.
And so the,
a lot of the good things kind of creep
up on us and they're never reported in
headlines,
whereas it's easy to blow something up
and that,
that does happen on a Thursday.
So you have a,
a very positive view of the future of
humans.
Well,
it's uh,
as,
uh,
the great,
Swedish,
uh,
a dot Ted Takstar,
Hans Rosling put it when he was asked,
are you an optimist?
And he said,
well,
I'm not an optimist.
I'm a very serious possible list.
So what happens in the future?
It depends on what we do now.
And there are real threats and dangers.
Sure,
there's a possibility of nuclear war.
There's a possibility of catastrophic
climate change.
So we can't sit back and say,
well,
things have gotten better.
Let's let them continue.
By sheer inertia or momentum,
that's not gonna happen,
but what it does indicate is,
well,
we face crises in the past and uh,
we have made things better.
Let's figure out how to deal with
crises.
Now.
That's a great way of looking at it too,
to be realistic about it because the
possibility of positive things is a
real.
That's real.
But also there's a reason why we find
those ruins in Guatemala.
Those people are there anymore.
I mean thriving culture,
thousands of structures,
and now it's a jungle.
Like what happened?
It's,
it's wise to remember that that can't
happen.
Didn't become Manhattan.
That's right.
I mean there is.
I think there is a difference between
modern all modern societies and all of
the ones that did collapse.
Namely that after the enlightenment we
developed a kind of a scientific network
and community.
We develop the habit of free speech and
open debate and accumulation of
information in written in an electronic
records.
I mean,
it is not the same now.
It doesn't mean that we're out of danger
because we've created new dangers,
you know,
like,
like nuclear war,
like climate change.
But there is a,
a,
there are mechanisms in place that if we
concentrate them,
if we are determined to keep doing it,
then there's a reasonable expectation of
success again,
but not automatically.
We've got to decide to make.
We've got to make those choices.
Yeah.
The,
the,
the history of the human race is so
weird in terms of the rise and fall of
these civilizations and cultures that
were always a least.
I am always looking at like what,
how long is this going to last?
Like how long has this one particular
nation going to keep it together?
I mean if you look at how many different
countries have been around that,
just how many,
you know,
dominant culture is Rome for instance.
Like just now it's just Italy.
It's just normal,
you know,
it's like a normal European country.
It used to be this conquering nation.
Like how,
how long can we keep this thing up and
what are your thoughts on the future of,
of just even the idea of nations.
It seems like our bout our boundaries
and our borders,
the way we have a online,
this ability to communicate with people
all over the place,
everywhere.
It seems to me to lessen the necessary
or the need rather for for borders and
for,
for these walls that we're now literally
and figuratively talking about putting
up.
I think there's going to be a kind of a
balance.
It's an interesting thing about nation
states now is that there is a sense in
which they're treated as immortal,
that whereas as you mentioned for most
of history,
they were conquering.
Emperors and a nation.
Nations were wiped off the map and
engulfed and conquered.
And you're now you look at a map of the
world and,
uh,
it's actually not that different from
what it was 70 years ago.
I mean,
there are colonies that achieved
independence.
There's some big states like Soviet
Union that broke fragmented,
but the borders in between the ribs,
Soviet republics are now borders between
nation states and no nation has gone out
of existence through conquest since,
uh,
since 1945,
at least internationally recognized
state by the,
by the UN.
So there's this norm,
even though the borders are often,
you know,
crazy.
Then they were arbitrary lines drawn a
map.
But one of the reasons that,
again,
this is counterintuitive,
that wars have gone down and deaths and
wars have gone down,
is that borders are now treated as
sacrosanct by the kind of international
community.
Not One hundred percent of the time you
had Russia annexing Crimea,
but those are exceptions.
And by and large unlike say in the past,
in the 19th century where the US had an
unpaid debt from Mexico,
so it conquered,
you know,
Texas and Colorado and Nevada and
California,
you know,
that doesn't happen anymore.
And so the board has kind of been
grandfathered in and that's one of the
reasons why the,
uh,
the,
the world has been more stable in terms
of the,
uh,
the map.
On the other hand,
as you mentioned,
there's another sense in which we have
this global community that transcends
borders.
We have things like the European Union,
we have the United Nations,
we have a trade agreements like Nafta,
which try to get simultaneously the
grandfathered borders,
but this extra layer of cooperation that
transcends the borders and we need them
more and more despite the fact that our,
our current president is pushing back
against the global community,
but because there are problems that are
global that my migration,
terrorism,
climate pollution,
rogue states,
and the fact that people,
even if they,
even if you grew up in France and you
consider yourself a French citizen,
you want to be able to spend a summer
in,
um,
you know,
in,
in Italy or in England or in Belgium,
if that's where there's a good job and
there's a desire among people to be able
to move to wherever the opportunities
are best.
So there's going to be some kind of
compromise,
I think,
between keeping the,
the,
the nation state borders just so you
don't have constant wars of conquest and
border disputes,
but allowing the world and allowing the
people of the world to take advantage of
a true global community.
Yeah.
I feel like that's one of the things
that people were most upset about brexit
was that this is a,
even though they,
the people that were pro brexit felt
like this was in the interest of the UK
and the interest of England to be
separate from all this because they were
doing better and because they didn't
want all the negative possibilities from
all these other places coming into their
environment.
But the,
what I think that people,
what they didn't like about it was the
idea that this is a regressive move and
that the progressive move is that we
would all move towards this idea of a
global community of this entire world
being free and connected.
And you know,
we've talked about,
um,
some of the problems that Paris has with
the immigration.
We showed some of the videos of these,
uh,
these immigrants that are just littered
all over the street and taking this
place apart.
And we're looking at it going,
man,
that is a,
that is a real tragedy.
But what it represents is a bunch of
people that really don't have anything.
Like.
The real tragedy is that these people
live like this.
The real tragedy is not that they've
done it to Paris.
The real tragedy is that these people
exist at all and that they moved to
Paris looking for a better life and now
they're stuck in the situation where you
know there's not a lot of sanitation and
the garbage is all over the place.
They're literally everywhere and it's.
I wonder if we ever will have a world
where there isn't a place where you can
go and ship a factory and pay people a
dollar an hour because they don't need a
dollar an hour because it's just like
living in Los Angeles or just like
living in Phoenix,
like you would never be able to pay
someone a dollar an hour because there's
too much opportunity.
The world has caught up and surpassed
it.
Yeah.
There's a number of really complicated
issues that they.
Your mobility is in general a good thing
in countries do well when they welcomed
Indian immigrants,
but not on the short term.
Yeah.
Not too many.
Too fast.
Faster than they can be assimilated and
integrated into the new country.
So it just opening the doors probably is
not a good idea.
No country really does that,
but building the wall is a terrible idea
to uh,
and of course the,
the,
the best way to prevent a massive
amounts of,
of migration is to make life better in
the countries of origin because that is
happening slowly and unevenly.
But it's been noted that even United
States and Mexico,
more people are going,
or the same number of people are doing
the reverse migration from the US back
to Mexico now that the economy of Mexico
so much my own parents when 25 years.
Okay.
Yeah.
My parents live in Mexico.
Okay.
There you go.
Yeah.
Um,
and there is a,
a,
um,
a harder to detect,
but there is a huge improvement in the
standard of living in what used to be
called the third world,
the developing world where,
um,
the,
if you look at the cutoff for extreme
poverty kind of defined,
defined somewhat arbitrarily is a dollar
90 per person per day,
kind of the bare,
bare,
bare minimum to feed,
feed your family.
Uh,
it's down now from a 50 percent a few
decades ago to 10 percent now,
and the United Nations have set the goal
of bringing it to zero by the year 20,
30,
and what street,
what is causing that?
What's causing the change?
So a lot of it is,
um,
globalization that,
I mean even though that's kind of a
villain in many people's eyes,
but when you have a,
a,
a huge global market than a and the
introduction of,
of uh,
factories and industrialization in
China,
in India and Bangladesh,
sometimes the conditions are grim,
but the conditions being a peasant in
the rice patties was even grimmer.
And when,
when you have a people integrated with
the economy,
selling their products on a world stage,
uh,
they can get richer.
And so a lot of also better policies.
We have governments that are no longer a
communist or like really heavy handed
forms of socialism where everything is
defined by the bureaucrats.
And you need 50 licenses to do anything
and you have a little bit more economic
flexibility that tends to make the
country's richer.
It doesn't mean that you could do away
with regulations on workplace safety
and,
uh,
environment and as countries get richer,
they tend to be more protective of their
workers and the environment,
right?
And leaders that think of their mandate
as how do I get my country to be richer?
And the most dramatic case was China
where,
uh,
you know,
Mao had these harebrained schemes have
huge collective farms and people
smelting iron in their backyards and you
know,
anything that occurred to him in the
middle of the night,
he would force on hundreds of millions
of people and it cost these massive
famines.
Then Deng,
Deng Xiaoping took over and he said,
getting Richard Good,
uh,
and he said,
black cat,
white cat,
as long as it catches mice,
it's a good cat.
So much more pragmatic,
much more concerned with the welfare of
their citizens.
When you have leaders who have that
mindset,
then the country can,
can get,
get wealthier and their citizens better
off
now.
But are you concerned?
I mean,
I,
I agree with you that it is probably is
one of the reasons why these people are
experiencing this greater quality of
life is because of globalization because
these factories moving in,
but they're living lives that are very
different and maybe perhaps it's by our
standards that their lives are better.
That may be if these indigenous people
were living this sort of subsistence
lifestyle that even though on paper they
would be existing in extreme poverty,
but if they're perhaps like living in
the jungle or somewhere along those
lines where you have access to all these
natural resources that even though
they'd be living in extreme poverty,
they'd be living maybe,
perhaps even a better life by just
eating the fish and eating the plants
and hunting and fishing and doing what
they had normally done for thousands and
thousands of years rather than making a
dollar an hour and a Nike factory.
Right.
And it's certainly true that indigenous
peoples who are living in a hunter and
horticultural lifestyles,
that there are real crimes in displacing
them often.
Not so much by factories but by miners
and loggers.
But the,
the,
there are a very tiny fraction of the
world's population,
tragically,
uh,
the vast majority of poor people or more
are peasants,
not,
not horticulturalists.
And,
and you know,
they are kind of agricultural laborers
and for them just based on their own
choices,
uh,
often the factory life is a,
is an improvement.
It's an improvement,
not just because they're not a kind of
in the fields,
knee deep in muck a pulling up seedlings
and getting bitten by disease carrying a
bugs.
But,
um,
for women,
uh,
being able to move from a,
a village to a city often means
liberation that they can start a
business and the kids to school,
uh,
be out from under the thumbs of their
husbands and the husband's family.
They're kind of can be a liberation just
just as what our aunts,
our ancestors did when they left the
farms for cities a hundred and 50 years
ago.
So not to say there isn't exploitation
and,
uh,
and cruelty which ought to be opposed.
And in the case of native peoples,
often,
you know,
criminal,
uh,
displacements.
But on the whole globalization has led
to this escape from grinding poverty for
literally hundreds of millions of
people.
So even when they moved these factories
into these places in charge or pay them
a dollar an hour,
rather,
it still a dollar an hour than
they would've gotten if the factory had
been there.
In many cases.
That's true.
Which exploitation.
But you know,
we look at our and said,
you know,
my grandparents worked in a clothing
factory and uh,
when they emigrated from Poland to
Canada and it often is a route to upward
mobility.
Yeah,
it's,
it's hard for us to accept that or even
think about it that way because it was
saying,
well,
why?
How come they don't have to pay these
Mexican folks minimum wage just like
they do in America?
Like,
well,
why don't they have the same sort of
setup we do here?
Just seems cruel.
It doesn't impair,
no doubt there is cruelty.
But the relevant
Harrison is not so much a difference
between working in a factory there and
working in an office,
you know,
in Berkeley or Manhattan.
It's the difference between working in a
factory
there and,
uh,
and,
and laboring in the fields there.
And the people are often given that
choice.
They line up to the factory jobs.
Do you anticipate a time where there is
no third world and there is no,
it's a massive economic disparity.
It's conceivable,
um,
you know,
it's a ways off,
but it's happened in huge parts of the
world.
I mean,
we forget that places like South Korea
now,
you know,
this rich,
a upper middle class society,
uh,
not so long ago.
That was the third world.
I mean,
they were,
they were hungry.
They were,
uh,
the,
the children died young.
A lot of them living in squalor.
Uh,
and that was true in certainly in China.
Lots of parts of places,
parts of China now that are pretty much
middle class that we're a squalid not so
long ago,
a Singapore.
Uh,
I have,
uh,
an anecdote in the book of enlightenment
now with my ex mother in law who grew up
in Singapore and she remembers a
childhood meal in which her family split
one egg for ways.
I was back in the,
uh,
in the 19 forties,
Singapore is now one of the world's
richest countries,
so it can happen.
It is happening.
The most remote,
poorest parts of the world are going to
be the hardest to bring up to middle
class standards.
Like,
you know,
Congo like Haiti,
like Afghanistan,
but large parts of the world.
There's been a huge increase in the
standard of living.
Um,
you talked recently about the dangers of
overly politically correct thinking of
or just politically correct thinking of
have a sort of a rebound effect where
political correct thinking is actually
causing more extremism,
uh,
more and more radical thinking in new,
in terms of response to that,
like an overcorrection at the,
at the top of our conversation we
talked about the possibility of,
of sex differences as being kind of
taboo from polite company.
And in a lot.
I'll give another example,
and this is kind of connects to our
conversation,
isn't a lot of academia.
There's just capitalism is just a dirty
word or something now called the Neo
liberalism and you know,
a,
a certain percentage.
Surprisingly,
large percentage of academics are
actually Marxists,
probably about 15 percent in the social
sciences,
uh,
and uh,
to say the obvious fact that capitalism
is better than communism.
I mean,
that's just a fact.
just compared,
we would rather live in South Korea or
North Korea would rather live in the old
East Germany or West Germany,
a I'd rather live now in Venezuela or in
Chile and it's just obvious that
capitalism makes people a richer and
freer and better off in pretty much
every way.
Now.
That's a fact.
That's almost unmentionable in academia
now,
but he say it by itself and suddenly
people discover it for the first time.
Then you can get the extreme right wing
position that any amount of regulation
is bad.
Any amount of social spending is bad.
We need the most extreme form of almost
an arco capitalism like radical
libertarianism.
And that's because I argue that if you
never have a discussion of the relative
advantages and disadvantages of
different economic systems,
you never hear the arguments for why
some mixture of a free market with
regulation of things that have to be
regulated because the market won't take
care of them,
like pollution.
I mean the market just won't put up,
put a price on the atmosphere because no
one owns the atmosphere.
And so having a combination of a free
market with environmental regulations
gives you the best of both worlds.
Likewise,
social spending for the elderly,
for children,
for the sick,
for the unlucky,
a bath not incompatible with a free
market,
and in fact some of the countries who
have the strongest social safety nets,
also one of the ones with the most
economic freedom.
So that argument that I've just given
you right now just doesn't take place
because there's just such a commitment
to the idea that capitalism is bad.
Opening up the possibility that someone
discovers hate capitalism isn't so bad,
then they reap to the strongest possible
conclusion.
Well,
if as soon as you have social security,
then we're going to be like Venezuela,
Venezuela,
or or,
or,
or our carbon pricing and the rational
way of organizing society with just the
right balance of free markets.
Regulation.
Social spending is just something that
doesn't get discussed out in the open.
You get these polarized extremes and
that that's the argument that what's the
origin of that thought process in
academia?
Like why has capitalism and demonized
and socialism being been praised despite
all the evidence that especially Marxist
socialism or Marxism is just,
it's never been shown to be effective
and it's been shown to be very
dangerous.
Yeah,
it's a good question.
One theory from Thomas Sowell,
an economist at the hoover institution
is that intellectuals tend to like
systems that where you can articulate a
theory and a bunch of verbal
propositions and you know,
the government kind of implements them.
Whereas there are certain phenomena in,
in,
in social life like market economies
where the intelligence is distributed
across millions of people.
No one actually knows how to make the
system work,
but people make things look for buyers.
They set the price where people will,
will buy them,
and then over the entire society,
things kind of work out,
but no one,
actually no single individual has the
theory as to how that ought to work.
Uh,
language is another example.
I mean,
there's no committee that designed the
English language.
There is no theory of how the English
language ought to work.
It's like hundreds of millions of people
just talking and they invent new slang
and they slur and they emphasize and
they borrow from other languages.
And the language changes and it works
pretty well.
Here we are speaking in English and no
committee ever designed it.
So according to souls theory and he,
I think he was influenced by a High Eq
Friedrich Hayek,
the Austrian economist,
that systems of distributed intelligence
where no one genius ever designed it,
but millions of people cooperating,
give rise to a collective intelligence
kind of run against the grain or the way
intellectuals often think,
not all intellectuals,
because of course you could do what high
console did and realized there is this
phenomenon of collective intelligence.
But if your first impulse is what's the
theory,
uh,
you know,
what are the set of principles,
then you're going to gravitate to
planned,
you know,
hyper plan systems and the a little bit
oblivious to distributed systems,
but in academia for whatever reason,
looking at things in terms of a,
from a social standpoint,
looking at things is a distribution of
wealth is a big,
a common subject that keeps getting
brought up and class structures that
there's going to be a time if everything
works out correctly.
If we continue to evolve our culture
where we will no longer have classes,
we'll know and we'll be able to
distribute wealth completely equally
across the board,
but it sort of denying the motivation
that human beings have to succeed.
It's designing the denying this desire
that people have to stand out and to
overachieve or to,
to be,
to be an outlier in terms of
performance,
which is just a natural part of human
beings and also competition.
That competition is fueled by reward and
without competition,
you don't have iphones.
You don't have most of the technological
innovation that we have that's been
funded by these companies have done it
in order to make money.
There's,
there's to be some sort of a reason why
they pushed all these things.
It's so ironic when someone is talking
about how capitalism sucks
on an iphone.
I mean,
didn't Jesus Christ.
That is one of the more bizarre ironies
is unexposed.
Will you put your finger on another
phenomenon?
And I discussed this in my book,
the blank slate when I also discussed
the kind of the politics of gender that
part of it is there's a history to it.
So there was an idea sometimes called
social darwinism.
It wasn't,
it had nothing to do with Darwin and
ironically,
but the idea that the only way society's
progresses through ruthless cutthroat
competition and poor people are just
dragging the species down and you know,
screw them,
and if we were were were bleeding hearts
than will retard the progress of
society.
And we need,
you know,
just everyone against everyone else for
two to advance.
Now you know that that's really not a
very good way to organize a society.
But there's such a reaction against that
in the 20th century that you got the
opposite extreme,
that we are all blank slates.
That is,
we all start off a identical and that,
uh,
any kind of competition is bad.
You need kind of this,
the benevolent government to distribute
everything in the fairest possible
manner.
Now,
the reality is,
is something in between,
we are a,
there's going to be an equality in any
fair system simply because some people
really are smarter than others and some
people have more discipline and more
self control and uh,
and it's good to harness that so that
our competitive impulses have some
people burning the midnight oil and
racking their brains to how to make
things better off because they
anticipate some rewards.
You don't want to sap all incentives,
which is kind of what happened in the
Soviet Union.
You also don't want a central committee
to decide that everyone has to have the
same amount and parcel out every reward
because that just gives too much power
to a government.
But it also doesn't mean that you have
the opposite extreme where the,
you know,
the poor people die,
then it's their own fault because
they're lazy and stupid.
I mean,
that's just not true.
It's not humane.
And what we need to do is find the right
balance between competition and freedom
that makes everyone better off and
recognition that just be,
there are going to be people who are not
as smart,
but they don't deserve to starve a,
there are people who are just going to
be unlucky because a lot of wealth isn't
distributed by a talent and hard work,
but there's a lot of luck that goes into
it as well.
And so we may want to kind of,
uh,
a sand down some of the sharp edges of
competition.
There it,
it doesn't have to be either or.
And the thing is,
if you make one position taboo,
then it makes things either or.
But how bizarre is it that these kinds
of rational conversations about this
very important subject is taboo in
intellectual circles and it's not good
academia.
How did that happen?
It's not good.
I,
you know,
I think some of it is a reaction to the
excesses of the past,
some of it,
because people do tend to form a kind of
intellectual tribes the same way you
have sports teams,
uh,
and you root for your team and you know,
and when you're a sports fan,
when you acquire information isn't to
become better and better informed in
some objective way.
It's to kind of enhance the fan
experience.
You want to find out what's great about
your team and what's awful about the
other team.
And that's a human habit that we bring
to intellectual debates where and,
and academia,
academics or are susceptible to it as
anyone.
Anyone else,
unless they take steps to recognize it
and avoid it.
But you know,
if you're on the left,
you root for the left team and if you're
on the right,
not so much in the universities but in
the think tanks,
you root for the right team and you tend
to discount evidence that goes against
your ideology.
You kind of filter out the things that
are a little bit embarrassing.
Uh,
and uh,
uh,
people then a adopt certain opinions is
almost loyalty badges and this is true
of a lot of controversies that people
often think are due to scientific
illiteracy,
like climate change where you ask a lot
of scientists,
why do people deny the obvious facts of,
of manmade climate change.
And I think,
well,
people just don't get enough information
that we need better outreach and I think
we do need better outreach,
but in fact,
and I talk about this and enlightenment
and enlightenment now,
if you actually do surveys of how well
people understand climate science is not
virtually no correlation between
acknowledgement of human made,
climate change and sophistication in
climate science.
So you get people who do believe in
human made climate change,
which I think is an incontrovertible
fact at this point,
but they don't really understand it.
I mean,
they may even think,
oh,
it's caused by a hole in the ozone layer
and we can fix it by cleaning up toxic
waste dumps me like crazy beliefs,
but they're still on.
You know,
what I would consider the right,
the right side.
What happens is that in some politicized
debates,
the people don't,
don't so much care about the truth.
They care about what belief will earn
them esteem in their,
their peer group.
Right?
Right.
This is human psychology,
but it's really bad when it comes to
arriving at the best understanding of
the truth collectively and what we need
both in the left wing academic
departments and the right wing think
tanks is kind of recognition.
We're probably all wrong about a lot of
things,
especially if we talk to each other and,
and act like kind of litigators like
lawyers who mouth the best possible case
for our side to prosecuted against the
other side.
That's just not a good way of arriving
at the truth.
You've got to kind of check the
tendencies in yourself to just want more
and more evidence for your belief and
force yourself to be enforced other
people to be as open minded as possible.
Yeah.
It's very fascinating to me.
These,
um,
these sort of mindsets that,
uh,
that you on the left
and on the right,
that there are certain subjects that
you,
if you support that subject,
you are automatically thought of as a
left winger.
Have you support this subject?
You're already automatically thought of
as a rule if you were on the right,
you probably think,
yeah,
in some way,
like if,
if someone says to me that they think
that climate change is probably an
overblown thing and it's a cycle that
the world has been going through
forever,
I go,
you're a right winger and you'd be
right.
Yeah.
Almost always,
always,
always.
And if you think,
you know,
all gay people should be allowed to get
married.
Who Cares?
Oh,
you're probably left winger.
Yeah,
that's probably true 10 years ago.
And it's actually less true now.
That's what these amazing changes.
So sometimes there can be these changes.
They just catch us all by surprise and
gay marriage is one of them.
I mean that was like,
even people on the left had misgivings
about climate change.
I've ever been gay marriage.
I'm sorry,
in the nineties it was still something
that a lot of people on the left,
we're kind of had let him,
let's not go that far.
Maybe we should have civil unions or you
know,
now the whole of the country is flipped,
but you.
But in general so these changes can
happen,
but you're right that a lot of opinions
are just loyalty badges to a coalition
and they can sometimes change in very
strange ways.
So we've seen it in the last year or so
with a Donald Trump who is in many ways
that pretty radical right winger in
things like,
what do you think?
What do,
what's your opinion of Russia now for
decades?
If you're on the right,
you mistrusted Russia and if you're on
the left there,
you know they weren't so bad,
they misunderstood.
Now it's totally flipped and opinions on
whether you trust Russia just because of
the influence of Donald trump have
shifted.
So the people on the right are more
sympathetic to Russia.
Something that would have been almost
unthinkable even 10 years ago.
Free Trade is another example.
It was kind of a right wing cars and
then trump managed to flip it.
So what it shows is where I'm going with
this and this is something that I've,
where I've changed my mind.
I used to think they were these
ideologies,
kind of like religious catechisms where
these are the beliefs that follow from
one another,
but a lot of us just rot tribalism.
It just like,
you know,
in sports,
the players,
your churn through the tip,
the rosters with free agency and you
know,
we used to be a guy.
He's a good guy.
Well that he's on the other team now.
He's a bad guy.
It was Jerry Seinfeld once said you
rooting for clothing and that kind of
happens with political ideologies as
well to I think to everyone's shock.
Yeah.
That the tribalism thing is very,
very confusing to me because you could
see it like it's such an obvious pattern
and that when it,
when it plays out,
like,
you know,
the global warming thing.
I was having a conversation with a guy
in my Jujitsu class and I'll never
forget this.
And he was like,
ah,
it's been a.
it's a cycle,
it's a cycle of global warming and
climate change has always been a cycle
and you know the people that say that
it's not.
It's like,
oh,
what will.
How much have you studied other
scientists?
Like,
I don't know a lot about global warming.
I don't know a lot about climate change,
but I know what I've read and it seems
to me to be a very complex issue and I'm
talking to this 25 year old guy who was
in the military who's telling me this.
I mean,
do you have an education?
And it's like,
no.
I'm like,
well,
why didn't you just automatically like
decide that this is a more talking about
the very temperature of the planet earth
that's complex and what is causing it?
Is it a carbon monoxide thing?
Is it a what?
Why do you just automatically subscribed
to this and it's because that's how his
tribe communicates.
This is how his tribe and that it gives
people comfort to be in these weird
little groups where everybody has group
think.
Yeah,
and this is a a,
a.
I talk about this phenomenon in
enlightenment now because it's a book
that argues for,
uh,
the,
the importance of reason and,
uh,
and how there has been progress thanks
to application of reason and a natural
pushback is,
well,
you look at things like that,
we don't seem so reasonable.
It's as a species,
how can you,
what's going on that were gay?
We seem to be getting less reasonable.
And I think the answer is there's reason
can work in,
for different goals.
And here I'm using the ideas of a Yale
scholar named Dan Dan Daniel Kahan where
he knows there's a perverse way in which
there's actually is a kind of
rationality to that kind of belief.
Namely,
when you vote,
what are the chances that your vote's
really gonna swing reelection pretty
close to zero.
On the other hand,
when you express an opinion in your,
your peer group,
the people you work with,
your family,
what are the chances that holding a
wrong opinion will lead you to be kind
of condemned and ostracized and treated
as a real weirdo?
You know,
very high.
So if you're,
if everyone thinks what opinion is going
to help my esteem and the people I care
about,
they can latch onto all kinds of beliefs
if they've become kind of identity
badges for their tribe.
Uh,
this is rational in terms of the world
they live in.
It's not so rational for the planet as a
whole.
If people just subscribed to beliefs
based on tribal loyalty instead of truth
and the challenges,
how do we align beliefs more with truth
and less with tribal loyalty?
Now it's not hopeless because there are
a lot of beliefs that people used to
have that are,
that have been,
have been overturned.
People don't believe in Unicorns anymore
or alchemy and fueled.
People believe in astrology and,
and a lot of scientific issues are.
There's no controversy.
Do Antibiotics work?
Yeah,
I mean there's no,
you know,
it doesn't matter whether you're in the
right or the left.
So part of the challenge is how do we
get more and more of our beliefs to be,
to get,
have our social norms be such that if
you believe something just because
you're on the writer on the left,
then you're an idiot.
But what you should be doing is looking
at the best possible study with an open
mind.
That's what a cool person does and only
an idiot just parrots the the right wing
lined.
That's the kind of social change we need
to aim for.
Ryan,
just.
I'm almost a shaming of that kind of
ignorance.
This is the desire that people have to
subscribe to a predetermined pattern of
thinking and behaving because it's.
It's comforting.
It's comforting that you know,
and it also like they know that other
people on their group will also think
like that.
It's like if you're in the right.
One of the things about you see about
right wingers,
it's kind of hilarious.
I was watching this Kyle Kuklinski
secular talk podcast where he was
talking about this,
these Christians who were talking about
trump,
and when you are on the right,
you must have a belief in God.
You just have to,
and when they were talking about trump,
they were saying,
we're talking about the man that existed
before he accepted Jesus.
You know,
I don't have it,
but the guy was literally saying,
I don't have a past.
Okay,
how about you?
Because I've accepted Jesus Christ into
my life and that once you accept Jesus
Christ,
like you are now a believer in Christ
and you're for,
you're forgiven for all of your past
sins.
And this is,
this is on the right.
There's a giant percentage of the people
that are on the right that subscribed to
I a religious Christian mindset.
It is fascinating,
especially when it comes to our current
president who by any standards is like
the least Christian leader that we've
ever had passed.
He accepted Jesus.
He doesn't have a past.
Well,
yeah,
but he's still,
you know,
the Christian virtues include things
like modesty for the week.
Sure.
A temperance.
Chivalry Gentlemen leanness and this guy
is lewd and vainglorious and arrogant
and contemptuous for for losers,
but which shows,
again,
kind of going back to our discussion,
it's just amazing how much loyalty
doesn't have to do with the actual
content of the beliefs.
It's just whoever's on on my side,
and of course he promised a lot of perks
for the,
for the religious right,
like the repeal of the amendment that a
tax exempt organizations can't engage in
politics and lobbying the so called the
Johnson amendment,
which meant that if you're a church,
if you don't pay taxes,
you can't be politically active.
Well,
they didn't like that and he promised to
repeal that amendment and so he got
their loyalty and so it was just raw
political muscle kind of overcame
Christian virtue.
So bizarre.
Yeah,
but it's,
it's fascinating to watch just these
patterns,
these tribal ideological patterns when
you see these groups that have this sort
of one mindset and this very clear.
The thing is I can flip another example.
People forget this is so take
environmentalist them,
you know,
kind of quintessential,
left green cars.
Not so long ago,
it was the other way around is actually
considered to be a cause of the right.
Why?
Well,
if you are,
if you're a left wing activist in the
sixties,
he would say,
well,
the only people concerned with the
environment are rich people who liked
the view from their country estates and
they don't want them to be spoiled by
being cut down for apartments,
for poor people,
uh,
or they're,
you know,
duck hunters who want to be able to go
and hunt ducks and,
and if you're really socially concerned,
you should care about Vietnam and racism
and poverty and it's just a luxury to
worry about,
you know,
trees and flowers and ducks that I
flipped and then environmentalist and
became a leftwing cause.
But it,
these,
uh,
these connections between your coalition
and your beliefs aren't set in stone.
Yeah.
It wasn't at the beginning of the
forming of the political parties.
It was.
The Democrats were very different and
Republicans are more like Democrats.
Oh yeah.
Well,
starting with Abraham Lincoln,
the first republican president and they
were the,
the,
of course they were the party against
slavery.
And in fact,
even in my lifetime,
through the sixties,
in the south,
the Democrats were the right wing racist
party.
I mean,
had George Wallace,
the governor of Alabama who said
segregation now,
segregation forever.
He was a democrat.
He formed his own party in [inaudible],
68.
Then back in [inaudible] 72,
he ran for the Democratic nomination.
And the southern Democrats were they the
kind of the right wingers.
And it was often the northeast
Republicans who were the liberals.
That's still partly true in
Massachusetts.
We had a little bit of a remnant of
that.
We've had some liberal Republican
governors.
We have one right now.
Charlie Baker was a Republican and he's
pretty moderate middle of the road,
uh,
William Weld,
who was then the libertarian vice
presidential candidate.
He was a republican even,
you know,
even when Mitt Romney was our governor,
he was not particularly conservative.
He was a republican.
So there's the remnants of that in
Massachusetts.
They used to be a little bit of that in
New York where they were liberal
Republicans.
Uh,
but yeah,
that's a case where it's flipped and now
democratic was left of center
Republican,
right,
of center.
Yeah.
You've seen some of that also with some
rub.
Republicans have tried to disingenuously
connect the Democratic Party with the
KKK because of the past.
Well,
and that was true.
That was true.
But you know,
they're talking about the people in the
present that,
you know,
this is the party of the support of the
KKK.
Well,
sorta.
Yeah,
that means that all the time ago,
that was the end.
Yeah.
Different people.
It's um,
it's just fascinating to me to watch
these groups of people and uh,
you know,
we've talked about um,
political parties,
the right versus the left.
It's always weird to me that there are
these two sides and that people sort of
like take comfort and in choosing this
group that they identify with these
issues where,
you know,
I identify as a right wing,
I identify as a left identify as this,
that these,
these things are very rigid in their
structure and they don't allow for
nuance thinking and they don't allow for
being objective about issues.
And considering the other side,
considering other people's points of
view and the way they're looking at
things and thinking of maybe there's
some common ground
I agree,
and in fact,
in,
in like mit now has the subtitle,
the case for reasons science humanism
and progress.
And so I have a chapter on reason.
I had a chapter on and I have a chapter
on humanism,
but in the chapter on reason,
I asked the question why does it?
On the one hand it appears that we're
getting smarter.
There's the flynn effect of rising Iq
scores and there are a lot of areas in
life where what you see just much more
intelligence being applied in just a few
years ago.
So just for example,
uh,
you know,
moving in evidence based medicine,
a lot of what your doctor does,
it's just based on kind of superstition
and tradition.
And now people are saying,
well,
let's,
you know,
let's do a randomized controlled trial,
see what works,
what doesn't.
So is getting smarter.
You look at policing,
one of the reasons that the crime rate
has gone down so much,
uh,
another positive development that I,
I talk about that people aren't aware of
is that policing has gotten smarter.
They everyday,
especially in New York,
they would gather data as to where the
homicides were,
which neighborhoods,
which blocks and which neighborhoods and
they would concentrate the police
forces,
you know,
on that day and to prevent things from
getting out of control with cycles of
revenge.
You at sports know moneyball,
where you've got kind of smarter teams
that can beat,
reached Richard Teams.
You look at policy and you've got
evidenced based policy.
So all these areas where it looks like
the country's getting smarter,
but then there are all these areas we're
looking at Kennedy's getting lots of
Jupiter and a lot of them are,
I argue cases where people were issues
get politicized and then people just go
with their own coalition.
And the ideal would be,
and this is an ideal that's in least
preached in science and to some extent
practice,
you know,
there's not leftwing science and writing
science.
It's what are the data?
What did the data say if you haven't
seen,
let's do an experiment.
Let's see who's right,
who's wrong,
and either side might be embarrassed and
I think in the case of these great
political and economic issues we've got,
we'd be better off if we thought like
scientists kept an open mind and say,
well,
what works?
There's a minimum wage lead to a higher
unemployment because labor becomes more
expensive.
Well,
maybe,
you know,
beats me if I know.
Let's let look at areas that have tried
it.
See what happens.
Uh,
do,
does too much welfare.
Make people,
you know,
unambitious and Lacey.
Well,
uh,
you know,
I can't figure this out from my arm
chair,
but let's look at different.
Compare.
Different countries compare different
states and cities issue after issue.
I think we need to be much more
pragmatic and open to evidence,
but when you do deal with these issues,
much like you were talking about,
the difference between genders,
when you deal with the actual raw data,
that raw data,
a lot of it gets very problematic for
people that hold these ideas very
rigidly in their mind.
And they don't,
they don't want to accept certain facts
and Statistics and they come up with
reasons why these things are either
inaccurate or biased or racist or sexist
or what have you.
Yeah,
no,
that's really true because I think
we're,
I think evolution didn't make us into a
intuitive scientists so much as a tool
intuitive lawyers and preachers.
So we,
the natural tendency is to amass the
strongest possible case for your own
side and to a boast that you,
the,
you are the side of virtue.
The people who disagree with you are
idiots.
And,
and,
uh,
evil.
Uh,
and we got to push back against that
tendency.
I,
I argued with enlightenment now.
Yeah.
I just,
I try to recognize that in my own mind
when it comes up.
But it's,
it's so incredibly common that tribalism
that we see on the right and the left,
we see it.
Men versus women.
We oftentimes see it even in gay versus
straight.
It's,
it's,
it's a very bizarre but incredibly
common aspect of being a human being.
It really is.
And I started out as a,
as a psychologist,
a clinical psychologist.
I don't see patients but on the
cognitive scientists,
so I'm interested in how the mind works
and so a lot of my ideas on which way
we're going to keep going in a positive
direction are influenced by a kind of a
recognition of what makes us tick and
what are the pitfalls in having a human
brain.
And I mean,
I,
I don't take credit for this.
This goes back to,
for example,
the American,
uh,
founders and framers,
Madison and Jefferson and Adams and
Hamilton,
when they were arguing,
well,
how should we set up this new new
country,
this new government?
They will kind of intuitive
psychologists and they would point it
out that,
well,
if you just empower a leader,
he's going to get drunk with his own
power and he's going to be diluted.
And what do we do about that?
Because we do need some kind of leader.
Well,
you've got these checks and balances.
How do,
what makes people better off?
They,
if they can exchange things and each one
produces something they're good at and
trades it with something that someone
else produces.
How do we set up a country where it
takes advantage of people's tendency to
treat things,
so the connection between politics and
psychology was has been there for a long
time.
Now.
The,
the,
the subject enlightenment.
That's a very loaded subject because it
is.
Yeah,
and especially in the world of Weirdos
and cult leaders,
Charlotte Tins and people that are sort
of promoting this idea,
this idea that you can achieve this sort
of zen state of bliss,
of being above it.
All of being,
you know,
wise to the point of being a sage.
That's a.
that's a weird concept,
isn't it?
In today's Day and age,
my
editor actually,
it was a little nervous about my choice
of title.
I went through a bunch of titles for it.
As I was writing it,
he said,
well,
don't you think people are going to
confuse it with you?
And so the reason that meaning for
enlightenment,
the other meeting that I had in mind was
the movement in the 18th century to
apply reason to human betterment.
The ideas of of hume and Adam Smith and
the American founders like Jefferson and
Madison and John Locke and Thomas Hobbes
and the 17th and 18th century,
and we said,
look,
if you know,
if some people are confused and they
think this is a path toward my book is
going to be a path towards spiritual
enlightenment.
Well,
let them buy the book.
They might enjoy it anyway,
but I went to the dictionary to see
which of the two meetings was listed
first and most of the dictionary is
listed.
The sense that I had in mind first,
namely the movement in the 18th century
toward greater reason is the spiritual
distinction,
right?
Spiritual enlightenment is the one that
people.
That's right.
And that's to be perfectly honest,
that's not what the book is about.
Uh,
but you know,
well,
some people think it has made it.
They'll buy the book by accident.
Do you meditate?
You know,
I don't,
but I think I should.
But you're such a smart guy.
Like why would you,
why would there be anything that I think
you should do that you don't do it?
It's a really good question because I'm
not clearly,
I'm not that smart.
It's not bad.
It's just a matter of like a practice
and,
you know,
I think so.
Yeah.
And I did,
uh,
I was in a,
in,
in Davos the week before last and was on
a panel with a maturity cow.
The French Buddhist monk who's a,
who I see eye to eye with an a lot of
matters.
He wrote the forward to the French
translation to the better angels of our
nature and he had it.
He had me in the whole room meditating
and it was,
yeah,
I mean I liked it and I probably should
do some orange.
It's probably a benefit to it for now.
Do you have any practices that you do do
to try to sorta like keep your,
your mind clean?
Like do you exercise regularly?
I definitely exercise regularly and I'm
a,
I like exercise my,
where the scenery goes by,
so I don't,
I tend not to hang around in gyms,
but I like jogging,
cycling,
hiking,
kayaking.
Uh,
I like a outdoor exercise and more
aerobic than a um,
than,
than bodybuilding.
Yeah,
they say that's one of the best things
for a cognitive function,
a high intensity aerobic exercise that I
like to think that,
and I try to,
uh,
you know,
sort of step back and exert some
discipline on this.
So social media email more,
more than social media is trying to
spend time with,
uh,
with my wife,
Rebecca Goldstein of novelist and
philosopher and we have a lot in common
and it'd be kind of wasting life if I
didn't get to,
uh,
you know,
enjoy,
enjoy time with her and she feels the
same way.
She's also a workaholic.
So we both are conscious of,
you know,
let's,
let's get,
go for a walk.
Uh,
you know,
let,
let's see,
see some friends.
Let's be close to our families.
Do you have a goal when you're writing a
book like this or is it just you,
you have an interesting subject and just
sort of follow it through?
I always begin a book when I have,
when I come across some really deep,
exciting,
interesting idea that I think has not
been made public enough.
Uh,
so in the case of,
of,
uh,
the better angels of our nature,
it was the fact that all these measures,
violence has been in historical decline
and this is like a mind blowing fact.
And I came across it by various
historians,
political scientists,
psychologists that have sent me their
data and I was of sitting on all these
graphs showing the we're getting less
violent and know,
know about it.
So I wanted to,
I thought I had an important story to
tell and I had a big intellectual
challenge.
Namely,
here I am,
a psychologist.
I,
I like to think I understand how the
mind works,
but it's a big puzzle.
Why were our ancestors so violent and
how come more or less violent?
We're kind of the same animals that we
were a couple of hundred years ago.
And likewise with the new book with
enlightenment now,
then I discovered that there was even
more good news that if you look at other
measures of human wellbeing like
poverty,
like illiteracy,
like,
um,
number of work hours,
uh,
like disease,
a graph after graph looks like we've
made improvements,
car safety,
plane safety,
workplace safety,
pedestrian safety,
death by fire,
death by drowning.
Almost all of them are going down.
And so that was a story that I thought I
was excited by it because,
uh,
I,
I knew that when people came across it,
they would find it interesting and it
was again,
an intellectual challenge.
How do you explain it?
And I attributed it to the enlightenment
ideas.
Do you encounter much resistance to this
narrative from bloom people?
Oh,
you bet.
Yeah.
You know,
and there are things that,
that go wrong here.
There's the opioid epidemic that's wrong
direction.
There's their big threats.
There's always a possibility of nuclear
war.
And we've got to be really careful not
to do anything stupid and to,
in fact try to world walk the world back
from nuclear weapons in the future.
And climate change,
um,
and then there's some people who just
don't believe it.
They said,
well,
what about that?
The terrorist attack yesterday?
And I just say,
well,
you know,
terrorism,
they're kind of jerking us around the
terrorists by doing an eensy weensy bit
of violence.
That gets a huge amount of publicity.
So let's not let ourselves get jerked
around by terrorists and rampage
shooters.
Not give them so much publicity
concentrate on where the deaths really
are.
Like in car accidents,
like in ordinary homicides,
like in opioid deaths.
Let's look at the numbers and not get
fooled by the headlines.
But yeah,
I do get resistance.
We have obviously we have a massive
reaction to any mass tragedy like a,
a mass shooting or something along those
lines,
but that this is a natural thing,
right?
Because this just seems so strange that
it could occur.
It's a natural thing to have this
reaction to this horrible tragedy,
but we don't have a reaction to,
you know,
how many thousands of people die every
day because of obesity.
Obesity.
Exactly.
Or even if we concentrate on violence,
we forget about,
you know,
the guy who shoots his wife because he,
he,
he thinks she's been flirting too much
or the two guys who have a fight in a
bar over who gets to use the pool table
next and one of them is,
is lying dead on the floor.
Uh,
and these are,
there are far more,
uh,
murders of that kind.
Then there are terrorists killings every
day.
There are something like 25 of those,
those homicides and uh,
so it's like a sandy hill massacred day
after day,
after day after day.
And they don't make the headlines
because they occur,
you know,
bit by bit here and there.
But it's still incredibly confusing to
people when someone does do something
like the vegas shooting,
like what,
what is this like?
So I have a discussion of that just
because it is such a puzzle and because
it attracts so much attention and a lot
of it is just the notoriety.
These are often,
not always,
but they're often kind of nobody's and
their life has gone,
going down the toilet and they're
thinking,
well,
how can I do something that makes my
life meaningful,
go out in a blaze of glory?
And so they think,
what is the.
In fact,
I would ask you this question.
Let's say you want to become,
no,
not you,
you're already famous,
but if I say to a typical person,
what is the one thing you can do that's
guaranteed to make you famous by
tomorrow?
The answer is kill a bunch of innocent
people.
And uh,
you know,
that's just a,
a,
a perverse fact about the world.
And so for people where fame and meaning
and mattering are more important than
anything including life itself,
we've kind of given this perverse
opportunity to become a somebody,
but because we just give them wall to
wall news coverage.
That's fascinating.
Has there been an uptick in,
in mass shootings and these sort of
tragedies along with social media and
more media in general?
Probably a sum.
And they do tend to be occurring in,
in cycles there.
There's a copycat phenomenon.
Yeah.
Until people get a little bit bored and
then it kind of dies down again.
So there is that.
And so there is a suggested policy.
Uh,
I actually signed onto this from some
criminologists that the news media
should not publish the names or the
faces of mass killers,
uh,
that,
what's news?
It may be newsworthy that had happened,
but the particular name of the guy,
wife,
why is that newsworthy?
The problem is it gets clicks.
It gets click.
You're right.
There's so many articles that you see
today that you,
you look at the title of the article and
it has very little to do with the actual
article itself.
It just because they come up mean this
salacious headlines.
They're just,
they're so attractive.
And it seems like today especially,
you're seeing less and less people
reading the Washington Post,
the New York Times,
the La Times,
they're struggling.
And one of the ways they keep up is by
giving people what they want.
If it bleeds,
it leads.
If you know,
who is this crazy asshole that shot 58
people,
let's,
let's find out what's going on in his
life.
It was his dad,
who was this who says brother,
exactly.
And that is according to this,
this movement.
I mean it's,
it's,
it's a case that's not so innocent.
It's not like the kind of click bait.
You wouldn't believe what happened to
the 19 seventies actress so and so.
And the picture of her in her seventies
if you know that kind of click bait,
but this is click bait that does real
harm.
And there are other,
you do have to balance it against,
of course,
freedom of the press.
You don't want there to be,
you know,
governments to tell newspapers where
they can publish.
But there have been some precedents
where press has voluntarily impose some
standards that do nothing to abrogate
freedom of the press.
But to make people better off.
So I'll give you an example from sports.
Uh,
when the,
the TV networks adopted a policy of not
filming a fans that run onto the field,
people stopped running onto the field
because why do they do it?
So they can say,
you know,
hi mom to be broadcast to 300 million TV
sets.
Of course,
Canada had a policy of no longer
publishing the names of juvenile killers
and uh,
you know,
that was a voluntary restraint and it
was socially responsible and I think
there is something to be said for,
for not giving rampage killers the
audience that they seek.
Hm.
Yeah.
I think that makes a lot of sense in
terms of,
uh,
you know,
the greater good of humanity,
but if you're a newspaper guy and your,
your,
your business is just to sell
newspapers,
you're,
you're a bottom line person.
That the whole thing is just to include,
increase the amount of revenue that
comes into your institution.
Yeah.
And,
and,
and not go bankrupt.
Yeah.
Especially today.
Right.
But you know,
journalists especially in a mainstream
forums like the,
the major networks and CNN and the today
and so on,
they still have a huge readership and,
and they do,
they have,
they have to look at themselves in the
mirror.
They do have journalistic codes of
ethics.
That's kind of one of the things that
distinguishes them from the fake news
and the rumor mills.
And so,
and that will always attract a large
following.
You,
you want to be able to trust what you
can read and so they've got a,
I think,
balance that against raw bottom line
because if they lose their integrity
than that's not so good for the bottom
line in the long run either.
Do you think that there's.
I wonder if there's room for new media
today in terms of.
I mean we obviously have these
established places like the New York
Times and like the Washington Post,
but I wonder if that,
these,
these like,
well respected,
longstanding traditional venue that I
wonder if that's really the right way to
do it anymore.
Well,
there has been a simultaneous with the
kind of bottom feeders and the clickbait
factories,
there are a lot of really good new
electronic magazines.
No vocs and medium and Pacific Standard
at Nautilus and Colette and Ian and uh,
you know,
there are others.
So,
uh,
and,
and a couple of decades earlier slate a
new.
These are really,
really good and you often can read
things that you're not going to find
necessarily in the legacy papers.
And they're responsible and they have
fact checkers and they're,
you know,
they're not,
they're not clickbait factories and so
there is a,
it's funny,
almost inequality in an intelligent
media where there's a lot of real crap
at the bottom,
but there's also a room at the top for,
for new voices,
when you look at a guy like the
president,
the United States who loves to use that
term fake news,
so it's,
it's one of the weirder times ever is
his attacks on the media and it seems to
be very similar to like the way he
reacted to Barack Obama,
mocking him during that speech,
like the media,
when they criticize him and critique
him,
his response is to completely attacked
them and just say that they're useless
and fake and it's.
It's a weird time for,
for news when it comes to that and for
journalism.
No,
I agree.
It is a very disturbing phenomenon
because there is a phenomenon of fake
news,
but fake news is not the same thing as
coverage.
That criticizes the precedent.
Right?
Exactly.
An example of a real lack of
comprehension of the,
of how democracy works.
Mainly if you're the president,
you can be,
will be,
should be criticized,
yes.
How democracy works.
We don't have a supreme divine leader
that we consider it infallible and um,
this event and that we bow down in front
of it.
Anything he says goes,
he's temporarily kind of a steward.
He's temporarily overseeing the
government,
but you know,
he screws up and if he says something
that's not true,
the people have the right to criticism
or criticized him and they better be
that criticism.
Otherwise we're going to get a,
you know,
a tyrant or a desk bought and,
uh,
taking any criticism and,
and labeling it fake news,
which is a real funnel problem.
Fake news is a genuinely anti democratic
impulse and it's really disturbing.
It is disturbing.
It's also disturbing his attacks on the
different intelligence agencies tax on a
law enforcement.
It's,
it's real weird.
It's weird.
It's a real weird that you know it.
If you boil it all down and you look at
it like,
well,
what's going on?
Oh,
well,
anyone,
anyone that's after him,
anyone that's attacking him,
criticizing him,
like the,
these people get demeaned and he uses
his influence and his power to kind of
shut down all of these criticisms
without any seemingly without any
concern,
for the longterm consequences of
diminishing the impact of these media.
A
really important point.
Yeah.
Again,
this is a big theme of enlightenment now
is what makes progress possible is that
we have the institutions that are
smarter than any of the flawed
individuals that make it make it up,
that we recognize it.
We humans are,
you know,
what,
what kind of smart,
poor,
not that smart and we all like to think
that we're good and decent and wise,
but no one of us in particular is that
good and decent and yes,
but we can set up rules and institutions
that make the society as a whole better
than any of the individuals that make it
up.
And democratic government is the prime
example.
And the whole,
the difference between a democracy and
as a cultive personality like Mao in
China or Stalin in Russia,
Hitler in Germany or uh,
uh,
Mugabe in Zimbabwe now,
or,
or the Kim's in North Korea,
is that we don't worship a supreme
leader who kind of embodies the virtue
of the people.
That's the idea that the United States
tried to get away from the ideas.
You got to procedure,
you've got some rules,
you gotTa,
you know,
you have to have someone making
decisions but you kind of reign it in
and it's not about him.
It's about the whole system.
And the fact that we've now got a leader
who just doesn't really seem to
understand that.
He seems to think that it's all about
him.
And that if you just,
you know,
I alone consultant,
trust me,
let me do it.
And,
uh,
the,
all these rules and regulations are the
deep state,
the administrative state.
Well,
thank God for the deep state.
The administrative state.
It prevents some desk bought from
foisting is cracked brain schemes on the
whole population.
We do need rules and bureaucrats and
checks and balances as an oppressed.
The can criticize the leader.
As a psychologist,
when you're looking at all this is,
is this a fascinating study to you or is
it terrifying?
I guess?
I guess some of each.
I'd rather not be as fascinated,
right,
because ultimately you really don't want
human psychology to be determining the
fate of the world.
You kind of want,
or at least you want one product of
human psychology,
namely what we collectively irrationally
agree upon to be embodied in a set of
rules and procedures and so it's not
about,
you know,
that guy.
There's also a way of behaving that we
deem presidential and Barack Obama,
in my opinion,
embodied that better than anybody.
He was very composed,
like one of the most composed leaders
ever in terms of leaders in the United
States,
like the way he would communicate and
the way he would respond to criticism.
He just had a very sort of composed a
higher level of his ability to
communicate is.
It was just,
it was very clean in a way.
I agree,
and,
and it was,
it was a kind of a dignity and state
street and yeah,
and decorum and statesman and there's a
reason for it.
It isn't just that it makes you feel
good when you see it,
but it actually is making a statement,
namely,
it isn't about me.
I'm occupying this office not to,
not to prove what a big shot I am,
what a genius,
what a,
a,
uh,
a glorious,
Noble,
divine figure I am.
But I've got this big responsibility.
I've got power to kill hundreds of
millions of people or to make them
better off or worse off.
Uh,
I take that seriously.
it's not about me feeling really
empowered is about me kind of serving
the people that elected me.
And that kind of self restraint and
respect for the office is a way of
reaffirming that principle of democracy.
What also concerns me is that the person
who's in charge is.
This is how a lot of the rest of the
country views the nation itself.
Like and if you have a person who's
measured and objective and well thought
out and well spoken and that when when
you would hear especially Obama
speeches,
agree with them or disagree with him,
everything was very clean,
like the way he maybe I use the word
clean too much,
but it was,
it was eloquent in.
It was smarter than most people.
You know,
it was more more articulate than most
people,
you know,
tho those,
the way the sentences were formed were
impressive in the intellectual capacity
of the person that's delivering those
words and so that made us feel better
about who we were as a country.
We're being led by this very wise,
smart person.
Whether you agree with his policies or
not,
there's no denying that this is a.
it's an exceptional human.
I agree.
And again,
I think there's a greater reason behind
it.
To United States has the most powerful
military.
It's the richest country.
The United States does matters to the
rest of the world and to reassure the
rest of the world that we're not just a
bunch of cowboys who are going to do
what's makes us the most powerful,
but we really think about our role.
We don't.
We don't do rash things that could
really be bad for the world.
That gets conveyed symbolically in the
way that a leader comports himself or
herself.
Well,
one of the things that I think of when I
see this whole thing going down and I
see also this a reaction to this
president,
like the giant women's March being
called the women's March all day and it
is a woman's march,
but it's also a march against the
president.
I mean that's a big part of what this
says.
It's like the idea is that he is kind of
against women in their eyes,
whether it's correct or not,
but that this March is to shorter sort
of show solidarity that they disagree
with the way things are going and I
wonder if having a guy like this in
power is going to,
as we were talking about before,
this sort of swing effect,
gonna re reignite more people to be
politically active and more people to do
recognize the things that they don't
like,
like the calling the media fake news or
like the attacks on the intelligence
community.
All these,
these various things,
these things that people deem to be
racist is things that people deem to be
hostile or or silly that he says and
that there'll be some sort of a powerful
reaction in response to that.
That is.
That is the hope.
It's too soon to tell because there are
two possibilities and one of them is
that he's sort of shattered.
Some norms created a precedent that
means their successors could be even
worse because norms can be fragile.
Like what you just don't do.
If you're president,
well now you can do them.
Right.
That's the pessimistic view of the
optimistic view is that the country will
say,
oh my God,
look what we've been through.
We try that.
Let's get we,
we,
we tried crazy.
Let's get back to sane.
Right?
Uh,
so those,
those are the two possibilities.
Um,
you're out of time.
Yes.
Listen,
thank you so much for being here.
Your book.
One more time.
Enlightenment now.
No reason.
Science,
humanism and progress.
Thank you so much.
It's been an honor and a pleasure.
I really appreciate you being honest.
Been Mine.
Thank you so much,
Joe.
Thank you Steven Pinker,
ladies and gentlemen.
Bye.
Wow.