There you go.
I know.
It seems like we were
great.
Now we are going to go cancer.
No cans.
What are you going to do?
I'll,
I'll go with you.
I'm going to get a note.
Cancer,
a fucking animal.
Semans just connect man.
Let's mind meld.
I think in mind meld more with those
things on really some weird way.
Yeah.
You were in each other's head.
I just hate my voice.
I sound like a woman.
You definitely don't sound like a woman.
Whenever I call for like tech support to
lead me through the first few steps and
then I'll be like,
alright,
and then I hit delete and they'll be
like,
no ma'am,
what you do is.
And then it's like it's too far into it
for me to correct them because it feels
too.
I'm too embarrassed to correct them at
that point.
So then I just can't.
I just let them assume I'm alone for the
rest of the call and it's weird because
then you see what it's like to be
treated like a woman like he talks.
I find that they talked down to you more
like especially about tech support,
right?
Oh fuck.
A chick on a computer.
They treat you like you're a baby and
now he's just screamed blue.
Shake your little mouse.
Why?
Why is there a difference in like tech
stuff?
Like why are men more attracted to the
tech stuff aren't,
aren't we more
mathematical than women?
Well,
that's a weird thing to say.
I mean there's right and left side of
the brain,
right?
I would say yeah,
men are much more mathematical to women,
but I'm not mathematical even slightly.
So what am I a woman?
You just said that like you're going to
kick my broad.
Like what do I read?
Fucking chick lit.
I'm a fucking skirt.
I wish I was.
Man.
They get it made right now.
Women got it made.
How so?
Well,
because there's,
you know,
there's this sort of like postmodern
feminism coming back where,
you know,
with this,
with the lean in and the like,
you know,
women really,
they really are going to start getting.
I think they're still making like eighty
cents on a dollar.
Do you know that's all bullshit.
I've heard you say that before and I
wanted to correct.
You know it's not true.
It's not.
It's not true.
No.
You know what that means when they say
women make eighty cents of the dollar,
it means overall women make eighty cents
compared to the dollar that men make,
but not for the same jobs when women and
men are making,
making the same when they're doing the
same job,
the,
the problem with that statistic is it
leads you to believe that a man and
woman are working alongside each other
doing the exact same amount of work,
the same amount of hours,
but the woman makes less.
It's not the case in the same.
Just a lot of executives.
It's been that have been found out to
be.
I know a couple that were,
that are executives that were doing the
same job,
leading the sales team and making less
money.
Perhaps.
Perhaps there's a few exceptions,
but for the most part when you talk
about overall jobs,
like it's pretty statistically proven
that like lawyers,
doctors,
whatever the fuck the is when they're
working
side by side,
it's very little disparity.
Yeah.
Very little podcast thing is women take
time off for work time off of work,
for a maternity leave.
Of course if they have babies,
but also they tend to work less hours.
Men tend to be more ambitious,
more driven work,
more hours and they get paid more
because of it.
Yeah,
that's what it is.
It's one of those weird ones where
you're.
Everybody says it.
Even fucking Obama said it.
You know the wage gap,
the income gap.
Like what?
What do you mean?
Like why are you saying that?
Because you're.
You're talking about you talking about
it as if there's some sort of
discrimination when in fact there's a
natural tendency that a lot of women
have to choose different jobs.
Like as far as like nursing,
like overwhelmingly a.
it's predominantly women.
So you're saying if you take the total
amount women make versus the total
amount,
men May.
That's where the eighty cents on the
dollar difference,
but it's the job choices.
You're saying the exact right job
choices.
Men are much more likely to die on the
job.
Yeah.
Um,
men,
men are much more likely to take high
paying high risk jobs like mining things
on those lines.
Yeah.
So that's what that is.
It's one of those weird ones where you
repeated a lot of people repeat it and
they think it's right.
They think that men and women who are
working alongside each other making the
same amount of money.
The other thing about executives is,
and this is something that no one wants
to say because it sounds sexist,
but it might be that the men are earning
more money.
Like it might not just be that they're
making more money.
It might be their actual performance as
an executive is better.
It's entirely possible.
It is possible.
But I can also see,
um,
like if I hired a man and a woman,
I would pay the woman less
just because you know,
men are just.
Did you better looking?
You want them around more women are
gross.
How dare you leave periods who I like
literally if you.
Why would I pay somebody who's bleeding
on the job as much as a man?
I'm glad I never have to have a
workforce.
I mean,
what do you got?
But he got one guy.
You got to.
You got a few people working for you.
Yeah,
but they're guys.
Call guys.
Sexy guys.
Okay.
You're a good looking guy.
Jamie is not a bad looking dude.
You play sports.
What'd you play?
I played back in high school.
I played basketball for four years.
For the city.
For three?
Yeah.
You got a lot of pussy.
I bet.
How old were you when you lost your
virginity?
Oh,
17.
Slow.
A little slow on the uptake there?
Yeah.
17.
You want to choose wisely?
How old were you?
16.
15.
Almost 16.
Maybe older woman.
I bet.
No,
I got molested by a girl when I was 13
and she was 21,
but nothing really happened.
It was one of those weird ones,
like she was grabbing my deck.
I was all confused and I made out with
her,
but I was like,
how are we doing here now?
She's so confused.
I.
You hit puberty yet.
I mean,
I guess I was 13.
When do you hit puberty?
I didn't hit until I was 15.
I wasn't beating off at the time.
I actually had sex before.
Beat off.
No Shit.
Yeah,
well I was just,
I didn't.
Once I figured out beating off though,
I was like,
oh,
I'm a slave.
I'm a slave to getting rid of this.
Come up.
Like,
oh no.
And then I realized like once I beat
off,
I was like,
oh,
why can do this myself?
And then I'm not so fucking needy and
weird.
I remember the first time I was dating
this girl and the first time I beat off
and then I was like,
I don't even want to call her.
Yeah,
I got,
I don't want to hang out with her.
Like,
this is annoying.
And I realized like,
Oh,
I wasn't so much that I was attracted to
her.
Was that not that it wasn't attractor.
It wasn't so much that I enjoyed being
around her.
I was,
I wanted to have sex with her and then
once the sex was taken out once a book
get rid of the load,
I was like,
oh,
I don't really want to be around her.
This is just some biological trick.
Yeah.
Like my body's tricking me into wanting
to be near her and hanging around with
her.
Yeah.
Weird.
Because teenage boys and girls have sell
a little income and all you care about
is sports laughing,
trying to get fucked up will,
you didn't really do that.
But like we did and then uh,
and girls at that age are just extremely
social beings.
They're very much about,
um,
their social circle and um,
you know,
establishing who's in the group.
And he was like,
I'm just talking about my,
my daughter is like this.
And I think that they're much more like
in line with what school is telling you
to do.
You know,
they tend to do better in school because
they're a little bit more linear and
they uh,
they,
they're self motivated more than boys
where we just were just distracted too
much.
I think what boys also have like a
serious problem with authority,
I want to.
Teachers are telling you what to do.
You automatically don't want to do it.
That's just a natural inclination that
people have of now I'm getting scared.
Yeah,
that's illegal though.
Can blow it in my face on legal problem
with that.
Yeah,
that's totally illegal.
I got a total second hand high and the
Green Room at the comedy store the other
night.
Holy Shit.
That was like,
there was a cigar going,
five joints going.
Ron White doesn't play.
He pulled out a joint yesterday.
We killed the joint and after the join
pulled out,
one of those vape pens is big gigantic
robot Dick.
I'm like,
Jesus,
wrong.
It goes that weed is like,
Oh hell yeah,
it's,
we good Lord.
So he's got a cigar going.
He brought it,
brings his own Tequila because he now
has his own Tequila company.
Now he does this.
He does,
so he has its number one Tequila
Tequila,
so he brings this bottle of Tequila.
It's really good Tequila and then he's
smoking a cigar.
He's passing out shots,
he's brings cups back there,
handing out shots of his Tequila.
Ron Wyden is damn walking party.
He is a walking part.
Hydro drove home the other night because
he doesn't drink and drive and he really
admire.
He goes to me,
he goes,
hey,
you want to just dry dry,
be home with my truck and then take an
uber back and then he hit your car and
drive home.
I'm like,
yeah,
that's not happening.
I go,
you want a ride home?
And he's like,
uh,
yeah,
I'll take a ride home.
I'll leave.
I'll leave my truck here.
So,
uh,
so he gets in my Prius,
which immediately he gives me shit for
the entire way he can barely fit in it.
And uh,
and we,
we get,
we are and I'm going down sunset here.
Yeah,
go down this way.
So I'm driving.
All of a sudden we hit like Beverly Glen
and I'm like,
where's your fucking house?
He goes,
where are we?
I go,
we're in fucking like ballet or
something,
and so he's like,
no,
go back.
So we go back all the way to the comedy
store and start from scratch,
start from scratch,
take a right down there and then I'm
going down a fucking cannon or something
and he's like,
uh,
Nah,
you went too far.
I'm like,
how the fuck did I know I was going too
far?
What was far?
What was the spot?
And then I can't make a left.
So you guys just make a left.
I'm late.
My wife is going to be why?
I told her I was gonna be over at 10:30.
I'm like,
look,
I'm not getting a fucking t the middle
of Beverly Hills where you get ticketed
for fucking picking your nose.
I'm not making the legal levies.
Like,
no,
make the left.
I'm not making the fucking left.
So I go past it and I doubled back and
then I get,
I get to his place and his place is a
hotel.
Did he talk about this on your show?
Why don't want to like do it is
personal.
You definitely said the name of the
hotel,
but he,
he had a water problem and it's not
about that,
right.
He spent like,
I think more than two years building
this house.
He told me five years,
bought it and then they had to get the
plans approved and then the building.
Yeah.
So it was a total process of about five
years.
Right.
So I think,
but I think it was two solid years in
building this house.
Right.
So he goes out of town and a water
faucet broke and the whole house from
the top floor flooded all the way down
to the bottom.
All the walls have fucking fungus and
mold in them and it's a complete tear
down.
Have you ever had that happen to you
ever have like a fungus or mold issue?
Yeah,
we did.
And um,
it wasn't lethal.
We got to test it.
It was a mold and my wife's very
sensitive to it,
so she was getting all kinds of like
allergies from it and they came in and
the testing is fucking expensive and it
was just,
you know,
it was just a leaky pipe under the house
and you know,
it's in Venice so it's,
it's kind of moist down there and uh,
they just,
you know,
they,
they shaved it out.
Bag.
No,
no big deal now.
But if it's the wrong kind of mold,
I mean it can cause fucking,
like your brain can go.
Do you remember that Tom?
Like this guy,
very nice guy,
great guy.
Tom Like is
Tuesdays crazy?
What a whip them out Wednesday to know
what you're driving.
I had one opie and Anthony had whip them
out Wednesday,
right?
Tom had like flash Friday.
Yeah,
driving down a highway or the road and
you show your tits to guys and then they
call in and then you know,
opie and Anthony got mad because they
thought that Tom has stole the idea
from.
And I'm like,
listen boys,
it's just gets the more tickets come
out,
the better.
Don't stop.
Not Encouraging people,
what are you doing?
Every radio one of the country should
have a day where women share their kids.
I mean,
it should be just a part of what people
do.
I was doing,
uh,
you know,
Bubba,
the love sponge right down in Tampa.
That dude is fucking out there as we
know because his wife had sex with all
Kogan and there was a video tape of it
going around,
which he basically got a web.
What's the website that gets shut down
because of Gawker fucking folded because
of that lawsuit from Baba or was there a
wait who did the lawsuit?
Baba or hall collected.
Oh,
hulk did it.
So I go down above his place and it's so
weird because Tampa is a fucking eerie
mystical place anyway.
And so they picked me up to go to radio
and we're going down these back roads
through swamps and shit.
And we pass a girl scout camp and um,
and then all of a sudden there's this
long driveway.
It's like a picture,
like you picture,
like the allman brothers must be making
a new album at the end of this,
this fucking read the shack and you go
back there and he'd go in and they're
like,
all right,
this is Bob's place,
and there's a.
there's a midget on a couch in the
waiting room,
and he pissed.
He had pissed the couch,
like they got them drunk on the show,
so drunk that he,
that he pissed themselves in the
studios.
They put them out on the couch.
Oh my God.
He was angry.
He was angry at me and I'm like,
dude,
I have no idea your situation.
I just guide.
I'm next.
And so I walk in and everybody's
drinking pabst blue ribbon.
This is like 7:00
in the morning drinking pabst blue
ribbon and they.
They gave me this joint to smoke,
which I didn't expect it to be that
strong and I,
I was.
I was ripped out of my mind.
So I go into the studio and Bubba has a
12 gauge Israeli handgun,
which is a fucking monster,
a shotgun,
handguns,
something like that.
He pulls out this huge 12 gauges,
like a shotgun.
He said it was a 12 gauge.
Maybe I got it wrong,
but it's huge.
It's huge.
Pulls it out and he's like,
my phone just started googling.
You just say,
Hey Siri.
And then now it's doing.
And um,
so he pulls it out.
He's like,
Nah,
it's cool.
And I'm like,
well then why did your entire staff just
fucking run out of the studio?
And I'm the only one in here and I'm
stoned in 7:00
in the morning.
And so he's waving it around and then he
starts taking calls because he sends,
he sends this van out,
they call it the hand job,
the handicap van,
and they pull up to office buildings and
they entice guys to get in the van with
his hooker who gives them handjobs live
on the radio before they go to work.
And that goes on.
And then a call comes in from a guy
who's about to rob a bank in Michigan,
I guess to show syndicates to Michigan.
And so he's talking this guy out of
robbing a bank.
The guy was for real.
Oh my God.
And uh,
and so,
and this all goes on.
I mean this went on for like two and a
half hours and then all the sudden it
just ended and I walked out.
I felt like a,
I felt like,
what's his name and in Training Day,
uh,
Ethan Hawke,
you know,
after he just tripped and been lead
through this gauntlet of and uh,
and I,
I go back every time.
I love it.
I did it once.
It was fun.
Yeah,
it was a good dude.
The,
the,
the morning radio thing.
Conduct and fucking get you.
Yeah.
I was just thinking,
what was that guy who was an athlete
that shot his driver?
Do you remember that story?
It was a radio guy.
No,
he was a professional athlete and he
pulled out a gun.
Jason Williams does that,
who it is that his name?
Um,
but he had like a,
a limo driver and apparently he pulled
out a gun.
He was like playing with a gun and
accidentally shot and killed his limo
driver.
And it was like,
whoa.
Wow,
look what the fuck?
Jason Williams,
he was a basketball player,
like pulp fiction.
I mean that kind of stuff happens.
Imagine if you got shot by bubble,
the last punch.
Like that's how it ends.
That's how you go to the next stage of
life.
You got accidentally shot by Baba.
Yeah,
dude,
here it is.
Williams.
I was a coward for covering up shooting
of the limo driver.
I mean is he free now?
Spent 26 months in prison and starting
in 2010.
So yeah,
maybe battled with alcoholism.
Well here's the thing.
Incredibly shadow with a 12 gauge
shotgun.
But here's the thing.
Say you kill a guy by accident with a
gun.
You then have a choice to cover it up or
come forward and say,
I did this whole shit.
Now existentially,
is it so wrong to cover it up?
I mean,
you're going to feel bad for the rest of
your life.
You don't really need to be punished.
It's not going to change how his family
feels about it.
Just say somebody else shot him.
That's a DB argument.
A DB argument about ethics.
[inaudible].
You're gonna.
You know you're going to face a of
hate of hate,
right?
No one's going to believe you have you
say it was an accident.
People are gonna.
Absolutely.
Assume that he murdered them.
You know they're going to pursue it that
way.
But on the other hand,
you did fucking kill a guy.
Alright,
what if here's it more innocuous
situation.
You're driving down an alley late at
night and a homeless person walks out in
front of your car and you hit him and he
dies.
You can either just drive away,
wash your car and know that a homeless
guy is no more.
Or you can go get the police and say,
yeah,
I was speeding and I killed a man.
It's like that Johnny cash song.
Isn't it fascinating that when you say
that story,
when you give that scenario that a
homeless person in some way or another
makes it like less fucked up?
No,
I just made in terms of like the family
blaming you for it.
Nobody's going to blame me for
for this,
but,
but even even so,
like it's not as bad as scenario as
hitting a nice person who's got their
shit together.
Well,
it's like if you kill somebody and you
get sued by the family,
depending on it.
Like if you,
if you kill a child and you get sued,
they're not.
You don't have to pay a lot of money,
but if you kill a guy who's supporting
his family,
they,
they'll take everything you got.
So that life in the eyes of the,
the law is
worth more.
How strange is it that we put a monetary
value on actual life itself?
Wow.
It's just such a strange,
strange concept.
Yeah.
Did you see that guy accidentally hit
that Moose with his car now?
Holy Shit,
Jamie.
Pull that video up.
I tweeted it.
This guy's driving down the road
somewhere probably near where they
kicked you out of that club that one
night
made you drive home and drive home and
because of Moose they kicked you out in
great detail.
It was supposed to be a clean gig.
He gets up there,
he starts swearing,
they kicked him out,
they kicked him out.
They had his bags packed.
By the time he gets off stage,
spend the night at the hotel after you
do the Gig and they fucking five hours
drive.
Whoa.
Oh
yeah.
Fucking
crazy,
crazy.
Everybody else has slowed down all these
other people.
It's slowed down a route.
People had seen the Moose and they were
kind of checking it out,
but look,
this guy fucking hits it full on and
since everything flying,
that was like an Olympic big
tumble.
You gotta wonder like,
is that Moose dead now?
I'm surprised the car wasn't trashed
more.
Do you think Moose is dead?
Got Up and walked away.
Oh,
Jesus,
look at that.
That is insane.
Something flew off and he lost her
first.
Fuck right.
You can create an animal.
No,
no,
not like that.
I've hit squirrels and rabbits.
I ran over a raccoon with a big wreck.
Oh Jesus.
It made a big thumping noise under the
car.
I've.
I was grossed out for hours.
Just disturbed.
Boom.
Look at that and that thing goes flying.
That's a huge animal.
Yeah,
they're dangerous in that sense.
Yeah.
No,
I think most are dangerous in the wild.
They can be there.
One of the few deer species that will go
after you.
Yeah,
probably the only one.
I mean maybe an elk would go after you
maybe,
but it's pretty rare like you have to
fuck up to get an elk to attack you.
Yeah.
But if you're too close to a Mama Moose
and she's got her babies in there,
she'll just fuck you up.
Yeah.
There was this kid that got killed.
I want to say it was on a campus
somewhere in Alaska and apparently
someone had been throwing snowballs at
the Moose and they had agitated the
Moose and this guy just walked in wrong
place,
wrong time and the Moose just starts
stomping the shit out of them.
It's really hard to watch.
This guy just gets stomped and stomped
and stomped by this huge animal and
she's rearing up and trying to kill him
and keep stomping on him.
It was horrific.
He just bang,
Bang,
Bang.
Just getting pummeled by these.
I mean this thing is a thousand pounds
and it was because they were throwing
snowballs at him because somebody else
apparently had been agitating the Moose
before this guy got there.
Yeah.
Don't fuck with wildlife,
man.
Had that gun.
Not Gun.
That's a bad one to fuck with.
You know,
you gotta think in their environment.
They're fighting off bears and wolves
and shit.
They just constantly like kicking at
things.
Yeah.
Have you ever been.
Not attacked,
but have you had an animal?
Like had you lined up in the cross hairs
when you're hunting or anything?
Not that I know.
Have you ever had a bear like come out
about a bear?
I've had a bear,
like encounters with bears.
It's weird.
You see them,
but most of the time they just run away.
Yeah,
like A.
I saw a grizzly bear once.
That was a weird one because they have a
different way of looking at you as
opposed to like a regular beer does.
Like a brown bear is a more aggressive
bear in terms of like a,
it's more of a hunter or as black bears,
they're.
They're kind of hunters,
but they're more.
I think they tend to eat more berries
and things along those lines,
but those big ass brown bears,
they have to be like really aggressive
because they're so big.
Like you've got to feed a thousand pound
body or whatever the fuck.
Did they eat meat?
Oh yeah.
What do they eat?
Bears eat a lot of crazy shit,
man.
They'll eat like a beached whale.
They'll camp out on a beach.
Whale eat that fucking thing for is
rotten and disgusting.
Wow.
That's one of the best places that
people find them.
If you want to go bear sighting,
you want to go looking for bears and
spot those big Kodiak bears.
They go to places where bears would find
like a dead whale.
It's almost lover.
Yeah.
It just gets rancid and disgusting and
they're still chewing it up,
but they,
they just have to eat a lot.
What's your,
uh,
what you usually kill something for the
winter to eat.
Right?
Usually an elk who is ever going to go
for this year,
trying to either got one already this
year.
How you did.
Okay.
Is that the one you were carrying?
Um,
when,
when you show me a picture of you
fucking carrying an animal on your back
that you had killed.
I think that was a different one.
Yeah.
You can't carry an elk on your back.
It's way too big.
Yeah.
And silk is like a thousand pounds.
So you cut it up out in the wild.
We'll put it in coolers or something.
I did it at this ranch and they have a
bunch of guys that work at the ranch
that just drag it into a pickup truck
and then you take it to like this cold
storage area and the cold storage area
that break it down.
Yeah.
But what you do is you just cut the
quarters off,
you cut the legs off and you break it
down just like a butcher shop does
freely.
Very.
Um,
it's very weird to see man because it
becomes meat.
Like it starts off an animal and then it
becomes meat as opposed to just seeing
meet,
like once.
It's once it's down and it's,
you know,
you start breaking it down.
It's like a sober,
sober reminder of what meat actually is.
One day they're going to have that lab
to test tube meat that they're working
on,
you know,
that stuff they're doing.
One day they're going to have that.
That's going to be like fully fully
available and there's going to be no
more.
Last night I was talking to the,
uh,
the chef at the laugh factory or the
comedy store,
you know,
the cook back there.
Got It.
Just fucking smiles all the time.
If you want some good energy man,
just go,
go back there and talk to that guy for a
little while.
And I'm like,
so what'd you,
what'd you eat for Christmas would you
make?
And he goes,
I think that Turkey.
I got it up.
I put it in the blender with a little
bit of oil and I flag it and chop it up,
put it on sandwiches with some lessons.
I gave it to my kids.
I'm like,
you blend fucking Turkey meat.
Oh yeah man.
Oh Wow.
I go,
what else do you put in the blender
goes?
Just a little bit of oil.
Maybe it's good.
That sounds like a,
like a chicken salad type thing,
right?
Sounds good.
And you jen,
that would keep after that.
I mean we have so much goddamn Turkey
meat in our fridge.
We got Turkey and ham meat because we
did a couple of different dinners.
Do you do the deep Turkey
now?
I hear that.
The way to get the way to go.
You have a fryer?
Yeah.
You get a,
like a,
you could buy them where you stick the
Turkey.
Uh,
like uh,
like,
like these prongs stick into it.
And then he just sort of lower it into
this,
this Vat for like 20 minutes.
Right.
It's like there's a certain time per
pound of bird.
The bird is,
but it's so good dude,
because he had cook it in peanut oil and
it's just juicy and delicious and crispy
on the outside.
It's my all time favorite way to get a
Turkey.
Yeah.
Oh,
but man,
turkeys,
that's all that factory farm shit is.
As I get older it's freaking me out more
and more.
It freaks me out.
Like buying chickens in the store freaks
me out because of the way you know they
were treated or a hundred percent.
Yeah.
Chickens for the.
That's the big one.
That freaks me out because there's
something like chickens and pigs because
there's something that we do with
chickens where you would.
You can't really do with a cow.
We stack them on top of each other.
Just smoosh them all into these places
where they can't even fucking move.
They just stuck there and then they wait
until they get to a certain size and
then they kill them and it's like,
oof.
What does that mean?
They're like a.
it's like they're a human or not human.
A living organism that's,
that's a battery,
like a power supplies.
They doing it.
The pumping them full of chemicals that
make them get fatter and big.
I don't know.
I know they definitely have used
chemicals on the birds,
I'm sure,
but I don't know if they use on them on
them all the time.
I think the thing that's going on with
those birds is genetic selection.
Yeah.
Where they've just genetically made
certain birds breed with certain birds.
They've established this gene does,
uh,
this,
genetic selection where they're just
like super fucking plump and like
ridiculously big breasts and then they
get those to do that in a very short
period of time.
And then they kill them and they can't
walk because their chests are so big.
They fall over forward.
Yeah.
Well it's like what they did with
bulldogs,
like how the fuck did they make a
bulldog out of a wolf?
Yeah.
How'd they do?
Who knows?
That's why they can't fucking breathe.
Yeah.
Pugs.
So sad.
It's so sad.
That was a wolf and they made,
they made the face smaller because they
wanted it to be cuter.
Acute,
a cute dogs having a fucking asthma
attack his entire life to the house.
Two ranges that you have at the chickens
and I think the only criteria for the
chicken pen is that the chicken has to
be able to turn around in it.
That's it.
That's how big it has to be.
That's so crazy and they're getting shit
on by all the chickens above it their
whole life.
Jesus Christ.
Yeah,
I know.
Is that really how it works?
How many do they stack on top of each
other?
12 for real now.
I don't know,
but a lot.
Say 100.
One went crazy.
One hundred.
One hundred floors and chicken.
That noise
around that is placed on.
Right,
but that's like taking an organism and
using it as cells in a battery.
It really is.
It's like you're taking like these
chickens and you're literally
compartmentalizing it into a specific
size,
like a cell and the Mitochondria of the
cell is this chicken and you've got
hundreds and hundreds of them stacked
into this place and they're like these
living organisms that you've.
You've got locked into these clearly
defined spaces and you're extracting
energy from those chickens you're
taking.
You're extracting food from them.
Yeah,
they're just protein.
They're protein bars.
Yeah,
I mean it is fucking bizarre.
It's a bizarre practice.
Wow.
Even when they're not in cages,
they have them so smushed together,
they can't even fucking move.
Yeah.
It's not fun.
They're not having a good time,
but it's not the only way to raise
chickens.
That's the problem.
I had this guy,
Joel Salitan on the podcast a while
back,
really,
really interesting guy and he runs,
I think it's farm's called polyface.
Polyface farm.
Um,
but he's into.
He's got these things that he does with
these chickens where he puts them in
these giant like chicken houses that are
on wheels and they're like,
roll them into an area and then you just
let them out and they run around at the
end of the day,
they go right back in because that's
where they do.
They go into their nest again,
then you roll them down a hill to
another place and then he has these
pigs,
they takes pigs and he puts a fence
around the pigs,
a movable fence and the pigs just stay
inside that fence and eat whatever the
fuck they want.
And then the next day they moved the
fence and they keep doing it.
So he's got these animals like that,
those chickens in like fucking chickens
don't freak out,
don't freak out when he comes near them.
And this guy is like the prime example
of what you would think of as like an
intelligent,
an intelligent take on ethical farming
practices because that's,
I think when
purdue and a lot of these houses buy
from you,
you have to use their cages in their
feet.
And they're,
it's a franchise like Mcdonald's,
like when you raise,
when you raise livestock for a lot of
these,
you know,
agro,
these,
what'd he call it?
A,
um,
big agro.
It's specific.
They wanted done a certain way.
And if you don't,
they don't buy from you.
Oh,
it's very hard to be independent like
that.
So.
Oh,
that's interesting.
So like if you're a poultry grower,
you,
uh,
like if you want to work for purdue,
you like grow chickens for them.
They don't,
you don't,
you don't think they grow their own
chickens?
Like,
how's that work?
No,
I think you get a contract with them and
they,
they come in and buy your stuff,
but it's all got to be done.
As I say,
Tyson track poultry farming.
Read that out there with Gregory Tyson
foods is one of the leading supporters
of American agriculture,
paying more than $15,
billion annually to independent farmers
supply us with cattle,
hogs and chickens.
We depend on more than 11,000
independent farmers across the country.
This includes more than 4,000
poultry farmers who contact us to raise
chickens.
Now
that's.
That's their website.
It's a.
it's a.
it's all done with a lot of leverage and
you have to do things exactly the way
they want you to.
I think.
I think it was.
Was it food inc or something that did a
documentary about it?
I was watching this documentary today
that was on dig A.
I found it.
It was about this guy who was like this
super bad ass Sushi chef in Japan,
like the best Sushi chef in Tokyo right
now.
I guess they were saying and it's really
interesting like watching this guy
acquire the,
the fish and how it talks about how he
ages to fish.
Like I didn't know that.
Did you know that when they catch tuna
they'll often age them for five days and
then.
Yeah.
And then they age a lot of times at the
fish market before he takes it or he
takes it back and he'll agent another
five days more.
So they might,
you know,
they might keep shit for like two weeks
before you eat it to make it more
tender.
Wow.
He's doing that with tuna.
Yeah.
I was watching this and I was like,
wow,
this is jamie and I were talking about
it.
We were like,
Whoa,
what are they going to do when they kill
all the fish?
Like how long does it take to grow a
fucking tune of that big.
This guy has his tune it right.
And there's sawing it with a giant Paul
Bunyan saw him.
It's a fucking huge to the video is
really cool.
And the people who made the video or
like obvious like serious Sushi dorks.
So they're like super amped up to be
getting some Sushi from this dude,
but all I could think of is like,
how many fish are there?
Like,
how many days can we do?
Like everyday they're knocking them out
of the AH,
the ocean.
Yeah.
Every day.
And there used to be areas where they,
uh,
they restricted how much fishing went on
and now it's like,
it's a free for all.
Well,
under Donald Trump we're going to fix
all this.
Thank God I've been,
I've been pulled for trump's.
I was a little kid.
Just the concept of trump.
I've always been really into.
I like when I remember studying the
constitution as a kid and thinking this
is fucking bullshit.
We need a guy who's got some balls,
who's going to come in and get around
all this fucking liberal bullshit.
I'm just kidding.
I think of the apocalypse is upon us.
I really think it's over.
I mean,
he hasn't even taken office yet and he's
already alienated China.
He thinks he's friends.
The best part is he thinks he's friends
with Russia.
That's like,
that's like hanging out with the school
bully.
And thinking you're safe until one day
you say something that bully doesn't
like any fucking cracks in the face and
you realize he's just a broken child.
How much you know way more about this
than I do because I've spent the
majority of my adult life ignoring
almost everything about how the system
works and you win.
But how much power does he really have
it president?
Yeah.
How much power does he really have in
terms of decisions to be made for things
like,
like any sort of a military action?
Well,
what you've already seen is,
but by taking a phone call from Taiwan,
a simple act that he didn't think twice
about that opened up the floodgates to
China saying that we are recognizing
Taiwan is an independent state,
which has been a.
there's been a one,
a one China policy going back to Nixon,
which basically ensured that it put a
clamp down on the cold war and it said,
we're not going to keep.
We're not going to keep building up
against each other.
And a part of that is we're going to
live by certain doctrines like the one
China policy and when he takes a call
from Taiwan,
something as simple as that.
All of a sudden,
China is talking about a nuclear
buildup.
It's that simple.
It's not about what laws he enacts,
it's about him as a spokesman for our
country.
And what messages he sends out.
I mean,
it's like Obama did with Israel.
I don't know what.
I don't know why,
but in his 11th hour he is soured
relations with Israel to the point
where,
you know,
um,
even though he's a lame duck president
on his way out,
it's,
it was a destructive thing.
He did.
I don't just,
I don't know if I disagree with it.
What did he do?
Well,
the UN had a resolution.
I was saying that the,
um,
Israel has new developments in the,
in the West Bank and which are illegal
according to UN previously UN
resolutions.
And so,
uh,
I dunno what they're calling it,
but it's illegal what they've done.
And,
and the US signed,
they signed onto it.
So they,
they set up these settlements in
Palestinian territories,
what it is,
well the disputed Palestinian territory
and they just decided to start building
their,
they've been doing,
they've been building there for years
and they put it,
they put up like 600 homes,
but they're planning on putting up 5,000
in an area that,
you know,
pieces the,
the,
there is no peace over there.
But what's keeping it from being an all
out war is that area that is,
that is supposed to be kept neutral for
now or,
and now they're building on it.
Why would someone want to build?
Are they running out of land?
They can't build other places?
No,
they,
they don't recognize uh,
the Palestinians.
And so they don't,
they see that that's all their land
still.
And so they,
they won't stop.
They will continue building and pushing
out.
I mean the tide is turned on Israel from
what I can tell.
And I don't follow Israel very closely
at all except for when I hear people
yelling about it at parties that I met
because I have friends that are like
hardcore Zionists and I have friends
that are hardcore anti Zionist and I,
they're totally rational people and they
can joke around about talking about
fucking your mother and Blah,
Blah Blah.
But as soon as Israel comes up,
shit gets real.
And they talk,
you know?
Um,
I think the tide is turned.
There's a lot more people that are
seeing Israel as a terrorist state.
Whoa.
Wow.
They're very aggressive net and yahoo is
just a fucking.
He's a bowl.
What's the right resolution?
What's the right solution?
Because what,
how much is in dispute?
Like how much territory?
I don't know.
That seems like a small place doesn't.
It seemed very small.
Isn't Israel like the size of
Connecticut or some shit like that.
Like how big is it?
I don't think it's very big,
but it's where it's located.
So let's find out how big is Israel?
Just a hotly charged subject?
Yeah,
it is.
It's one of the most charged subjects
and all of the Holocaust survivors
basically.
Yeah.
And you're talking about people that are
right next to each other with opposing
ideologies and various reasons for being
righteous or villain and Iran.
Iran looking at Israel erected that.
I said it right,
right.
Is it Iran?
Iran.
Yeah.
I was saying that they don't have a
right to exist and that they're gonna
throw a nuclear bomb over there.
What did you see?
That was the guy from Pakistan who
wasn't Jamie that,
uh,
got duped by a fake news story.
Jamie Masada.
No,
not that guy by the.
Oh yeah,
I did see that in the guy got.
He got duped by fake news story and you
said some inflammatory shit about
causing a war and all of a sudden it's
like,
Whoa,
you guys got got all up in arms about a
fake story.
Yeah.
Like,
what in the fuck is going on?
What do you think was the first fake
news story?
Because you go back to,
you know,
I'm thinking that it was an old fake
news story was a
fake news stories.
And I think probably been around for a
long time.
Well the Bible was a giant fake news,
dare you.
They did their best.
They did their best to remember the
stories.
Find a good map.
I think part of the provinces,
the arguments over the maps and.
Oh I see.
Right,
right,
right.
This was the one I have.
Does it say like,
I just want to know,
like I'm too stupid to know what that
is.
So why don't you ask,
ask Google compared to a state like,
because I think there was a,
there's a simple comparison.
I just don't remember what it is.
It's like Connecticut or something like
that.
Or maybe Massachusetts size comparison
map Israel in USA anyway.
What were we just telling you with a
size comparison and fake news?
Yeah,
very good.
New Jersey.
Okay.
Yeah.
So it's basically the size of New Jersey
and New Jersey is building a lot of
homes.
It looks a little bit bigger than New
Jersey.
But look at that.
It barely fits in Lake Michigan.
You can stick Israel in Lake Michigan.
What the fuck?
How big is Lake Michigan?
Holy Shit.
Yeah.
Isn't that insane?
I know a giant ocean of water that you
can surf on Lake Michigan.
What's the one that's near Chicago?
Lake Michigan.
Um,
I stayed at girl and when she was a kid
her,
you dated her when she was a kid?
No,
dude,
a story she told when she was a dare you
when she was a kid,
she was in a,
uh,
a storm on Lake Michigan where they had
to turn into the,
into the waves,
like over and over and over again all
night.
They were not safe like they were in
danger,
being capsized by the waves on a fucking
lake.
It's amazing.
And I think it was her stepdad.
I forgot who,
who's steering the boat,
but was just wrecked by the end of the
day.
Like his arms were falling off.
Like he,
he barely could use his arms because he,
like,
he had to keep turning the boat all
night long.
They had to strap everyone down to the
boat on a,
on a fucking lake.
Yeah.
On a lake.
Not the ocean.
Yeah.
I don't care where you put a boat in,
you got what you got.
Whatever's coming to you.
Is that Lake Michigan?
Oh my God.
Look at the waves by foot waves on Lake
Michigan.
It says 25 foot waves on land.
That's so crazy.
Well,
let's all that wind that comes in.
It's just an immense puddle.
Yeah.
That used to be a fucking glacier
glaciers that are in some places as high
as two miles high and they became all
that stuff.
It's nuts.
Mad.
I have a buddy of mine lives,
uh,
in Wisconsin,
in the driftless area.
It's like the area where the,
uh,
glaciers didn't hit.
It's really kind of cool because it's
all these hills and crazy,
like a beautiful typography.
The rest of the place,
like a,
an eraser came along.
It just flattened that motherfucker out
just from the weight of the glacier is
pushing down on the land,
the glacier just pushing for and
crushing everything in its path.
Literally like God's eraser.
And that's when the wind whips up
because there's nothing stopping that
wind.
Nothing.
I mean,
I remember driving through,
I think it was North Dakota,
it was North Dakota and I was driving
from I think Iowa or Nebraska and North
Dakota is doing a college gig and the
Gig was at night and it was like a good
four hour drive and they told me,
look,
this is a single lane road.
The only,
it's the only way there and it's flat as
shit and it's windy out so be careful.
So I'm in my rent a car and a snow snow
starts as I'm and the snow
is just going just vertically across the
road and it starts to build up.
It starts to build up the snow on the
road and all of a sudden I'm like
halfway there and it's fucking white out
conditions.
All I can see is the light,
the snow in my headlights ahead of me.
And for a long time I was just looking
at that,
looking at the line on the road and
following that line disappeared.
Oh Shit.
And I fucking freak out.
And so I just pull what I think is to
the side of the road because I don't
know where I'm driving and I wait and
all of a sudden I see headlights coming
from behind me,
fucking 18 wheeler barreling down,
hopefully hope and he sees me.
He passes me and I immediately get
behind him and I rode that motherfucker
for two hours to get to the school
shaking,
fucking shaken.
And I got to the Gig and it was like
these kids,
it was like fucking Jesus Christ has
shown up in their town.
They were like,
this is our only entertainment all year.
And so we did a.
We did a show in so many people came
that they added a second shell,
but half the kids stayed for the second
show.
So it was definitely one of those year
material got told that night.
Joe Rogan,
I guarantee you that your is Don Gavin,
Steve Sweeney.
Todd Parker's fucking ripping every joke
out of my ass.
I can think of that second step.
They paid me devil hilarious.
And I couldn't get out of there for two
days afterwards.
We were,
yeah.
Oh my God,
There was so much uncertainty in the
winters in Boston.
There was like you weren't certain if
you were going to get home.
Yeah.
Like I think that's right.
I think that's important for people to
understand that don't live in a place
like that.
Like if you got hit with a big January
snow storm and it hit while you were at
work,
if you've got to work,
do you.
First of all,
there'd be warnings everywhere.
They'd be worn.
They'd cancel school before the first
fucking drop up.
Snow fell right there.
Don't freak out about like big blizzard.
But if a big one hit and you fucked up
and you weren't paying attention,
you could get stuck wherever the fuck
you are.
Yeah.
Highways just stopped for days.
Yep.
It takes forever for them to chew all
that snow way and if it stays cold in
Boston it will stay cold for a long
fucking time.
We remember those black piles of ice ice
that had just gotten road grime and
exhaust on it,
but it was too cold for it to melt,
so we just push that shit to the side.
It would narrow the fucking highway.
Yeah,
right.
Yeah.
They'd get out there with those,
uh,
those trucks throwing the salt and the
sand down.
I mean they be out there before the snow
had started.
They were laying down.
Salt
did.
That was why if you've got an old car,
you wanted to get a California car where
they didn't,
they didn't use salt on the.
If you've got an old car in Boston,
the fucking fenders were all rotted out.
Everything rotted it out because of all
that salt.
And they constantly re up the,
uh,
the highways.
Oh yeah,
that's right.
It's just chewing through it.
But isn't that kind of the only way to
ensure that shit's gonna Melt?
You kinda have to salt.
Yup.
Salt it and say.
I think they sand it more than they salt
it now.
They probably are,
you know where they get this?
They get the salt from like on these
giant fucking barges from South America.
Salt wars,
like the old days.
Is that right?
No,
but imagine they used to go to war for
salt.
How you mean like way,
way back salt.
It's amazing that we give it away for
free because if you really think of what
it was worth like five,
600 years ago,
it was incredibly valuable.
Right?
Why?
Because food was so bland.
No To preserve food.
Uh,
they didn't have refrigeration,
so like their meat,
if you cover the outside of it with
salt,
the bacteria can eat the meat and it
slows the decaying process.
You could dry things out and salt them
and as a way to preserve food,
like an important way to preserve food.
I think,
you know,
I don't know how long you get to have a
piece of meat and just cover it with
salt and leave it laying around at room
temperature,
but I think it's a lot more than it
would if you didn't have the salt.
And I think,
uh,
it's one of the reasons why it was.
I mean it was one of the most valuable
things in the world at one point in
time,
which is crazy now when you think about
it.
Yeah.
And everything you ate must've had salty
a shit.
People must just get used to that.
Taste is salt.
Do you remember when everybody was
thinking that salt causes high blood
pressure and then it doesn't?
Oh No,
it's a mineral.
Yeah.
I mean it's like you're not supposed to
have too much of it,
but like that's not what's wrong.
Like what else is going on?
And then there was this study that came
out recently,
a paper that came out recently that was
pointing to the sugar industry,
accepting bribes or giving bribes to
scientists in the 1950.
Just do that to,
to push the blame away from sugar and
saturated fat.
The amount of heart disease that it
causes,
no sugar is.
It has become the new salt.
It's become the new cholesterol.
It's become the new everything.
It's everybody's saying is fear.
Yeah.
It's everybody's fear now.
Wha Wha.
How do salt and sugar prevent microbial
spoilage says they use sugar and salt.
That's the name way to Cerner to.
Hmm.
Interesting.
Well,
it tastes better that way probably.
Yeah.
Okay,
so it says protection of foods from
microbial spoilage,
using salt,
usually sodium chloride or sugar.
Usually sucrose has ancient roots and is
often referred to assaulting salt.
Curing corning or sugar curing pieces of
rock salt used for curing are sometimes
called corns,
hence the name.
Corned beef was wonder why they call it
the corned.
No Shit.
That's what it does.
Fascinating.
Okay.
Where's it shut?
I'm sorry.
What does it say?
Where it goes several ways here.
Oh,
okay.
There's several ways in which salt and
sugar inhibit microbial growth.
Most notable is simple osmosis or
dehydration,
salt or sugar,
whether in solid or equias form.
Attempts to reach equilibrium with the
salt or sugar content of the food
product with which it is in contact.
This has the effect of drawing available
water from within the food to the
outside and inserting salt or sugar
molecules into the food interior.
The result is a reduction of the so
called water activity measure of unbound
free water molecules in the food that is
necessary for microbial survival and
growth.
That is fucking fast.
Yeah,
it is.
I never thought about how because I was
think about when I put salt on my food.
It seems like,
especially with seesaw where they would
sit there so big,
the particles that you don't just get
like that,
it doesn't spread,
but they would eat the food,
like say you put it in your mashed
potatoes,
right?
It spreads really evenly throughout the
mashed potatoes that it realizes all
that chemical reactions going on between
all the cells in the potatoes and the
salt.
It's kind.
It's flowing back and forth.
Yeah.
I mean think about how difficult it must
have been to get fresh food to a city in
1700.
Throwing salt on everything and packing
things in salt and taking them down the
road on the back of wagons,
being pulled by horses
with Ms Dot added control mosquitoes and
flies on everything that was for so
long.
How people lived for so long.
Open wagons,
there was no like air tight
compartments.
No,
I mean I bet kings that's a pretty dope
compartments.
Yeah.
Like in game of thrones,
those like sitting there like just chill
and how long is this ride?
The horses are pulling the wagon along
that fan themselves and shit that hadn't
happened to.
It was like the real pimps,
like if you were a dude,
you could pick a checkup and take her to
the back of the the carriage.
She'd be like,
Oh my God.
You have your own character?
Yeah.
Baby carriage.
And you have hepatitis this.
Did they have hepatitis back then?
Was Him the first VD came into play?
Well,
syphilis was probably the first one I
read about it in the Bible.
Really?
Yeah.
Syphilis was all over the place.
I think,
uh,
you know,
they call it.
I think they call it syphilis.
Really,
didn't I?
I'm looking at the clap,
I think.
I think syphilis is the clap.
Like how do you think that?
Do you think that happens in animals?
Do you think animals give each other.
Okay.
I haven't thought about that.
My friends got a herpes blister,
but it busts
out like every couple months.
She just showed me this morning,
come on,
give me a kiss.
Things the size of a dime.
Was it on her lip?
Yeah,
I used to get those.
It's such a shame because she's
beautiful.
She changed her diet.
Is that Koalas have chlamydia or do they
are known for having.
What do you.
Why do you say it?
Looking at me like it doesn't count if
it's a stuffed animal.
No,
no.
They all have it,
but it's like a.
it's a thing I thought I heard like they
spread stds.
Well,
it looks good.
Article Says Koala,
chlamydia,
the std threatening and Australian icon.
Didn't aids come from a monkey or is
that A.
is that a myth that man,
I wish I could remember exactly how to
answer this because I listened to a
radio lab podcast called patient zero,
I think it was.
That was all about this.
They were trying to figure out who was
the first person that contracted the HIV
virus and it did have something to do
with someone who was tending to meet
that he had killed of a chimpanzee and
maybe perhaps had an open cut.
Yeah.
That was one of the speculations,
which of course turned into somebody
fucked up monkey.
That's just the American translation of
facts.
It's fucking natural one with people.
Awesome dude.
Fuck the monkey.
How else do you get an std?
From a monkey,
you gotta fucking see that Chappelle
bit.
Yeah.
Oh my gosh.
Chappelle had one of the funniest bits
of all time.
He goes,
do you know how hard it would be to fuck
a monkey?
Once he said it,
I was like,
I never even thought of that.
Imagine the battle right there.
You would have to go through to actually
fuck a monkey.
Yeah.
How do you just think it's a given?
Like,
you know,
hey,
I'm going to have some dry days.
I'll go,
fuck a monkey,
dude.
Not so easy.
Yeah.
I've.
I do a bit of my act.
That's true about my cat biting me in
the hand and me getting pissed at him.
I'm like,
what the fuck dude?
And he's looking at me and his ears are
pulled back.
Like that's a cat is.
That's a fucking powerful little animal,
but it's nothing compared to a monkey.
Monkeys throw themselves through the
air.
Oh yeah.
Little tiny body swings itself to the or
catches itself,
throws his to the lab.
They can do ridiculous shit with their
bodies and you got to think they get a
hold of you.
If that thing bites your face,
if it gets a hold of your neck,
it might look a little,
you know,
especially if it's a champ,
like oh,
like a little baby champ we had on the
set of news radio and it was like a two
year old chimp and this thing slapped me
in my back.
Like dude,
it Kinda like when you let them climb
on,
you kind of does whatever he wants
because he's a baby.
He wasn't trying to hurt me,
but first of all he felt like he was
made out of corrugated,
would just like,
it was like a wooden animal,
like his.
He might've been like this,
like you could kind
of pick them up and carry him,
but he felt like nothing,
like a person feels like nothing.
It was just solid muscle and he just
slapped me on the back and all I could
think of is like a big one of these
appeal,
full grown one of these things and they
get a great shit around people.
When we were down in A.
we're in South Africa and Cape Town and
we were taking a walk down to the Cape
of good,
no Cape of whatever at the tip,
the very tip of South Africa and is a
field that you walked through with the
path and the deranged is came up to us
and my son was about maybe about three
years old and they said to us,
yeah,
you're gonna.
You're gonna.
Want to hold him the whole time?
And we're like,
why?
They're like chimps.
Chimps will take them.
They'll just come down and grab them.
Yeah.
They'll steal your kid and he.
That's real.
Can you imagine that?
You go on a trip with your kid,
he come back with no kid and you watched
your kid get taken.
Fuck,
fuck.
Where's your son?
Baboons to there.
Another animal will do the same thing.
Yeah.
They'll go after it.
You know what I might be thinking of
baboons.
Oh,
that makes more.
I think it was bare bones.
It makes more sense,
but there have been stories of chimps
doing it too.
Yeah.
Look,
man.
Well,
who's the woman?
I got a face bitten off by a chance of
people,
but the one woman who was a most
recently,
her friend had this pet chimp and she
was given xanax and wine and maybe
sucking stuff.
Why did he xanax?
If if she's sucking his Dick,
what the hell's he need?
Could you imagine being so fucking crazy
then?
Not only do you have a 200 pound ship
living with Xanax?
Do you think she gave it the Xanax so
that he'd be more pliable?
I think she was just banging this
monkey.
I think she live with this monkey and
she was banging it.
I really,
really think that because I shouldn't
say monkey.
It's a champ.
Whatever.
She was living with this chimp and
banging it and so her friend came over.
There was a chip.
Chip used to dress up.
That's inhuman.
He was fucking late.
Yep.
That was the lady.
No Way.
That was his girlfriend man.
Who Do you think initiated?
The first time she got a pet chimp.
She raised it.
It's a boy.
It's got a dick.
She's like,
look,
this is my new body guard,
and she's got this chip and she has a
couple of glasses of red wine that
shipped,
wants a fucker.
He's,
she's like,
who?
Who's gonna know,
she lets that chimp fucker a couple
times and then he keeps swinging dick or
way and that's his girlfriend now and
this lady came over and she interrupted
his fun time.
She was,
she was cock blocking and he didn't take
too kindly to it.
So he did chimps shit to her.
Just ripped her apart.
Yeah.
Tour faceoff.
They bite your fingers off.
He's huge.
He was 200 pounds.
Gets big.
Overfed chimpanzee.
Super ridiculous.
Ungodly strong.
No foreplay.
Oh,
he wanted to fuck you got fucked.
Get fucked.
You get out of the shower.
Naked bubble is going to fuck you.
You have your period.
Forget it.
Try to keep that chip off eye.
You're menstruating.
A police officer who responded to the
scene of the attack shot and killed
travis when he clawed,
opened the cops cruiser door and flashed
his bloody teeth.
Oh my God,
Dude.
He opened the fucking door.
The cop was shooting it as it was
pulling the door open,
flashing it's bloody teeth looking at,
tear him apart to holy fuck,
holy fuck.
Imagine if that was you and you didn't
have a gun and you weren't a cop.
He just pulled up and you saw some chimp
tearing apart a lady and you're like,
what the fuck?
And the chimp just scores running
towards you and decides he's going to
open up your fucking door now.
And he's flashing his bloody teeth after
just ate some lady's face.
Fuck man.
Where was this?
I love this part.
Investigators later speculated that a
dose of Xanax caused the chimp to go
preserve a look at that face.
Looks like now.
Oh my God.
Her face transplant was being rejected.
Oh my gosh.
Surgery.
Does that mean like she's going out to
meet guys and she's being rejected?
No,
her body rejects face transplants.
Any kind of transplants are notoriously
tricky.
Apparently.
Poor Lady.
God said,
wait,
where's it say that she was fucking him?
Um,
that's mine part.
I added the.
Oh,
oh,
I thought you were serious.
I don't know what they're doing.
I mean,
it's totally plausible,
it's completely plausible,
but I absolutely made it up for regarded
as her son.
Okay.
Maybe she didn't fuck it.
Do you think a woman could get pregnant
from a monkey?
Depends on the woman.
Depends on the monkey.
Yeah.
Some super smart monkey and really
stupid person who knows.
Yeah.
No,
there's some hybrids,
right?
That uh,
that wind up being viable.
That's all like new species get
developed sometimes,
but most of the time it doesn't like a
lagger,
but they can't make babies.
You know,
they can,
you can make a baby lion and a tiger can
breed and make a baby,
but that baby can make babies.
So I wonder man,
like what was it,
if you believe in evolution,
of course.
What was it in history like?
What was it like when there was a bunch
of different species of humans because
they think there's a bunch now they've
documented how many have documented now
because they keep finding new ones.
Like they found some new one in Russia
recently.
Oh,
by the way,
all the people that,
uh,
that tweeted at me and sent me messages
that have fucked up and said,
facility Lowman Chenko is Russian.
He's actually from the Ukraine.
I apologize.
I am a retarded American.
Who?
Anybody who's over there in that spot
who talks like that?
I go,
that's how the Russian dude.
Yeah,
but
that I understand that people would
think.
Doesn't that give you an out?
No,
because I had a buddy of mine growing up
who's Ukrainian.
He always regarded himself as Ukrainian.
He never thought of himself as Russian.
So I get it.
I get it.
It's like if we were America,
North America,
Canada,
and in Mexico,
we're all just one thing.
Oh,
you're from that spot.
No,
no,
no.
I'm from America,
motherfucker.
Yeah,
I'm from this spot,
bitch.
Well,
as far as the cave men go.
Yeah.
They didn't used to think that
neanderthal man and sapient's existed at
the same time.
Like when you look at a timeline of cave
[inaudible],
they make it seem like one ended in the,
one just fucking started,
like in a year,
you know,
3000 bc all sudden they just changed
3000 BC,
20,000
BC.
How?
I think it was a lot more than that.
I think when they're talking about
people living alongside Neanderthal,
I think they're talking about like 40 or
50,000
years ago.
Yeah.
So there was,
like you said,
they coexisted and they say that the
fights,
because neanderthal man was a fucking
beast.
Totally different kind of person.
Totally different than sap and came
along and sapient was much smarter and
that's the only way he was the one that
survived over neanderthal would show me
that again,
they were able to,
they were able to out hunting out kill
or we fucked them all and then we
interbreed with them.
That probably might have happened to
you.
What does it say,
Jamie?
It says a guy is trying to make a hybrid
between a chimp.
Nineteen,
24.
Whoa.
Let me guess.
German,
a wild group of 13 female chimpanzees to
bring back to primary research facility.
It's a sucky me.
The female chimpanzees were repeatedly
injected with human male sperm,
but none became pregnant.
It was rumored that Ivonne have used his
own sperm or that of his son,
but few people believe on.
Can we come downstairs for a minute?
Well,
where else is he going to get come?
You try to go for a hard to get come.
He tried to get a female volunteers to
get injected with a male chimpanzees and
how many did it rumored that it only
happened once,
but apparently he got arrested and sent
away to work in a veterinary station and
stand and died two years later.
But note,
no pregnancy actually happened,
but maybe he actually did do it.
Who knows?
The rumor was the pregnancy actually did
happen.
Did Not deny.
There's a rumor that he did actually
inject a woman with sperm.
This story,
the story of this was like the beginning
of like some crazy superhero x men type.
Yeah,
we'll have some new,
some new.
Uh,
instead of Wolverine,
some man champ,
some hybrid like wolverine looked like
he was kind of a man champ.
Hybrid.
Real Wolverine.
Like from the comic books,
he was hairy looking half human looking
person.
Well,
the Nazis did all kinds of shit like
that.
Yeah.
Taking heads off one animal and trying
to put them on other
animals.
But how many find this out,
Jamie?
Find out when did human beings and the
endo talls coexist.
How long ago was that?
Or how about this?
How long ago did neanderthals go
extinct?
Because that's what would tell us a lot.
If you had to guess,
what are you going to get Craig?
I'd say yeah.
20,000
sounds bonus.
Say for.
Oh,
I was right.
Neanderthals went extinct in Europe
about 40,000
years ago.
Giving them millennia to coexist with
modern humans culturally and sexually.
New findings suggest the research also
suggests that modern humans did not
cause neanderthals to rapidly go
extinct.
As some researchers have previously
suggested they killed the.
Yeah.
There was a lot of people that did.
There was one guy that had a crazy
fucking theory.
That's probably absolutely not true,
but his theory was that they didn't look
like people.
His theory,
we don't know what their soft tissue
looked like.
So his tea,
he had this idea of a really intelligent
apelike creature because he compared
what do you remember?
That whole guy,
his whole thing,
he made like an animated video of what
it looked like.
It was terrifying,
like gorilla looking thing.
It's like heavily muscled because they
were only like five,
two or five three,
but they were like 205 pounds with giant
boulders,
sized bones in their body.
They had way different bone structure
than we do.
And they were supposed to be like
freakishly strong.
Yeah.
But I think they were sorta like on all
fours and standing upright,
but then really sapiens stood upright.
Is that true?
I think so.
I know there was a difference in the way
they moved that uh,
the sapiens were faster but they weren't
as strong.
So if they got into any kind of a
battle,
they were fucking dead.
Right?
Hmm.
That's interesting.
Yes.
I read sapiens.
Yeah.
This is what they absolutely think that
they looked like the neanderthals looked
like,
but there was a guy had some crazy
alternative theory that was probably
horseshit that I want to focus on.
Probably totally fake,
but it was like his theories,
like what if she would have neanderthal,
didn't look anything like us.
Like what if deanna tall like had
gorilla like skin and was just just
hooking scary looking fanged up,
you know,
jacked humanoid kind of ape.
Yeah.
Who knows,
man.
There was definitely like a bunch of
different kinds of people though.
They keep
did more,
more and more evidence of new teeth and
shit.
Right.
But the evolution was so slow.
Like we think about things.
The way evolution happens for us today
is technological.
So we see shit happened from decade to
decade.
Oh yeah.
The end.
It's all profile was super predator.
So in this video,
when you're looking at the end,
it's all,
he's got like gorilla look
and scan or these big crazy eyes and
it's a terrifying looking beast as
opposed to the way we always project
them and he bases it on like the shape
of their head and like what,
what a gorilla's head longer jaw mean.
It's crazy like you.
Cause we don't know what their soft
tissue looks like,
but if you give them a gorilla nose
instead of a human nose,
they look way fucking scarier.
And his argument was like,
we have no idea what their nose look
like.
Why are we giving them a human nose?
I wonder if that flies.
I wonder if anthropologists are getting
angry right now.
There were some vicious motherfucker.
Look at the way that thing looked,
if that's what it looked like.
Like what the fuck?
I know he looks up right now though.
I guess they were.
They were partly on all fours.
Ended up right.
I think they were upright.
I think I'm pretty sure neanderthals
were completely upright.
Oh No.
Yeah.
Because they were a type of human.
They just weren't Homo Sapiens,
right?
Yeah.
So I'm so stupid to have these
conversations.
I'm so stupid because I read an entire
book about sapiens and this whole
transformation and I just.
The problem is I read when I go to sleep
and I don't.
I'm so fucking tired.
Right.
It all goes through me the next night.
I can't even find out.
I can't even find where I left off on
the book is in reading at night,
like the best way to fucking fall
asleep.
Oh yeah.
It makes you go to sleep so much easier.
Yeah.
Like something about reading.
I'm just conk dude.
My wife opens up our book at night every
night and she,
she does not get to the second page and
she's sitting upright and I can hear her
breathing change and she's asleep.
Wow.
I can't.
I take a sleeping pill every night.
Take Asleep.
Taking a Lunesta and the side effects.
I think a loss of memory.
I think that's what it is.
I'm taking the sleep pill and then I'm
reading and uh,
nothing sticks.
But otherwise I can't sleep.
My mother and brothers,
same way.
We cannot sleep,
we just our minds fucking race and I'll
lay there for hours and nothing
happened.
So I,
I'd rather be a little groggy in the
morning then then be exhausted in five.
Have you tried any kind of meditation or
anything to calm your mind for you when
you started meditating?
But I've,
I only started meditating like two years
ago and I've been taking the sleeping
pills for probably like four,
so I should try to get off of him.
It's stupid,
but I think if you get off those things,
that's where it gets hairy.
Really?
Yeah.
So if you start going crazy,
call me up so I know,
I'll know.
Just say just say,
Hey,
I tried going off these fucking sleeping
pills.
I'm like okay,
Gotcha.
Failure.
No,
I need you to do my 10:20
spot at the laugh factory tonight.
I think
when you get off those things like
sleeping pills,
they have a real bizarre reaction some
people have to them or they'll do things
and wake up in the middle of doing them,
driving down the highway in a shootout
with the cops.
Like that kind of Shit,
like you wake up in the middle of an act
going,
what the fuck am I saying?
Why you're on sleeping while you're on
certain
sleeping pills.
He,
Ambien is crazy.
Like I ran out and I took a friend's
ambien recently and I had the most
insane dreams.
Oh,
I've heard.
I'm terrified of that stuff.
Yeah,
I know a lot of people who love that
stuff.
I Dunno why Ambien is prescribed.
It's the same thing with opioids.
It's like,
why are they still prescribing this shit
when it's so addictive and so dangerous?
Because people want to be able to make
their own choices.
You know?
And if you could go to a doctor,
if you're informed correctly and you go
to a doctor and you go,
look,
I don't give a fuck what they say.
I want a fucking ambient.
I know it's not good for you.
I know it's bad for my sleep.
I don't give a fuck.
I need to go to sleep.
If you're a grown adult,
I feel you should be able to make that
decision.
You can.
How come you can make that decision?
And drank a fucking bottle of,
uh,
of um,
Ron White's tequila a night if you so
choose to.
Why can't you decide to take an ambient?
It's true.
Is it,
is it really worse than getting hammered
and everybody gets hammered and there's
a lot of people getting hammered.
Well,
it just seems like with all the options,
like I know with Lunesta I don't have
these side effects.
Oh really?
Yeah.
I mean,
no,
it's,
there's no side effects with luminess.
I'm not a paid spokesman for Lunesta by
the way,
but I just found that I did take ambien
and it was crazy.
It was like tripping.
So lunesta does it for you.
Lunesta works.
Joe Lunesta works for me.
Have you ever done anything like
Melatonin or have you tried like a
Melatonin?
Melatonin works.
It's good,
does it?
Yeah.
Yeah,
yeah.
Why don't you just try that then?
Since it's a natural migration,
we like to get addicted to things.
I put the booze.
So now I drink.
And what is this shit you gave me?
Caveman coffee,
man.
It's got a nice little kick.
It's got a hell of a kick.
It's got a hell of a kick to it is.
It's kind of mainly because it doesn't
taste that good.
Right,
right.
Well,
it's like black coffee.
Yeah,
exactly.
Like when I say it doesn't taste that
good.
I mean it doesn't taste like a Caramel
Macchiato,
you know?
That's,
that tastes good.
That's what every slurpee like this is
delicious,
but it's full of sugar.
This tastes like a.
we're calling it like a Guinness.
Guinness have coffee.
It's got this weird sort of acquired
taste for a little fuzziness to it,
which is nice.
Nitrogenated.
I don't know why.
I don't know if it works.
More gifts.
You're more fucked up.
I don't know,
but it's got 270 milligrams caffeine.
Yeah.
I'm a caffeine freak.
I drink a lot of caffeine.
Yeah,
but that one's manageable.
Does caffeine never really derails your
judgment to manageable addiction?
If he got to like a legit addiction,
caffeine is not a bad one.
Yeah.
That's,
that's one you can kind of.
You could skate by with that one.
Cigarettes is going to get.
Yeah.
That's the one that's gonna get you
cigarettes.
Probably the worst thing you can be
addicted to then heroin,
it seems like pills might be worse than
cigarettes because you can make rational
decisions when you're on cigarettes.
The problem is though,
the health consequences of cigarettes or
almost
inescapable.
We've just made an irrational decision
if you're lighting a cigarette.
Yeah,
so it's got you in a point of addiction
where you are literally killing yourself
slowly.
It's kind of amazing that it's still
around.
It's amazing really.
But again,
I'm 100 percent in favor of people doing
whatever the fuck they want to do.
If you were informed and you go,
I don't give a shit,
I want a fucking cigarette,
you should be able to do it.
So by that hand,
if you could do that with booze,
if you could do that.
When we.
I think freedom is best.
It's best to have people figure it out
on their own.
It's best to decide for people what they
can and can't do.
Good.
I think it's the same with raising a
kid.
You know,
I try to give my kids a lot of free
freedom,
you know?
I informed them,
I reign them in,
I try to shepherd them,
but I don't ride them,
you know,
and when they make mistakes I don't,
I don't overly punish,
I just try to.
I tell them I'm disappointed and that
means a lot to them,
but I think that,
you know,
the,
this year your kids are,
they need to internalize responsibility
and the earlier they do it the better
because then the process of
internalizing responsibility should
start as in in whatever ways you can
parcel it out from a young age.
That's how you got to do it because by
the time they move out,
you know,
it's like you're not going to be there
to make these decisions for them.
Yeah.
The,
the,
the task of raising human is probably
one of the most important things.
One of the most impossible to correct.
Once you fucked it up and it's put in
the hands of everybody who is most
likely raised incorrectly themselves.
Well,
the hope is,
is more therapy than there was today.
There's more literature,
there's more studies and I do think
we're more informed about what we do.
I think we're more vigilant about it.
I think men,
the fact that I just said that to
another man that wouldn't have happened
25 years ago,
no guy would talk about parenting in any
deep way to another man.
No,
it was kinda almost gay.
Yeah,
it was.
It was not,
it was not your role to do that.
And now pay parents.
It's a partnership,
the mother and the father because the
worst thing,
and I know a couple that's like this
where they're never on the same page and
their kids are all fucked up and neither
one of them is a bad parent.
They're just doing it in opposite ways,
ways.
What's the.
He's very like,
you know,
uh,
checked out in some ways,
but like in the way,
not in a healthy way,
I describe the hands off is still caring
and controlling and supporting his is a
little bit more,
a little bit more like I can't handle
this.
Hers is,
she's super eight type personality and
she's trying to drive the kids to be,
you know,
the best,
their best potential,
which is good.
A little bit of that is good.
And little bit of what he's doing is
good,
but they're both polar opposites and not
really their strategies
will either.
But I,
I really think that the,
the main thing is that your kids can't
feel like they're getting two different
messages at the same time.
Time for Mommy and daddy can't feel like
they're being smothered either.
Right?
You know,
one of the things about kids that you
find out real early,
if you tell them not to do something,
that's what they want to do.
They don't want you telling them what to
do because they're little people.
Even though they might be five or six,
there's still little people and people
don't like you telling them what to do.
You got to explain to them,
it's much better to explain to them why
it's important that you do the thing
that you don't want to do and why it's a
good thing.
You've got to change the way you think
about it.
Don't think about it like,
Oh,
it's this chore.
Think about it.
Like,
this is just a thing that I have to do
right now and I'm so lucky in so many
ways and that's how I should look at
life and that jumped on.
Don't just get annoyed at things.
You know,
you don't want to go to bed,
go to bed,
you got to get sleep.
I know you don't want to go to bed.
I get it.
I feel the same way all the time.
But as a person who's in charge of your
biology,
I know that you're not quite wise enough
to make the decisions.
You want to be healthy.
Your little kids need to get like 10 to
12 hours sleep.
How do you get to tell them?
Give them the association that they're
making choices and that their choices
have ramifications.
You're going to wake up to you that
sometimes it's hard for me to wake you
up and it hurts in the morning.
Will they won't be that way.
If you go to sleep now,
you'll wake up and you'll feel good.
Yeah,
that's man.
That is the fucking biggest difference
when,
when I had day jobs and um,
you know,
a lot of times I was a,
like for years I had sleep deprivation
because I was getting up in the morning
for delivering the newspapers and it was
trying to go back to sleep,
but I always stayed up at night because
I was doing stand up and like for the
longest time,
like I was really screwed up.
And then once I quit doing that,
once I just started doing,
just stand up and I started getting
sleep.
Like I go to bed after the clubs and I
would get up at 11,
wake up and I felt so good.
I was like,
oh my God.
Like,
everything feels great.
Like I don't feel like I'm constantly at
a lack.
That feeling that you have when you're
tired all the time.
When you work too many hours you don't
get enough sleep because that fucking
feeling like you're always at a lack.
There's always like a hole in your,
your,
your biological game as it were.
I'm just,
ugh.
Just trying to be left alone.
Yeah,
just,
you just don't.
But if you can get that solid eight to
10 hours sleep,
that goes away,
especially if you can get 10,
but he could only get eight.
It's worth so much,
you know?
Yeah.
So fucking value through it.
Throw a 20 minute meditation on top of
that.
The next day around 2:30
in the afternoon when you're crashing
out after lunch
if you can do that.
That's a good move.
Yeah.
If you could just sit down.
I mean the meditation,
just the,
the,
the word meditation is so loaded you
because it has
that.
There's a sort of like A.
Oh,
a lot of us I think have this idea about
people meditate is like,
ah,
you know,
he's just trying to find some spiritual
peace and this is like some masturbatory
weirdness and you stand in front of
fucking incense and pretend you're from
a different culture.
But I think that just being alone with
your thoughts and just your thoughts and
just concentrating on just thinking
about as little as possible was just
thinking maybe even just about
breathing.
I'm breathing in and breathing out.
Just that alone is a form of meditation.
Yeah.
I mean,
it's like it's,
it's a guided sleep.
Think of it as taking a nap.
You know,
Eckhart tolle talks about,
you know,
with,
with meditation,
it's just really,
it's reminding you to not think about
the past to the future for a little
while.
It's about just thinking about the
breathing that's happening right now or
the mantra that's happening right now
and when you come out of it,
you're not going to stay in that state
all day,
but you will have brought yourself back
to that point if only for 20 minutes and
that will sort of,
that will guide you for the rest of the
day.
Yeah.
I think the momentum of most people's
lives is so strong.
Mine included,
I'm sure yours included that are
oftentimes you just get caught up in how
you're thinking or how you're behaving
or what you're doing.
You just get caught up in it.
Like it's just like,
wow.
It's like pushing you from behind and if
you can just stop as often as possible
and do nothing for an hour and breathe,
just do nothing but think and breathe.
You come out of it with a more balanced
perspective.
You make better decisions.
You're not reacting to things
exactly.
You're not.
You're not being pushed from behind by
the momentum of everything you've
experienced over the last x amount of
months.
You get a fresh restart to contemplate
your existence.
Well,
you know,
we can't do anything about the past,
but here's where we are right now and
this is what we.
Okay.
Now I've decided that instead of
concentrating on that,
I'm going to concentrate on this and it
give yourself like a chance to almost
give yourself a little personal seminar.
Give yourself a little garlic will.
Okay.
Are you happy about this?
Like,
like if you were giving yourself advice,
he'd probably be way different than what
you actually do.
You know,
I've always thought that if I was giving
myself advice,
like how,
what,
how brutal would I be with myself?
Honest,
would I be with myself?
Well,
that's why you're supposed to set goals,
because goals are you sitting down in a
cold calculating way and saying,
where do I want to be in a year?
What are the steps that I need to get to
that and then setting small goals to get
you there because day to day you're
reacting to people are codependent with
their wives or their kids instead of
reacting to that.
You're wondering if your phone's going
to ring.
You're wondering what people are saying
on social media.
There's so many dynamics that have you
spinning around and not in your own
space.
So that said,
that's what I love the beginning of the
year.
I love sitting down and setting up some
new goals.
I mean,
you and I just talked a couple of nights
ago
about that.
Like your goal is to sort of try to not
get off social media more.
Not Answer your phone all day.
Mine cast,
stay off my phone for many,
many hours at a time.
Yeah,
that's the big one.
And I'm just thinking about the amount
of time that I spend.
Just looking for something interesting.
Looking on twitter feed,
looking on facebook or on,
um,
instagram.
Just looking for something interesting.
I'm going to just fluttering through
fucking pictures of Shit.
Oh look,
another car all.
Look at that lion.
That's crazy.
After awhile,
chimpanzee attacking a car.
Well,
that video that I showed you today,
that's how I found it.
The fucking lady that hit that,
or the guy that hit that moves.
I don't know if the guy or girl,
whoever the fucking hit that moves,
but I'm inundated by that and people
keep sending me these fucking videos of
these Russian crazy like acrobats doing
flips on the top of buildings.
You've seen those guys daredevils,
these Russian daredevil characters.
They go on the top of buildings and do
like handstands and glean their feet off
the edge.
You can't watch it,
man.
It's hard to watch.
It's too fucking scary.
I mean it's fucking terrifying and some
of them get up on top of him with those
hoverboards,
those little wheely boards and they'd go
like to the edge and that.
That makes me uncomfortable.
You just describing it and they spin
around.
Who's the skyscraper?
Look at this.
This is in Russia.
This.
I don't know where this one is,
but they're.
Do they do these all over the place?
I think this is Dubai.
This guy is on the fucking edge of a
crazy skyscraper.
Like,
what is that?
100 stories.
High holy days doing a handstand.
Oh,
came down backwards.
that was terrifying.
What do you.
What do you do after that?
I just hurt my elbow reacting to that.
I whacked my phone.
That's hilarious.
This guy's got a helmet on and his
underwear and he's walking on a bar.
Oh my God.
That is so crazy.
These kids are fucking nuts,
man.
Jesus Christ.
This guy's doing a balance beam over a.
It looks like a harbor.
I don't know how far down it is,
but he's way the fuck up on some
criminal oil rig and looked like.
Oh my goodness.
Uh,
uh.
Yeah.
A,
I'm,
I think I'm done.
I'm done.
I used to do crazy shit.
My friend,
my friend lived on the fifth floor of
and apart building and there's a picture
of me when I was about 14 hanging off
his balcony by my knees.
Oh my God,
I will.
I was into gymnastics.
I did gymnastics pretty hard for like
six years.
So I would hang off anything I would do,
I would do flips off fucking anything
anywhere.
Yeah.
Dude,
I got sweaty hands.
Just looking at that.
I do too.
Sweaty hands.
Don't show this
Jamie.
God Damn it.
That guy jumped off the roof into a
pool.
I mean,
how many stories is six stories to shut
this off?
I can't do this anymore.
Oh my hands are fucking sweaty,
man.
There's like soaking wet.
Feel them feel Jesus wet,
soaking wet.
I'm.
Hey,
can I plug some dates?
Come on everybody.
I got my big winter,
a comedy tour coming up.
I'm coming to your town,
Tacoma,
Washington.
February ninth and 11th.
So everybody knows where to get all the
dog.com
for tickets.
Portland,
Oregon,
a February 16 through 18,
Oklahoma City one night.
Uh,
February Twenty First Austin,
Texas February 22nd to 25th,
Fort Lauderdale and March Burlington,
Vermont in March.
Houston in March.
Uh,
check it all out at Greg Fitz show and
uh,
fits dog radio.
It's it the Irvine Improv,
the new Irvine Improv is fucking awesome
dude.
Right?
Giant.
I did it once and uh,
I just remember I didn't,
uh,
I didn't fill it.
I'll tell you that by no means that I
feel it is a very big place.
Yeah.
But I'm doing it then.
I've got to St Patrick's Day shows,
uh,
which you've done I think the last three
years.
You've done my Saint Patrick's day show
a pet,
the Hollywood improv.
I have to support the one quarter Irish
though,
man.
That's right.
Get in there for that.
That's always a fun show though,
isn't it?
Pack it out.
We get all Irish comics on it.
Throw a black guy in there just to keep
it.
Keep the fucking pc police off my back.
Get Ian Edwards on there.
Yeah,
that's a fun show,
man.
Yeah,
it's good.
Joey Diaz.
I did a one year and it was um,
it was all the cool comics.
And then Joey Diaz,
he was like Zach Galifianakis,
Sarah Silverman and know Andy Kindler.
And they went up and they didn't know
who Joey Diaz was and uh,
I had him go on like second just to
fucking,
just to raise the bar and everybody
else.
And he went up there and he's doing this
whole bit about having some chick piss
in his mouth in a bathtub and I'm
drinking it like a soldier and uh,
and the place they don't know what to
make of him.
At first it takes some,
it takes them like a good two minutes
for them to just pick their jaws up off
the table,
put the,
put the job back in their head and then
start to laugh.
And then you just saw them convulsed and
in the back,
Sarah and all them,
they're going like,
who is this guy?
What,
what is this?
I go,
this is fucking Joey Diaz.
They didn't know.
They didn't know when.
How long ago was this?
Two years ago.
Wow.
I did not know who Joey d is,
is because he doesn't work.
I don't think he works the Improv.
Does he have a different comic knows
like you hear about like a guy like you
always hear about.
So I heard about big Jay oakerson
before I saw him.
You gotta see this guy.
It's very foreign.
I think maybe there's this,
you know,
splintered comedy world.
Exact doesn't do a ton of stand up and I
think,
uh,
you know,
Sarah,
Sarah works the comedy store sometimes.
Sometimes.
I've seen her there a few times.
Not as often as she should.
What are you judging?
Well,
she needs you.
She needs that,
you know,
I think some comics they work,
they'll work largo a lot and uh,
and I think it,
you can,
you can draw your own crowd,
but she's like a real comic.
She can play in a room like the store
where they didn't all come to see her
and she can fucking prove something to
people that maybe don't know what a good
comic she is.
Yeah.
Well I would agree with you that I think
she's one of the best comics live.
Sure.
She,
she killed at the comedy store last time
I saw her,
which was,
I want to say it was quite awhile ago.
It might've been a year ago,
matter of fact,
sometime between now and a year.
Anyway,
she destroyed and I was laughing really
hard.
There was some funny shit in there,
but on the other hand,
she's obviously got money and she's
obviously comfortable,
so she should do whatever the fuck she
wants.
Right.
I mean there's guys like Paul f
Tompkins,
that dude,
I haven't seen him in a comedy club in
10 years,
but he does his show at Largo.
I don't know how often and he does.
He'll go to San Francisco and fucking
sellout cobb's.
The guy's got his circuit.
He's got his crowd.
I think it makes a very nice living and
I think he does the style of comedy he
does,
which is a little bit more storytelling.
It's a little slower,
a little more esoteric may not work in
the other kinds of clubs.
So yeah,
maybe it fosters his ability to go
deeper into what he's doing by playing
select clubs.
Yeah,
I mean I guess it's all in whether or
not what you enjoy doing,
whether it fits in with clubs.
Yeah,
because some people it just doesn't.
Some people they don't enjoy just always
being,
you know,
always going for the laugh always.
You know like what,
like our style Boston style,
like Boston styles,
like punchline set up,
punchline set up punchline and to try to
build punchlines and some people have
like they,
they want to tell you a story that
happens to be humorous.
They don't want to be confined by this
idea that it has to be set up punchline
set up punchline.
So it is sorta stand up and a lot of
ways,
but in a lot of ways it's not.
It's like you're,
you're,
you're being an orator,
a narrator,
you're telling stories,
you know,
which is cool too,
like there's a lot of people who like
Henry Rollins is a great example.
You wouldn't say that necessarily.
What he does is stand up.
You would say it's a spoken word thing,
right?
But what is he doing?
He's telling stories,
you know,
I mean they're just,
they have punchlines.
They have like very clear setup and
punchlines that I'm,
I guess obviously he knows where the
funny parts are so he's kind of doing
standup,
but he's doing it his fucking way.
Like if a lot of people really liked
that is what my point is like and they
don't want to go see him try to do a 15
minute set at the.
It can change.
Like I find that if I go through a run
of clubs that are bad,
I'm like say Florida.
It changes the way I'm doing standup
because in Florida you've got.
It's just a schizo side crowd.
You've got rednecks mixed in with old
people mixed in with Latino's mixed in
with fucking spring breakers or
whatever.
It's never one crowd.
You have no fucking idea who you're
applying to.
So you're up there for an hour and
you're just.
It's a drunk and knife fight in the
alleys.
You're just trying to fucking keep your
spinning plates.
You're trying to keep this guy happy.
This guy's Hecklin,
they're not paying attention.
And I find that like it makes my act
worse because I'm not getting in the
pocket and doing what I want to do.
I'm pleasing because I'm trying to
survive.
Right.
And then you go to a club like fucking
Austin Cap City and Austin,
Texas and Holy Shit,
man,
you just kicked back and they come to
you.
I just did Madison,
Wisconsin.
They came to me.
Oh,
madison is a really cool town.
Yeah,
it is really interesting.
Yeah.
Like super open minded.
Liberal Wisconsin town.
Yeah.
What a great theater.
There's a theater there too.
What the hell is that theater there?
Is it acme theater?
No.
Did I make that up?
Acme is in Minneapolis.
It means the comedy club in Minneapolis.
Right.
The theater in Madison or film.
I don't know.
I had a point,
but it's fucking lost.
There's an orpheum there.
Maybe that's where I went.
Yeah.
It's a great little city.
It's a college town.
That's where I went.
Good food is really only one block
though.
Yes,
not a lot.
It's psyche.
There's a block that goes from the State
House to the university and there's not
much often,
and again,
it's one of those places where people
that are living in a place where it gets
really,
really fucking cold theater family.
That's where I was.
Those people are hardier like that thing
that we're talking about.
Yeah.
This idea that you might not make it
home tonight.
There's a god blizzard.
You might get stuck in the side of the
road and you see flashing like a light
on the side of the road.
Like someone's hazard lights.
They pulled over like a lot of times
people help because that person might
die.
Like there's a difference between like
if you see somebody on the four,
oh five and they were pulled over.
Do you ever even think for a fucking
second pulling over and helping them?
No.
No,
but if you were driving down a snowy
road in New Hampshire and you saw
someone pull over the side of the road
and you start thinking,
what if that's a mom with her kids?
What did she think?
It's great.
It totally fosters community when you
live in a harsher,
whether you have a trust and there's
like a symbiotic relationship with your
neighbors and you know,
I,
I think that like you think about people
that live up in Alaska and how they
share supplies and fucking in the spring
help rebuild a barn and you know that
that's community that's living.
I mean,
in La our needs is so easily met.
It just don't have any fucking.
Our roof doesn't go bad because it rains
three days a year and you know,
you can take an uber here and you could
get a fucking yelp review on the Sushi
play.
It's all easy.
It all comes to you.
There's no sense of,
yeah,
I don't need to help you.
I,
if I hang out with you,
it's because I want to hang out with you
there.
You hang out with your neighbor because
you're fucking surviving together.
We were all hanging out in the back of
the comedy store last night and we were
all stoned and we're all laughing and
giggling and joking around and I was
thinking,
boy,
like what a great place this is to be
like at the sunset strip in Hollywood in
2016.
And then all I could think of because of
the pod probably was like,
what if an asteroid,
just not even a big one,
but a pretty big one.
Just slammed into downtown La Right now.
Not enough to kill me,
but enough for me to just feel the
impact.
See that thing flying through the sky
and hear the people scream and run for
the hills and realize.
I realized at that moment because I was
so high,
I was like,
how fragile is this existence that we
think is so concrete.
We think it's so locked in and permanent
and secure and all we take is one
fucking rock that comes from this guy.
Boom in the downtown La.
Kill a half a million people and then
the rest of us at beaches,
shit in our pants and terror
on highway goes out in la,
we're fucked.
Fucked because there's only two roads
downtown.
There's the 10 and the four.
Oh five.
And if those go either one of those go.
The city shuts down to.
This is such a stupid place to live.
There was three earthquakes last night
too.
Yeah.
Three earthquakes.
A pretty big one on the Nevada border.
Five point seven.
That's a pretty big one.
It's not a,
you know,
a one like a,
the 19,
90 whatever the fuck.
It was one which was a lot higher.
That was more than seven,
but this was a significant earthquake.
Five point seven is a pretty good shock,
but that's what's so weird about.
I mean you talk about it being tenuous
and all that is that that shit can fuck
things up bad and people go,
oh we do,
but we just elected an earthquake
we chose
was a fucking tragedy to happen.
And if you're a trump supporter,
go fuck yourself.
You fucked us.
Can I?
Thanks for coming.
These liberals in Hollywood that think
they can talk down to you,
the good people of trump landia you just
watch.
I am not on his side.
I do not support any of the statements
and I think it's about time we showed a
little respect for the office of
Commander in chief.
Maybe he will rise to the job.
He could.
Maybe.
Maybe we can get him some mushrooms.
Maybe he will have a,
a revelation while he's in office that
this has achieved the highest
achievement than any human being can
ever attain.
That he has won the race and now and
maybe he will change his entire cabinet
appointments that he's made over the
last month and like Bill Gates dedicate
the remaining years of his life to
philanthropy work.
Yes.
You know,
Joe,
my attitude towards this year was
supposed to be positive and you just saw
an example of negativity come out
negative.
I can't do it.
I can't go negative on it.
I can be vigilant.
I can keep an eye on what he does.
My wife has this app where every day she
can call or write a congressmen or a
cause or a place you can donate money so
that you feel like every day what's the
APP called you?
No,
no.
I'll find out.
Jimmy could find it,
but it's a way of not feeling alienated
and not feeling isolated and like you're
doing something whether or not it makes
a difference.
Maybe it does.
Well if everybody reacts that way,
it makes a difference.
It's really sheer numbers.
So we have used it on as an example on
the show before,
but you remember when the United States
had that I'm the president had the press
conference where Obama was saying that
we're probably going to go to war with
Syria and America was like,
fuck you.
It was a unanimous across the board.
Right.
And left.
So when he said that he drew a line in
the sand about if they use chemical
weapons,
we'd go to war.
Yeah.
There was something along those lines.
If there was a fucking blatant rejection
by the American people,
it was very obvious.
Very vocal and no,
no commentators though,
right or left.
We're saying this is a good idea,
like this is a terrible idea.
I want to go to another fucking
unwinnable war in Syria and so it
stopped.
Yeah.
Stopped.
I mean obviously it's a terrible fucking
place and you know that it's terrible
videos that are coming out of there
every day.
It's a salient.
It's just fucking wiped out to insane.
It's insane.
I don't think,
I mean it's hard for us to even imagine
what it would be like to be living there
living over here and fucking Los Angeles
where everything's perfect.
Imagine what it's like to be someone who
just buy a bad roll the dice.
You were born over there.
I've had parts of Africa,
you know,
south Sudan and Congo and places were
places where people are giving their
lives in the street because there were
voted discrepancies that ideologically
are,
are letting themselves be shot in public
squares because they're demonstrating.
That's intense.
Yeah.
It's incredible.
It's,
I mean there's,
there's pockets of the world that are
living a sophisticated version of the
way people were living six,
700 years.
Yeah.
They're just living a more sophisticated
version of using cell phones and
technology,
but they have almost the same mindset as
people who lived hundreds and hundreds
of years ago for good and for bad.
They found an uncontacted tribe in the
Amazon.
Oh,
I saw that.
Saw the pictures.
Holy Shit.
We were talking.
We were trying to figure out where like
imagine if there was a way where you
could infiltrate those people,
but they wouldn't let.
You would have to.
They would not.
The only way to really know how they
lived would be to become one of them.
Like
you really couldn't figure out how they
lived by you going in there as Greg
Fitzsimmons because they would go,
whoa,
what the fuck is this?
You have clothes,
like,
what's that thing on your wrist?
It tells the time why.
Why do you need to know what time it is?
I do.
It would be.
It would be amazing,
but you would be to affected like you
would.
You would affect them rather,
whereas I think you might kill them
because very often people,
people,
anthropologist tried to go in there and
study and they give them a disease and
they wiped.
They've,
there's been cases where they wiped out
entire tribes.
Yeah.
There's a guy named
Dan Flores who's,
um,
he wrote a paper about,
the bisons and a bison diplomacy bison
ecology,
I think it's called.
And one of the things he was talking
about was the amount of native Americans
that were wiped out just because of
diseases by settlers.
And it was some insane number,
like high 80 percent.
Oh,
down in Mexico,
that was,
I don't know where it was,
but what percentage of native Americans
Google this,
what percentage of native Americans
where
killed by diseases from European
settlers,
because I know the Spanish,
when they,
when they came into Central America,
they fucking so many
people died.
Diseases.
Well,
he was equating it to the boom and the
buffalo herd sizes.
Oh No,
she was saying.
Yeah,
he was saying that when the native
Americans contacted the Europeans,
they got these horses from them.
Okay.
What does it say here?
Ninety percent.
No Shit.
When Europeans arrived carrying germs,
which thrived on a dense semi urban
populations,
the indigenous people of the Americas
were effectively doomed.
They had never experienced smallpox,
measles or flu before,
and the viruses tore through the
continent,
killing an estimated 90 percent of
native Americans.
Hey Shit.
Holy Shit.
Sent and then we went to war against the
remaining 10 percent.
Holy Shit.
It's located them and push them around.
God Damn.
And we wonder why they drink?
Well,
I mean
the same thing that I said about those,
that that tribe that lived in the jungle
like I would have,
I would love if there was a way where
you could somehow or another be amongst
them without them knowing it so you
could really truly see how they behave
and exist unaffected by a person like
you or personally me.
That obviously doesn't does it wasn't
born there.
There was this documentary about this
guy from the,
from Greenwich Village,
I think it was a gay guy,
and he went down to this village in,
might've been Columbia and he lived with
them on the river for 20 years and they
were gay.
The tribe was not,
their tribe wasn't gay,
but they didn't delineate between gay
sex,
straight sex.
It was just all kind of fluidly would
happen.
And so he had this boyfriend basically,
but the boyfriend had a wife and kids,
but he slept with the guy for 20 years
and then he left and he was gone for
like 15 years.
I forget why he didn't go back.
Um,
I think he didn't go back as like,
they eventually attacked him and they
were going to kill him.
He realized,
oh no,
I know.
It was one night he realized that they
were cannibals.
They went and they attacked another
tribe.
They,
all of a sudden,
one night it had never happened before
and all of the years he was there,
maybe,
maybe it's only 10 years.
They all put on paints and they went to
the next village and they killed.
And then they ate flesh and the guy just
went,
I'm fucking out of here.
Where's my,
where's my return ticket?
And he left.
And so he came back to the village and
he wrote about it and he lectured about
it and then he went back like,
yeah,
like 15 years later he goes back,
finds the dude.
And this is like,
I think that I think the movie might
have been called keep the river on your
right.
And he went back and he found the dude
and they like rekindled their
relationship.
Oh my God.
It was incredible.
Keep the river on your right.
I think so.
I'm writing that down.
I need to see the.
What the fuck,
dude,
I didn't know that the incidences of
cannibalism were so prevalent among
native Americans.
They would occasionally do that.
Like the Nez perce apparently they had
occasionally catch people and kill them
and eat them.
Yeah.
Especially people like they'd catch you
had your brain,
right,
that eat your whole body.
Yeah.
But probably your brain
do.
But think about it.
I mean it's very symbolic.
You conquer and you consume.
Yeah.
But it's,
it's the thing that freaks us out the
most,
the idea being just reduced to meet,
right?
Yeah.
And by someone just with a bigger
Tomahawk,
you know.
So I mean,
or do to got to you before you get to
him.
There's no like real serious weapons.
Yeah.
Bows and arrows and spears and,
and it's really a fight to exhaustion.
See who lasts the longest
mark or the capture you if you're trying
to get away from them.
But in their case,
I mean,
do you imagine if you and your people
had lived in this one patch of land for
10,000
years,
then all of a sudden these fucking
demons carrying death in their breath
and they're very touch.
Like just getting in contact with a
makes all of your relatives wilt away,
kills 90 percent of the people you know,
just them being around.
Not Forget about all the shit they
killed with guns.
All the people they probably shot and
killed because just emanating evil and
death.
Think about that.
And then they ran you up like fucking
cattle and they rape your women.
Jesus.
I mean,
enough can't be said people.
Oh,
are already fucking liberal.
We're in about the native Americans.
It was pretty bad.
Well,
I didn't know how bad it was until I
read a priest's account
of Columbus is men interacting with
native Americans and it is horrific.
Yeah.
This a religious guy went with them on
one of the voyages and wrote books about
how they would hack off guys arms and
they would tell them to bring them gold.
They had to bring their weight in gold
and if they didn't do it,
they would hack off one of their arms
and they do it in front of everybody
else to freak them out.
And at first the natives were very
friendly and once they realize that the
natives were friendly and the natives
were sort of weak,
they,
they started taking advantage of them
and brutalizing them and getting them to
acquire gold and they would smash babies
on rocks like this priest.
Oh,
it was horrible.
Horrible,
horrible shit.
Is Priest wrote about this.
So when we think of Christopher
Columbus,
we think of this noble Spanish gentleman
who came over and landed in America and
you know,
looked regal as he got off with fucking
rosy cheeks and walked amongst the
people and declared this American,
all that bullshit and made friends with
the Indians,
but they were a horrible band of
monster.
They also stopped in the Caribbean on
the way here and they literally
committed genocide on an entire fucking
island of people.
They work them to death.
Same thing like a lot of these people,
gold didn't mean anything to them.
Like it was something that they used to
decorate or whatever,
but there was no value the way there was
in Europe.
So they gave it to them.
They're like,
yeah,
you want the gold fucking just right
over there and grab the gold.
And then when they.
And once they took all that,
then they made them start working for
it.
And it seems like also like these tribes
that they encounter,
they don't,
these,
they don't have any concept of large
scale slave labor like the Europeans
did.
Like the Europeans were like,
oh,
we'll just get you to work for us or
we'll kill you like that.
I don't think that was like a thing that
native Americans were known for and I
would say probably there probably are
we.
What are we doing here?
Why we keep digging for gold?
Like what the fuck is going on here?
Yeah.
Like they had weird concepts in terms of
like what is possession?
Like they didn't have the same sort of
concepts of this being yours.
Like if you left something there,
he would just,
someone would just take it because it
would do well that's the thing that I
want.
It's right there.
I mean I'm just going to take that
stuff.
Anybody's.
Nobody owns it.
So it confused the shit out of them when
they would get accused of stealing.
Like there was a whole different in,
in many of these inner encounters
apparently there was a whole different,
like not just a language barrier but a
culture barrier.
Like understanding what these fucking
crazy white assholes we're doing.
Yeah.
But the whole concept that you still see
in,
in a lot of like Middle Eastern
countries,
which is the,
the idea of giving to as a host,
you know when you come,
when you come to somebody's home,
you give them your bed and you give them
food and date.
You would never ask them to leave as
long as they want to stay.
And it's all about generosity and with
the western mentality is more about
collecting and owning.
Yeah,
it's interesting.
And isn't that also what we were talking
about before that a long time ago is a
lot like living in a place that has
unbelievably harsh winters.
A long time ago you're faced with danger
all the time and you had to make bonds.
They had to be important.
So like if you came over to my house,
I'd have to think,
hey greg,
you know,
the ship might go down one day.
If the ship goes down,
I'm here with you.
You're here with me,
we're going to break bread,
we're going to sleep.
You sleep in my bed.
I got you bro.
You're here.
So like there was like this intense need
to form these community bonds today.
Nobody even knows what they're fucking
neighbor is.
Do you think they live like that?
A thousand years ago,
you fucking first shore knew who that
guy was.
Then you for sure knew who that guy was
and everybody would be on the lookout
for some people that we didn't know that
might be sneaking over the top of the
hill.
There's none of that anymore.
It's gone.
So when you talk about gossip,
well you know,
small towns from a long time ago,
people guy.
Everybody was gossiping.
Yeah.
You know what they were saying,
that guy's a rapist to watch out for
him.
Or Hey,
this guy can vouch for it.
He's a good guy.
That's what gossip.
Yeah.
And you needed to know.
You know who's a freak?
Who was fucking crazy,
right?
Who's doing weird shit?
Hey,
who's jerking off and all the girls'
shoes in the middle of the night when
the fuck did you find the girls like
doing it?
Yeah.
The girls will like it.
You got to set separate them.
They knew their own hut with loose door,
send them to vegas,
just people like what we've become right
now as the people that are living here
in 2016.
It's a weird process that's been going
on for hundreds and hundreds of years
and we're just at the end of it.
We're obviously not at the end end,
but we're at the front of the line as
far as all the history of it all pushing
behind us.
It's hard for us to appreciate how weird
it must have been to be our parents or
to be our parents.
Parents already come here from another
country or to be someone who existed
back when you only live 30 years old and
you die of old age.
Have a heart attack at 30 or you'd catch
a disease or someone would shoot you in
the Arrow.
That was like a giant panda brothers and
sisters died from shit like smallpox or
in the balls.
Get in a boat and leave Spain and head
across the fucking ocean and land in the
Bahamas.
Those are marauders,
those people.
Well,
I just think about landing even even,
you know later to like,
you know,
the beginning of the 19th century when
people were,
um,
or the 20th century when people coming
over from Europe,
you landed in,
in,
you know,
Manhattan,
you've got a burlap sack with some
clothes on it and an address of a
fucking second cousin out in Brooklyn.
You don't know how to get to Brooklyn.
You don't speak the native language.
You speak in Italian.
Italians are fucking hated when you land
your shit.
Nobody wants to help you.
People don't realize that today because
that stigma's kind of gone away.
My grandfather used to about all the
time
because,
you know,
he came over from Italy and my
grandmother came over from Italy on my
mom's side and they would talk about it
all the time.
How horrible was kids would call them
Guinea Wasps,
you know,
that he would be,
you would be treated as like a saw,
a lower level person,
you know,
because you're Italian.
But then suddenly it went away.
Jersey shore brought a passion real
housewives.
They're getting lops yeah,
they,
they're the real housewives of New
Jersey.
Holy Shit.
Yeah.
It is funny because like the Italians
are in some ways,
you know,
you think about the,
the holy Roman Empire.
I mean,
you and I were both in Rome this summer
and it's mind blowing that,
you know,
irrigation started there.
Every major thing started there.
Demark.
Well,
I guess to her he was Greek or Roman,
right?
Didn't they have that first?
Well,
who,
who created democracy,
I think it was the Greeks.
That's a Greek word,
but uh,
but just what you get blown away by what
the Italians are capable of.
You see the craftsmanship of marble work
in this country that the Italians
brought over and the,
the,
the opera and,
and then you see Jersey.
Sure.
It's such a fucking weird dichotomy of
Italians can be so fucking dumb and
materialistic and yet they are the,
the fucking high point of culture and
civilization.
Well,
in some ways,
but there were also fucking kids.
Yeah.
Right.
Like that's a big part of what they did
to.
Yeah.
They did that along with make incredible
architecture.
Unbelievable.
Art,
incredible buildings filled with statues
that are just beyond compare,
an incredible artistic expression,
but rampant kid.
Fuck it.
Right?
Yeah.
And the.
We both grew up Catholic,
right?
Yeah.
I mean we knew Catholics.
Our family was,
were all Catholic.
Everyone around us was Catholic.
Yeah.
We all knew a priest that tried to fuck
a kid or a kid.
Well,
you heard about a priest.
You fucked a kid.
Yeah.
Or My,
my friend was um,
he went away to some fucking camp in
this.
The priest like climbed into bed with
them and was trying to grab his hand and
shove it down his pants.
And he was like literally fighting the
guy off and running away from him.
It was a crazy story.
I was like,
what?
Yeah,
the Catholics.
I think there's a work ethic that comes
with it and a service of God thing and a
Christian soldier thing.
And then there's also all the repression
and shame about sexuality that plays
out.
The Irish are the same way the Irish
have,
you know,
they saved the Bible.
There's this book called how the Irish
saved civilization and when the Roman
empire was being destroyed,
they were burning every single Bible in
Europe,
like they literally destroyed all the
bibles and in Ireland there were the
monks that were like,
you know,
the,
uh,
what are those scrolls called in Dublin,
I'm the,
whatever they're called,
but they were hand writing bibles by the
fucking thousands and that's what saved
Christianity.
Wow.
And so,
and then,
then you get into the poets,
you know,
Yates and Eugene O'neill and,
and you think about what the Irish have
offered to this place,
but the same thing.
Massive kid fuckers.
Yeah.
It's the,
the,
the number of people throughout history
that were kid fuckers.
That's what was really weird.
It was like if you go through history
and you know,
what would you call it,
pet arrestees that would you call it up
the technical word for,
is it having sex with underage boys?
But it's really common like,
like throughout human history throughout
Rome and the Middle East,
and there's so many fucking instances of
great men threw in.
Like it wasn't socrates a kid fucker.
No,
yeah,
yeah.
I mean like how many people quote
socrates and then have that caveat,
but it also fucked kids.
No,
that's not.
That doesn't give them a pass on that.
They didn't know you weren't supposed to
fuck kids back then.
Cause people.
A lot of people probably fuck them too.
It was probably sexual exchanges were
like we a bunch less rigid idea of what
sexual exchanges were acceptable,
but that's not that long ago.
Know.
It's weird that hundreds of years ago
people were just fucking fucking animal
before I'd fuck a kid.
There's a lot of animals.
I think that would probably be good to
fuck right.
I think a horse would probably fight
back the least.
I don't know about that.
I wouldn't fuck her horse because if
they kick you,
you're dead.
That's true.
They decided they're done.
They're not going to be cool about it.
That I can be like,
all right,
go ahead,
finish.
No,
they're going to take you off of him.
He want a fat,
lazy animal.
Yeah.
You don't want death by female horse or
a male horse if you're into that kind of
shit.
Probably had,
she seems she's pretty popular show.
Yes.
Yeah,
that would definitely be the one,
you know,
it's weird that it's illegal to kill
animals when you are going to do
anything but eat them like um,
and it's illegal.
It's illegal to fuck animals.
Like you can't fuck them,
but you can kill them.
Yeah,
you can eat them,
but you can't fuck them.
Yeah.
So you can't do a dual purpose.
You can't kill them.
Fuck them.
Then eat them because then you're
fucking dead animal and that's gross.
Illegal.
I think it's more illegal to fuck a dead
animal than a live animal.
That makes sense because what are you
doing?
Then?
You're really just masturbating because
there's not a living thing in your
presence.
It can't be rape if it's debt,
but you notice how there's like stages
of like how you feel about the dead
animal.
There's one stage.
One is the live animal,
right?
If you fucking alive,
anima,
you crazy asshole.
What are you subject to that animal to
stage two,
your fucking a dead animal.
Like what is wrong with you?
Like why?
Why do you want to fuck this thing?
Forget about whether you should be able
to do it,
but if you kill it and then eat it,
right,
everybody's
fine with that because that's like what
you're supposed to do,
but you can't fuck it's body.
But what if you just jerked off with a
chicken cutlet?
What if you took a chicken,
he wrapped around your Dick and someone
came in the room like,
what the fuck you doing?
Greg?
Like,
dude,
I'm telling you it sounds crazy,
but it feels so good and I just cleaned
it up and then I eat it for dinner.
It takes a bite.
What's this nice cream sauce?
Dare you.
Now that you say fucking a chicken
cutlet,
it's all I can think about it because he
had slippery.
It's soft.
When those gmo chickens would wrap right
around your heart and it's a breast.
You thinking about it being at your tit.
Fucking it.
You know what you would do?
You would take a bag,
like a Ziploc storage bags?
Yeah,
the chicken cutlet in the bag and then
heat up some water to about a 99 degrees
and then you dunk the chicken cutlet in
the water so that it heats up.
It gets,
but you know,
like a body skin temperature.
Then you just covered that bitch with.
Yeah,
just lather it in there.
And then you put an oven Mitt on cutlet.
You wrapped that color on your shaft.
Oh,
crimes against humanity.
Never felt so good and then yeah,
you can eat it.
You're gonna Cook that Shit because
you've tenderized it.
Especially like you don't have to use in
edible oil.
You could jerk off with a nice avocado
oil or coconut oil.
You know,
avocado oil has a high flash point.
It's good oil to jerk off with because
then after you're done,
as long as you don't come on your
chicken.
Oh,
you know,
you pull out.
That's gross.
I don't want to come on your food,
but that way it will be like really
green multiple uses.
I love it.
Well,
we can't accept the fact that we
wouldn't.
We want pleasure.
You know that we want pleasure from a
fleshlight is gross.
You want to fuck that thing?
Oh,
that's gross.
That we want pleasure from a chicken
cutlet.
Using an animal flesh as a masturbation
tool will eat.
It will sink our teeth into it and
swallow it belong as you interested in
animal will eat a cow's fucking milk.
Leave.
There's rule so we.
Here's the rules.
According to section 69 of the sexual
offenses act of 2003 69 commits,
a person commits an offense of
intercourse with an animal.
If a he unintentionally or intentionally
intentionally,
excuse me,
performs an act of penetration which is
penis be.
What is penetrated is the vagina or anus
of a living animal.
So blow jobs are afraid.
So that's not intercourse with an animal
and blow jobs are free.
But notice how both of them are heat.
You know,
to he doing it,
they're not referring to a chick fucking
a horse.
That chick fucking a horse seems totally
legal.
Wouldn't be a horse.
Fucking a chick though.
Not the chick.
Fuck No.
That dirty bitch.
She shows that horse what's up?
She backs up to them,
keeps them stuck in that stall.
He can't back up or go forward.
It's totally against as well.
It has to do with,
uh,
David Cameron and the prime minister.
I think of what the UK or Britain,
uh,
just just talking about if he could have
gotten in trouble if something happened
with some allegations of something in
some memoirs about something that I'm
not reading all of the article.
I was just reading them
his penis in a dead pig head.
He did.
And that's what it says.
That's the allegation.
Well,
he was in a university.
Oh,
so,
but it was breaking down if what he did
is actually illegal or not.
And you,
it has to be a dead animal or this was a
dead animal in this court in this case.
So for the live animal it's sex with an
animal.
Yes.
So if it's dead animals,
no big deal.
And then I broke it down that it would
have mattered where it happened and if
someone would have taken a picture of
it,
if there's no picture,
you're fine.
If it happened in public,
you're also maybe,
okay,
that is fucking hilarious.
How weird is it that we have rules on
what we allow you to fuck,
but you can kill them and eat them,
but you can't just kill them.
You can only kill them if you're going
to eat them.
If you can't just shoot a cow in the
head,
leave it to rot even though that's like
the natural processes of animal falls
down.
Cro,
start eating it.
Rats eating the grass devours it.
It gets,
you know it decays and goes into the
ground,
but you can't do that.
Will shoot if you are,
unless you strap a bit and it's mouth.
Sit on it and whip it around a fucking
to Deauville track.
You can do that.
Then he breaks his leg.
Then you can kill.
Shoot him in the head,
the dentist fair.
Here we go.
Weird rules with how we interact with
animals,
not.
I'm definitely not saying you should go
around fucking animals.
I'm not saying you should be able to.
I'm not saying you should hope nobody
interprets.
What we're saying is that.
I'm just saying it is weird that we make
rules about things like that,
like who was fucking these animals to
the point where they're like,
we gotta write this down.
I'm surprised there's not more animal
fucking because think about how horny
people are and you think about people
that can't get laid.
Oh yeah.
And I just.
It seems incredible to me that,
that you don't hear all that.
Maybe it just does.
People don't find out maybe this more
animal fucking going on than we really
are aware of how many,
many people's lives alone with a fucking
giant dog.
Yeah.
Like one of those big fucking sheep
dogs.
That's weird that a guy would live with
that because he's fucking it.
Oh Greg.
That's so not true.
Sometimes they just have a nice pet dog
and they love them and they give him a
kiss on the face and they throw the ball
for him and he's a wonderful companion,
but at least a few guys are out there
right now while I'm talking.
Three hundred million people in this
country plus Mexicans.
What's that number?
Three 50.
Whatever it is.
We don't even know what the number is.
Right,
and we don't want to say plus Mexicans.
I'm not trying to be racist.
You're welcome here.
I say he could stay.
That's what I was.
Fuck.
Yeah,
let stay.
She still fuck
the animals,
but what I'm saying is at a 300 plus
million people,
there's at least one person right now
who has his balls covered in whip cream.
His dog is sucking on his balls and so
many more than that.
Yeah.
At least one though.
He has super confident.
Like if I had.
If they said Mr Rogan,
would you like to bet $10,000
on that being true?
Yes.
That's good money right now.
Out of $300 million has whipped cream on
his balls and he's jerking off while his
dogs looking.
It's not.
And then the,
the map.
So the spots on the map where it's
happening and it would be like those
trump states just like,
you know when you like,
I can't believe they're all red.
It'd be like that's what it'd be like.
Like,
like the sky,
like a constellation in the entire
country would light up.
It'd be like 3000 people at the same
time.
That's too much.
Right?
Well,
that's probably not happening.
It says right here that uh,
there's beastiality is legal in
Kentucky,
Montana,
New Jersey,
Nevada.
Of course,
Ohio.
Texas Jersey does permit civil unions.
You can marry an animal.
You can have a civil union with your
animal.
Fifty five percent of the states were in
beastiality is legal same sex marriage
is not.
Oh my God.
That's a thing that is insulting the
states,
which do not criminalize beastiality
yet.
Banned same sex marriages are Kentucky,
Montana,
New Jersey,
Nevada,
Ohio,
Texas,
Virginia,
West Virginia and Wyoming.
Holy Shit.
They don't criminalize theology,
but they have a ban on dudes.
Marion dudes.
Just a misdemeanor and a lot of other
states too.
What if you,
you're a gay for a male dog,
right?
How's that work?
I think he can't do it.
So if you're allowed to marry a dog,
you could fuck it for sure.
Right now they don't have problems with
beastiality in those towns,
right?
Oh No.
Jersey Jersey allows for a civil union
amongst people who are gay.
They don't allow for a civil union
amongst you and your animal.
Yeah.
How dare you interpreted that way,
but you know,
I mean,
how can,
how can you say that it's okay to fuck
animals.
Gay People can't get married.
That is the way.
The fact that we let that stay on the
books,
like everybody needs to sit down and go,
what are we doing?
Like what's this?
What does this.
Do you think it's okay?
Is it okay to fuck his sheep dog?
But these two lesbians that can't get
married out here,
man,
get out of the way.
Boys that insult and get out of the way.
But now it's national.
Now gay marriage is legal in all states,
correct?
Is it?
I think so.
I mean it'll be challenged once trump
comes in is illegal and all states
federally.
I think it is.
Right?
I think that was a a year ago.
I think it's federally illegal,
but it's the states that have issues
with.
That's interesting.
So it's like the opposite of the problem
with marijuana.
Marijuana being legal in a lot of
states,
but federally illegal,
a weird system.
Never get it.
That was the issue with that lady in
Kentucky.
She wouldn't.
She wouldn't personally wouldn't issue
the marriage license and so that's
right.
You're right,
Jamie,
you're right.
Yeah.
That was that crazy lady for Jesus.
Jesus don't want no clear cut each other
off onto the power of government and
they brought it to the convention.
The Republican convention.
She was a hero.
A goddamn here.
I'll pull it around.
I'm gonna.
You know what I love is the trump's
inauguration.
He see what he's got lined up for the
talent so far.
Mormon Tabernacle choir and some of the
rockettes.
A bunch of them won't do it,
I'm sure.
Meanwhile,
while the Democrats I heard,
I don't know,
is this confirmed that the Democrats are
putting on a concert that same night and
they've got springsteen Lady Gaga,
fucking Jay z and beyonce like literally
like 15 of the biggest names in
entertain and trump is such a star
fucker.
This is kill it up.
How Weird the Democrats are doing
something on the inauguration night like
that.
Why did that?
Maybe it's not that night,
but it's around then maybe they're
trying to fuck with them.
Oh yeah,
totally.
Fucking with them.
I think it's raising awareness that we
have to stay vigilant that,
you know,
I don't think we should shut down
government,
but I think that we should make sure
that the constitution is being honored.
That's the big question right now.
How,
how does a guy go from being a reality
star to being the president?
I mean,
it's almost beyond imagination,
like the fact that it's real and I keep
opening up CNN everyday going,
oh yeah,
everyday,
everyday I'll go to CNN.com.
I go,
Oh yeah,
yeah,
he's the guy.
Oh yeah.
He Won.
Now that bit you did about it last night
about how we just wanted a fuck.
Oh Damn.
Don't give a away.
I'm still working on.
Supposedly this was called the.
We have the people concert,
but I'm not seeing.
There's no tickets for sale right now.
Uh,
we,
the people for trump.
No,
this a democratic concept.
Supposedly.
There's rumors that a promoter was going
to book it.
Is it called a clock of cooks?
A class?
This is a clean.
According to politico,
this was gonna happen,
but cucs or anybody who supports
Hillary.
A cook is cuckold like a guy who.
I mean,
it's not just that.
It's like has been cheated on her cook.
If you're a,
if you're white knighting,
you're a cook.
Like it's a new alt right.
Speak.
No,
she came out of the originally from the
porn,
a phrase cuckold in,
which is like a guy fucks your wife in
front of you and you'll go like some
guys like watching.
Oh No,
it goes back to Shakespeare.
Yeah.
But they,
they changed it.
But how is it that they're maligning her
for her husband cheating when trump has
had three wives.
But wait a minute.
Who's,
who's the deed?
All right.
Isn't that a big generalization?
Well,
they went after they brought,
they brought out,
uh,
all of all of Clinton's ex mistresses at
the Republican convention.
Well,
what's that?
All people that he allegedly sexually
assaulted this a little stronger than
just mistresses.
Um,
I think it's probably a combination.
It's the best stuff.
I think the all stars,
there were women that were accusing him
of rape,
weren't they?
Were they all?
I think so.
It was in the or accusing him of sexual
assault and weren't.
That wasn't.
That was the big deal was it wasn't just
that he had affairs with these women.
Yeah,
it was that.
There was like some allegations,
right?
It's all.
Yeah.
I think that's what it was,
but it is amazing how much that was used
against her list of sexual advances and
things like that.
Sexual advances is,
in my opinion,
very different than sexual assault.
Groping,
groping,
okay.
Forcibly kissing.
So when you say sexual advances,
like it's always like,
what does that mean?
Does he talk to her?
Probably like grabbing pussies.
How dare you,
how dare you.
What is weird is that you know,
without permission,
and again,
I'm not defending trump on this one,
but the first move your first move,
you can either go,
you can go hard or you can be Johnny
Gentlemen.
You know,
and not too many guys are saying,
may I kiss you?
You usually just go in and try to kiss
somebody.
Right?
Which is what he did.
Not only that,
can you go in and grab a woman's Vagina
as your first move?
Can you cut the third?
Can you steal first and second and go
right to third.
Who says you can't?
Well,
if it worked,
it will be a fucking bold move.
Didn't he say they let you.
Wasn't that one of the sun?
Yes.
And he's talking about crazy groupies.
I don't want to defend it because this
is a way to do it.
Like if you're sitting,
like I remember when I was a teenager
there was a girl driving a car and I
didn't know her that well,
but we were like 16 or 17 and while she
was driving I put my hand.
There were like three kids in the back
and everybody's getting high and I put
my hand on her knee and I kind of worked
at.
I worked at down the thigh slowly,
slowly.
Is it okay not saying it,
but it's,
it's dark,
it's quiet.
And I got,
I got to her,
I got her vagina and I massaged it while
she drove.
And then we got to where we're going.
I got out of the car and I never saw her
again.
Was that in fact Joe Rogan immoral?
Not In my eyes.
Um,
girls like boys and boys like girls,
she might've called her friends over and
going,
dude,
check this out.
This do fingered me all the way.
Home was awesome.
And I went home and finished.
Ooh,
maybe she knows she finished.
What does he get home to grab them by
the pussy quote.
What?
He said your girl's hot as shit in the
purple.
Says Bush.
Now coast host of NBC today show I got
to use some tic tacs just in case I
start kissing her.
Trump says.
And when you're a star,
they let you do it.
Trump says,
grab them by the Pussy.
Trump says you can do anything.
He's being funny.
You know,
it's unfortunate that,
that,
that's,
you know,
when people like making this,
this thing about it being a locker room
talk is inexcusable.
You can't say it's locker room talk like
it can't expect someone's words when
it's two guys talking shit to each other
like that to be transferred literally
onto like a,
uh,
like when you're reading it,
you're reading it out and you're not
taking into account.
There are two guys sitting next to each
other on the bus talking shit being
funny and that one of them is a fucking
renowned entertainer and his whole thing
is about him being this braggadocious
winter and uh,
he's,
he's obviously playing it up and he's
playing it up to an audience of one,
not to audience of 80 million or however
many people found out about it or more
or whatever the hell it was that read
that.
But can you see that as a,
as sort of an insight into his character
in terms of showing women from a power
structure of him having the power in
them not.
And will that affect how he leads the
country?
For sure.
That is absolutely a way to look at it.
Another way to look at it is he was used
to groupies that wanted to do and a lot
of them probably did.
I think when you're a fucking
billionaire,
when you're powerful,
forget the money.
Yeah,
but he's also a multibillionaire.
He has many billions of dollars.
The type of gold digging holes,
the muzzle launch themselves in his
direction.
I mean it must be like they must have to
fight them off like,
like the,
the hoard and Lord of the rings.
Just fucking attorney.
I mean,
he's worth a lot of fucking money.
A Gal could just sneak in and take a
piece of that.
You think he's peeled off a million here
and there for women.
It wouldn't hurt them.
Think it wouldn't hurt them.
Maybe take,
get some nice good at a gift shop.
Get yourself settled.
He does not.
He's not a Marauder of business marauder
because just because he likes money.
Like he likes the whole thing.
He likes all of the above and that's
part of all of the above,
of the massive success.
He can do whatever he wants.
He flies in his jet.
He's got billions of dollars.
Got this super hot wife,
he's like,
he's,
he's the president of the United States.
Now he's doing what I mean,
that's standard for his operational
procedure.
He does whatever the fuck he want.
Well,
it's kind of animalistic because if you
think about it,
you know the,
the re procreating is the most important
thing and you get to do that as a male
when you are the most powerful.
So in the animal kingdom,
all that,
everything translates into being able to
fuck the female.
And so for a guy like that,
you know,
to be the most powerful man in his own
mind means this despoiled
yeah,
the winner goes the spoils.
Plus he's heterosexual.
It's just that boils it down.
Heterosexual man with a massive amount
of money and power and you know,
and now he's the president with the
fuck.
We'll see what happens.
It's going to be interesting.
The interesting thing to me is now
there's a guy who has been literally
paying off politicians for the longest
time,
right?
Giving massive campaign contributions.
Now he's the president himself.
What's he going to do when it gets in
there?
I mean,
he's even talked himself about how the
electoral college is stupid and he's
like,
yeah,
well we probably should go to the
popular vote.
He goes,
that would be a different race though.
I didn't try to win the race,
like saying that she won the electoral
vote or that she won the popular vote,
but he won the electoral college vote
and she won the popular vote by many
hundreds of thousands.
Three was he drew three or 4 million
case.
Like he was saying,
well that's a different race.
Like you could do a popular vote.
He goes,
it actually be an easier race,
but it's a different race.
Like if you want to win the electoral
college,
you got to win those states.
It's just how it goes.
And he figured it out and he did it and
she even avoided those states to Bill
Clinton's fucking angst.
Apparently he was furious that there's
some story that he threw a cell phone
down and he was yelling at her,
you got to go to these places.
You've got a campaign.
He was.
She was like,
those aren't my people.
Like too many liberals thought they had
it in the bag.
Too many liberals thought,
well,
everybody thinks the way I think and
everybody I know thinks this.
Trump can be president.
There's people just all throughout those
cornfields just was so happy,
so happy when he got an office man.
There's a lot of instagram posts that I
follow.
Instagram pages.
You go to people's pages and it's all
Hashtag Maga.
Hashtag make America great again.
He gives me my pickup truck and my make
America.
I would have talked to every one of
those motherfuckers in two years.
I want to talk to all of you face to
face and how do you account for
yourself.
Don't say that because then they're
going to blame the liberals and you're a
part of the liberal conspiracy and the
reason why trump wasn't successful
because the liberal back Congress tried
to interrupt the power structure.
Liberals don't back Congress.
Trump,
listen man,
I know how it works.
[inaudible] DOT com.
I'll fucking tell you right now.
The Republicans have the right idea.
If he is not successful.
He's got the Senate and Congress and the
Supreme Court and the Uber Guide,
the gubernatorial control.
He's got it all.
That's Chris's agenda,
doesn't go through.
He cannot blame liberals.
I'm hoping with great sincerity that we
slowly phase out.
The idea of having one individual
president I think is ridiculous and I
think it goes back to the ancient
fucking primates and their alpha male
king.
I think families occupy that one thrown
too many people.
Too many bushes,
too many Clinton's.
Just stop,
stop and would.
If Donald Trump wins and then you know,
few years down the road,
his son gets in,
what if they're the next empire?
That easily could happen.
Yeah,
I know.
You never know.
It's.
The idea
was great when we first started.
The idea was great to have one person
who is really exceptional and have that
one person lead,
but I think at this point in time,
the collective strength of human beings
has been demonstrated really clearly in
this world.
The collective strength is far greater
when everyone contributes,
when it's a collective group of minds
thinking and communicating about things
and people go,
oh well,
you know,
everybody's going to want their way and
we have to realize like what's the right
way?
Like there's too much debate back and
forth about what's the left and what's
the right,
what's the healthy way,
what's the,
what's the correct way for like the
society to be even and smooth and your
kids be able to walk to school in the
morning without worrying about someone
taking them and eating them.
You know,
like there was this fucking guy,
Jordan Peterson that I had on recently.
It was talking about these posters that
they put up in Russia in the 19 thirties
saying don't eat
children
who's talking about Marxism and
communism and where,
where can go awful and where a lot of
these ridiculous posturing intellectuals
that claimed to be Marxist,
they don't understand the consequences
of Marxism and he does really,
really well.
And so,
you know,
you talked about the Gulag archipelago
and reading about all the different
things that had happened to people that
had become indoctrinated into these
ideologies and then started carrying out
these horrific crimes in the name of
them.
And fuck,
it's terrifying.
Finding all the people who died because
of communism.
Like,
like we look at human history,
it's just a bunch of people getting
jacked.
Well wait,
so you're saying that there shouldn't be
a strong leader?
Are there shit because Marxism is
without a strong
later then?
Well I don't think there should be one
person,
but I think we should figure out who the
top minds as far as people that want to
contribute who the top minds are and vet
them out and have a whole goddamn panel
of people like,
you know,
like what,
what superhero movies would they go to?
Like A,
like Captain America,
a council of elders or something.
Right.
You know,
we always have the hose,
we have a bunch of wise men sitting
around there would be glowing from
behind,
like some thor type shit.
Right?
It's literally what we need.
But the elders is the problem because a
lot,
a lot of times these oligarchies become
old people.
Like,
like Congress before,
before Johnson came in,
Congress was literally seniority.
Every committee in Congress was based on
seniority.
The oldest motherfucker ran things and
so crazy and it was crazy and it gets
totally backlogged.
Any legislation.
And he came in and he,
he broke that up.
So he's alive the longest.
He knows the old ways,
right?
Right.
The old ways we will continue the old
words.
Yeah.
Put your powdered wig on.
How long were you away from that?
How long ago was the powdered wig?
Two hundred years ago.
The day.
Whether it was like,
what the fuck are we doing?
I'm not wearing the wig bro.
I'm not wearing the fucking wig.
Like what day?
I should bring it back.
Fuck it.
My hair fell out.
I'm gone.
Powdered we'll with you.
What?
The comedy store you,
you and me.
Fanny fanny packs right here,
dude.
Right there on that.
That's right.
I,
I wear mine all the time and my son gave
me shit about it.
And then guess what?
Six months later he's dead.
He's still got that fanny pack.
What?
He's wearing those.
I'll get 'em one.
Yeah,
I've got some.
My higher primate ones.
Ones.
I'll give you one of those.
Hey,
I wear it all the time.
That's what I'm saying.
I'll praise be to dice clay.
He started.
He told me about it.
Yeah.
Well,
I always wore war fanny packs.
I'd been wearing fanny packs forever,
but they were crappy and then dice clay
came in.
I went,
what is this exceptional piece of
hardware you have around your waist?
It was like,
oh,
you'll like this.
Oh yes.
It's from roots.
Roots,
roots.
His fanny pack.
It's fucking beautiful.
The way it clips together,
it's like it's perfect size or hate shit
in my pockets.
Transmit phone year.
I take everything out of my pockets
wherever I go and I lose shit.
Shorts don't shut.
It was nothing in my pockets.
A little man bag.
That's it.
I wore a fanny pack this morning.
I got a sports one because I ran.
Ooh.
Those are good and I put it around my
waist.
A little sports once.
Oh yeah.
Oh by the way,
shit my pants while running this
morning.
Not Hard,
just a.
It was a shark.
I was coming up the hill.
I was,
I was in mile for,
had nothing left and I and I thought I
had to fart and just Bam shirt and my
underwear.
I did that the other day in my house.
Yeah,
just a little squirt and what she's as
Christ feels like such a failure,
but it had some good farts before the
problem.
Yeah.
I got motivated because I had from you
on it.
You were on a roll.
Rumblers was Jesus and it was just me.
I wish I didn't have to cover them from
nobody,
so I was pausing and leaning into them
and I'm just a little fuck,
fuck,
catch the shower.
That's a shower.
But it was really interesting because as
soon as I got on the bowl,
all of a sudden I had explosive
diarrhea.
I'm like,
where was this?
Like?
I had no idea that some diarrhea was
looming.
Meanwhile that's holiday eating
probably.
Yeah.
Well dreams and shit was also.
I go off the Diet and I started eating
like Pumpkin Pie and ice cream and she
did all the cream.
Yeah,
with a lot of bread.
I had a peanut butter and jelly sandwich
last night,
but as the ultimate failure,
because your job as a human is to
provide for your family and not shit
your pants.
You think about it all the time.
Every time you fart,
you,
you.
There's a little moment where you weigh
in on it.
You feel it out,
feel your intestines,
you fill your anus,
you make a judgment call and you let it
rip.
What's interesting,
if you think about how tuned in you are
to the sensations you get from your
inner colon,
because there's times you know like,
oh no,
I'm about to shit my pants.
There's like A.
There's a certain alarm that goes off
like when you're like,
oh no,
no,
we're concerned
a little too hard here.
Okay,
we've got a problem here boys.
We got a runner.
We got to.
It
just barely keep it in their closing
rates going up and down and it's the
same exact
feeling that you get is when you're
trying to hold common.
You know that Domo.
Yeah,
like superbad and clamping everything in
like that.
I've,
I've always say one day I'm going to try
Tantra.
I'm going to learn how to like
completely like guy said that you can
have like an internal orgasm for your
contractions so long that you come,
but no come,
comes out and your body just reabsorbs
it and it makes you like Super Sayan
power.
Yeah.
I've choked one back.
Wow.
I just got to grab the base right before
impact.
And so what?
He's really hard.
It's got to be long enough where it
begins,
but not so long that it comes out and
I've pushed it back in again.
But what if you cause an injury?
Yeah,
that's the problem.
What have you get crazy and you just
really grab it.
Why?
I've only done it a couple times.
Mop broke your own Dick because you
grabbed it too hard.
God Damn.
Life would not be worth living.
Can you imagine that?
Not Having your Dick come anymore for
the rest of your life and knowing that
what percentage of your life revolves
around getting rid of come once a day.
Okay.
But once a day.
So if it's once a day,
if it's even 45 minutes of your time,
the other 23 hours and 15 minutes are
bullshit.
You thinking like,
this is what I can't lose.
I can't lose
embarrassing.
Myself.
Said to a lot of guys like if you had to
choose between being blind or having
your Dick break where you can ever get
it up again.
Oh no question.
What would you say?
Give me the fucking stick and the dog.
Give me this tv one,
two glasses.
Various to possession
and he's getting laid after the show.
Man.
I was uh,
driving last night and I was listening
to that song.
You know,
sometimes you go through your phone and
you're a look at an itunes,
like recently added like,
Oh yeah,
I forgot I bought this.
I listen to some old school stevie
wonder's superstitious song I listened
to like three times in a row last night.
Coming home from the comedy store,
it's like God damn that song was.
Yeah,
he made some of the great.
I mean just anytime somebody can take
soul and funk and bring it together.
That to me is like,
we were talking about it last night.
I was talking to Dean del Ray about soul
and fucking earth,
wind and fire and uh,
uh,
who did I listened to you?
Yeah.
So sly and the family stone when you get
them when they're pound in that fucking
base and get little little fucking fast
guitar going.
Yeah man.
But I don't know.
I mean there was an amazing time
of music and like the sixties and
seventies,
like sometimes I wonder if we have so
much music that we're constantly
cranking out.
Like how many people go back and check
out some of the old site,
how much great shit just got Kinda Ms.
misplaced,
misplaced last year.
Bruno Mars is bringing back that sound a
lot.
He does some cool shit that's got that
sound.
He's got some great shit.
Childish Gambino album.
I think I've mentioned it to you.
It's almost like a funk album now.
Really.
People were expecting a hip hop album
from because that's what he does
usually,
but it's a lot of like funkadelic will
basically what you're describing.
Yeah,
that's really good.
We sober,
that's the concert.
Did the 1200 milligrams of edibles for.
But I,
I got the CD recently.
I bought it for my mom for Christmas.
Do you understand what he just said?
Twelve hundred milligrams of edibles.
He did.
How much?
How much is a gummy bear?
I like 20.
Oh fuck.
Up At old Brownie.
That was a thousand because I knew it
was going to be a crazy concert.
They did this three d experience,
so I was.
I was going to go in and fight at any
point or it was all was waiting for it
to hit it never hit.
See.
Here's the deal.
Jamie has some weird constitution were
edible.
Weed doesn't work on him.
Wow.
Yeah.
Agent ever hit?
I don't.
I don't think so.
Oh,
he was.
He's always a little high.
That's the problem.
It was like his,
his constitution is like a dude who's on
a low dose of edibles all the time.
So I think when you give Jamie a high
dose of vegetables,
his body goes,
I know want to do with this and your
body just clears it out of the way.
Interesting.
It doesn't work on him.
He's an alien.
I don't know what to do.
He'll be fine.
Take more than Joey Diaz.
He's given me plenty and I've done it.
I like I,
he gave me 800 during a show when he was
on here and I didn't know whatever.
Nothing happened.
Yeah.
He never gets too high.
But.
But here's the thing.
He gets high when he smokes it.
Super.
You have to smoke a lot to get high.
No,
not necessarily.
Totally normal in that regard.
Yeah.
Like normal.
Like if we were all sitting around
passing a joint,
he would hit it the same amount as
everybody else would be.
Just we all be looking at each other
like,
Ooh,
there's been many a podcast we've done
including the beginning of this one.
More as,
as it starts out,
you're like,
whoa.
I don't even know if I should be talking
right now.
I'm barely holding out of the words as
they're coming out of my mouth and
forming them in the right way.
It's like their little fucking clay kids
that are running out of my mouth and I
got to like form.
All right.
Put your hat on.
So barbecued.
Why are you upside down this new weed?
It seems to be getting stronger.
This a la speed.
We'd like to speak.
I want to know what's going on.
Like since legalization hit,
it feels like the weed went up a bump,
like pumped
or maybe ask for less,
less than strong lead.
Like I wanted back in like whatever I
was getting back in Ohio,
like middle,
mid,
we'd call mids.
I just wanted to go back to the middle.
He just gave me something that was like
$5 cheaper.
I was like,
no,
that's not what I wanted.
I wanted what your shit.
He basically
mild.
I don't even have it.
No,
you,
you just got to take a little baby hits.
But the problem is everybody likes
taking a couple of hits.
I that's part of the fun.
She'll take a couple hits,
but like last night at the comedy store
I went way too far.
Way Too.
How many hits is that?
I only.
I never get.
I try not to get too high before the
show,
like I never get as high as I got before
this show.
Before I stand up show I'd like to be
right where I am now,
where I was high a couple of hours ago
and then go on stage if that's the way,
the best way to do it.
But afterwards everybody was just
passing joints around.
It's just since it's legal now,
everybody just goes out and they're all
just passing joints.
Hey man,
he wants some of this.
Oh,
well fuck it.
And Ron White with his contraptions.
He's got the fucking pen.
He's got a joint.
He's got his own Tequila and a cigar.
It's hilarious.
Who drove him home?
I don't know.
Somebody did.
I don't know what happened last night,
but uh,
he was talking about how he left.
Hey,
I'll just left my truck back here,
came back and got it.
It's an animal.
We need more people.
I can see the last of the Mohicans
constitution.
My Dad had that constitution,
you know,
they got John Wayne apparently would be
the last guy drinking.
Then I'd be an a drank whiskey and he'd
be the first guy on set and he was on
point for everything.
If you were late.
He was like,
what the fuck?
I got a buddy of mine who's a firearms
enthusiast in Vegas.
My buddy named Justin Justin.
Justin's a legit giant.
He's like seven feet tall,
300 pounds a gun nut and he can put the
booze away like nobody's business.
First of all,
he's a legitimate hundred pounds bigger
than me and so I can't compete with them
just liver wise,
just like volume wise.
He's just way bigger.
His body just burns through it.
Come on,
dude.
We're drinking.
He just,
he's just,
he's way too big and experienced.
He just puts it away.
What does he drink?
Um,
makers and coke always makers and coke.
Always makers and cover.
You know what together you don't have to
ask.
There is right there.
And if he gets a meal,
the CFDA.
Wow.
Legit giant.
He's the sweetest guy in the world to
super,
super good dude.
So he's.
He's in for two entrees at a meal.
Oh Dude.
We feast in Vegas.
You go to that place was the place he
told me that the Brazilian place he took
me.
Oh,
Fogo de Chao.
Did you guys go there and we'd been to
Texas?
Yeah,
we go to,
um,
there's a bunch of good steak houses,
like a craft steak strip steak.
One of them's the MGM and one of them is
at Mandalay.
I always forget which one's which crafts
steak is mgm.
Right?
That one's dish is one at the palm,
I think.
Called nine.
So good.
Yeah.
That place is amazing.
That plays amazing.
Pick UFC this weekend,
dude,
after 11 tomorrow.
How are you?
See?
Yeah.
You'll see this weekend.
New Year's Eve?
No,
it's the day before New Year's Eve to
not compete with new years eve.
It's the 30th,
so it's Friday night because,
which is super,
super rare.
And it's the return of Ronda Rousey.
Wow.
Yeah,
that's good.
She's fine.
Just fighting the champion.
Amanda Nunez,
very intense match up.
Run around.
He had been trained like a fucking demon
man.
It's crazy.
It's kind of frightening.
So are you doing to share while you're
out there?
No,
not this time.
Just hanging out.
Just gonna hang out with some friends
are in town.
I don't want to always do shows like,
uh,
tomorrow night I'm going to work out
with mark [inaudible].
So a kickboxing trainer.
That's a real good buddy of mine that
works in the UFC and he's going to be
there.
So we'll do the weigh ins,
go get something to eat and go to the
gym,
go wax and pads around.
It's fun.
Just relax.
You take the weekend off because I can
come in to read the weigh ins on the one
day which this way usually it's Friday,
but it be Thursday now.
Then the fights are on Friday night.
And then d,
do you do much prep?
You have to like review stats and stuff?
Most of the prep I do,
I just do naturally,
believe it or not because I'm just
curious about the fights because I know
they're coming up.
So like we did a breakdown show on,
um,
Monday.
Yeah,
on Monday we did a breakdown show.
We went over the card and I'll do more
of that on my own,
but it's not like anybody asked me to do
it and it's not like I'm,
I'm doing it because I want to do it.
I do.
I'm doing it because it enhances my
appreciation of the fights.
Find out a little bit about each dude,
watch a few of his old fights go,
Ooh,
I like how he does this or look how she
does that.
Or Oh,
this guy's got a good one,
good position.
Like if you get,
he gets you in this position.
He finished his guys.
So it's fun to do it from that
perspective.
So then when I'm watching the fight,
um,
I've,
I've got a kind of an understanding of
how,
at least how they used to move,
you know,
six months ago or a year ago.
People get better quick too is the other
weird thing about this world.
The MMA world is changing so fast.
The like the level of athlete is moving
in such a fast direction.
These guys keep getting better and
better and better and better and better
and they're all getting better,
so it's hard to tell,
but when you can pair like a top level
athlete of today versus a top level
athlete have,
you know,
20 years ago,
that's when you see these stark gigantic
differences.
You know,
when the UFC started in [inaudible] 93
in comparison to 2016,
it's just stark crazy differences,
which you're not going to see guys stay
at the top as long you think,
well,
some guys or some girls can,
you know,
depending on how good they are,
some people just have massive advantages
that are very difficult to overcome.
Like Anderson Silva,
when he was in his prime,
Anderson Silva had a massive advantage
in timing and speed and creativity and
striking.
Whereas he could defend himself on the
ground.
He was difficult to take down and when
he got him down,
he's pretty good defensively with his
guard,
but standing up he's a goddamn genius.
He was a virtuoso and he would just like
move on you and do weird shit to you.
And then blam catch you with a front
kick to the face or something.
He would time you figure you out,
find your distance and then land some
crazy shit on you and fuck you up.
And it did it to so many people.
So when a guy like that I was at the
top,
he's so truly exceptional at one
particular aspect of the,
of the game.
A lot of times they can go on a good
run,
you know?
So it's,
it's hard.
It's hard for people to go on a run like
demetrius mighty mouse Johnson's
probably on like the longest run as a
champion now.
I think on the longest run the most wins
as a champion.
I think he's,
he might be like right up there with
Anderson in the most wins.
And then maybe John Jones is in there
too.
Wait,
is he?
He's the smallest guy.
He's won 25.
He's a flyweight champion.
But he's a,
in my opinion,
he's the best pound for pound guy
because if you look at like,
he's definitely smaller than the other
guys.
He couldn't move differently because
he's not so way down by gravity.
So it's,
it's very difficult to like look at his
movements and say,
well you could compare him to a guy like
for Overdo,
it was 240 pounds,
like for Breesa was just more hampered
down by gravity.
Like his body just has to push around so
much more.
There's no way he can move with the kind
of fluidity that I got like mighty
mouse,
Ken.
And what's the biggest guy?
That mighty mouse will fight?
Anderson Silva 10 fight win streak.
And Demetrius Johnson is at eight right
below George St Pierre,
which is at nine at night now.
I think this is as of July.
Oh okay.
So Demetrius defended his title again
recently.
So he's tied with George St Pierre for
second place.
So that's like a guy like Anderson.
Perfect example,
super tough.
John Jones,
another one.
Perfect example.
Jon Jones is a ridiculously talented
athlete and so like when you have these
like really,
really talented guys like extreme
outliers,
they,
they tend to be able to go on roles also
because when you fight them,
it's terrifying because you know,
you're stepping in there with the Alpha
who's stepping in there with Anderson
Silva and his prime and he bows to you
and you're like,
oh my God,
what the fuck have I gotten myself into?
You know?
Yeah,
you can pump yourself up for it and get
yourself thinking like,
I'm the fucking man now.
But like when you actually across the
street from the man and you're looking
at each other eye to eye and you realize
like that's Anderson motherfucking Silva
and I'm about to step into the ring,
step into the octagon rather with the
best ever.
He do enhanced sit on the edge of a tall
building,
so it's hard for them to get over that.
It takes a super strong mind just to be
able to fight at your best.
Whether or not your best is good enough.
That's another aspect of the fight.
Whether or not your best is good enough
is really secondary because you're not
going to be able to be at your best.
You're going to be so freaked out and so
fucking nervous.
Your timing's going to be off.
Your adrenaline is going to be fucking
pumping through your veins.
You might get an adrenaline dump,
so you might tie her out in the second
round.
You got to manage your resources.
You got to manage your anxiety and your
facing a goddamned engine,
like a real live superhero character and
he's seeing all of those weaknesses in
you.
He sees everything.
He sees everything too.
When you start moving around,
when you would move around with them,
he had moved around with you and he
would see how you move,
whether they move slow,
like he would take his time.
He would take his time and then just
open up on guys.
It's fascinating to watch him,
man,
because he would dissect guys.
You'd see him dissect and guys he'd be
bouncing around and move and he would
change his footwork.
He would like throw a little fake your
way and see how you react to you.
I could have hit you right there.
Okay,
I see what's going on here,
and then you do some stuff at him and
he's like,
no,
not today with that.
And you would see him doing all these
calculations in his mind and setting up
traps and then somewhere in the second
round he would attack and when he was in
his prime,
it was just stunning to behold.
Here he is right now,
hood a standing in front of this guy,
hands down,
and he just barely moves his head out of
the way.
It's just timing.
I'm just trying to figure out then Plop
pop some with a jab and drops him.
I mean,
you're watching all this in slow motion
to unfortunately,
but this was when he fought.
You should Okami.
I mean he was just an assassin back
then.
He was so good.
That's when he was the middleweight
champion and he was just a lighting
people up in there.
Man,
if you're a guy guy,
get up because he's better on his feet.
I didn't give a fuck dude.
Go to Anderson Silva highlight reel.
See if you could find that.
He didn't give a fuck if you were on
your feet like you were going to get
knocked out against him in his prime.
That's his attitude.
He would stand with anybody.
I mean,
his standup was so exceptional,
but he's still fighting.
Yeah,
he's still fighting,
but he's 40,
40 or 41 now and that's the only fucking
thing in the world that's undefeated.
His father time,
man.
Just check this out.
This is him when he was in his prime,
just slides out of the way and drops out
dude with a punch.
I mean he just had a way of moving.
Let's just see if you have a like a
highlight reel.
Not just this one fight.
Oh,
it's highlight tribute.
okay.
I see.
But it's just the same fight a couple
times in a row.
This guy had a real good chance to get
some travis luder.
There's a bunch of people that he
fought.
They're showing.
He was so goddamn good.
That's Travis Luder caught in a triangle
getting elbowed in the head.
He was,
at that time in particular,
he was the next level of striking
because we had never seen anybody who
had like real world class striking
skills in the middleweight division like
Anderson did.
He just had,
especially in particularly in mma,
striking,
just grounded his balance is amazing.
While he was just exceptional,
truly exceptional and physically strong
for sure.
But the big thing about Anderson wasn't
like how big he was.
It was just how,
how technical it was and how,
uh,
how brilliant his uh,
ability to,
uh,
figure guys out was.
This was the guy he fought named Lee
Marie Lee Marie is the guy who put on
the biggest bank robbery in the history
of the great of Great Britain.
That guy stole hundreds of millions of
dollars,
allegedly from a bank and is in jail I
think in Morocco now because of it.
But,
uh,
he was an assassin to and they to meetup
and Anderson Silva lit them on fire.
Just fucked him up.
Just stood right in front of them.
Lead,
kick the shit out of him,
beat his ass,
took his best shots.
He was so good.
So you friends with Silva?
I know him,
I see him.
He doesn't speak English that good,
but I always give him a hug when I see
him.
He's a very nice guy.
Yeah.
And again,
it's the greatest of all time if you're
a fan of the sport in my opinion,
like that guy when he was in his,
like whatever.
There's like a few year period where
someone exist at the highest
of our pms and when he was in the
highest of our pms,
the argument is really between him and
maybe fate or a million Eiko who fought
in pride.
Um,
I think fate or is a real possibility.
Like I could,
I definitely could see the argument that
he was number one instead of Anderson.
But it's really like,
who the fuck knows they play on
different organizations,
different people,
you know,
I think the,
the talent level probably a little bit
better in the UFC,
but it's arguable that it wasn't because
he was fighting cro cop in his prime and
Nogueira in his prime and he it fade or
fought some of the all time greats at
their best and beat them.
So it's arguable that he fought a
tougher range of opponent.
So maybe it's arguable that fate or his
accomplishments or more impressive
because of the opposition he fought was
bigger,
more dangerous.
And I fought cro,
cop cro,
cop was just a,
an assassin,
just smashing people,
knocking everybody dead and he walked
him down and out kickbox them mostly.
That's mostly what the fight was about.
So when you get to know these guys,
like I'm sure you're more friendly with
some than others do.
Is that hard to affect your,
the way you call the fights in terms of,
uh,
being critical?
It can be.
I try not to make it though.
I try really hard to be as objective as
possible,
but what I'm saying and sometimes people
get upset like that I'm friends with
because I'm talking about things that
they're doing wrong or things that are
going wrong for them and so they'll
think that I'm rooting against them and
I'm like,
look,
I'm not.
And they'll say something to you back.
Yeah,
we'll have conversations with them.
I'm like,
dude,
I am not rooting against like,
this is what I'm seeing.
I'm seeing this like I'm seeing,
you know,
I know you're thinking that you're
winning this part of the fight or you're
thinking that I'm being hypercritical,
but I have to say it.
If I'm seeing it and I'm not,
I try really hard to have a point like I
don't want.
I'm not a critical person.
I'm like mocking someone for no reason
or did a talking in a negative way about
their technique for no reason.
It's only because it's not,
it's not happening and I want everybody
to know the momentum of the fight and
also I want to know what's going on
that's wrong.
Like so because your,
your job as a commentator is not just to
to say what's happening and talk about
what's happening,
but in mma it's also to explain things
like I have to explain certain things
like that are critical in a fight.
Like save someone gets kicked in the leg
really hard a few times.
You see them start to limp on it.
I have to point out that I see him
limping now.
This is going to be huge issue.
If he tries to shoot in or if he wants
to move away,
it's going to hinder his mobility.
It's a very important.
So then the people at home now they go,
okay,
well that makes sense.
Oh Yeah,
look,
that guy is limping.
Oh Shit.
He got hit in that same spot again.
Now he's on the ground again.
Oh my God.
He can't get up.
I see it now.
So you know,
you know you're a storyteller.
You're also,
you're,
you're talking about a mathematical
problem essentially a problem.
It's being duped out.
Like there's literally like force
problem.
It's like this versus this and you're
trying to get there.
You're trying to hit harder in the
better positions,
so like the geometry of the human body,
you're trying to accelerate towards the
vulnerable areas and do it better.
So what are the best ways to do that?
And then there's a science and art
behind doing it in the best way.
And it's my job to explain that science
and art to the best.
I can live in motion while it's all
happening.
I can't be biased.
I try very hard to not be,
you know,
because it's really important that I
point out both sides and sometimes
people who accuse you of it and I swear
to God if,
uh,
if you do feel that I'm doing it,
it is absolutely not intentional.
I try very hard to try to be as balanced
and unbiased as I can walk splaining
exactly what I see playing out.
Even with my friends.
Like I'll see my friend getting fucked
up and I'm like,
he's,
he can't drop that right hand.
He's driving that right hand.
The guy stepping to the right and he's
going to catch them.
And then boom,
when they catch them,
like fuck,
like you see it happening sometimes
before they can see it.
Does that ever affect how close you let
yourself get to a fighter?
No,
no,
no.
I respect them all very deeply.
You know?
And I,
and I,
I,
I'm really good friends with a lot of
them and I want the best for all of
them.
And that sounds contradictory.
It sounds like impossible.
Like someone will think like if they
fight that person and they hate that
person and you like that person,
but you like them,
like you're,
you're a trader or something or like
what?
How can you talk to that person?
How can you talk to him?
He's my mortal enemy,
but look,
man,
I hate the fact that you guys are
enemies.
I don't know how much of is real,
how much of it you do it for press,
but I'm not happy with it.
But I liked the guy.
He's a good guy.
The guy.
I can be friends with,
somebody that you're not friends with.
Like if you have some guy that you don't
let,
you would have to have a good reason,
you know,
like somebody fucked you over.
I couldn't be like a competitive reason.
Like two guys who fought and they're
bitter about it,
you know what I mean?
Like if it was like if you told me about
some guy fucked you over and a business
deal or something like that,
I'd be like,
oh well fuck that guy.
You know what?
That guy did something wrong.
It's just a competitor.
Like that fucking guy I tried to follow
in Miami and I bombed.
Fuck him.
Like,
you know,
like I kicked your ass.
Yeah.
You know.
And that's with a lot of fighters,
they develop these very,
these deeply sort of conflicting
relationships with fellow fighters.
Like you can't get too close to them
because then you're going to have to
fight them or.
Yeah.
Some guys don't give a fuck.
Some guys become friends with guys than
wind up fighting him.
Oh yeah.
And is there any shay stories of that
happening?
A lot of guys,
a lot of guys have done a lot of guys.
They started out friends and then
because they had a fight each other like
Jon Jones and Rashad Evans,
that was a big story like Rashad Evans
was like Jon Jones,
bigger older brother and they were real
close and then when John fought for the
title,
he fought for the title because Rashad
was injured and John won the title.
John stepped in on short notice,
one the title,
and then it became a possibility of one
day Rashad fighting John for the title
and then they wound up getting super
bitter about it and not liking each
other anymore.
It's really,
really interesting to watch,
but that's just one example.
There's a lot of guys who are close,
close guys.
They're buddies
with each other and they get in there
and they beat the fuck out of each
other.
Yeah,
it's crazy and not get close.
It's like with Comedians,
you know,
you talked about hanging out at the
store.
It's like,
I can't talk like somebody was telling
me about,
like he hates being called a legend who
said that.
I'm not gonna say Whoa,
zero legend.
Yeah.
Oh Dawn Gavin.
Now,
I mean,
and the point was,
well I don't want to know,
just telling me it was Ron White,
oh ha.
And I and he is,
he's alleging is legit,
but I think he got,
he got an intro of being a legend the
other night you were saying to me,
I fucking hate that because you know,
I'm in here scrap and like everybody
else,
you know,
these lineups are killed.
Like the lineup the other night was
like,
it was like Dalea and you and him and a
nick and succeed and it's like on any
given night you don't want to be called
the legend because that's just
immediately puts you on a shelf instead
of in the fight.
And so anyway,
he said that to me and the reason I want
to say it is I could see somebody taking
that into context and going like,
oh,
you hate being called alleged.
But it's like I can.
I've been called that by young comics
and it's like,
don't call me a fucking legend because
I,
first of all,
I didn't earn it.
And second of all,
like I'm still playing the game.
I'm still on the roster here,
but I was just thinking like you can't
have that conversation with somebody
who's not doing what we do because it
would almost sound like a,
like you're full of yourself and it's
same thing with fighters.
It's probably things that they can only
talk to each other about that they could
never talk to straight people about it
because they just haven't been there.
Oh for sure.
So how do you not get close to other
fighters that you might have to have to
fight one day?
Especially when there's a lot of guys in
the same way,
in the same camp,
which is very beneficial because if you
get a bunch of like really good guy like
team Alpha male is a perfect example of
that.
There's all these guys that are around
the 135,
255 pound weight class,
but it's like really elite Guy in 1:25
even.
But a lot of elite guys in the lower
weight classes and they all train
together but they never fight each
other.
Yeah.
And then they had a big falling out
because Tj dillashaw won the title and
then he left team Alpha male and went to
Denver and now they don't like each
other like this.
There's so much camaraderie and,
and,
and teams and,
and like there's this weird sort of
tribal bond that goes with teams and the
teams that compete against other teams
and they're like gangs and a lot of way,
a lot of ways,
but you know,
they're not,
they're not criminals,
they're just a bunch of dudes that are
bonded together.
And women too fucking serious hardcore
women in the sport.
Now there's like Amanda Nunez,
the world champion,
she's the first openly gay MMA fighter.
He's a champion rather first openly gay
MMA champion.
And she's the women's 135 pound fighter.
She's the one who's going gonna Fight
Ronda Rousey.
Where is she from?
She's from Brazil.
That she lives in Florida.
Strains at American top team.
Just like the big camp.
It's like there's a few big camps all
throughout the world,
but when it comes to like elite level
MMA fighters,
like who's got the biggest amount of
them,
it's between Jackson's in Albuquerque,
New Mexico and um,
Miami American top team.
They just have so many fucking elite
fighters.
Tough for her to train with people if
she's that good to find somebody who's
appear.
Now she,
she fucking fights with dudes.
Dudes.
I'm sure that a lot of them do.
Almost all women spar with dudes at
least somewhat.
And that's the most of the dudes,
at least in high level camps are very
respectful.
Like they're not,
they're not gonna.
Try to hurt a woman.
The best people in the best camps now
realize the,
uh,
the damage that you take.
Inspiring.
It's like a frequent conversation now
it's like to not spar hard.
Like sparring should almost be like
technical and playing and like very
light.
So you're not damaging your body,
not taking unnecessary shots.
Taking people to the leg.
Well,
you kick them a little bit in the legs.
It's not bad,
but the problem is the head.
That's the real problem.
You know,
and even kicking him in the leg,
there's no,
no reason to kick someone full blast.
You know,
you kicked the bag full blast.
You don't need to kick a person full
blast.
And so these big teams,
the more talent you get in like one
weight class,
the more you get a bunch of sharks
circling the same seal or whatever the
fuck you,
whatever the analogy would want.
Like you get better,
more competition,
you better interaction as long as
there's a good comradery between all the
fighters,
but it's so hard to maintain.
Almost always wind up getting mad at
each other.
So many fucking hit somebody after
practice and some of the,
you know,
there's always some thing where they're
going to have to fight.
Some days they talk shit to each other
and know well also,
I mean I'm sure you know a lot more
about this than I do,
but the people that will be drawn to a
sport like this might be contentious
people.
They might be people that have pretty
good size egos and are maybe
confrontational and so those people
aren't going to necessarily always
interact that well with others.
Quite a few of them for sure,
but you'd be amazed.
It's one of the more fascinating things
about mma.
You'd be amazed at how many college
educated,
very reasonable rational people just
view it as the ultimate extreme
challenge.
Whether it be,
you know,
riding a fucking snowboard off the top
of a mountain and you get dropped off in
a helicopter and you go down the side of
a cliff.
It's those kinds of people.
Yeah,
like those kinds of extreme athlete.
People that might've gotten into BMX
riding or might've gotten into a lot of
things that we don't think of as being
like a violent aggressive,
but they're ultra risk taking sports and
the reward that comes from doing like a
flip when when you're,
you know,
bmx jumping and you flipped through the
air and land on your feet.
Like that's I'm cheating death thing.
And those same people.
I think a lot of like elite ones are
getting.
They're getting interested in possibly
competing in MMA and taking that risk
and challenging themselves in that way.
So you see a lot of very smart people,
man.
It's,
and I think that at the highest level
you have to be smart like you.
We've talked to a guy like John Jones.
He might make some poor decisions with
his life because parties aligned.
It's kind of
crazy,
but he's very smart.
When you talked to them and you look in
his eyes,
you know whether or not he has access to
the same vocabulary as Christopher
hitchens did.
No,
maybe not.
But he's a fucking genius.
And fighting.
He knows how to figure people out.
He knows how to fight under pressure is
good as anybody alive.
And when you talk to him,
he's very engaging.
He's not in any way stupid.
He's a very smart guy.
He has his interest in his focus and if
he is his focus and his interests were
an intellectual pursuits,
if he,
if that was really what stimulated him
and made him want to,
uh,
you know,
to follow through on something like
that,
I'm sure he'd be really good in that.
Yeah.
I would think it's real easy for people
to sort of discredit someone and
someone's intellectual capacity just
because I wasn't talking about
intellect.
I was just talking about in terms of
Alpha status,
that it is hard to put a bunch of Alpha
people near each other without a little
bit of a,
you know,
banging elbows.
Yes.
But my point is that less than you would
think it would be much more comradery
and much more social,
like very reasonable interaction
gentlemen interaction than you would
imagine.
There's much more of that.
Yeah.
But the problem is a guy like conor
mcgregor comes along and he talks mad
shit and he likes the world on fire and
everybody wants to talk shit now and I
get it.
I get it.
I mean,
it sells,
it sells paper view.
It's good for the sport.
They more money if they talk shit food.
They just released this thing on a.
someone did it on how much?
Conor mcgregor.
He sold more paper views in a year than
the entire roster combined.
Wow.
You compare all the other fights of
like.
I forget how it was dealt with.
Brendan Schaub sent it to me.
He sent it to you,
Jamie,
but I saw.
I'll try to find out what kind of money
are we talking about.
I got it right here.
I don't know what he gets paid.
I don't under.
I don't know how much he gets per paper
view,
but look at us.
The entire roster drew three point three
to three point two.
Oh,
three to three point $2 million in 2014.
Conor mcgregor drew double that on his
own in 12 months.
Well,
GSP holds the record for the most pay
per view buys in total because he had a
lot of paper reviews more than connor.
Connor holds basically every other paper
view.
Record.
Mcgregor has drawn an insane six point
eight,
5 million buys and just 15 months.
Holy Shit.
Wow.
Twice as many buys in one year than the
entire UFC roster in 2014.
Just his fights.
So whereas a run see making.
Well that's a good question.
Like um,
he was saying recently that uh,
he wouldn't fight unless it's a,
well actually nate Diaz was saying that
he wouldn't fight rather,
um,
who was his opponent in the last,
not this last fight,
which was a Eddie Alvarez,
but the fight before that,
there was a rematch with nate.
Nate beat him in the first five and then
it was a real close fight in the second
fight.
And Connor wanted decision and nate
saying that he won't fight unless he
gets 20 million bucks and a lot of
people say,
well that's too much.
He's not going to get paid that I don't.
I don't know how much.
Like,
how much money is there?
Like let's look at it this way to be 20
million in purse or in endorsements or
it's going to be perse,
but here's.
And paper you is separate than purse,
right?
Well,
no,
no paper views based on pers.
Pers is based on paper,
like you get points or you get a piece
of the action or you can get a
guarantee,
right?
So if it's going to be guaranteed,
like say if that's what he said.
And obviously I'm not a mathematician,
we know this,
right?
So if he said 20 million bucks,
that's what he wants to fight for them.
If paper view is what,
$60,
how much does it cost?
Let's say it's 60 and they,
let's say they sell a million paper
reviews,
which is an excellent number.
That's $60.
Million dollars,
right?
Yep.
Okay,
so $60,000,000.
He wants a third of that right off the
top and then you would got to think,
well who's going to fight?
Conor?
Conor is going to take a third of that
to write it.
At least he's going to,
he's not going to take less than me.
What's up nate?
And he's gonna fight conor.
So if he's gonna fight connor,
Connor's going to take probably even
more than that.
Right?
So it's 20 and what?
Twenty five.
So there's less for the UFC then those
two guys.
Well that's how it is in boxing,
that's how it is in like if you look at
the person's for like a lot of boxing
matches the way they have it described
as like the big guys like floyd
mayweather get the lion's share of the
purse and then everybody else gets less
including the promoter.
So ticket sales,
which is probably just a couple of
million ticket sales are probably pretty
substantial or anywhere it is to get
five.
It was 17 point 7 million.
So there you go.
Seventeen point 7 million in Madison
Square Garden.
Right.
And then what about that giant Vegas
place that the t mobile arena in Vegas,
that's a lot more people.
When that sells out,
what is it?
You're saying $70 million for one ticket
sales.
That's the square garden.
Holy Shit.
Yeah.
So then you've got merchandise,
but that's theirs,
right?
Because it's about the UFC.
It's not about the fighter like I don't
think.
I mean maybe if the fighter is selling,
they're selling conor mcgregor
merchandise.
That's a different story.
Yeah.
Then they should definitely get a giant
chunk of that.
I don't know how much they get.
And then this isn't including
sponsorships.
Well,
there's no sponsors,
right?
The UFC has some sponsors in the
octagon.
I mean they have some movie sponsors and
stuff,
but as for the fighters,
there's really no sponsors that they
carry into the octagon with them.
The only sponsors,
Reebok and some people have a deal with
monster energy drink.
Again,
putting hats on after they went.
Not always in the UFC,
most likely in beltour or unless they
have a monster energy drink deal.
So UFC also has a deal with but it's,
it's,
it's real.
It's real weird.
For the longest time they did,
they had it all over their shorts.
They would wear whatever they want.
They would wear tee shirts coming into
the octagon based on.
But then they signed this deal with
Reebok and a lot of people are upset
about it.
They have to wear reebok stuff now.
Okay.
It's a hot point.
I'm sure.
A lot of money.
Yeah,
it is for a lot of fighters,
for a lot of fighters it's like it was
hundreds of thousands of dollars.
So um,
so in terms of like how much money is
left then,
how much does it cost to run a global
organization like that?
How much does it cost to keep the
infrastructure alive?
How much does it cost to upload
everything to review,
how much does it cost to hire all these
people?
How much does it cost to put that
production together?
Right.
So if it's only 60 million bucks and
then 15 million bucks from obviously,
I don't know.
And there's got to be international shit
too because they sell it internationally
all over the world.
I mean the UFC is everywhere.
So a big fight,
Nate Diaz and conor mcgregor doesn't
just sell in the United States.
It sells everywhere.
I don't know if that's all included.
I don't know how they work that shit
out.
But my point is when someone says he
wants $20,000,000,
that might make sense or that may may
not make sense.
Like I don't know what the numbers are.
And also you gotta pay taxes,
like if you're making all that money,
if you're bringing it all that money,
you got to pay taxes on that money.
Who pays the taxes?
Does UFC pay the taxes first and then
pay the fighters out of what's left?
Do they all act as private contractors?
That's a good question.
But I don't know.
But as far as like how much money
they're making,
I think for a guy like conor mcgregor,
the correct answer would be a fuckload
yeah.
He's making fuckloads of what's at five
fights a year.
He's not fighting that often,
but he's.
He's probably fought in the last 24
months.
How many?
How many times have you fallen the last
24 months he went on a crazy run beat.
Although he be dentists,
seaver all though.
And then the nate diaz fight.
Eddie Alvarez
Twenty 15.
So one,
two,
three times in Twenty 15,
three times in 2016.
So that's about right.
That's a lot of $5.
Million a year.
Every four months.
Like that is very hard on your body.
Very hard on your body.
Hard to do.
But some guys like cowboy,
cowboy cerrone,
he lives off that.
That's what he love.
Think about it.
If you break down the numbers though,
and granted nfl or NBA has a lot more
revenue coming in,
but you're also paying and you know,
nfl,
you got what 44 guys on the team is
interested in these traders,
all that fucking shit.
You should look like
the number was put up,
the number of revenue,
the amount of revenue that they bring in
versus the UFC.
It's hilarious.
But the NFL is like $375 billion.
The UFC is like to.
Yeah,
I mean the difference is fucking
preposterous.
Yeah.
Like find out there's a chart,
like a graph that they can show you that
somebody put together that shows you the
NBA,
the nfl,
Major League baseball and MMA is like
below hockey
and you know that porn use to beat all
of them put together NBA,
nfl,
all of it.
And CBS,
NBC and ABC as well.
And all the major movies all together,
dwarfed by porn.
And now it's gone.
Now it's all gone.
I mean the Avn awards at its height,
I hosted it when it was 7,000
people in the audience on showtime.
Now it's like 200 losers in a room with
an open mic or hosting it.
Yeah,
it's over.
Whoa.
I shouldn't say
that.
I don't want to disparage them.
Let's just say it's smaller than it used
to be.
I just think they're doing awesome.
Craft work now.
Now it's.
They're doing it for the love of the
art,
I think.
Sounds different.
I mean I.
for me it's all about Japanese hidden
camera.
Massage porn.
That's your shit.
Yeah,
because it's real.
I got to see shit.
That's real casting couch guarantee that
a lot of that is real.
That's what I liked.
Nerves.
Want to see the girl a little bit
nervous.
Confused.
I want to see the transition in her eyes
from I'm auditioning for a Pajama
commercial to.
I'm taking it
hit hard on camera.
Yeah.
I don't want to see two people that are,
you know,
too into it.
I want to see.
I want to see somebody get taken for a
ride.
Somebody just get hoodwinked.
Yeah.
Like the massage thing,
they're getting a regular massage from a
woman and it's a good massage.
You can tell that these are like
practice misuses,
and then all of a sudden they just get
their there,
their on their stomach and they,
they get up in that ass crack a little
bit and they get down in the valley and
you can see and they've got a camera on
the woman's face and above and below and
usually somewhere else and they keep it
on the face.
You can see the eyes open and kind of
look around and I'm telling you,
fucking Mia Farrow,
who's a great actress.
A Jane Fonda couldn't portray the Sufi
dunaway.
Faye dunaway could not portray the
subtle nuances of coming around to being
suddenly fingered by.
I'm assuming.
Oh,
so you think it's real.
I defy anybody.
I will.
I will send you clips that are
undeniable.
I think you should take that and run
with it.
Just don't look at anything that points
to the contrary.
Right?
Why would I?
Why would you?
What his line of perception.
It's not reality.
It's not empowering to think that that's
staged and you're just being tricked by
some unenthusiastic people didn't need
the money.
No.
You want to think that this is a real
massage.
Absolutely.
Realize finger in her completely.
Heck no,
I don't watch those.
You don't want something because that
seems rapey rapey.
But what if the guy's laying down the
grill just starts sucking his dick.
Now that's from a girl and guy gets a
massage from a girl.
She just starts blowing them.
Well,
she,
you know,
a woman is pleasuring.
Another woman.
Okay,
I see what you're saying.
You like it?
Yeah,
because it's.
I enjoy it.
You want to see everyone had a good day.
Everybody had a good day.
You know the [inaudible] is getting paid
handsomely.
She knows she's on camera.
Plus they're lesbians.
I think most women are.
They don't get a chance to explore it as
much.
Wow.
Strong words for some hidden cameras and
they're receiving what really happened.
I can't believe he's saying that.
I believe that all women have the
propensity for lesbians,
lesbianism because it's soft.
They're being touched in a gentle way.
Not The way I do it.
I do my lesbian and stuff.
Lesbian biker style.
Yeah.
That's style.
A lot of hardware.
What kind of.
What style of fucking do you employ?
Something like a lesbian biker.
My shirt.
I'm like,
how a lesbian would fuck you if she was
mad with a strap on.
Yeah,
she's mad.
Angry boots on.
You were flirting with a guy.
The pizza thought so just fucking.
Oh,
you were talking to the enemy?
Yeah.
She's got like a strap on with like
little,
like a dog collar with those little
buttons.
Little silver snaps pops in place.
Yeah.
Big Green Dick.
That's what I think.
Yeah.
She probably heats it up in the water.
Just like that chicken cutlet trick I
told you earlier.
I can't wait to get home.
Hi.
Do we have for dinner tonight?
Greg Fitzsimmons and space and pool.
Tell these people where to were to get
your tickets.
One more time.
Fits dog.com.
Also check out the podcast fits dog
radio numbers.
Had been shooting up the last six
months.
I've doubled my downloads.
That's what the fuck happened.
Podcasting is super popular.
Big Man do to come back.
You came out with New Year's Day.
Two thousand 16.
Let's,
um,
let's do it soon.
Yeah,
I'm around for awhile.
I love it soon.
Yeah.
Your podcast is awesome.
It's still on.
I'm serious as well.
I'm doing the show on Sirius Monday
nights at 5:00
pst and uh,
and today's.
Have those shows ever available online?
Yes.
They're on the APP there on the serious
side of sap.
And then also they're letting me release
the old serious episodes now on the
podcast.
So I got.
I got Brian Wilson for the beach boys
coming up.
Norm Mcdonald.
Bunch of.
Great.
Cool.
I'm glad they do.
That's a very powerful move by serious.
Yeah.
Congratulations.
Serious company.
That's a great company,
man.
That's how it should be done.
That's a very cool thing that they did.
I've been there for eight years.
I've never gotten one note about.
Do this right in the fucking note right
now.
Stuck.
Stuck talking about chicken cutlets.
Greg Fitzsimmons.
Are you at the door night?
Uh,
I'm not a New Year's eve at cobb's.
That's San Francisco.
Fuck,
yeah,
that's a God damn.
That's one of the great clubs.
Yeah.
That's one of the best.
That's a fun one.
All right,
thanks brother.
Thanks man.
Bye everybody.
See you next week.
No ads today.
Bucket no ads before or after on a.com.
Use the code word rogue and bye.