Hey everybody,
I snuck up on you bitches barely let you
know that we were doing a podcast today
at all.
So there's a lot of people on Ustream
that are like the really hardcore freaks.
They're sitting in front of the camera,
the computer waiting for Shit to start
and those are the ones that are paying
attention right now.
We did.
I didn't even smoke weed dude.
Be careful. The government is
listening. This is federally illegal.
Um, the Joe Rogan experience podcast
is brought to you by several things.
One of them is, does
that me? Yeah, that's me.
Of course I'm to retard is a Ting Tang
is a cell phone company that we've been
working with.
That is a really interesting experiment
in the way a cell phone company conducts
business and one of the things they're
doing is they have no contracts. Okay.
Complete, no contracts, excellent phones.
They sent me the Samsung Galaxy
s three and it is the shit.
I am using it right now. It's an amazing
phone. It's on the sprint network,
which is a, it's great for service.
Joey Diaz raves about splint sprint.
He's had sprint for awhile
and I've been using it now.
I really enjoy the big screen on this
fucking phone and it's hard to go back to
an iPhone.
Even this little iPhone five,
you silly little bitch
with your extra half inch.
Dario,
I might go to Tim because I got so pissed
off at apple and they fucked my iPhone
five order up and I might just fucking
say fuck it and get one of these s three
dude, we'll hook you up. You
need to get one of these.
The galaxy s three is for looking at
photos and looking at the web and looking
at like videos and movies. You can't
beat it, man. It's, it's incredible.
When people send you pictures,
it's like,
it's almost like looking
at a picture on a laptop.
It's just so vibrant and big and the
screen's amazing and the operating system
is so, it can do so many
fucking cool things go online.
And I don't want to just sell the Samsung
Galaxy s three because Tim has a lot
of really cool, uh, different, uh,
phones that you can buy. There's,
there's a plethora of devices
that you could pick up from them.
And if you go to
rogan.ting.com you sign up,
uh,
or rather a login through that URL,
you get $50 off of any smartphone
that you, you choose to buy.
And they have this Samsung Galaxy s two,
the Samsung Galaxy s three,
looking at your website. It has a
little girl holding your face. Look,
if you've got a Rogan Diet,
look behind you.
It's a cool a little girl holding my face.
It's trawling.
There's a little little girl just like,
Hey,
I'm wondering the Joe Rogan
experience that welcomes the Joe
and listeners. Oh, that's so cute.
And he saved 50 bucks and a here's another
good thing like say if you and your
wife and maybe even how to have a daughter
and our son and they, uh, you know,
you don't use enough minutes to,
to warrant having three
different phone bills. Well,
with teaching you can all share minutes.
So with,
with three different devices,
you can all be on one plan.
If you don't use all of your minutes,
they carry over to the next month.
And if you use more minutes,
it's just scaled your, your,
your bill is a,
is scaled.
So it's a really fair way of doing
business. It's all explained at,
at Tang. And if you go to
rogan.ting.com you could check it out.
But you know what,
look man,
the contracts and all the stuff
that you have to deal with,
if you go through the bigger cell phone
companies, they're kind of fucked.
It's kind of shitty and it
kinda sucks for the consumer.
And Ting is correcting that and they're
correcting it with excellent signal,
excellent service, really good phones,
really good customer service man.
They've trained some cool
people and they've, uh, they've,
they've set an environment at
Ting and that environment is,
we're trying to be fair.
We're trying to provide you with a
really good service and do it at a really
good rate. And a, I love it.
I love the idea behind it.
I love what they're trying to do and uh,
I'm, I'm happy to be working with them.
If you've got a rogan.ting.com
you can see all of the, uh,
the devices that they have, uh, all
the different smart phones and, uh,
the different plans that they have and
uh, no contracts. So go check it out.
And a thank you to Tim and thank you also
to onnit.com we're always sponsored by
on it makers of Alpha brain.
I've had no Alpha brain and no pot before.
I'm fucking sober. Shit, bitches. I'm
confusing. Maybe not right now. Maybe,
maybe in a few.
Uh,
we have to get through this as quickly
as possible because we're doing a live
phone call with, uh, with Shane
Smith from vice any second now. Uh,
so before I do that,
please go to [inaudible] dot com and
check out all of the different supplements
of our sponsor on it is not
just a sponsor, the podcast.
I own a piece of on it.
And the reason why I do
is because first of all,
I believe very much in supplementation
and vitamins and minerals and,
and keeping your body healthy and,
and providing it with nutrients that
can enhance the way your body performs.
And these are subtle enhancements.
It's not like if you're a fat fuck we'd
cheeseburgers and smoked cigarettes,
you're instantly going to feel better
from Alpha brain. But what it is, is it's,
it's giving, no offense,
it's giving you a, a wind.
I wasn't thinking about Brian and all
I said that sounded that way. I wasn't,
I wasn't, I just, why I corrected
it and said, no offense, um,
health is very important to me.
You know,
I'm one of those people that believes
that your body and your mind are all one
unit and they don't work better there.
They don't work well rather, uh,
in less.
All of it is healthy.
And I think nutrients are a
very important part of that.
It's very important to eat healthy foods.
It's very important to get a lot of
vegetables in your diet, clean meats,
grass fed meat if you
can, you know, wild fish.
It's very important to take
fish oil and supplements,
but I also think that you can get more,
more performance out of your mind,
more performance out of your body
by taking certain supplements.
And all of those supplements are
available@auditona.com that's Oh and nit
including shroom tech, which
is a, uh, there's two stream
tech sport, which is uh,
uh, based on the quadriceps mushroom
and it enhances your physical endurance.
I use some today before Jujitsu class,
I believe in.
I take it before every
workout. Um, all of it,
all the controversial information about
all these different supplements is all
explained with the science behind all of
it at [inaudible] dot com and on it we
also have kettle bells and battle ropes.
We're starting to sell exercise equipment,
real manly type shit for full body
workouts bitches when you get a functional
strength and a really, really brutal
stuff. Battle ropes are amazing.
We sell them as cheap as you can buy
them online, same as kettlebells.
We're selling them literally as cheap as
you possibly can. And because of that,
the code named Rogan,
which works for any and all
supplements give you get 10% off.
It does not work with the battle ropes,
the battle ropes or the kettle bells,
but what we're promising you is that
we're selling them as cheap as we can.
We are selling you the best
quality exercise equipment,
the best quality kettlebells.
These motherfuckers will last forever.
They're awesome and
there is solid as a rock.
They're literally solid cast
iron and go check it out.
If you're interested in kettlebells,
Google what kettle bells are all about.
Google nootropics too while you're at it
and find out what the Fuck Alpha brain
is all about and then check out shroom
tech sport and checkout hem force protein
powder and all of that good shit@ona.com.
All right Brian,
let's call Shane up and chew the fucking
music son. Get this shit started.
Okay.
The Joe Rogan experience.
Try it by day.
Joe Rogan podcast by night all day.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we are about to go live on the phone
with my man Shane Smith from vice.com and
they have a new thing out today on
the Great Mitt Romney and should be a
fascinating, hello, this is Joe
Rogan calling. Hello. Sorry.
Uh, does this, sorry, is
this the right number?
Okay,
this is Joe.
Yes,
Okay.
Is this Shane?
Is it Shane? Yeah. Dude,
you sound fucked. Are you,
are you drunk right now?
Are you covering an underwear?
What's going on over there buddy?
Okay,
I'm covered in a Mazola
oil and no underwear.
Are you, you, you, you're very low energy.
Are you tired from all of this craziness
from exposing this craziness to the
world?
Is that what's going on?
I'm high or Dean, whenever
I'm talking to you, I'm I or,
well, I'm hiring a gene
whenever I talk to you too.
So tell me what the fuck is going on.
You are,
you are premiering the Mexican Mormon
war series on vice and the vice youtube
channel. Correct. Tell us all about this.
Well, we went down to, um,
to Allah in northern Mexico to do a story
on Mormons who are fighting the drug
cartels.
The first people we met were the Lebaron
from the Lebaron colony and now they,
the Romneys, the live
bands, the Jones was there.
I went down from Utah when the
American government outlawed polygamy.
And they believe that, uh, because
Joseph Smith said that, uh,
you have to get to the highest level
of celestial heaven by being part of a
plural marriage. They said, well, fuck
it. I'm not going to stay in America,
not go to heaven. So they went
down to Mexico. That's a good,
it could be polygamous.
That's it. I, Jan is a
beautiful wrap by the way.
Got Mad props that Joseph
Smith for keeping his
giant hair. I'm strong.
I'm sorry, go ahead.
Exactly. And I think, you know,
Brigham Young had had had a hell
of a lot of whys. I forget the,
I think it was 23 but it don't quote me
on that. But anyway, so they believed,
you know, to keep going to heaven
that they had to have many partners.
So anyway,
they went down there,
they form these Mormon colonies and
the colonies did quite well. I mean,
they're, they're, they're successful
farms. They have, you know,
nice little towns and, you know,
they're, they're, they're, they're,
they're sort of affluent and deals.
They're big tall guys and cowboy hats.
They looked like a bunch of
Texans down there. So anyway,
we heard that some of the Mormons down
there had been fighting the cartels
because the cartels started kidnapping
the Mormons and extorting them for money.
So this one plan, the
Lebaron plan had, had, had,
had gone to war with this guy
and then elevate key news.
Like it was one of the
biggest bad ass, um, uh,
narcos.
He actually massacre 18 people in a
drug rehab center just cause they were
trying to get off of trucks.
She's a very bad man and he lived eight
miles down the road from the Lebaron
colony. So they started
going to war. Um, they,
they, they forced him to release, uh,
they're a 16 year old
cousin who because of that,
he got pissed off and he killed,
um, you know, two of them. Uh,
in retaliation and then it all went crazy.
So as we were down there hanging out
with them and seeing what they had done
using antiquaries techniques
from Afghanistan and, and, uh,
and Iraq have checkpoints and
snipers posts and all this stuff.
And I were going crazy there.
What's going on?
Got Our connection,
got wind of it where,
Oh, I didn't, it sounds fine
over here. And we heard you
loud and clear. Okay, great.
So ignore that noise. Yeah, I
don't, I don't hear it over here.
So, so they started making these
military checkpoints. They had snipers,
a lookout points and, and, uh, you know,
military checkpoints and all of a sudden
the violence died down and their region
excepted continued in, in,
in the rest of the areas.
And so as we were hanging out
with the, the, uh, the, the,
the little barons who told
us some crazy stories,
the reason why the Lebaron
we're ready for the, the, this,
the sort of narco cartels,
uh,
aggression was because they were already
armed and ready to fight because they
had had a civil war within their sort
of fundamentalist break off church.
Um,
where this guy named oval,
a baron who tried to take over the church
and he's also dubbed the Mormon Manson.
He killed,
well,
he says he suspected and about 40
murder cases in America and in,
in Mexico. And then they caught him
and he tried to actually, he was,
he threatened to commit Jimmy to
kill Jimmy Carter at one point.
And then they caught him in 25 people
were killed after they caught him because
he left his blood atonement
last will and testament.
So they kept killing his family.
He had a 20 to 30 children,
I believe from 10 wives and they
were, they became as hip. It's acid,
they would kill people for him.
So they were ready because of this sort
of civil war within their own family,
within their own church. They were
ready to fight. And because of that,
when the Narcos came after them, uh, you
know, they were armed and ready to go.
And they famously,
the Lebaron outshot the Mexican military
in a shootout when they came to,
to try to get the guns off them.
So anyways, when we were, when we
were hanging out with the Lebaron,
um, they were saying, oh yeah, you know,
you should go hang out with the Romney's.
They live just across the valley. And
when I called on the Romney's like, yeah,
mid, I'm like, what? And
they're like, yeah. Uh,
George Romney,
Mitt's father was born in a Mormon colony.
Um,
originally it polygamous Mormon colony
and colonial the blind and, you know,
went to America. You know, it's, it's,
it's been reported that actually,
uh,
George Romney went to America illegally
as an illegal immigrant or they crossed
the border illegally anyway.
And, uh, but they're still there.
The Romneys are still
there and in our law,
and they have a comme une now there
LDS or not the latter day saints there,
there are sort of orthodox Mormons
are not polygamist anymore. Um,
what's the benefit of staying in,
in Mexico?
I don't know. I mean, that's their own,
you know, they, they, they, you know,
they live there and, uh, they have
their community there and you know,
that's what they do.
They've been kidnapped as well.
They had a kidnap things within
their own family. And uh,
um,
but you know that they've been there
for a while and they're like, well,
you know, we're not leaving.
You know, they have to leave.
So what's interesting about it
though is the Romneys are like,
they're really nice guys and they're like,
look,
Mitt Romney should contact us because his
policy on immigration is wrong because
policy on, on, on drugs is
wrong. They're like, look at,
unless you decriminalize it,
it's much like prohibition.
You know,
Al Capone and Lucky Luciano became big
because everyone's still Jack as much
during prohibition. They just, the mob
Brian, it's the same thing with drugs.
So you know,
it's,
it's interesting to talk to them because
they live on the front war, sorry,
front line of this drug war and they
see what's happening with illegal
immigration and these are sort of big,
you know,
tough Texas died dudes
who, who are, you know,
pro Romney and go republican and all that
stuff and they're like, look, you know,
he's wrong and he should talk to us
because the drug policy is wrong.
And the immigration policy as well.
So it was really interesting to hang out
with them because they're actually at
war, you know, every day.
And you know, it's, it's,
it's literally not even
one generation removed.
And this,
the whole story is crazy.
It's crazy what they have to go
to down then after, you know,
how they're fighting the narco is because
the NAACOS control the whole area and
these pockets of Mormon
resistance or uh, you know, are,
are the only ones fighting the,
the cartels.
It is crazy because it's one
generation removed from Mitt Romney.
Guy was running for president and there
essentially living like a mad max movie.
Correct. That's, that's, that's the whole
thing. It's wild is everyone, you know,
making a big deal about Obama's, you know,
a history and, and, and, and everything.
And you're like, hold on a
second. Myth and history is crazy.
They went down as polygamous
colonies and the fighting,
there's kidnappings and cocaine and drug
cartels and whore and, and he, you know,
he's just ignoring it. And so when
we went down there, you know, we,
we just thought, wow, what a
story. And the story is crazy.
It probably wants up today when we
were doing seven plots and it just gets
crazier and crazier as we go. But
like, you know, internal, you know, uh,
civil wars and murders and cartels
and killings and it's just crazy.
And it's like, you know, right.
Just out to the American border and these
guys had been living down there sort
of in their own little world and now
it's, it's, you know, it's just coming.
It's just coming to the fore
crazy
story. And, and the fact that, you know,
Mitt Romney is literally, you know,
his dad, his dad had
had to leave there. He,
his dad came up from a Mormon
colony in, in Mexico. So it's crazy.
I know by the way, his dad
ran, ran for president,
but his campaign didn't last very long
because they called into question his
citizenship as well as, uh,
his colonies polygamous past.
So I think, you know, once burned,
twice shy, I mean it is very, um,
you know, he doesn't want
to get into this obviously,
and he for sure doesn't want to get into
what's happening with the rest of the
ones down there because it's a,
it's crazy.
Yes. I don't think most people are
aware of this whole Mormon colony.
They're certainly not aware of that.
Mitt Romney's a part of it.
How is this being, this sounds like crazy
information. Like it's, it's really,
it has dark implications
that this is being ignored
when you look at the media.
I mean it's,
it's really damning if this is like
readily available information. Yeah.
Is Sort of Mormon,
which I mean,
obviously he's not sort of going forward
with it saying, yes, you know, I'm a,
I mean,
this is what the Mormon church is and
this is what it should be doing and this
is what I'm doing and all that stuff,
you know. But he's also definitely not,
um, you know, he just
started to sort of say,
you know, my, my dad was from Mexico to
try to sort of get the, the Latino vote.
What's interesting is,
you know,
it was dad who came from Mexico
and then did really well here,
you know, is the poster child of his Mitt
Romney for the dream act for, you know,
if you come here and you work
hard and make a living, um, then,
then you can get amnesty and,
and you know,
his dad who was the poster child for it
and he actually said he would veto the
dream act. So he's actually, you know,
being incredibly sort of, you know,
even more right wing than the they already
republican sort of right wing party
and, and uh, you know,
there's a lot of supposition that the
reason why is it's kind of like me thinks
di does protest too much because he
doesn't want to get sort of dragged into
this sort of whole history because it
cannot do him any good because drug wars
and immigration and, uh,
you know, kidnapping and,
and people getting their heads
chopped off it, you know, and,
and history of polygamy does not a good
presidential candidate make. And I'm,
I'm sure that, you know, they're
worried about the other and you know,
obviously Mormonism has history and,
and still some current problems with
polygamy and they for sure want to stay
away from that. But also they
want to stay away from stories.
More importantly,
like the failure of the war on drugs,
which has been a complete
and utter failure. Um,
there's never been more drugs in America
for cheaper or better quality yet
people are dying because
we let the mob run it. Um,
and it's just totally doesn't work yet.
He insists on maintaining those,
those standard operating procedures,
sort of policies that just don't work.
And by the way his mom and brother and
but also his own flesh and blood is
paying the price for it.
Well a guy like the scariest to
me about written Mitt Romney,
Mitt Romney seems like a robot.
He doesn't seem like a real person when
he interacts with people and that kind
of like disconnected behavior,
the way he interacts with people.
So weird and disconnected.
That's indicative of a lot
of people who are really,
really religious and I have a friend
who went through most of her life being
very religious and has recently fallen
like over the last sort of decade,
kind of fallen away from religion and
is now starting to question her life.
And one of the things that she said
was that when she was really religious,
she didn't question anything. She just
sort of went along with things. She just,
you,
you become like indoctrinated into this
kind of thinking where there's always
someone smarter than you.
Always someone who tells me what to do.
You don't ever question it.
God has a plan for everything.
It's like the same sort of package that
it all went into in her head and I see a
guy like Mitt Romney,
I'm like,
they can tell this guy to do anything and
he's going to do it. He's got no spine,
he's got no real opinions on things.
He he,
his opinions are based on what he thinks
will work numbers wise and when he's
communicating with people,
he makes no connection with them.
When he has these conversations with
like regular folks who have questions for
him, it's one of the worst
things he could ever do.
They should have never let him do that
because every time he tries to be like a
man of the people and gay marriage comes
up or medical marijuana comes up or
anything, anything that requires
like real thinking, a real debate.
He's a fucking robot man.
He's a monk. A mechanical guy.
Yeah. I think he, look, he's the typical
whatever it'll take to get elected.
So He's,
he's trying to be all things to
all people, which just can't work.
You have to be a human being.
Well, you understand this.
I'm sorry, go ahead, please.
Yeah. What I think I'd rather,
there's no one's perfect,
but what I'd rather somebody who says,
yeah, I come from this, you know,
crazy shit and Mexico and yes,
it's a problem and we have to do something
to fix that problem because all of
the money for the cocaine comes from
pod and every other drug comes from
America.
The guns come from America.
Everything like the market
for all the drugs in America,
but all the people being killed in Mexico.
And you know,
we've got to do something to help
that because you know, I'm from there.
If he would say something human, you know,
that's, it's just like, look, you know,
I don't want these people to be
killed. You know, there's more,
it's by a factor of 10.
So 10 times more Mexicans have
been killed or people, sorry,
people have been killed in the,
in the war on drugs.
And then in the real wars in American
killed American soldiers killed him in
Iraq and Afghanistan.
It's quite a factor of 10
but it's after 10 the point you're like,
look, this is a right on our board.
It's going to be a failed state soon and
it's all flowers and we just can't do
anything to fix it.
And what,
I'd much rather just have someone
be a human being and say, yeah,
I came from that.
That's where I came from and now I'm here,
this is what I'm doing. But you know
what, like people are dying down there.
We've got to do something.
Or you know,
we've got to sort of look at immigration
a little bit better than than,
than we have been because obviously
that's not working either.
And instead of that,
it's just the standard pat political
answers that don't mean anything.
And the no one's gonna do
anything. And, and, and,
and the same policies that haven't worked,
you know, in the past 20 or 30 years,
I mean, the won drudge is just
like, it's a fucking joke and
it's weekend when you go down,
it's weakening when you go down.
No,
where do you go down there you like
literally you cross over from El Paso,
Texas into our as Mexico. It's the
same city just divided by a border.
El Pastor is one of the safest cities in
America because it's a police state and
the cartels live up there
and you pass into Juarez,
which is w w it's the most dangerous
city in the world for journalists.
And it was one of the most
dangerous cities in the world,
but I believe it's just been up to the
most dangerous city in the world, uh,
for murders. So you're sitting
there going, how is that
possible? You know, how,
how is that the most dangerous city in
the world is the same city as El Paso,
Texas. So you know the whole
thing when you're down there,
you realize that this,
we always say where all the adults are,
you know, this is the absurdity
of the modern condition.
But when you're down there,
you're exactly right.
It's Mad Max five minutes out of the
American border and it's not like we can
just say, oh, so it was crazy. Mexicans.
I mean all the guns are coming from us,
all the money is coming from us.
The market for the cocaine is here.
Like it's just, it's all
us. We're just saying,
well you guys can shoot each other
down there and we don't care.
Well not only that,
there's documented of our guys are
people selling guns to the Mexican drug
cartels so they can, you know, quote
unquote trace them or something. So they,
they've sold them guns that have
actually wound up killing American border
agents that gets real mad
fasten period where
there's been a bunch of,
the most famous is the fast and furious.
How does that happen?
Well, they gave, they were
giving, giving, not selling,
giving guns to the cartels and
thinking they could track them.
And the only, they found them, they
lost track of them all the same.
They came up in a, in,
in, yes, you're correct.
In the deaths of American agents
guns that we had given them. Uh,
we're, we're using those murders, which
has just, I found it to be shocking,
but also there was,
when I was down there actually
two things when I was down there,
the largest hall of ammunition, uh,
got caught the, at the Mexican border,
which we went to. It's
all, all the ammunition,
all the weapons coming from America.
It's shocking the amount of like they've
truckloads full of weapons grade, uh,
you know,
7.62 a ammunition.
But also one of the things
that, that, that you know,
is crazy about,
you know,
what's happening is the amount of
killings that go on with weapon. Oh yeah.
Sorry. The other thing was
there was, uh, an ex CIA,
I forget which one,
but the ex head of the CIA,
his ceremonial pistol is
ceremonials 45 that they,
they give you like,
you know,
as a ward and when you leave office was
found on a narco lord when he was done.
And so he had the head of CIA.
CIA is a 45 caliber.
Uh,
we're just sitting there and going like,
now it's in the level of absurdity.
Now it's in the level of,
you know,
fast and the furious and we'll give them
guns and then they kill us with her own
guns.
And
it's a Cohen brothers can't at crazy
in any way where I would
think, oh, that's a good idea.
Give them guns and track them.
It's amazing that these fucking morons
are the ones who are in charge of these
things. The people that could come up
with an idea like that, either some,
either they're lying and they're making
money and they're corrupt and this is
just how they masked it or
they're criminally and competent.
Yeah. Well, what makes it worse is the,
the sort of the lead
cartel now that they test.
What happened with them is
they were actually trained,
the core group of the Vegas were
trained by the DEA to be counter,
um, you know, counter cartel, you know,
super police.
And so they were trained by the DEA
and then they went down and then we're
working for a bit, and
then they said, screw this.
And they sold themselves as
mercenaries to the various hotels,
famously the Gulf cartel. And
then they said, well, screw this,
we're just going to take over.
And now they're sort of
hedge demonic you cocktail.
And they were all trained by the DEA.
So they use the training that the DEA
gave them to take over from the other
cartels, and now they're running shit. And
you're just like, holy fuck. I mean this,
you couldn't write a
Hollywood script this week.
Well,
that's very similar to the
who then became the Taliban,
right?
Isn't that the same thing
that happened in Afghanistan?
100% then and, and so now we're fighting
the people that we armed and trained.
And guess what? It's happening
now. We actually admit to it,
we are arming and training, um, uh,
Islamic fundamentalists in Somalia,
uh,
in an effort to fight Al Shabaab there.
But this,
these people who were training to
fight Al Shabaab are avowed, um,
you know, anti western Islamic
fundamentalists. So we're doing it again.
It's not like we were over, it's not
like we're learning from my mistake.
Whilst while this is going on, there's
all this crazy saber rattling about Iran,
you know,
I mean this really looks like,
it looks like the end of the world
is like knocking on our front door.
Well, I'm actually going,
my next trip is to Pakistan.
I'm the guy who developed
a bomb for Pakistan,
gave illegally, gave the
technology to run. Um,
I mean I'm interviewing him because um,
you know,
it's not only around having the bomb,
but Pakistan,
which is quickly becoming a
failed state has a lot of,
uh, weapons, a ballistic weapons.
And so we're going to see,
just going over to see just how
loose the new, cause I over there
absolutely terrifying. What's happening.
What's scary about this though, is that,
um, you know, the Mexico, uh,
issue is Mexico runs the risk of turning
into a failed state as well. But again,
it's a booger. It's a, and by the way,
it's a, it's a problem that we're
causing. Like, you know, it's, it's, it's,
you know,
it's a scary time
and when they're bored or quits,
if they become a failed state and they
stopped having patrols on their side of
the border, you know,
we're going to have to,
they don't have any employees doing that.
We're going to have to up all
the people that work down there.
They're going to have to do
something to try to tie it,
and then they're going to have to go in.
That's what's going to be really crazy.
They're going to have to
realize like there's an army of,
of real it truly evil people that are
involved in a crazy criminal enterprise
and they're,
they're billionaires and they have,
and they're right there and they've
become an army now and they're doing okay.
It's a joke, like whenever you're down
that you hear all these stories of,
you know, they're trying to
build a wall, which is he'll,
cause you just taught him a
hundred or go over it. But yeah,
will come sort of put up a wall
during the day and at night.
They just come and take all of this stuff
for scrap, you know, because you know,
it just,
it's impossible to do.
And if you think you're just
going to build a wall and that,
that's going to stop people from, from
going under it or over it, you're insane.
Yeah.
I just crazy.
I don't know how you stop something that
is out of control as the drug war in
Mexico. It seems so crazy. It's like,
is there even a solution that anybody
proposes that makes sense to fix this
decriminalizing God's, I mean,
this is, this is the, the
argument is you say, look,
it's like alcohol. You know, every,
excuse me, everyone drank and then they,
they made it illegal and everyone's
drag but the mob, right. Um,
and now you're like,
it's not as if the argument that if we
decriminalize drugs more people will do
drugs is,
is,
is ludicrous because no one is not buying
drugs or not taking drugs or whatever
because it's illegal.
You can get pot anywhere,
you can get coke anywhere you get acid.
Then we had sort of basically any
drug anywhere incredibly easily.
I don't know anyone that can't
get any drug with a call of a,
yeah, but you run it. Can
I call you up later tonight
Brian?
And the thing is is like we said,
there's never been more right.
Drugs in America, never higher
quality and the better product.
So the thing is is you sit not worried.
That argument, that argument is, is his
mood. Like what you have to do is say,
okay, people are going to do drugs.
Okay, you have to decriminalize it.
And that way at least you can
regulate it or, or, or you know,
that take the criminal element out of it.
Because quite frankly,
as long as people want to take drugs
and I don't see that happening,
you know the people are not going
to want to take drugs to anytime,
then the war will just get worse because
it's billions and billions and billions
and billions of dollars that is going to
be run by the criminals because it has
to be because the government won't run it.
I also think that we have an issue
where the the people that are making the
decisions for whether or not things
are or are not illegal have a vested
financial interest in keeping them illegal
and that's something that we really
have to address in this country.
Like what you can make money off of and
the fact that you can make money off of
people being in prison and the fact that
you can make money off of hiring more
law enforcement and DEA officers and
having more government programs to Radica
drugs, the more money that you can spend
in, the more money that you, it it,
it beefs up this whole
industry that all goes away.
If marijuana becomes legal and all goes
away, if drugs become decriminalized,
nothing happens in this country unless
there's an economic interest right now,
there's a massive economic incest
and the drug industry. You know,
I was reading a fascinating article,
um, you know, the other the other day,
about half of America is on prescribed
drugs and the other half is on illegal
drugs.
Okay.
You know, it's, it's, it's, it's there,
it's not going away and either we
come up with some sort of intelligence
solution or it's just going to get
worse and worse and worse and worse.
How is Mitt Romney is a guy
that the Republicans chose?
How did he get past their vetting process?
How did they not look at this guy's
past and go, Whoa, Whoa, Whoa,
you're dad was from fucking where?
How do they not do that?
How do they not let just look at the
Mormon religion in general and how people
look at it as being a really wacky
subset of Christianity with roots in the
ridiculous,
when you hear the story
that it was created by this
Joseph Smith kid who was 14
and found golden tablets that he can
only read with a magic rock. I mean,
it's fucking ridiculous. How
did this guy get cozy? The Guy,
and again,
you're right,
he's sort of an auto bot,
been preparing to try to beat,
doesn't designated for his whole
life. He, he, he, you know, and, and,
and if you look at it, you just
say, look, this guy, you know,
it looks like a president.
He acts like a president and
he talks like a president.
But it's like anybody like you,
Joe,
if you were to run for President
Obama's running for president,
they would find all kinds of crazy shit
in our, in our past because that's human.
What's interesting about it is he rejects
all that humanity and doesn't want to
say that he's from, actually doesn't
want to say that this stuff was going on.
Doesn't want to admit it.
Does he ever addressed,
because it's crazy. But at the
same time you want to say, okay,
well we should be electing humans
and we shouldn't be lacking robot.
Has He ever been questioned
on this publicly?
Um, I know it's come up a
few times. He, he, he, he,
he's been skirting around
it until recently when he,
I believe smoked this, spoke to the, uh,
American Latino Conference and said, um,
you know, uh, you know, I,
you know, I'm from Mexico.
I'm from a Mormon colony and Mexico.
And also he said in the RNC speech,
you know,
my dad came from Mexico
or to Michigan and that,
uh, you know, we were more
minutes, but people didn't care.
It was more about the sports teams.
We were like,
address it
because it's coming out. But the thing
is that, to your earlier question,
about 14 minutes too late is
the reason why it has come out.
So I wasn't the first journalist to go
down there. People found out that they,
you know, he was born there
and actually, you know,
it was an old story because it was a big
story when his father ran for president
and, uh, everyone went crazy. But, um,
what, what nobody did it stay there.
I went down there three different times.
I stayed there, hung out with them.
I actually liked them,
you know, because they're,
they're fighting cartels and the cartels
guys, you, like you said, they're,
they're in cities,
people who are cutting off heads and then
killing people at random and throwing
grenades into nightclubs and
kidnapping and it's just, look, it's
movie.
Then these guys are standing up to them.
And then, you know, I, I respect that.
And you'd have to protect your family and,
and I believe in that.
And I just think that,
you know,
these guys sort of doing it
on their own is crazy. And,
um, you know, when I, when I,
when I was staying with them, you realize
that this is, this is crazy. Like,
it's not, you know, it's, it is
like a Terentino's really. And,
and you know, the fact that you know, he,
he's his cousin, like they're all named,
brought me. I mean, was it cousins?
They're all there. You know,
you'd think that actually this, they say
this in the piece, they're like, look,
I wish he would contact us because
I think we could help them.
And we got to talk to them about,
about immigration.
We've got to talk to them
about this sucks balls
we can help and we want to talk to him
about his drug policy. That's incredible.
Yeah.
Well because they're on the front lines.
They understand what it's all about.
We have to stop treating Mexico as if
it's another thing that we don't have to
deal with. It's right next door. I mean,
it literally is connected. It is us.
You know, it's, we pretended they're two
separate countries. It's, it's so silly.
It's just people,
just people,
and they were born a mile this way or a
mile that way. So they're fucked. Now.
They're not going to stand that they're
coming across left and right back and
forth. And we all know
somebody, if you live in La,
you owe somebody who is either family
came here illegally and they came here and
it's so normal. We have to fucking
start treating them like they're us.
Like we gotta, we gotta fix that
spot. It's connected to us. You know,
if you're there for a little while too,
what happened was because of Nafta,
which was again, it was a, an
American policy. Um, you know, Mexico,
northern Mexico got really
slammed because the farms,
they couldn't compete anymore because of
Americans still had substance use here,
but they didn't have subsidies. They're
all this stuff, you know, again,
you can go into that stuff for a long,
but basically Nafta, the Mexican,
uh,
ag agriculture.
So they only had two options once,
at least sort of agriculture
died in northern Mexico.
And that was either you sneak into
America to get jobs. And by the way,
one of the things that you
learned there is, you know, they,
these people are Mexican.
They don't want to leave their homes,
they don't want to leave their families.
They don't want to leave their sons and
daughters. Of the moms or whoever it is,
they do it because of survival.
And when do you get your,
when you're faced with survival,
you'll do anything.
You don't want to crawl under
borders through rat infested tunnels.
You don't want to, you know, put your
life in the hands of coyotes and cartels.
So you know, on one side they
had to sneak into America,
which is not a lovely process or
they have to join the cartels.
And those are the two options left to
them for survival because of policies that
were cooked up in Washington. Now I've
got to say that when you say, look, it's,
it doesn't matter what side of
the border that's a, that's a,
that's an ethical and moral obligation.
But I'm on top of that is the majority
of the problems of northern Mexico,
a hundred percent caused by America.
And you sit there and say, okay,
it's not like Mexico was intrinsically
poor. They couldn't feed themselves this,
this all happened within the last 30
years. And, and you just sit down and say,
okay,
look,
sometime at some point we have to take
responsibility for what we're doing.
And for sure the president, I just dates
it has to have to look at this because,
okay, we're worried about around
where we're worried about this.
We're worried about that. But
guess what? Our back yard,
we have something that's killed 10 times.
The amount of American soldiers killed
in the words that we've been fighting.
So I don't know how it could be any worse.
And it just appeared over the
last decade when I was a kid,
one of the first gigs I did when
I came to California for MTV,
uh, in Cancun. I would never think
about doing that. Now I'd be like,
fuck that.
That sounds crazy.
But back then they would have
MTV shows in Cancun. I mean,
nobody was scared to go to Mexico.
Mexico is great. People enjoyed it.
A lot of great places to go on
vacation there and then add a nowhere.
All this violence started happening
and, and mass scale. And it's,
it's so hard for people to wrap their
heads around. But if this was in Detroit,
if this was in New York, we would
be fucking terrified. We would be.
If it was in Houston, we would be fucking
terrified of this kind of violence.
But because it's in Mexico for whatever
reason, people don't think it affects us.
It's,
it's really nuts.
Like there's a giant patch of humanity
that lives in utter chaos and they are
literally physically connected to us.
Exactly right. Because the, the,
the increase in violence to scale up in
violence in Mexico has been the last 10
years. And it's because they tried
to implement the war on drugs.
And not only has it not helped an iota,
but it's led to a lot of people being
killed because what they're doing and the
policies is there, they're
using just don't work. And the,
the Zetas are a perfect example.
Let's train a hyper group of mercenaries
that then become the worst guys who are
our worst enemies because we
them, I mean the, the, it's, it's,
we've done such a bad job. It's literally
laughable. And we have a, uh, a series,
we're going to be doing
calls where all the adults,
cause I don't know who the fuck is
that you need to listen to lectures.
Not at all.
Yeah.
It's a weird place where at,
where are the capabilities of our
government have been overshadowed by their
abilities. Like they, they can't see the,
the greater impact of what they're
doing and they make these incompetent,
ridiculous decisions and yet they have
the power to implement these stupid ideas
and the impact of them is tremendous.
And people who are more knowledgeable
socially who understand, you know, what,
what we, what we need to do to try to fix
the situation, they're not being heard.
We were all,
we're only hearing from the people that
are benefiting financially from the drug
war and the, the whole
thing is all based on, Oh,
protect the children and protect people
and drugs kill lives with nary a mention
of the biggest issue
that this country faces,
which is the fucking
pharmaceutical drug problem.
There are a bunch of fucking zombies
sanctioned zombies walking our streets and
I know quite a few of them.
I've met quite a few people in my life
that have lost themselves to pain pills
and they get them from a doctor and they
have no problem staying medicated and
they're gone.
They are not the same person anymore.
And this is an epidemic in this country
and it's not being addressed at the same
time while people are
going after illegal drugs,
which for the most part aren't,
aren't the real problem in this country
for sure. I mean, if you
look at it, you say, okay,
we're talking mainly about pod and,
and Co coming from Mexico.
Obviously, you know, they,
they do some, other than that,
I'm going to be things like that,
which is not great, but the, the, the,
the majority of heroin,
um,
and with a country or in all countries,
uh,
over 90% estimated comes from Afghanistan,
which theoretically we've been in control
over the last 10 years and have them
nothing to called the poppy,
uh, population growth puppy.
Um, and so what's happening now
is there's never been one heroin,
heroin in the last 10 years.
A heroin use in American has doubled
places going down. Quality has gone up,
and that's what America is in control.
I don't know what anyone wants to talk
about conspiracy theory or this or that,
but, um, you know, if America
and Mexico, Oh really?
Okay. Fighting, uh, you
know, a drug war hadn't yet,
there's never been more coke or more
thought. And by the way, heroin,
just flooding the streets out of the
country that we control it theoretically
then, you know, somebody is not opening
her eyes because if you look at it,
if you want to take it down to its,
uh,
its simplest level America since it's
been running Afghanistan has become the
largest drug dealer in the world and
the largest heroin dealer in the world.
That's, that's a, that's a fact because,
uh, you know, heroin addiction has,
has skyrocketed in Russia,
in, in, in, in Europe,
in America, and then in countries, you
know, that don't even have money for it.
He didn't do the west coast of
Africa and in, and, um, um, uh,
India and Pakistan and Afghanistan and
around places where they never had a
heroin addiction because it's gone.
It's on the trail. And by the way,
this is during a time when,
you know, theoretically we're
supposed to be in there,
uh, uh, regulating the country. Well,
we're not, and I don't know why,
but I get to tell you were always,
a lot of people are making a
lot of money off that airline.
Well, Shane Smith, it sounds
like you hate America.
That's what I hear when I hate talking
like this sounds like you hate America.
I do not know what I'm saying man.
That's the argument against it. I mean,
it's so blatant and one of the weirdest
things is watching video of US soldiers
guarding poppy fields. I'm sure
you've seen those. That is so surreal,
man. It's so, it's so like on your face.
America. I'm, I'm the, I'm the
perfect example of the American dream.
I came down here and, and you know,
started a company and, and, and you know,
uh, hired a bunch of people and I love
the promise of America. I love the people.
I think it's the greatest
country in the world.
What I don't like is the fact that
we suck up so much propaganda.
I don't know how it's
different than Nazi Germany.
Nazi Germany was doing bad shit,
but they said, no, no, it's okay.
We're doing good shit. And then I
went, okay, and how are we different?
Like this is the land of the
free. We're supposed to, you know,
we're supposed to have a free media that
tells the truth and then we make up our
own, our own minds. What I'm saying
is, okay, I love, I love this coaching,
but if I want to, you know,
I'm going to tell the truth.
And if if we're know
complicit in, in, you know,
doubling heroin addicts in America,
then we have to know that if
we're complicit and you know,
50,000 murders in Mexico,
then I'm going to say that because
otherwise if nobody's saying it,
then guess what? How are we different
than Nazi Germany? I don't fucking know.
Yeah,
well we got a bunch of lazy unpatriotic
motherfuckers running this thing because
if people really were patriotic and
really wanted to Spec the ideal of what
America is supposed to be,
there would never be any
problem with freedom of press.
They would never be any problem like
what's going on with Wiki leaks this way.
It would be something where they would
want to take account and look at the
grievances that the people have.
But we're running by lazy people that
they don't have this idea of the perfect
Utopian society that we think that we
can all aspire to and can be created
someday.
We all hope if humanity keeps evolving,
that we're going to get
past this ridiculous, uh,
system of crime and violence and poverty
and eventually move on to some elevated
level of society,
some elevated state of consciousness
where we all can get along together and we
basically can eliminate
violence and eliminate all
the bullshit aspects that are
created by inequality and losers and
doing a shitty job of raising children.
And I think that this is something
that we should all aspire to.
This is something that we
should all look towards.
And when our government is being run
by hacks and dummies, it's, it's,
it's a real problem.
And when they placate to all these
dummies out there that you know,
form special interest groups and you know,
right wing,
crazy religious wings and it's there,
they're all doing themselves a disservice.
Everybody should be trying to move this
fucking thing further than where it's at
right now. And with rational
discussion and logical thinking,
you look at it and you go, okay,
this drug thing is a big problem,
but you got to fix this and who's
making money and how is this?
Where's this money going?
Just knowing those numbers,
the government should be
chasing that down on TV.
They should be going ladies and
gentlemen, the Afghanistan, you know,
opium supplies 90% of the world's opioid
supply. We're in control of Afghanistan.
So we're trying to figure out where
the fuck this money's going. But no,
it's just something instead
that's never even brought up.
It's swept under the table.
Whoever is making money
off of it continues to make
money off of it and we're
supposed to just ignore it, you
know, because honey booboo is on TV,
you know
it's true.
This country was founded on a weekend,
like a modern day utopia and you know,
it's founded on the American dream and,
and the thing is is that shouldn't go
away. That should be number one thing.
But it also has to be founded on truth.
And the thing is,
is what I tried to do is find truth.
And what you do is you find that
truth and then, and then say, look,
now we have to action that truth.
And I think if there's a lot more,
I believe there's a lot of people like
you and there's a lot of people like me
up there and we do. We become
disenfranchised because
media is a big business.
You know, we're sort of,
you know, pushed out.
There's only two parties in
this country and you know that,
I know that you're a
libertarian. And I'm like, look,
I think there should be three,
four or five parties in this country.
Because if there's only two parties in
the country, then they're always in power.
That means both parties are always
empowered. And that's not a democracy.
What you have to do is you have to say,
look,
there's a lot of people like us out there.
We have to start by telling the truth
and then once we told the truth,
we have to say, now what do we do to
try to go forward and not go backwards.
And when people have to understand his
true patriotism is pointing out all the
fucked up shit that you see.
True.
Patriotism is not just sticking your
head in the sand and ignoring it because
you're on team America.
That's bad because these people are not
representing what means America to you
or to I what means America to you and
I's opportunity and freedom and the place
where you can.
There's not really a caste system and
you can really rise from rags to riches
and you can really seek your dreams.
I mean there's so many different
things you can do in America. The the,
the upside of America is fucking awesome.
And the pretend that somehow or
another ignoring all the corruption and
craziness and all the things
that turned it into a money grab,
all the things that ruin everything.
That's great about America where
our government has been as become a,
where people can regulate
the flow of money.
The decisions that government make are
all greatly influenced by corporations
and when you see you connect the dots
and you connect the the money trail,
it's disgusting.
It should be illegal.
It should be eradicated for
government from government.
Government should not be about that.
Government should be about the will of
the people and the will of the people
where they've sat down and intelligently
debated every single situation.
You know with the,
if the United States government can
have a real succinct debate with the
American people about why
we're invading other countries,
that would be some fascinating shit if
we could do that on television and have
her, but no, we don't get,
we don't get any decision
making capabilities at all
when it comes to that stuff.
We just have to choose an a representative
and then watch them do shit we don't
want them to do.
You know, we've talked about
this in the past as well,
but when I went to the
Middle East where they have
all come to sell their weapons and they
come to sell their weapons to, you know,
whoever wants to buy them. You know,
North Korea is about weapons. Uh,
well for example, Siri,
it was buying weapons.
They're examined and they were using
those weapons against her own people. Um,
and that's sponsored by us and
it's our companies, uh, that are,
that are making those arms, uh,
to, to, to suppress democracy,
to kill people. And we just
care about making money. And
when I saw that, you know,
I was, I was, I was bombed.
But when I hung out with the Marines
who were there as part of a, the,
as part of the cell effects, they do this
sort of that bad. It's the, you know,
a special ops team on the planet and a
force recon the marines were there and
they're like, hold on a second. These,
these weapons are being used against us.
They were here as they're just
selling them like that. A model,
this is what the fuck is going on.
And when you actually talk to people in
the military about that kind of shit,
or using Marines to,
uh, to be protection on,
on Halliburton trucks,
bringing like a six pack because
they get paid per truck load,
you just start to go, what
the fuck is happening? I mean,
if you talk to most people in the military
who saw that kind of stuff happened
in Iraq, they're there. They're
there, they're disgusted.
I'm disgusted. And I only heard about
it. I didn't have to risk my life. Uh,
you know, to do that kind of stuff. And
then at a certain point you're like, look,
when we can't use our military as
cannon fodder, you know, did that,
I don't know what the hell
is going on, you know, with,
with these kinds of deals. But you
know, when we were at so effects,
the marines were, you
know, it made me cry.
They'll tell you the truth because
these guys came to the realization that
American companies are selling weapons
to other armies that are using those
weapons to kill us.
It's such a fucking mess,
man, and not being addressed.
It should be one of the primary issues
that our society deals with is where's
the money going?
Where our dollars going,
how are they being represented in these
foreign countries and what is the actual
physical liability of it?
How many people have actually died?
I've never seen a real honest
accounting of that either.
Like you look at the innocent and amount
of innocent deaths in Iraq and if it
varies from the really conservative
people but wring it into like a hundred
thousand that's like the
really conservative people.
But the people that are really
adamant against the war have it erotica
million. I don't know what it is
tied together. It's over a million
and you're like, okay, so you guys,
we had to go and get what I'm saying.
I'll compete with an evil dictator.
But what about all the
African evil dictators?
What about Charles Taylor in Liberia?
You know, did we get him out? No,
we supported him. I mean
like, you know, well,
well did they have oil?
You know what? We need dude, for
real. We need like real live Avengers.
We really need like superheroes
who are bulletproof.
It could turn into the hulk and
just go in over there and fuck up,
you know like dictators and take,
I mean really if science and engineers
are working on things like that,
they need to develop a real superheros.
That's the only thing that's going to say.
I know that you just got your black belt,
you to be our first superhero.
Congrats.
Double
Double Rainbow.
Yeah. I got my black belt today from John
Jacques Machado. Both of them like, no,
no, no, no, no.
Where one of them is like a symbolic
in Nogi you don't really wear a belt,
but you get to wear a black rash guard
if you want, but it's a in John jocks.
It's a GE class are we're a black belt,
like actual belt. That's awesome. Yeah.
Thank you. Thanks brother.
As an honor. Listen man,
when you going to be back in La again,
we've got to have these fucking long,
long crazy conversations
that we always have.
I know you have a bunch of other press
that you're doing for this and you've got
to go.
I love you. I love being on the show.
I wish it could be there in person.
I really appreciate being on the show,
but I know you got another a guest
and I won't take up any more time,
but I love you. I love the show.
Congratulations on the block.
Oh thank you.
I'm going to Pakistan
and Afghanistan and Iraq and Iran and
if I can get it to her and sneak into
Afghanistan so when I get back
I'll come straight out until
Jesus Christ. What stories you'll have.
Holy Shit Dude. The feeling is mutual.
I was a huge fan of yours before.
I haven't met you and now I'm,
I'm honored that we're friends.
You're the coolest motherfucker I know
and just keep going out there and doing
what you're doing cause it's beautiful.
You're videos are the best fucking
thing that's on the Internet television
period. I, I find the, the,
the whole vice.com team to be that
you guys are exposing the coolest,
most interesting, most
intriguing, the most baffling
mystifying shit in the world.
And uh,
I'm honored that with friends brother.
Thank you man. We'll talk
soon. All right. Take it easy.
Bye Bye Shane.
Shane might be one of the cools humans
on the planet. He's fearless man.
This motherfucker's just telling us he's
going to Pakistan and I ran and I rack
Jesus Christ son Jesus Christ.
Sam triple you awake over there.
Come on over here.
You sexy bitch.
Sam Tripoli and Brian Redman
when my dancing partners
this weekend in Sacramento,
first of all,
how fucking awesome is Sacramento.
Sacramento's like one of those lost gems
of a city that people don't recognize.
You know when people talk about
like cool cities to go to,
like you gotta throw Sacramento in that
mix. Sacramento is fucking bad ass.
It's beautiful up there.
It was weird flying in and seeing these
crazy river systems they have up there
and seeing all the farms and you
realize like irrigation. Yeah,
there's a big slice of
California that is just farms,
you know when you're flying over
it and looking down at that shit.
Sacramento's interesting cause like I was,
you know,
doing the show and they're like
I said something about every,
all the MMA fighters and adult film
stars come from Sag. They look good,
Sacramento and it's like, it's
a great city, man. It's like,
I know you guys think it sucks, but it's
pretty phenomenal man. Oh it's great.
It's a great place to live. You're
Ryan famous, cut a fat setup up there.
He's got this huge gym and
all that. A team, Alpha male
dudes. And they were like,
I love their setup too,
because they also bought like
houses together on a street.
They call it like the block.
I think that's cool. Yeah.
And so they all live in one neighborhood.
So like one guy lives here,
they're like,
I was across the street,
which is what I've been
wanting to do for a long time.
I think that would be the
fucking coolest thing ever.
And I've been stressing it lately with
all my friends and we had an icehouse
protocols here the other day. We all got
hammered and we were talking about it.
We're all like, we're going to
move to Santa Barbara. Fuck it.
We're all gonna move to great city,
dude. It's a fucking great city.
And what I was thinking is
gigging there soon. We just did.
I just did the Lobero theater there. How
was it? Fucking phenomenal. Coolest shit.
There's no standup up there.
There's no standup.
It's this great town and they don't
have a goddamn comedy club. Well,
it's really weird because it's
a, it's a late, late night crowd.
It's like you don't come
out til like 10 at night.
And then like before that it's
really dead. I like State Street,
which is their main street. Really?
Yeah. I've done shows out there.
There's a lot of people
in the daytime there.
I've been there a couple of times in the
day times a lot of people down there.
It's got everything.
You want a very intelligent and becomes
like a more of a nighttime crowd.
Like a nightclub type cloud crowd.
Yeah,
they'd be in all the good people hide
that we're hanging out during the day,
buying like little gifts and stuff
like that. And then we'll just repeat.
Nightlife goes in like two lost some
colleges there and there's a very uh,
intelligent population there. So it's
like the perfect place for a comedy club.
And he noted also is a lot
of old Hollywood is there.
Why was our soft Carol
Burnett for Calvert? Calvert
net fucking looks good man.
She still looks good. She's like 79 she
looked great. I was like, Holy Shit.
That's Carol Burnett.
You know,
there's a lot of like old Hollywood
that lives there. They're like,
they checked out and they
moved up to this one spot.
They all agreed to go to this one spot.
I Dunno, I dunno how they pulled it off,
but it's basically one of the
fucking best climates on earth.
It never gets hotter than weather's per
gets like it's from 85 to 65 all year
round. That's it. That's like
the hole that's all year round.
I like San Diego a little more
like just outside of San Diego.
But both those cities are pretty,
San Diego is phenomenal.
But what we were talking about,
you couldn't hear because you were,
you didn't have headphones on.
We sitting back there,
but we were talking about with Shane
Smith was Mexico and how crazy Mexico is
because of the drug wars. And I
heard part of it. Yeah. Phenomenal.
That's phenomenal. It amazing.
He's amazing guy. But,
but Mexico is right next to San Diego.
I mean that is uh,
one of the nuttiest things about
this country is that La Jolla,
which has some of the most
beautiful homes on earth.
I mean La Jolla is fucking staggering.
Where that comedy story is the views.
Have you ever like looked over at some
of those houses and you look out in those
views, you're like, oh
my God, what is this?
When time I did a show there and these
two drunk like cougar or at the show and
they just got shit faced and then
afterwards they came out, they're like,
you get in the car.
And they pointed me and it was this,
this Bentley and I just
jumped in like is bent.
And they drove me around and they took
me in this area and it was the biggest
house I've ever seen. And it's
like, there are some rich, rich
people in La Jolla.
Oh yeah.
Well there's also that core
Natto island that's right there,
that is apparently one of
the richest places on earth.
That's where Donald Rumsfeld lives.
He lives on this island.
Like they have all these
castles and fucking, you know,
billionaires lived there,
isn't it right after like Manhattan,
it's like the most expensive lamp
per square foot,
Coronado islands right up there.
I think it's supposed to be like this
really elite community have looked at some
of the houses online and they
are just fucking jaw dropping.
They're like palaces like works of art.
You know,
like someone's just put tons and millions
and millions of dollars into fucking,
you know, big importing marble
and all this crazy shit.
And you're looking at it like,
what a fucking house man.
And then you can walk to Mexico. Yeah.
You could walk to Tijuana from that.
That's crazy man. You could get there in
a day on foot. Just walking wild west.
Just think about the old days like when,
when countries,
like when you really did like people
did walk around like in the Conan the
barbarian days, they really like got on
horses or they walked from town to town.
You could walk from La Jolla to Tia Juana
and you could get there easily and a
couple of hours. What is it?
How many miles is it? Well,
I think La Jolla is about like 20
minutes from downtown San Diego,
which is about probably like five to
10 minutes from the, from the border,
so it's like,
it's like 20 miles.
San Diego Downtown San Diego is only
five to 10 minutes from the border.
It's like right there. Wow. Yeah.
I took a wrong turn on the way home
from comic con and I was going that
direction. I was like, Holy Shit,
I need to turn around before I,
I can't believe I'm going to match.
She was Jesus Christ. Well, I
enjoyed that American comedy company.
A place that we worked out.
It's a beautiful club.
Is there issues now or are we
going to be going back there?
Sam Aaa that's going on
there. I, I was a great time.
It was just a discussion between me and
him on the wording of the deal and the
wording of, uh, what the show he
agreed to him, what he actually got.
And I don't want to get into it.
Well listen man,
we can start doing regular
shows in San Diego. You know,
we could Kodaly start doing that.
We've got to do it to everywhere.
Should do it everywhere. And Diego,
Santa Barbara, wherever we want,
we can drive to, I mean it's, I'm,
I'm doing all these road gigs and there's
a lot of shit that I could do around
la too that we need to do more often. But
the comedy store, I'm in, uh, the, uh,
the ice house, which is my new
version of the comedy store.
I can't do the comedy store anymore,
but I do the ice house.
I would love to see you come
back at some point. Yeah.
It told you that it has to happen.
Certain people have pit by
meteors and abducted by aliens.
When we were flying
back from a Sacramento,
a woman sat in the middle of me and red
band and she must've been loving life.
But uh,
she's from Chico and Chico and their
Santa Rosa and there's all those awesome
parties,
cities that have these gorgeous theaters
that they have nothing going on. Right,
right,
right.
Go out there and do a couple theater
gigs and make some great cash out there.
Yeah. And you know, places, if you could
do a show in a place like Santa Barbara,
you can do, do a show in a
number, a number of different
places like that. There's,
they're all, there's 20 million of us
here. Yeah. In La it's pretty nutty.
And then there's all the fucking nor shit
Ventura where nobody goes to, you know,
nobody ever. When was the last time
you saw commonly shown Ventura?
There's a venture, a comedy, a
comedy club. It's to a new place.
No, it's, well, it's been
there for a little while. It's,
it sounded like a boat harbor
and it's actually a really fun,
I think Diaz told me he did
that the das do that play.
You got to pick certain nights cause
he likes it really clean there. Oh,
how dare he,
which I don't understand where the exits,
like I get the comedy magic club because
that's kind of a tradition and it's
Kinda like a thing there.
But like at certain place to live,
you got to keep it clean. It's
like where does that exist? Silly,
this silly comedy,
the idea of keeping it clean for standup
comedy in that you're selling the wrong
thing.
There can be clean guys.
There's going to always be guys like
Gaffigan who are fucking hilarious.
Who's clean or Mitch Hedberg, who's
one of my all time favorites. Yup.
And Mitch Mitch Hedberg was very
clean, very clean. There's no sex.
Very rarely swore. Didn't
need to swear. You know,
and if he swore it was like
an afterthought, you know,
fuck man, you know, it's,
and there's not like a part of his bed.
He didn't have to have the swearing it.
And, uh, you know, he was brilliant, but
that was his style man. That was what he,
that's the way he did his comedy. And
you know, the way you do your comedy,
you swear the way Diaz does his comedy.
I couldn't imagine someone telling me
that Joey Diaz could be the same with Joey
Diaz didn't square it because
that's crazy. That's crazy tight.
And it's a stupid way to think.
No, I didn't know Mitch Hedberg,
but how he offstage was he
that guy off stage? I'd,
it's like usually how you are off stage,
you should be that onstage to a degree,
you know, maybe even amplify it. Oh, well
he does. He was a regular guy. I mean,
I only had a chance to talk to him a few
times. I never really hung out with him,
but he was good buddies with Stan hope.
But I did get to work with them a couple
of times to work with them at the store
once and he was a good dude. It's just a
regular guy. But his comedy was, uh, just,
he had to such a unique cadence
to it. You know, in a unique,
sort of a really relaxed, silly,
uh, um, observations on things.
It was really fun to watch. But
you know, again, nothing like me,
squeaky clean, nothing like me,
but I still love it. You know,
I think comedy is just who are you?
Who are you? Are you Tony Hinchcliffe?
Are you Sam Tripoli or you Brian Redman?
Who the fuck are you and your comedy?
Brian's has a lot of silly shit that I
really would never pull off on stage with
him,
with his personality and his,
it's like everybody has their own vision
of what is funny and you can't say,
you know, oh, inforce your vision, but do
it with limited language. I want you to,
I want you to not be free
to say everything you want
or discuss everything you
want. I'm not saying that you
should discuss sex or you know,
or anything fucked up,
anything controversial, but
if you want to, you should,
you shouldn't, but you, you,
you mean it's not like you have to do
it because every people have gotten by,
like Jerry Seinfeld never talks about
politics on stage, never talks about sex,
but yet brilliant comic and
it has this amazing career.
It's like you don't have to do anything.
I can appreciate Stan hope and Bill Hicks.
And then I also grew up loving Ellen.
I Alan's like standup
is very simple to me,
but it's very funny and it's well written
and I like to think that maybe that's
her. I mean I, I've never really watched
her talk show. She started at all.
I mean, before she ever had a talk show,
she was doing great standup. She didn't,
you know, I don't think she had writers.
It's all her. Yeah. Jeff Foxworthy.
Same thing. Like you can,
you know, give him that, you
know, you might be a redneck,
but like his standup is, I always thought
was very well written and very fun.
It's good joke writer. Yeah,
he's got great. Some of you
might be a redneck shit.
Look, people discount it because you know
they love to discount redneck anything,
you know, but this is a lot of,
that's good fucking writing. So good.
So popular it,
it almost becomes like I have to
hate it because everybody loves it.
There's a little of that. I felt that
it was a little going on with Larry,
the cable guy. You know Larry, the cable
guy I've always felt was a fun character.
He's funny. I think his
writing is good. I, I've, I've,
I've seen some of his shows.
He's a fucking good comic man.
He made me laugh and he took
a gigantic rash of shit,
which I feel was mostly based on
just people like, first of all,
everybody has their own
taste as far as comedy goes,
but there's a one weird thing that
people do if they have a certain type of
taste. Your taste has got to be
wrong. You know, if you're, you're,
what you're doing is bullshit.
You're like, you could,
I've heard the argument that, you
know, dice clay is homophobic. Dice.
Clay is a, is a, he's a massage
and as he's this and that,
that if you don't say that,
that is a crazy exaggerated,
exaggerated character that he's just
going over the brink for the sake of
entertainment.
Like if you want to hold him to stand up,
if that's who he is really as a
human being, you're ridiculous.
You're ridiculous person.
I agree. And you know, if,
if someone else was saying it
maybe looked a little different,
they wouldn't be so angry.
It's so interesting how it's so much
more the messenger that in the message he
something that comes with
comedy right now. Well,
it's also when you're get famous and
you have a lot on the line, like if, uh,
like the what with Daniel Tosh said that
all that stuff that got, uh, you know,
everybody all fired up.
If he was nobody and said that
no one would have given a shit.
It was the fact that he's,
the sky was this huge comedy central show.
He allegedly said something that pissed
some woman off about rape. That's,
that's where the, the impact
came from. The impact came
from, he had a lot to lose.
And that's this weird thing where we
got in this country because immediately
people were calling out for
him to be fired. He should
lose his job. But he said,
first of all, besides it not
being that big a deal, it was a,
it was a normal thing
to say in a comedy club.
It also had nothing to do with his
television show. Right. You know,
and to say that,
you know,
he should be held accountable to every
word that comes out of his mouth when
he's adlibbing living on
stage in a comedy club.
You don't understand the art of comedy
then and you have no fucking business
judging it because you know,
and I know that when you're in the fucking
heat and bullets are flying your way
and you're interacting with a heckler
and you got, you got, you got to respond.
There's a brief window of maybe a second
or two after the word where you really
have impact, where you have the
instant correct answer and boom,
you got to drop it on that bit
that you're going to drive
Sacramento course. It did.
I had to put some people in their place,
which was really hard because
the room is all black,
so you can't even see who you're
dealing with. Well, this is just,
it's not that the real,
it's the spotlight is super powerful too,
and it's in your face and
all you see is silhouettes.
I have a big problem
within this country and uh,
with the whole notion that if you
say something I don't like, uh,
you have to go away and I can't,
we can't disagree on a point.
It drives me nuts. Like, you know, I, I,
I'm a liberal guy and there's sometimes,
you know,
these conservative say some pretty wacky
shit and then people want to fire them.
I don't get that. Like, I'd rather prove
you wrong. Then actually make you go away.
Like the guy who used to book David
Letterman Show, who said women,
the Midwest doesn't think women are,
are funny. That's a Ed, right? Yeah.
Uh, who is it? What is that? I
forget his name, but it, oh my God.
Can't remember his name. But he got to
think he got fired from that position.
But you shouldn't fire him because he
stating something that he feels he's
learned over a certain amount of time.
So what should they showed
him that he was wrong? Um,
women are funny and if you think
that you should have shown him,
making him go away doesn't
change. Eddie, Eddie, Eddie Brill,
and he brill doesn't hate when
that happens. My brain sucks.
That's where I'm saying to
take Alpha ran today. Yeah.
If your brain is broken down,
I wonder if Alpha brain and
we'd just cancel each other.
No, not to me. No. No.
I definitely have a,
an impact whether I take it,
I don't take it.
Cause you remember, do you remember when
you first started smoking weed and, uh,
the next morning you'd wake up and
you're like, wow, man, I'm my head.
I'm still fucked up from that.
We,
last night I flew foggy and then
that just kind of went away.
No, I mean I think everybody's body
processes things differently. You know,
my body's always processed.
We'd where for whatever reason,
the next day I was fine. Really? Yeah,
I'm fine in a few hours my body
goes through a pretty quick.
I remember I used to be a big thing when
I first started smoking weed and how it
like almost lasted they the next day
where I felt my brain just not being as
clear.
People don't know how deep we go
sometimes too. Sometimes we get so high,
it's just Dunkin and I. The other day
we talked about it on his podcast,
we had a great podcast that we did
together. The Duncan Trussell family hour.
You get a download it from, you can find
it, go online and figure it out. UH,
T R U s s e l l,
but we got Super Bazooka,
Bazooka Ud, and then we went to Costco
and it was my first time going to
[inaudible]. Have you ever been to
any kind of thing like that before?
I don't think I had,
I don't think I had, I might've been to
something that long, long, long time ago.
And it didn't mean anything to me because
I was probably sober when I was there.
But to go through high was like,
we were totally fear and loathing in
Las Vegas and get him and I were like,
weird shit. Oh, we were so
baked with, isn't it? We had
no business out in public,
no business cause we, uh, we're about
to do a podcast together and uh,
we were,
first of all,
I was very happy because Dunkin and
Brian had finally made up and all this
craziness of two of my best
friends, uh, at war with each other.
It was fucking nonsense. And it lasted
for so long. It was really stressful. But,
uh, thankfully it all worked out
and so we were super psyched.
So we just got deep, deep,
deep, deep, deep into the
hole. We just kept going at it.
We kept killing this joint and they
were like, oh my God, we're too high.
We're too high.
We walked down to the Costco and I
forget what we were trying to get. Oh,
you have 82 paper towels in your
car? No, I didn't get anything. Well,
you know why we didn't get anything
because that's what happened.
We went down there to get a grill
and they don't sell grills will after
September it was 110 fucking
degrees outside after
September. And they were like,
well that's a seasonal item.
I go, Whoa, Whoa, whoa.
Fucking barbecue grill is seasonal
in la when it's always warm.
I use my grill year round.
I love barbecuing.
I think like barbecuing steak
on the grill. It for me,
it lights up some caveman shit
that I have for, you know,
they say dudes have like neanderthal
in them for, I got champion me, dude.
I have some DNA
that came from the first champ that
figured out how to start a fire by banging
rocks together. And so I good
dude, I can't take that shit.
And when I uh,
when I get like a primal satisfaction
over like grilling steaks,
like it's, so it's a creepy
thing. Blood pumping. Like,
if anybody else in my family wanted
to cook the steaks, I be like,
fuck is wrong with you. Back the
fuck off. My crazy. Are you crazy?
You don't know how to fucking
cook a steak on a grill.
You're going to fuck this experience up.
I got it down where I have an iPhone,
a s a stopwatch thing and know
exactly how long I know exactly.
I know how many I use these
little charcoal chimneys.
You ever seen those things?
Well the um, you know, when
you get let go a Weber grill,
you know those Weber grills is all
you need. But those Weber grills,
they also sell these Webber,
charcoal chimneys and you
stuffed like some ripped up, uh,
like a trash bag or something.
Oh,
well some paper on the bottom it looks
like a flour sifter. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
And then you pour the charcoal in it and
light a fire on the bottom and it cooks
it all the way through the tops
of the coals or like white hot.
You lay those pitches down and
know exactly how high the grill is.
And I let it sit on that grill
for five minutes. I let that grow,
get stupid hot and then I know exactly
how much the time based on how thick the
steak is based on how much it's,
how much.
What's your favorite steak?
Because I,
I hear Bobby flay and then
I just went with the, uh,
what's the one that has to fillet and
the other state together to help for
health reasons and tastes reasons.
There's two different, I have to say,
it's two different things I like.
I love the taste of grass fed rib eyes.
It's a different taste.
It's more meaty or a more gamey rather.
It's almost like a buffalo or a like,
it's a weird,
it's more a game animal because what we
don't realize is that we're feeding cows
shit they're not supposed to be at.
That's why I just, I don't know man.
I know you gave me shit about one
become a vegetarian and I don't,
but I just don't like the way
we're raising animals right now.
It just doesn't seem, I agree.
Well, you can raise them grass fed,
you can buy grass fed meat.
And we're actually,
we're having a guy in on the
podcast a in the future, uh,
the guy from the who who wrote the
bulletproof executive, uh, Dave Asprey,
he's coming on the podcast soon and he's
going to explain all of this shit for
us. And, uh, that's a, that's
a, that's much needed because a,
I don't understand like what, you
know, how how much of an effect, uh,
grass fed meat has on you
as opposed to corn fed.
But apparently it's pretty fucking
Substan I'm sure it is. Yeah.
Apparently it's substantial,
not just with the meat but with the milk.
If you drink milk from
grass fed animal and a,
and even a cheese and butter from, uh,
from grass fed cows is better for you,
which is really kind of nuts. But
the corn, uh, in this country,
corn is a gigantic crop and they
try to use it for everything.
Everything now and the price
of corn is skyrocketed.
But also people like the way corn fed
beef tastes because it gets so fatty.
You. There is really an argument
for the how delicious, uh,
corn fed rib eye is because
they're fucking substantial.
You get a fast corn fed ribeye and
cook it over some mesquite wood.
Oh son.
Big uh,
big griller is Michael favor men.
Oh,
my shaman is a chef's amazing
mother fucker Bro. Yeah,
he's a bad motherfucker. Some of the best
steak I've had in awhile as his stake.
Yeah. Favorite mins. A bad motherfucker.
We, we've talked about, uh,
him like we should have an event here and
have him cook here. All that would be,
that'd be fucking bad ass man.
That'd be totally bad ass.
And he could do stand up to
hold the grill. He's going
to do 10 minutes. He's got,
if he's done a podcast, I know he's
looking to do something. We should be,
he should ask casking show. No cooking
guys like Faber and faber mins. Uh, guys,
guys, big meaty motherfucker. And
he's fast too. He's really funny.
So that's one of my favorite people
to gigs with. So he's a great guy.
He's a fun guy to talk to too. He has
crazy fees. Old Score comedy store.
He's been around there forever. Yeah.
We've known favor men since the,
it was the 90s, I think. First met fame,
wasn't it like eight days working a lot
when I got picked up and that was about
99. Well we went to his
place after September 11th.
We were watching all the shit go
down on TV from favorites house.
I got pictures of me and Diaz
and Ralphie May and yeah, we were
baked.
Baked is fuck hanging out of favor.
Brent's place watching the guys
who were high as fuck. Ugh,
ag lasted well. That was,
um, she got a high back then.
I didn't know you got high that long ago.
Yeah,
I was going to say that was about a
year after I started smoking weed.
I started smoking weed at 2000. I
remember that too. Yeah. Round 2099,
maybe 99, 2000, somewhere
around then. And then, um,
right after that, September 11th
happened. So maybe it was my fault, man.
I fucked reality up with my thinking man.
After right around
September 9th I started,
I just can't watch television
because everything's just a wreck.
Reenactment of that crazy ass shit
was um, those attacks on the, um,
the American embassies. What Day did
those take place? September 11th date for.
So they did it. They did it like on
purpose symbolically on that day.
That guy who put out that video. I mean
there's so much bullshit with that video.
First of all,
it looks to explain what you're talking
about for people to love them. Video. Ah,
innocence of Muslims that came out.
Yeah, I think it's, it's on youtube.
It's so poorly done and
it's like everybody's in
blackface or this is more brown
face cause they're playing Muslims.
It's so stupid.
Like I can't believe that people went
back crazy over something that dump,
like give, if Steven Spielberg came out
with something that was well executed,
I can understand why. So we would go,
no, I really can't even understand that.
But I can understand if it was done
well, this is so poorly done. You know,
there's the really crazy,
uh, I shouldn't say crazy,
but conspiracy inclined folks
think this is a CIA job.
And they think that the CIA
is doing this to a rally up these,
uh,
American enemies so that we're forced
to go to a war against Muslim countries
and we can justify a war against
Iran or, or anybody else. And uh,
that, that that's the reason
why they think this thing
got so popular so quickly.
Because before I even
knew about this film,
they were already bombing us embassies.
Like they just immediately went
to rocket attacks. And I was like,
how did they find out about it?
I mean,
what kind of Twitter account
did they have? You know,
I have 800,000 people on my
Twitter account and I didn't
find out about it until
someone shot a rocket into an embassy.
You know, how are these people, how,
how was that information
distributed so quickly?
And then how is this organized so
quickly where people just immediately are
protesting it? Like you've all seen it.
Yeah. You all got together and saw it.
I'm not sure that that's how viral that
video was. It seems to me like, man,
if I wanted to,
to look at the past of like some
of the shit that America has done,
like the Gulf of Tonkin incident and all
the different things that we've done to
try to get us into war.
And I understand that that's happened.
That has happened. It's fact.
There's no getting around it.
It's a hundred percent fact. The Bay
of pigs, that's a fact too. You know,
the Northwood operation,
Northwoods, that's a fact.
There's a lot of crazy
facts about like about war.
So if you want it to really
piss off Muslims and get
them to do something stupid,
what's really ridiculous as all you have
to do is make a depiction of their guy,
make a depiction of
this Muhammad character.
And you could do it as a CIA cycop cyop
or you know, whatever they call it.
The one of the woman who was on
the show and actress Cindy Lee,
she claims that her voice was
dubbed and she says that, um, uh,
who she has a role in the controversial
low budget film titled The innocence of
Muslims, which has sparked riots against
the u s in the Middle East. I mean,
this is like some shit
out of a fucking movie.
This movie is some shit out of a movie.
And she's saying, she says, yeah, exactly.
The act, the act more than that,
more, more crazy than that.
The actors were deceived.
A Garcia told the Hollywood reporter,
my voice was dubbed and I wasn't,
it wasn't even my voice.
I had no idea he did that
until the trailer came out.
My only part was the role of a mother
talking to her husband, her daughter,
and this man named master
George in the film. Uh,
Garcia plays the mother of a 12 year
old girl who is set to marry the Prophet
Muhammad. Whoa. Garcia is
heard. Insulting Mohammed,
asking her husband if Muhammad
was a child molester because uh,
her daughter is but a child
and he's 55 years old. Wow,
this is crazy. So they put all
that into her mouth after it was.
This is, it's very possible
that this is like some CIA shit,
a lot of money trying to just trying to
rile these motherfuckers up to give us
an excuse to start going in there.
And this is how it starts.
Rocket attacks on embassies is step one.
It's a real weird to listen to General
Wesley Clark talk about all this stuff in
like 2000 and it was 2004
or 2008 he basically,
Brian can you pull that up please?
A General Wesley Clark predicts a u s tax.
Maybe. I can't believe that. You know,
we got to stop calling it military defense
and just start calling military off
fence cause that's what
it seems to be now.
We're just always on the offensive man
and it never seems to work out. Yeah.
The plan.
Look up General Wesley Clark and it says,
reveals US plan to
invade Iraq and this guy,
I forget what year this was,
that he uh, did this interview,
but he basically outlines everything
that's happening today. Okay.
It was 2007 he outlined this,
join me,
better me and join me in more this,
enjoy this big
jerk off this lotions are sponsoring
this very important message.
Jerk off. Lotions are so
critical to a good masturbate.
It's this here. No, no, no. You got,
you're watching movies on general.
Wesley Clark reveals US plan.
If you just,
just type general and Clark and
youtube. Yeah, that's exactly it.
And democracy now hit the,
hit the volume. He says,
we've made the decision. We're
going to war with Iraq. Oh,
I came back to see him a few weeks later
and by that time we were bombing in
Afghanistan. I said, are we still going
to war with Iraq? And he said, oh,
it's worse than that.
He said he reached over on his desk.
He picked up a piece of paper.
He said, I just, he said,
I just got this down from upstairs
mean separate events office today.
And he said,
this is a memo that describes how we're
going to take out seven countries in
five years starting with Iraq
and in Syria, Lebanon, Libya,
Somalia,
Sudan and finishing off Iran
is, and there's no, you
wrap your heads around that.
Wrap your heads around that.
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is General Wesley Clark in 2007
describing the u s plan to invade Iraq,
Syria, Lebanon, Libya, Somalia,
Sudan and I ran and that these are all
areas where shit is going down. Um,
especially like what just happened
in Libya. Look what's going on.
I mean that's where the a US
embassy was bombed as in Libya.
Somalia is of course a hotbed of piracy.
There's always some crazy shit going
on in Somalia, which by the way, uh,
I don't necessarily blame
the Somalians at all.
If you go and look up their history and
look up what they call the volunteers,
what do they call the
voluntary coast guard of Somalia?
I think that's what they call themselves.
They started kidnapping people because
they were kidnapping European ships who
are dumping poison.
It's their waters.
Their waters were completely polluted
and they are like a fishing culture.
And so they started going out
and kidnapping these Europeans.
But then it became like much
more profitable to kidnap people.
Then it was to fish because they fucking
polluted the shit out of that water.
They dump toxic waste right off their
ocean. It's just the fishing population
that's just horrible.
Yeah, it's crazy shit.
So these people really
went full on Desperado.
Like it was created by greed.
The Somalian problem was created by
green and that seems to be the biggest
problem with a lot of
the decisions be made.
One thing that scares me about the
military right now and is that how many
people are in charge of the military
that never were in the military? Right.
You know, it's chicken.
It's very easy to be like,
you know the talk game about punching
people in the face if you've never been
punched in the face, you know, it's
like if you've been punched in the face,
you think twice about starting a fight.
Cause you know the air hurts, right?
And you know what you can do to
somebody if you know how to fight.
And you know when you can do to somebody
and you don't want someone doing that
to you. You know, you're
like, whoa Nelly, you know,
I had a conversation with a dude is like,
ah, I could have kicked that guy's a,
you know, he's talking shit. I
could have kicked his ass. I'm like,
how do you know he could
have kicked his ass?
You don't know anything about that guy.
I know some little dudes that
can fuck you up. You know?
And people who run around thinking that
they could just get in fights, fights,
fights are fucking terrible.
It's never a good thing to get in a fight.
I think this is the first election
ever were both guys running for the
presidency. I think neither
don't have military backgrounds.
And I think that's like such
an interesting thing that
you're putting the guy in
charge of the military that's never
actually had any military experience.
That's interesting.
Is that the case?
Well currently than Clinton went
against George Bush senior military.
Well he was CIA and yeah,
he was military World War Two flu.
Yeah. I mean, but he was
a, not just military,
he was actually a part of the intelligence
community and the head of the CIA,
Reagan was military. What was I
saying? He, I think he flew to, or he,
I know he was something in the military
and of course George Bush Jr was like
all the craziness of it is national
guard. Cub Scouts. Yeah. He went,
he went fishing once. He was in a
weird situation. But then again, um,
well who was the opposing
McCain? Yeah. Mccain.
Mccain was running for president and
he was obviously a war hero. Yeah.
It's kind of interesting.
These are the first two guys against a
guy who married the ketchup Eris who was
the guy, uh, that they actually
somehow made him look bad. Uh,
who was the guy that Bush
ran against the, uh, second,
first term was Al Gore. Second
Term John Kerry. John Kerry. Oh,
did you say, I thought you said
John McKay my bad? No, no, no.
I said Mccain was the guy who,
uh, Obama went again. Yeah.
So I think this is the first time
we've had two guys who have no military
background at all. Yeah, no, I think
you're right. John Kerry was a military.
Obviously the whole swiftboat
thing was ridiculous. Won't carry,
probably should have won.
You know,
who knows how much fuckery
was going on with that.
Go go watch on TV or on Youtube.
Go look up hacking democracy.
It's one of the craziest documentaries
I've ever seen about those voting
machines and how easily
they could change the votes.
And I don't understand why people don't
think that this is at all possible.
Come on when that much money is at stake,
people do some shady shit.
There's so much money at stake,
we can't even wrap our head around it
and people become addicted to all this
money. It's just like I was talking
about earlier with Shane Smith, the,
the idea that the, uh, the,
the whole criminal system is a,
a profitable system for a lot of people.
There's a lot of people who get contracts,
you know,
for us to hire new security guards.
And there's a lot of people that run
private prisons in California, everywhere,
man, everywhere. This is look, this
jobs to be had in keeping drugs illegal.
The real thing is you just
got to figure out how to,
how to make something that replaces
those jobs with something that's actually
good for people instead of
arresting kids for pot. You know,
there's gotta be a way to do that where
you're figuring out how to use all these
people and you don't,
you don't take them out of work.
He just give them something productive
to do instead of being fucking crazy. Uh,
you know, anti-drug Crusaders. I mean,
the whole thing about these
stabilizing regions too,
you see that going on right now in Mexico.
Like we are de stabilizing that
whole area for whatever reason.
I don't know either cheap labor or lower,
there's this whole, you ever hear the,
the marrow, that whole conspiracy
theory about trying to turn like Canada,
America and Mexico into one kind of one,
I don't know.
Groups so that they all have
the same denomination. Yeah.
It didn't someone talk about that on CNN.
Yeah.
And then they were talking about
how they did that with the euro,
but it's crumbling.
The euro right now it's like cause all
the different countries at different
economic schemes going on and they
can all support each other and it's,
it's just really interesting.
But there's that whole saying
that they're trying to, you know,
make Mexico so poor that they need us to
join in and then we make everybody like
the marrow.
It's like this whole,
and then when you do that you get rid of
the US Constitution. That's the whole,
that whole conspiracy theory
about that. Yeah, it was,
Jack wasn't a Jack Cafferty who was
on CNN who actually brought up that.
But I think that's proven to be
like Obama actually addressed that.
And running for president. He said
there's no evidence of that. Well,
that's what he's going to sell. Well, I
mean, do you really think that they're,
they're destabilizing Mexico on purpose.
Do you think that that's what's going
on and that the idea is to just combine
everything,
destabilize it so we have a reason to
combine with it and then just take it over
really a whole bunch of theories about
that one. Yeah. But the stabilizing,
it's easier to, you know, it's easier to
deal with something when you're paying.
If you're saying that these
drug cartels or have us, us, uh,
our firearms,
it's easier to pay off the cartel than
it needs to pay off an entire Mexican
government. Do you understand
what I'm saying? Yes.
It's much easier to pay off one guy
then pay off a whole group of people.
Yeah. Yeah. It's, it, the whole
thing is very interesting.
And if that's really how
they've organized it,
that they've decided
to d stabilize Mexico,
what are they going to do to Canada and
get them to join because the Canada's
economy's great. The people were fucking
coolest shit. They're the, you know,
like how are they gonna how are we going
to make them hop on the Amiro the only
thing that could make this as
Canadians are so god damn agreeable,
they might just join up anyway.
Alrighty.
Where I guess we all have the same money.
Canada is phenomenal.
I'm very excited about
going there this week.
We're going to have a good time
at Toronto this week and uh, I'm,
I'm really sorry.
I've,
I keep hearing all these stories about
people that are trying to buy tickets and
then they buy them online.
Uh,
the only ones that are available are
from these disreputable places that are
charging like a stupid stupid amounts of
money. I got no control over that folks.
I'm really sorry to hear about it.
There's certain venues where you
can kind of make different deals,
but a lot of venues including great ones
like Massey Hall, they, they have, um,
they have it set up online and people can
just buy the tickets and then they can
just sell them and there's
nothing anybody can do about it.
I don't know how he could stop people
from buying the tickets and then trying to
resell them at a higher, uh,
face of scalping. Yeah, scalp.
It's essentially like a leader
in herself. Scalping. I mean,
I don't know how they do it,
but they charged stupid amounts
of money for the tickets.
I have nothing to do with that though,
folks.
I'm sorry Louis C K is
doing something different.
Hash only you have to run to the
comedy club and, and pay for cash.
That's how he did it.
He just said that's at the comedy store.
But I think other places he's allowing
people to buy tickets with credit cards.
But you,
you will,
he can only use certain venues that
don't have deals and he's trying to like
figure out how to do it where it's
going. Pearl Jam. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I guess I'm somewhere on that.
But you can't do anything
he wants, you know. Yeah.
I mean he sold out the comedy store,
which has 400 seats in like 20 minutes.
And did he do it off of Twitter?
Like how did people know that he
was doing it? He just said, hey,
I'm going to be at the comedy store. Yeah,
he's not in town. They're very often,
so when he's in, you know,
in town, it's a big deal.
It's so good to see that La Salle has a
great comedy scene like that. You know,
that people are enjoying comedy enough
that there's a big enough group of people
that they can just
immediately hear about that.
And everybody like runs out cause those
are probably like comedy fans, you know,
seals come right out here. There's
like, like when I moved out here,
it was like 99,
I think there was like three comedy clubs.
Now. There's like five or
six comedy clubs. Yeah.
There's all these new ones
too that have popped up.
And there's so many like peripheral
clubs, like the Irvine Improv, the Bray.
I did Breyer last night with Collin. I'll
let you go down. There was headlining.
It popped in fucking hilarious man.
He was great. It was really funny.
And that's a great improv too. And
then of course, the ice house. Oh,
we have a show this, um, this Wednesday
night at the ice house. And, uh,
it's a fucking stacked lineup. Ladies and
gentleman, this is one of our best ones.
Uh,
were doing these as often as possible.
We're trying to do these fucking things,
uh, if not every week real close to him.
And for us it's like an opportunity to
fuck around to work on new material.
And so you get a lot of guys
who are stretching out and
just fucking around and,
and, and we also do a podcast
simultaneously that you could download.
It's only available off of the desk
squad network, which is on iTunes.
Are you guys selling tickets
off that? No, no, no.
We're selling tickets here at
the ice house. The Ice House
takes it, but it's Dom Irrera,
uh, Doug Benson, Joey Diaz,
Duncan Trussell. Um, and Oh,
Greg Fitzsimmons I as a good line and
maybe Thompson girl, he might come down.
He told me it's a phenomenal line and
we're trying to do these as often as we
can. And uh, it's 15 bucks and the
fucking show sick. And you know,
it goes on forever.
I think death squad shows are great,
but like it's hard for me
to do new material there
cause it always crushes cause
you know they listened to the podcast
and then like I have to take it somewhere
else and try and crowd that doesn't listen
to a podcast or doesn't know anything
about that squad because
there's such phenomenal crowds.
They're like always so hot. And then I
do a joke and I'm like, oh that crushed.
And then I go somewhere where maybe
they don't know my podcast and then just
like, okay it did not get
the refill. It's also,
they don't know you're his personality.
So he's saying all this twisted shit.
Yeah. What's the little fuck
is this crazy Armenian asshole,
but you're up there just slinging that
comedy deck. Like they're your fans. Yeah,
yeah, yeah. I go in there,
I don't give a shit.
And like I had to fall Ian Edwards last
the couple a couple of days ago. Man,
that kid is funny. Very funny dude. That
guy's one of the best writers I know.
And he always has huge clumps of new
material and he makes me feel so lazy.
Well you aren't lazy. I'm not lazy.
Dooley's I worked my ass off Bro.
Cause he lazy.
I write a lot.
I think he's really busy and a lot
of different projects. I don't know.
Let me say, do you feel lazy? Do you
feel lazy when you watch a guy like Ian?
I sometimes I'll tell you why.
Let me say when your gig not doing
new new shit, whisper in there.
There's a little feeling dizzy doodle
feeling that you may be lazy. Listen, I,
there was a time when I was doing a little
too much partying and I didn't write
like I used to. A reality
comes out. I omit that.
I always admit that.
Now I know why people come my podcasts
and stare at themselves. Hold back.
It's very hard not to look
at yourself on that squeak.
Can you take me off and you can easily
not looked at it. You're a grown man, Sam.
I'll look me in the eye. I'm a very vain
man. You liking the way you look? No,
not at all. Being on this podcast right
here on my rare quit drinking. Really?
Yeah, so I'm self all Chubby
and fat faced and then a,
apparently Daniel tosh said it was
bothering him and, and Tom's like,
you know what? That's it. Yeah.
Well, I'm a, I'm in that same boat.
I was doing a lot of party. I wish I
could just do a little partying. I just,
I want to party like it's,
I don't remember flying
Zeplin 1972 I'm going, we just got a
new album out and it's a world tour.
Yeah. That's not good for your liver.
Yeah. Well that's why I wish I had them.
I could just do it a little,
but for me it's like going to the gym
and just doing like one pushup and then
you're like, oh, that's all I want
to do. That's not how I do it.
And you can enjoy a little
bit of the marijuana.
Just didn't the can once in a while,
but it's not really like
he has the air. I get really like
paranoid. Yeah. You know why you should.
Life is terrifying.
Should be paranoid.
You're a little flesh bag,
little flesh bag walking around.
I was going to here.
That's what we are.
We're human flesh bags that we're all
coming with vulnerable that cats dude.
You know why?
Because it's the only place you
could talk some political shit.
What brains not freezing up on you.
I did one last night and you
bring up the top and even it's a,
it's a political podcasts and their brains
just freeze and nobody wants to talk
about Sam triple youtube.
Most of your podcast with porn stars.
Now that's not true. You do most of
your mum without porn stars. I do.
I do a wide range of it. That's
one fourth. Yeah, there's still,
the naughty show is only one fourth porn
stars now to a whole bunch of, okay,
so I'm,
I'm out of the loop.
So did you start off at one point in
time was all like you would draw to get
porn stars on and then you, you just
backed off of it and just fixed it up.
It's like I'm bored with that. I want
to be interviewed. Different things.
I want to explore different
parts of the world.
But you find that when
you get in dudes on,
you talk politics with them
and they freeze it up well,
and not just necessarily on a podcast,
but just in general in
like normal conversations.
This podcast I did last night where it's
like brain just freeze up if you bring
up, if you challenge someone's
idea, they get like, uh, you know.
But do you think that's what it is?
I think also people are tired of
hearing about politics. It's gross.
Like they want to talk about sports,
they want to talk about fun shit.
They want to talk about movies or video
games or anything. That's fun. It's like,
you know when they're off of work and
you start bringing up politics like,
Oh fucking Christ with this. You
know? And for a lot of folks,
I mean that's really how they
look at Shit. It's, it's,
it's hard to want to concentrate on some
bullshit hustle that you have no real
control over.
Yeah.
And I also think they're just tired of
the same rhetoric and like they think
it's going to just devolve into screaming.
You got to put America back to work.
Why they signed like free trade deals.
That's what I left.
Like that's why I like to talk about
the stories that you only here for a
glimpse and then they disappear.
You're like, well what about that?
And people that are, that's why.
What do you think of Gay Republicans?
There's a lot of them. Um, it's sorta
like vampire familiars, you know,
they want to stay close to the master,
but it's also like,
it's very interesting that they decided
to go with their financial needs more
than their social needs because I feel
like most people vote on their social
needs. Very complicated. Sam.
It was a lot of shit going on with being
a gay repo again, first of all, the, the,
the, the self loathing
aspect of, you know,
a lot of gay people are very ashamed
of being gay. It's very sad and tragic,
but it's also true. You know,
I, I know gay people that are,
that like are really uncomfortable about
the way people view people that are
gay. And so there's some
self-loathing going on.
There's also people that came from,
you know,
perhaps they came from like really
restrictive a family environment.
So they have like a deep sense of
shame and, and their own sexual needs.
And, you know, they, uh, they,
they don't mind that this,
a Republican party loads
their existence and,
and wants to stop them from being married.
They don't mind as long as
they appear to be, you know,
they appear to be respectable and
they're connected with the Republicans.
It's like they're having dinner with
the vampire. Right. You know, they're,
they're like right there with the,
the monster that,
that holds them back and treats them like
shit and wants to throw rocks at them.
They caught them fucking, you know, so
there's something to that. Yeah. Well,
there's something that people become,
well, there's a lot of, uh, you know, uh,
black eyes become, uh, really, uh,
they become like uncle Tom Ish with,
with, with, with racists. And they, they,
they embrace the, the one that's
holding the Mac. You know, it's a,
a common thing that's d that drove people
crazy in the black community when they
would find a, a black eye, you know, cow
town to racists like that just set a,
you know,
that that gross sort of a thing whole
came massa whatever you need mass. Right.
And I'm like man, this is sad shit. Like
what are you doing man? You're, you're,
you're like, you get need to get
away with this piece of shit.
This guy's a slave owner.
One of my favorite bits of years when I
first started watching him perform was
about how interracial porn is.
Like the number one porn and it
disproportionate amount of people watch
internet, interracial porn in the
deep south disproportionate amount.
And I was like, well that's not not
black guys watching that shit. Yeah.
It's white guys. Yeah. Yeah.
Cause they just so nasty.
There's just something about
that. It seems so taboo. Boobs.
She bond that black did
limit her enjoying it.
Yeah. It's a, there's something
fucked up about race hasn't man,
there's something really weird about it
from a state of fear. It's just fear of,
uh, and there's some, uh, you know,
ethnocentrism is also weird shit.
We were, you know, it's not even
about black people. Like, well,
how about about like Chinese workers that,
you know,
make your cell phone to get 50
cents a week? I'm exaggerating.
I don't know what they really
get, but it's, you know,
the Foxconn suicides and you find out
these factories where all your iPhone shit
is getting creative is got nets set up
because people want to jump off the roof.
Like, Oh yeah, yeah, pretty fucking crazy.
And I've heard people defending
that when they go, well,
actually if you think about it, the number
of people that commit suicide there,
it's a actually less
than your average city.
And Foxconn is basically like a city.
There's 500,000 people live in there.
And you're like, yeah, but
most people don't commit
suicide at work. And the, the,
their whole argument was, well, if
they made an iPhone here in America,
it will cost $5,000. You're like, okay,
so that's kind of a like a very
selfish point of view, right? Yeah.
Well it is true.
It is true that it would cost more money,
but I think it's been disproven that
it would cost that much more money.
I think they said it would cost like an
extra 50 bucks or something like that.
And you can make a, an iPhone in, in
America and pay people a fair wage.
I forgot the number,
so I shouldn't really say 50 bucks,
but it wasn't enough to really
shock the shit out of me.
But then I've seen other ones that say
it's thousands of dollars, like 14,000 so
I don't know who the fuck is.
Right.
And who's telling the truth and what kind
of funny Hollywood logic they're doing
as far as their, their math and a lot
racism. Go to China. That's racism, man.
I went there with Steve Burns.
I had a beard on,
I looked very middle eastern when I get
a beard rocking and I could not get a
taxi to pick me up because
middle easterns over there,
they think they're all drug dealers.
So no one would pick us up. So we,
we flagged down this one guy that would
pick us up and he literally had taken
what looks like a hot dog vending machine
and turned it into a taxi and we sat
in the back and you can ask anybody who
goes to like China driving over there is
crazy. They have lights
but they don't follow him.
They're like Christmas ornaments,
traffic lights.
They're just over there blinking
and no one's following them.
Really go through red lights. I
do. Here's a crazy thing, right?
You want to make a lefthand turn in China.
You don't make it from the left hand side.
You come all the way from the right
and you turn over there. Why don't,
I don't know why. It's two weirdest thing
I've ever seen. No one does it that way.
Yeah, but because that's how they do it
over there. Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
Wait a minute. They don't ever
turn left from the left lane.
No math from the right and we were
over here. You turn way over there.
Can we find evidence of this online?
Google the I. Everything I say here,
I know will be instantly googled.
Uh, but yeah, man, it's crazy.
Me and Steve Byrne,
we screamed like little girls at
least 13 times on the ride home.
It is scary. Here's the
thing, didn't see one
traffic accident,
not one over there.
And the bulk of the country
drives on the right. Oh, okay.
I think there's some confusion here.
Well, I don't know what
the confusion is. I did it.
I think, um, some of the country
in China drives on the right,
but some drives on the left. So maybe
that's where the, the, the, the issue is.
Does that make sense?
See, after people drive on the
right side and half people,
why I'm telling you man, they
travel. They don't slow down, dude.
They just go right in to the,
they just go
right in.
What are we watching accidents?
This is Chinese trafficked.
I don't want to see Chinese traffic
cause you know someone's going to get run
over. There was some horrible
shit that I saw online of a,
Oh shit.
Oh fuck dude on a motorcycle.
They nailed it.
Let's see. That's what they do. They just
drive through. They don't give a shit.
There's no rules. No. Look at this.
This is nuts. Oh my God, this is nuts.
You know what?
I hate seeing stereotypes played
out right before my fucking eyes,
but where are the Chinese Nascar drivers?
Oh my God.
He just nailed an old lady on her bike.
These people are fucking crazy telling
you, man, you scream like a little girl,
like dried mixed.
Look at this video.
This is crazy.
These people are in the with the shitty
cars and they just drive and through
intersections.
I hate saying this because
I know on it would,
I don't want to believe in
stereotypes. Oh Jesus. Oh,
hit by a bike and the other guy
runs over him and then keeps going.
They don't care, dude. There's
a billion of them. Oh my God.
Look at this guy trying to make it across.
This is insane.
This guy cannot do this. He must back
up and rethink and get a helicopter.
That's the only way he's getting across
that lane. People are fucking nuts, man.
They don't care. I don't like watching
this. This has given me mad anxiety.
Can you imagine? Oh Jesus
Christ. He's kind of motorcycle.
Oh he had dodged one and then
got nailed by another. Oh my God.
They man, the fact that those guys are
stopped is amazing. It just like they,
we vote Jesus. Look at this.
Oh Jesus, look at this.
Boom. Oh my God. These
people on bikes are insane.
They're trying to cross the
traffic. They just say ready. Go.
Their streets must just be like egg
drop soup everywhere. Just brain.
What they saying.
A lot of it has to do with the Chinese
culture and the way they interact with
people. They mind their own business. They
don't look to the left into the right.
They just keep, keep straight. And
because of that, this leak there socially,
this is explained to me by a
Chinese man that the, the, the,
the way they're socially,
um,
sort of a groom to interact
with people and walking.
Cause there's so many people you bump
into people all the time that they've sort
of taking this and then drive.
They drive with the same mentality.
They go through red lights.
Yeah,
exact opposite of what you're
supposed to do when you're driving.
You're supposed to look to the left,
look to light, check your rear view.
Look who's beside you. Check.
This is fucking crazy ass
hole. He might drive nutty.
Let me back off. Let him ahead. Amazed
about you while we were in Sacramento.
How much you follow the rules
of the road? Really? Yeah.
Like yeah.
Well what did you think I would do?
We'll look at bigs. No, when my
fake my own cop light on the roof.
Not that at all.
But when like drinking bottles,
when drug and red band
with our gps to the,
where we went to go eat
afterwards. Uh, you did a u turn,
you're like a make a uturn here and you're
like, ah, I can't do that right here.
I have to pull in over here.
Like I would have been like
just you turn right there,
there's a little sign that says no.
You turn and when you see one of those,
don't take a fucking new term. It's not
that hard. Well there's nobody coming.
I would you turn it in common,
but that could be someone
watching Sam cops.
You don't want to give them an excuse
to pull you over. It Says No. You turn.
How hard is it to take a left pull
into a driveway and turn in an Rv Park?
Pretty fucking easy. Yeah. We
went to an ivy mark when, uh,
if they ever do you have season China,
you should do a show because there's
tons of ex pats cause it's like the wild
west over there. It's like you don't
have everybody in China, in China.
There's a lot of ex pats. I had
the best time out there, man.
You did a lot of stand up.
Steve Byrne took me out.
We did a co we gigs all over the
place. Man. Shanghai is the shit man.
I really, Shanghai is the shit dude.
Who knows how people, I don't know.
Steve Byrne took care of it and he'd
say, Hey, you want to come out? I'm like,
yeah man, I'll do it. And
it was a great time, man.
I saw an Anthony Bordain
special in Shanghai.
It looked like he was having
a good fucking time. Dude.
They leave. They leave.
If you're like an American, they'd leave
you alone, man. I think it was Shane.
I had to leave you alone, dude. Oh yeah.
He'd drink all night and it's like old,
the old west where men are men. Dude.
It's like a gray, like, whoa.
This is what it was like. Well,
you're telling me is you can go to
a massage power and get jerked off.
Anything you want over there as a,
as a, as an American man. Really.
I had the best time. How's the food?
Food's phenomenal, man. Dude dies.
They'll eat it. Whoa. That's how China,
you go to a menu, they're like squirrel.
They got everything and they're
throwing anything on a grill.
Did you fuck around at all and
experiment with different kinds of,
you need a dog or anything?
No, I, you know what man,
I can't eat a dog and I don't want to eat.
Like they put,
they do that thing from Indiana Jones
where they put a monkey in the middle of
the fucking table and he started
whacking on fat and I'm like,
that never happened to me. But I'm
like, dude, I can't watch this.
I don't want to eat this
thing. And they'll watch it
getting pound on the, hey,
what did they hit with a hammer?
They hit the monkey's head like
they didn't do it for me, but I,
someone told me they were over
there in China and they were, they,
they like put them in the middle thing,
locked him up. Heads. You stay and they go
rains, right? Yeah, I can't do
it. What the fuck is that man?
How is that a real way to eat? I just
think it's just cruel. Delicious.
But you think it is because you would
want to whack on a poor monkey's head.
You know that like how smart they are.
Well you know what it is. I think,
I think if you're trying to like
appease only the elite, you know,
and give them some crazy thing
that only they have access to is a,
there's a certain satisfaction that some
sick fucks get into being cruel and to
having something that's so delicate.
It's such a delicacy.
So rare we have brought in a special
McCall monkey, you know, poor little fuck.
It's locked up in a little guillotine
choke. You mean Agar old? The goal,
as soon as they put the monkey and
the thing I'm out, they sat in real.
Cause I heard that the scene in
faces of death was faked that scene.
Well that's probably, that part is
fake, but they really do do that.
Do they really? Yeah.
Okay. Let's look that up.
That seems like something I showed
them. No Rogan's fact checks. But yeah.
So it say among his sound effect check
bonky hit with so far Sam's record
hammer. So monkey and
hit with a hammer, uh,
in front of guests. Maybe diners,
front of diners, Youtube. That shit,
man. Youtube that sheet.
Let's see. Faces of death.
The monkey diner scene is
also unconvincing. Yeah. Okay.
But it, but it does, it actually
happen. This is, it's a lot of,
this is all about the, uh, can you Google
that? Does monkey eating monkey brains?
Yeah. Maybe another search. Let me try
another shirt. Shop eating monkey brains.
I couldn't do that, dude. That's
another reason I just, I want China.
Okay. Yeah, yeah, yeah. That's uh,
eating monkey brains and China's actually
monkey baby is controversial food
stuff often attributed
to the Chinese. Okay.
Wow. This is crazy, dude.
If you go to Google,
they have images of like
pleats of monkey brains. Dude,
I don't want to see that here too.
It's also found it's not,
it's a controversial food stuff
often attributed to the Chinese,
but also found is certain other countries,
the practice of eating monkey brains
has led to over hunting in Indonesia.
Especially due to the unfounded belief
that eating monkey brains can cure
impotence. It turns is about
curing impotence with these fucks.
They're always eating no China,
they're always even like tiger claw
and all this nutty shit that doesn't do
anything to try to cure and
don't they know about Viagara.
Why do you have to have monkey brains
when you have viagara silly box that's
discussing the brain is when the,
when the Beijing Olympics happened,
they put out the government without,
you can't serve dog.
Cause they knew like Westerners would
freak out and they were told they have to
serve black people. Cause the Chinese,
they're not in the black people,
but yet they love Kobe Bryant and
Lebron James and all that shit.
But they had to put that out to the
Chinese. Don't care man. It's okay.
Here's a problem.
Uh,
the eating of monkey brains from living
monkeys is a part of some restaurants
menu is this one? Well, no example
of urban legend. It's not true.
Yeah. They don't actually eat monkeys
like that in restaurants. I mean,
maybe someone's tried it,
but it's not a every restaurant.
I still get a point for
that. That's real shit. Well,
monkey brains eating monkey brains is
real shit. Thank. Apparently they just,
they'd cook them too.
It's like also it was a scene in Indiana.
Jones been a scene of a
bunch of movies. But, uh,
I don't say according to this article
at least it seems to think that it's an
urban legend. Maybe I should check
Snopes. Snopes as good at that shit.
How about we just agree I'm
right and we just, well,
you definitely are right about
the meat and monkey brains.
I want to know whether or not they
actually hold the fucking monkey in that
little box and beat his head and
then scoop it out. Speaking of, okay,
here's a question.
Speaking of Monkey.
Yeah.
I,
I found out that Bobby leads in a new
TV show or now I NBC where he plays with
the monkey from the hangover and I guess
that that the monkey is going to be a
huge,
it's going to be a new monkey show.
And like every week it's happening
in the bear. Yeah. Oh, so based,
supposedly really funny.
It's lobbying and a monkey like tested
like the highest they've ever tested on
NBC. Any, yeah. Any TV show
ever on NBC lobbyists. A
monkey. Gabby, Leanna, monkey.
Can't wait. Yeah. What,
what, what happens with that?
This rehearsed that scene.
It's like a monkey.
Yeah. That's a, how do you get the
monkey to do what you want them to do?
Yeah. It's either going to be the greatest
thing ever or the worst thing ever,
but I have feeling it's
feelings to be phenomenal.
I think anything Bobby Lee's going to be
as funny. Yeah, that mustache is lethal.
He's hilarious.
So it's Todd glass man on the burn.
If he'd get to check out
Todd glass on the burn,
he just fucking came in there
and just destroyed. Well,
he's a guy who's just fast and
always had a great opinion.
Anytime you watch them on stage, he's
the guy that's very much in the moment.
He's not just, it's not just complete
scripted. He, he's not afraid to lay in,
lay the wood to the crowd.
Would you ever get high and
go scouting what? Scouting?
Like Eagle Scout and you were talking
about the boy scouts earlier and I was
thinking how cool it would it be just
like once a month you and your friends get
high and go scouting in the woods
just to make fun of the other scouts.
So it'd be like pretty funny.
No,
because we're too old for
that and they add our age.
You put in the scouts were
probably pedophiles. Okay,
here's the deal. Um, this is the deal.
A lot of people do eat monkey brains,
Ra and they shoot them.
They have a special way of shooting
the monkey out of the tree. Oh yeah.
We shoot them to get them to jump first.
You shoot Adam and he jumps and then
you have to shoot him because you can't
just shoot them when they're up in
the tree because they'll, you know,
they'll lock onto a branch
and then they'll rot up there.
You can never get them down.
It's really crazy. The,
apparently they shoot
him all the time and uh,
but the monkey brains are eating raw and
they do eat them like generally right
after they killed him. So
that, that is, that is a real,
a way they eat the monkey brands.
That's fucked up.
Yeah. I don't want that man. That's like
going to a hamburger restaurant and hey,
here's your sledge hammer
and you got to go like,
just drop the wood on some a cow,
man. I like, I don't dig that at all.
Yeah. Whoa. Okay. Well, here's
the, here's another thing though.
A guy is, uh, giving a depiction
in another article, uh,
of a monkey's head being
supported in a bracket,
two pieces of wood with a semicircular
hole on each side so that when you put
them together, they form a complete
circle around the animal's neck,
allowing the head to be
exposed above the plank.
The hair around the head is shaved with
a razor blade and a small chisel and a
hammer is used to quickly chisel a circle
around the crown and the top part of
the skull is removed.
A teaspoon is used to scoop up the brains,
which is immediately, this has to be
done before the monkey dies. Oh God.
Why you just unnecessary there
people? Wow. So this is a,
not only will you a corrected that
has happened that this is, um,
this has been going on for a long time.
This was written in 1948 or 1949.
He's an eye witness. And he didn't
say whether or not he'd partaken in.
The brain's themselves. Look
behind. You know, don't, don't,
dude, I want to see that.
Is that legit? Dude? I
want to see that. Whoa.
This is fucking crazy. Keeping
on, keeping on. Keeping on.
Uh, this is just a documentary talking
about the faces of death documentary.
So is it real? They're saying
that this is a real middle of the,
the table.
We're prepared
for the kill.
You don't have to watch it.
We don't have to watch it.
You can watch it if you
want. Yeah. We don't know.
Some people that want to see that shit.
Um, you know what? What is
that? Is that just a Desperado?
They just need food so bad. It just seems
like when you go that deep or you're,
you're being cruel to a monkey like that.
You're not, you. You want to scoop out.
His brains were still alive. Yeah. And
you know how smart they are. I just,
I don't know. Ever since I got a dog,
I'm really sensitive. What about animal?
What about monkeys that are assholes?
Yeah, there's a lot of them.
Monkeys are assholes.
They killed the mayor in India.
Monkeys assaulted and killed a mayor.
The mayor was just hanging out and the
monkeys just walked up and just mean
mugged him. He's fucking with the
monkeys. Why would he do that?
I think monkeys steal things from you.
They steal food from you and shiny things
and you have to give them food to get
the shiny things back sometimes and they
steal things that they think that you
will find valuable.
Like they'll steal your cell phone.
You have to give them food to get it back.
And if you just try to take the cell
phone, they'll fucking attack you.
That sounds like it's survival. I mean
like there's a bit of survival. They,
I just, I don't know man. When I see
people fucking with animals, I just,
I root for the animal. I don't know
why they don't have any commerce.
They don't have any concept
of personal like property.
Like they don't get that. They don't own
things. So when you have something shiny,
they're a little brain knows that
if they just Jack your shiny shit,
then you have to give them food and
wanted to get that shiny shit back.
That's how their culture
works. So you bribed monkeys?
Yes. You can bribe him. Yeah,
you can get your shit back.
There's actually like a small town or
village that there's are a monkey that
would tried to rape a bunch
of women and that were,
here's the article on the Telegraph.
I'll just live monkeys.
Just looks like a rapist. Monkey
tried to take it. Look at his face.
He looks all rapists.
That definitely is a rapey monk.
That's a Reiki looking a little monkey.
Okay. This mean face. This looks like
he doesn't give a fuck about anything.
Take your manhood.
Oh,
he'll fuck you would not want to go to
jail and share a cell with that monkey.
You imagine. How long could you
think you could fight off a monkey?
I was at the zoo the other
day and the dude who a,
the got an a little train tour,
you know,
and the dude who's gay
gave us the train tour,
said that these little monkeys
that they had were only 25 pounds,
but they had twice the
strength of a grown man.
Is that real fuck does a monkey
that's 25 pounds have twice.
Imagine a retarded monkey.
Superman strength.
Take 75 is so rude.
Do they have down syndrome monkeys?
I was saying about that.
You never see that in any other
animal, do you? No. No you don't. Yeah,
we'll sign.
He's looked like Johnny has like the
Johnny Carson eyes where the closer
together. So I think so. I think
some of those monkeys might be, no,
I don't think so. I don't think
they live. I don't think, uh,
I don't know. I'm, I'm guessing,
but I don't think that they,
I don't think they live.
Monk monkeys are like Asians.
They put a stop to that shit quick.
This guy's saying that I've seen a 25
pound monkey overpower 50 pound man.
A 50 pound man. Was We all, sorry,
150 pound male. Sorry. Yeah.
Um, this was a guy who is
a, um, an anthropologist,
but that guy could have been
a pussy. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
And you ever see that
one video where like,
they showed that women could beat up
guys and they had like a girl box,
but it was like the most feminine Asian
Man could possibly flows. They did.
They had a boxing match
between when a woman and a man,
the battle of the sexes and the
guy they got was the most feminine,
Real Asian Man I've ever seen.
He's guys asked straight up whooped.
Okay, so they set it up.
They get chicken. Well, yeah,
you put Ronda Rousey and what some dude,
it doesn't have to have know how to
fight. She will fuck you up. I would quit.
I do like that. I love her. Just getting
mouthy. So high angled by is really hot.
It's hot as fuck. She's cool
as fuck too. She can hang man.
She can hang with anybody and she trains
hard. I was talking to some dudes today,
they've got arm barred her
by her it cold cars place.
The only reason I couldn't date a girl
like that skilled in MMA is because I've
literally been swung on by every girl
I've ever dated. So I mean the girl,
you've pretty much,
at some point they swung on me and
I never hit a girl in my life.
Oh well that's not what we're saying.
But why would all these people, sometimes
they get emotional with me. Why?
What do you Sam, what are you
doing to these girls? Sometimes.
Sometimes I got to play a bad guy and
I got to cut off the Dick for a little
while is sometimes you cut off the Dick.
That's what makes him swing.
What kind of magic, Dick, are
you swinging? Fucking Mandy Dick,
kind of delicious candy. Did
Sam Shipley. I got Cuckoo Dick.
I got to make the girls go. I
got stocker Dick. I'm not hung,
but for some reason they go
stocker crazy. Really? Yeah. Wow.
That's interesting. You just know
how to fuck. Is that what it is?
I take a lot of pride in that. Take
a lot of pride in your work. Well,
you know what?
I've seen what you do on stage and if you
could rock it like that in the bedroom,
I would imagine would be pretty
blown away by your performance.
I got to find a girl with a small set
of vagina and then we're good to go.
You know, small. I'm
not hung it all. Okay.
You just need a small vagina
that you could really tear up.
I could get a big one and just, you
know, I got to work a little harder.
But how do you gauge whether or not
a girl is a small vagina? No. Oh,
I put it in and if I'm banging the sides,
it's a little bigger than if,
and then there, there used to
be this chicken, uh, Canada.
Way Back in the day I used to bang.
I mean,
I've never felt something that type
before in my life. I mean, I was,
I'm not, and I'm not
hungry. I'm like, Oh my God,
I'm fighting to get it in. It was, was
she muscular? No. Is it her asshole? No.
Was it her taint?
You just broke a hole through her team.
You didn't even fuck are
you just stabbed her? Yeah.
I dated a girl who was not a small girl.
She was a big
girl, man. I mean, she was like, uh,
like stout that she was a like,
I think she's mostly Ukrainian.
She's really strong. Like a strong,
her policy was like, oh, vice. Yep,
like a vice. I was like, wow,
like I've dated girls that were like way
smaller than her physically with like
bigger vaginas.
I have a theory that's where
it's not completely sound right
but like the taller,
bigger girls had the tighter vaginas.
A smaller smaller girls have the,
I don't think so cause I was met.
I'll tall girls have giant pussies to
what's weird is my first and my first
girlfriend ever.
I could fist and I was talking to this
today like I remember like kind of
squeeze my hand and I get it in there
and then it was just like go town and I
would wait a minute,
that's a meme right there.
I would squeeze my fingers know and get
my whole hand in there and then it was
just like go town.
But but
you'd have little hands. No
I'm, that's what I'm saying.
Did I just have small hands as a child
now and now I'm trying to think what if I
have really small hands and everyone
made fun of me. I didn't know about it.
How old were you? 1515 a buddy of
mine and I hate telling his story,
but it's so good for a year.
He's,
he always tells me about all these crazy
craigslist shit he does and back page
and he goes, he goes, yeah. He goes,
I want to hook up with this chick.
And she goes,
she made me fist her while she watched
gay porn. Whoa. And like all
fist, her ass, her pussy,
her pussy.
And I go,
Huh. And then did you have to pay her
because you're doing all the work,
work on that and what did he get out
of it? I don't know. He gets off.
I'm begging hookers. It's this thing.
She's a hooker. I mean like it's a,
it's a bat like backpage is
really hooker. Ish. Okay.
So he's getting this girl in this
really hooker ish manner and then he's,
and it's his story. I want to give him
credit. I just don't know. Honestly,
I don't know if he wants his name.
Don't say his name just in case he's a,
so he's fisting them and paying them.
I'm like, why are you paying them? They
should pay you. I've heard a dude's to,
I've heard of it,
kind of
a gay dudes who pay guys
to suck their dicks,
pay like straight guys and
suck their dicks like that.
Apparently it's pretty common.
I don't know. Can you be,
it's better than giving plasma.
I bet you know that. You know,
like when he kicked drawing for money,
by the way,
we're going to get that Peter Duesberg
guy on the podcast and people have told
me that it's an irresponsible
thing to do, uh, that he's, uh,
the professor is a unit from the
University of California Berkeley and is a
biology professor,
is rock solid credentials this guy has.
And he apparently claims that HIV is a
virus and it is not what is responsible
for aids. He claims that AIDS is, uh,
what it is is when people
have a crushed immune system,
most likely in the gay community,
it has to do with
partying and has to do it.
Taking email nitrate and
a bunch of different,
like really heavy drugs that are 10
crystal meth that are devastating to your
immune system. Hold on. And he says that
when these people show these, uh, the,
their,
their immune system is crushed and then
they show that they have HIV in their
system. The reason is that their immune
system is too weak to fight off the HIV.
It's not that HIV has
brought them to that point.
He said it's a variety of different
ailments that a lot of it is caused by,
um, by hardcore partying. Then
what's the blood transfusion
and careless? Well, he's,
well, first of all, he's a, um,
he's a very prominent scientist. I mean,
he's very well respected guy. Again,
he's from the, he has
tenure at the University of
California, Berkeley. I mean,
he's a, is Berkeley with a B or
is it like, what do you mean?
Like I can say correctly, spelled,
spelled silent. K Two. They're getting,
that's funny. Yeah. Yeah. Well, he's
a super, super controversial guy.
Why did they say it's reckless though?
Because people say he's full of Shit
and that, uh, AIDS does. Um, you know,
I've talked about this with Fitzsimmons
and we had this discussion and one of
the things that I said was that it's
really terrifying when you to fucking dumb
to know who's stupid,
you know,
like is he stupid or are the other people
that are climbing the HIV does cause
aids? There's no way they stupid. Maybe
he's interpretation of it. It's different.
I mean, it's really crazy. Um, I,
I don't, I don't know who's right,
but I'm going to bring him on and then
of course there'll be some people that
disagree with him,
so I'm going to want to hear from them
too and just Holler at me on Twitter and
we'll figure out what,
how, how to address this.
I all I can do when it
comes to this sort of a,
um, this sort of incredibly controversial
subject that I really am not qualified
medically to under.
I mean,
I don't understand the idea behind a
retro viruses and [inaudible] and HIV.
I don't understand it. I don't understand
the argument either way. So we'll,
we'll be forced to try to spell this out.
Mr Duisburg argument as
as cleanly as possible.
But of course there's a lot of
really controversial aspects to it.
One of the big ones being how the fuck
is it possible that something can get to
be this sort of mainstream accepted
belief that HIV causes AIDS when he says
it's Bs and what is his argument?
And then of course we'll get someone
else on afterwards that's a counselor,
whatever's initially told to them
and then they just run with it.
That's what politicians
had been doing forever.
They just put something out and then they
just, that's, it's all misinformation.
I don't know about that.
I don't,
I mean I know there's a lot of scientists
who work on AIDS cures and HIV cures,
so I need to of course speak to someone
like that as well as Mr Duesberg.
And then ultimately the fucking most
awesome thing would be to have the two of
them together and give them
a forum after, uh, you know,
Duisburg podcast and then dues
someone who refutes his information.
Then have the two of them would get
together and then we can, Tom Tom Wrestle,
play poker. I don't know. I think that
will be pretty fucking interesting.
I would like to know, I mean, if Duesberg
is right, that's a crazy thing. I mean,
if you think about all the nutty things
that we've already discovered about how
fucking goofy our culture is,
if we found out that that's the case too.
But again, I'm not giving out
any health advice folks. Okay.
Especially when it comes to diseases.
I'm a fucking standup comedian
slash cage fighting commentator.
I'm the last person you should be
listening to when it comes to information
about aids. So all the people that are
worried about like distributing this,
like this guy is a
murderer. What? He's his,
this information that let the guy talk.
He's,
if he's way of fucking smarter
and more educated on this subject,
and most of the people that
are questioning him. So it's a,
I wa I re-read odd,
behold the pale horse,
uh, that one book that he was
talking about aids and how like it's,
it's government made and that guy's,
that Guy William Cooper is his
name. Yeah. Him and your boy.
Who's the other conspiracy
theories? Jones. Yeah. They
supposedly had a big like,
yeah. Well, you know,
conspiracy theorists all hate the other
conspiracy theorists like Latino comics,
they're like Latino.
Somebody just put out a picture
of a monkey and a fuck you looking at
Tripoli. I know. Hey, hey, hey, oh yeah.
A lot of those conspiracy guys,
they come from complained that the other
gods are idiots and that they're all
spewing out this information.
And they always claimed that the other
guy's a government agent. You know,
they all think that everybody,
everybody's a government agent.
It's really interesting.
But that Guy William Cooper said a
lot of the shit I remember reading,
behold a pale horse. Is
that what it's called? Yeah.
And I remember reading it going,
this guy is either crazy or he's doing
this is like some disinformation bit.
Well, yeah, that was the
whole theory on that too.
But big on aliens that
they're already here,
but are part of everything here.
That, and I go, come on, man,
you gotta give me some evidence. You can't
just say the aliens are here. You know,
you just, there was too much.
There's bases on the moon.
Aliens are and they'd show you traveled
to far galaxies and all that stuff.
If you've seen those arguments, the
images about basis. Yay. Let's see,
this was the glass tower. Like what are
you seeing that, I'm not saying it's fine.
Once you find what you're looking for,
there's,
if you Google structures on the moon,
you will lose all faith in human race,
look googled structures in the moon.
And these images that people
are trying to say are like,
like buildings and shit and you're like,
what the hell? They're talking about.
All righty. Uh, a huge moon
base. And that one point,
the Russians and the Americans work
together on it and that the Russians tried
to take all the Americans hostages and
they had to send in some like navy seal
motherfuckers and it killed off 66 people.
Yeah.
There's people that think that the moon
is actually an alien base and then it's
a spaceship and a,
they point to the fact that we dropped
a satellite on the moon once and it rang
for like a day. Like it, like
it rang like it was hollow.
It's like there's some nutty motherfuckers
been contacted from people that
believed that the earth is hollow. If
you ever been contacted by those people.
Now is that the lizards
live? Um, I don't think so.
I think they think that there's a
whole sky in there. I'm not sure.
I think there's more than one group of
people when it comes to the hollow earth
thing. But uh, that there,
it was like the matrix that
there's a whole civilization
underground. Yeah. Yeah.
There's a whole world going on in there
inside the earth. You just got to go.
There's a whole,
you find you're always raving.
He'd go in there and just like stars
and shit. I guess they just have like,
like a little kid has those glow in the
dark stickers. They have stars somehow.
I Dunno. I Dunno what the fuck
they're claiming, but it's, uh,
it's pretty hilarious
at this point in time.
How many times we have to see volcanoes
and go, oh, that's inside of it. Yeah.
Where does that come from?
Looking at a Krispy Kreme doughnut and
thinking there's diamonds in there. Look,
there's this cream in their stupid,
see it coming out the top? Yeah.
That's what's in the whole
fucking it backed up chimneys.
What's going on down there?
More proof that this whole
road is not real. Joe,
check this at the Guardian us data.
A whistle blower.
It's a violation of everyone's
constitutional rights and it's the formal
national security agency officer.
It was saying how the u s is illegally
collecting huge amounts of data on his
fellow citizens.
Right.
And then the first sentence sitting in
its surroundings of an olive garden,
all that. So it's an uh,
an an olive garden too.
Is he talking about the restaurant,
the Nakia surroundings of an olive
garden and the Baltimore suburbs.
He's talking about the restaurant he
ate at the restaurant. He ate it all.
Garn yeah, that's the guy that we had
when we had David Seaman on the podcast.
Yeah, I remember that.
Congressional candidate. Yeah.
Vinnie is the NSA whistleblower.
He's the mathematician I know needs it.
Olive Garden, you know, you have create
you how crazy you are with this shit.
You fuck you know crazy.
You are.
I was watching an olive garden commercial
at all I could think of is you,
you silly bitch, you can get free
breadsticks. I'm like fucking Brian.
And I'm watching the elite more for
them. Their commercials. Oh yeah,
he's made olive garden. A cool thing
to do, people were fans of the podcast.
Sometimes we'll go to olive garden. Just
how to support. Where do you want to eat?
Well, red band likes all garden.
Let's go eat there. By the way, a,
I'm wearing a death squad
tee shirt, one of the, uh,
the new super sexy ones with a,
my favorite cat.
And you can get these go to desk squad.
Dot. TV and, and, and by him. And uh,
whenever you do something like that,
it supports a Brian's podcast.
Now I might put the black
cock bomb on the, on the,
which Sam Tripoli is a part of which
I was going to say the naughty show,
which is Sam's. It's we're doing tonight.
You guys doing tonight? What are you,
who's on it tonight? Gareth
Reynolds, the funniest fucker.
And a good friend of mine had a show,
has a show coming out and MTV,
he went to New York to shoot
until he just got back.
So I'm going to have him on maybe
Dave Anthony's. Gonna come on. We're going
to talk about those. It, uh, it's, uh,
what's it, how comes Greinke show?
I know it's a, uh, it's called,
isn't it called something like laugh or
fail or it's called fail or something
like that. It's like some weird kind
of like, it's some Internet thing.
I don't even know.
He'll describe it.
Just fails. Would fuck ups. I mean,
think about how many traffic accidents.
It's,
Doug Benson had a great idea that I
need to really get on about me doing
commentary over Internet fight.
Yeah. I always wanted to do
that, dude. Just like, pick
up the, fucking find these,
these are hilarious videos of black chicks
swinging on each other or some of the
best videos you'll ever
watch in your life.
Yeah. And me doing it, it would be,
you know, that I would like to do that.
I think that'd be a perfect thing
for me because uh, you know,
obviously the UFC commentary background
and stand up and watching those things.
There's some funny fucking
Vinnie and there's so many.
You never run out of them.
Did you ever see the ones where the guys
fight at the Wendy's at night and it's
the most hilarious video you'll ever,
they had one recently, man.
I saw a dude head kick,
a meter maid and a, I think it
was an England to it. Pull it up.
Pull it up. Cause it's a, it's
really a show. It's called
epic fail. No, no, no, no.
I'll pull that up. No, no, no,
but I'm just saying what my
buddies shelf settle the fuck down.
It was running this shade.
What the hell?
Fuck Sam.
She should together this trying to see
a dude get kicked in the head and your
promo and your bullshit
man kicks man kicks
meter maid in the head.
I think it is dude,
just end.
The sad thing is that dude was skilled
like it was a real roundhouse kick.
He roundhouse kicked this
guy in the fucking head and
the guy just went straight.
Okay. I got to know who's fault. I mean
like the guy could have been an asshole,
a meter main or you have to
see it. You have to see it.
You say that, that's crazy.
The,
if you look at it like there's no way
that guy did anything that a warranted
head kicks, maybe fucked
his mouth. Whoa. Um,
that's always a good point is always
a possibility. Dad. I'm sorry,
I don't find it on Youtube. I looked
for a man. Karate kicks. Meter maid.
Well,
I got nothing better.
Did you ever see the one where this
crazy guys in the park just swinging on
chicks and guys and everyone's
flipping out and they're like,
what the fucks and then the guy just
walks and all sudden this here, hold on.
Oh, here it is. Horrific moment. Uh,
look up go man kicks parking officer
and the second one down, horrific
moment traffic warden is karate kicked.
Found it. So what we're saying, Sam,
there's this one where this guy
just has like this crazy drug.
He's just swinging on people
and in the park and then he,
you see him walk away and now to
know where this dude just like this,
it happens to be like
some professional boxer
just go boom and just knocks him the
fuck out after he's been terrorizing
everybody in the park. It's
hilarious. A horrific moment.
Traffic warden is karate kicked. Oh,
you got to see the video of this guy.
Like he's in Turkey and he like fights
the whole village do net. Yeah, we put,
we played that on the podcast for a couple
of times when I think when bill burr
was on, we did it. That's a great
fight. Yeah, it was ridiculous.
The guy kept cracking dudes. They kept
running after him. You got it Brian too,
too, too too too. Can I
push you on that thing?
If you watch, watch this, what
happens? The guy is riding this shit.
They come out and they ask
him like, Hey man, why you uh,
why you writing these guys right here,
the two guys with the white shirt,
they're like, hey, what are you doing man?
And so he spit on him and so he said
something to him and they gave him really
douchey within no, watch this guy.
This is fucked up man. Watch this.
Oh man, boom. Look at
that. Watch this kick dude.
Boom. Yeah. Once with a
sound effects. Is that you?
You fucking spastic. He's getting
good at that. I've got hurt man.
You don't even care.
You putting cartoon noises and that's
straight worn when yo yo yo yo,
I, that's what jails meant for people are
going to be violent like that right in
the middle of nowhere. Bam. Yeah,
that's a douchebag. That's there's no,
that guy just teed off on that guy
and he kicks hard. That guy was like,
you could tell that was like real
technique turned his head that yeah,
that wasn't a guy who's
never kicked somebody before.
He knocked that guy out and that guy went,
his head went off the
concrete and that's fucking,
that guy could be dead and you'll probably
be fucked up for a long time for her.
That's that. She takes a long time to
recover from. If you survive at all,
your head bouncing off the
fucking concrete like that.
She ever see the one where
the guy pulls a prank,
he jumps out of the trash and the black
guy just turns around and just, yeah,
I love it here.
See this one?
I always thought this one
was the most fucked up one.
This is an old classic where they had
guys like horrible one. What the fuck?
Yeah. Horrible. I don't
know what that was about.
How about the Russians fighting at the
pool? Yeah, that guy got fucked up.
But who knows what that was about?
Do you ever see the ones where all
the Russians for some reason in Russia
there's a public pool with dolphins in
it and the dolphins are swimming around
and you just see these crazy Russians
just starting to get in a fight outside
right at the pool.
Well,
have you ever seen Russian like gang
fights when they're like, did this,
these like groups of kids like meat in
this field and beat the fucking shit out
of each other and they literally go and
skins and shirts and it's like, you know,
they're just swarming into
this town. Oh, here it is.
Oh yeah, I've seen this. Yeah.
It turns into a crazy fist
fight and it often pull. Ha,
why would anyone want to fight?
I don't often pull. Yeah,
here it goes and we're off.
That's scary shit too.
When you're in a fucking
fight in the pool.
Russians don't fuck around Bro.
Oh, Lula guy just kicked him out.
Come over here, dude. Come over here.
Some over here. Oh boom. Throw him in.
This guy's just climbing up and as he
gets out and the guy talks more shit,
you just got knocked into the Dolphin
Pool. Yeah. They like to fight in Russia,
man. By the way, that girl to beginning
of this video is smoking hot lava.
Hot Russian brides, right? I'm
full of, Oh, it's going off son,
back in the water again. That guy got
thrown in the water. It's twice, I think.
Get a camera. Man's laughing. Oh, this
is her. That's every youtube video.
Last is going to get punted again. He's
just getting out. Won't Donk, donk?
There's a knee to the
face, son. Oh, left hook.
Right hand for right hand guys down in
the water. Don't get tossed in again.
Sprawl son. You Guys Bra. Oh Wow.
Look at it as shooting a double.
He's got a bad double.
It's like he's trying to suck his dick.
The guy even looked at least claim to
suck my Dick Nigga. The guy sitting down.
Oh, rods are getting involved. I'm
like, Oh shit. Girl goes down. Wow.
That girl's scream. Wow.
That's like an alarm. Oh Dude.
Got kicked from a seating position.
This is ridiculous. And other girl.
What's up at the girls? Get
the girls out of here. Yeah,
the China get their flip
flops. They're like, oh,
in the water again, son, that's
three in a row. This is ridiculous.
You've got to get that rear naked choke
sign. You've got the armor on the neck.
Finish the job.
There's this guy in the yellow shirt.
He doesn't seem like he fits here guys
just hanging out. He's like, hey buddy,
you need to stock.
Even though these guys,
this is the first time I
hung out with them. Yeah,
you could lose all faith in humanity if
you stay on youtube or live leak long
enough. Well here's the police. Come on.
They're in Russia or there's
Bert Kreischer. Yeah,
Bert Kreischer hammered and come
back looking for his wallet.
So this guy is just, this is some,
I wonder what this is all about.
I know if there's any Russians Beckon
Attos that day just to stay in the water.
He keeps getting knocked in
the water safe in the water.
Well it safe in the water.
If you don't get knocked the fuck out
and then knocked in the water cause guess
what? No one's going to rescue her
down. You're going to drown, man.
Oh. Oh that guy was like chill.
Sudden throwing the elbow.
Just totally missing after the audio
listener is just a bunch of fun. Steve,
what is the video does name,
what does the name of the
video so people can watch it?
It's Russian dolphin fighting.
Russians brought near a dolphin,
Paul full and it's four
minutes and 29 seconds.
Love. What? A silly,
crazier more Jesus.
So funny how it's like white
shirts versus black shirts. Yeah,
and no shirts too.
I guess they know who's who,
but they keep like trying to make up
and then fight again. Who's this guy?
This pony boy.
That's
Chris Titus.
You go back to the beginning of the
video and just see how hot the chick is.
No enough. And know. That's
uncalled for. Come on,
let's go back and look
at the pretty girls.
That's amazing to these iTunes
listeners. True. Too. True.
Being silly.
There's a billion pretty girls online.
You need to see this blurry vision.
You can tell she's smoking.
You can barely see their faces. No, you
can see it in this one. The fuck up.
Shut the fuck you looking at carefully.
You want it to shell and he said you
want us to show it and then we'll decide.
Let's look at it again.
And I bet you can't tell at all.
I bet you could probably see this bitch.
How much you want bet $5 okay.
Go to the beginning of the video. $5
I bet it blurry is right. I bet it is.
Blurry sites, dollars riding
on this shit. Winner, winner,
chicken dinner. Very excited about
Toronto this weekend. Sam trip. I am too.
We get in Thursday night and there's
allegedly a place where you can allegedly
smoke marijuana while you allegedly
have a comedy show. At the same time.
I need to find out what the laws are. I've
allegedly done standup at that legend.
No, no, no, no. Nonsense
craziness. You've never been there.
Arch fear might be joining us.
It's all depending on whether or not
he's contractually obligated to say he
can't. Oh, that's right.
Well it's just for laughs is also
promoting my show up there as well.
It's all taking place
during the comedy festival,
so we're doing Massey hall on Friday,
which is super duper fucking awesome. Did
you do a Massey Hall with me last time?
So sick. Yeah, it was a
great time to is phenomenal.
It's Doug Benson going to be there.
I don't think he's in Canada that week,
but he is going to be at the ice house
Wednesday night. Dad's, Doug Benson, dom,
I rera, Greg Fitzsimmons, Duncan Trussell,
Brian Red Ban and me.
Can I promote where he did his show?
He is to promote the shit out of it.
Sam trevally.
September 26 the noughties show presents
the 2012 searchlight model finale by
fleshlight whites. A searchlight
for now. A model. Well yeah.
What do you like the
American idol of sex toys.
So you,
a bunch of girls dance around and then
they decide which one gets a flashlight
on. You been having like voting's
been going on for like a month.
Do they have to see their pussy? Do
they have to show that? Cause you,
you should really know like what
if it's a training, any wins.
We need to set these big name girls
there. Oh, I saw Alexis, Texas,
Kayden Kross and this girl with the grace
name a fixie out. No War is her name.
Alexis Texas is one of those girls
who could never make it on a sitcom.
Never make it like in the, the the like
the movie version of what you know,
super skinny girls so
people think is high,
but dude's look at that girl's ass and go
crazy for that. Yeah. A lot of girls
would be like, oh, she's too big or she's,
they'll fuck outta here.
That's not what dudes thing.
They look at that big giant
juicy ass and go, holy fuck.
I wonder if she's insured.
It let people like and what like the
media is image of what is hot is like,
is this a little off?
I tell girls all the time to stop
letting television and magazines tell you
what's sexy guys don't like that.
Guys like me on the bone. It's, yeah,
there's something about
a girl who's like really,
really like lean and
skinny and like six packy.
It says something a
little weird about that.
Where's the girls got like 10
pounds more honor than she needs.
Z androgyny is what? I can't like these
supermodels, they're not even hot anymore.
Well you know that's all designed like
the idea of supermodels or reason why
they were like really tall and thin. It's
so clothes look good on them. So close,
sorta lay on them and you've got a
chance to really see the clothes.
Whereas like you put light but
you come way back in the day.
We put some clothes on a girl with big
giant tits and a big ass and all you're
seeing is that big giant
tits and the big ass.
Any Crawford was hot back in the
day and she was the supermind.
Now they're all just so in. They look like
heroin addicts. I don't pay attention.
Not Looking at model magazine.
Sam, what the fuck are you doing?
This is some major pieces of
his life when he, he's always,
I can't say, I'm not trying to
drag you up to the 21st century
Russian chicks in dolphin fighting videos
trying to make you a part of today.
Sam,
I to come apart today,
bring you up to the now I'm writing a lot.
Working hard are stopping.
Listen man,
it's important that we all give each
other shit about that. No, I know.
It's got to be inspired. You know
we bought Xoom shitty new shit in a,
a big show like yours while
it's only shitty new shit,
if you decide that you're writing shitty
stuff. Brian opened up with a fucking,
not opened up but he did a whole new bit
in front of 1200 people in a sold out
show and it killed my first time doing
it. First Time doing that. Right.
You know why? Cause he's got
boss. Don't even say that.
My whole thing is false.
I'll set the place on fire.
You say that and we say that but yet you,
you feel like your new stuff is just
like never said that said I want to,
don't want to, I mean allium
dude, I write in volume.
I'm always throwing stuff against the
wall and sometimes I only find it funny.
So if you write 10 new bits,
I'm happy if three or four of them are,
are good crushers, meet you. Let me too.
So I don't want to try that
other six in, in, in a sh show,
like a theater show we're
doing here at the ice house.
I'll throw garbage and
just see what works.
So what you're saying is you just,
when you get to like a theater show,
there's no fucking around.
You just get to business,
bang it out as much as possible.
I think it's, I think for you,
maybe you could work it, but for me,
I think they're, they're, they're,
they have a shell. I'm there to get
them going, set them up. I mean,
you could just walk out and crush,
but I feel like my job is to get them
really rocking. So when you come up,
it's a supercross involving me in fucking
decisions that becoming an enabler
here. Not at all. Um, I, uh,
I vote like Ari and I had
this conversation once and
uh, you know, he was like, uh,
you know, we'll sort of do, should I
go up and do my best stuff? I says,
who gives a fuck it do
whatever you want to do,
I guess is your time when you're up there
20 minutes for half an hour. I mean,
I wouldn't want you to flatline,
but you don't want to flat line,
flat line of purpose. And there's
nothing wrong with like taking chances.
I don't know.
I just find it like,
I don't know when people are playing that
kind of money that they want to show,
they do want to show, but that's part of
a live show. Sometimes shit goes wrong.
There's nothing wrong with that. It's you
can get out of it. You're a fucking pro.
You've been doing comedy
for almost two decades.
You can pull yourself out of
any downward spiral. You know?
It's not like you can't like
open up and fuck around,
but with reo is like you can't get
fired, so just go fuck around. Right.
It doesn't matter. It's like you're
going to have a good set. No,
I totally understand that.
And that's the,
I think that's the sort of mindset that
you have to have to do like wild standup.
Right. You know when you,
when you play it safe,
the problem with playing it safe is
you have that mentality of planet. Say,
I've never played it safe. That's kind of
why I am who I am. That is who you are,
who you are. What are you Jesse? James
Motherfucker. I told, look, gangster
Duncan fire. That's how I am ma'am.
It Papa. That's what I do. I do it.
Slash. Uh, what was the girl? I don't
know. Maybe. I just think theater shows.
I meant to bring the heat from the
wood. Of course you do. You still,
everybody should bring the heat. What was
it? Was that girl not jewel 80 per cow.
You're either eating for Keller.
Popeye. Yeah. I'm bringing the woods.
That's who I am bringing the who brings
the woods. You'll bring in the wood. Yeah.
What does that even mean? Bringing
the back. I'm bringing the woe.
You bring it to bat baseball term.
I understand my name,
my new album that you guys are both very
funny in Sacramento was fucking awesome.
It was a great show, man. Yeah,
those crowds are a amazingly awesome.
They're like the nicest fucking
people in the history of the world.
It's the weirdest thing and we keep
harping on it and saying how much we
appreciate it, but just because
we're all blown away by it,
I've never had a nicer crowds.
So we talk about the woman who got
mad at you about bees yet. Jesus,
I got a picture of her crazy Vegan
lady got mad cause I was making fun.
Upbeat. She was vegan cheese.
You said she was, what?
Was she vegan or who she was as people
got mad on other people's behalfs no,
she was, I was talking about
the whole thing about being,
one of the things that's most silly about
vegans is the ones who won't eat honey
cause they don't want bees to be enslaved.
So I go,
I have this giant fucking bit about bees
and includes like real facts about bees.
It's hilarious. I can't wait to do it
again. Can we do a Wednesday night,
the ice house or Friday night
in Massey Hall in Toronto.
Um, but anyway, this lady,
it was like all vegan doubt and she got
fucking really bummed out at my, my,
my lack of respect of B's. She's
walked out. She was shit face too.
And people will tell you like, you know
bs really are important man. Yeah, I know.
Guess what? I have no bearing on
whether or not bees live or die.
I'm just doing comedy.
You fuckhead
well take, just to get
mad at that. It's like,
does this lady get mad every time she
watches a movie and someone gets shot and
killed?
Like does she really think that person
got shot and killed or the director
really wants that person to get shot and
killed. It's like, why is it with comedy?
They take it so literally.
It's not they,
it's just a few dummies and
they have 1200 people in a room.
You're going to get a few
dummies. She also said to
you, she was mad at you for,
for Liking Sarah Pailin
though. So I was like, wait,
I think maybe you are drunk and a,
you shouldn't be that.
Her sister was hot and I don't say that.
I like Sarah Palin. I say Sarah Palin.
It's just a misinformed Dominique
is probably a nice person, you know?
She's probably not a bad person.
There's really not that much bad on her.
Her ideas are stupid,
but there's a lot of people too,
but ideas and you could probably drink
with them and have a good time and
they're fine, you know, that's all
I said. Silly bitch of the clock.
Me Out was five.
She probably was just super attracted
to you and just get so angry.
Well she's probably attracted to you and
she knew you could, she couldn't get.
Yeah, so she decided to turn it
on me. Oh well that happens a lot.
I wish I could do that. Happens a lot.
Henry Middle Eastern looking motherfucker.
She was still shit face.
She was talking to me and red
band before she succumbed off.
Not knowing that we were in the show.
She just, she just talking shit. Solace.
Oh Susie.
That's right.
Well why don't you just close
the deal right there in the
hallway. Oh, I remember.
I tried to kiss her.
You have the worst Karma ever.
If it comes to like girls being open
to seeing how far can it go with it.
Girls Fall in love with though. I love
that though. Let me kiss you. That's, uh,
just put it out there. Well,
if you say to a girl like that,
she might just stab you and I know what
the fuck was going on in that girl's
head. You're playing with, you're
playing with a wild animal,
but that's why he's attracted to, Oh,
you attracted to it like crazy bitches.
What did you just ask that?
How long have you known Brad?
I'm trying to get them to talk. Okay.
Fuck is wrong with you. Cock blocker.
Jesus Christ. Here's her, her. Here's
that girl by the way. Ruined up though.
It's sideways. That's her face
melting. What's going on with that?
And when you eat a lot of carrots,
sometimes you face can just fall off.
Crazy. Silly pitch. There's
a lot of them out there.
She's probably going to sue
you now though. Huh? Now
she doesn't have a Twitter.
She doesn't have a Twitter,
but she's going to hear about this man.
She had friends at the show.
I'm sure they got mad and she,
no, she works out in like a UFC gym,
right? Yeah. Did she say that? Yeah.
Well she needs bees.
Julie.
I'm really bummed out fucking
some shit from everybody.
Fucking bees across her
sister was hot lead,
just a fat tats all over her tits.
She had fantastic.
Yeah. Just up to big fat tat over big
fat tick. What was the tattoo off?
It's always a heart with some kind of
angel wings with some kind of like, uh,
uh, I dunno. Shrubbery
shrubberies Hardy's pubic hair.
That's always like some leaves and
shit. Right. What's with the leaves?
There's always like some kind of
thorns or something. My heart fly,
but it's in a cage that's
just saying Ron fucking run.
Did you, what do you, what do you
know about this Julian Assange case?
Do you know about this at all? Is
that this guy? The founder? Yeah.
That he put out a bunch of, uh,
classified documents. Right.
And they're trying to,
they're trying to send him to Sweden.
I tried on some sort of a
sexual assault trial. Well,
the latest is that there's no DNA,
uh,
the link in the condom to,
that's central to their sexual
assault case. There's no DNA. Lincoln,
it might not even be him.
The whole thing is amazing.
The guys held up at the Ecuador embassy
and they're talking about storming the
NSC and the, the premise is this case,
this case, this sexual assault case,
and now the,
the latest is that a,
a a condom given the Swedish police
by one of the Julian Assange,
his accuser does not contain the wikileaks
founders DNA forensic evidence have
found and they reportedly found and
the banks have cut off any funding to
wikileaks. They, you can no longer donate
to keep it going. And it's all, yeah,
that makes sense. It's a smear
campaign. He likes us a smear campaign.
They're trying to just like squish
this guy up on Jack Em. I mean,
who knows what they're gonna do to them.
If they decided to put them in a
Swedish jail, he's probably dead.
They'll probably kill them, you know,
they'll just, they'll just have, you know,
some prison uprising,
let some dudes into his jail and give
them free cigarettes if they've stumped
him to death. I mean it's to bring the
wood, he's going to bring the wood,
like that scene in breaking bad.
And you ever seen like the last,
the are you giving spoilers from
breaking bad? Don't do that.
What the fuck? Not My podcast buddy.
Not this one. I my podcast. All right,
I'll just sit here quietly.
Shut the fuck up.
Sam's know about balls are all about
balls and monkey and bringing wood.
Um,
I gotta apologize to Mac Danzig.
Mack Danzig did a podcast with
me and the beginning of it,
I got the audio of it and it, um,
it wasn't going up on the audio,
wasn't going up to Ustream for
[inaudible]. Brian was there. And so the,
the second part of it, well, I'm saying
it wasn't your fault, it was my fault.
And then the second part of it that
the file's corrupt. So it's fucking,
what's really crazy is Mac Danzig had
the same problem with Ari Shaffir.
He did a podcast with Ari
Shaffir is haunted and yeah, and,
and Ari had the podcast and deleted it
accidentally and then emptied his trash
and then freaked out that he couldn't
get it back. Even tried to bring to,
I think he tried to use
like a data finding program,
but the point is Mac Danzig might be
haunted when it comes to podcasts.
We're going to make it up to him and he's
going to come back in on things random
fucking with them actually,
you know, he doesn't,
he knows it would come in to punch me,
but he's a super inch.
He's a super interesting guy, so it'll
be fun to talk to them again anyway.
He's a really good, really good fight
coming up. Does it? He does. Isn't
even find somebody a, I thought it
was a really good match up. Yeah.
I want to say it's a Japanese fighter.
Oh yeah, it is gummy tucking away goes.
Yeah, that's a good fight. Great.
Fine. Yeah. Yeah. He's fine.
A saccharine to two of the great. Um, uh,
Japanese fighters are sac
saccharine and Tucking Origami.
The great fighters of the, especially
with the last generation, you know,
and go me stills, big knockout puncher.
It's knocked out Tyson Griffin.
Shorter arms though, right? I think
that's what I've seen with Asians,
that they tend to have to shorter arms,
do racism.
When you were talking
to USC on my podcast,
Sam tripled none of a bitch.
He's going for the cheap laugh and
making fun of the Asians arm length.
Yes.
I'm saying that's a big reason why.
Okay. Who's that basketball player?
What's his name? Jeremy Lin.
The you're fucking your arguments.
The wind. No, but I'll tell you about
a Yo Ming. He looks like a t rex.
He's tall with these huge legs. He's
got short, shorter arms. Fuck up.
He does not have short arms.
Arms. No, he doesn't. Not for his.
Bottle him up. Brian. Pull them
up. Pull them up full. Okay,
now I'm going for three for three.
You're going to go down.
You're going to go down with this one.
This one. I swear to God. I'm telling you,
I've watched this guy play
basketball forever. He's not.
His arms are proportional to his
body. Like Blake Griffin. I'm telling,
having super long arms. You are no
judge of symmetry and human beings.
I watch, I learn. I love [inaudible].
I bring the wood.
Yo, Ming is yelling. Which one
is the, the really tall guys.
He's the biggest guy. Yeah,
he's, he was the seven.
Six Guy said he's seven foot seven.
That seems like pretty
decent. No, but you're Scott,
right? Shut the fuck up. Sam. Sam,
Sam, Sam, Sam. That is,
or that guy is in proportion.
There's nothing is proportionate
about his build at all.
You're so silly now.
I can't listen to you and trust you
on anything because we've got clear
photographic evidence that shows you
your shitty theory is no good and you're,
you're rejecting it. You're rejecting in
front of all these people on the inside.
Yes I am. I'm saying that
only that very short on your,
the fuck he does sound. You're wrong.
Sam. This is the shit observation.
I wish you'd brings observation on stage
and have people stare at you and go, no,
no. He doesn't know. You know,
it's like, crowd is nice.
You can say like, lady Gaga has a big
nose and people go, you know what?
She's done. She's really hot, but
she does kind of have a big nose.
You cannot say y'all oming is short arms.
Do the scouting report of Y'all Maine
coming into the draft and they will say
tall guy.
We short proportionally shorter arms.
Awesome.
How do you spell me?
Why a Oh Maine and I end machine
proportionately short on pro pour tea.
Short arms.
Let's say.
How good would yell Ming be
if his arms were longer? Yeah,
arms are pretty short for his height,
but he still has one of the highest.
Okay.
This is inside hoops.
They're too short for his height.
Are you serious?
Yes. Give me back my point. Let me see.
I need to see some more photos of
him cause that looked normal to me.
That look normal. This can be just
some racist bullshit. When he got,
when he was getting drafted.
Date said that his arms long
man. Brian, I think we
need to Google. Yeah.
Yo Ming. Uh, images.
Y'All Ming short arms.
Yeah.
What are you going to eyeball it?
Yes and no.
I don't trust all these racists on wine.
Shit. What's up to the giant Chinese
man? hoops.com is a racist web.
Clearly they know what
kind of man. No, take away.
Nobody said China,
man.
I'm measuring.
It is correct that using this measure
yells arms are proportionally shorter than
the average. This is another one.
This is Yao Ming Mania. Okay.
No, no, no. This is just
a forum. Chantel. Yeah.
How long are y'all means arms wiki
answers seven foot. Six inches.
Wow. That's pretty long. You
could really say those are short.
Do this seven foot, six inch
arms. That's crazy. Well,
isn't that always the case that your
reach is like exactly. No, it's not. No.
There's some guys who have,
just like a lot of these NBA players now,
they have these incredibly long length
long reaches a guy named like Elton brand
who's six, five but he has
a seven to wingspan. Right.
That's like the same thing with Jon Jones.
Jon Jones is six four but he's got a
wingspan of like a seven foot tall guy.
The what is that?
Is that like an extra wide shoulders
that propelled the arms out or is it the
arm actually is longer. I think they
probably a little both. A little.
Both.
Yeah,
because dudes who have short shoulders
definitely always have like a shorter
reach. And guys like Tommy Hearns
where like real wide backs, you know,
had a longer reach on top of the fact
that he was tall and had long limbs.
This guy that just got drafted, number
one, Anthony Davis, his wingspan,
it's like a terror dactyl it's huge.
Did I think you get a point for that?
I think we've got to
give a point back to AAA.
I think you already did
you already give it to me.
I'll be going to give him a ding.
They'll give him a dang.
But the thing,
I'll take it then because yeah.
Um, the, um,
people online are saying that
and there's no like experts,
but enough people in our line
of saying it that I would see.
And that's why when I go
me is a great fighter.
I just think he has a
short reach. Yeah. Well,
he's uh, he, um,
is a really good wrestler and one of the
things that he does with a lot of good
wrestlers do they develop that,
that jump,
that leap forward with our power double,
you know, are Aa takedowns and when they,
you know, they developed that
in intense explosion forward,
they put that in there punch
and that's what go me does,
he throws punches like a fast ball.
I think you actually was a pitcher at
one point in time as well. Um, wow. Okay.
There's all, there's also people that
say he's not disproportionally short.
Huh? Uh, no. Yeah. It's
not particularly strong.
His height long arms. Who says that? Dude,
I just, I if you go back to his whole
thing, I will just make this up.
Uh, yeah. Maine has a
wingspan that is shorter.
Yeah. Some of them say it's not,
it's really interesting. Okay.
That's, it's not, it's,
it seems to be what people like to say.
I think that's a point. Yeah. It's
easier that people like to say,
but also people like to dispute it.
So I googled it both ways.
I Google not proportionally shorter.
You actually watched him play?
You could tell he has short arms
for his height. You could tell.
You could tell when he went to go
block a uh, I don't care. Okay.
Well I'm still fighting for my point.
Why do you want it so bad? Cause I just,
I just know.
Um,
every statement I make is going to be
Google or Wikipedia and I like to go three
for three. So do you think you would be
better? I mean I think it got us a tall,
basically just came,
hold the ball above everybody's head and
it gets a certain point when dudes are
like 10 feet tall. Yeah. But we
still gonna use the same height.
Basketball cause they've already
talked about moving it up a foot.
Five minute warning. All right,
let's wrap this pitch up. We uh,
yeah because at one point in time, like
no one was seven foot six, right? Yeah.
Who's seven foot six? Just 10 years
old was the tallest man in the world.
When did he, when was he alive? Like the
tall scowling worlds, like eight, six.
But those are the guys with
like fucked up pituitary glands.
They're not like a Yao Ming who's like a
functional normal dude who just happens
to be gigantic. But you just, I mean like,
okay.
Kevin Garnett,
when he came into Lee,
he was like a seven footer who's
built like a, uh, a normal,
like a horse if I use proportionate so
it could run no normal because before it
was like these guys with these very
long legs, right? Small Torsos.
There was the first time it was like
actual proportionate seven footers. Yeah.
That pretty soon,
that's the whole Mbas is going to be
like all seven footers at every different
position just with different
strengths and weaknesses.
And if they didn't have weight
classes in the UFC, by the way,
if the 265 pounds wasn't the heavyweight
limit and the superhero heavyweight
division, like those guys are
going to dominate those. There's,
there's gonna be some Chai Ganta
anti human beings in the future,
and they call it the monster
weight division. Well, if
there's enough fighters to,
to have that sort of a weight division,
they eventually will, you know.
Right now the reason why we
haven't implemented it is
because there's not really
enough super heavyweight fighters to fill
a whole division and they would be the
cream of the crop, the super heavy, what
would be the best, biggest, the best guy.
But I think one day eventually that's
going to happen, but he's in there.
This whole fear that people wouldn't
like try to make weight as much.
Like you'd see guys who probably
could fight at the heavyweight level,
but they would like lean back,
like kinda like big country
who could be very dominant,
two oh five but he prefers to
stay at the heavyweight thing.
You might see that a little bit more guys.
If they could make it like
a super heavyweight would
go there instead of trying
to make the way a heavy, we have a
dude's can do whatever they want anyway.
You know, you could fight it,
whatever weight class you want.
I mean Bj Penn is fought heavyweight
before Bj Penn fought Leo Machida
essentially at heavyweight. Liotta was
heavier than two oh five and they fought.
So it's like, you know, if you want
to get up to that weight class,
as long as you weigh in more than two 65,
you can find where the fuck you want.
Well,
if you're a guy like built like a guy
like big country or if you build a good
guy,
like you know,
Anderson Silva is lean and you can
do whatever the fuck you want really.
So it's this, I don't think there's any
like fear of people like getting too big,
but uh, I think it would be interesting
to see big giant dudes this weekend and
Montreal,
or excuse me,
in Toronto also is the UFC and the first
ever UFC flyweight title will change
hands. And Joseph Benevidez
was at our show at the,
in Sacramento and we want to wish him
luck and he's fighting a mighty mouse,
Demetrius mighty mouse Johnson.
I want to wish him luck too.
It's going to be a great fucking fight
and it's for the first ever first ever
flyweight champion ship. It's going
to be sick this weekend. All right,
tomorrow we have rich roll on the
podcast who is a Vegan athlete.
And then Mac Danzig,
we'll return on Wednesday.
And Mac Danzig is also a Vegan athlete.
So it sounded like I'm just anti
Vegan folks. I'm just anti dummy.
So I respect that and I'm anti beans.
Peas can go fuck themselves.
But I'm pro Sam Tripoli.
I Follow Sam Tripoli on Twitter folks.
It's t, R I, P, O, l, I and a
your could support Sam. You know,
I love you and I'm just always
a privilege to be people.
A lot of people hear comedians talk shit
with each other and they get a little
nervous. And that's what we do folks. We
fucking rag each other constantly. And uh,
that's why we enjoy hanging
out. And when I, uh, I,
I'd say that Sam's a little lazy, but he
is very, very, very fucking funny though.
And uh,
it's an honor to wrote Gig it with you.
My brother and I am honored
and privileged. And by the way,
Brian Redman crushed it
in Sacramento. Ladies and
gentlemen, I was very impressed.
That was a, that was a real
solid set dude. Brian's a real,
been really been dedicated
to a stand up lately.
And the rewards are showing.
And he'll also be at the ice
house this Wednesday night.
So this one's in as a crazy fucking show.
Doug Benson, Joey Diaz, Duncan Trussell,
Greg Fitzsimmons, Brian Red band. Uh,
and uh, maybe even Thompson Gara too.
We don't know. It's going to be fucking
crazy. So tomorrow which role? Wednesday,
um, uh, Mac dancing and Joey Diaz might
want to come in Wednesday as well.
We might do two on Wednesday.
That's how little of a fuck
we give you feel me, Sam.
Troubling dude. You're bringing the
wood. Damn, I'm bringing the wood. Uh,
I want to thank Ting for sponsoring
this podcast. Uh, the um,
the website to go to his
rogan.ting.com and if you go there,
they will welcome you.
The first you can save.
There's a girl like she's holding up
my sign and where my faces should be,
her tits.
That's how awesome this picture is.
And you can say 50 bucks on your
First Ping a Ting Ping. How dare I.
Your First Ting device is an amazing
service that no cell phone contracts.
You get the highest end cell phones
available, especially that droids.
They're really beautiful phones and uh,
they have really fair rates and uh,
and great plans and a,
they have it set up so that you can have
several phones in one account so that
you can, you know, if you, both you
and your wife barely use the phone,
you don't have to pay for
two fucking accounts. You,
you have all your minutes
connected to the two phones.
So there's a lot of great advantages
to ting and I want you to check it out.
Go to [inaudible] Dot Com uh,
well the actual shout out to our real
supposed to eat rogan.ting.com Rogan dot
tang.
Shout out to tank and shout
out to [inaudible] dot com
always the sponsor of our
podcast, creator of Alpha brain and shroom
tech and new mood. Some Alpha brain.
You can son the five HTP and l
trip defense supplement new mood,
which actually enhances your
brain's production of Serotonin,
making you fucking happier.
That's what kind of shit we're dropping
on doing that. We also have kettle bells,
battle ropes, hemp protein powder.
So not only do you get your protein,
but you get your marijuana street cred.
See what I'm saying? Shout out to a desk.
Squad dot. TV sweat this beautiful
shirt that I have. It too can be yours.
If you go to death squad.
Dot t v an order that shit's sun
where you can get a shop. squad.tv.
Now the shop's quiet. Ooh, look at that.
What does shop squad? This is the store.
You have a shorter store now, how awful.
Shop squad. So if you can't remember,
shop squad. Go to desk squad. Death Squad.
Death Squad desk bought that TV. Jane,
do you know Mary Jane? She modeled the
girl new girl shirts. We have all the, Oh,
you got girl shirts, but I
don't felt powerful. Sexy girl.
Far too dirty bitches
bathroom at the comedy store.
Did you hear all this bath? Oh, that's
hilarious. Oh you Brian. You silly.
Silly Bitch. All right folks. We'll be
back tomorrow with rich roll and, uh,
hopefully we'll get Joey d as in this
week as well. We'll see you soon.
Thank you very much.
We love you all.
Thanks for all the positive energy and
the positive messages and all the fucking
groovy vibes were a part of this wild
wave. Let's write it right into the beach.
You fucks.
Yeah.